<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2017.lilt">
  <volume id="15">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Linguistic Issues in Language Technology, Volume 15, 2017</booktitle>
      <publisher>CSLI Publications</publisher>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Lexical Factorization and Syntactic Behavior</title>
      <author><first>James</first><last>Pustejovsky</last></author>
      <author><first>Aravind</first><last>Joshi</last></author>
      <abstract>In this paper, we examine the correlation between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_semantics">lexical semantics</a> and the syntactic realization of the different components of a word’s meaning in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language">natural language</a>. More specifically, we will explore the effect that lexical factorization in verb semantics has on the suppression or expression of semantic features within the sentence. Factorization was a common analytic tool employed in early generative linguistic approaches to lexical decomposition, and continues to play a role in contemporary <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a>, in various guises and modified forms. Building on the unpublished analysis of verbs of seeing in Joshi (1972), we argue here that the significance of lexical factorization is twofold : first, current models of verb meaning owe much of their insight to factor-based theories of meaning ; secondly, the factorization properties of a lexical item appear to influence, both directly and indirectly, the possible syntactic expressibility of arguments and adjuncts in sentence composition. We argue that this information can be used to compute what we call the factor expression likelihood (FEL) associated with a verb in a sentence. This is the likelihood that the overt syntactic expression of a factor will cooccur with the verb. This has consequences for the compositional mechanisms responsible for computing the meaning of the sentence, as well as significance in the creation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">computational models</a> attempting to capture linguistic behavior over large corpora.</abstract>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <url hash="1bb480bf">2017.lilt-15.1</url>
      <bibkey>pustejovsky-joshi-2017-lexical</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">Deep Neural Networks</a> to Learn Syntactic Agreement</title>
      <author><first>Jean-Phillipe</first><last>Bernardy</last></author>
      <author><first>Shalom</first><last>Lappin</last></author>
      <abstract>We consider the extent to which different deep neural network (DNN) configurations can learn syntactic relations, by taking up Linzen et al.’s (2016) work on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subject–verb–object">subject-verb agreement</a> with LSTM RNNs. We test their methods on a much larger corpus than they used (a 24 million example part of the WaCky corpus, instead of their 1.35 million example corpus, both drawn from Wikipedia). We experiment with several different DNN architectures (LSTM RNNs, GRUs, and CNNs), and alternative parameter settings for these systems (vocabulary size, training to test ratio, number of layers, memory size, drop out rate, and lexical embedding dimension size). We also try out our own unsupervised DNN language model. Our results are broadly compatible with those that Linzen et al. report. However, we discovered some interesting, and in some cases, surprising features of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">DNNs</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> in their performance of the agreement learning task. In particular, we found that DNNs require large vocabularies to form substantive lexical embeddings in order to learn structural patterns. This finding has interesting consequences for our understanding of the way in which DNNs represent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax">syntactic information</a>. It suggests that DNNs learn syntactic patterns more efficiently through rich lexical embeddings, with semantic as well as syntactic cues, than from training on lexically impoverished strings that highlight structural patterns.</abstract>
      <issue>2</issue>
      <url hash="8a8a83f1">2017.lilt-15.3</url>
      <bibkey>bernardy-lappin-2017-using</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Dynamic Argument Structure</title>
      <author><first>Elisabetta</first><last>Jezek</last></author>
      <abstract>This paper presents a new classification of verbs of change and modification, proposing a dynamic interpretation of the lexical semantics of the predicate and its arguments. Adopting the model of dynamic event structure proposed in Pustejovsky (2013), and extending the model of dynamic selection outlined in Pustejovsky and Jezek (2011), we define a verb class in terms of its Dynamic Argument Structure (DAS), a representation which encodes how the participants involved in the change behave as the event unfolds. We address how the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_(computer_science)">logical resources</a> and results of change predicates are realized syntactically, if at all, as well as how the exploitation of the resource results in the initiation or termination of a new object, i.e. the result. We show how DAS can be associated with a dynamically encoded event structure representation, which measures the change making reference to a scalar component, modelled in terms of assignment and/or testing of values of attributes of participants.</abstract>
      <issue>3</issue>
      <url hash="bbb8f510">2017.lilt-15.4</url>
      <bibkey>jezek-2017-dynamic</bibkey>
    <title_ar>هيكل الحجة الديناميكية</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Structure d'argument dynamique</title_fr>
      <title_pt>Estrutura de Argumento Dinâmico</title_pt>
      <title_es>Estructura de argumentos dinámica</title_es>
      <title_ja>動的引数構造</title_ja>
      <title_zh>动参数结构</title_zh>
      <title_hi>गतिशील तर्क संरचना</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Динамическая структура аргументов</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Struchtúr Argóine Dinimiciúla</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Δυναμική δομή επιχειρημάτων</title_el>
      <title_hu>Dinamikus argumentumstruktúra</title_hu>
      <title_kk>Динамикалық аргумент құрылымы</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Dinaminė argumentų struktūra</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Динамичка структура на аргументи</title_mk>
      <title_it>Struttura dinamica degli argomenti</title_it>
      <title_ml>ഡൈനാമിക് ആര്‍ഗമെന്റ് സ്ട്രാക്ട്രൂട്ട്</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Динамик аргументын бүтэц</title_mn>
      <title_ms>Struktur Argumen Dinamik</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Struttura ta’ Argument Dinamiku</title_mt>
      <title_no>Dynamisk argumentstruktur</title_no>
      <title_pl>Dynamiczna struktura argumentów</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Динамична структура аргумента</title_sr>
      <title_si>නිර්මාණික සාක්ෂික සංවිධානය</title_si>
      <title_ro>Structura dinamică a argumentului</title_ro>
      <title_so>Qoraalka</title_so>
      <title_sv>Dynamisk argumentstruktur</title_sv>
      <title_ur>دینامیک آرگنم ساختار</title_ur>
      <title_ta>Dynamic Argument Structure</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Cấu trúc Vật lý</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Динамична структура на аргументите</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Name</title_hr>
      <title_id>Struktur Argumen Dinamik</title_id>
      <title_da>Dynamisk argumentstruktur</title_da>
      <title_nl>Dynamische argumentstructuur</title_nl>
      <title_de>Dynamische Argumentstruktur</title_de>
      <title_fa>ساختار ارجمند دینامیک</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Dynamic Argument Structure</title_sw>
      <title_tr>_Senedler</title_tr>
      <title_af>Dinamiese Argument Struktuur</title_af>
      <title_am>dialogs-action</title_am>
      <title_hy>Comment</title_hy>
      <title_sq>Struktura dinamike e argumentit</title_sq>
      <title_ko>동적 논원 구조</title_ko>
      <title_bs>Dinamička struktura argumenta</title_bs>
      <title_bn>ডাইনামিক আর্গামেন্ট কাঠামো</title_bn>
      <title_cs>Dynamická struktura argumentů</title_cs>
      <title_ca>Dynamic Argument Structure</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Dynaaminen argumentin rakenne</title_fi>
      <title_et>Dünaamiline argumendi struktuur</title_et>
      <title_az>Dinamik Argument Yapısı</title_az>
      <title_jv>dynamics argument structural</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Dinamična struktura argumentov</title_sk>
      <title_he>מבנה הטיעון דינמי</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>Dynamic Argument Structure</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تقدم هذه الورقة تصنيفًا جديدًا لأفعال التغيير والتعديل ، تقترح تفسيرًا ديناميكيًا للدلالات المعجمية للمسند وحججه. باعتماد نموذج هيكل الحدث الديناميكي المقترح في Pustejovsky (2013) ، وتوسيع نموذج التحديد الديناميكي الموضح في Pustejovsky and Jezek (2011) ، نحدد فئة الفعل من حيث بنية الحجة الديناميكية (DAS) ، وهو تمثيل يشفر كيف يتصرف المشاركون المشاركون في التغيير مع تطور الحدث. نتناول كيفية تحقيق الموارد المنطقية ونتائج مسندات التغيير بشكل نحوي ، إن وجد ، وكذلك كيف يؤدي استغلال المورد إلى بدء أو إنهاء كائن جديد ، أي النتيجة. نعرض كيف يمكن ربط DAS بتمثيل بنية الحدث المشفر ديناميكيًا ، والذي يقيس التغيير الذي يشير إلى مكون عددي ، على غرار من حيث التخصيص و / أو اختبار قيم سمات المشاركين.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo apresenta uma nova classificação dos verbos de mudança e modificação, propondo uma interpretação dinâmica da semântica lexical do predicado e seus argumentos. Adotando o modelo de estrutura dinâmica de eventos proposto em Pustejovsky (2013), e estendendo o modelo de seleção dinâmica descrito em Pustejovsky e Jezek (2011), definimos uma classe verbal em termos de sua Estrutura Argumentativa Dinâmica (DAS), uma representação que codifica como os participantes envolvidos na mudança se comportam à medida que o evento se desenrola. Abordamos como os recursos lógicos e os resultados dos predicados de mudança são realizados sintaticamente, se for o caso, bem como como a exploração do recurso resulta no início ou término de um novo objeto, ou seja, o resultado. Mostramos como o DAS pode ser associado a uma representação de estrutura de eventos codificada dinamicamente, que mede a mudança fazendo referência a um componente escalar, modelado em termos de atribuição e/ou teste de valores de atributos de participantes.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Cet article présente une nouvelle classification des verbes de changement et de modification, proposant une interprétation dynamique de la sémantique lexicale du prédicat et de ses arguments. En adoptant le modèle de structure d'événement dynamique proposé dans Pustejovsky (2013) et en étendant le modèle de sélection dynamique décrit dans Pustejovsky et Jezek (2011), nous définissons une classe de verbes en termes de structure d'argument dynamique (DAS), une représentation qui code la façon dont les participants ont participé au changement se comporter à mesure que l'événement se déroule. Nous expliquons comment les ressources logiques et les résultats des prédicats de changement sont réalisés syntaxiquement, le cas échéant, ainsi que la façon dont l'exploitation de la ressource entraîne le lancement ou la fin d'un nouvel objet, c'est-à-dire le résultat. Nous montrons comment le DAS peut être associé à une représentation de structure d'événement codée dynamiquement, qui mesure le changement en faisant référence à une composante scalaire, modélisée en termes d'affectation et/ou de test des valeurs des attributs des participants.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo presenta una nueva clasificación de los verbos de cambio y modificación, proponiendo una interpretación dinámica de la semántica léxica del predicado y sus argumentos. Adoptando el modelo de estructura dinámica de eventos propuesto en Pustejovsky (2013), y ampliando el modelo de selección dinámica descrito en Pustejovsky y Jezek (2011), definimos una clase de verbos en términos de su Estructura de Argumentos Dinámicos (DAS), una representación que codifica cómo los participantes involucrados en el cambio comportarse a medida que se desarrolla el evento. Abordamos cómo los recursos lógicos y los resultados de los predicados de cambio se realizan sintácticamente, si es que se realizan, y cómo la explotación del recurso da como resultado el inicio o la terminación de un nuevo objeto, es decir, el resultado. Mostramos cómo el DAS puede asociarse con una representación de estructura de eventos codificada dinámicamente, que mide el cambio haciendo referencia a un componente escalar, modelado en términos de asignación y/o prueba de valores de atributos de los participantes.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>この論文は、変化と修飾の動詞の新しい分類を提示し、述語とその引数の語彙的意味論の動的な解釈を提案している。Pustejovsky （ 2013 ）で提案された動的イベント構造のモデルを採用し、PustejovskyとJezek （ 2011 ）で概説されている動的選択のモデルを拡張することで、私たちはその動的引数構造（ DAS ）の観点から動詞クラスを定義します。これは、イベントの展開に伴って変更に関与する参加者がどのように振る舞うかをコード化する表現です。私たちは、変化述語の論理的リソースと結果が構文的にどのように実現されるか（もしあれば）、そしてリソースの利用が新しいオブジェクトの開始または終了、すなわち結果にどのようにつながるかに取り組んでいます。DASがどのように動的にエンコードされたイベント構造表現に関連付けられるかを示します。これは、参加者の属性の値の割り当ておよび/またはテストの観点からモデル化されたスカラーコンポーネントを参照する変更を測定します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर परिवर्तन और संशोधन की क्रियाओं का एक नया वर्गीकरण प्रस्तुत करता है, जो विधेय और इसके तर्कों के लेक्सिकल शब्दार्थ की एक गतिशील व्याख्या का प्रस्ताव करता है। Pustejovsky (2013) में प्रस्तावित गतिशील घटना संरचना के मॉडल को अपनाते हुए, और Pustejovsky और Jezek (2011) में उल्लिखित गतिशील चयन के मॉडल का विस्तार करते हुए, हम अपनी गतिशील तर्क संरचना (डीएएस) के संदर्भ में एक क्रिया वर्ग को परिभाषित करते हैं, एक प्रतिनिधित्व जो एनकोड करता है कि परिवर्तन में शामिल प्रतिभागी घटना के रूप में कैसे व्यवहार करते हैं। हम संबोधित करते हैं कि तार्किक संसाधनों और परिवर्तन विधेय के परिणामों को वाक्यात्मक रूप से कैसे महसूस किया जाता है, यदि बिल्कुल भी, साथ ही साथ संसाधन के शोषण के परिणामस्वरूप एक नई वस्तु की दीक्षा या समाप्ति होती है, यानी परिणाम। हम दिखाते हैं कि डीएएस को गतिशील रूप से एन्कोडेड ईवेंट संरचना प्रतिनिधित्व के साथ कैसे जोड़ा जा सकता है, जो प्रतिभागियों की विशेषताओं के मूल्यों के असाइनमेंट और / या परीक्षण के संदर्भ में मॉडलिंग किए गए अदिश घटक के संदर्भ में परिवर्तन को मापता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>本条变化改动词类,谓词论词汇语义解。 Pustejovsky(2013)之动事件结构,广PustejovskyJezek(2011)之概述,因其动参数(DAS)义动词类,DAS一表也,编码与变者参与者展其行事。 臣等论逻辑资源变化谓词所以语法成者(若有言),及资源之用所以启止者,可也。 展DAS动编码之事件结构,度标量组件之引改,以参与者性之分/试建模之。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>В данной работе представлена новая классификация глаголов изменения и модификации, предлагающая динамическую интерпретацию лексической семантики предиката и его аргументов. Принимая модель динамической структуры событий, предложенную в работе Pustejovsky (2013), и расширяя модель динамического отбора, изложенную в работе Pustejovsky and Jezek (2011), мы определяем класс глаголов с точки зрения его динамической структуры аргументов (DAS), представления, которое кодирует, как участники изменения ведут себя по мере развития события. Мы рассмотрим, как логические ресурсы и результаты предикатов изменения реализуются синтаксически, если вообще реализуются, а также как эксплуатация ресурса приводит к инициированию или завершению нового объекта, то есть результата. Показано, как DAS может быть связан с динамически закодированным представлением структуры события, которое измеряет изменение со ссылкой на скалярный компонент, смоделированный в терминах присвоения и/или тестирования значений атрибутов участников.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Cuireann an páipéar seo aicmiú nua i láthair na mbriathra athraithe agus mionathraithe, ag moladh léirmhíniú dinimiciúil ar shéimeantaic léacsach an tuar agus a chuid argóintí. Ag glacadh leis an tsamhail de struchtúr imeachtaí dinimiciúil atá molta in Pustejovsky (2013), agus ag leathnú an tsamhail de roghnú dinimiciúil atá leagtha amach in Pustejovsky and Jezek (2011), sainímid aicme briathar i dtéarmaí a Struchtúr Argóine Dinimiciúla (DAS), léiriú a ionchódaíonn conas a iompraíonn na rannpháirtithe a bhí páirteach san athrú de réir mar a théann an imeacht ar aghaidh. Tugaimid aghaidh ar an gcaoi a ndéantar acmhainní loighciúla agus torthaí réamh-mheastacháin athraithe a réadú go comhréir, más rud é ar chor ar bith, chomh maith leis an gcaoi a n-eascraíonn saothrú na hacmhainne go dtionscnaítear nó go gcuirtear deireadh le réad nua, i.e. an toradh. Léirímid an chaoi ar féidir DAS a nascadh le hionadaíocht ar struchtúr imeachtaí atá ionchódaithe go dinimiciúil, a thomhaiseann an t-athrú ag tagairt do chomhpháirt scálach, arna mhúnlú i dtéarmaí sannadh agus/nó tástáil luachanna tréithe na rannpháirtithe.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία παρουσιάζει μια νέα ταξινόμηση των ρήμων αλλαγής και τροποποίησης, προτείνοντας μια δυναμική ερμηνεία της λεξικής σημασιολογίας του υπαρκτού και των επιχειρημάτων του. Υιοθετώντας το μοντέλο δυναμικής δομής γεγονότων που προτείνεται στο Πούστεjovsky (2013), και επεκτείνοντας το μοντέλο δυναμικής επιλογής που περιγράφεται στα Πούστεjovsky και Τζέζεκ (2011), καθορίζουμε μια τάξη ρήματος από την άποψη της δυναμικής δομής επιχειρημάτων (μια αναπαράσταση που κωδικοποιεί πώς συμπεριφέρονται οι συμμετέχοντες που εμπλέκονται στην αλλαγή καθώς το γεγονός εξελίσσεται. Εξετάζουμε πώς υλοποιούνται συντακτικά οι λογικοί πόροι και τα αποτελέσματα των προϋπολογισμών αλλαγής, αν überhaupt, καθώς και πώς η εκμετάλλευση του πόρου οδηγεί στην έναρξη ή τερματισμό ενός νέου αντικειμένου, δηλαδή του αποτελέσματος. Δείχνουμε πώς μπορεί να συνδεθεί με μια δυναμικά κωδικοποιημένη αναπαράσταση δομής γεγονότων, η οποία μετρά την αλλαγή κάνοντας αναφορά σε ένα κλιμακωτό στοιχείο, μοντελοποιημένο από την άποψη ανάθεσης ή/και δοκιμής τιμών χαρακτηριστικών των συμμετεχόντων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A tanulmány a változás és a módosítás igéinek új osztályozását mutatja be, amely a prédikátum lexikai szemantikájának és érveinek dinamikus értelmezését javasolja. A Pusztejovszkijban (2013) javasolt dinamikus eseménystruktúra modelljének alkalmazásával, valamint a Pusztejovszkijban és Jezekben (2011) vázolt dinamikus kiválasztás modelljének kiterjesztésével egy igéosztályt definiálunk Dinamikus Argument Structure (DAS), amely kódolja, hogy a változásban részt vevő résztvevők hogyan viselkednek az esemény kibontakozása során. Megvizsgáljuk, hogyan valósulnak meg a logikai erőforrások és a változási prédikátumok eredményei szintaktikusan, ha egyáltalán, valamint hogyan eredményezi az erőforrás kihasználása egy új objektum, azaz az eredmény kezdeményezését vagy megszűnését. Megmutatjuk, hogyan lehet DAS kapcsolódni egy dinamikusan kódolt eseménystruktúra-reprezentációval, amely méri a változást egy skaláris komponensre hivatkozva, modellezve a résztvevők attribútumainak hozzárendelése és/vagy tesztelése szempontjából.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დომენტის ახალი კლასიფიკაცია ცვლილების და მოცემების გერბების განსაზღვრება, რომელიც განსაზღვრებას დინამიკური სიმენტიკის განსაზღვრება და მისი არგუმენტების ელექსიკური სი მოდინამიკური მოვლენების სტრუქტურის მოდელს, რომელიც პუსტეჯოსკური (2013) და პუსტეჯოსკური და ეზეკური (2011) განსაზღვრებული დინამიკური მოვლენების მოდელს გავაკეთებთ, ჩვენ განსაზღვრებთ ვერბური კლასის მისი დინამიკური აპგუმენტის სტრუქტურაციის (DAS)  ჩვენ ვაკეთებთ როგორ ცვლილების ლოგიკური რესურსები და წარმოდგენები სინტაქტიურად აღმოჩნდება, თუ ყველაფერი, და როგორ რესურსების экოლუტირება შეიძლება ახალი ობიექტის თვიციაციაში ან დასრულ ჩვენ ჩვენ აჩვენებთ, როგორ DAS შეიძლება დაკავშირება დინამიკურად კოდირებული მოვლენის სტრუქტურაციის რესპენტირებაზე, რომელიც შეცვლების შეცვლების შესახებ სკალარის კომპონენტებისთვის, მოდელურ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Questo lavoro presenta una nuova classificazione dei verbi di cambiamento e modifica, proponendo un'interpretazione dinamica della semantica lessicale del predicato e dei suoi argomenti. Adottando il modello di struttura dinamica degli eventi proposto in Pustejovsky (2013), ed estendendo il modello di selezione dinamica delineato in Pustejovsky e Jezek (2011), definiamo una classe verbale in termini di struttura dinamica degli argomenti (DAS), una rappresentazione che codifica il comportamento dei partecipanti coinvolti nel cambiamento mentre si svolge l'evento. Ci occupiamo di come le risorse logiche e i risultati dei predicati di cambiamento sono realizzati sintatticamente, se del tutto, così come di come lo sfruttamento della risorsa comporta l'avvio o la cessazione di un nuovo oggetto, cioè il risultato. Mostriamo come DAS può essere associato a una rappresentazione dinamicamente codificata della struttura degli eventi, che misura il cambiamento facendo riferimento a una componente scalare, modellata in termini di assegnazione e/o test dei valori degli attributi dei partecipanti.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз өзгерту мен өзгерту вербаларының жаңа түрлендірімін көрсетеді. Бұл аргументтердің лексикалық семантикалық түрлендірімін және оның аргументтерінің динамикалық түрлендірімін Пуштеджовски (2013) дегенде ұсынылған динамикалық оқиға құрылымының үлгісін қабылдап, Пуштеджовски және Джезек (2011) дегенде жазылған динамикалық таңдау үлгісін кеңейту үлгісін біз оның динамикалық аргумент құрылымының (DAS) динамикалық класын анықтаймыз. Оқиға қатысушылар Біз логикалық ресурстар мен өзгертулердің нәтижелерін синтактикалық түрде қалай түсіндіру үшін, егер бұл нәтижесі қалай, ресурстардың жұмыс істеу немесе жаңа нысанның бастау немесе аяқтау нәтижесін қалай түсі Біз DAS динамикалық кодталған оқиға құрылымына қалай байланыстырылатынын көрсетедік. Бұл өзгерістерді қатысушылардың атрибуттарының масштабына сәйкес келтіру мен/немесе сынақтау үшін модельді түсіндіреді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente pateikiamas naujas pokyčių ir pakeitimų žodžių klasifikavimas, kuriame siūloma dinamiškai aiškinti teksto tekstinę semantiką ir jos argumentus. Priimdami Pustejovskije pasiūlytą dinaminės renginių struktūros model į (2013 m.) ir išplečiant Pustejovskije ir Jezeke (2011 m.) aprašytą dinaminės atrankos modelį (2011 m.), mes apibrėžiame žodžių klasę pagal jos dinaminę argumentų struktūrą (DAS), atstovavimą, koduojantį, kaip pokyčių dalyviai elgiasi vykstant renginiui. Mes sprendžiame, kaip logiški i štekliai ir pokyčių rezultatai yra suvokiami sintetiškai, jei iš viso, taip pat kaip naudojant išteklius pradedamas arba nutraukiamas naujas objektas, t. y. rezultatas. Mes parodome, kaip DAS gali būti siejama su dinamiškai koduotu renginių struktūros atstovavimu, kuriuo matuojamas pokytis, kuriame daroma nuoroda į skalinį komponentą, modeliuojamas pagal dalyvių požymių paskirstymą ir (arba) bandymą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Kertas ini menghasilkan klasifikasi baru verb perubahan dan pengubahsuaian, melaporkan interpretasi dinamik semantik leksikal predikat dan argumennya. Mengadopsi model struktur peristiwa dinamik yang diusulkan di Pustejovsky (2013), dan memperluas model pemilihan dinamik yang diletakkan di Pustejovsky dan Jezek (2011), kami takrifkan kelas verb dalam terma Struktur Argumen Dinamik (DAS), perwakilan yang mengekodkan bagaimana peserta yang terlibat dalam perubahan bertindak semasa peristiwa berkembang. Kami mengatasi bagaimana sumber logik dan keputusan predikat perubahan diketahui secara sintaktik, jika sama sekali, serta bagaimana pengeluaran sumber menghasilkan pemulaan atau penghentian objek baru, iaitu keputusan. Kami menunjukkan bagaimana DAS boleh berkaitan dengan persembahan struktur peristiwa yang dikodekan secara dinamik, yang mengukur perubahan membuat rujukan kepada komponen skalar, dipodelkan dalam terma tugasan dan/atau ujian nilai atribut peserta.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Овој весник претставува нова класификација на промени и модификации, предлагајќи динамична интерпретација на лексикалната семантика на предикатот и неговите аргументи. Прифаќајќи го моделот на динамичната структура на настани предложен во Пустејовски (2013) и проширувајќи го моделот на динамичната селекција објаснет во Пустејовски и Језек (2011), дефинираме класа на дефинирање во поглед на нејзината динамична структура на аргументи (ДАС), претставница која кодира како учесниците вклучени во промената се однесуваат Ние решаваме како логичните ресурси и резултатите на предикатите на промената се реализираат синтактички, ако воопшто, како и како искористувањето на ресурсот резултира со иницијација или завршување на нов објект, т.е. резултатот. Ние покажуваме како ДАС може да се поврзува со динамично кодирана претстава на структурата на настаните, која ја мери промената со референција на скаларна компонента, моделирана во поглед на призначување и/или тестирање на вредностите на атрибутите на учесниците.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jippreżenta klassifikazzjoni ġdida ta’ verbs ta’ bidla u modifika, li tipproponi interpretazzjoni dinamika tas-semantika lexika tal-predikat u l-argumenti tiegħu. L-adozzjoni tal-mudell tal-istruttura dinamika tal-avvenimenti proposti f’Pustejovsky (2013), u l-estensjoni tal-mudell tal-għa żla dinamika deskritt f’Pustejovsky u Jezek (2011), aħna niddefinixxu klassi ta’ verbs f’termini tal-Istruttura Dinamika tal-Argument (DAS), rappreżentanza li tikkodifika kif il-parteċipanti involuti fil-bidla jaġixxu hekk kif jiżviluppa l-avveniment. Aħna nindirizzaw kif ir-riżorsi loġi ċi u r-riżultati tal-predikati tal-bidla jitwettqu b’mod sintetiku, jekk fuq kollox, kif ukoll kif l-isfruttament tar-riżorsi jirriżulta fil-bidu jew it-terminazzjoni ta’ oġġett ġdid, jiġifieri r-riżultat. Aħna nuru kif DAS tista’ tiġi assoċjata ma’ rappreżentazzjoni dinamikament ikkodifikata tal-istruttura tal-avvenimenti, li tkejjel il-bidla billi tagħmel referenza għal komponent skalari, immudellat f’termini ta’ assenjazzjoni u/jew ittestjar tal-valuri tal-attributi tal-parteċipanti.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ മാറ്റം മാറ്റുന്നതിനും മാറ്റങ്ങളുടെ വാക്കുകളുടെ പുതിയ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചുകൊടുക്കുന്നു. മുന്‍കൂട്ടിക്കൊണ് പുസ്റ്റെജോവ്സ്കിയില്‍ പ്രാദേശിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്ന ഡൈനാമിക് സംഭവങ്ങളുടെ രൂപത്തില്‍ മാതൃകയും പുസ്റ്റെജോവ്സ്കിയിലും ജെസ്കിലും വെളിപ്പെടുത്തിയിരിക്കുന്ന ഡിയാനിമിക്ക് ആര്‍ഗമെന്റ്റ്  ഒരു പുതിയ വസ്തുവിന്റെ ആരംഭിക്കുന്നതിനും അവസാനിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനും വിഭവങ്ങളുടെ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതിനും പുതിയ വസ്തുക്കളുടെ ആരംഭിക്കുന്നതിനോ അവസാനിക്കുന് പങ്കുകാരുടെ മൂല്യങ്ങളുടെ മൂല്യങ്ങള്‍ പരീക്ഷിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള മാറ്റങ്ങള്‍ പരീക്ഷിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള മാറ്റങ്ങള്‍ പരിശോധിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള മാതൃകയാണ് ഡി</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret viser eit nytt klassifikasjon av forandringar og endringar, som foreslår ein dynamisk tolking av den leksiske semantikka av de predikarte og argumentene. Ved å godta modellen for dynamiske hendingsstrukturken som foreslått i Pustejovsky (2013) og utvide modellen for dynamiske utval som utformar i Pustejovsky og Jezek (2011), definerer vi ein verbklasse i forhold til sine dynamiske argumentstrukturen (DAS), eit representasjon som koderer korleis deltakarane som er med deltakarane i endringane oppfører som hendinga oppfører. Vi adresserer korleis den logiske ressursane og resultatene av endringslinjene blir innført sintaktisk, dersom i det hele tatt, og korleis ekspluatasjonen av ressursen resulterer i oppstart eller avslutting av eit ny objekt, dvs. resultatet. Vi viser korleis DAS kan vera tilknytt til ein dynamisk koda hendingsstruktursrepresentasjon, som målar endringane som gjer referanse til ein skalærkomponent, modelert ved tillegg og/eller testing av verdiar av attributt av deltakarar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>W artykule przedstawiono nową klasyfikację czasowników zmiany i modyfikacji, proponując dynamiczną interpretację semantyki leksykalnej predykatu i jego argumentów. Przyjmując model dynamicznej struktury zdarzeń proponowany w Pustejovskim (2013) oraz rozszerzając model selekcji dynamicznej opisany w Pustejovskim i Jezku (2011), definiujemy klasę czasownika pod kątem jej Dynamicznej Struktury Argumentów (DAS), reprezentacji kodującej, jak uczestnicy zaangażowani w zmianę zachowują się wraz z rozwojem zdarzenia. Zajmujemy się tym, w jaki sposób zasoby logiczne i wyniki predykatów zmiany są realizowane składnie, jeśli w ogóle, a także w jaki sposób eksploatacja zasobu skutkuje inicjacją lub zakończeniem nowego obiektu, czyli wyniku. Pokazujemy, jak DAS można powiązać z dynamicznie zakodowaną reprezentacją struktury zdarzeń, która mierzy zmianę poprzez odniesienie do składnika skalarnego, modelowanego pod względem przypisania i/lub testowania wartości atrybutów uczestników.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас өөрчлөлт болон өөрчлөлтийн хэлний шинэ хэлбэрүүдийг харуулж байна. Энэ цаас давхар болон түүний аргументуудын лексикийн хэлбэрүүдийг хөдөлгөөнтэй тодорхойлж байна. Pustejovsky (2013 онд) дэлгэрүүлсэн динамик үйл явдлын бүтэц загварын загварыг хүлээн зөвшөөрвөл, Пустежковски болон Жезек (2011 онд) тайлбарласан динамик аргументын бүтэц загварын загварын загварыг нэмэгдүүлэхэд бид өөрчлөлт дээр оролцогчдын хэрхэн үйл явдлыг ашиглаж буй үйл явдлын тухай хэл Бид өөрчлөлтийн логикийн нөөц болон үр дүнг хэрхэн шинэ объект эхлэх эсвэл зогсохын тулд хэрхэн ойлгохыг хичээдэг вэ? Бид DAS-г хэрхэн динамик кодлогдсон үйл явдал бүтээгдэхүүнтэй холбогдож болох талаар харуулж байна. Энэ нь оролцогчдын харилцааны утгыг шалгах болон/эсвэл шалгах өөрчлөлтийг шалгана.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Lucrarea prezintă o nouă clasificare a verbelor de schimbare și modificare, propunând o interpretare dinamică a semanticii lexicale a predicatului și a argumentelor sale. Adoptând modelul de structură dinamică a evenimentelor propus în Pustejovsky (2013) și extinzând modelul de selecție dinamică prezentat în Pustejovsky și Jezek (2011), definim o clasă de verbe în termeni de Structura Argumentului Dinamic (DAS), o reprezentare care codifică modul în care participanții implicați în schimbare se comportă pe măsură ce evenimentul se desfășoară. Ne adresăm modului în care resursele logice și rezultatele predicilor de schimbare sunt realizate sintactic, dacă este deloc, precum și modul în care exploatarea resursei rezultă în inițierea sau încetarea unui obiect nou, adică rezultatul. Vă arătăm cum DAS poate fi asociat cu o reprezentare a structurii evenimentelor codificate dinamic, care măsoară schimbarea făcând referire la o componentă scalară, modelată în termeni de atribuire și/sau testare a valorilor atributelor participanților.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir predstavlja novu klasifikaciju verba promjene i modifikacije, predlažeći dinamičnu interpretaciju leksičkih semantika predikata i njegovih argumenata. Prihvaćajući model dinamične strukture događaja predložene u Pustejovsku (2013), i proširenjem model a dinamičnog selekcija navedenog u Pustejovsku i Jezeku (2011), definišemo klasu verba u smislu njegove dinamične strukture Argumenta (DAS), predstavljanja koja kodira kako se učesnici uključuju u promenu ponašaju kao što se događaj otvara. Rešavamo kako se logički resursi i rezultati predikata promjene sintaktično shvaćaju, ako uopšte, kao i kako ekspluatacija resursa rezultira inicijacije ili prekida novog objekta, to je rezultat. Pokazujemo kako se DAS može povezati sa dinamički kodiranim predstavljanjem strukture događaja, koja mjeri promjenu koja vodi referenciju na skalarnu komponentu, modeliranu u smislu zadataka i/ili testiranja vrijednosti atributa učesnika.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ පත්තුව පෙනුවෙන් අලුත් වෙනස් සහ වෙනස් වාර්තාවක් වර්ගයක් පෙනුම් කරනවා, ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක සහ ඒකේ වාර්තාවක් ලෙක Adopting the Model of Dinamic Octave Struktō සැලසුම් පුස්ටිජෝව්ස්කී (2013), and zoom in the Model of Dinamic selection outline in Pustejovky and Jezezek (2011), we definition a verb classification in terms of its Dinamic argment Struktō අපි කොහොමද වෙනස් කරන්නේ ප්‍රතිචාර ප්‍රතිචාරයක් වෙනස් විදියට තේරුම් ගන්නේ කියලා, කොහොමද කියලා, අලුත් ප්‍රතිචාර ප්‍රතිචාර විදියට,  අපි පෙන්වන්නේ DAS කොහොමද සංවේදනය කිරීමේ සංවේදනය සංවේදනය සමඟ සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න පුළුවන් කියලා, ඒකෙන් සංවේදනය කරපු වෙනස් සම්බන්</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Kanu wuxuu soo bandhigaa fasax cusub oo ah hadallada beddelka iyo is-beddelka, wuxuuna soo bandhigayaa fasirka dabiicadda ah oo ku saabsan qoraalka leksikada iyo argumentiyada. Tilmaanka dhaqdhaqaaqa dhacdooyinka ee loo soo jeeday Pustejovsky (2013), iyo sii fidinayaa modelka doorashada dynamic ee ku qoran Pustejovsky iyo Jezek (2011), waxaynu qoraynaa fasalka verb sida ay u muuqato dhaqdhaqaaqa Dynamic Argument Structure (DAS), taas oo ku qoran qayb ka mid ah kuwa ka qeybqaadan tababarka kala duwan sida dhacdooyinku soo dhacdo. Waxaannu ka sheekaynaa siduu ugu baahan yahay rasmiga deegaanka iyo resultinta beddelka, haddii ugu yaraan, sidoo kale sidoo kale isticmaalka midhaha ayaa ku sababan kara bilowga ama dhamaanshaha wax cusub, tusaale ahaan dhamaadka. Waxaynu tusnaynaa sida DAS loola xiriiri karo nooca dhacdooyinka ee loo qoray, taas oo qiyaasa beddelka looga jeedo qaybaha scalabka ah, oo lagu sameynayo tusaale ahaan qasnadda iyo/ama imtixaanka qiimaha qeybaha dadka ka qeybqaada.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats presenterar en ny klassificering av verb för förändring och modifiering och föreslår en dynamisk tolkning av predikatets lexikala semantik och dess argument. Genom att anta modellen för dynamisk händelsestruktur som föreslås i Pustejovskij (2013) och utvidga modellen för dynamisk selektion som beskrivs i Pustejovskij och Jezek (2011), definierar vi en verbklass i termer av dess Dynamic Argument Structure (DAS), en representation som kodar hur deltagarna som deltar i förändringen beter sig under händelsens gång. Vi behandlar hur logiska resurser och resultat av förändringsprodikater realiseras syntaktiskt, om överhuvudtaget, samt hur utnyttjandet av resursen resulterar i initiering eller avslutande av ett nytt objekt, dvs resultatet. Vi visar hur DAS kan associeras med en dynamiskt kodad händelsestruktur representation, som mäter förändringen med hänvisning till en skalar komponent, modellerad i termer av tilldelning och/eller testning av värden av attribut för deltagare.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த தாள் மாற்றம் மற்றும் மாற்றுதல் மற்றும் மாற்றுதல் சொற்களின் புதிய வகுப்பை கூட்டுகிறது, முன்னிருப்பு மற்றும் அளபுருக் புஸ்டீஜோவ்ஸ்கி( 2013) யில் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படும் இயங்கும் நிகழ்வு அமைப்பு மாதிரியை தேர்ந்தெடுத்து, புஸ்டிஜோவ்கி மற்றும் ஜெச்கில் வரையப்பட்ட தேர்வு மாதிரியின் மாதிரி மாதிரியை நாம் விவரிக்கிறோ We address how the logical resources and results of change predicates are realized syntactically, if at all, as well as how the exploitation of the resource results in the initiation or termination of a new object, i.e. the result.  நாம் எவ்வாறு DAS குறிப்பிட்ட நிகழ்வு அமைப்பு குறிப்பிடுதலுடன் இணைக்கப்பட முடியும் என்பதை காட்டுகிறோம். அது குறிப்பிடுபவர்களின் குணங்களின் மதிப்புகள</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>یہ کاغذ تغییر اور تغییر کے ویروں کی نئی کلاسیفوں کو پیش کرتا ہے، جو پیشڈیکل اور اس کے اردوментوں کی لکسیکل سیمانٹیکوں کی تفسیر کرتی ہیں۔ Pustejovsky (2013) میں پیشنهادہ کیا گیا ہوا دینامیک ایمبنی ساختار کی مدل قبول کرتا ہے، اور Pustejovsky اور Jezek (2011) میں پیشنهادہ کیا گیا ہوا دینامیک ایمبنی ساختار (DAS) کی مدل پھیلاتا ہے، اور ہم اس کے دینامیک آرگنم ساختار (DAS) کی مدل پھیلاتے ہیں، ایک نمونہ جو تغییر میں شامل ہونے والوں کو کس طرح عمل کرتا ہے جبکہ وہ کھ ہم کس طرح تغییرات کے منطقی منطقی منطقی منطقی اور نتیجے کو سینٹاکٹی طور پر متوجہ ہوتے ہیں، یعنی نتیجہ، یعنی نتیجہ. ہم دکھاتے ہیں کہ DAS کس طرح ایک داینامی کوڈی ہوئی حادثہ کی ساختار نمونش کے ساتھ رابطہ کیا جاتا ہے، جس نے تغییر کی مطابق اسکالار رقم کے ذریعہ مقرر کیا ہے، جو مشرکین کے اثرات کے ذریعہ مطابق مقرر کیا گیا ہے اور/یا امتحان</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu hujjat o'zgarishlar va o'zgarishlarning yangi darajasini koʻrsatiladi. Koʻrsatiladigan leksikal semantika va argumentlarining dynamik tarjima qilishini anglatadi. Name We address how the logical resources and results of change predicates are realized syntactically, if at all, as well as how the exploitation of the resource results in the initiation or termination of a new object, i.e. the result.  @ info: whatsthis</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này phân loại các động từ thay đổi và sửa đổi mới, đề xuất một cách diễn giải động động từ ngữ pháp của Đức giáo ngữ và các lý luận của nó. Nhận dạng mô hình cấu trúc sự kiện động động động cơ được đề xuất ở Pumalề (thậm chí chỉ trong một diễn biến có giá giật gân) và mở rộng mô hình tuyển chọn động động cơ được vạch ra ở Pumaphiếm và Jezek (11), chúng tôi xác định một hạng động từ theo dạng cấu trúc Argument (DAS), một đại diện giúp mã hóa cách mà những người tham gia thay đổi diễn ra khi sự kiện diễn ra. Chúng tôi giải thích cách mà các nguồn tài nguyên logic và kết quả của các giai đoạn biến đổi được thực hiện theo cấu trúc, nếu tất cả, cùng cách khai thác nguồn tài nguyên dẫn đến khởi đầu hoặc kết thúc của một vật thể mới, tức là kết quả. Chúng tôi cho thấy làm thế nào mà DAS có thể được liên kết với một đại diện cấu trúc sự kiện được mã hóa động động động động động động, dùng để đo định dạng mô tả các tính chất kích thích của các thành viên.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия представя нова класификация на глаголите за промяна и модификация, като предлага динамична интерпретация на лексикалната семантика на предиката и неговите аргументи. Приемайки модела на динамична структура на събитията, предложен в Пустеевски (2013), и разширявайки модела на динамична селекция, очертан в Пустеевски и Йезек (2011), ние дефинираме клас глаголи по отношение на неговата динамична аргументална структура (ДАС), представяне, което кодира как участниците, участващи в промяната, се държат с развитието на събитието. Разглеждаме как логическите ресурси и резултатите от промяната се реализират синтактично, ако изобщо, както и как експлоатацията на ресурса води до иницииране или прекратяване на нов обект, т.е. резултата. Показваме как ДАС може да бъде свързан с динамично кодирано представяне на структурата на събития, което измерва промяната, като се позовава на скаларен компонент, моделиран по отношение на задаване и/или тестване на стойности на атрибутите на участниците.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel presenteert een nieuwe classificatie van werkwoorden van verandering en wijziging, waarbij een dynamische interpretatie van de lexicale semantiek van het predicaat en zijn argumenten wordt voorgesteld. Door gebruik te maken van het model van dynamische gebeurtenisstructuur voorgesteld in Pustejovsky (2013), en het model van dynamische selectie uit te breiden zoals beschreven in Pustejovsky en Jezek (2011), definiëren we een werkwoordklasse in termen van zijn dynamische argumentstructuur (DAS), een weergave die codeert hoe de deelnemers die betrokken zijn bij de verandering zich gedragen als de gebeurtenis ontvouwt. We behandelen hoe de logische resources en resultaten van veranderpredicaten syntactisch worden gerealiseerd, of al dan niet, evenals hoe de exploitatie van de resource resulteert in het initiëren of beëindigen van een nieuw object, d.w.z. het resultaat. We laten zien hoe DAS gekoppeld kan worden aan een dynamisch gecodeerde gebeurtenisstructuur representatie, die de verandering meet door verwijzing naar een scalaire component, gemodelleerd in termen van toewijzing en/of testen van waarden van attributen van deelnemers.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir predstavlja novu klasifikaciju verba promjene i modifikacije, predlažeći dinamičnu interpretaciju leksičkih semantika predikata i njegovih argumenata. Prihvaćajući model dinamične strukture događaja predložene u Pustejovsku (2013), i proširenjem model a dinamičnog izbora navedenog u Pustejovsku i Jezeku (2011), definiramo klasu verba u smislu njegove dinamične strukture Argumenta (DAS), predstavljanja koja kodira kako se učesnici uključuju u promjenu ponašaju kao što se događaj otvara. Mi se obraćamo kako se logički resursi i rezultati predikata promjene sintaktično shvaćaju, ako uopće, kao i kako iskorištavanje resursa rezultira pokretanja ili prekida novog objekta, tj. rezultat. Pokazujemo kako se DAS može povezati s dinamički kodiranim predstavljanjem strukture događaja, što mjeri promjenu koja čini referenciju na skalarnu komponentu, modeliranu u smislu zadataka i/ili testiranja vrijednosti atributa učesnika.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel præsenterer en ny klassifikation af udsagnsord for forandring og modifikation, der foreslår en dynamisk fortolkning af prædikatets leksikalske semantik og dens argumenter. Ved at benytte modellen for dynamisk begivenhedsstruktur foreslået i Pustejovsky (2013) og udvide modellen for dynamisk udvælgelse skitseret i Pustejovsky og Jezek (2011), definerer vi en verbklasse i form af dens dynamiske argumentstruktur (DAS), en repræsentation, der koder, hvordan deltagerne i forandringen opfører sig, mens begivenheden udfolder sig. Vi behandler hvordan de logiske ressourcer og resultater af forandringsprædikater realiseres syntaktisk, om overhovedet, samt hvordan udnyttelsen af ressourcen resulterer i igangsættelse eller afslutning af et nyt objekt, dvs. resultatet. Vi viser, hvordan DAS kan knyttes til en dynamisk kodet hændelsesstrukturrepræsentation, som måler ændringen med henvisning til en skalar komponent, modelleret i form af tildeling og/eller test af værdier af attributter af deltagere.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>In diesem Beitrag wird eine neue Klassifizierung von Veränderungs- und Modifizierungsverben vorgestellt und eine dynamische Interpretation der lexikalischen Semantik des Prädikats und seiner Argumente vorgeschlagen. Wir übernehmen das in Pustejovsky (2013) vorgeschlagene Modell der dynamischen Ereignisstruktur und erweitern das in Pustejovsky und Jezek (2011) skizzierte Modell der dynamischen Selektion. Wir definieren eine Verbklasse in Bezug auf ihre dynamische Argumentstruktur (DAS), eine Repräsentation, die kodiert, wie sich die an der Änderung beteiligten Teilnehmer während des Ereignisses verhalten. Wir untersuchen, wie die logischen Ressourcen und Ergebnisse von Änderungsprädikaten syntaktisch realisiert werden, wenn überhaupt, sowie wie die Ausnutzung der Ressource zur Initiierung oder Beendigung eines neuen Objekts, also des Ergebnisses, führt. Wir zeigen, wie DAS mit einer dynamisch codierten Ereignisstrukturdarstellung verknüpft werden kann, die die Änderung unter Bezugnahme auf eine skalare Komponente misst, modelliert in Bezug auf Zuordnung und/oder Testen von Werten von Attributen von Teilnehmern.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini mempersembahkan klasifikasi baru dari verb perubahan dan modifikasi, mengusulkan interpretasi dinamik semantik lexik predikat dan argumennya. Mengadopsi model struktur peristiwa dinamik yang diusulkan di Pustejovsky (2013), dan memperluas model seleksi dinamik yang ditampilkan di Pustejovsky dan Jezek (2011), kami mendefinisikan kelas verb dalam terma Struktur Argumen Dinamik (DAS), sebuah perwakilan yang mengkode bagaimana peserta yang terlibat dalam perubahan bertindak saat peristiwa berkembang. Kami mengatasi bagaimana sumber daya logis dan hasil dari predikasi perubahan direalisasikan secara sintaks, jika sama sekali, serta bagaimana eksploitasi sumber daya menghasilkan inisiasi atau penghentian objek baru, i.e. hasilnya. Kami menunjukkan bagaimana DAS dapat diassokasikan dengan representation struktur peristiwa yang dinamik terkode, yang mengukur perubahan membuat referensi kepada komponen skalar, dipodelkan dalam terma pengaturan dan/atau tes nilai atribut dari peserta.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ یک گروهی جدید از کلمات تغییر و تغییر را نشان می دهد، پیشنهاد یک تعبیر دینامیک از شکل‌شناسی زبان‌شناسی پیش‌فرض و ارائه‌هایش را می‌دهد. با پذیرفتن مدل ساختار رویداد dinamikی پیشنهاد در پاستیوvsky (2013) و گسترش مدل انتخاب dinamikی که توصیف شده در پاستیوvsky و جیزک (2011) است، یک کلاس عبارت را به عنوان ساختار آرژومتهای دینامیک خود (DAS) تعریف می‌کنیم، یک نمایش که می‌دهد چگونه شرکت کنندگان در تغییر در حال بازگشت رویداد می‌شوند. ما درباره اینکه چگونه منابع منطقی و نتیجه تغییر پدیکات ها با تغییر متوجه می شوند، اگر اصلاً و چگونه استفاده از منابع به شروع یا پایان یک شیء جدید، یعنی نتیجه. ما نشان می‌دهیم که چگونه DAS می‌تواند با یک نمایش ساختار رویداد‌های دینامیک رمز شده ارتباط داشته باشد، که تغییرات را به عنوان یک نمایش مقدار مقدار می‌دهد، نموده شده به عنوان تعیین و/یا آزمایش ارتباط ویژه‌های مشترک.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 동사의 변화와 수식에 대해 새로운 분류를 하고 술어와 그 매개 변수의 어휘 의미의 동태적 해석을 제시했다.Pustejovsky(2013)에서 제시한 동적 이벤트 구조 모델을 활용하고 Pustejovsky와 Jezek(2011)에서 개술한 동적 선택 모델을 확장했다. 우리는 동적 변원 구조(DAS)에 따라 동사류를 정의했다. DAS는 변화에 참여하는 참여자가 이벤트를 전개할 때의 행위를 인코딩하는 형식이다.우리는 술어를 변경하는 논리적 자원과 결과가 어떻게 문법적으로 실현되는지, 그리고 자원의 이용이 어떻게 새로운 대상(즉 결과)의 시작이나 중지를 초래하는지 토론했다.우리는 DAS가 동적 인코딩의 이벤트 구조 표현과 어떻게 연결되는지 보여 주었다. 이 표현은 표량 구성 요소를 인용하여 변화를 측정하고 참여자의 속성에 따라 값을 부여하거나 테스트를 통해 모델링하는 것이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier stel 'n nuwe klasifikasie van verbe van verandering en verandering, voorstel 'n dinamiese interpretasie van die leksiese semantieke van die predikaat en sy argumente. As ons die model van dinamiese gebeurtenis struktuur aanvaar wat voorgestel is in Pustejovsky (2013), en die model van dinamiese keuse uitgevoer is in Pustejovsky en Jezek (2011), ons definieer 'n verb klas in terms of sy Dynamiese Argumente struktuur (DAS), ' n voorstelling wat kodeer hoe die deelnaders in die verandering gedrag word as die gebeurtenis oopmaak. Ons besluit hoe die logiese hulpbronne en result at e van veranderinge predikate sintakteel aanbevestig word, as in elke geval, en hoe die uitbreiding van die hulpbronne resultate in die aanvang of beëindiging van 'n nuwe objek, i.e. die result a at. Ons wys hoe DAS kan geassosieer word met 'n dinamies kodeerde gebeurtenis struktuur voorstelling, wat die verandering maak verwysing na' n skaal komponent, modeliseer in terms van toewysing en/of toets van waardes van eienskappe van deelnaders.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz üýtgewler we üýtgewler verbeleriniň täze bir klasifikasyny görkezýär, öňki-öňki we argumentleriniň tekiz semantikleriniň dinamik terjimesini teklip edip bilýär. Pustejovski (2013-nji ýylda görkezilen dinamik terjime strukturynyň nusgasyny we Pustejovski we Jezek (2011-nji ýylda geçirilen dinamik saýlawyň nusgasyny) we bu nusgasyny Dynamik Argument strukturynyň (DAS) yönünde bir verb klasyny tanyşdyrýarys. Bu nusgasy üýtgewleriň nähili bolup geçýän zady görkezilýän netijesi görkezilý Biz logik çe şmeleriň we netijesi önümleriniň sintaktik şeklinde çykyp biljek bolýarys, eger hem bolsa, Resursiň i şleriniň başlangyç ýa-da täze bir zadyň söndürmesine netijesi nähili netijesi çykýar. Biz DAS'i dinamik kodlanmış bir durum düzenlemesi ile nädip ilişkilendirilip görkezip, bu da sahypalaryň tanyşlaryň häsiýetlerini ölçüp, taýýarlamak we/veya testi edilen düzenlemesini ölçür.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument paraqet një klasifikim të ri të verbëve të ndryshimit dhe modifikimit, duke propozuar një interpretim dinamik të semantikës lexike të predikatës dhe argumenteve të saj. Duke miratuar model in e strukturës dinamike të ngjarjeve të propozuara në Pustejovsky (2013) dhe duke zgjeruar modelin e zgjedhjes dinamike të përshkruar në Pustejovsky dhe Jezek (2011), ne përcaktojmë një klasë verb ësh në termat e strukturës së saj dinamike të argumentit (DAS), një përfaqësim që kodon se si pjesëmarrësit e përfshirë në ndryshim sillen si ngjarja zhvillohet. Ne trajtojmë se si burimet logjike dhe rezultatet e ndryshimit predikojnë të realizohen sintaktikisht, nëse në të gjitha, si dhe se si shfrytëzimi i burimeve rezulton në nisjen apo përfundimin e një objekti të ri, pra rezultati. We show how DAS can be associated with a dynamically encoded event structure representation, which measures the change making reference to a scalar component, modelled in terms of assignment and/or testing of values of attributes of participants.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>This paper presents a new classification of verbs of change and modification, proposing a dynamic interpretation of the lexical semantics of the predicate and its arguments.  በPustejovsky (2013) ውስጥ በተዘጋጀው የዲያማዊ የጉዳዩ አካባቢ አካባቢ ምሳሌ ማዘጋጀት እና በፓስቶጆቪክ እና ጃዜክ (2011) የተዘጋጀውን የdynamic ምርጫ ሞዴል ማዘጋጀት እናደርጋለን፡፡ የግንኙነት ሀብት እና የለውጥ ፍጻሜ እንዴት እንደተገለጸ እናስታውቃለን፡፡ እናሳያቸዋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Այս աշխատանքը ներկայացնում է փոփոխության և փոփոխության բայերի նոր դասակարգում, առաջարկում է դինամիկ մեկնաբանություն նախադասության լեքսիկական սեմանտիկայի և դրա բանավեճերի մասին: Պուստեյովսկիում (2013) առաջարկված դինամիկ իրադարձությունների կառուցվածքի մոդելը ընդունելով և ընդլայնելով պուստեյովսկիում և Ջեզեքում (2011) նկարագրված դինամիկ ընտրության մոդելը, մենք սահմանում ենք բայերի դասը իր դինամիկ բանավեճի կառուցվածքի (DAS) տեսանկյունից, ներկայացում, որը կոդավորում է, թե ինչպես են փոփոխ Մենք քննարկում ենք, թե ինչպես են փոխության տրամաբանական ռեսուրսները և արդյունքները սինտակտիկ, եթե ընդհանրապես, իրականացվում, ինչպես են ռեսուրսների օգտագործման արդյունքում նոր օբյեկտի սկիզբը կամ վերջ դնելը, այսինքն արդյունքը: We show how DAS can be associated with a dynamically encoded event structure representation, which measures the change making reference to a scalar component, modelled in terms of assignment and/or testing of values of attributes of participants.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt dəyişiklik və dəyişiklik verblərinin yeni klasifikasyonu göstərir, predikat və onun argumentlərinin leksik semantikalarının dinamik yorumlarını təbliğ edir. Pustejovsky (2013-ci ildə) təklif edilmiş dinamik vaxt quruluşunun modelini qəbul etmək və Pustejovsky və Jezek (2011-ci ildə) təklif edilmiş dinamik seçimlərin modelini uzatmaq üçün dinamik Argument Structure (DAS) ilə bir verb sınıfını təyin edirik. Bu dəyişikliklərin necə davranışlarını a çıldığı üçün kodlayan bir göstərim. Biz dəyişiklik predikatların lojik kaynaqlarının və sonuçlarının sintaktik olaraq nəticə edildiyini çəkirik, həmçin in heç vaxt, həmçinin ressursunun istifadəsi yeni bir objektun başlamasına və ya bitməsinə nəticə edildiyini çəkirik. Biz DAS'nin dinamik kodlanmış olaraq işlənməsi ilə necə bağlanıldığını göstəririk ki, bu dəyişiklikləri skalar komponenti ilə dəyişiklik edir, iştirakçilərin qiymətlərinin və/və sınaması ilə modelləşdirildir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটি পরিবর্তন এবং পরিবর্তনের শব্দের নতুন ক্লাস্ফিকেশন উপস্থাপন করেছে, যার প্রস্তাব হচ্ছে লেক্সিক্সিক সেমেন্টিক এবং এর যুক্তি পুস্টেজভস্কি (২০১৩) এ প্রস্তাবিত ডাইনমিক ইভেন্ট কার্যক্রমের মডেল নির্বাচন করা এবং পুস্টেজভিস্কি এবং জেজেক (২০১১) লিখিত ডায়ামিক আর্গামেন্ট ক্লাসের মাধ্যমে আমরা একটি ভার্ব ক্লাস নির্ধারণ করি, যা প্রতিন আমরা কথা বলি কিভাবে পরিবর্তনের পূর্ববর্তী সম্পদ এবং ফলাফল সাথে সাথে বুঝতে পারি, যদিও, আর সম্পদের ব্যবহার কি ভাবে নতুন বস্তুর শুরু অথবা শেষ করার ফলাফল, যেমন ফলাফল। আমরা দেখাচ্ছি কিভাবে ডিএসএস একটি ডায়াম্বাভাবে এনকোড করা অনুষ্ঠানের প্রতিনিধিত্বের সাথে যোগাযোগ করতে পারে, যেটি একটি ক্যালার অংশগ্রহণকারীদের বৈশিষ্</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_sw>Gazeti hili linaonyesha tafsiri mpya ya maneno ya mabadiliko na mabadiliko, inayopendekeza tafsiri ya msimamo wa kisaikolojia wa utabiri na hoja zake. Kuboresha mfano wa muundo wa tukio lililopendekezwa huko Pustejovsky (2013), na kuongeza mfumo wa uchaguzi wa kidunia ulioandikwa kwenye Pustejovsky na Jezek (2011), tunaelezea darasa la utaratibu wa mazingira ya kimapenzi (DAS), uwakilishi ambao unajumuisha namna washiriki wanavyojihusisha katika mazingira ya mabadiliko yanavyotokea wakati wa tukio hilo. Tunaongelea jinsi rasilimali na matokeo ya mabadiliko yanavyoonyesha kwa pamoja, kama kwa ujumla, na jinsi matumizi ya rasilimali yanavyotokea kuanzishwa au kusitishwa kwa kitu kipya, yaani matokeo yake. Tunaonyesha jinsi DAS inavyoweza kuunganishwa na uwakilishi wa muundo wa tukio lililoandikwa na kimsingi, ambacho kinaweza kufanya mabadiliko yanayohusiana na kifaa chenye uzoefu, inayoonyesha kwa mukhtadha wa jukumu na/au kujaribu thamani za watashiriki.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir predstavlja novu klasifikaciju verba promjene i modifikacije, predlažeći dinamičnu interpretaciju leksičkih semantika predikata i njegovih argumenata. Prihvaćajući model dinamične strukture događaja predložene u Pustejovsku (2013), i produžavanju model a dinamičnog selekcija navedenog u Pustejovsku i Jezeku (2011), definiramo klasu verba u smislu njegove dinamične strukture Argumenta (DAS), predstavljanja koja kodira kako se učesnici uključuju u promjenu ponašaju kao što se događaj otvara. Mi se obraćamo kako se logički resursi i rezultati predikata promjene sintaktično shvaćaju, ako uopšte, kao i kako ekspluatacija resursa rezultira u pokretanju ili prekinuti novi objekt, to je rezultat. Pokazujemo kako se DAS može povezati sa dinamički kodiranim predstavljanjem strukture događaja, koja mjeri promjenu koja čini referenciju na skalarnu komponentu, modeliranu u smislu zadataka i/ili testiranja vrijednosti atributa učesnika.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest paper presenta una nova classificació de verbs de canvi i modificació, proposant una interpretació dinàmica de la semàntica lèxica del predicat i els seus arguments. Adoptant el model d'estructura dinàmica d'esdeveniments proposat a Pustejovsky (2013), i ampliant el model de selecció dinàmica esboçat a Pustejovsky i Jezek (2011), definim una classe de verbs en termes de la seva estructura dinàmica d'arguments (DAS), una representació que codifica com els participants involucrats en el canvi es comporten mentre l'esdeveniment. Ens ocupem de com els recursos lògics i els resultats del canvi es concretitzen sinàcticament, si en absolut, i de com l'explotació del recurso result a en l'iniciació o la terminació d'un nou object e, és a dir, el result at. Mostrem com el DAS pot estar associat a una representació dinàmicament codificada de l'estructura d'eventos, que mesura el canvi fent referència a un component escalar, modelat en termes d'asignació i/o prova de valors dels atributs dels participants.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek představuje novou klasifikaci slovesa změny a modifikace, navrhuje dynamickou interpretaci lexikální sémantiky predikátu a jeho argumentů. Přijetím modelu dynamické struktury událostí navrženého v Pustejovském (2013) a rozšířením modelu dynamického výběru nastíněného v Pustejovském a Ježkovi (2011) definujeme třídu slovesa z hlediska její dynamické argumentní struktury (DAS), reprezentace, která kóduje, jak se účastníci změny chovají v průběhu události. Řešíme, jak jsou logické zdroje a výsledky predikátů změny realizovány syntakticky, pokud vůbec, a jak využití zdroje vede k iniciaci nebo ukončení nového objektu, tj. výsledku. Ukážeme, jak lze DAS spojit s dynamicky kódovanou reprezentací struktury událostí, která měří změnu s odkazem na skalární komponentu, modelovanou z hlediska přiřazení a/nebo testování hodnot atributů účastníků.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolev töö esitab uue klassifikatsiooni muutmise ja modifitseerimise tegusõnade kohta, pakkudes välja predikaadi leksikaalsemantika ja selle argumentide dünaamilise tõlgenduse. Võttes kasutusele Pustejovsky (2013) esitatud dünaamilise sündmuste struktuuri mudeli ning laiendades Pustejovsky ja Jezek (2011) kirjeldatud dünaamilise valiku mudelit, määratleme tegusõnade klassi selle dünaamilise argumendi struktuuri (DAS) järgi, mis kodeerib, kuidas muutuses osalejad käituvad sündmuse kulgemisel. Käsitleme, kuidas loogilised ressursid ja muutuste eelkõige tulemused realiseeruvad süntaktiliselt, kui üldse, ning kuidas ressursi kasutamine toob kaasa uue objekti ehk tulemuse algatamise või lõpetamise. Näitame, kuidas DAS-i saab seostada dünaamiliselt kodeeritud sündmuste struktuuri esitusega, mis mõõdab muutust viidates skalaarkomponentile, modelleerituna osalejate atribuutide väärtuste määramise ja/või testimise seisukohalt.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä työssä esitellään uusi muutos- ja modifikaatioverbien luokitus, jossa ehdotetaan dynaamista tulkintaa predikaatin leksikaalisesta semantiikasta ja sen argumenteista. Pustejovsky (2013) -julkaisussa ehdotettua dynaamisen tapahtumarakenteen mallia ja Pustejovsky ja Jezek (2011) -julkaisussa hahmoteltua dynaamisen valinnan mallia laajennetaan määrittelemme verbiluokan Dynamic Argument Structure (DAS), joka koodaa muutoksen osallistujien käyttäytymisen tapahtuman edetessä. Tarkastelemme sitä, miten muutoksen loogiset resurssit ja tulokset toteutuvat syntaktisesti, jos lainkaan, sekä miten resurssin hyödyntäminen johtaa uuden objektin eli tuloksen käynnistämiseen tai lopettamiseen. Näytämme, miten DAS voidaan liittää dynaamisesti koodattuun tapahtumarakenteen esitykseen, joka mittaa muutosta viittaamalla skalaarikomponenttiin, mallinnettuna osallistujien attribuuttien arvojen osoittamiseksi ja/tai testaamiseksi.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Perintah sing nyimpen kelas anyar karo verb sing ngubah karo Ngubah, nggunakake sistem Dinakan tarjamahan kanggo kelas semanti karo perintah karo akeh argument. Ngawe dumadhi model sing sistem dadi nggawe akèh dumadhiné ning Pustejov (2013), lan uga nambah model sing dadi nggawe diuwisan dynamics sing bisa Ketoken in Pustejov lan Jejak (2011), kita diwisik kelas verb sing usul ning arep Dinaman argument structural (DES), kita nguasai representasi sing dadi kode piye cara nggawe ngubah akeh dumadhi cah dumadhi akèh dumadhi. Awak dhéwé éntuk sistem logik lan gambaran sistem pakan ing pakan-pakan bakal nguasai winih dhéwé, nek kabèh njaluké, lan kabèh njaluké pejalaké pangan iki bakal terus winih dhéwé bakal nguasai winih dhéwé. Awak dhéwé menehi, piye dadi nggawe barang karo sistem Dinamni koder tentang</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Wannan takardan na bãyar da wani fassarar-nau'i na canje-canza da gyare, yana ƙara wani fassarar sunaye na kasa fassarar wa kekkisiki na littafin da musammakinsa. Aka amfani da shirin ayuka na buƙata cikin Pustjovski (2013), kuma yana shimfiɗa motel na zaɓen hanyoyi wanda aka nuna wa Pustjovki da Jezek (2011), za'a bayyana wani daraja na verb a cikin sha'anin ¦arako na DDDNAMI Argument Tirko (DAS), wani mai wakilishi wanda ke kode yadda mãsu haɗuwa da aikin musanyawa take idan an nuna. We address how the logical resources and results of change predicates are realized syntactically, if at all, as well as how the exploitation of the resource results in the initiation or termination of a new object, i.e. the result.  Tuna nũna jinin DAS za'a yi haɗa da wani shirin ayuka wanda aka kode shi da hanyoyi, mai motsa musanyawa zuwa wani ƙunci wanda aka lissafa, da misalin ya yi amfani da kuma/ko jarraba kimar masu hushi.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>העבודה הזו מציגה מסווג חדש של אלברים של שינוי ושינוי, מציעה פרשנה דינמית של הסמנטיקה הלקסית של הקודיקט והטיעונים שלו. לאמץ את מודל מבנה האירועים הדינמיים המוצע בפוטייאובסקי (2013), ולהרחיב את מודל הבחירה הדינמית המתואר בפוטייאובסקי וג'זק (2011), אנחנו מגדירים כיתה של פרים במונחים של מבנה האירועים הדינמיים (DAS), מייצג שמקודם איך המשתתפים בשינוי מתנהגים כשהאירוע מתפתח. אנחנו מתייחסים לאיך משאבים הגיוניים ותוצאות שינויים מתייחסים באופן סינטאקטי, אם בכלל, כמו גם איך ניצול המשאבים מוביל בהתחלה או הסיום של אובייקט חדש, כלומר התוצאה. We show how DAS can be associated with a dynamically encoded event structure representation, which measures the change making reference to a scalar component, modelled in terms of assignment and/or testing of values of attributes of participants.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku je predstavljena nova klasifikacija glagolov spremembe in modifikacije, ki predlaga dinamično interpretacijo leksikalne semantike predikata in njegovih argumentov. S sprejetjem modela dinamične strukture dogodkov, predlaganega v Pustejovskem (2013), in razširitvijo modela dinamične selekcije iz Pustejovskega in Jezeka (2011), definiramo razred glagolov v smislu dinamične argumentne strukture (DAS), reprezentacije, ki kodira, kako se udeleženci, vključeni v spremembo, obnašajo ob razvoju dogodka. Obravnavamo, kako se logični viri in rezultati predikatov sprememb realizirajo sintaktično, če sploh, ter kako izkoriščanje vira povzroči iniciacijo ali končanje novega objekta, tj. rezultata. Prikazujemo, kako lahko DAS povežemo z dinamično kodirano predstavitvijo strukture dogodkov, ki meri spremembo s sklicevanjem na skalarno komponento, modelirano v smislu dodeljevanja in/ali testiranja vrednosti atributov udeležencev.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་བཟོ་བཅོས་དང་བཟོ་བཅོས་བྱ་ཚིག་གི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་གསར་བ་སྟོན་པའམ། སྔོན་སྒྲིག་དང་སྒྲུབ་རྟགས་ལ་འགྱུར་བའི་དབྱེ་རིམ Adopting the model of dynamic event structure proposed in Pustejovsky (2013), and extending the model of dynamic selection outlined in Pustejovsky and Jezek (2011), we define a verb class in terms of its Dynamic Argument Structure (DAS), a representation which encodes how the participants involved in the change behave as the event unfolds. ང་ཚོས་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་རྒྱུ་དངོས་ཐོག་འགྱུར་བ་དང་གི་རྐྱེན་འབྲེལ་དག་གི་སྔོན་ཚོའི་གྲས་ཤིག་དུ་ཅི་སྦྲེལ་བ་ཡོད་པ་དང་། གལ་སྲིད། རྒྱུ་དངོས་འབྲས་ཀྱི་རྒྱུ་རྐྱེན ང་ཚོས་DAS་ནི་ཇི་ལྟར་བྱུང་བའི་རྣམ་འགྱུར་བ་ཅིག་དང་མཐུན་འབྲེལ་བ་ཡིན་པ་མངོན་འཆར་ཡོད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>