<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2019.jeptalnrecital">
  <volume id="long" ingest-date="2020-08-14">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes de la Conférence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles (TALN) PFIA 2019. Volume I : Articles longs</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Emmanuel</first><last>Morin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sophie</first><last>Rosset</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pierre</first><last>Zweigenbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Toulouse, France</address>
      <month>7</month>
      <year>2019</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="c6bca06e">2019.jeptalnrecital-long.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2019-actes</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    </volume>
  <volume id="court" ingest-date="2020-08-14">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes de la Conférence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles (TALN) PFIA 2019. Volume II : Articles courts</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Emmanuel</first><last>Morin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sophie</first><last>Rosset</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pierre</first><last>Zweigenbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Toulouse, France</address>
      <month>7</month>
      <year>2019</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="885aa8a1">2019.jeptalnrecital-court.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2019-actes-de</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Multilingual and Multitarget Hate Speech Detection in Tweets</title>
      <author><first>Patricia</first><last>Chiril</last></author>
      <author><first>Farah</first><last>Benamara Zitoune</last></author>
      <author><first>Véronique</first><last>Moriceau</last></author>
      <author><first>Marlène</first><last>Coulomb-Gully</last></author>
      <author><first>Abhishek</first><last>Kumar</last></author>
      <pages>351–360</pages>
      <abstract>Social media networks have become a space where users are free to relate their opinions and sentiments which may lead to a large spreading of hatred or abusive messages which have to be moderated. This paper proposes a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervised_learning">supervised approach</a> to hate speech detection from a multilingual perspective. We focus in particular on hateful messages towards two different targets (immigrants and women) in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English tweets</a>, as well as sexist messages in both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>. Several <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> have been developed ranging from feature-engineering approaches to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network">neural ones</a>. Our experiments show very encouraging results on both languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="88f663d9">2019.jeptalnrecital-court.21</url>
      <bibkey>chiril-etal-2019-multilingual</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
  <volume id="recital" ingest-date="2020-08-14">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes de la Conférence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles (TALN) PFIA 2019. Volume III : RECITAL</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Emmanuel</first><last>Morin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sophie</first><last>Rosset</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pierre</first><last>Zweigenbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Toulouse, France</address>
      <month>7</month>
      <year>2019</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="edcd1f53">2019.jeptalnrecital-recital.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2019-actes-de-la</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Automatic summarization of medical conversations, a review</title>
      <author><first>Jessica</first><last>López Espejel</last></author>
      <pages>487–498</pages>
      <abstract>ion et pour l’analyse du dialogue. Nous dcrivons aussi les utilisation du Traitement Automatique des Langues dans le domaine mdical. A BSTRACT Conversational analysis plays an important role in the development of simulation devices for the training of health professionals (doctors, nurses). Our goal is to develop an original automatic synthesis method for medical conversations between a patient and a healthcare professional, based on recent advances in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_summarization">summarization</a> using convolutional and recurrent neural networks. The proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> must be adapted to the specific problems related to the synthesis of dialogues. This article presents a review of the different methods for extractive and abstractive summarization, and for dialogue analysis. We also describe the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a> in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medicine">medical field</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="f4c77d4a">2019.jeptalnrecital-recital.3</url>
      <bibkey>lopez-espejel-2019-automatic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
  <volume id="demo" ingest-date="2020-08-14">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes de la Conférence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles (TALN) PFIA 2019. Volume IV : Démonstrations</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Emmanuel</first><last>Morin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sophie</first><last>Rosset</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pierre</first><last>Zweigenbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Toulouse, France</address>
      <month>7</month>
      <year>2019</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="e2581c44">2019.jeptalnrecital-demo.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2019-actes-de-la-sur</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    </volume>
  <volume id="deft" ingest-date="2020-08-14">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes de la Conférence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles (TALN) PFIA 2019. Défi Fouille de Textes (atelier TALN-RECITAL)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Emmanuel</first><last>Morin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sophie</first><last>Rosset</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pierre</first><last>Zweigenbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Toulouse, France</address>
      <month>7</month>
      <year>2019</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="3ad255cf">2019.jeptalnrecital-deft.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2019-actes-de-la-sur-le</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    </volume>
  <volume id="tia" ingest-date="2020-08-14">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes de la Conférence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles (TALN) PFIA 2019. Terminologie et Intelligence Artificielle (atelier TALN-RECITAL \&amp; IC)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Emmanuel</first><last>Morin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sophie</first><last>Rosset</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pierre</first><last>Zweigenbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Toulouse, France</address>
      <month>7</month>
      <year>2019</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ad21d1bc">2019.jeptalnrecital-tia.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2019-actes-de-la-sur-le-traitement</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Terminology systematization for Cybersecurity domain in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_language">Italian Language</a><fixed-case>I</fixed-case>talian Language</title>
      <author><first>Claudia</first><last>Lanza</last></author>
      <author><first>Béatrice</first><last>Daille</last></author>
      <pages>7–18</pages>
      <abstract>This paper aims at presenting the first steps to improve the quality of the first draft of an Italian thesaurus for Cybersecurity terminology that has been realized for a specific project activity in collaboration with CybersecurityLab at Informatics and Telematics Institute (IIT) of the National Council of Research (CNR) in Italy. In particular, the paper will focus, first, on the terminological knowledge base built to retrieve the most representative candidate terms of Cybersecurity domain in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_language">Italian language</a>, giving examples of the main gold standard repositories that have been used to build this semantic tool. Attention will be then given to the methodology and software employed to configure a system of NLP rules to get the desired semantic results and to proceed with the enhancement of the candidate terms selection which are meant to be inserted in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Controlled_vocabulary">controlled vocabulary</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="de1e5938">2019.jeptalnrecital-tia.1</url>
      <bibkey>lanza-daille-2019-terminology</bibkey>
    <title_ar>منهجية المصطلحات لمجال الأمن السيبراني في اللغة الإيطالية</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Sistematização de terminologia para domínio de cibersegurança em língua italiana</title_pt>
      <title_es>Sistematización terminológica para el dominio de ciberseguridad en italiano</title_es>
      <title_fr>Systématisation terminologique pour le domaine de la cybersécurité en italien</title_fr>
      <title_ja>イタリア語のサイバーセキュリティドメインの用語体系化</title_ja>
      <title_zh>意大利语网络安全域之术语系统化</title_zh>
      <title_ru>Систематизация терминологии в области кибербезопасности на итальянском языке</title_ru>
      <title_hi>इतालवी भाषा में साइबर सुरक्षा डोमेन के लिए शब्दावली systematization</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Córasú téarmaíochta d'fhearann Cybersecurity i dTeanga na hIodáile</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ტერმინოლოგიის სისტემატიზაცია კიბერსუკური დიომინის იტალიური ენაში</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Terminológia rendszerezés a kiberbiztonsági területre olasz nyelven</title_hu>
      <title_el>Συστηματοποίηση ορολογίας για τον τομέα της ασφάλειας στον κυβερνοχώρο στην ιταλική γλώσσα</title_el>
      <title_it>Sistemazione terminologica per il dominio Cybersecurity in lingua italiana</title_it>
      <title_lt>Kibernetinio saugumo domeno terminologinė sistematizacija italų kalba</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Терминолошка систематизација за домен на киберосигурност на италијански јазик</title_mk>
      <title_kk>Италия тілінде кибер қауіпсіздік доменінің терминология жүйесі</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Sistemasi terminologi bagi domain Keselamatan Cyber dalam bahasa Itali</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ഇറ്റാലിയന്‍ ഭാഷയിലെ സൈബെര്‍ സുരക്ഷിത ഡൊമെനിനുള്ള ടെര്‍മിനോളജി സിസ്റ്റമേഷന്‍</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Sistematizzazzjoni tat-terminoloġija għad-dominju taċ-Ċibersigurtà fil-lingwa Taljana</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Италийн хэл дээр Цибер аюулгүй байдлын тухай терминологийн систематик</title_mn>
      <title_no>Terminologisk systematisering for sybersecurity domain in Italian Language</title_no>
      <title_pl>Systematyzacja terminologii dla domeny cyberbezpieczeństwa w języku włoskim</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Sistemarea terminologiei pentru domeniul securității cibernetice în limba italiană</title_ro>
      <title_si>ඉතාලියාන් භාෂාවයේ සායිබර්සුකුරීත් ඩොමින් සඳහා තාර්මිනෝලෝජික පද්ධතිය</title_si>
      <title_so>Isticmaalka Terminology ee domain ammaanka Internetka ku qoran luqada Talyaaniga</title_so>
      <title_sr>Sistematizacija terminologije za sajber sigurnosnu domenu na italijanskom jeziku</title_sr>
      <title_sv>Terminologi systematisering för cybersäkerhet domän på italienska språket</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>ایتالیایی زبان میں سئبرسی ڈومین کے لئے ترمیمینولوژی سیستماتیزی</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Hệ thống mẹ học cho lĩnh vực an ninh mạng ở nước Ý</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Терминологична систематизация за областта на киберсигурността на италианския език</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Sistematizacija terminologije za domenu sigurnosti na italijanskom jeziku</title_hr>
      <title_da>Terminologi systematisering for cybersikkerhed domæne på italiensk sprog</title_da>
      <title_nl>Systematisering van terminologie voor cybersecurity domein in het Italiaans Taal</title_nl>
      <title_id>Sistematisasi terminologi untuk domain Keamanan Cyber dalam bahasa Italia</title_id>
      <title_sw>Ufumo wa Terminalology kwa ajili ya maeneo ya usalama wa Mtandao kwa lugha ya Kiitalia</title_sw>
      <title_de>Systematisierung der Terminologie für den Bereich Cybersicherheit in italienischer Sprache</title_de>
      <title_ko>이탈리아어 네트워크 보안 분야 용어 체계화</title_ko>
      <title_tr>Kibersekuriýet domeniniň itäliýa dilinde terminologiýa sistemasyzlyk</title_tr>
      <title_af>Terminologie sistematiseering vir Sibersekuriteit domein in Italiese taal</title_af>
      <title_fa>سیستم‌سازی ترمینولوژی برای دومین سایر امنیت در زبان ایتالیایی</title_fa>
      <title_sq>Terminology systematization for Cybersecurity domain in Italian Language</title_sq>
      <title_bn>Terminology systematization for Cybersecurity domain in Italian Language</title_bn>
      <title_am>ኢጣሊያንኛ ቋንቋ</title_am>
      <title_hy>Իտալացի լեզու կիբեր ապահովության ոլորտի տերմինոլոգիայի համակարգման</title_hy>
      <title_az>İtalyan dilində İncil Qüdrəti Domeninin Terminoloji sistematizasyonu</title_az>
      <title_bs>Sistematizacija terminologije za sajber sigurnosnu domenu na italijanskom jeziku</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Sistematització de terminologia del domini de cibersiguretat en idioma italià</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Systematizace terminologie pro doménu kybernetické bezpečnosti v italském jazyce</title_cs>
      <title_et>Terminoloogia süstematiseerimine küberjulgeoleku valdkonnas itaalia keeles</title_et>
      <title_fi>Terminologian systematisointi kyberturvallisuuden alalla italian kielellä</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Terminal in italian Language</title_jv>
      <title_he>שיטת טרמינולוגיה לתחום ביטחון Cyber בשפה איטלקית</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Terminologija sistematizacije za področje kibernetske varnosti v italijanskem jeziku</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Terminology systematization for Cybersecurity domain in Italian Language</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تهدف هذه الورقة إلى تقديم الخطوات الأولى لتحسين جودة المسودة الأولى من قاموس المرادفات الإيطالي لمصطلحات الأمن السيبراني التي تم تحقيقها لنشاط مشروع معين بالتعاون مع CybersecurityLab في معهد المعلوماتية والتليماتية (IIT) التابع للمجلس الوطني للبحوث (CNR) في إيطاليا. على وجه الخصوص ، ستركز الورقة ، أولاً ، على قاعدة المعارف الاصطلاحية التي تم إنشاؤها لاسترداد المصطلحات الأكثر تمثيلا لمجال الأمن السيبراني باللغة الإيطالية ، مع إعطاء أمثلة على مستودعات المعيار الذهبي الرئيسية التي تم استخدامها لبناء هذه الأداة الدلالية. سيتم بعد ذلك الانتباه إلى المنهجية والبرامج المستخدمة لتكوين نظام لقواعد البرمجة اللغوية العصبية للحصول على النتائج الدلالية المرغوبة والمضي قدمًا في تحسين اختيار مصطلحات المرشح التي من المفترض إدراجها في المفردات الخاضعة للرقابة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_fr>Cet article vise à présenter les premières étapes pour améliorer la qualité de la première ébauche d'un thésaurus italien pour la terminologie de la cybersécurité qui a été réalisé pour une activité de projet spécifique en collaboration avec CyberSecurityLab de l'Institut informatique et télématique (IIT) du Conseil national de l' Recherche (CNR) en Italie. En particulier, l'article se concentrera tout d'abord sur la base de connaissances terminologiques conçue pour récupérer les termes candidats les plus représentatifs du domaine de la cybersécurité en italien, en donnant des exemples des principaux référentiels de référence qui ont été utilisés pour construire cet outil sémantique. Une attention particulière sera ensuite accordée à la méthodologie et au logiciel utilisés pour configurer un système de règles de PNL afin d'obtenir les résultats sémantiques souhaités et de procéder à l'amélioration de la sélection des termes candidats destinés à être insérés dans le vocabulaire contrôlé.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo visa apresentar os primeiros passos para melhorar a qualidade do primeiro rascunho de um tesauro italiano para a terminologia de segurança cibernética que foi realizado para uma atividade de projeto específica em colaboração com o CybersecurityLab no Instituto de Informática e Telemática (IIT) do Conselho Nacional de Pesquisa (CNR) na Itália. Em particular, o artigo se concentrará, primeiro, na base de conhecimento terminológica construída para recuperar os termos candidatos mais representativos do domínio de segurança cibernética em língua italiana, dando exemplos dos principais repositórios padrão-ouro que foram usados para construir essa ferramenta semântica. Em seguida, será dada atenção à metodologia e software empregados para configurar um sistema de regras de PNL para obter os resultados semânticos desejados e prosseguir com o aprimoramento da seleção de termos candidatos a serem inseridos no vocabulário controlado.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo tiene como objetivo presentar los primeros pasos para mejorar la calidad del primer borrador de un tesauro italiano de terminología de ciberseguridad que se ha realizado para una actividad de proyecto específica en colaboración con CyberSecurityLab en el Instituto de Informática y Telemática (IIT) del Consejo Nacional de Investigación (CNR) en Italia. En particular, el documento se centrará, en primer lugar, en la base de conocimientos terminológicos creada para recuperar los términos candidatos más representativos del dominio de ciberseguridad en italiano, dando ejemplos de los principales repositorios estándar de oro que se han utilizado para construir esta herramienta semántica. A continuación, se prestará atención a la metodología y al software empleados para configurar un sistema de reglas de PNL para obtener los resultados semánticos deseados y continuar con la mejora de la selección de términos candidatos que deben insertarse en el vocabulario controlado.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、イタリア国立研究評議会（ CNR ）の情報学・テレマティクス研究所（ IIT ）のCybersecurityLabと協力して、特定のプロジェクト活動のために実現されたサイバーセキュリティ用語のイタリア語シソーラスの初稿の品質を向上させるための最初のステップを提示することを目的とする。特に、この論文は、まず、イタリア語でサイバーセキュリティドメインの最も代表的な候補用語を取得するために構築された用語知識ベースに焦点を当て、このセマンティックツールの構築に使用された主なゴールド標準リポジトリの例を挙げます。次いで、所望の意味的結果を取得し、制御された語彙に挿入されることを意図する候補用語選択の強化を進めるために、NLPルールのシステムを構成するために使用される方法論およびソフトウェアに注目する。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>本文旨在介意大利网络安全术语库初稿质量之首,该术语库已与意大利国研究委员会(CNR)信息学远程信息处理研究所(IIT)之网络安全实验室合作,为特定目动成其草案。 特以首重为检索意大利语中最具代表性者网络安全领域候选术语而构建之术语知识库,并举例说明以建此语义器之大黄金准存储库。 然后留意于NLP法系统之法软件,以得其语义,续增其术语,术语旨入受控词汇表。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>इस पेपर का उद्देश्य साइबर सुरक्षा शब्दावली के लिए एक इतालवी थिसॉरस के पहले मसौदे की गुणवत्ता में सुधार करने के लिए पहले चरणों को प्रस्तुत करना है जिसे इटली में राष्ट्रीय अनुसंधान परिषद (सीएनआर) के सूचना विज्ञान और टेलीमैटिक्स इंस्टीट्यूट (आईआईटी) में साइबर सिक्योरिटीलैब के सहयोग से एक विशिष्ट परियोजना गतिविधि के लिए महसूस किया गया है। विशेष रूप से, पेपर सबसे पहले, इतालवी भाषा में साइबर सुरक्षा डोमेन के सबसे प्रतिनिधि उम्मीदवार शर्तों को पुनः प्राप्त करने के लिए बनाए गए टर्मिनोलॉजिकल नॉलेज बेस पर ध्यान केंद्रित करेगा, जो इस शब्दार्थ उपकरण के निर्माण के लिए उपयोग किए जाने वाले मुख्य सोने के मानक भंडारों के उदाहरण देगा। फिर वांछित शब्दार्थ परिणाम प्राप्त करने के लिए एनएलपी नियमों की एक प्रणाली को कॉन्फ़िगर करने के लिए नियोजित पद्धति और सॉफ़्टवेयर पर ध्यान दिया जाएगा और उम्मीदवार शर्तों के चयन की वृद्धि के साथ आगे बढ़ने के लिए जो नियंत्रित शब्दावली में डालने के लिए हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Целью настоящего документа является представление первых шагов по улучшению качества первого проекта итальянского тезауруса по терминологии кибербезопасности, который был реализован для конкретной проектной деятельности в сотрудничестве с CybersecurityLab в Институте информатики и телематики (IIT) Национального совета по исследованиям (CNR) в Италии. В частности, в документе основное внимание будет уделено, во-первых, терминологической базе знаний, созданной для получения наиболее репрезентативных терминов-кандидатов в области кибербезопасности на итальянском языке, с примерами основных хранилищ золотого стандарта, которые использовались для создания этого семантического инструмента. Затем внимание будет уделено методологии и программному обеспечению, используемому для настройки системы правил NLP, чтобы получить желаемые семантические результаты и приступить к улучшению выбора терминов-кандидатов, которые предназначены для вставки в контролируемый словарь.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Tá sé mar aidhm ag an bpáipéar seo na chéad chéimeanna a chur i láthair chun feabhas a chur ar cháilíocht an chéad dréachta de theasáras Iodálach do théarmaíocht Cybersecurity atá réadaithe le haghaidh gníomhaíochta tionscadail ar leith i gcomhar le CybersecurityLab ag Institiúid na Faisnéisíochta agus Teileamaitice (IIT) den Chomhairle Náisiúnta um Thaighde (CNR) san Iodáil. Díreoidh an páipéar go háirithe, ar dtús, ar an mbonn eolais téarmaíochta a tógadh chun na téarmaí iarrthóra is ionadaí d’fhearann Cybersecurity i dteanga na hIodáile a fháil ar ais, ag tabhairt samplaí de na príomhstórtha caighdeánacha óir a úsáideadh chun an uirlis shéimeantach seo a thógáil. Tabharfar aird ansin ar an modheolaíocht agus ar na bogearraí a úsáidtear chun córas rialacha NLP a chumrú chun na torthaí shéimeantacha inmhianaithe a fháil agus chun dul ar aghaidh le feabhsú an roghnúcháin téarmaí iarrthóra atá le cur isteach sa stór focal rialaithe.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία έχει ως στόχο να παρουσιάσει τα πρώτα βήματα για τη βελτίωση της ποιότητας του πρώτου σχεδίου ιταλικού θησαυρού ορολογίας στον κυβερνοχώρο που έχει υλοποιηθεί για μια συγκεκριμένη δραστηριότητα έργου σε συνεργασία με το Ινστιτούτο Πληροφορικής και Τηλεματικής (ΙΤ) του Εθνικού Συμβουλίου Έρευνας (CNR) στην Ιταλία. Ειδικότερα, η εργασία θα επικεντρωθεί, πρώτον, στην ορολογική βάση γνώσεων που χτίστηκε για να ανακτήσει τους πιο αντιπροσωπευτικούς υποψήφιους όρους του τομέα της κυβερνοασφάλειας στην ιταλική γλώσσα, δίνοντας παραδείγματα των βασικών αποθετηρίων χρυσού προτύπων που έχουν χρησιμοποιηθεί για την κατασκευή αυτού του σημασιολογικού εργαλείου. Στη συνέχεια, θα δοθεί προσοχή στη μεθοδολογία και το λογισμικό που χρησιμοποιείται για τη διαμόρφωση ενός συστήματος κανόνων ώστε να επιτευχθεί το επιθυμητό σημασιολογικό αποτέλεσμα και να προχωρήσει στην ενίσχυση της επιλογής υποψηφίων όρων που προορίζονται να εισαχθούν στο ελεγχόμενο λεξιλόγιο.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A tanulmány célja, hogy bemutassa az első lépéseket a kiberbiztonsági terminológia első olasz sztezauruszának minőségének javítására, amelyet egy konkrét projekttevékenység keretében valósítottak meg az olaszországi Nemzeti Kutatási Tanács Informatikai és Telematikai Intézetének CybersecurityLab-jával (IIT) együttműködésben. A tanulmány elsősorban arra a terminológiai tudásbázisra fog összpontosítani, amelyet az olasz nyelven a kiberbiztonsági domain legreprezentatívabb jelöltfelvételeinek visszaszerezésére építettek, és példákat ad azokra a főbb aranyszabású adattárakra, amelyeket e szemantikai eszköz megépítéséhez használtak. Ezt követően figyelmet fordítunk arra a módszerre és szoftverre, amelyet az NLP szabályok rendszerének konfigurálására alkalmaznak a kívánt szemantikai eredmények elérése érdekében, valamint a jelölt kifejezések kiválasztásának javítására, amelyeket az ellenőrzött szókincsbe kell beilleszteni.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დოკუმენტის მიზეზია, რომ საიბერსუკური ტერმინოლოგიის პირველი პროექტის კონფიგურაციის კონფიგურაციის კონფიგურაციის კონფიგურაცია პროექტის ექსპერსუკურაციის კონფიგურაციის კონფიგურაციისთვის აკეთებაში საიბერსუკურა განსაკუთრებულია, პირველად, დაახლობა ტერმინოლოგიური მეცნიერების ბაზაზე, რომელიც დააყენებულია, რომ კიბერსუკური დიომინის უფრო გამოსახულებელი კანდიდენტის კონდიდენტის კონდიდენტის კონდიდენტის კ შემდეგ დაახლოებით მეტოლოგია და პროგრამა, რომელიც გამოყენებული NLP წესების სისტემის კონფიგურაციას, რომ მიიღებთ მომენტიკური წესების შესაძლებლობა და გამოყენება კანდიდენტის წესების შესაძლებლობა, რომელიც მოსაძლებ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Il presente lavoro intende presentare i primi passi per migliorare la qualità della prima bozza di un thesaurus italiano per la terminologia della Cybersecurity realizzato per una specifica attività progettuale in collaborazione con CybersecurityLab presso l'Istituto di Informatica e Telematica (IIT) del Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche (CNR) in Italia. In particolare, l'articolo si concentrerà, in primo luogo, sulla base di conoscenze terminologiche costruita per recuperare i termini candidati più rappresentativi del dominio Cybersecurity in lingua italiana, fornendo esempi dei principali repository gold standard utilizzati per costruire questo strumento semantico. Verrà poi prestata attenzione alla metodologia e al software utilizzati per configurare un sistema di regole NLP per ottenere i risultati semantici desiderati e per procedere con la valorizzazione della selezione dei termini candidati da inserire nel vocabolario controllato.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз Италия Ұлттық Research Council (CNR) Информациялық және Телематикалық институтты (IIT) Италия Италиялық зерттеулер институтындағы CybersecurityLab жұмыс істеу үшін бірінші қадамдарды жасау үшін бірінші қадамдарды көрсетуге мақсат береді. Әрине қағаз, біріншіден, бұл semantic құрылғы үшін қолданылатын негізгі алтын стандартты репозиториялардың негізгі алтын репозиторияларының негізгі құрылғысын алу үшін қолданылатын терминологиялық білім негізіне көздейді. Содан кейін NLP ережелердің жүйесін баптау үшін қолданылатын методология мен бағдарлама қажетті семантикалық нәтижелерді алу үшін жұмыс істейді және басқару үшін қолданылатын кандидаттарды таңдау шарттарын жақсарту үшін қолданылады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente siekiama pristatyti pirmuosius žingsnius siekiant pagerinti Italijos kibernetinio saugumo terminologijos tezauro pirmojo projekto kokybę, kuris buvo įgyvendintas konkrečiai projekto veiklai bendradarbiaujant su Italijos Nacionalinės mokslinių tyrimų tarybos (CNR) Kibernetinio saugumo laboratorija (IIT). Visų pirma dokumente daugiausia dėmesio bus skiriama terminologinei žinių bazei, sukurtai siekiant gauti labiausiai reprezentatyvius kandidatų kibernetinio saugumo srities terminus italų kalba, pateikiant pagrindinių aukso standartinių saugyklų, naudojamų šiai semantinei priemonei sukurti, pavyzdžius. Tada bus atkreiptas dėmesys į metodiką ir programinę įrangą, naudojamą sukurti NLP taisyklių sistemą siekiant pasiekti pageidaujamus semantinius rezultatus ir toliau gerinti kandidatų sąvokų atranką, kuri turi būti įtraukta į kontroliuojamą žodyną.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Овој документ има за цел претставување на првите чекори за подобрување на квалитетот на првиот нацрт на италијански тезаурус за терминалогија на кибер-безбедност, кој е реализиран за специфична проектска активност во соработка со кибер-безбедност лабораторијата на Институтот за информатика и телематика (ИТ) на Националниот Посебно, весникот ќе се фокусира, прво, на терминолошката база на знаење изградена за добивање на најпретставните кандидатски термини на киберосигурноста на италијански јазик, давајќи примери на главните златни стандардни резервоари кои се користат за изградба на оваа семантична алатка. Потоа ќе се обрати внимание на методологијата и софтверот што се користи за конфигурација на систем на правила на НЛП за да се добијат желбите семантични резултати и да продолжат со подобрувањето на изборот на кандидатските термини кои треба да се внесат во контролираниот речник.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>ഇറ്റാലിയിലെ നാഷണല്‍ പരിശോധന കൌണ്ടിറ്റിയുടെ (സിഎന്‍ആര്‍) യുമായി സൈബെര്‍സിക്ക് ടെര്‍മിനോളജിയുടെ ആദ്യത്തെ തിയൂറസിന്‍റെ സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യം മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്താന്‍ ഈ പേപ്പറിന്‍റെ ആദ്യത്തെ പടികള്‍ കാ പ്രത്യേകിച്ച്, ആദ്യം ഈ സെമാന്റിക് ഉപകരണത്തിനായി ഉപയോഗിച്ചിരിക്കുന്ന സൈബര്‍ സുരക്ഷിതാവ് ഡോമെനിന്റെ ഏറ്റവും പ്രതിനിധിയുള്ള വിജ്ഞാനത്തിന്റെ ബേസില്‍ പ ആഗ്രഹിക്കുന്ന സെമാന്റിക് ഫലങ്ങള്‍ ലഭ്യമാക്കുവാനും നിയന്ത്രിക്കപ്പെട്ട വാക്കുകള്‍ തെരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുവാനും ആഗ്രഹിക്കുന്ന പ്രാര്‍ത്ഥിക്ക് തെരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുന്ന വ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_ms>Kertas ini bertujuan untuk memperkenalkan langkah pertama untuk meningkatkan kualiti draf pertama dari tesaur Itali untuk terminologi Keselamatan Cyber yang telah diselesaikan untuk aktiviti projek tertentu dalam kerjasama dengan CybersecurityLab di Institut Informatik dan Telematik (IIT) Dewan Negara Penelitian (CNR) di Itali. Secara khususnya, kertas akan fokus, pertama-tama, pada pangkalan pengetahuan terminologi yang dibina untuk mendapatkan terma calon paling mewakili domain Keselamatan Cyber dalam bahasa Itali, memberikan contoh repositori piawai emas utama yang digunakan untuk membina alat semantik ini. Perhatian akan diberikan kepada metodologi dan perisian yang digunakan untuk konfigur sistem peraturan NLP untuk mendapatkan keputusan semantik yang diingini dan untuk melanjutkan peningkatan pemilihan terma calon yang dimaksudkan untuk disertai dalam vokbulari terkawal.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument għandu l-għan li jippreżenta l-ewwel passi biex itejjeb il-kwalità tal-ewwel abbozz ta’ tesauru Taljan għat-terminoloġija taċ-Ċibersigurtà li twettaq għal attività speċifika ta’ proġett b’kollaborazzjoni mal-Cybersecurity Lab fl-Istitut tal-Informatika u t-Telematika (IIT) tal-Kunsill Nazzjonali tar-Riċerka (CNR) fl-Italja. B’mod partikolari, id-dokument se jiffoka, l-ewwel nett, fuq il-bażi ta’ għarfien terminoloġiku mibnija biex jinkisbu t-termini l-aktar rappreżentattivi kandidati tad-dominju taċ-Ċibersigurtà fil-lingwa Taljana, billi jagħti eżempji tar-repożitorji ewlenin tal-istandards tad-deheb li ntużaw għall-bini ta’ din l-għodda semantika. Attention will be then given to the methodology and software employed to configure a system of NLP rules to get the desired semantic results and to proceed with the enhancement of the candidate terms selection which are meant to be inserted in the controlled vocabulary.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret mål å vise dei første stegane for å forbedra kvaliteten til den første utviklinga av ein italiansk teorus for cybersecurity terminology som er realisert for eit spesifikke prosjektaktivitet i samarbeid med CybersecurityLab i Informatics and Telematics Institute (IIT) av National Council of Research (CNR) i Italia. I særskilt vil papiret fokusere først på terminologisk kunnskapsbasen bygd for å henta dei mest reprezentativste kandidatene for cybersecurity-domene i italiansk språk, og gje eksemplar av hovudlageret for gull standard som er brukt for å bygge dette semantiske verktøyet. Dette blir derfor gjeven oppmerksomhet til metodologien og programvare som er arbeida for å setja opp eit NLP- reglar for å få dei ønskte semantiske resultatene og for å gå fram med forbetringa av utvalet av kandidatbegrepene som skal setjast inn i den kontrollerte ordboka.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł ma na celu przedstawienie pierwszych kroków w celu poprawy jakości pierwszego projektu włoskiego tezauru terminologii cyberbezpieczeństwa, który został zrealizowany dla konkretnej działalności projektowej we współpracy z CybersecurityLab w Instytucie Informatyki i Telematyki (IIT) Narodowej Rady Badań (CNR) we Włoszech. W szczególności artykuł skupi się, po pierwsze, na terminologicznej bazie wiedzy zbudowanej w celu uzyskania najbardziej reprezentatywnych terminów kandydatów domeny cyberbezpieczeństwa w języku włoskim, podając przykłady głównych repozytoriów standardów złota, które zostały wykorzystane do budowy tego narzędzia semantycznego. Następnie zwrócona zostanie uwagę na metodologię i oprogramowanie zastosowane do konfiguracji systemu reguł NLP w celu uzyskania pożądanych rezultatów semantycznych oraz rozszerzenia wyboru terminów kandydatów, które mają zostać wprowadzone do kontrolowanego słownictwa.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare își propune să prezinte primii pași pentru îmbunătățirea calității primului proiect de tezaur italian pentru terminologia securității cibernetice, realizat pentru o activitate specifică de proiect în colaborare cu CybersecurityLab de la Institutul de Informatică și Telematică (IIT) al Consiliului Național de Cercetare (CNR) din Italia. În special, lucrarea se va concentra, în primul rând, pe baza de cunoștințe terminologice construită pentru a recupera cei mai reprezentativi termeni candidați ai domeniului Cybersecurity în limba italiană, oferind exemple ale principalelor depozite gold standard care au fost utilizate pentru construirea acestui instrument semantic. Se va acorda atenție apoi metodologiei și software-ului utilizat pentru a configura un sistem de reguli PNL pentru a obține rezultatele semantice dorite și pentru a continua cu îmbunătățirea selecției termenilor candidați care sunt meniți să fie inserați în vocabularul controlat.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас нь Италия улсын Шудалгааны Их Судалгааны Интернэтик болон Телематикийн Институт (IIT) дээрх Цибер аюулгүй терминологийн анхны загварыг сайжруулахын тулд анхны алхам гаргах зорилго юм. Ялангуяа цаас, эхлээд, цаас нь Цибер аюулгүй байдлыг Италийн хэлний хамгийн их захиралдаг мэдлэгтэй суурь дээр анхаарлаа хандуулна. Энэ semantic хэрэгсэл бүтээхэд хэрэглэгдсэн үндсэн алтын стандарт хадгаламжуудын жишээ гаргадаг. Дараа нь NLP дүрмийн системийг загварчлахын тулд хэрэглэгдсэн програм хангамжийн методологийг анхаарлаа хандуулах болно. Хэрэглэгдсэн семантийн үр дүнг авах болон удирдагдсан үгсийн сонголтыг нэмэгдүүлэх болно.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats syftar till att presentera de första stegen för att förbättra kvaliteten på det första utkastet till en italiensk tesaurus för cybersäkerhet terminologi som har genomförts för en specifik projektaktivitet i samarbete med CybersecurityLab vid Informatik och Telematik Institute (IIT) vid National Council of Research (CNR) i Italien. Framför allt kommer uppsatsen att fokusera på den terminologiska kunskapsbasen byggd för att hämta de mest representativa kandidattermerna för cybersecurity-domänen på italienska språket, med exempel på de viktigaste guldstandardarkiv som använts för att bygga detta semantiska verktyg. Uppmärksamhet kommer sedan att ägnas åt den metod och programvara som används för att konfigurera ett system med NLP-regler för att få önskade semantiska resultat och för att fortsätta med förbättringen av valet av kandidattermer som är avsedda att infogas i det kontrollerade ordförrådet.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalkan wuxuu ku jeedaa in uu soo bandhigayo tallaabooyinkii ugu horreeyey in uu hagaajiyo suurtagalka ugu horeeyay qoraalka qoraalka ammaanta Cyberminology oo loo xaqiijiyey hawlo gaar ah oo la shaqeynayo CybersecurityLab ee Informatics and Telematics Institute (IIT) of the National Council of Research (CNR) ee Italy. Marka ugu horeysa warqaddu wuxuu ku hagaajin doonaa aasaaska aqoonta terminology ee loo dhisay in lagu soo celiyo sharciga ugu xuquuqda kandidada ah oo ku qoran afka Itaaliya, wuxuuna tusaalayaal ka dhigan karaa bakaaradaha dahabka ee ugu horeeya ee loo isticmaalay dhisidda qalabkan semantika ah. Markaas waxaa la sii jeedi doonaa qoraalka iyo software oo loo isticmaalay in loo soo qoro nidaamka NLP si ay u helaan resultiyada loo baahan yahay semantika iyo in lagu sii socoyo kordhiska doorashada kandidada oo loo talogalay in lagu galo afka la ilaaliyo.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தின் முதல் படிகளை முன்னேற்றுகிறது இத்தாலிய நாட்டு ஆராய்ச்சி கூட்டத்திற்கான சைப்பர் பாதுகாப்பு முன்நிலையில் ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட திட்டப்பணிக்கு தெரிந்துள்ளது இது இத்தாலியில்  குறிப்பிட்டு, முதலில், இத்தாலிய பைபர் பாதுகாப்பு டொமைனை மீட்டெடுக்க முடியும் முதலில் இந்த பென்டிக் கருவியை உருவாக்க பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட முக்கிய தங்க இயல்பா பின்னர் தேவைப்படும் semantic முடிவுகளை பெற NLP விதிகளை வடிவமைக்க பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட முறைமையிலும் மென்பொருளுக்கும் கவனம் கொடுக்கப்படும் மற்றும் தொடர்ந்து செல்ல வேண்டி</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>یہ کاغذ کا ارادہ ہے کہ ایک ایتالیایی ٹیسوروس کی پہلی ڈراٹ کی کیفیت زیادہ کرے جو ایتالیا میں سیبرسی ٹریمولوژی کے ذریعہ ایک خاص پروژہ کی فعالیت کے لئے پائی گئی ہے۔ مخصوصا، یہ کاغذ، پہلی بار، ترمینلوژیکی علم بنسس پر بنیاد کیا گیا ہے تاکہ اسے ایتالیایی زبان میں سایر سیپرسی ڈومین کے سب سے زیادہ واضح ترمینٹیوں کے معاملات حاصل کریں، اس کے ذریعہ مثالیں بیان کریں جو اس سیمنٹی تولیل بنانے کے لئے اس کے بعد نصیحت کی جاتی ہے کہ NLP قانون کے سیستم کو پیدا کرنے کے لئے استعمال کئے جاتے ہیں اور کاندینڈیٹ ترمیم کا انتخاب کرنے کے لئے استعمال کئے جاتے ہیں اور ان کا انتخاب کئے جاتے ہیں جن کو کنٹرول کی لکھ میں داخل کرنا چاہتا ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir je cilj da predstavi prve korake za poboljšanje kvalitete prvog projekta italijanskog teorusa za terminologiju kiberbezbednosti koja je shvatila za specifičnu aktivnost projekta u saradnji sa kiberbezbednosnim laboratorijom u Informatičkom i telematičkom institutu (IIT) Nacionalnog Saveta istraživanja (CNR) u Italiji. Posebno, papir će se prvo fokusirati na terminološku bazu znanja izgrađenu kako bi dobio najreprezentantniji kandidatski uslovi domena sajber sigurnosti na italijanskom jeziku, dajući primjere glavnih zlatnih standardnih repozitorija koji su korišteni za izgradnju ovog semantičkog alata. Onda će biti pružena pažnja metodologiji i softvera koji su zaposleni za konfiguraciju sustava pravila NLP-a kako bi dobili željne semantičke rezultate i nastavili s poboljšanjem izbora kandidatskih uslova koji se trebaju uključiti u kontrolirani rečenik.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ පැත්තේ අදහස් කරනවා ඉතාලියානු සායිබර්සුකුරිත් වර්තනය සඳහා පළමුවෙන් පැත්තක් පෙන්වන්න, ඉතාලියාන් ජාතික විශ්වාසයේ සායිබර්සුකුරිත් ලැබ් එක්ක සම්බන්ධ විද විශේෂයෙන්, පිළිබඳින්, මුලින්, ඉතාලියානු භාෂාවේ සායිබර්සුකුරිත් වර්තනයේ ප්‍රධාන ස්ථානයික දන්නවත් පද්ධතියේ ප්‍රධාන ස්ථානය පස්සේ අවශ්‍ය විද්‍යාව සහ සෆ්ටෝවර් පද්ධතිය NLP නීති පද්ධතියක් සැකසුම් කරගන්න සඳහා අවශ්‍ය විද්‍යාවක් ලැබීමට සඳහා අවශ්‍ය විද්‍යාවක් තෝරණය ස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_uz>Bu gaz Italyaning Tashqi Council (CNR) davlatida xavfsiz loyihasi amalga oshirilgan birinchi qadamni yaxshi ko'rsatish uchun Italyaning birinchi qadamlarni o'rganish uchun birinchi qadam beradi. In particular, the paper will focus, first, on the terminological knowledge base built to retrieve the most representative candidate terms of Cybersecurity domain in Italian language, giving examples of the main gold standard repositories that have been used to build this semantic tool.  Keyin, kerak boʻlgan semantik natijalarini olish uchun NLP qoidalarini moslash uchun ishlatadigan усул ва дастурлар ishlatiladi va boshqaruv vosita qoʻyish uchun ishlatiladi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Mục tiêu của bài báo này là những bước đầu tiên nhằm nâng cao chất lượng của bản phác thảo đầu tiên của một thuật ngữ về an ninh mạng người Ý được thực hiện cho một dự án cụ thể, phối hợp với Cyber Security Lab ở Informics và Telematics Institute (lT) của National Council of Research (CNR) ở Italy. In particular, the paper will focus, first, on the terminal knowledge base built to catch the most representative Ứng viên of Cyberdyne miền in Italian language, with exampIe of the main gold tiêu chuẩn regions that have been used to built this semantics tiện tiện tiện. Sau đó sẽ được chú ý đến phương pháp và phần mềm được sử dụng để cấu hình một hệ thống luật lệ lẩn trốn nhằm đạt được kết quả theo ngữ pháp yêu cầu và tiến hành tăng cường khả năng chọn các từ ngữ ứng cử viên cần được thêm vào từ vựng được kiểm soát.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir je cilj predstavljati prve korake za poboljšanje kvalitete prvog nacrta italijanskog thesaurus a za terminologiju kibersigurnosti koja je shvatila za određenu aktivnost projekta u suradnji s kiberecurityLab u Informatičkom i telematičkom institutu (IIT) Nacionalnog vijeća istraživanja (CNR) u Italiji. Posebno, papir će se prvo usredotočiti na terminološku bazu znanja izgrađenu kako bi dobio najpredstavljivije kandidatske uvjete domena sajber sigurnosti na italijanskom jeziku, dajući primjere glavnih zlatnih standardnih skladišta koje su korištene za izgradnju ovog semantičkog alata. Onda će se pozornost dati metodologiji i softver zaposlenim kako bi se konfigurirao sustav pravila NLP-a kako bi dobio željeni semantički rezultati i nastavio s poboljšanjem izbora kandidatskih uvjeta koji se trebaju uključiti u kontrolirani riječ.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel heeft tot doel de eerste stappen te presenteren om de kwaliteit van het eerste ontwerp van een Italiaanse thesaurus voor cybersecurity terminologie te verbeteren dat is gerealiseerd voor een specifieke projectactiviteit in samenwerking met CybersecurityLab bij het Instituut voor Informatica en Telematica (IIT) van de Nationale Raad van Onderzoek (CNR) in Italië. In het bijzonder zal de paper zich in de eerste plaats richten op de terminologische kennisbank die is gebouwd om de meest representatieve kandidaat termen van Cybersecurity domein in de Italiaanse taal op te halen, met voorbeelden van de belangrijkste gouden standaard repositories die zijn gebruikt om deze semantische tool te bouwen. Vervolgens zal aandacht worden besteed aan de methodologie en software die wordt gebruikt om een systeem van NLP regels te configureren om de gewenste semantische resultaten te krijgen en verder te gaan met de verbetering van de selectie van kandidaat termen die bedoeld zijn om in de gecontroleerde woordenschat te worden ingevoegd.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel har til formål at præsentere de første skridt til at forbedre kvaliteten af det første udkast til en italiensk tesaurus for cybersecurity terminologi, der er blevet realiseret til en specifik projektaktivitet i samarbejde med CybersecurityLab på Informatik og Telematik Institut (IIT) under National Council of Research (CNR) i Italien. Artiklen vil især fokusere på den terminologiske videnbase, der er bygget til at hente de mest repræsentative kandidattermer for cybersecurity domæne på italiensk sprog, og give eksempler på de vigtigste gold standard repositories, der er blevet brugt til at opbygge dette semantiske værktøj. Derefter vil der blive lagt opmærksomhed på den metode og software, der anvendes til at konfigurere et system med NLP-regler for at opnå de ønskede semantiske resultater og fortsætte med at forbedre udvælgelsen af kandidattermer, som skal indsættes i det kontrollerede ordforråd.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия има за цел да представи първите стъпки за подобряване качеството на първия проект на италиански речник за терминология за киберсигурност, реализиран за конкретна проектна дейност в сътрудничество с Киберсигурност към Института по информатика и телематика към Националния съвет за научни изследвания в Италия. По-специално, докладът ще се съсредоточи, първо, върху терминологичната база от знания, изградена за извличане на най-представителните кандидатски термини в областта на киберсигурността на италиански език, като даде примери за основните хранилища със златен стандарт, използвани за изграждането на този семантичен инструмент. След това ще се обърне внимание на методологията и софтуера, използвани за конфигуриране на система от правила за НЛП, за да се получат желаните семантични резултати и да се продължи с подобряване на избора на кандидат термини, които са предназначени да бъдат въведени в контролирания речник.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini bermaksud untuk memperkenalkan langkah pertama untuk meningkatkan kualitas draft pertama dari sebuah tesaur Italia untuk terminologi Keamanan Sibernetik yang telah direalisasi untuk aktivitas proyek spesifik dalam kolaborasi dengan CybersecurityLab di Institut Informatik dan Telematik (IIT) dari Dewan Nasional Penelitian (CNR) di Italia. In particular, the paper will focus, first, on the terminological knowledge base built to retrieve the most representative candidate terms of Cybersecurity domain in Italian language, giving examples of the main gold standard repositories that have been used to build this semantic tool.  Perhatian akan diberikan pada metodologi dan perangkat lunak yang digunakan untuk mengkonfigurasi sistem peraturan NLP untuk mendapatkan hasil semantis yang diinginkan dan untuk melanjutkan dengan meningkatkan seleksi istilah kandidat yang seharusnya dimasukkan ke dalam vocabulari terkendali.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Ziel dieses Beitrags ist es, die ersten Schritte zur Verbesserung der Qualität des ersten Entwurfs eines italienischen Thesaurus für Cybersecurity-Terminologie vorzustellen, der für eine spezifische Projektaktivität in Zusammenarbeit mit CybersecurityLab am Institut für Informatik und Telematik (IIT) des Nationalen Forschungsrates (CNR) in Italien realisiert wurde. Insbesondere wird sich der Beitrag zunächst auf die terminologische Wissensdatenbank konzentrieren, die erstellt wurde, um die repräsentativsten Kandidatenbegriffe der Cybersecurity-Domäne in italienischer Sprache abzurufen, wobei Beispiele für die wichtigsten Goldstandard-Repositorien angeführt werden, die zum Aufbau dieses semantischen Tools verwendet wurden. Die Aufmerksamkeit wird dann auf die Methodik und Software gelegt, die verwendet wird, um ein System von NLP-Regeln zu konfigurieren, um die gewünschten semantischen Ergebnisse zu erhalten und mit der Verbesserung der Auswahl der Kandidatenbegriffe fortzufahren, die in das kontrollierte Vokabular eingefügt werden sollen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 이탈리아 네트워크 보안 용어 사전 초고의 질을 높이는 첫걸음을 소개하고자 한다. 이 사전은 이탈리아 국가연구위원회(CNR) 정보학 및 원격통신연구소(IIT)의 네트워크 보안 실험실과 협력해 특정 프로젝트 활동에서 실현되었다.특히 본고는 먼저 이탈리아어 네트워크 보안 분야의 대표적인 후보 용어를 검색하기 위해 구축된 용어 지식 라이브러리에 주목하고 이 의미 도구를 구축하는 데 사용되는 주요 황금 표준 라이브러리를 예를 들어 설명하고자 한다.그리고 NLP 규칙 시스템을 설정하는 방법과 소프트웨어에 주목하여 필요한 의미 결과를 얻고 후보 용어 선택을 계속 강화하며, 이 후보 용어들은 통제된 어휘표에 삽입될 것이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ هدف دارد که اولین مرحله‌ها را برای بهتر کردن کیفیت اولین پروژه‌ی تئاتوروس ایتالیایی برای ترمینولوژی سایبرسکوری که برای یک فعالیت پروژه خاصی در همکاری با آزمایشگاه سایبرسکوریتی در موسسه اطلاعات و تلمیاتیک (IIT) از شورای ملی تحقیقات (CNR) در ایتالیا متوجه شده است. مخصوصا، این کاغذ، اول، روی پایگاه علم ترمینالوژیکی ساخته می شود که برای دریافت کردن بهترین اصطلاح کاندیداتی از دومین سایر محافظت در زبان ایتالیایی، به عنوان مثالهایی از انبارهای استاندارد طلا که برای ساختن این ابزار semantic استفاده شده اند، به عن سپس توجه به روش‌شناسی و نرم‌افزار استخدام می‌شود تا سیستم قوانین NLP را پیکربند تا نتیجه‌های semantic خواسته را بدست بیاورد و با افزایش انتخاب شرایط کاندیده‌ای که قرار است در کلمات کنترل وارد شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Makala hii inakusudia kuonyesha hatua za kwanza za kuboresha ubora wa rasimu ya kwanza ya thesaurusi ya utambulisho wa masuala ya usalama wa Mtandao ambayo imegunduliwa kwa ajili ya shughuli maalum ya mradi wa ushirikiano na ulinzi wa Mtandao wa Kitaarifa na Taasisi ya Telematika (IIT) ya Baraza la Taifa la Utafiti (CNR) nchini Italia. Kwa hakika, gazeti hilo litajikita, kwanza, kwenye msingi wa maarifa ya kimaadilojia ulioanzishwa ili kurejesha vipengele vya mgombea zaidi vya usalama wa Mtandao katika lugha ya Italia, na kutoa mifano ya vituo vikuu vya dhahabu ambavyo vimetumiwa kujenga zana hii ya kigaidi. Attention will be then given to the methodology and software employed to configure a system of NLP rules to get the desired semantic results and to proceed with the enhancement of the candidate terms selection which are meant to be inserted in the controlled vocabulary.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument synon të paraqesë hapat e parë për të përmirësuar cilësinë e projektit të parë të një tezauri italian për terminologjinë e sigurisë kibernetike që është realizuar për një veprimtari të posaçme projekti në bashkëpunim me Laboratorin e Sigurisë Kibernetike në Institutin e Informatikës dhe Telematikës (IIT) të Këshillit Kombëtar të Kërkimit (CNR) në Itali. Në veçanti, gazeta do të përqëndrohet, së pari, në bazën e njohurive terminologjike të ndërtuar për të marrë termat më përfaqësuese kandidate të domenit të Sigurisë Kibernetike në gjuhën italiane, duke dhënë shembuj të depozitave kryesore të standardeve të artë që janë përdorur për të ndërtuar këtë mjet semantik. Atëherë do t'u jepet vëmendja metodologjisë dhe softuerit të përdorur për të konfiguruar një sistem rregullash NLP për të marrë rezultatet semantike të dëshiruara dhe për të vazhduar me përmirësimin e zgjedhjes së termave kandidate që duhen të futen në fjalorin e kontrolluar.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz Italia Milli Araştyrmalar (CNR) konseptiniň (IIT) bilen CybersecurityLab bilen birleşmegde tassyklanan ilkinji gezek gatnaşmasynyň CybersecurityLab üçin Ilkinji gezek beýleki hereket etmäge maksady berilýär. Aýratyn bolsa, bu gazet, ilkinji gezek, bu semantik gurama üçin ullanýan altyn standart depolarynyň örneklerini çykarýar. Soňra NLP kurallarynyň sistemasyny düzenlemek üçin ullanýan methodologiýa we softwaryna üns berilecek we isleýän semantik netijeleri almak üçin isleýän sözleriniň gelişmegi we kontrol edilen sözleriniň içine girmek üçin ullanýan kandidat şertleri gelişmegi bilen üns berilecek.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier is doel om die eerste stappe te voorsien om die kwaliteit van die eerste projekt van 'n Italiaanse thesaurus te verbeter vir Sibersekuriteit terminologie wat vir 'n spesifieke projek aktiviteit in samekorbeid met Sibersekuriteit Lab by Informatike en Telematiese Institute (IIT) van die Nasionale Raad van Research (CNR) in Italia te besluit. Spesifieke sal die papier eerste fokus op die terminologiese kennis basis gebou om die mees reprezentante kandidate terme van Sibersekuriteit domein in Italiese taal te kry, voorbeelde van die hoofde goud standaard stoorplekke wat gebruik is om hierdie semantiese nutsprogram te bou. Aangaande sal dan gegee word aan die metodologie en sagteware wat gebruik word om 'n stelsel van NLP reëls te konfigureer om die verwagte semantiese resultate te kry en om voort te gaan met die verbetering van die kandidate terme keuse wat bedoel word om in die kontroleerde woordeboek te voeg.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>ይህ ፕሮግራም የኢንተርኔት ካውንቲክ እና ቴሌሜቲክ ተርሚክ (CNR) ካሉት የኢንተርኔት ካንስቲክ እና ቴሌማቲክ (IIT) ተማሪ ክፍል ጋር በተለይ የፕሮጀክት ተሟጋቾችን የኢጣሊያንኛ ቴሶሮስ የፊተኛውን የጥያቄ ጥያቄ አካባቢውን ለማድረግ ያሳያል፡፡ በተለይም፣ ፕሬዝዳንቱ አስቀድሞ፣ የቆቤር ደህንነት ድሜን በጣሊያንኛ ቋንቋ ለማምጣት በተሠራው ተርሚኖሎጂ እውቀት መቀመጫ ላይ ትክክል ይሆናል፡፡ Attention will be then given to the methodology and software employed to configure a system of NLP rules to get the desired semantic results and to proceed with the enhancement of the candidate terms selection which are meant to be inserted in the controlled vocabulary.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটির উদ্দেশ্য হচ্ছে ইতালিয়ান নিরাপত্তা টার্মিনোলজির জন্য একটি ইতালিয়ান থিউজারের প্রথম পদক্ষেপের মান উন্নতি করার জন্য যা ইতালির জাতীয় গবেষণা কাউন্সিল অফ সিএনআর (সিএনআর) এর সাইবার সিকিউরি বিশেষ করে, প্রথমে ইতালীয় ভাষায় সাইবার নিরাপত্তা ডোমেইনের সবচেয়ে প্রার্থী শর্ত পুনরুদ্ধারের জন্য টার্মিনোলজিক্যাল জ্ঞানের বেসে প্রতিনিধিত্বিত প্রার্ তারপর প্রার্থীর নির্বাচনের বাড়িয়ে যাওয়ার জন্য এনএলপি নিয়ম কনফিগার করা পদ্ধতি এবং সফটওয়্যারের দিকে মনোযোগ প্রদান করা হবে যা নিয়ন্ত্রিত শব্দভাণ্ডারে ঢোকা যাবে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir je cilj da predstavi prve korake za poboljšanje kvalitete prvog projekta italijanskog thesaurus a za terminologiju kibersigurnosti koja je shvatila za specifičnu aktivnost projekta u suradnji s kiberecurityLab u Informatičkom i telematičkom institutu (IIT) Nacionalnog vijeća istraživanja (CNR) u Italiji. Posebno, papir će se prvo fokusirati na terminološku bazu znanja izgrađenu kako bi dobio najreprezentantniji kandidatski uslovi domena sajber sigurnosti na italijanskom jeziku, dajući primjere glavnih zlatnih standardnih skladišta koje su korištene za izgradnju ovog semantičkog alata. Tada će se pažnja dati metodologiji i softver zaposleni kako bi konfigurirali sistem pravila NLP kako bi dobili željeni semantički rezultati i nastavili s poboljšanjem izbora kandidatskih uvjeta koji se trebaju uključiti u kontrolirani reč.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_hy>Այս փաստաթղթի նպատակն է առաջին քայլերը ներկայացնել Իտալիայի կիբեր ապահովության տերմինոլոգիայի առաջին նախագիծի որակը բարելավելու համար, որը իրականացվել է Իտալիայի Հետազոտության ազգային խորհրդի (CNR) Cyber-ապահովության լաբորատորիայի (IIT) համագործակցության համար որոշակի նախագիծ: Նախ և առաջ, թղթին կկենտրոնանա տերմինոլոգիական գիտելիքների հիմքի վրա, որը կառուցվել է Իտալական լեզվով Cyber-ապահովության բնագավառի ամենաներկայացուցիչ պայմանները վերցնելու համար, ներկայացնելով օրինակներ հիմնական ոսկու ստանդարտ պահեստներից, որոնք օգտագործ Հետո ուշադրություն կդարձնենք այն մեթոդոլոգիային և ծրագրավորումներին, որոնք օգտագործվում են ՆԼՊ օրենքների համակարգի կազմակերպելու համար, որպեսզի ստանան ցանկացած սեմանտիկ արդյունքներ և շարունակեն բարելավել թեկնածու տերմինների ընտրությունը, որը պետք է ներառվի վերահ</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu kańüńĪt ilk adńĪmlarńĪ ńįtalya Ulusal AraŇütńĪrma Konseyi (CNR) Informatics and Telematics Institute (IIT) il…ô ńįtalya ńįtalya tezarosu terminologiyasńĪnńĪn ilk qismini daha yaxŇüńĪlaŇüdńĪrmaq m…ôqs…ôdil…ô ke√ßirildi. √Ėzellikle, bu kańüńĪt ilk d…ôf…ô, bu semantik vasit…ôsini in Ňüa etm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn inŇüa edilmiŇü terminolojik bilgi tabanńĪna, ńįtalyan dilind…ôki …ôn d…ôst…ôkli KandidatlńĪ s…ôviyy…ôl…ôrini almaq √ľ√ß√ľn t…ôrzd…ô t…ôrzd…ô t…ôrzd…ô t…ôrzd…ô g√∂st…ôr…ôc…ôk, bu semantik vasit…ôsini inŇüa etm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn istifad…ô edil…ôn altńĪn standart depositl…ôrinin √∂rn…ô Sonra NLP kurallarńĪnńĪn sistemini yapńĪlandńĪrmaq √ľ√ß√ľn istifad…ô edil…ôn metodolojiya v…ô proqramńĪna dikkat edil…ôc…ôk v…ô ist…ôdiyi semantik sonu√ßlarńĪ almaq v…ô kontrol s√∂zl…ôrd…ô daxil edil…ôc…ôk kandid√°t ŇüartlarńĪ se√ßm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn daha yaxŇüńĪ t…ôrzd…ô davam ed…ôc…ôk.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest paper té l'objectiu de presentar les primeres etapes per millorar la qualitat del primer projecte d'un tesaure italià per a la terminologia de la cibersiguritat que s'ha realizat per a una activitat específica de projecte en col·laboració amb el CybersecurityLab a l'Institut d'Informatica i Telemàtica (IIT) del National Council of Research (CNR) d'Itàlia. En particular, el paper s'enfocarà, en primer lloc, en la base de coneixements terminològics construïda per recuperar els termes candidats més representatius del domini de cibersiguretat en idioma italià, donant exemples dels principals repositoris d'or standard que han estat utilitzats per construir aquesta eina semàntica. Attention will be then given to the methodology and software employed to configure a system of NLP rules to get the desired semantic results and to proceed with the enhancement of the candidate terms selection which are meant to be inserted in the controlled vocabulary.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek si klade za cíl představit první kroky ke zlepšení kvality prvního návrhu italského tezauru pro terminologii kybernetické bezpečnosti, který byl realizován pro konkrétní projektovou aktivitu ve spolupráci s CybersecurityLab na ústavu informatiky a telematiky (IIT) Národní rady výzkumu (CNR) v Itálii. Příspěvek se zaměří zejména na terminologickou znalostní bázi vytvořenou pro získání nejreprezentativnějších kandidátských termínů domény kybernetické bezpečnosti v italském jazyce a uvádí příklady hlavních repozitářů zlatého standardu, které byly použity k vytvoření tohoto sémantického nástroje. Pozornost bude pak věnována metodice a softwaru použitému pro konfiguraci systému NLP pravidel tak, aby byly dosaženy požadovaných sémantických výsledků a pokračovalo v rozšíření výběru kandidátských termínů, které mají být vloženy do řízené slovní zásoby.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Tämän artikkelin tarkoituksena on esitellä ensimmäiset vaiheet kyberturvallisuusterminologian italiankielisen sanaston ensimmäisen luonnoksen laadun parantamiseksi, joka on toteutettu tiettyä hanketoimintaa varten yhteistyössä kansallisen tutkimusneuvoston (CNR) tietotekniikka- ja telematiikkainstituutin (IIT) CybersecurityLabin kanssa. Työssä keskitytään erityisesti terminologiseen tietopohjaan, joka on rakennettu hakemaan edustavimmat kyberturvallisuusalan ehdokastermit italian kielellä, ja annetaan esimerkkejä tärkeimmistä kultaisen standardin arkistoista, joita on käytetty semanttisen työkalun rakentamisessa. Tämän jälkeen kiinnitetään huomiota menetelmiin ja ohjelmistoihin, joita käytetään NLP:n sääntöjen järjestelmän määrittämisessä haluttujen semanttisten tulosten saamiseksi ja hallittuun sanastoon sisällytettävien ehdokastermien valinnan tehostamiseksi.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Käesoleva dokumendi eesmärk on esitada esimesed sammud Itaalia küberturvalisuse terminoloogia tesauruse esimese projekti kvaliteedi parandamiseks, mis on teostatud konkreetse projektitegevuse jaoks koostöös Itaalia Teadusnõukogu Informaatika- ja Telemaatika Instituudi (IIT) Küberturvalisuse Labiga. Eelkõige keskendutakse töös kõigepealt terminoloogilistele teadmistebaasidele, mis on loodud küberturvalisuse valdkonna kõige esindavamate kandidaatringimuste leidmiseks itaalia keeles, tuues näiteid peamistest kuldstandardite hoidlatest, mida on kasutatud semantilise vahendi ehitamiseks. Seejärel pööratakse tähelepanu metoodikale ja tarkvarale, mida kasutatakse uue õigusloome reeglite süsteemi konfigureerimiseks, et saavutada soovitud semantilised tulemused ja jätkata kandidaatterminite valiku täiustamist, mis on mõeldud lisada kontrollitud sõnavara.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>Perintah iki lak wis nambah kanggo ngerasakno perusahaan sing sambanjur nggawe barang kelas nang ingkang dolanan sing perusahaan karo Terminal Sibersecurity sing berarti kanggo nganggep sistem sing perusahaan kanggo nggawe gerakan akeh sing perusahaan ning SibersecurituyLab baruga ning Informatiks lan telematis instit (IAR) ning Ngawe Padha Nalikar Sibersecurity (SER) ning Italiya. Peringatan, pebuk sing wis dipontrol, perusahaan, nang angkang punika terminal sing gagale nggawe gerakan kanggo ngerasakno perusahaan ping mbukakipun cibersecurity domain nang lengkang italian, sing nyimpen isumbal kelompok dolanan sing isi mbutuhan nggawe bendhu kuwi semantar iki. Attribute</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Wannan karatun na aim a gabatar da hanyõyi na farko dõmin a improve tsarin matsalar na farkon thesaurus na Italian for tsaron cyberspace which has been garwaya for a special program Active in association with cyberSeuritLab at Datarmatiques and telemattic Installation (IIT) of the National Commission of Research (CNR) in Italy. A cikin ƙayyade, takardar zai fokus, a farkon, a kan bangon saniya na tamammali wanda aka gina dõmin a sami mafi yawan matsayin masu nuna maganar tsari na Kyuberiya cikin harshen Italian, yana bãyar da misãlai na kurositori masu ƙaranci na nau'in zĩnãriya da aka yi amfani da su kuɓutar da wannan zane na semantic. Za sa'an nan a bãyar da saurãre zuwa shirin ayuka da kwamfyuta wanda aka yi amfani da shi dõmin a canza wata na'urar na'urar NLP don a sami matsalar da za'a yi amfani da shi na semanti kuma za'a tafiya da ƙaranci wa shirin ayuka masu kandida da za'a shigar da shi cikin maganar da aka lissafa.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Cilj prispevka je predstaviti prve korake za izboljšanje kakovosti prvega osnutka italijanskega tesavra za terminologijo kibernetske varnosti, ki je bil izveden za določeno projektno dejavnost v sodelovanju s CybersecurityLab na Inštitutu za informatiko in telematiko (IIT) Nacionalnega sveta za raziskave (CNR) v Italiji. Prispevek se bo osredotočil zlasti na terminološko bazo znanja, zgrajeno za pridobitev najbolj reprezentativnih kandidatnih izrazov področja kibernetske varnosti v italijanskem jeziku, pri čemer bo navedel primere glavnih repozitorijev zlatih standardov, ki so bili uporabljeni za izgradnjo tega semantičnega orodja. Pozornost bo nato namenjena metodologiji in programski opremi, ki se uporabljajo za konfiguracijo sistema pravil NLP, da bi dobili želene semantične rezultate in nadaljevali z izboljšanjem izbire kandidatnih izrazov, ki so namenjeni vstavitvi v nadzorovani besednjak.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག དམིགས་བསལ་ན། ཤོག་བྱང་འདི་དག་ཆ་མཉམ་དུ་དམིགས་གཏད་འོང་། དང་པོའི་མཐའ་སྒྲོམ་གྱི་གནས་སྟངས Attention will be then given to the methodology and software employed to configure a system of NLP rules to get the desired semantic results and to proceed with the enhancement of the candidate terms selection which are meant to be inserted in the controlled vocabulary.</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>This paper aims at presenting the first steps to improve the quality of the first draft of an Italian thesaurus for Cybersecurity terminology that has been realized for a specific project activity in collaboration with CybersecurityLab at Informatics and Telematics Institute (IIT) of the National Council of Research (CNR) in Italy.  In particular, the paper will focus, first, on the terminological knowledge base built to retrieve the most representative candidate terms of Cybersecurity domain in Italian language, giving examples of the main gold standard repositories that have been used to build this semantic tool.  שימו לב לאחר מכן למטדולוגיה ותוכנה שמשתמשת כדי ליצור מערכת של חוקי NLP כדי להשיג את התוצאות הסמנטיות המשמעותיות ולהמשיך עם השיפור של התנאים המועמדים בחירה שהם אמורים להכניס באופן מושלם.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Terminology-based Text Embedding for Computing Document Similarities on Technical Content</title>
      <author><first>Hamid</first><last>Mirisaee</last></author>
      <author><first>Eric</first><last>Gaussier</last></author>
      <author><first>Cedric</first><last>Lagnier</last></author>
      <author><first>Agnes</first><last>Guerraz</last></author>
      <pages>31–42</pages>
      <abstract>We propose in this paper a new, hybrid document embedding approach in order to address the problem of document similarities with respect to the technical content. To do so, we employ a state-of-the-art graph techniques to first extract the keyphrases (composite keywords) of documents and, then, use them to score the sentences. Using the ranked sentences, we propose two approaches to embed documents and show their performances with respect to two baselines. With domain expert annotations, we illustrate that the proposed methods can find more relevant documents and outperform the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baselines</a> up to 27 % in terms of NDCG.</abstract>
      <url hash="32dbbb15">2019.jeptalnrecital-tia.3</url>
      <bibkey>mirisaee-etal-2019-terminology</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Entropic characterisation of termino-conceptual structure : A preliminary study</title>
      <author><first>Kyo</first><last>Kageura</last></author>
      <author><first>Long-Huei</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <pages>55–68</pages>
      <abstract>Terms represent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concepts</a>, which consist of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">conceptual characteristics</a>. In actual concept-term formation, which is done by researchers, the process is in reverse : conceptual elements / characteristics are consolidated to form <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concepts</a>, which are represented by terms. As <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concepts</a> do not exist on the fly, what we may call termino-conceptual system provides scaffolding in this process. Terminologists, both in practice and in research, do not only collect and list terms but also analyse, describe and define terms and systematise <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminology">terminologies</a>. To carry out these tasks, terminologists must refer to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_system">conceptual systems</a>, to the extent that they contribute to systematising terminologies ; terminologists thus also deal with the sphere of termino-conceptual system. In this paper, we consolidate the status of termino-conceptual sphere and propose a way to characterise the structure of termino-conceptual system by using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy">entropy</a>. The entropic characterisation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminology_of_the_Low_Countries">English terminologies</a> of six domain, i.e. agriculture, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Botany">botany</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chemistry">chemistry</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_science">computer science</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physics">physics</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychology">psychology</a> are presented.</abstract>
      <url hash="419de580">2019.jeptalnrecital-tia.5</url>
      <bibkey>kageura-chen-2019-entropic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>