<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.mwe">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Joint Workshop on Multiword Expressions and Electronic Lexicons</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Stella</first><last>Markantonatou</last></editor>
      <editor><first>John</first><last>McCrae</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jelena</first><last>Mitrović</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Carole</first><last>Tiberius</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Carlos</first><last>Ramisch</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ashwini</first><last>Vaidya</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Petya</first><last>Osenova</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Agata</first><last>Savary</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>online</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="fa57eb6a">2020.mwe-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>mwe-2020-joint</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>CollFrEn : Rich Bilingual EnglishFrench Collocation Resource<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>oll<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>r<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>n: Rich Bilingual <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish–<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>rench Collocation Resource</title>
      <author><first>Beatriz</first><last>Fisas</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis</first><last>Espinosa Anke</last></author>
      <author><first>Joan</first><last>Codina-Filbá</last></author>
      <author><first>Leo</first><last>Wanner</last></author>
      <pages>1–12</pages>
      <abstract>Collocations in the sense of idiosyncratic lexical co-occurrences of two syntactically bound words traditionally pose a challenge to language learners and many Natural Language Processing (NLP) applications alike. Reliable ground truth (i.e., ideally manually compiled) resources are thus of high value. We present a manually compiled bilingual EnglishFrench collocation resource with 7,480 collocations in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and 6,733 in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>. Each <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collocation">collocation</a> is enriched with information that facilitates its downstream exploitation in NLP tasks such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word-sense_disambiguation">word sense disambiguation</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-language_generation">natural language generation</a>, relation classification, and so forth. Our proposed enrichment covers : the semantic category of the collocation (its lexical function), its vector space representation (for each individual word as well as their joint collocation embedding), a subcategorization pattern of both its elements, as well as their corresponding BabelNet i d, and finally, indices of their occurrences in large scale reference corpora.</abstract>
      <url hash="e9869b4e">2020.mwe-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>fisas-etal-2020-collfren</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/talnupf/collfren" additional="false">talnupf/collfren</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Hierarchy-aware Learning of Sequential Tool Usage via Semi-automatically Constructed Taxonomies</title>
      <author><first>Nima</first><last>Nabizadeh</last></author>
      <author><first>Martin</first><last>Heckmann</last></author>
      <author><first>Dorothea</first><last>Kolossa</last></author>
      <pages>22–26</pages>
      <abstract>When repairing a device, humans employ a series of tools that corresponds to the arrangement of the device components. Such sequences of tool usage can be learned from repair manuals, so that at each step, having observed the previously applied tools, a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequential_model">sequential model</a> can predict the next required tool. In this paper, we improve the tool prediction performance of such methods by additionally taking the hierarchical relationships among the tools into account. To this aim, we build a taxonomy of tools with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyponymy_and_hypernymy">hyponymy</a> and hypernymy relations from the data by decomposing all multi-word expressions of tool names. We then develop a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequential_model">sequential model</a> that performs a binary prediction for each node in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taxonomy_(biology)">taxonomy</a>. The evaluation of the method on a dataset of repair manuals shows that encoding the tools with the constructed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taxonomy_(general)">taxonomy</a> and using a top-down beam search for decoding increases the prediction accuracy and yields an interpretable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taxonomy_(general)">taxonomy</a> as a potentially valuable byproduct.</abstract>
      <url hash="a47f13b7">2020.mwe-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>nabizadeh-etal-2020-hierarchy</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>AlphaMWE : Construction of Multilingual Parallel Corpora with MWE Annotations<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>lpha<fixed-case>MWE</fixed-case>: Construction of Multilingual Parallel Corpora with <fixed-case>MWE</fixed-case> Annotations</title>
      <author><first>Lifeng</first><last>Han</last></author>
      <author><first>Gareth</first><last>Jones</last></author>
      <author><first>Alan</first><last>Smeaton</last></author>
      <pages>44–57</pages>
      <abstract>In this work, we present the construction of multilingual parallel corpora with annotation of multiword expressions (MWEs). MWEs include verbal MWEs (vMWEs) defined in the PARSEME shared task that have a verb as the head of the studied terms. The annotated vMWEs are also bilingually and multilingually aligned manually. The languages covered include <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_language">Polish</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a>. Our original <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English corpus</a> is taken from the PARSEME shared task in 2018. We performed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a> of this source corpus followed by human post editing and annotation of target MWEs. Strict quality control was applied for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Error_detection_and_correction">error limitation</a>, i.e., each MT output sentence received first manual post editing and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation</a> plus second manual quality rechecking. One of our findings during corpora preparation is that accurate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation_(biology)">translation</a> of MWEs presents challenges to MT systems. To facilitate further MT research, we present a categorisation of the error types encountered by MT systems in performing MWE related translation. To acquire a broader view of MT issues, we selected four popular state-of-the-art MT models for comparisons namely : Microsoft Bing Translator, GoogleMT, Baidu Fanyi and DeepL MT. Because of the noise removal, translation post editing and MWE annotation by human professionals, we believe our AlphaMWE dataset will be an asset for cross-lingual and multilingual research, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multilingualism">MT</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_extraction">information extraction</a>. Our multilingual corpora are available as open access at github.com/poethan/AlphaMWE.</abstract>
      <url hash="16e295b9">2020.mwe-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>han-etal-2020-alphamwe</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/poethan/AlphaMWE" additional="false">poethan/AlphaMWE</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Annotating Verbal MWEs in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irish_language">Irish</a> for the PARSEME Shared Task 1.2<fixed-case>MWE</fixed-case>s in <fixed-case>I</fixed-case>rish for the <fixed-case>PARSEME</fixed-case> Shared Task 1.2</title>
      <author><first>Abigail</first><last>Walsh</last></author>
      <author><first>Teresa</first><last>Lynn</last></author>
      <author><first>Jennifer</first><last>Foster</last></author>
      <pages>58–65</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the creation of two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irish_language">Irish corpora</a> (labelled and unlabelled) for verbal MWEs for inclusion in the PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 on automatic identification of verbal MWEs, and the process of developing verbal MWE categories for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irish_language">Irish</a>. A qualitative analysis on the two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpora</a> is presented, along with discussion of Irish verbal MWEs.</abstract>
      <url hash="c78d9a40">2020.mwe-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>walsh-etal-2020-annotating</bibkey>
    <title_ar>شرح MWE اللفظية باللغة الأيرلندية لمهمة PARSEME المشتركة 1.2</title_ar>
      <title_es>Anotaciones de MWE verbales en irlandés para la tarea compartida 1.2 de PARSEME</title_es>
      <title_pt>Anotando MWEs Verbais em Irlandês para a Tarefa Compartilhada PARSEME 1.2</title_pt>
      <title_fr>Annotation des MWE verbaux en irlandais pour la tâche partagée PARSEME 1.2</title_fr>
      <title_ja>PARSEME共有タスク1.2のためのアイルランド語での口頭MWEの注釈付け</title_ja>
      <title_zh>以爱尔兰语注 PARSEME 共享任务口 MWE 1.2</title_zh>
      <title_hi>PARSEME साझा कार्य 1.2 के लिए आयरिश में मौखिक MWEs annotating</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Аннотирование словесных MWE на ирландском языке для общей задачи PARSEME 1.2</title_ru>
      <title_ga>MWEanna Briathartha i nGaeilge a Anó don Tasc Comhroinnte PARSEME 1.2</title_ga>
      <title_el>Σχολιασμός προφορικών MWE στα ιρλανδικά για την κοινή εργασία PARSEME 1.2</title_el>
      <title_hu>Szóbeli MWE-k megjegyzése ír nyelven a PARSEME megosztott feladathoz 1.2</title_hu>
      <title_ka>გვერბალური MWEs-ს ინერიონეთში აღმოჩვენება PARSEME გაყოფილი პარამეტრის 1. 2</title_ka>
      <title_it>Annotazione di MWE verbali in irlandese per il compito condiviso PARSEME 1.2</title_it>
      <title_kk>PARSEME ортақтастырылған тапсырма 1. 2 үшін Ирландиядағы Вербал MWEs- ті белгілеу</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Įrašymas žodžiu „MWEs“ Airų kalba dėl bendros PARSEME užduoties 1.2</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Онотирање на вербалните MWEs на ирски за заедничката задача 1.2 на PARSEME</title_mk>
      <title_mt>Annotazzjoni tal-MWEs Verbali bl-Irlandiż għall-Kompitu Konġunt tal-PARSEME 1.2</title_mt>
      <title_ml>ഐറിഷിലെ വെര്‍ബല്‍ എംഡസ് അറിയിക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Menganotasi MWEs Perkataan dalam Irlandia untuk Tugas Berkongsi PARSEME 1.2</title_ms>
      <title_pl>Annotacja słownych MWE w języku irlandzkim dla wspólnego zadania PARSEME 1.2</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Adnotare MWE-uri verbale în limba irlandeză pentru sarcina partajată PARSEME 1.2</title_ro>
      <title_no>Annotering Verbal MWEs i Irsk for PARSEME delt oppgåve 1. 2</title_no>
      <title_mn>PARSEME хуваалтын ажлын хувьд Ирландын Вербал MWEs-г анзаарлах нь 1.2</title_mn>
      <title_sr>Annotirajući Verbal MWEs na Irsku za zajednički zadatak PARSEME 1.2</title_sr>
      <title_sv>Notera verbala MWE på irländska för PARSEME Shared Task 1.2</title_sv>
      <title_si>PARSEME සමාගත වැඩක් 1. 2 වෙනුවෙන් වෙර්බාල් MWes වල අයිරිෂ් වලින්</title_si>
      <title_ur>پارسEME Shared Task 1.2 کے لئے وربل MWEs کو ایرلند میں اپنا انکار کر رہا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_so>Wargelinta Verbal MWES ee Irish ugu qoran PARSEME Shaqada la sharciyey 1.2</title_so>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Chú thích Verbil MWEs bằng tiếng Ai-len cho công việc chia sẻ PARSEME 1.2</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Анотиране на устните МВС на ирландски език за споделената задача на PARSEME 1.2</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Annoteren van verbale MWE's in het Iers voor de PARSEME Shared Task 1.2</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Annotirajući Verbal MWEs na Irsku za zajednički zadatak PARSEME 1.2</title_hr>
      <title_da>Anmærkning Verbal MWE på irsk til PARSEME delt opgave 1.2</title_da>
      <title_ko>PARSEME 공유 작업 1.2 동사 MWe</title_ko>
      <title_de>Annotierung mündlicher MWEs auf Irisch für die PARSEME Shared Task 1.2</title_de>
      <title_sw>Akitangaza MWS wa Verbal nchini Irish kwa ajili ya PARSEME kushirikisha kazi 1.2</title_sw>
      <title_fa>نویسی وربال MWEs در ایرلند برای کار مشترک PARSEME ۱. ۲</title_fa>
      <title_tr>PARSEME Paýlaşmış Görevi 1.2 üçin Verbal MWEs'i ýazylýar</title_tr>
      <title_af>Noteer Verbal MWEs in Irse vir die PARSEME Gedeelde Opdrag 1. 2</title_af>
      <title_sq>Duke vënë në dukje MWEs në irlandez për detyrën e përbashkët të PARSEME 1.2</title_sq>
      <title_am>Annotating Verbal MWEs in Irish for the PARSEME Shared Task 1.2</title_am>
      <title_hy>Գործողություն գրելով Իրլանդերեն լեզվով բառական MWEs-ները, որոնք ներկայացնում են Փարսեմ համագործակցած առաջադրանքը 1.2</title_hy>
      <title_az>PARSEME paylaşılmış iş iş 1.2 üçün İrlandalı Verbal MWEs</title_az>
      <title_bn>পার্সেম শেয়ার করা কাজের জন্য আইরিশে ভার্বাল এমডিউএস ঘোষণা দিচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_id>Menganotasi MWEs Verbal dalam Irlandia untuk tugas berbagi PARSEME 1.2</title_id>
      <title_ca>Anotant les MWEs verbals en irlandès per la tasca compartida PARSEME 1.2</title_ca>
      <title_bs>Annotirajući Verbal MWEs na Irsku za zajednički zadatak PARSEME 1.2</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Anotace ústních MWE v irštině pro sdílený úkol PARSEME 1.2</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Sanallisten MWE:iden huomautusten tekeminen iiriksi PARSEME Shared Task 1.2</title_fi>
      <title_et>Sõnaliste MWE märkuste tegemine iiri keeles PARSEME jagatud ülesande jaoks 1.2</title_et>
      <title_jv>Text</title_jv>
      <title_he>הערות על MWEs מילוליים באירלנית עבור משימה משותפת PARSEME 1.2</title_he>
      <title_sk>Pripombe besednih MWE v irščini za skupno nalogo PARSEME 1.2</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>Annotating Verbal MWEs in Irish for the PARSEME Shared Task 1.2</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تصف هذه الورقة إنشاء مجموعتين أيرلنديتين (مصنفتين وغير موسمتين) من أجل MWEs اللفظية لإدراجها في مهمة PARSEME المشتركة 1.2 بشأن التعريف التلقائي لـ MWE اللفظية ، وعملية تطوير فئات MWE اللفظية للأيرلندية. يتم تقديم تحليل نوعي عن المجموعتين ، جنبًا إلى جنب مع مناقشة MWEs اللفظية الأيرلندية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_fr>Cet article décrit la création de deux corpus irlandais (étiquetés et non étiquetés) pour les MWE verbaux à inclure dans la tâche partagée PARSEME 1.2 sur l'identification automatique des MWE verbaux, et le processus de développement de catégories d'EMT verbaux pour l'irlandais. Une analyse qualitative des deux corpus est présentée, ainsi qu'une discussion sur les MWE verbaux irlandais.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo descreve a criação de dois corpora irlandeses (rotulados e não rotulados) para MWEs verbais para inclusão na Tarefa Compartilhada PARSEME 1.2 sobre identificação automática de MWEs verbais e o processo de desenvolvimento de categorias de MWE verbais para irlandês. Uma análise qualitativa dos dois corpora é apresentada, juntamente com a discussão dos MWEs verbais irlandeses.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo describe la creación de dos corpus irlandeses (etiquetados y no etiquetados) para los MWE verbales para su inclusión en la Tarea Compartida 1.2 de PARSEME sobre la identificación automática de los MWE verbales, y el proceso de desarrollo de categorías de MWE verbales para el irlandés. Se presenta un análisis cualitativo de los dos cuerpos, junto con una discusión de los MWE verbales irlandeses.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>この論文では、言語MWEの自動識別に関するPARSEME Shared Task 1.2に含めるための言語MWEのための2つのアイルランドのコーポラ（ラベル付けおよび非ラベル付け）の作成、およびアイルランド人のための言語MWEカテゴリの開発プロセスについて説明します。アイルランド語の言葉によるMWEの議論とともに、2つのコーパに関する定性的分析が提示されている。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>本文述为口头MWE创立二爱尔兰语料库(标记及未标记),以包在自动识别口MWE之PARSEME共享1.2中,及为爱尔兰语开口头MWE类。 本文定性分析两语料库,并议爱尔兰语MWE。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>В настоящем документе описывается создание двух ирландских корпусов (помеченных и немаркированных) для вербальных MWE для включения в общую задачу 1.2 ПАРСЕМЕ по автоматической идентификации вербальных MWE и процесс разработки вербальных категорий MWE для ирландских. Представлен качественный анализ двух корпусов, а также обсуждение ирландских словесных MWE.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर मौखिक MWEs की स्वचालित पहचान पर PARSEME साझा कार्य 1.2 में शामिल करने के लिए मौखिक MWEs के लिए दो आयरिश कॉर्पोरेट (लेबल और बिना लेबल वाले) के निर्माण का वर्णन करता है, और आयरिश के लिए मौखिक MWE श्रेणियों को विकसित करने की प्रक्रिया। आयरिश मौखिक MWEs की चर्चा के साथ दो कॉर्पोरेट पर एक गुणात्मक विश्लेषण प्रस्तुत किया गया है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Déanann an páipéar seo cur síos ar chruthú dhá chorpora Éireannacha (lipéadaithe agus neamhlipéadaithe) do MWEanna briathartha le cur san áireamh i dTasc Comhroinnte PARSEME 1.2 ar shainaithint uathoibríoch MWEanna briathartha, agus ar an bpróiseas chun catagóirí MWE ó bhéal a fhorbairt don Ghaeilge. Cuirtear anailís cháilíochtúil ar an dá chorp i láthair, mar aon le plé ar MWEanna briathartha Gaeilge.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία περιγράφει τη δημιουργία δύο ιρλανδικών σωμάτων (επισημασμένων και μη επισημασμένων) για προφορικές MWE για ένταξη στην κοινή εργασία PARSEME 1.2 για τον αυτόματο προσδιορισμό λεκτικών MWE, και τη διαδικασία ανάπτυξης λεκτικών κατηγοριών MWE για ιρλανδικά. Παρουσιάζεται ποιοτική ανάλυση των δύο σωμάτων, καθώς και συζήτηση των ιρλανδικών προφορικών MWE.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a tanulmány bemutatja a verbális MWE-k automatikus azonosításáról szóló PARSEME Shared Task 1.2-be történő beépítését, valamint a verbális MWE kategóriák fejlesztésének folyamatát. A két korpora kvalitatív elemzését mutatjuk be, valamint az ír verbális MWE-k beszélgetését.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ეს დოკუმენტი აღწერს ორი ინერიული კოპორაის შექმნა (მარტიკური და უცნობილი) გერბალური MWEs-ის შექმნა, რომელიც PARSEME გაყოფილი დანაწილეთ დავალება 1.2. გერბალური MWEs-ის ავტომატურად განსაცნობაზე და გერბალური MW კალგატიტური ანალიზია ორი კორპორაზე, და ინერიული გერბალური MWEs-ის განსაზღვრებით.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз Вербалды MWE ортақ тапсырмасына 1. 2 ортақ тапсырмасына автоматты MWE- дерді автоматты түрде идентификациялау және Ирландия вербалды MWE категорияларының процесін құру үшін екі Ирландия корпорасын (жарлық және жарлық) құрылған Екі корпорадағы квалификациялық анализ Ирландия вербалды МВЕ талқылауымен бірге көрсетіледі.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente apibūdinamas dviejų Airijos (pažymėtų ir nenurodytų) žodinių MWEs korporai, skirti įtraukti į PARSEME bendros užduoties 1.2 dalį dėl žodinių MWEs automatinio identifikavimo, sukūrimas ir žodinių MWE kategorijų Irish kūrimo procesas. Pateikiama kokybinė dviejų korporų analizė ir diskusija apie Airijos žodinius MWEs.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo descrive la creazione di due corpora irlandesi (etichettati e non etichettati) per MWE verbali da includere nel PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 sull'identificazione automatica di MWE verbali, e il processo di sviluppo di categorie MWE verbali per l'irlandese. Viene presentata un'analisi qualitativa sui due corpi, insieme alla discussione dei MWE verbali irlandesi.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jiddeskrivi l-ħolqien ta’ żewġ korporazzjonijiet Irlandiżi (ittikkettati u mhux ittikkettati) għall-MWEs verbali għall-inklużjoni fil-Kompitu Konġunt 1.2 tal-PARSEME dwar l-identifikazzjoni awtomatika tal-MWEs verbali, u l-proċess tal-iżvilupp ta’ kategoriji verbali tal-MWE għall-Irlandiż. Hija ppreżentata analiżi kwalitattiva dwar iż-żewġ korporazzjonijiet, flimkien mad-diskussjoni dwar l-MWEs verbali Irlandiżi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>പാര്‍സെമില്‍ പങ്കുചേര്‍ത്ത ടാസ്കില്‍ ചേര്‍ക്കുവാന്‍ വേണ്ടി രണ്ട് ഐരിഷ് കോര്‍പ്പോരা (ലേബ്ലേഡ് ചെയ്തിട്ടില്ലാത്ത) സൃഷ്ടിക്കുന്നതിനായി ഈ പേപ്പറ് വിവരിക്കുന്നു ഈ രണ്ടു കോര്‍പ്പോരയില്‍ ഒരു ക്വാലിറ്റിവിലേഷന്‍ കൊണ്ടുവന്നിരിക്കുന്നു. ഐരിഷ് വാര്‍ബല്‍ എംവിഎസിനെ സംസാ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mk>This paper describes the creation of two Irish corpora (labelled and unlabelled) for verbal MWEs for inclusion in the PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 on automatic identification of verbal MWEs, and the process of developing verbal MWE categories for Irish.  Предложена е квалитетна анализа за двата капиора, заедно со дискусијата за ирските вербални МВЕ.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret beskriver opprettinga av to irske korpora (merket og ikkje merket) for verbale MWEs for inkludering i PARSEME delt oppgåve 1. 2 om automatisk identifisering av verbale MWEs, og prosessen for å utvikla verbale MWE- kategoriar for irsk. Ein kvalitativ analyse på to korporane er presentert saman med diskusjon om irske verbale MWEs.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł opisuje stworzenie dwóch irlandzkich korpusów (oznakowanych i nieoznakowanych) dla werbalnych MWE do włączenia do PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 dotyczących automatycznej identyfikacji werbalnych MWE oraz proces opracowywania werbalnych kategorii MWE dla irlandzkich. Przedstawiono analizę jakościową dwóch korpusów wraz z dyskusją irlandzkich werbalnych MWE.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ms>This paper describes the creation of two Irish corpora (labelled and unlabelled) for verbal MWEs for inclusion in the PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 on automatic identification of verbal MWEs, and the process of developing verbal MWE categories for Irish.  A qualitative analysis on the two corpora is presented, along with discussion of Irish verbal MWEs.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас PARSEME хуваалтын ажил 1.2-д автоматически MWEs-ийн хуваалтын автоматически тодорхойлолтын тухай хоёр Ирландын корпора (нэрлэгдсэн, бичигдэггүй) бүтээлийг тайлбарладаг. Хоёр корпоратын талаарх чадвартай шинжилгээ Ирландын үгийн MWEs-ийн талаар ярилцаж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare descrie crearea a două corpore irlandeze (etichetate și neetichetate) pentru MWE verbale pentru includerea în PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 privind identificarea automată a MWE verbale și procesul de dezvoltare a categoriilor verbale MWE pentru irlandezi. Este prezentată o analiză calitativă asupra celor două corpore, împreună cu discuția despre MWE verbale irlandeze.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>Name කොර්පෝරා දෙන්නෙක් ගැන පුළුවන් විශේෂ විශ්ලේෂණයක් තියෙනවා, අයිරිෂ් වර්ගල් MWE ගැන සමඟ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats beskriver skapandet av två irländska corpora (märkta och omärkta) för verbala MWE för inkluderande i PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 om automatisk identifiering av verbala MWE, och processen att utveckla verbala MWE kategorier för irländska. En kvalitativ analys av de två korporarna presenteras tillsammans med diskussion om irländska verbala MWE.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir opisuje stvaranje dva irskog korpora (označena i neopisena) za verbalne MWE za uključenje u zajednički zadatak PARSEME 1.2 o automatskoj identifikaciji verbalnih MWE-a i proces razvoja verbalnih kategorija MWE-a za irce. Predstavlja se kvalitativna analiza dva korpora, zajedno s diskusijom o Irskom verbalnom MWEs-u.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>Name இந்த இரண்டு நிறுவனத்தின் மீது ஒரு குறிப்பு ஆய்வு காண்பிக்கப்படுகிறது, ஐரிஷ் வார்ப்பு எம்விஎஸ் விவாதத்து</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>This paper describes the creation of two Irish corpora (labelled and unlabelled) for verbal MWEs for inclusion in the PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 on automatic identification of verbal MWEs, and the process of developing verbal MWE categories for Irish. ان دونوں شرکتوں کے بارے میں ایک قابل تحقیق پیش کیے جاتے ہیں، اور ایرلند کلام MWEs کی بحث کے ساتھ۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_so>Kanu wuxuu ku qoran yahay abuuridda labo shirkad ee Irish (labelled and labelled) oo lagu qoro qoraal MWEs oo lagu sharciyey shaqo la sharciyey PARSEME 1.2 oo ku saabsan aqoonsiga maamulka MWEs, iyo baaritaanka horumarinta kooxaha qoraalka MWE ee Irish. Shahaadada qiimeynta ee labada shirkad waxaa la soo bandhigaa, iyadoo la sheekaysanaya afka Irish ee MWEs.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_uz>Name Ikki kompaniya haqida qualitativ analytik, Irish verbal MWEs haqida topilmadi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này mô tả việc tạo ra hai nhóm Ái Nhĩ Lan (có nhãn và không nhãn) cho các MWEs bằng miệng để được tham gia vào công việc chia sẻ parSEME 1.2 về việc nhận diện tự động các khẩu MWE, và tiến trình phát triển các loại MWE bằng miệng cho người Ái Nhĩ Lan. Một phân tích chất lượng về hai hạ sĩ được trình bày, cùng với thảo luận về tiếng cười của Ireland.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir opisuje stvaranje dva irskog tijela (označena i neopisivana) za verbalne MWE za uključenje u zajednički zadatak PARSEME 1.2 o automatskoj identifikaciji verbalnih MWE-a i proces razvoja verbalnih MWE kategorija irca. Predstavlja se kvalitativna analiza o dvojici tijela, zajedno s raspravom o Irskom verbalnom MWEs-u.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel beschrijft de creatie van twee Ierse corpora (gelabeld en niet gelabeld) voor verbale MWE's voor opname in de PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 over automatische identificatie van verbale MWE's, en het proces van het ontwikkelen van verbale MWE-categorieën voor Iers. Een kwalitatieve analyse van de twee corpora wordt gepresenteerd, samen met discussie over Ierse verbale MWE's.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия описва създаването на две ирландски корпорации (маркирани и немаркирани) за вербални МВЗ за включване в Споделена задача 1.2 за автоматично идентифициране на вербални МВЗ и процеса на разработване на вербални категории МВЗ за ирландски. Представен е качествен анализ на двете корпорации, както и дискусия за ирландските словесни МУЗ.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel beskriver oprettelsen af to irske corpora (mærket og unlabeld) for verbale MWE til inkludering i PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 om automatisk identifikation af verbale MWE, og processen med at udvikle verbale MWE kategorier for irske. En kvalitativ analyse af de to korpora præsenteres sammen med diskussion af irske verbale MWE'er.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Diese Arbeit beschreibt die Schaffung von zwei irischen Korpora (markiert und nicht markiert) für verbale MWEs zur Aufnahme in die PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 zur automatischen Identifizierung verbaler MWEs und den Prozess der Entwicklung verbaler MWE Kategorien für Irisch. Eine qualitative Analyse der beiden Korpora wird zusammen mit der Diskussion der irischen verbalen MWEs präsentiert.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 PARSEME 공유 작업 1.2에 포함된 언어 MWE 자동 식별을 위한 두 개의 아일랜드 자료 라이브러리(라벨 및 라벨 없음)를 만들고 아일랜드어를 위한 언어 MWE 클래스를 개발하는 과정을 기술한다.본고는 이 두 개의 자료 라이브러리에 대해 정성 분석을 하고 아일랜드어 동사 MWE에 대해 토론했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ آفرینش دو شرکت ایرلند (نامیده و نامیده شده) را برای تولید کردن MWEs کلمه برای تولید در کار مشترک PARSEME ۱.۲ در مورد شناسایی خودکار MWEs کلمه و فرایند توسعه کلمه MWE کلمه برای ایرلند توصیف می‌کند. یک تحلیل کیفیت در دو شرکت، همراه با بحث سخنرانی ایرلندی MWEs، پیشنهاد می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini menggambarkan penciptaan dua korpra Irlandia (ditabel dan tidak ditabel) untuk MWEs verbal untuk memasukkan ke dalam PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 tentang identifikasi otomatis MWEs verbal, dan proses mengembangkan kategori MWE verbal untuk Irlandia. Analisis kualitatif pada kedua korpora diperkenalkan, bersama diskusi tentang MWEs verbal Irlandia.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Gazeti hili linaelezea kutengenezwa kwa kampuni mbili ya Irish (isiyotajwa na isiyotajwa) kwa ajili ya MWEs kwa ajili ya kuingia katika kazi ya PARSEME ilizoshirikishwa 1.2 kuhusu kutambuliwa kwa faragha ya MWEs, na mchakato wa kuendeleza makundi makubwa ya MWE kwa ajili ya Irish. Uchambuzi wa sifa juu ya kampuni hizo mbili unaonyeshwa, pamoja na mjadala wa lugha ya MWEs ya Ujerumani.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz iki iýrläniň korporaty (etiket edilen we ýazmaýan) verbal MWEs(etiket edilen we ýazmaýan) PARSEME Paýlaşan Görevi 1.2 we verbal MWEs awtomatik tanyýandygyny we Iýrläniň verbal MWE kategoriýasyny döwletmegini tassyýar edýär. Iki korpora bilen mykdarlyk analýusiýa, iýrläniň verbal MWEs hakynda gürleşdirilýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument përshkruan krijimin e dy korprave irlandeze (të etiketuara dhe të paetiketuara) për MWEs verbale për përfshirje në detyrën e përbashkët të PARSEME 1.2 mbi identifikimin automatik të MWEs verbale dhe procesin e zhvillimit të kategorive verbale MWE për irlandezët. A qualitative analysis on the two corpora is presented, along with discussion of Irish verbal MWEs.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier beskryf die skepping van twee Irse korpora (etiketeerde en ongeabelde) vir verbale MWEs vir inklusie in die PARSEME Gedeelde Opdrag 1. 2 op outomatiese identifikasie van verbale MWEs, en die proses van ontwikkeling van verbale MWE kategories vir Irse. 'n Kvalitatiewe analiseer op die twee korpora word voorgestel, saam met diskusie van Irse verbale MWEs.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>ይህ ፕሮግራም የኢራሪክ ኮርፖርት (በlabelled እና ያልታወቀ) መፍጠርን ለPARSEME የተሰራጨውን ስራ 1.2 በማስታወቂያው እና የኢራሪክ ብሔራዊ MWE ክፍተቶችን ለመፍጠር ይናገራል፡፡ በሁለቱ ኮፖሪያዎች ላይ የተመሳሳይ አስተያየት፣ የኢራሪሽ አበባ አሜድዩኤስ ውይይት በተቃውሞ ይታያል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Այս հոդվածը նկարագրում է երկու Իրլանդական կոպորա (պիտակ և անպիտակ) ստեղծումը արտահայտվելու համար արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտված արտահայտվ Երկու կապորանների վերաբերյալ որակային վերլուծությունը ներկայացվում է միասին Իրլանդական լեզվով ՄWE-ների քննարկումների հետ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt, PARSEME paylaşılmış Task 1.2 ilə verbal MWEs təşkil etmək üçün verbal MWE kategoriyalarını təşkil etmək üçün İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalı İrlandalıq İrlandalıqların İrlandalıq verbal MWEs müzakirələri ilə birlikdə iki korpora haqqında kvalitativ analizi göstərilir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকা দুই আইরিশ কর্পোরা তৈরি করে (চিহ্নিত এবং অচিরেই চিহ্নিত) পার্সেমে শেয়ার করা কাজ ১. আইরিশ ভার্বাল এমডিউএসএর আলোচনার সাথে এই দুই কর্পোরার বিশ্লেষণের বৈশিষ্ট্য প্রদর্শন করা হয়েছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek popisuje vytvoření dvou irských korpusů (označených a neoznačených) pro verbální MWE pro zařazení do PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 o automatické identifikaci verbálních MWE a proces vývoje verbálních MWE kategorií pro irské. Je prezentována kvalitativní analýza těchto dvou korpusů a diskuse o irských verbálních MWE.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest paper descriu la creació de dos corpores irlandès (etiquetats i no etiquetats) per a les MWEs verbals per a integrar-se a la tasca compartida PARSEME 1.2 sobre la identificació automàtica de MWEs verbals, i el procés de desenvolupament de categories MWE verbals per a l'irlandès. A qualitative analysis on the two corpora is presented, along with discussion of Irish verbal MWEs.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas dokumendis kirjeldatakse kahe iiri korpora (märgistatud ja märgistamata) loomist verbaalsete MWE-de jaoks, mis lisatakse PARSEME jagatud ülesandesse 1.2 verbaalsete MWE-de automaatse identifitseerimise kohta, ning suuliste MWE-kategooriate arendamise protsessi iiri keele jaoks. Esitatakse kahe korpuse kvalitatiivne analüüs koos Iiri verbaalsete MWE aruteludega.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa kuvataan kahden irlantilaisen korporan luomista (merkitty ja merkitsemätön) sanallisille MWE:ille sisällytettäväksi PARSEME Shared Task 1.2:een verbaalisten MWE:ien automaattisesta tunnistamisesta sekä prosessia verbaalisten MWE:n luokkien kehittämiseksi iirille. Näistä kahdesta korpusesta tehdään kvalitatiivinen analyysi sekä keskustellaan irlantilaisista suullisista MWE:istä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir opisuje stvaranje dva irskog korporacija (označena i neopisena) za verbalne MWE za uključenje u zajednički zadatak PARSEME 1.2 o automatskoj identifikaciji verbalnih MWE-a i proces razvoja verbalnih kategorija MWE-a za irce. Predstavlja se kvalitativna analiza o dvojici korporacija, zajedno s raspravom o Irskom verbalnom MWEs-u.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_sk>Ta prispevek opisuje ustvarjanje dveh irskih korpusov (označenih in neoznačenih) za verbalne MWE za vključitev v skupno nalogo PARSEME 1.2 o avtomatski identifikaciji verbalnih MWE in proces razvoja verbalnih kategorij MWE za irščino. Predstavljena je kvalitativna analiza obeh korpusov, skupaj z razpravo o irskih verbalnih MWE.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Wannan karatun na bayyana the ƙiƙiro of IIrish Corana biyu (labated and ablabated) wa verbalar MWEs wa include in the PARCEME Shared Taimar 1.2 on farat-jini na MWEs, da aikin kwamfyutan tebur masu motsa nau'in MWS wa Irish. An bãyar da wani anayya mai ƙayyade kan wannan firma biyu, sami da magana na maganar Irish MWEs.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>העיתון הזה מתאר את יצירת שני גופורות אירי (מוטבעות ולא מוטבעות) עבור MWEs מילוליים להכניס למשימה משותפת PARSEME 1.2 על זיהוי אוטומטי של MWEs מילוליים, והתהליך של פיתוח קטגוריות MWE מילוליות עבור אירי. ניתוח איכותי על שני הקופורה מוצג, יחד עם דיון על MWEs מילוליים אירי.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Name Wang alih sing dipileksi karo perusahaan sampeyan iki, dadi mêng seneng pisan kelas karo bugem sing lunak SME .</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>This paper describes the creation of two Irish corpora (labelled and unlabelled) for verbal MWEs for inclusion in the PARSEME Shared Task 1.2 on automatic identification of verbal MWEs, and the process of developing verbal MWE categories for Irish. སྒོ་འབྱེད་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་གླེང་སྡོམ་གྱི་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་དཔྱད་ཞིག</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Multi-word Expressions for Abusive Speech Detection in Serbian<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>erbian</title>
      <author><first>Ranka</first><last>Stanković</last></author>
      <author><first>Jelena</first><last>Mitrović</last></author>
      <author><first>Danka</first><last>Jokić</last></author>
      <author><first>Cvetana</first><last>Krstev</last></author>
      <pages>74–84</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents our work on the refinement and improvement of the Serbian language part of Hurtlex, a multilingual lexicon of words to hurt. We pay special attention to adding Multi-word expressions that can be seen as abusive, as such lexical entries are very important in obtaining good results in a plethora of abusive language detection tasks. We use Serbian morphological dictionaries as a basis for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_cleaning">data cleaning</a> and MWE dictionary creation. A connection to other lexical and semantic resources in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serbian_language">Serbian</a> is outlined and building of abusive language detection systems based on that connection is foreseen.</abstract>
      <url hash="1a680f61">2020.mwe-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>stankovic-etal-2020-multi</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Comparing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word2vec">word2vec</a> and GloVe for Automatic Measurement of MWE Compositionality<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>lo<fixed-case>V</fixed-case>e for Automatic Measurement of <fixed-case>MWE</fixed-case> Compositionality</title>
      <author><first>Thomas</first><last>Pickard</last></author>
      <pages>95–100</pages>
      <abstract>This paper explores the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word2vec">word2vec</a> and GloVe embeddings for unsupervised measurement of the semantic compositionality of MWE candidates. Through comparison with several human-annotated reference sets, we find <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word2vec">word2vec</a> to be substantively superior to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GloVe">GloVe</a> for this task. We also find Simple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_Wikipedia">English Wikipedia</a> to be a poor-quality resource for compositionality assessment, but demonstrate that a sample of 10 % of sentences in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_Wikipedia">English Wikipedia</a> can provide a conveniently tractable corpus with only moderate reduction in the quality of outputs.</abstract>
      <url hash="a1809f27">2020.mwe-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>pickard-2020-comparing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>MultiVitaminBooster at PARSEME Shared Task 2020 : Combining Window- and Dependency-Based Features with Multilingual Contextualised Word Embeddings for VMWE Detection<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>ulti<fixed-case>V</fixed-case>itamin<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>ooster at <fixed-case>PARSEME</fixed-case> Shared Task 2020: Combining Window- and Dependency-Based Features with Multilingual Contextualised Word Embeddings for <fixed-case>VMWE</fixed-case> Detection</title>
      <author><first>Sebastian</first><last>Gombert</last></author>
      <author><first>Sabine</first><last>Bartsch</last></author>
      <pages>149–155</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we present MultiVitaminBooster, a system implemented for the PARSEME shared task on semi-supervised identification of verbal multiword expressions-edition 1.2. For our approach, we interpret detecting verbal multiword expressions as a token classification task aiming to decide whether a token is part of a verbal multiword expression or not. For this purpose, we train <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gradient_boosting">gradient boosting-based models</a>. We encode tokens as feature vectors combining multilingual contextualized word embeddings provided by the XLM-RoBERTa language model with a more traditional linguistic feature set relying on context windows and dependency relations. Our system was ranked 7th in the official open track ranking of the shared task evaluations with an encoding-related bug distorting the results. For this reason we carry out further unofficial evaluations. Unofficial versions of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> would have achieved higher ranks.</abstract>
      <url hash="40e930c0">2020.mwe-1.20</url>
      <bibkey>gombert-bartsch-2020-multivitaminbooster</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>