<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.intexsempar">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Interactive and Executable Semantic Parsing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ben</first><last>Bogin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Srinivasan</first><last>Iyer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Victoria</first><last>Lin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dragomir</first><last>Radev</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alane</first><last>Suhr</last></editor>
      <editor><first /><last>Panupong</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Caiming</first><last>Xiong</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pengcheng</first><last>Yin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Tao</first><last>Yu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Rui</first><last>Zhang</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Victor</first><last>Zhong</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="677e9d09">2020.intexsempar-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>intexsempar-2020-interactive</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Improving Sequence-to-Sequence Semantic Parser for Task Oriented Dialog</title>
      <author><first>Chaoting</first><last>Xuan</last></author>
      <pages>18–22</pages>
      <abstract>Task Oriented Parsing (TOP) attempts to map utterances to compositional requests, including multiple intents and their slots. Previous work focus on a tree-based hierarchical meaning representation, and applying constituency parsing techniques to address TOP. In this paper, we propose a new format of meaning representation that is more compact and amenable to sequence-to-sequence (seq-to-seq) models. A simple copy-augmented seq-to-seq parser is built and evaluated over a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TOP500">public TOP dataset</a>, resulting in 3.44 % improvement over prior best seq-to-seq parser (exact match accuracy), which is also comparable to constituency parsers’ performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="190ad7b5">2020.intexsempar-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.intexsempar-1.3</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939455" />
      <bibkey>xuan-2020-improving</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/cxuan2019/top" additional="false">cxuan2019/top</pwccode>
    <title_ar>تحسين المحلل الدلالي التسلسل إلى التسلسل للحوار الموجه نحو المهام</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Amélioration de l'analyseur sémantique séquence à séquence pour les boîtes de dialogue orientées tâches</title_fr>
      <title_es>Mejora del analizador semántico secuencia a secuencia para el diálogo orientado a tareas</title_es>
      <title_pt>Aprimorando o analisador semântico de sequência a sequência para a caixa de diálogo orientada a tarefas</title_pt>
      <title_ja>タスク指向ダイアログのシーケンスツーシーケンスセマンティックパーサーの改善</title_ja>
      <title_hi>कार्य उन्मुख संवाद के लिए अनुक्रम-से-अनुक्रम सिमेंटिक पार्सर में सुधार करना</title_hi>
      <title_zh>改进向事之对话框序于序语义分析器</title_zh>
      <title_ru>Улучшение семантического анализатора последовательности к последовательности для диалогового окна, ориентированного на задачу</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Parsálaí Séimeantach Seicheamh-go-Seicheamh a Fheabhsú le haghaidh Dialóg atá Dírithe ar Thasc</title_ga>
      <title_ka>დავალების ორიენტირებული დიალოგიისთვის სემენტიკური პანელიზერი</title_ka>
      <title_el>Βελτίωση της σειριακής ανάλυσης διαδοχής σε ακολουθία για διάλογο προσανατολισμένο στην εργασία</title_el>
      <title_hu>A szekvencia-szekvencia szemantikus elemző javítása a feladatorientált párbeszédpanelen</title_hu>
      <title_it>Miglioramento dell'analisi semantica sequenziale per la finestra di dialogo orientata alle attività</title_it>
      <title_lt>Semantinio analizatoriaus, skirto užduotims orientuotam dialogui, tobulinimas iš eilės į eilę</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Подобрување на семантичкиот анализатор од секвенција до секвенција за дијалог ориентиран на задачите</title_mk>
      <title_kk>Тапсырмалар бағытталған диалогтың реттеу- және реттеу бөлшегін жақсарту</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Improving Sequence-to-Sequence Semantic Parser for Task Oriented Dialog</title_ms>
      <title_mt>It-Titjib tal-Analizzatur Semantiku minn Sekwenza għal Sekwenza għal Djalogu orjentat lejn ix-Xogħol</title_mt>
      <title_ml>പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കപ്പെട്ട ജോലിക്കുള്ള സെമാന്റിക് പാര്‍സര്‍ മുന്‍കൂട്ടുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Дараагийн дарааллаас дарааллаас дарааллаас эхлэх диалогын төлөөлөгч</title_mn>
      <title_no>Forbetra semiantisk tolking for oppgåveorientert dialog</title_no>
      <title_pl>Poprawa parasera semantycznego sekwencji do sekwencji dla dialogu zorientowanego na zadania</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Îmbunătățirea parserului semantic secvență-secvență pentru dialogul orientat spre activități</title_ro>
      <title_si>වැඩක් ප්‍රමාණය සංවාදය සඳහා ක්‍රියාක්‍රිය සෙමාන්තික විශේෂකය වැඩ කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_sr>Poboljšanje semantičkog razmatrača sekvence do sekvence za orijentirani dijalog zadataka</title_sr>
      <title_sv>Förbättra sekvens-till-sekvens semantisk tolkning för uppgiftsorienterad dialogruta</title_sv>
      <title_so>Horumarinta jardiinada Semantic-to-Semantic Parser for Task oriented Dialog</title_so>
      <title_ta>செயல் திருத்தப்பட்ட உரையாடலுக்கான வரிசையில் இருந்து வரிசைப்படுத்தல் பார்சர் மேம்படுத்தல்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>ٹاکس اوریٹ ڈیلوگر کے لئے سکوئنس-تا-سکوئنس سیمنٹی پارس</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Vazifani tahrirlash oynasi uchun davom etish</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Thay đổi dãy số thành dãy</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Verbetering van sequentie-naar-sequentie semantische parser voor taakgerichte dialoog</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Подобряване на семантичен анализ от последователност към последователност за диалогов прозорец, ориентиран към задачи</title_bg>
      <title_da>Forbedring af sekvens til sekvens semantisk fortolker til opgaveorienteret dialog</title_da>
      <title_hr>Poboljšavanje semantičkog razmatrača sekvence do sekvence za orijentirani dijalog zadataka</title_hr>
      <title_de>Verbesserung des Semantischen Parsers von Sequenz zu Sequenz für den aufgabenorientierten Dialog</title_de>
      <title_fa>بهتر کردن بازرس سطح به سطح سطح برای محاورۀ تاریخ کار</title_fa>
      <title_ko>작업 대화를 위한 시퀀스에서 시퀀스 의미 해석기까지의 개선</title_ko>
      <title_id>Menembangkan Penganalis Semantik Sekuensi-ke-Sekuensi untuk Dialog Berorientasi Tugas</title_id>
      <title_sw>Kuboresha Mfuko wa Mifuko-kwa-Mfumo wa Mifumo kwa ajili ya Dialog ya Kazi inayotengenezwa</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Task Oriented Dialog üçin yzarlama</title_tr>
      <title_af>Verbeter volgorde- na- volgorde Semantiese verwerker vir taak oriënteerde dialoog</title_af>
      <title_sq>Përmirësimi i analizuesit Semantik nga sekuenca në sekuencë për dialogun e orientuar në punë</title_sq>
      <title_am>አዲስ ዶሴ ፍጠር</title_am>
      <title_az>G칬nd톛ril톛n Dialoog 칲칞칲n S캼radan-S캼radan Semantik Parser</title_az>
      <title_hy>Improving Sequence-to-Sequence Semantic Parser for Task Oriented Dialog</title_hy>
      <title_bn>কাজ উল্লেখিত ডায়ালগের জন্য সেকেন্স- থেকে সেম্যান্ডিক পার্সার উন্নতি করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Poboljšanje semantičkog razmatrača sekvence do sekvence za orijentirani dijalog zadataka</title_bs>
      <title_ca>millorar l'analitzador Semàtic Sequence-to-Sequence per a un diàleg orientat a les tasques</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Zlepšení sémantického parseru sekvence na sekvenci pro dialog orientovaný na úkoly</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Sequence to Sequence Semanttisen Parserin parantaminen tehtäväsuuntautuneessa dialogissa</title_fi>
      <title_et>Järjest järjestusse semantilise parseri parandamine ülesannetele orienteeritud dialoogi jaoks</title_et>
      <title_jv>ProgressBarUpdates</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_he>שיפור מעבד סמנטי מעקב לעקב לדיולוגיה ממוקדת משימה</title_he>
      <title_sk>Izboljšanje semantičnega razvrščanja med zaporedji za pogovorno okno, usmerjeno v opravila</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Task Oriented Dialog ལ་ཆ་རྐྱེན་ལ་དབྱེ་རིམ་དང་ལྟར་སྔོན་མཐུན་གྱི་ཆ་ལག་སྟར་ཡར་རྒྱས་གཏོང</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>التحليل الموجه نحو المهام (TOP) يحاول تعيين الكلمات المنطوقة للطلبات التركيبية ، بما في ذلك الأهداف المتعددة وفتحاتها. يركز العمل السابق على تمثيل المعنى الهرمي المستند إلى الشجرة ، وتطبيق تقنيات تحليل الدائرة الانتخابية لمعالجة الجزء العلوي. في هذه الورقة ، نقترح تنسيقًا جديدًا لتمثيل المعنى يكون أكثر إحكاما وقابلية لنماذج التسلسل إلى التسلسل (seq-to-seq). تم إنشاء محلل بسيط من نوع seq-to-seq المعزز بالنسخ وتقييمه عبر مجموعة بيانات TOP عامة ، مما أدى إلى تحسن بنسبة 3.44٪ مقارنة بأفضل محلل seq-to-seq السابق (دقة المطابقة التامة) ، والذي يمكن مقارنته أيضًا بأداء محللي الدوائر الانتخابية .</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_fr>Task Oriented Parsing (TOP) tente de mapper les énoncés aux requêtes de composition, y compris les intentions multiples et leurs emplacements. Les travaux précédents se sont concentrés sur une représentation hiérarchique des significations basée sur l'arborescence et sur l'application de techniques d'analyse des regroupements pour traiter le TOP. Dans cet article, nous proposons un nouveau format de représentation de signification plus compact et adapté aux modèles séquence à séquence (seq-to-seq). Un analyseur seq-to-seq augmenté par copie simple est construit et évalué sur un ensemble de données TOP public, ce qui se traduit par une amélioration de 3,44 % par rapport au meilleur analyseur seq-to-seq précédent (précision de correspondance exacte), ce qui est également comparable aux performances des analyseurs de circonscription.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_pt>A Análise Orientada a Tarefas (TOP) tenta mapear enunciados para solicitações de composição, incluindo várias intenções e seus slots. Trabalhos anteriores se concentram em uma representação de significado hierárquica baseada em árvore e na aplicação de técnicas de análise de constituintes para abordar o TOP. Neste artigo, propomos um novo formato de representação de significado que é mais compacto e passível de modelos de sequência a sequência (seq-to-seq). Um simples analisador seq-to-seq com cópia aumentada é construído e avaliado em um conjunto de dados TOP público, resultando em 3,44% de melhoria em relação ao melhor analisador seq-to-seq anterior (precisão de correspondência exata), que também é comparável ao desempenho dos analisadores de constituintes .</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>El análisis orientado a tareas (TOP) intenta asignar enunciados a solicitudes de composición, incluidas múltiples intenciones y sus espacios. El trabajo anterior se centró en una representación jerárquica de significado basada en árboles y en la aplicación de técnicas de análisis de circunscripciones para abordar TOP. En este artículo, proponemos un nuevo formato de representación del significado que es más compacto y adecuado para los modelos de secuencia a secuencia (seq-to-seq). Se crea y evalúa un analizador simple de secuencia a secuencia con copia aumentada sobre un conjunto de datos TOP público, lo que resulta en una mejora del 3.44% con respecto al mejor analizador de secuencia a secuencia anterior (precisión de coincidencia exacta), que también es comparable al rendimiento de los analizadores de la unidad constitutiva.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>タスク指向分析（ TOP ）は、複数のインテントとそのスロットを含む構成的要求に発話をマッピングしようとします。これまでの研究では、ツリーベースの階層的意味表現に焦点を当て、トップアドレスに選挙区構文解析技術を適用しています。本稿では、よりコンパクトでシーケンス間（シーケンス間）モデルに適した意味表現の新しい形式を提案する。単純なコピー拡張シーケンスツーシーケンス構文解析器が構築され、パブリックトップのデータセット上で評価されるため、従来のベストなシーケンスツーシーケンス構文解析器（正確な一致精度）よりも3.44 ％改善され、これは選挙区パーサーのパフォーマンスにも匹敵します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>向事之分 (TOP) 试以语映射合请,多意及槽。 前事侧重于树之义,而以选区解析术为TOP。 于本文中,新义表式,宜式更紧,并宜序(seq-to-seq)模样。 于公共 TOP 据集上构评一简复制增 seq-to-seq 解析器,视前之最 seq-to-seq 解析器(精配精度)崇 3.44%,亦与区解析器相当。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>कार्य उन्मुख पार्सिंग (TOP) कई इरादों और उनके स्लॉट सहित रचनात्मक अनुरोधों के लिए कथनों को मैप करने का प्रयास करता है। पिछला काम एक पेड़-आधारित पदानुक्रमित अर्थ प्रतिनिधित्व पर ध्यान केंद्रित करता है, और शीर्ष को संबोधित करने के लिए निर्वाचन क्षेत्र पार्सिंग तकनीकों को लागू करता है। इस पेपर में, हम अर्थ प्रतिनिधित्व के एक नए प्रारूप का प्रस्ताव करते हैं जो अनुक्रम-से-अनुक्रम (seq-to-seq) मॉडल के लिए अधिक कॉम्पैक्ट और अनुकूल है। एक साधारण प्रतिलिपि-संवर्धित seq-to-seq पार्सर का निर्माण और मूल्यांकन एक सार्वजनिक TOP डेटासेट पर किया जाता है, जिसके परिणामस्वरूप पूर्व सर्वश्रेष्ठ seq-to-seq parser (सटीक मैच सटीकता) पर 3.44% सुधार होता है, जो निर्वाचन क्षेत्र पार्सर्स के प्रदर्शन के लिए भी तुलनीय है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Синтаксический анализ, ориентированный на задачу (TOP), пытается сопоставить фразы с композиционными запросами, включая несколько интентов и их слотов. Предыдущая работа была сосредоточена на иерархическом представлении значения на основе дерева и применении методов синтаксического анализа избирательных округов для решения ВЕРХНЕЙ ЧАСТИ. В этой статье мы предлагаем новый формат представления смысла, который является более компактным и поддающимся построению моделей последовательности к последовательности (seq-to-seq). Простой расширенный копированием парсер последовательности к последовательности построен и оценен по публичному ВЕРХНЕМУ набору данных, что приводит к улучшению на 3,44% по сравнению с предыдущим лучшим парсером последовательности к последовательности (точная точность совпадения), что также сопоставимо с производительностью парсеров избирателей.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Déanann Parsáil atá Dírithe ar Thasc (TOP) iarracht ar chainteanna maidir le hiarratais chomhdhéanaimh a mhapáil, lena n-áirítear cuspóirí iolracha agus a gcuid sliotán. Díríonn obair roimhe seo ar ionadaíocht brí ordlathach crann-bhunaithe, agus teicnící parsála toghlaigh a chur i bhfeidhm chun aghaidh a thabhairt ar BARR. Sa pháipéar seo, molaimid formáid nua de léiriú brí atá níos dlúithe agus níos so-úsáidte do mhúnlaí seicheamh-go-seicheamh (seic-go-seq). Tógtar agus measúnaítear parsálaí simplí cóip-mhéadaithe seicheamh-go-seq thar thacar sonraí poiblí TOP, rud a fhágann go bhfuil feabhas 3.44% ar an bparálaí seq-go-seq is fearr a bhí ann roimhe seo (cruinneas meaitseála beacht), atá inchomparáide le feidhmíocht parsálaithe toghlaigh freisin. .</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>მიმდინარე დაწყვეტილი პარამეტრება (TOP) მოცდილობა, რომელიც მრავალური საზოგადოებები და მათი მხოლოდ კომპოზიციალური მოთხოვრებისთვის შესახებ. პირველი სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო იერაქტიკალური ნიშნავზე დაფარდება და TOP სამუშაო სამუშაო ტექნოგიების გამოყენება. ჩვენ ამ დოკუნეში ახალი ფორმატის განსაზღვრება, რომელიც უფრო კომპექტურია და შესაძლებელია კომპექტური მოდელები (seq-to-seq). სახელსაწყოთა TOP მონაცემების სახელსაწყოთა მონაცემების შესაძლებლობა, რომელიც 3.44% უფრო უფრო უკეთესი seq- to- seq პანელიზაციაზე გააკეთებულია (მარტივი მარტივია), რომელიც კონსტუტების პანელიზაციაზე შემდგ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A feladatorientált értelmezés (TOP) megpróbálja feltérképezni a kimondásokat kompozíciós kérésekhez, beleértve a többszörös szándékot és azok résidőit. Az előző munkák egy fa alapú hierarchikus jelentésképviseletre összpontosítanak, és a választókerületi elemzési technikákat alkalmazzák a TOP kezelésére. Ebben a tanulmányban a jelentésreformáció új formátumát javasoljuk, amely sokkal kompaktabb és alkalmasabb a szekvenciától-szekvenciáig (seq-to-seq) modellekre. Egy egyszerű másolással kiegészített seq-to-seq elemzőt építenek és értékelnek egy nyilvános TOP adatkészleten, ami 3,44%-os javulást eredményez a korábbi legjobb seq-to-seq elemzőhöz képest (pontos egyezés pontossága), ami szintén hasonlítható a választókerületi elemzők teljesítményéhez.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Προσπαθεί να χαρτογραφήσει τις εκφράσεις σε συνθηματικά αιτήματα, συμπεριλαμβανομένων πολλαπλών προθέσεων και των υποδοχών τους. Προηγούμενες εργασίες επικεντρώνονται σε μια ιεραρχική αναπαράσταση νοημάτων βασισμένη σε δέντρο, και την εφαρμογή τεχνικών ανάλυσης εκλογικών περιφερειών για την αντιμετώπιση της TOP. Στην παρούσα εργασία, προτείνουμε μια νέα μορφή αναπαράστασης εννοιών που είναι πιο συμπαγής και προσιτή σε μοντέλα ακολουθίας σε ακολουθία. Ένας απλός αναλυτής Seq-to-seq κατασκευάζεται και αξιολογείται πάνω από ένα δημόσιο σύνολο δεδομένων με αποτέλεσμα 3.44% βελτίωση έναντι του προηγούμενου καλύτερου αναλυτή Seq-to-seq (ακριβής ακρίβεια αντιστοίχισης), η οποία είναι επίσης συγκρίσιμη με την απόδοση των αναλυτών εκλογικής περιφέρειας.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Task Oriented Parsing (TOP) tenta di mappare le parole alle richieste compositive, inclusi gli intenti multipli e le loro slot. I lavori precedenti si concentrano su una rappresentazione gerarchica del significato basata su alberi e sull'applicazione di tecniche di analisi delle circoscrizioni per affrontare TOP. In questo articolo, proponiamo un nuovo formato di rappresentazione del significato più compatto e suscettibile ai modelli sequenza-sequenza (seq-to-seq). Un semplice parser seq-to-seq incrementato di copia è costruito e valutato su un set di dati TOP pubblico, con conseguente miglioramento del 3,44% rispetto al precedente miglior parser seq-to-seq (precisione esatta della corrispondenza), che è anche paragonabile alle prestazioni dei parser elettorali.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Тапсырманың бағытталған талдау (TOP) сөздерін композициялық сұрауларға, бірнеше мақсаттарын және олардың слоттарын қоса, картасын көрсету әрекеті. Алдыңғы жұмыс TOP адресі үшін ағаш негіздеген иерархикалық мәліметті көрсетуге жұмыс істейді. Бұл қағаздың жаңа пішімін таңдаймыз. Бұл келесі реттеу (seq-to-seq) үлгілеріне көмектесетін және келесі үлгілерін жасаймыз. Қарапайым көшірме көшірмелеген seq- to- seq талдаушысы ашық TOP деректер жиынының арқылы құрылып бағалады. Сонымен қатар, алдыңғы ең жақсы seq- to- seq талдаушысының арқылы 3. 44% жақсы жақсартылып (дұрыс сәйкес келетін дұрыс), сон</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Task Oriented Parsing (TOP) attempts to map utterances to compositional requests, including multiple intents and their slots.  Претходната работа се фокусира на хиерархичното значење засновано на дрвото и примената на техниките за анализирање на изборните окрузи за решавање на TOP. Во овој документ предложуваме нов формат на значење претставување кој е покомпактен и способен за модели од секвенца до секвенца. Едноставен анализатор од секунда до секунда, зголемен со копија, е изграден и оценет преку јавен тоП податок, што резултира со подобрување од 3,44 отсто во однос на претходниот најдобар анализатор од секунда (точна точност на совпаѓање), што е исто така споредливо со резултатите на анализаторите од изборните</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Į užduotis orientuotas analizavimas (TOP) bando nustatyti išraiškas pagal sudėties prašymus, įskaitant kelis ketinimus ir jų laikotarpį. Ankstesniame darbe daugiausia dėmesio skiriama medienos hierarchinei reikšmei, taip pat rinkimų apygardos analizės metodų taikymui TOP spręsti. Šiame dokumente siūlome naują reikšmės reprezentacijos formą, kuri būtų kompaktiškesnė ir pritaikytinesnė prie sekos (seka-seka) modelių. Paprastas kopijomis padidintas sek-to-sek analizatorius sukuriamas ir vertinamas per viešą TOP duomenų rinkinį, todėl 3,44 proc. pagerėja ankstesnis geriausias sek-to-sek analizatorius (tikslus atitikties tikslumas), kuris taip pat yra panašus į rinkinių analizatorių rezultatus.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Penghuraian Berorientasi Tugas (TOP) cuba untuk peta ungkapan kepada permintaan komposisi, termasuk niat berbilang dan slot mereka. Kerja sebelumnya fokus pada persembahan berarti hierarkis berdasarkan pokok, dan melaksanakan teknik penghuraian konstitusi untuk alamat TOP. Dalam kertas ini, kami cadangkan format baru untuk mewakili makna yang lebih sempit dan boleh diterima untuk model urutan-ke-urutan (seterusnya-seterusnya). Penghurai sek-ke-sek ditambah-salinan sederhana dibangun dan dihalami melalui set data TOP awam, yang mengakibatkan penambahan 3.44% melalui penghurai sek-ke-sek terbaik terdahulu (ketepatan sepadan tepat), yang juga boleh dibandingkan dengan prestasi penghurai sek-ke-sek.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Il-Analiżi Orientata lejn ix-Xogħol (TOP) tipprova timmappa l-espressjonijiet għal talbiet kompożittivi, inklużi intenzjonijiet multipli u s-slots tagħhom. Il-ħidma preċedenti tiffoka fuq rappreżentazzjoni tat-tifsira ġerarkika bbażata fuq is-siġar, u tapplika tekniki ta’ analiżi tal-kostitwenzi biex tindirizza t-TOP. In this paper, we propose a new format of meaning representation that is more compact and amenable to sequence-to-sequence (seq-to-seq) models.  Jinbena u jiġi evalwat parser sempliċi b’kopja miżjuda minn sekwenza għal sekwenza fuq sett pubbliku ta’ dejta TOP, li jirriżulta f’titjib ta’ 3.44% fuq l-a ħjar parser minn sekwenza għal sekwenza minn qabel (preċiżjoni eżatta tal-qbil), li huwa wkoll komparabbli mal-prestazzjoni tal-parser tal-kostitwenza.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Тапсын ориентиролт шинжилгээ (TOP) хэлэлцээг бүтээлч хүсэлтэй, олон зорилго болон тэдний слотуудыг газрын зураг зураг хийх хичээлдэг. Өмнөх ажил нь модны үндсэн дүрслэлийн утгыг илэрхийлэх, TOP-г илэрхийлэх хэмжээсүүдийн хуваалцах технологийг ашиглах юм. Энэ цаасан дээр бид илүү компьютер болон дарааллаар дарааллаар (seq-to-seq) загварын шинэ хэлбэрийг санал болгож байна. Энгийн хувилбар нэмэгдсэн seq-to-seq хуваалцагч нь олон нийтийн TOP өгөгдлийн суурь дээр бүтээсэн ба 3.44% нь өмнө нь хамгийн сайн seq-to-seq хуваалцагч (яг тохиромжтой зөв тохиромжтой), мөн байгууллагын хуваалцагчийн үйл ажиллагаатай харьцуулсан</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Oppgåveorientert tolking (TOP) prøver å kartera uttrykk til komposisjonsførespurnader, inkludert fleire uttrykk og plassene. Førre arbeid fokuserer på eit trebasert hierarkisk meningsrepresentasjon, og brukar konstitusjonstolkingsteknikar for å adressa TOP. I denne papiret foreslår vi eit nytt format med meningsrepresentasjon som er meir komprimert og gjennomsiktig for sequence-to-sequence-modeller (seq-to-seq). Eit enkel kopi-økt seq-to-seq-tolkar er bygd og evaluert over ein offentleg TOP-dataset, som fører til at 3,44% forbetringa over førre beste seq-to-seq-tolkar (nøyaktig samsvar med nøyaktighet), som også er samanlikbar med utviklinga av konstitusjonstolkaren.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Parasowanie zorientowane na zadania (TOP) próbuje mapować wypowiedzi do żądań kompozycyjnych, w tym wiele intencji i ich slotów. Poprzednie prace skupiają się na hierarchicznej reprezentacji znaczeń opartej na drzewie oraz zastosowaniu technik parsowania okręgów wyborczych w celu rozwiązania TOP. W niniejszym artykule proponujemy nowy format reprezentacji znaczeń, który jest bardziej kompaktowy i dostępny dla modeli sekwencji do sekwencji (seq-to-seq). Prosty parser seq-to-seq jest budowany i oceniany na publicznym zbiorze danych TOP, co powoduje 3,44% poprawę w porównaniu z poprzednim najlepszym parserem seq-to-seq (dokładność dopasowania), która jest również porównywalna do wydajności parserów okręgu wyborczego.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ml>കൂട്ടത്തിലുള്ള ആവശ്യങ്ങള്‍ക്കുള്ള വാക്കുകള്‍ മാപ്പ് ചെയ്യാന്‍ ശ്രമിക്കുന്ന പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിനുള്ള പാര്‍സിങ്ങ് ചെയ മുമ്പുള്ള ജോലി ഒരു മരത്തിന്‍റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തുള്ള ഹിയേരാര്‍ക്കിക്കല്‍ അര്‍ത്ഥം പ്രതിനിധിയിലും പ്രയോഗിക്കുന്നതും ടോപി ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ ഒരു പുതിയ രീതിയില്‍ പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. അത് കൂടുതല്‍ സമ്പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായും കൂടുതല്‍ സംവിധാനത്തിന്റെ മാതൃകങ്ങള്‍ക് ഒരു പൊതുവായ ടോപി ഡാറ്റാസെറ്റില്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കപ്പെട്ട സെക്ക്- സെക്ക്- സെക്ക് പരാജയപ്പെടുത്തുന്ന ഒരു ലളിതമായ പകര്‍പ്പ്- കൂട്ടിച്ചേര്‍ത്ത സെക്ക്- സെക്ക് പരാജയപ്രകാര</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_ro>Interpretarea orientată spre activități (TOP) încearcă să mapeze pronunțările la cererile compoziționale, inclusiv intențiile multiple și sloturile acestora. Lucrările anterioare se concentrează pe o reprezentare ierarhică a semnificației bazată pe arbori și aplicarea tehnicilor de analizare a circumscripției pentru a aborda TOP. În această lucrare, propunem un nou format de reprezentare a semnificației, care este mai compact și supus modelelor secvență-la-secvență (seq-to-seq). Un simplu parser seq-to-seq amplificat de copie este construit și evaluat pe baza unui set de date TOP public, rezultând o îmbunătățire de 3,44% față de cel mai bun parser seq-to-seq anterior (precizia potrivirii exacte), care este, de asemenea, comparabil cu performanța parserilor de circumscripție.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Ориентиран проучање задача (TOP) покушава да картају речи на композиционне заяве, включујући много намере и их места. Prethodni rad se fokusirao na hijerarhičko značenje na drvetu i primjenjivanje tehnika za analizu predstava za obraćanje TOP-a. U ovom papiru predlažemo novi format predstavljanja značenja koji je kompaktniji i prilagodljiviji modelima sekvence do sekvence (seq-to-seq). Postavlja se i procjenjuje jednostavno povećan analizator sek-to-seq na javnom setu podataka TOP, što je rezultiralo da je poboljšanje od 3,44% preko prethodnog najboljeg analizatora sek-to-seq (to čna tačnost odgovara), što je takođe usporedno i sa učinkovitosti parser a konstitucija.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>කාර්ය සිද්ධිත විශ්ලේෂණය (TOP) පරීක්ෂණය සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ස්ථානය සම්පූර්ණය සඳහා ක්‍රියාත්මක විශ්ලේෂණය ස මුලින් වැඩක් අධාරිත වර්ගයක් අදහස් කරලා තියෙන්න, සහ TOP විශ්වාස කරන්න ප්‍රධාන විශ්ලේෂණ විශ්ලේෂණ මේ පත්තරේ අපි අළුත් වින්යාසයක් ප්‍රසිද්ධා කරන්න පුළුවන් වෙනවා, ඒක තරම් සම්පූර්ණය සහ සම්පූර්ණයි (seq-to-seq) පත්තර සාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රතිලිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළි</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Jardiinooyinka shaqada (TOP) wuxuu isku dayaa in uu karo hadal ku saabsan codsiga kooxaha ah, kuwaas oo ku jira qalabka kala duduwan iyo jagadaha. Shaqo hore wuxuu focus on a tree-based hierarchical meaning representation, and codsanayaa techniques parsing si ay TOP u address. Qoraalkan waxaynu soo jeedaynaa qaab cusub oo macluumaad ah, kaas oo aad u wada xidhan tahay iyo mid u suurtagal tusaalayaasha xilliga (seq-to-seq). Waxaa la dhisay oo lagu qiimeeyaa koobiyo-koox-to-seq baaritaankeeda oo fudud, taasoo ka horeysa 3.44% hagaajinta horumarinta ugu wanaagsan seq-to-seq Parser (exact match accuracy), kaasoo sidoo kale u eg sameynta sameynta baarlareyaasha.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Task Oriented Parsing (TOP) fﾃｶrsﾃｶker kartlﾃ､gga yttranden till kompositionsfﾃｶrfrﾃ･gningar, inklusive flera intentioner och deras platser. Tidigare arbete fokuserar pﾃ･ en trﾃ､dbaserad hierarkisk betydelserepresentation och tillﾃ､mpar valkretstolkningstekniker fﾃｶr att adressera TOP. I denna uppsats fﾃｶreslﾃ･r vi ett nytt format av betydelserepresentation som ﾃ､r mer kompakt och mottagligt fﾃｶr sekvens-till-sekvens (sekvens-till-sekvens) modeller. En enkel copy-augmented seq-to-seq parser byggs och utvﾃ､rderas ﾃｶver en publik TOP dataset, vilket resulterar i 3,44% fﾃｶrbﾃ､ttring jﾃ､mfﾃｶrt med tidigare bﾃ､sta seq-to-seq parser (exakt matchningsnoggrannhet), vilket ocksﾃ･ ﾃ､r jﾃ､mfﾃｶrbart med valkrets parsers prestanda.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>کام Oriented Parsing (TOP) کی کوشش کرتی ہے کہ کلمات کو کامپیوتنی خواہشات میں نقشه بنانے کی کوشش کرتی ہے۔ پیچھے کام ایک درخت پر بنیاد رکھی ہوئی ہیرارشیک معنی نمایش پر تمرکز کر رہی ہے اور ٹوپ کے بارے میں کامستونٹ پارسینگ ٹیکنالوجی کا استعمال کرتا ہے. اس کاغذ میں ہم نے ایک نوی فرمود کی پیشنهاد کرتی ہے جو زیادہ پیچیدہ ہے اور اس کے ذریعہ سے آسان ہے۔ ایک ساده کپی-اضافہ کی سq-to-seq پارچر بنایا گیا ہے اور ایک عمومی TOP ڈاٹسٹ پر ارزش کیا گیا ہے، اس کے نتیجہ میں 3.44% اگلوں سے بہترین سq-to-seq پارچر (دقیق مطابق مطابق) کے مطابق اضافہ ہوتا ہے، اور یہ کامیٹنسیٹ پارچر کے کام سے بھی</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>கூட்ட கோரிக்கைகளுக்கான வார்த்தைகளை வரைபடத்தின் முயற்சி செய்கிறது, பல விருப்பங்களும் மற்றும் செருகுவாய்க்கைகளும முந்தைய வேலை ஒரு மரத்தில் அடிப்படையில் உள்ள hierarchical meaning representation, மற்றும் TOP முகவரிப்பாட்டு பாகிங் தொழில்நுட்பத்தை பயன்படுத் இந்த காகிதத்தில், நாம் ஒரு புதிய வடிவத்தின் பார்வையை பரிந்துரைக்கிறோம். அது மிகவும் ஒப்புக்கொண்டுள்ளது மற்றும் பின்வரும் தொடர் ஒரு சுலபமான நகல்- கூட்டப்பட்ட பொது TOP தரவுத்தளத்திற்கு மேல் உருவாக்கப்பட்டு மதிப்பிடப்படுகிறது, முன்னால் 3. 44% மேம்படுத்தப்படுகிறது சிறந்த த துண்டு- துண்டு மதிப்பு (சரிபார்த</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Name Name Bu hujjatda, biz yangi tashkilotni tahrirlash imkoniyatini taqdimiz. Bu bir qanday murakkab bo'lgan va seksiz modellariga (seq-to-seq) oʻrnatish mumkin. Name</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Nhiệm vụ Google Parsons (TOP) đã tìm ra bản đồ cho các yêu cầu liên kết, bao gồm nhiều mục đích và các khe hở của chúng. Trước đây, tập trung vào một đại diện cấp dưới gốc cây, và sử dụng các kỹ thuật phân tích bầu cử để đối phó với TOP. Trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi đề xuất một định dạng mới của mô tả có ý nghĩa gọn hơn và thích hợp với các mô hình lặp lại (dãy-tới-seq) hơn. Một bộ phân tách đơn giản được cải tạo thành một nhà phân tích cách đặc biệt, được xây dựng và đánh giá qua một bộ dữ liệu TOP công cộng, dẫn tới 3.44+ cải tiến tiến hơn chính xác phân tích cách biệt biệt, cũng tương đương với khả năng của phân tích phân tích bầu cử.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Опитва се да картографира изказванията до искания за композиция, включително множество намерения и техните слотове. Предишната работа се фокусира върху дървобазирано йерархично представяне на значението и прилагане на техники за анализ на избирателните райони за адресиране на ТОП. В настоящата статия предлагаме нов формат на представяне на смисъла, който е по-компактен и податлив на модели последователност към последователност (от-до-последователност). Прост анализатор на сек-до-сек се изгражда и оценява върху публичен TOP набор от данни, което води до 3,44% подобрение спрямо предишния най-добър анализатор на сек-до-сек (точност на съвпадението), което също е сравнимо с производителността на избирателните анализатори.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Task Oriented Parsing (TOP) probeert uitingen in kaart te brengen aan compositionele verzoeken, inclusief meerdere intenties en hun slots. Eerder werk concentreerde zich op een boomgebaseerde hiërarchische betekenisrepresentatie, en het toepassen van kiesdistrict parsing technieken om TOP aan te pakken. In dit artikel stellen we een nieuw formaat voor van betekenisweergave voor dat compacter is en vatbaarder is voor seq-to-seq modellen. Een eenvoudige copy-augmented seq-to-seq parser wordt gebouwd en geëvalueerd over een openbare TOP dataset, wat resulteert in 3,44% verbetering ten opzichte van eerdere beste seq-to-seq parser (exacte matchnauwkeurigheid), die ook vergelijkbaar is met de prestaties van kiesdistrict parsers.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Opgaveorienteret fortolkning (TOP) forsøger at kortlægge udtalelser til kompositionelle anmodninger, herunder flere hensigter og deres slots. Tidligere arbejde fokuserer på en træbaseret hierarkisk betydning repræsentation, og anvender valgkreds parsing teknikker til at adressere TOP. I denne artikel foreslår vi et nyt format af betydning repræsentation, der er mere kompakt og tilgængelig for sekvens-til-sekvens (sekvens-til-sekvens) modeller. En simpel copy-augmented seq-to-seq parser er bygget og evalueret over et offentligt TOP datasæt, hvilket resulterer i 3,44% forbedring i forhold til tidligere bedste seq-to-seq parser (præcis match nøjagtighed), hvilket også er sammenligneligt med valgkreds parsers præstation.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Zapovjednički proračun (TOP) pokušava mapirati izraze na sastavne zahtjeve, uključujući višestruke namjere i njihove mjesta. Prethodni rad usredotoči se na hijerarhičko značenje na drvetu i primjenjivanje tehnika za analiziranje područja za rješavanje TOP-a. U ovom papiru predlažemo novi oblik zastupanja značenja koji je kompaktniji i prilagodljiviji modelima sekvence do sekvence (seq-to-seq). Postavlja se i procjenjuje jednostavno povećan analizator sek-to-seq na javnom setu podataka TOP-a, što je rezultiralo poboljšanje od 3,44% preko prethodnog najboljeg analizatora sek-to-seq-a (to čna točnost odgovara), što je također usporedno i s učinkovitosti analizatora kompitucija.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_id>Analisasi Orientasi Tugas (TOP) mencoba untuk memetakan ungkapan ke permintaan komposisi, termasuk tujuan berbilang dan slots mereka. Pekerjaan sebelumnya fokus pada persembahan berarti hierarkis berdasarkan pohon, dan menerapkan teknik penghuraian konstitusi untuk mengatasi TOP. Dalam kertas ini, kami mengusulkan format baru dari persembahan arti yang lebih kompakt dan mudah untuk model urutan-ke-urutan (sek-ke-sek). Sebuah parser seq-to-seq yang ditambah dengan salinan sederhana dibangun dan dievaluasi melalui set data TOP publik, yang berasal dari 3,44% peningkatan atas parser seq-to-seq terbaik sebelumnya (persis persamaan), yang juga dapat dibandingkan dengan prestasi parser konstitusi.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Task Oriented Parsing (TOP) versucht, Äußerungen kompositorischen Anforderungen zuzuordnen, einschließlich mehrerer Intents und deren Slots. Bisherige Arbeiten konzentrierten sich auf eine baumbasierte hierarchische Bedeutungsrepräsentation und die Anwendung von Wahlkreisparsing-Techniken, um TOP zu adressieren. In diesem Beitrag schlagen wir ein neues Format der Bedeutungsdarstellung vor, das kompakter und zugänglicher für Sequenz-zu-Sequenz (seq-to-seq) Modelle ist. Ein einfacher copy-augmented seq-to-seq-Parser wird über einen öffentlichen TOP-Datensatz erstellt und ausgewertet, was zu einer 3,44% Verbesserung gegenüber dem vorherigen besten seq-to-seq-Parser (exakte Übereinstimmung Genauigkeit) führt, die auch mit der Leistung von Wahlkreis-Parsern vergleichbar ist.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>작업에 대한 분석(TOP)은 여러 의도와 간격을 포함하여 합성 요청에 말을 비추려고 합니다.이전의 업무 중점은 나무의 차원적 의미 표시를 바탕으로 선택 영역 분석 기술을 응용하여 최상의 문제를 해결하는 것이다.본고에서 우리는 새로운 의미 표시 형식을 제시했는데 이것은 더욱 치밀하고 순서대순(seq-to-seq) 모델에 더욱 적합하다.공공 최고급 데이터 집합에 간단한 복사 강화된 seq-to-seq 해상도를 구축하고 평가했는데 이전의 가장 좋은 seq-to-seq 해상도(정밀 일치 정밀도)에 비해 이 해상도의 성능은 3.44% 높아졌고 선택 영역 해상도와 비슷했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Jaribio la Uchaguzi wa kazi (TOP) linajaribu kusambaza hotuba kwa ajili ya maombi ya viwanda, ikiwa ni pamoja na malengo mengi na kurasa zao. Kazi iliyopita imejikita kwenye maana ya maarufu yenye mti, na kutumia mbinu za kuomba jimbo kwa ajili ya TOP. Katika karatasi hii, tunapendekeza namna mpya ya uwakilishi wa maana ambayo ni makubaliano zaidi na yenye uwezekano wa mifano ya mfululizo (sekta-hadi-sekunde). Anachambua chenye nakala rahisi iliyoandaliwa kwa ngono-mpaka-seq unajengwa na kutathmini zaidi ya seti ya data za umma ya TOP, na kusababisha maboresho ya asilimia 3.44 zaidi ya kabla ya mazingira bora ya ngono na seq (sawa na uhakika), ambayo pia inafanana na utendaji wa mabunge.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Taýýarlanan Taýýarlama (TOP) sözlerini compositional isteklere görkezmäge synanyşýar, birnäçe niýetleri we ýerlerini görkezmäge synanyşýar. Öňki işe TOP adresini görkezmek üçin agaç tabanly iýerarhiýaly umytlarynda fokus edýär. Bu kağıt içinde, daha düzgün ve sıralanabilen bir ifade şeklini teklif ediyoruz. Basit bir nusga eklenýän seq-to-seq täzeledi we jemi bir TOP veri setirinden çykarylýar. Öňki 3.44% seq-to-seq täzelediginden öňki iň gowy bir nusga täzeledi (dogry eşiklik we dogry ýagdaýy) täzeledi. Bu hem constituency parsatçylaryň eserini görä gabdalýar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_fa>تلاش پیدا کردن (TOP) تاریخی برای نقشه کردن کلمات به درخواست‌های ترکیب، شامل تعدادی از هدف‌های متعدد و نقطه‌هایشان است. کارهای قبلی روی نمایش معنای معنای درخت بر اساس درخت تمرکز می‌کند، و تکنیک‌های تقسیم نمایش نمایش نمایش نمایش نمایش نمایش نمایش نمایش نمایش نمایش‌های نمایش برای آدرس TOP در این کاغذ، ما یک قالب جدید از معنی معنی پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که برای مدل‌های sequence-to-seq (seq-to-seq) بسیار پیچیده‌تر است. تقسیم‌کننده‌ی سq-to-seq بسیار ساده‌ای بر روی مجموعه داده‌های TOP عمومی ساخته می‌شود و ارزیابی می‌شود، به نتیجه بهترین تقسیم‌کننده‌ی seq-to-seq (دقیقاً مسابقه‌ی مسابقه‌ای) که همچنین قابل مقایسه با انجام‌دهنده‌های تقسیم‌کننده‌های محی</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Opdrag Orienteerde verwerking (TOP) probeer na kaart uitdrukkings na komposisiese versoeke, insluitend veelvuldige doels en hulle plekke. Vorige werk fokus op 'n boom-gebaseerde hierarkies betekening voorsien en toepassing van konstituency verwerking tekniks na adres TOP. In hierdie papier, voorstel ons 'n nuwe formaat van betekening voorstelling wat meer kompakte en amenable is om sekwensie-na-sekwensie (seq-to-seq) modele te stel. 'n Eenvoudige kopie-augmenteerde seq-to-seq ontleerder is gebou en evalueer oor 'n publieke TOP-datastel, wat resultaat in 3.44% verbetering oor vooraf beste seq-to-seq ontleerder (presies ooreenkomstigheid), wat is ook vergelykbaar met die opstelling ontleerders se prestasie.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>አድራሻ የቀድሞው ስራ በዛፍ-based hierarchical meaning አካባቢ ላይ ትኩረት እና የመስመር ምርጫዎች ለTOP ማድረግ ጥያቄዎችን ለመጠቀም ነው፡፡ በዚህ ካላት አዲስ መልዕክት፣ አዲስ መልዕክት ማሳየት እና ማሰናከል እና ማሰናከል እና በቁጥር (seq-to-seq) ሞዴላዎችን ለመስጠት እናስባለን፡፡ የቀላል ኮፒ-ተጨማሪ የsex-to-seq ምርጫው የተገነባ እና በተመሳሳይ የTOP ዳታተር ሰርቨርስቲ ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Görüş Orientli Səfləmə (TOP) sözlərini kompozisyonal istəklərinə xəbərdar etmək istəyir, çoxlu niyyətləri və yerlərini də dahil edər. Əvvəlki işlər, a ğac tabanlı hiyerarşik anlamının göstəricisi və TOP-a istifadə etmək üçün dəstək ayırma tekniklərini uygulayır. Bu kağızda, daha kompakt və seq-to-seq modellərinin yeni formasını təbliğ edirik. Basit kopya-to-seq ayırıcı in şa edilir və halkı TOP veri qutusu üzərində değerlendirilir. Bu, 3.44% daha öncə seq-to-seq ayırıcısının ən yaxşısının üstündə (tam uyğunluğu ilə uyğunluğu ilə) daha yaxşılaşdırılır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_sq>Analizimi i orientuar në detyrë (TOP) përpiqet të hartojë shprehjet ndaj kërkesave kompozitive, duke përfshirë qëllime të shumta dhe kohët e tyre. Puna e mëparshme përqëndrohet në një përfaqësim të kuptimit hierarkik bazuar në pemë dhe zbatimin e teknikave të analizimit të qarkut zgjedhor për të trajtuar TOP. Në këtë letër, propozojmë një format të ri përfaqësimi të kuptimit që është më kompakt dhe më i përshtatshëm për modelet sekuencë-në-sekuencë. Një analizues i thjeshtë të shtuar me kopje nga pas është ndërtuar dhe vlerësuar nëpërmjet një grupi të dhënash publike TOP, që rezulton në 3.44% përmirësim mbi analizuesin më të mirë të mëparshëm nga pas në pas (saktësia e përputhjes), që është gjithashtu e krahasueshme me performancën e analizuesve të qarkut zgjedhor.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Խնդիրներին ուղղված վերլուծությունը (TOP) փորձում է քարտեզագրել բաղադրական խնդրանքների արտահայտությունները, ներառյալ բազմաթիվ մտադրությունները և դրանց վայրերը: Անցյալ աշխատանքը կենտրոնացնում է ծառի հիերարխիկ նշանակության ներկայացման վրա, և օգտագործում է ընտրական շրջանների վերլուծության մեթոդներ TOP-ի լուծման համար: Այս թղթի մեջ մենք առաջարկում ենք նոր նշանակության ներկայացման ձևեր, որը ավելի խիստ է և ավելի հարմար է հաջորդականության մոդելներին: Սկզբում կառուցվում է և գնահատվում ընդհանուր TOP տվյալների համակարգի միջոցով մի պարզ վերարտադրող, որը հանդիսանում է 3.44 տոկոսի բարելավում նախկինում ամենալավ վերարտադրողի համեմատ (ճշգրիտ համապատասխանություն), ինչը նույնպես համեմատուկ է ընտրական համեմատակի վերարտադրողների արտադրող</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>কাজ উল্লেখযোগ্য অনুরোধের মানচিত্রে বক্তৃতা মানচিত্রের চেষ্টা করছে, যার মধ্যে রয়েছে বেশ কয়েকটি উদ্দেশ্য এবং স্লোট। পূর্ববর্তী কাজ একটি গাছের ভিত্তিক হিয়ারার্কিল মানে প্রতিনিধিত্বের উপর মনোযোগ আকর্ষণ করে এবং টোপির ঠিকানা করার জন্য সংসদ এই কাগজটিতে আমরা নতুন একটি বিন্যাস প্রস্তাব করছি মানে প্রতিনিধিত্বের মানে যা আরো কপ্টেক্ট এবং সেকেন্সের (যৌক্তি-থেকে সেকেক) মডেলে একটি সাধারণ কপি-অ্যাগমেন্ট-সেক ব্যবহারকারী একটি পাবলিক টোপি ডাটাসেটের উপর তৈরি এবং মূল্যায়ন করা হয়েছে, যার ফলে সেরা সেক্ষেত্র-সেক প্যারাসারের অনুষ্ঠানের পূর্বে ৩.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Pokušavaju da mapiraju izraze na kompozicionalne zahtjeve, uključujući višestruke namjere i njihove mjesta. Prethodni rad se fokusirao na hijerarhičko značenje na drvetu i primjenjivanje tehnika za analizu predstava za obraćanje TOP-a. U ovom papiru predlažemo novi format predstavljanja značenja koji je kompaktniji i prilagodljiviji modelima sekvence do sekvence (seq-to-seq). Postavlja se i procjenjuje jednostavno povećan analizator sek-to-seq na javnom setu podataka TOP-a, što je rezultiralo poboljšanje od 3,44% preko prethodnog najboljeg analizatora sek-to-seq (to čna točnost odgovara), što je također usporedno i s učinkovitosti analizatora konstitucija.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Úlohově orientované parsování (TOP) se pokouší mapovat výroky na kompoziční požadavky, včetně více záměrů a jejich slotů. Předchozí práce se zaměřuje na stromově založenou hierarchickou reprezentaci významů a aplikaci technik analýzy volebních okresů k řešení TOP. V tomto článku navrhujeme nový formát reprezentace významů, který je kompaktnější a přístupnější modelům sekvence na sekvenci (seq-to-seq). Jednoduchý kopírováním rozšířený parser seq-to-seq je sestaven a vyhodnocován na veřejné TOP datové sadě, což vede k 3,44% zlepšení oproti předchozímu nejlepšímu parseru seq-seq (přesnost shody), které je rovněž srovnatelné s výkonem parserů volebních okresů.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Task Oriented Parsing (TOP) pﾃｼﾃｼab kaardistada vﾃ､ljendeid kompositsioonipﾃ､ringutele, sealhulgas mitmetele kavatsustele ja nende pesadele. Varasemad tﾃｶﾃｶd keskenduvad puupﾃｵhisele hierarhilisele tﾃ､henduse esitamisele ja valimisringkonna parsimise meetodite rakendamisele TOP-i lahendamiseks. Kﾃ､esolevas tﾃｶﾃｶs pakume vﾃ､lja uue tﾃ､hendusvormi, mis on kompaktsem ja vﾃｵimalik jﾃ､rjestusest jﾃ､rjestuseni (seq-to-seq) mudelitele. Lihtne kopeeritud tﾃ､iendatud sek-sek parser ehitatakse ja hinnatakse avaliku TOP andmekogumi pﾃｵhjal, mille tulemuseks on 3,44% parem sek-sek parser vﾃｵrreldes varasema parima sek-sek parser (tﾃ､pne vaste tﾃ､psus), mis on vﾃｵrreldav ka valimisringkonna parserite jﾃｵudlusega.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ca>L'analització orientada a les tasques (TOP) intenta mapejar les expressions a les peticions de composició, incloent múltiples intencions i els seus slots. La feina anterior es centra en una representació de significats jeràrquics basada en arbres, i aplicant tècniques d'analització electoral per abordar el TOP. In this paper, we propose a new format of meaning representation that is more compact and amenable to sequence-to-sequence (seq-to-seq) models.  Un simple analitzador seq-to-seq augmentat amb còpia es construeix i es valora a través d'un conjunt de dades TOP públic, resultant en una millora del 3,44% en comparació amb el millor analitzador seq-to-seq anterior (precisió exacta de la coincidencia), que també és comparable amb el rendiment dels analitzadors electorals.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Tehtäväorientoitunut parsing (TOP) yrittää kartoittaa lauseet sävellyspyyntöihin, mukaan lukien useat tarkoitukset ja niiden paikat. Aiemmat työt keskittyvät puupohjaiseen hierarkkiseen merkityksen esittämiseen ja vaalipiirin jäsentelytekniikoiden soveltamiseen TOP:n käsittelemiseen. Tässä työssä ehdotamme uutta merkityksen esittämisen muotoa, joka on kompaktimpi ja mukautuvampi sekvenssimalleille (seq-seq). Yksinkertainen kopioitu seq-to-seq-parser rakennetaan ja arvioidaan julkisen TOP-datajoukon päälle, mikä johtaa 3,44% parannukseen verrattuna edelliseen parhaaseen seq-to-seq-parser (tarkka osuman tarkkuus), joka on myös verrattavissa vaalipiirin parserien suorituskykyyn.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>task Oriented Laptop" and "Desktop Nang pember iki, kita enyester sistem anyar sing dibunaké ning titik dhéwé basa sing kompak lan nambah kanggo modelan seq-to-seq (seq-to-seq). Una seneng copy-agemented seq-to</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>המחקר המיועד למשימות (TOP) מנסה למפות את הצהרות לבקשות המרכיבות, כולל כוונות רבות והמקומות שלהם. העבודה הקודמת מתמקדת באמצעות מייצג הייררכי של משמעות על עצים, והשתמשת בטכניקות אבחנה במחוז הבחיר כדי להתייחס לטופס TOP. בעיתון הזה, אנו מציעים פורמט חדש של מייצג משמעות שיותר kompact ומתאים למודלים רצף-לרצף. מערכת מערכת נתונים TOP ציבורית נובנה ומערכה מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכת מערכ</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Opravilo usmerjeno razčlenjanje (TOP) poskuša kartirati izjave na zahteve za kompozicijo, vključno z več nameni in njihovimi režami. Predhodno delo se osredotoča na drevesno hierarhično predstavitev pomena in uporabo tehnik razčlenjanja volilnih okrožij za naslov TOP. V prispevku predlagamo nov format predstavitve pomena, ki je bolj kompakten in primeren za modele zaporedja v zaporedje (seq-to-seq). Preprost razčlenjevalnik seq-to-sek je zgrajen in ocenjen na javnem naboru TOP podatkov, kar ima za posledico 3,44% izboljšanje v primerjavi s prejšnjim najboljšim razčlenjevalnikom seq-to-sek (natančnost natančnega ujemanja), kar je primerljivo tudi z zmogljivostjo razčlenjevalcev volilnih okrožij.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>KCharselect unicode block name @ action: button Ga wannan takardan, Munã buɗe wani tsari na tsari na fassarar muhalli da za'a sami mafi kamata kuma masu iya daidaita zuwa-sequence (seq-to-seq). An samar da wani nau'in kofi-ƙari ga-seq Paramer aka samar da shi kuma an ƙaddara shi a kan tsarin umalum na TOP, mai yiwuwa ya ƙara sigar 3.44% da ya fi kyau a gaba ga mafi kyaun seq-zuwa-seq Paramer (daidai da lissafi), da kuma yana daidai da aikin parser.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ལས་ཀ་འདི་སྔོན་ལྟེ་ཡོད་པའི་བསམ་བློ་ཞིབ་པ(TOP)ཡི་སྒྲ་ཚིགས་ནང་གི་ཐ་སྙད་རིས་འབྲི་བ་དང་ཁོང་གི་ས་གནས་སྟངས་འདི་དག་འབ སྔོན་མའི་ལས་ཀ་དེ་ལྟར་གཞི་བཙུགས་ཡོད་པའི་དབུས་ཡུལ་གནས་ཚུལ་གྱི་གནས་སྟངས་དང་མཉམ་དུ་སྤྲོད་པ་constituency parsing techniques to address TOP In this paper, we propose a new format of meaning representation that is more compact and amenable to sequence-to-sequence (seq-to-seq) models. A simple copy-augmented seq-to-seq parser is built and evaluated over a public TOP dataset, resulting in 3.44% improvement over prior seq-to-seq parser (exact match accuracy), which is also comparable to constituency parsers' performance.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>ColloQL : Robust Text-to-SQL Over Search Queries<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ollo<fixed-case>QL</fixed-case>: Robust Text-to-<fixed-case>SQL</fixed-case> Over Search Queries</title>
      <author><first>Karthik</first><last>Radhakrishnan</last></author>
      <author><first>Arvind</first><last>Srikantan</last></author>
      <author><first>Xi Victoria</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <pages>34–45</pages>
      <abstract>Translating natural language utterances to executable queries is a helpful technique in making the vast amount of data stored in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relational_database">relational databases</a> accessible to a wider range of non-tech-savvy end users. Prior work in this area has largely focused on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_(literary_theory)">textual input</a> that is linguistically correct and semantically unambiguous. However, real-world user queries are often succinct, colloquial, and noisy, resembling the input of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_search_engine">search engine</a>. In this work, we introduce data augmentation techniques and a sampling-based content-aware BERT model (ColloQL) to achieve robust text-to-SQL modeling over natural language search (NLS) questions. Due to the lack of evaluation data, we curate a new dataset of NLS questions and demonstrate the efficacy of our approach. ColloQL’s superior performance extends to well-formed text, achieving an 84.9 % (logical) and 90.7 % (execution) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> on the WikiSQL dataset, making it, to the best of our knowledge, the highest performing model that does not use execution guided decoding.</abstract>
      <url hash="a7835a2c">2020.intexsempar-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.intexsempar-1.5</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939457" />
      <bibkey>radhakrishnan-etal-2020-colloql</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/karthikradhakrishnan96/ColloQL" additional="false">karthikradhakrishnan96/ColloQL</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wikisql">WikiSQL</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>