<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.dmr">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Second International Workshop on Designing Meaning Representations</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Nianwen</first><last>Xue</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Johan</first><last>Bos</last></editor>
      <editor><first>William</first><last>Croft</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jan</first><last>Hajič</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Chu-Ren</first><last>Huang</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Stephan</first><last>Oepen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Martha</first><last>Palmer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>James</first><last>Pustejovsky</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona Spain (online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="4276e725">2020.dmr-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>dmr-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Cross-lingual annotation : a road map for low- and no-resource languages</title>
      <author><first>Meagan</first><last>Vigus</last></author>
      <author><first>Jens E. L.</first><last>Van Gysel</last></author>
      <author><first>Tim</first><last>O’Gorman</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrew</first><last>Cowell</last></author>
      <author><first>Rosa</first><last>Vallejos</last></author>
      <author><first>William</first><last>Croft</last></author>
      <pages>30–40</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Road_map">road map</a> for the annotation of semantic categories in typologically diverse languages, with potentially few linguistic resources, and often no existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_resource">computational resources</a>. Past <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_annotation">semantic annotation</a> efforts have focused largely on high-resource languages, or relatively low-resource languages with a large number of native speakers. However, there are certain typological traits, namely the synthesis of multiple concepts into a single word, that are more common in languages with a smaller speech community. For example, what is expressed as a sentence in a more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analytic_language">analytic language</a> like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, may be expressed as a single word in a more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synthetic_language">synthetic language</a> like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arapaho_language">Arapaho</a>. This paper proposes solutions for annotating analytic and synthetic languages in a comparable way based on existing typological research, and introduces a road map for the annotation of languages with a dearth of resources.</abstract>
      <url hash="305a3f9b">2020.dmr-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>vigus-etal-2020-cross</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Anotação multilíngue: um roteiro para idiomas com poucos e sem recursos</title_pt>
      <title_ar>التعليق التوضيحي متعدد اللغات: خارطة طريق للغات منخفضة الموارد وعديمة الموارد</title_ar>
      <title_es>Anotación multilingüe: una hoja de ruta para idiomas con pocos recursos o sin recursos</title_es>
      <title_fr>Annotation multilingue : feuille de route pour les langues à faibles ressources et sans ressources</title_fr>
      <title_zh>跨语注:低资源语言、无资言之路线图</title_zh>
      <title_ja>クロスリンガルアノテーション：低リソース言語と非リソース言語のためのロードマップ</title_ja>
      <title_hi>क्रॉस-भाषी एनोटेशन: कम और बिना संसाधन वाली भाषाओं के लिए एक रोड मैप</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Кросс-лингвистическая аннотация: дорожная карта для языков с низким и нулевым объемом ресурсов</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Nóta tras-teangach: léarscáil bóthair do theangacha íseal-acmhainne agus teangacha gan acmhainní</title_ga>
      <title_hu>Többnyelvű megjegyzések: ütemterv az alacsony és nem erőforrásokkal rendelkező nyelvek számára</title_hu>
      <title_ka>a road map for low- and non- resource languages</title_ka>
      <title_el>Διάγλωσση παρατήρηση: ένας οδικός χάρτης για γλώσσες χαμηλού και χωρίς πόρους</title_el>
      <title_kk>Төменгі тілдер жазбалары: a road map for low- and no- resource languages</title_kk>
      <title_it>Annotazione multilingue: una tabella di marcia per lingue a basso contenuto e senza risorse</title_it>
      <title_lt>Tarpkalbinė anotacija: žemos apimties ir išteklių neturinčių kalbų veiksmų planas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Кросјазична анотација: патна карта за јазици со ниски и без ресурси</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Anotasi saling bahasa: peta laluan untuk bahasa rendah dan tiada sumber</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ക്രോസ്- ഭാഷ അഭിപ്രായം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Annotazzjoni translingwistika: pjan direzzjonali għal lingwi b’riżorsi baxxi u mingħajr riżorsi</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Хөгжим хэлний нотолгоо: бага болон асуудалгүй хэлний зам газрын зураг</title_mn>
      <title_no>Krysspråk notasjon: a road map for low- and no- resource languages</title_no>
      <title_pl>Adnotacja wielojęzyczna: mapa drogowa dla języków niskich i bez zasobów</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Adnotare translingvistică: o foaie de parcurs pentru limbile cu resurse reduse și fără resurse</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Prejezična annotacija: putna map a za jezike niske i bez resursa</title_sr>
      <title_si>a path map for low- and no- source language</title_si>
      <title_so>Waraaqashada luuqadaha iskuulka ah: kartada wadooyinka ee luqadaha hoose-iyo-aan-resource-lahayn</title_so>
      <title_sv>Tvärspråkiga kommentarer: en färdplan för språk med låg- och resursbrist</title_sv>
      <title_ta>கிராஸ்- மொழி அறிவிப்பு: குறைந்த- மற்றும் மூலம் இல்லாத மொழிகளுக்கான ஒரு பாதைய வரைபடம்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Cross-lingual annotation: a road map for low- and no- resource languages</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Ghi chú ngôn ngữ rộng: bản đồ đường cho ngôn ngữ thấp và vô tài nguyên</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Междуезична анотация: пътна карта за езици с нисък ресурс и без ресурс</title_bg>
      <title_da>Tværsproget annotering: en køreplan for sprog med lav og ingen ressourcer</title_da>
      <title_hr>Prejezična annotacija: putna map a za jezike niske i bez resursa</title_hr>
      <title_id>Anotasi saling bahasa: peta jalan untuk bahasa rendah dan tanpa sumber daya</title_id>
      <title_nl>Meertalige annotatie: een routekaart voor talen met weinig en geen bronnen</title_nl>
      <title_de>Sprachübergreifende Annotation: eine Roadmap für Sprachen ohne und ohne Ressourcen</title_de>
      <title_ko>다중 언어 주석: 낮은 자원과 무자원 언어의 노선도</title_ko>
      <title_tr>Duruz diller</title_tr>
      <title_af>Description</title_af>
      <title_sq>Anotacion ndërgjuhësor: një hartë rrugës për gjuhët me ulje dhe pa burime</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Խոսքերի միջև annoտացիա. ցածր և առանց ռեսուրսների լեզուների ճանապարհի քարտեզ</title_hy>
      <title_sw>Tamko la lugha: ramani ya barabarani kwa lugha ndogo na isiyo na rasilimali</title_sw>
      <title_fa>نشان‌دهنده‌های زیادی زبان: نقشه جاده برای زبانهای کم و بی‌منبع</title_fa>
      <title_az>X…ôrcli dil m…ôlumatlarńĪ: a road map for low- and no- resource languages</title_az>
      <title_bn>ক্রস-ভাষার বিবৃতি: নিম্ন- এবং কোন রাস্তা ভাষার জন্য একটি রাস্তা মানচিত্র</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Prejezična annotacija: putna map a za jezike niske i bez resursa</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Křížová anotace: cestovní mapa pro jazyky s nízkými zdroji a bez zdrojů</title_cs>
      <title_et>Keeleülene märkus: vähese ressursiga ja vähese ressursiga keelte tegevuskava</title_et>
      <title_am>ቋንቋ</title_am>
      <title_fi>Monikielinen huomautus: etenemissuunnitelma vähävaraisille ja vähävaraisille kielille</title_fi>
      <title_ca>Anotació translingüística: un map a de ruta per llengües amb baix recursos i sense recursos</title_ca>
      <title_sk>Medjezična opomba: načrt za jezike z nizkimi viri in brez virov</title_sk>
      <title_he>Name</title_he>
      <title_jv>structural navigation</title_jv>
      <title_ha>Cire-ɗabi'ar-harshen na-nau'in: a kart hanya wa harshen aiki na ƙasan-da-resource</title_ha>
      <title_bo>Cross-lingual annotation: a road map for low-and non-resource languages</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تقدم هذه الورقة "خارطة طريق" للتعليق على الفئات الدلالية بلغات متنوعة نسبيًا ، مع موارد لغوية قليلة محتملة ، وغالبًا ما لا توجد موارد حسابية. ركزت جهود التعليقات التوضيحية الدلالية السابقة بشكل كبير على اللغات عالية الموارد ، أو اللغات منخفضة الموارد نسبيًا مع عدد كبير من المتحدثين الأصليين. ومع ذلك ، هناك سمات نمطية معينة ، وهي تجميع مفاهيم متعددة في كلمة واحدة ، وهي أكثر شيوعًا في اللغات ذات مجتمع الكلام الأصغر. على سبيل المثال ، ما يتم التعبير عنه كجملة بلغة أكثر تحليلاً مثل اللغة الإنجليزية ، يمكن التعبير عنها ككلمة واحدة بلغة أكثر تركيبية مثل Arapaho. تقترح هذه الورقة حلولاً للتعليق على اللغات التحليلية والتركيبية بطريقة قابلة للمقارنة بناءً على البحث النوعي الحالي ، وتقدم خارطة طريق لتعليق اللغات مع ندرة الموارد.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo presenta una «hoja de ruta» para la anotación de categorías semánticas en lenguajes tipológicamente diversos, con pocos recursos lingüísticos potencialmente y, a menudo, sin recursos computacionales existentes. Los esfuerzos de anotación semántica anteriores se han centrado principalmente en idiomas de recursos altos o idiomas de recursos relativamente bajos con un gran número de hablantes nativos. Sin embargo, hay ciertos rasgos tipológicos, a saber, la síntesis de múltiples conceptos en una sola palabra, que son más comunes en idiomas con una comunidad de habla más pequeña. Por ejemplo, lo que se expresa como una oración en un lenguaje más analítico como el inglés, puede expresarse como una sola palabra en un idioma más sintético como el arapaho. En este artículo se proponen soluciones para anotar lenguajes analíticos y sintéticos de manera comparable en base a la investigación tipológica existente, e introduce una hoja de ruta para la anotación de idiomas con escasez de recursos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo apresenta um “roteiro” para a anotação de categorias semânticas em linguagens tipologicamente diversas, com potencialmente poucos recursos linguísticos, e muitas vezes sem recursos computacionais existentes. Esforços anteriores de anotação semântica concentraram-se principalmente em idiomas de alto recurso, ou idiomas de recursos relativamente baixos com um grande número de falantes nativos. No entanto, existem certos traços tipológicos, nomeadamente a síntese de vários conceitos numa única palavra, que são mais comuns em línguas com uma comunidade de fala menor. Por exemplo, o que é expresso como uma frase em uma linguagem mais analítica como o inglês, pode ser expresso como uma única palavra em uma linguagem mais sintética como o Arapaho. Este artigo propõe soluções para anotar linguagens analíticas e sintéticas de forma comparável com base em pesquisas tipológicas existentes e apresenta um roteiro para a anotação de linguagens com escassez de recursos.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Cet article présente une « feuille de route » pour l'annotation de catégories sémantiques dans des langues typologiquement diverses, avec potentiellement peu de ressources linguistiques, et souvent aucune ressource informatique existante. Par le passé, les efforts d'annotation sémantique se sont concentrés principalement sur les langues à ressources élevées ou sur les langues à ressources relativement faibles avec un grand nombre de locuteurs natifs. Cependant, certains traits typologiques, à savoir la synthèse de plusieurs concepts en un seul mot, sont plus courants dans les langues où la communauté linguistique est plus restreinte. Par exemple, ce qui est exprimé sous forme de phrase dans un langage plus analytique comme l'anglais peut être exprimé en un seul mot dans un langage plus synthétique comme l'arapaho. Cet article propose des solutions pour annoter les langages analytiques et synthétiques d'une manière comparable sur la base de recherches typologiques existantes, et présente une feuille de route pour l'annotation de langues présentant une pénurie de ressources.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>この論文は、潜在的に言語リソースが少なく、多くの場合、既存の計算リソースがない、類型的に多様な言語における意味カテゴリの注釈のための「ロードマップ」を提示する。過去のセマンティックアノテーションの取り組みは、主に高リソース言語、またはネイティブスピーカーが多い比較的低リソース言語に焦点を当てています。しかしながら、特定の類型的特質、すなわち、複数の概念を単一の単語に合成することは、より小さな音声コミュニティを持つ言語でより一般的である。例えば、英語のようなより分析的な言語で文章として表現されるものは、アラパホーのようなより合成的な言語で単一の単語として表現され得る。本稿では，既存の類型論的研究に基づいて，分析言語と合成言語を同等の方法でアノテーションするためのソリューションを提案し，リソース不足の言語のアノテーションのためのロードマップを紹介する．</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>本文作"路线图",施于多样化语语义类,或言资甚少,而常无见计算资源。 旧语义注事,主集高资言语及多母语人士对低资源语。 然有类型学特征,将数名合为一单词,此小语音社区之言也。 如英语等更具分析性言为句,于更合为语(如Arapaho)为单词。 本文基于见类学,发以比义析合成语言之解决方案,而引其资源匮乏之路线图。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर टाइपोलॉजिकल रूप से विविध भाषाओं में शब्दार्थ श्रेणियों के एनोटेशन के लिए एक "रोड मैप" प्रस्तुत करता है, जिसमें संभावित रूप से कुछ भाषाई संसाधन होते हैं, और अक्सर कोई मौजूदा कम्प्यूटेशनल संसाधन नहीं होते हैं। पिछले शब्दार्थ एनोटेशन प्रयासों ने बड़े पैमाने पर उच्च-संसाधन भाषाओं, या बड़ी संख्या में देशी वक्ताओं के साथ अपेक्षाकृत कम-संसाधन भाषाओं पर ध्यान केंद्रित किया है। हालांकि, कुछ टाइपोलॉजिकल लक्षण हैं, अर्थात् एक ही शब्द में कई अवधारणाओं का संश्लेषण, जो एक छोटे भाषण समुदाय वाली भाषाओं में अधिक आम हैं। उदाहरण के लिए, अंग्रेजी जैसी अधिक विश्लेषणात्मक भाषा में एक वाक्य के रूप में क्या व्यक्त किया जाता है, इसे अरापाहो जैसी अधिक सिंथेटिक भाषा में एक शब्द के रूप में व्यक्त किया जा सकता है। यह पेपर मौजूदा टाइपोलॉजिकल अनुसंधान के आधार पर एक तुलनीय तरीके से विश्लेषणात्मक और सिंथेटिक भाषाओं को एनोटेट करने के लिए समाधान का प्रस्ताव करता है, और संसाधनों की कमी के साथ भाषाओं के एनोटेशन के लिए एक रोड मैप पेश करता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>В настоящем документе представлена «дорожная карта» для аннотирования семантических категорий на типологически разнообразных языках с потенциально ограниченными лингвистическими ресурсами и часто отсутствующими вычислительными ресурсами. Предыдущие усилия по семантической аннотации были сосредоточены в основном на языках с высоким уровнем ресурсов или на языках с относительно низким уровнем ресурсов с большим количеством носителей языка. Однако существуют определенные типологические черты, а именно синтез нескольких понятий в одно слово, которые более распространены в языках с меньшим речевым сообществом. Например, то, что выражается как предложение в более аналитическом языке, таком как английский, может быть выражено как одно слово в более синтетическом языке, таком как Arapaho. В настоящем документе предлагаются решения для аннотирования аналитических и синтетических языков сопоставимым образом на основе существующих типологических исследований и вводится "дорожная карта" для аннотирования языков с дефицитом ресурсов.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Cuireann an páipéar seo “léarscáil bóthair” i láthair chun anótáil a dhéanamh ar chatagóirí séimeantacha i dteangacha atá éagsúil ó thaobh na clódóireachta de, le poitéinseal ach beagán acmhainní teanga, agus go minic níl aon acmhainní ríomhaireachtúla ann. Dhírigh iarrachtaí anótála shéimeantacha san am atá caite go mór ar theangacha ard-acmhainne, nó ar theangacha a bhfuil acmhainní réasúnta ísle acu ina bhfuil líon mór cainteoirí dúchais. Mar sin féin, tá tréithe tíopeolaíochta áirithe ann, eadhon sintéis na gcoincheap iolrach in aon fhocal amháin, atá níos coitianta i dteangacha le pobal cainte níos lú. Mar shampla, is féidir an rud a chuirtear in iúl mar abairt i dteanga níos anailísí cosúil le Béarla, a chur in iúl mar fhocal amháin i dteanga níos sintéiseacha cosúil le Arapaho. Molann an páipéar seo réitigh chun anótáil a dhéanamh ar theangacha anailíseacha agus shintéiseacha ar bhealach inchomparáide bunaithe ar thaighde tíopeolaíochta atá ann cheana féin, agus tugtar isteach léarscáil bóthair le haghaidh anótáil teangacha a bhfuil ganntanas acmhainní acu.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία παρουσιάζει έναν "οδικό χάρτη" για την επισήμανση σημασιολογικών κατηγοριών σε τυπολογικά διαφορετικές γλώσσες, με δυνητικά λίγους γλωσσικούς πόρους και συχνά χωρίς υπάρχοντες υπολογιστικούς πόρους. Οι προηγούμενες προσπάθειες σημασιολογικής σχολιασμού έχουν επικεντρωθεί σε μεγάλο βαθμό σε γλώσσες υψηλής περιεκτικότητας ή σε γλώσσες σχετικά χαμηλής περιεκτικότητας με μεγάλο αριθμό μητρικών ομιλητών. Ωστόσο, υπάρχουν ορισμένα τυπολογικά χαρακτηριστικά, δηλαδή η σύνθεση πολλαπλών εννοιών σε μία λέξη, τα οποία είναι πιο συνηθισμένα σε γλώσσες με μικρότερη κοινότητα ομιλίας. Για παράδειγμα, αυτό που εκφράζεται ως πρόταση σε μια πιο αναλυτική γλώσσα όπως τα αγγλικά, μπορεί να εκφραστεί ως μια λέξη σε μια πιο συνθετική γλώσσα όπως το Αραπάχο. Η παρούσα εργασία προτείνει λύσεις για την σχολιασμό αναλυτικών και συνθετικών γλωσσών με συγκρίσιμο τρόπο με βάση την υπάρχουσα τυπολογική έρευνα και εισάγει έναν οδικό χάρτη για την σχολιασμό γλωσσών με έλλειψη πόρων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ამ კანოგურაში სემონტიკური კატეგორიების ნიოტაციას, ტიპოლოგიურად განსხვავებული ენებით, პოტენციალურად რამდენიმე ენგურაციის რესურსებით, და ზოგჯერ არ არის კომპუტაციური რე ბოლო სიმენტიკური ანოტაციების ძალიან ძალიან უფრო დიდი რესურსის ენაზე, ან relatively low-resource ენაზების მნიშვნელოვანი ენაზებით. მაგრამ არსებობს განსაკუთრებული ტიპოლოგიური განსაკუთრები, ანუ რამდენიმე კონცექტის სინტეზი ერთი სიტყვაში, რომელიც უფრო საერთო ენაში უფრო საერთო სიტყვაში მაგალითად, რაც უფრო ანალიტიური ენაში, როგორც ანგლისური ენაში, შეიძლება იყოს ერთი სიტყვაში უფრო სინტეტიური ენაში, როგორც აპაოჰო. ამ დოკუმენტის განსაზღვრება ანალიტიკური და სინტეტიკური ენაზების განსაზღვრებისთვის განსაზღვრებულია რაიპოლოგიური შესწავლებისთვის და დააყენება საზოგადო კაპრატი ენაზების ანტორაციისთ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a tanulmány bemutatja a szemantikai kategóriák tipológiailag különböző nyelveken történő jegyzetelésének útitervét, potenciálisan kevés nyelvi erőforrással és gyakran nem létező számítástechnikai erőforrásokkal. A korábbi szemantikai jegyzetfelvételi erőfeszítések nagyrészt a nagy erőforrású nyelvekre, vagy viszonylag alacsony erőforrású nyelvekre összpontosítottak, amelyek nagy számú anyanyelvű beszélővel rendelkeznek. Vannak azonban bizonyos tipológiai tulajdonságok, nevezetesen több fogalom szintézise egyetlen szóba, amelyek gyakoribbak a kisebb beszédközösséggel rendelkező nyelvekben. Például, amit mondatként fejeznek ki egy analitikusabb nyelven, mint az angol, egyetlen szóként fejezhető ki egy olyan szintetikusabb nyelven, mint az Arapaho. A tanulmány megoldásokat javasol az analitikus és szintetikus nyelvek hasonló módon történő jegyzetelésére a meglévő tipológiai kutatások alapján, valamint útitervet vezet be az erőforráshiánnyal rendelkező nyelvek jegyzetelésére.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo presenta una 'road map' per l'annotazione di categorie semantiche in lingue tipologicamente diverse, con potenzialmente poche risorse linguistiche e spesso senza risorse computazionali esistenti. Gli sforzi passati di annotazione semantica si sono concentrati in gran parte su lingue ad alto contenuto di risorse, o lingue a basso contenuto di risorse, con un gran numero di madrelingua. Tuttavia, ci sono alcuni tratti tipologici, vale a dire la sintesi di più concetti in una sola parola, che sono più comuni nelle lingue con una comunità vocale più piccola. Ad esempio, ciò che viene espresso come una frase in una lingua più analitica come l'inglese, può essere espresso come una singola parola in una lingua più sintetica come Arapaho. Il presente documento propone soluzioni per annotare linguaggi analitici e sintetici in modo comparabile sulla base della ricerca tipologica esistente, e introduce una road map per l'annotazione di linguaggi con scarsità di risorse.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente pateikiamas semantinių kategorijų anotacijos tipologiškai įvairiomis kalbomis planas, kuriame gali būti nedaug kalbinių išteklių ir dažnai nėra esamų skaičiavimo išteklių. Ankstesnės semantinės pastangos daugiausia buvo skirtos daug išteklių turinčioms kalboms arba palyginti mažai išteklių turinčioms kalboms su dideliu vietinių kalbėtojų skaičiumi. Tačiau yra tam tikrų tipologinių požymių, būtent daugelio sąvokų sintezė į vieną žodį, kurie dažniau pasitaiko kalbomis su mažesne kalbų bendruomene. Pavyzdžiui, tai, kas išreiškiamas kaip sakinys labiau analitine kalba, kaip antai anglų kalba, gali būti išreiškiamas kaip vienas žodis labiau sintetine kalba, kaip antai arapaho. Šiame dokumente siūlomi sprendimai, kaip panašiai anotuoti analitines ir sintetines kalbas remiantis esamais tipologiniais tyrimais, ir pateikiamas kalbų, kuriose išteklių trūksta, anotacijos veiksmų planas.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз типтологиялық түрлі тілдерде, мүмкіндік көп лингвистикалық ресурстар болып, көпшілік компьютерлік ресурстар болмайды. Соңғы семантикалық жазбалар көпшілік ресурстар тілдеріне немесе негізгі тілдерінің көп саны тілдеріне көпшілікті болды. Бірақ бірнеше типтологиялық қасиеттер бар, мысалы, бірнеше концепциялардың синтезасы бір сөзде болады, бұл тілдерде кішкентай сөйлеу коммуникациясы бар. Мысалы, ағылшын тілінің аналитикалық тілінде сөз ретінде, арапахо секілді синтетикалық тілінде бір сөз ретінде сөз көрсетіледі. Бұл қағаз аналитикалық және синтетикалық тілдерді бағытталған типтологиялық зерттеулерге негізделген салыстырмалы тәсілдер үшін шешімдерді ұсынады, және тілдердің ең көлемі ресурстары үшін жол картасын та</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас нь хэлбэрийн олон хэл дээр семантик хэлбэрүүдийн зам газрын зураг илэрхийлэгддэг. Магадгүй хэлний боловсролын баялаг, ихэвчлэн тооцооллын баялаг байхгүй. Өмнөх semantic annotation efforts have largely focused on high-resource languages, or relatively low-resource languages with a large number of native speakers. Гэхдээ хэлэлцээний жижиг хэлэлцээний нийгэмд олон ойлголтын шинжлэх ухааны тодорхойлолт байдаг. Жишээлбэл, Англи хэл шиг илүү шинжилгээ хэлний үг гэж илэрхийлэгддэг зүйл нь Арапао шиг илүү шинжилгээ хэлний нэг үг гэж илэрхийлэгдэж болох юм. Энэ цаас шинжилгээ болон синтетик хэлнүүдийг харьцуулахын тулд шийдвэрлэл санал болгож байна. Мөн суурь бичлэгийн судалгааны үндсэн аргаар харьцуулан хэлнүүдийн санал болгох зам газрын зураг илэрхийлдэг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ സെമാന്റിക് വ്യത്യസ്ത ഭാഷകളില്‍ സെമാന്റിക് വ്യത്യസ്ത ഭാഷകളുടെ പ്രഖ്യാപിക്കാന്‍ 'റോഡ് മാപ്പ്' കാണിക്കുന്നു. സാധ്യതയ അവസാനം സെമാന്റിക് അഭിപ്രായത്തിന്റെ ശ്രമങ്ങള്‍ വളരെ ഉയര്‍ന്ന വിഭവഭാഷകളില്‍ ശ്രദ്ധിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു, അല്ലെങ്കില്‍ വളരെ കുറഞ് However, there are certain typological traits, namely the synthesis of multiple concepts into a single word, that are more common in languages with a smaller speech community.  ഉദാഹരണത്തിനായി, ഇംഗ്ലീഷിനെപ്പോലെ ഒരു വാക്കില്‍ പ്രസ്താവിക്കുന്നത്, അരാപാഹോയെപ്പോലുള്ള ഒരു കൂടുതല്‍ സങ്കീര്‍ത്തിക ഭ ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ നിലവിലുള്ള ടൈപ്പോളിക്കല്‍ പഠനത്തിന്‍റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ നിലവിലുള്ള വിശദീകരണവും സംസാരിക്കുന്ന ഭാഷകളും പരിശോധിപ്പിക്കുന്ന വഴ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jippreżenta 'pjan direzzjonali' għall-annotazzjoni ta' kategoriji semantiċi f'lingwi tipikament differenti, b'potenzjalment ftit riżorsi lingwistiċi, u spiss l-ebda riżorsi komputattivi eżistenti. L-isforzi semantiċi tal-passat iffukaw l-aktar fuq lingwi b’riżorsi għoljin, jew lingwi b’riżorsi relattivament baxxi b’għadd kbir ta’ kelliema nattivi. Madankollu, hemm ċerti karatteristiċi tipoloġiċi, jiġifieri s-sinteżi ta’ kunċetti multipli f’kelma waħda, li huma aktar komuni f’lingwi b’komunità ta’ diskors iżgħar. Pereżempju, dak li huwa espress bħala sentenza f’lingwa aktar analitika bħall-Ingliż, jista’ jiġi espress bħala kelma waħda f’lingwa aktar sintetika bħall-Arapaho. Dan id-dokument jipproponi soluzzjonijiet għall-annotazzjoni tal-lingwi analitiċi u sintetiċi b’mod komparabbli bbażat fuq riċerka tipoloġika eżistenti, u jintroduċi pjan direzzjonali għall-annotazzjoni tal-lingwi b’nuqqas ta’ riżorsi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mk>Овој документ претставува „патна карта“ за анотацијата на семантичките категории на типологички различни јазици, со потенцијално малку јазички ресурси и честопати нема постоечки компјутерски ресурси. Претходните семантични напори за анотација се фокусираа главно на јазици со високи ресурси или релативно ниски ресурси со голем број родни говорници. Сепак, постојат одредени типологични особини, имено синтезата на повеќе концепти во еден збор, кои се почесни на јазици со помала говорна заедница. На пример, она што се изразува како реченица на поаналитички јазик како Англиски, може да се изрази како еден збор на посинтетички јазик како Арапахо. Овој документ предложува решенија за анотирање на аналитичките и синтетичките јазици на споредлив начин базиран на постоечките типологички истражувања и претставува патоказ за анотирање на јазиците со губење на ресурси.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret viser ein «veikart» for annotasjonen av semantiske kategoriar i typologisk ulike språk, med potensielt få språkkressursar, og ofte ingen eksisterande dataressursar. For tidlegare semantiske notasjonsforsøk har fokusert stort på høg ressursspråk, eller relativt låg ressursspråk med stor mange innslag. Det er imidlertid nokre typologiske eigenskapar, som er syntese av fleire konseptar i eit enkelt ord, som er meir vanleg i språk med ein mindre talesamfunn. For eksempel, det som vert uttrykt som eit setning i ein mer analytisk språk som engelsk, kan uttrykkes som eitt ord i eit mer syntetisk språk som Arapaho. Denne papiret foreslår løysingar for å merke analytiske og syntetiske språk på ein sammenlignbar måte basert på eksisterande typologiske forskning, og introduserer ei veikart for oppmerkinga av språk med dørste ressursar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>W artykule przedstawiono "mapę drogową" adnotacji kategorii semantycznych w zróżnicowanych typologicznie językach, z potencjalnie niewielkimi zasobami językowymi, a często brakiem istniejących zasobów obliczeniowych. Wcześniejsze wysiłki dotyczące adnotacji semantycznej koncentrowały się w dużej mierze na językach o wysokich zasobach lub stosunkowo niskich zasobach językach z dużą liczbą native speakerów. Istnieją jednak pewne cechy typologiczne, a mianowicie synteza wielu pojęć w jedno słowo, które są bardziej powszechne w językach o mniejszej społeczności mowy. Na przykład, co jest wyrażone jako zdanie w bardziej analitycznym języku, takim jak angielski, może być wyrażone jako pojedyncze słowo w bardziej syntetycznym języku, takim jak Arapaho. Niniejszy artykuł proponuje rozwiązania do adnotacji języków analitycznych i syntetycznych w porównywalny sposób w oparciu o istniejące badania typologiczne oraz wprowadza mapę drogową adnotacji języków z brakiem zasobów.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare prezintă o "foaie de parcurs" pentru adnotarea categoriilor semantice în limbi tipologice diverse, cu potențial puține resurse lingvistice și adesea fără resurse computaționale existente. Eforturile anterioare de adnotare semantică s-au concentrat în mare măsură asupra limbilor cu resurse ridicate sau asupra limbilor cu resurse relativ scăzute, cu un număr mare de vorbitori nativi. Cu toate acestea, există anumite trăsături tipologice, și anume sinteza mai multor concepte într-un singur cuvânt, care sunt mai frecvente în limbile cu o comunitate de vorbire mai mică. De exemplu, ceea ce este exprimat ca o propoziție într-o limbă mai analitică, cum ar fi engleza, poate fi exprimat ca un singur cuvânt într-o limbă mai sintetică, cum ar fi Arapaho. Lucrarea propune soluții pentru adnotarea limbilor analitice și sintetice într-un mod comparabil bazat pe cercetările tipologice existente și introduce o foaie de parcurs pentru adnotarea limbilor cu lipsă de resurse.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir predstavlja 'putnu mapu' za annotaciju semantičkih kategorija na tipološki različitim jezicima, sa potencijalno malo jezičkih resursa i često nema postojećih računalnih resursa. Poslednji semantički napori za annotaciju usredotočili su se uglavnom na jezike visokog resursa ili relativno niskog jezika resursa sa velikim brojem govornika. Međutim, postoje određene tipološke karakteristike, a to je sinteza višestrukih koncepta u jednu reč, koja su češće u jezicima sa manjom govornom zajednicom. Na primer, ono što se izražava kao rečenica na više analitičnom jeziku kao što je engleski, može se izraziti kao jedna reč na sintetičnijem jeziku kao što je Arapaho. Ovaj papir predlaže rešenja za annotaciju analitičkih i sintetičkih jezika na usporednom načinu na temelju postojećih tipoloških istraživanja, i predstavlja putnu mapu za annotaciju jezika sa mrtvim resursima.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalkan wuxuu soo bandhigaa kartada jidadka oo ku qoran kooxaha semantika oo ku qoran luqado kala duduwan, waxaana laga yaabaa in ay leedahay manfacyo luuqad ah, marar badanna ma jirto resources xisaabta ah. Shaqooyinka qaynuunka ee ugu dambeeyey waxay si badan ugu cusboonaayeen luuqadaha sare ee rasmiga, ama luuqadaha hoose ee rasmiga ah waxay ku leeyihiin hadal badan oo hooyo ah. Si kastaba ha ahaatee waxaa jira dhibaatooyin kala duduwan, tusaale ahaan fikrada kala duduwan oo isku hadal ah, kuwaas oo luuqadaha ugu wada caadi ah oo ku qoran jamii hadal yar. Tusaale ahaan waxa looga hadlaa hadal af kale oo afka ingiriisiga ah oo la mid ah, waxaa looga hadli karaa eray keliya oo af ka mid ah luqad Arapaho oo kale. Kanu wuxuu soo jeedaa xalal ku saabsan luqadaha analyaalka iyo bandhigyada si u eg, taasoo ku saleysan waxbarashada qoraalka ah oo ku qoran, wuxuuna soo bandhigaa kartada jidadka si ay u taqaano luuqadaha oo aad u gaabaneyso.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats presenterar en "vägkarta" för kommentering av semantiska kategorier på typologiskt olika språk, med potentiellt få språkresurser och ofta inga befintliga beräkningsresurser. Tidigare semantiska anteckningar insatser har fokuserat till stor del på högresursspråk, eller relativt lågresursspråk med ett stort antal infödda talare. Det finns dock vissa typologiska egenskaper, nämligen syntesen av flera begrepp till ett enda ord, som är vanligare i språk med en mindre språkgemenskap. Till exempel, vad som uttrycks som en mening på ett mer analytiskt språk som engelska, kan uttryckas som ett enda ord på ett mer syntetiskt språk som Arapaho. Denna uppsats föreslår lösningar för att kommentera analytiska och syntetiska språk på ett jämförbart sätt baserat på befintlig typologisk forskning, och introducerar en färdplan för kommentering av språk med brist på resurser.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>මේ පැත්ත පෙන්වන්නේ සෙමැන්ටික් වර්ගයක් විවිධ භාෂාවිද්‍ය භාෂාවිතයෙන්, භාෂාවික සම්බන්ධයක් තියෙන්න, සමහර විශ පසුගින් සැමැන්තික ප්‍රශ්නයක් ගොඩක් විශාල භාෂාවට ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා, නැත්තම් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ලොකු සංඛ ඒත් තියෙන්නේ විශේෂ විශේෂතාවක් තියෙන්නේ, කියන්නේ විශේෂ විශේෂතාවක් එක වචනයක් තියෙන්නේ, ඒ වගේම භාෂ උදාහරණයෙන්, ඉංග්‍රීසි වගේ විශ්ලේෂ භාෂාවක් වගේ වාක්ය විදිහට ප්‍රකාශ කරලා තියෙන්න පුළුවන් අරාපාහෝ වග මේ පැත්තේ විශ්ලේෂක සහ සංවිධාන භාෂාවට විස්තර කරන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා වගේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්න පුළුවන් විස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ms>Kertas ini menghasilkan 'peta laluan' untuk anotasi kategori semantik dalam bahasa yang berbeza secara tipologi, dengan sumber bahasa yang mungkin sedikit, dan sering tiada sumber komputasi yang wujud. Usaha anotasi semantik yang lalu telah fokus pada bahasa sumber tinggi, atau bahasa sumber relatif rendah dengan bilangan besar pembicara asli. Namun, ada ciri-ciri tipologi tertentu, iaitu sintesis konsep berbilang ke dalam satu perkataan, yang lebih biasa dalam bahasa dengan komuniti ucapan yang lebih kecil. Contohnya, apa yang dikatakan sebagai kalimat dalam bahasa yang lebih analitik seperti bahasa Inggeris, boleh dikatakan sebagai satu perkataan dalam bahasa yang lebih sintetik seperti Arapaho. Kertas ini mencadangkan solusi untuk anotasi bahasa analitik dan sintetik dengan cara yang boleh dibandingkan berdasarkan kajian tipologik yang wujud, dan memperkenalkan peta laluan untuk anotasi bahasa dengan kehabisan sumber.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ta>This paper presents a 'road map' for the annotation of semantic categories in typologically diverse languages, with potentially few linguistic resources, and often no existing computational resources.  கடந்த பாதிப்பு அறிவிப்பு முயற்சிகள் அதிக மூலத்தின் மொழிகள் மீது கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, அல்லது சார்ந்த குறைந்த மூலம் மொழ ஆனால், சில வகையான பாதைகள் இருக்கின்றன, அதாவது, பல கருத்துக்கள் ஒரே வார்த்தைக்கு ஒத்திசைப்படுத்தல், அது சிறிய பேச்சு சமூகத்தில் ம எடுத்துக்காட்டாக, அராபாஹோ போன்ற ஒரு மொழியில் மேலும் ஆர்பாஹோவைப் போன்ற ஒரு ஒற்றைச் சொல்லாக வெளிப்படுத்தப்படும். இந்த காகிதத்தில் இருக்கும் வகையான ஆராய்ச்சி அடிப்படையில் ஒரு ஒப்பிட்ட மொழிகளை அறிவிப்பதற்கான தீர்வுகளை தெரிவுகளை அளிக்கிறது, மொழிகளின் மூலம்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>This paper presents a 'road map' for the annotation of semantic categories in typology various languages, with potentially few linguistic resources, and often no existing computational resources. اگلے سیمنٹی اظہار کی کوشش بہت زیادہ سرمایہ کی زبانوں پر، یا بہت سی موجود زبانوں کے ساتھ نسبتا کم سرمایہ کی زبانوں پر تمرکز کی گئی ہے. لیکن ایک کلمه میں بہت سی تایپولوژیکوں کی تعریف ہے، یعنی ایک کلمه میں بہت سی قول کی تعریف، جو زبانوں میں بہت سی تعریف ہے ایک چھوٹے کلام کی جماعت کے ساتھ۔ مثال، جو بات انگلیسی کی طرح زیادہ تحلیل کی زبان میں واضح کی جاتی ہے، ایک کلمہ کے طور پر آراپا کی طرح ایک سینٹیسی زبان میں واضح کی جاتی ہے۔ This paper proposes solutions for annotating analytic and synthetic languages in a comparable way based on existing typological research, and introduces a road map for the annotation of languages with a dearth resources.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này đề nghị một "bản đồ đường phố" để ghi chú về các loại ngữ ngữ ngữ văn học khác nhau theo kiểu, với khả năng rất ít tài nguyên ngôn ngữ, và thường không có nguồn tính toán. Nỗ lực ghi chú mẫu giáo trước đây đã chủ yếu tập trung vào ngôn ngữ có nguồn cao, hoặc ngôn ngữ ít tài nguyên với một số lượng lớn người dân bản xứ. Tuy nhiên, có một số đặc điểm, cụ thể là tổng hợp các khái niệm trong một từ, phổ biến hơn trong ngôn ngữ với cộng đồng ngôn ngữ nhỏ hơn. Thí dụ như, những gì được diễn tả như một câu trong ngôn ngữ phân tích nhiều hơn như tiếng Anh, có thể được diễn tả như một từ duy nhất trong một ngôn ngữ nhân tạo hơn như Arapaho. Đề tài này đề xuất giải pháp để ghi chú ngôn ngữ phân tích và tổng hợp theo một cách tương tự dựa trên các nghiên cứu khác nhau hiện tại, và đưa ra một bản đồ hướng dẫn ghi chú ngôn ngữ thiếu nguồn.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Bu qogʻoz turli tillarda semantik kategoriga taʼminlov qiladigan 'йўл харитаси' ga ega. Bu qogʻoz turli tillarda, juda kam necha lingvistik 资源 bor, va ko'pincha hech qanday kompyuterga mavjud emas. Oxirgi semantik taʼminlovchi jarayonlar juda katta murakkab manba tillariga, yoki juda katta natijadagi gapiruvchilar bilan juda kichkina rasm tillariga foydalanadi. Lekin, bir necha fikrlar bir so'zda bir so'zni bir so'zda bir necha fikrlarning bir tizimini bir so'zda o'zgartirish mumkin. Bu bir necha gapir jamiyat bilan ko'proq gapiradigan tillar. Masalan, ingliz tilida bir so'zni aniqlash tilidagi so'zlar, Arapaho kabi bir necha bir so'z deb hisoblanishi mumkin. Бу саҳифа маълумотлар мавжуд тарқатувчиларга таҳлиқ ва синтентик тилларга эълон қилиш учун мосламаларини тақдим этилади ва мазкур турли манфаатлар бўйича тақдим этиш учун йўл харитларини кўрсатади.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия представя "пътна карта" за анотация на семантични категории в типологично разнообразни езици, с потенциално малко езикови ресурси и често без съществуващи изчислителни ресурси. Миналите усилия за семантична анотация са се фокусирали предимно върху езици с висок ресурс или сравнително ниски ресурсни езици с голям брой носители на езика. Съществуват обаче някои типологични черти, а именно синтеза на множество понятия в една дума, които са по-често срещани в езици с по-малка речна общност. Например, това, което се изразява като изречение на по-аналитичен език като английския, може да бъде изразено като една дума в по-синтетичен език като арапахо. Настоящата статия предлага решения за анотиране на аналитични и синтетични езици по сравним начин въз основа на съществуващи типологични изследвания и представя пътна карта за анотиране на езици с недостиг на ресурси.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel presenteert een 'roadmap' voor de annotatie van semantische categorieën in typologisch diverse talen, met potentieel weinig linguïstische bronnen, en vaak geen bestaande rekenmiddelen. In het verleden hebben semantische annotatieinspanningen zich voornamelijk gericht op talen met veel bronnen, of talen met relatief weinig bronnen met een groot aantal moedertaalsprekers. Er zijn echter bepaalde typologische eigenschappen, namelijk de synthese van meerdere concepten in één woord, die vaker voorkomen in talen met een kleinere spraakgemeenschap. Bijvoorbeeld, wat wordt uitgedrukt als een zin in een meer analytische taal zoals Engels, kan worden uitgedrukt als een enkel woord in een meer synthetische taal zoals Arapaho. Dit document stelt oplossingen voor voor het annoteren van analytische en synthetische talen op een vergelijkbare manier op basis van bestaand typologisch onderzoek, en introduceert een routekaart voor annoteren van talen met een gebrek aan middelen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel præsenterer en 'road map' for annotering af semantiske kategorier på typologisk forskellige sprog, med potentielt få sproglige ressourcer og ofte ingen eksisterende beregningsressourcer. Tidligere semantiske annoteringsindsatser har hovedsageligt fokuseret på sprog med høj ressource eller sprog med relativt lav ressource med et stort antal indfødte talere. Der er dog visse typologiske træk, nemlig syntesen af flere begreber i et enkelt ord, som er mere almindelige i sprog med et mindre talefællesskab. For eksempel, hvad der udtrykkes som en sætning på et mere analytisk sprog som engelsk, kan udtrykkes som et enkelt ord på et mere syntetisk sprog som Arapaho. Denne artikel foreslår løsninger til anmærkning af analytiske og syntetiske sprog på en sammenlignelig måde baseret på eksisterende typologisk forskning, og introducerer en køreplan for anmærkning af sprog med mangel på ressourcer.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag stellt eine "Roadmap" für die Annotation semantischer Kategorien in typologisch unterschiedlichen Sprachen vor, mit potenziell wenigen linguistischen Ressourcen und oft ohne vorhandene Rechenressourcen. Bisherige semantische Annotationsbemühungen konzentrierten sich größtenteils auf ressourcenintensive Sprachen oder relativ ressourcenarme Sprachen mit einer großen Anzahl von Muttersprachlern. Es gibt jedoch bestimmte typologische Merkmale, nämlich die Synthese mehrerer Konzepte zu einem einzigen Wort, die in Sprachen mit einer kleineren Sprachgemeinschaft häufiger vorkommen. Zum Beispiel, was als Satz in einer analytischeren Sprache wie Englisch ausgedrückt wird, kann als ein einzelnes Wort in einer synthetischeren Sprache wie Arapaho ausgedrückt werden. Dieser Beitrag schlägt Lösungen für die Annotation analytischer und synthetischer Sprachen auf vergleichbare Weise vor, basierend auf bestehenden typologischen Forschungen und stellt eine Roadmap für die Annotation von Sprachen mit Ressourcenmangel vor.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini mempersembahkan 'peta jalan' untuk anotasi kategori semantis dalam bahasa tipologis yang berbeda, dengan potensi sedikit sumber daya bahasa, dan sering tidak ada sumber komputasi yang ada. Usaha anotasi semantis masa lalu telah fokus pada bahasa sumber daya tinggi, atau bahasa sumber daya relatif rendah dengan jumlah besar pembicara asli. However, there are certain typological traits, namely the synthesis of multiple concepts into a single word, that are more common in languages with a smaller speech community.  Contohnya, apa yang diungkapkan sebagai kalimat dalam bahasa yang lebih analitis seperti bahasa Inggris, dapat diungkapkan sebagai satu kata dalam bahasa yang lebih sintetis seperti Arapaho. Kertas ini mengusulkan solusi untuk anotasi bahasa analitis dan sintetis dengan cara yang bisa dibandingkan berdasarkan penelitian tipologi yang ada, dan memperkenalkan peta jalan untuk anotasi bahasa dengan sumber daya yang hampir habis.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 유형이 다양한 언어에서 의미 유형을 주석하는'노선도'를 제시했다. 이런 언어는 언어 자원이 적고 기존의 계산 자원이 없을 수 있다.과거의 의미 표기 작업은 주로 고자원 언어나 대량의 모국어 인사가 있는 상대적으로 저자원 언어에 집중되었다.그러나 어떤 유형학적 특징은 여러 개념을 하나의 단어로 합성하는데 이것은 언어 집단이 비교적 작은 언어에서 더욱 흔히 볼 수 있다.예를 들어 더욱 분석적인 언어(예를 들어 영어)에서 문장으로 표현된 내용은 더욱 종합적인 언어(예를 들어 아라파호어)에서 하나의 단어로 표현될 수 있다.본고는 기존 유형학 연구를 토대로 비교할 수 있는 방식으로 언어와 합성언어를 주석 분석하는 해결 방안을 제시하고 자원이 부족한 언어를 주석하는 노선도를 소개한다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir predstavlja 'putnu mapu' za annotaciju semantičkih kategorija na tipološki različitim jezicima, s potencijalno malo jezičkih resursa, a često nema postojećih računalnih resursa. Posljednji semantički napori za annotaciju usredotočili su se uglavnom na jezike visokog resursa ili relativno niskog jezika s velikim brojem govornika. Međutim, postoje određena tipološka osobina, a to je sinteza višestrukih koncepta u jednu riječ, koja su češća u jezicima s manjim govornom zajednicom. Na primjer, ono što se izražava kao rečenica na više analitičkom jeziku kao što je engleski, može se izraziti kao jedna riječ na sintetičnijem jeziku kao što je Arapaho. Ovaj papir predlaže rješenja za annotaciju analitičkih i sintetičkih jezika na usporednom načinu na temelju postojećih tipoloških istraživanja i predstavlja putnu kartu za annotaciju jezika sa mrtvim resursima.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier stel 'n 'pad kaart' voor die annotasie van semantiese kategorie in tipologies verskillende tale, met potensieel paar lingwisiese hulpbronne en dikwels geen bestaande rekenaar hulpbronne. Verlede semantiese annotasie versoekte het groot gefokus op hoë- hulpbron tale, of relativies lae- hulpbron tale met 'n groot aantal natuurlike sprekkers. Maar daar is sekere tipologiese eienskappe, naamlik die sinteze van veelvuldige konsepte binne 'n enkele woord, wat meer gemeenskap is in tale met 'n kleiner spreekgemeenskap. Byvoorbeeld, wat uitgevoer word as 'n seting in 'n meer analitiese taal soos Engels, kan uitgevoer word as 'n enkele woord in 'n meer sintetiese taal soos Arapaho. Hierdie papier voorstel oplossings vir annotering van analitiese en sintetiese tale op 'n vergelykbare manier gebaseer op bestaande tipologiese resekings en introduseer 'n pad kaart vir die annotasie van tale met 'n doder van hulpbronne.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ یک نقشه جاده را برای نویسندگی گونه‌های semantic در زبان‌های گونه‌شناسی با احتمالا کمی منابع زبان‌شناسی نشان می‌دهد و اغلب منابع محاسبه‌شناسی وجود ندارد. تلاش گذشته‌ای از نوشته‌های سنتی بیشتر بر زبانهای منابع بالا تمرکز شده‌اند، یا به نسبت به زبانهای منابع کم با تعداد بسیاری از سخنان‌گویان مادری. با این حال، ویژگی‌های نوع شناسی، یعنی مجموعه‌ای از مفهوم‌های چندین به یک کلمه، که در زبان‌ها با یک جامعه‌ی سخنرانی کوچکتر مشترک‌تر است. برای مثال، چیزی که به عنوان یک جمله در زبان تحلیل بیشتری مانند انگلیسی تعریف می‌شود، ممکن است به عنوان یک کلمه تنها در زبان متن‌تری مانند آراپا تعریف شود. این کاغذ راه حل برای نویسندگی زبانهای تحلیل و سناتیک به طریق مقایسه بر اساس تحقیقات نوع شناسی موجود پیشنهاد می‌کند و نقشه جاده برای نویسندگی زبانها با کراترین منابع معرفی می‌کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Gazeti hili linaleta ramani ya barabara kwa ajili ya kutangaza makundi ya a in a ya sekini kwa lugha mbalimbali, kwa uwezekano wa rasilimali chache za lugha, na mara nyingi hakuna rasilimali za kompyuta. Jitihada za kusikitisha kwa kiasi kikubwa imejikita kwenye lugha za rasilimali za juu, au lugha za rasilimali chini kwa kiasi kikubwa na wazungumzaji wengi wa asili. Hata hivyo, kuna matatizo ya kawaida, yaani mfululizo wa dhana mbalimbali katika neno moja, ambalo ni kawaida zaidi kwa lugha yenye jamii ndogo ya hotuba. Kwa mfano, kile kinachoonekana kama hukumu katika lugha ya uchambuzi zaidi kama Kiingereza, inaweza kuonyeshwa kama neno moja kwa lugha yenye ushirikiano zaidi kama Arapaho. Makala hii inapendekeza suluhisho kwa kutangaza lugha za uchambuzi na pamoja kwa njia inayofanana na kulingana na utafiti wa kitaalamu uliopo, na inaonyesha ramani ya barabara kwa ajili ya kutangaza lugha zenye uchunguzi wa rasilimali.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_am>This paper presents a 'road map' for the annotation of semantic categories in typologically diverse languages, with potentially few linguistic resources, and often no existing computational resources.  በተለፉት የsemantic ማስታወቂያ ድጋፍ በብዙ የአገራቸው ንግግር በሚያህል ቋንቋዎች ላይ፣ ወይም በአካባቢው የክፍለ ምዕራፍ ቋንቋዎች ላይ ተማክሮአል፡፡ ነገር ግን አንዲት ንግግር በተለየ ቋንቋዎች በተለየ ትንሽ ንግግር ማኅበረሰብ የተለየ የብዙዎች አካባቢዎች ጉዳይ አሉ፡፡ ለምሳሌ፣ እንደእንግሊዘኛ ቋንቋ የሚታየው ቃል፣ እንደአርፓho በሚመስል አንዲት ቃላት በሚያሳየው ቋንቋ ይታያል፡፡ ይህም ሕገት በተገኘ የቲፖሎጂ ትምህርት ላይ በተመሳሳይ ቋንቋዎች እና በተያያያይነ ቋንቋዎችን ለማሳሳየት መፍትሄቶችን ያስጀምራል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument paraqet një 'hartë rrugës' për anotimin e kategorive semantike në gjuhë tipologjikisht të ndryshme, me potencialisht pak burime gjuhësore dhe shpesh pa burime kompjuterike ekzistuese. Përpjekjet e kaluara semantike të anotacionit janë përqëndruar kryesisht në gjuhët me burime të larta apo gjuhët me burime relativisht të ulëta me një numër të madh të folësve vendas. Megjithatë, ka disa tipologjike, veçanërisht sintezën e koncepteve të shumta në një fjalë të vetme, që janë më të zakonshme në gjuhë me një komunitet më të vogël fjalimi. Për shembull, ajo që shprehet si një fjalë në një gjuhë më analitike si Angleza, mund të shprehet si një fjalë e vetme në një gjuhë më sintetike si Arapaho. This paper proposes solutions for annotating analytic and synthetic languages in a comparable way based on existing typological research, and introduces a road map for the annotation of languages with a dearth of resources.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Այս աշխատանքը ներկայացնում է «ճանապարհի քարտեզ» սեմանտիկ կատեգորիաների annoտացիայի համար տիպոլոգիապես բազմազան լեզուներում, որոնք պոտենցիալ քիչ լեզվական ռեսուրսներ ունեն, և հաճախ գոյություն չունեն հաշվարկ Անցյալ սեմանտիկ նշումների ջանքերը հիմնականում կենտրոնացել են բարձր ռեսուրսների լեզուների վրա, կամ համեմատաբար ցածր ռեսուրսների լեզուների վրա, որոնք շատ բնիկ խոսնակներ ունեն: Այնուամենայնիվ, կան որոշ տիպոլոգիական առանձնահատկություններ, հատկապես բազմաթիվ գաղափարների սինթեզը մեկ բառի մեջ, որոնք ավելի հաճախ են լեզուներում, որոնք ավելի փոքր խոսքի համայնքի հետ են: For example, what is expressed as a sentence in a more analytic language like English, may be expressed as a single word in a more synthetic language like Arapaho.  This paper proposes solutions for annotating analytic and synthetic languages in a comparable way based on existing typological research, and introduces a road map for the annotation of languages with a dearth of resources.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt tipolojik müxtəlif dillərdə semantik kategoriyaların məlumatlarına 'yol haritası' göstərir, mümkün olaraq az dil kaynaqlarına sahib, çox çox müxtəlif hesap kaynaqlarına sahib deyildir. Əvvəlki semantik annotation çabaları çox yüksək ressurs dillərinə, yaxud çox yerli danışanlardan çox düşük ressurs dillərinə odaqlandı. Lakin, çoxlu fikirlərin sintezi tək sözlərə bəzi typolojik özellikləri var ki, bu sözlərdə daha çox yaygın dillərdir. Məsələn, İngilizce kimi daha analitik dildə ifadə edilən cümlələr Arapaho kimi daha sintetik dildə bir söz olar. Bu kağıt analitik və sintetik dillərin müəyyən edilmiş tipolojik araştırmalarına dayanılması üçün çətinlikləri təbliğ edir və dillərin xəbərdarlıqlarına kötü mənbələr olan yol haritasını təşkil edir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir predstavlja 'putnu mapu' za annotaciju semantičkih kategorija na tipološki različitim jezicima, sa potencijalno malo jezičkih resursa, a često nema postojećih računalnih resursa. Posljednji semantički napori za annotaciju usredotočili su se uglavnom na jezike visokog resursa ili relativno niskog jezika resursa sa velikim brojem govornika. Međutim, postoje određena tipološka osobina, a to je sinteza višestrukih koncepta u jednu riječ, koja su češća u jezicima sa manjom govornom zajednicom. Na primjer, ono što se izražava kao rečenica na više analitičkom jeziku kao što je engleski, može se izraziti kao jedna riječ na sintetičkoj jeziku kao što je Arapaho. Ovaj papir predlaže rješenja za annotaciju analitičkih i sintetičkih jezika na usporednom načinu na temelju postojećih tipoloških istraživanja, i predstavlja putnu mapu za annotaciju jezika sa jeftinim resursima.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest paper presenta un "map a de ruta" per anotar categories semàntiques en llengües tipològicament diverses, amb pocs recursos lingüístics i sovint cap recurso computacional existent. Past semantic annotation efforts have focused largely on high-resource languages, or relatively low-resource languages with a large number of native speakers.  No obstant això, hi ha certs trets tipològics, a saber, la síntesi de múltiples conceptes en una sola paraula, que són més comuns en llengües amb una comunitat de discurs més petita. Per exemple, el que s'expressa com una frase en una llengua més analítica com l'anglès, pot ser expressat com una sola paraula en una llengua més sintètica com l'arapaho. Aquest paper propon solucions per anotar llengües analítiques i sintètiques d'una manera comparable basada en la recerca tipològica existent, i introdueix un map a de ruta per anotar llengües amb molts recursos.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas dokumendis esitatakse semantiliste kategooriate annoteerimise teekaart tüpoloogiliselt mitmekesistes keeltes, kus on potentsiaalselt vähe keelelisi ressursse ja sageli puuduvad olemasolevad arvutusressursid. Varasemad semantilised annoteerimise jõupingutused on keskendunud peamiselt suure ressursiga keeltele või suhteliselt vähese ressursiga keeltele, kus on suur hulk emakeelt kõnelevaid. Siiski on teatud tüpoloogilised tunnused, nimelt mitme kontseptsiooni süntees üheks sõnaks, mis on tavalisemad väiksema kõnekogukonnaga keeltes. Näiteks seda, mida väljendatakse lausena analüütilisemas keeles nagu inglise keel, võib väljendada ühe sõnana sünteetilisemas keeles nagu Arapaho. Käesolevas dokumendis pakutakse välja lahendused analüütiliste ja sünteetiliste keelte annoteerimiseks võrreldaval viisil, mis põhineb olemasolevatel tüpoloogilistel uuringutel, ning tutvustatakse tegevuskava ressursside puudusega keelte annoteerimiseks.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটি সাধারণ ভাষায় সেম্যান্টিক বিভিন্ন ভাষায় বিভিন্ন ভাষার বিভিন্ন ভাষায় বিভিন্ন ভাষায় বিভিন্ন ভাষার বিভিন্ন ভাষায় প্ পূর্বে সেমান্টিক ক্ষোভের প্রচেষ্টা বেশীরভাগ উচ্চ সম্পদ ভাষায় মনোযোগ প্রদান করেছে, অথবা প্রায় কম সম্পদ ভাষায় বেশ কয়েকটি স্থানীয় ভ তবে বিশেষ কিছু টাইলজিক্যাল ট্রেস রয়েছে, যার মধ্যে বেশ কিছু ধারণা একটি শব্দের সাথে সিন্টিসিটিস, যা একটি ছোট ভাষায় ভাষায় বেশী  উদাহরণস্বরূপ, যা আরপাহোর মতো আরও বিশ্লেষণীয় ভাষায় বিশ্লেষণের একটি বাক্য হিসেবে প্রকাশ করা যায়, তা আরপাহোর মতো আরো একত্রিত ভাষায় এক এই পত্রিকাটি বিশ্লেষণ এবং সিন্টেটিক ভাষাকে বিশ্লেষণ করার সমাধান প্রস্তাব করে বিশ্লেষণ এবং বিশ্লেষণের সমাধানের প্রস্তাব করে বিদ্যমান টাইলজিক্যা</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek představuje "cestovní mapu" pro anotaci sémantických kategorií v typologicky různých jazycích, s potenciálně málo jazykových zdrojů a často žádnými existujícími výpočetními zdroji. Dřívější snahy o sémantickou anotaci se zaměřily převážně na jazyky s vysokými zdroji nebo na jazyky s relativně nízkými zdroji s velkým počtem rodilých mluvčích. Existují však určité typologické rysy, konkrétně syntéza více pojmů do jednoho slova, které jsou častější v jazycích s menší řečovou komunitou. Například, co je vyjádřeno jako věta ve více analytickém jazyce, jako je angličtina, může být vyjádřeno jako jediné slovo v syntetickém jazyce, jako je Arapaho. Tento článek navrhuje řešení pro analýzu a syntetických jazyků srovnatelným způsobem na základě existujícího typologického výzkumu a představuje cestovní mapu pro anotaci jazyků s nedostatkem zdrojů.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa esitetään tiekartta semanttisten luokkien merkitsemiseksi typologisesti erilaisilla kielillä, joilla on mahdollisesti vähän kielellisiä resursseja ja usein ei ole olemassa laskennallisia resursseja. Aiemmat semanttiset merkinnät ovat keskittyneet pitkälti suuriresurssisiin kieliin tai suhteellisen vähäresurssisiin kieliin, joissa on suuri määrä äidinkielenään puhuvia. On kuitenkin olemassa tiettyjä typologisia piirteitä, nimittäin useiden käsitteiden synteesiä yhdeksi sanaksi, jotka ovat yleisempiä kielillä, joilla on pienempi puheyhteisö. Esimerkiksi se, mikä ilmaistaan lauseena analyyttisemmällä kielellä, kuten englanniksi, voidaan ilmaista yhtenä sanana synteettisemmällä kielellä, kuten arapaho. Tässä työssä ehdotetaan ratkaisuja analyyttisten ja synteettisten kielten merkitsemiseen vertailukelpoisella tavalla olemassa olevaan typologiseen tutkimukseen perustuen ja esitellään etenemissuunnitelma resurssien puutteellisten kielten merkitsemiseen.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz semantik kategoriýalary typolojik dürli dillerde ýazyklamak üçin 'road map' görkezýär, güýçli bir az dil çeşmeleri bilen we köplenç hiç hili hasaplanç çeşmeleri ýok. Geçen semantik duýdurma çabalary ýeke-çeşmeli dillerde iň köp görnüşde durýar, ýada birnäçe ýeke-çeşme dillerde iň köp görnüş diller bilen üns berildi. Ýöne, köp düşünjäniň sintezi birnäçe söze bolan tapylyklaryň belli hasaplary bar, bu iň kiçi söz jemgyýeti bilen has köp bölegi. Mesela, iňlis dilinde köp analitik dilde sözlem diýip a ýdylanýan, Arapaho ýaly syntetik dilde ýeke söz bolup biler. Bu kagyz analytik we sintetik dillerini mevcut typolojik araştyrmalarda daýanýan ýaly çözgütler üçin çözümleri teklip edip, we bu käzirki çeşmeler üçin ýüz görkezilýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_jv>Awak-awak iki gunakake 'path map' kanggo kelengatan kelas semantar neng sampeyan urip, lan akeh liyane ingkang kaya bantuan, lan padha akeh sistem komputasi sing gak dhéwé. Wulangan sematik tor Awak dhéwé, ana karo akeh tipik-alaman sing gak, mengko, seneng pisan karo akeh sing klok saben kelas, kuwi wis aséwé kanggo wong liyane karo komunitas sing nyenyane. Sampeyan, ono sing dipun ngomong kapan bangsane kanggo ingkang, iso dipun ngomong nik awak dhéwé seneng pisan bangsane koyo arapapa. Perusahaan iki supoyo perusahaan kanggo nggunakake tarjamahan karo sistem sing nggawe geraraning kapan winih, lan ingkang dianggawe mapan kanggo langkung banjuré karo perusahaan kelas.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Wannan karatun na bãyar da wani 'karan hanya' wa mai sanar da categories na semanti cikin lingui masu motsi, da littafi kaɗan na fassarar harshen, kuma ko daidai ba da manyan lissafi. Bayan aikin sharuya na semanti da aka ƙara, sun yi zura girma a kan harshen sarki-resource, ko kuma yana da ɗan-wuri-resource da wasu masu saurãre masu hushi. A lokacin da, akwai wasu matabbata masu typogi, ɗai'a, kafin zato-zato masu yawa zuwa wata magana guda, waɗanda ke da abu mafi kawaici cikin harshe da jamii ƙaranci. Misali, abin da aka ƙayyade shi kamar wata kalma cikin harshen mai fassara kamar Ingiriya, za'a iya bayyana shi kamar wata magana guda cikin harshen da ke ƙaranci kamar AraPaho. Wannan karatun na buƙata masu yin fasalin lugha masu yin analyta da synthetic da ke daidaita a kan hanyar da ke samar da littafan taƙaita, kuma yana ƙara wata karanta ga kunnufi lugha da yunwa mai girma.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>העיתון הזה מציג "מפה דרכים" עבור הערות של קטגוריות סמנטיות בשפות טיפולוגיות מגוונות, עם פוטנציאל מעט משאבים שפותיים, ולעתים קרובות אין משאבים חישובים קיימים. מאמצי הערות סמנטיים בעבר התמקדו בעיקר בשפות משאבים גבוהים, או שפות משאבים נמוכות יחסית עם מספר גדול של דוברים מקומיים. However, there are certain typological traits, namely the synthesis of multiple concepts into a single word, that are more common in languages with a smaller speech community.  לדוגמה, מה מוביע בתור משפט בשפה אנליטית יותר כמו אנגלית, יכול להיות מוביע בתור מילה אחת בשפה סינטטית יותר כמו ארפאו. העבודה הזו מציעה פתרונות להציג שפות אנליטיות וסינטטיות בדרך שווה מבוססת על מחקר טיפולוגי קיים, ומציג מפה דרך להציג שפות עם חסר משאבים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku je predstavljen 'časovni načrt' za označevanje semantičnih kategorij v tipološko različnih jezikih, z potencialno malo jezikovnih virov in pogosto brez obstoječih računalniških virov. Pretekla prizadevanja za semantično označevanje so se v veliki meri osredotočila na jezike z visokimi viri ali relativno nizkimi viri z velikim številom maternih govorcev. Vendar pa obstajajo določene tipološke lastnosti, namreč sinteza več konceptov v eno besedo, ki so pogostejše v jezikih z manjšo govorno skupnostjo. Na primer, kar je izraženo kot stavek v bolj analitičnem jeziku, kot je angleščina, se lahko izrazi kot ena beseda v bolj sintetičnem jeziku, kot je Arapaho. Prispevek predlaga rešitve za označevanje analitičnih in sintetičnih jezikov na primerljiv način, ki temelji na obstoječih tipoloških raziskavah, in uvaja načrt za označevanje jezikov s pomanjkanjem virov.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>This paper presents a 'road map' for the annotation of semantic categories in typologically diverse languages, with potentially few linguistic resources, and often no existing computational resources. དེ་ལྟ་བུའི་སྔོན་ཤུགས་བསྡད་པའི་སྐད་ཡིག་གཙང་ཆ་ཁག་ཅིག་མཐོང་ནུས་མེད་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་ལ་མཐོང་ནུས་མེད་པ་དང་ཡང་ན ཡིན་ནའང་། དབྱེ་རིགས་ཀྱི་ཁྱད་ཆོས་ཁག་ཅིག་ཡིན། དེ་དག་ཚིག་རྐང་ཆ་གཅིག་ནང་གི་ཚིག དཔེར་ན། ཨིན་ཡིག་དང་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་ཀྱི་སྐད་ཡིག ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་དང་དབྱེ་སྟངས་ཅན་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལྟར་མཉམ་དུ་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་ཐབས་ཤིག་བྱས་ཡོད་པའི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་བཤད་ཐབས་ལམ་ཞིག་བྱེད་ཀྱི་</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>K-SNACS : Annotating Korean Adposition Semantics<fixed-case>SNACS</fixed-case>: Annotating <fixed-case>K</fixed-case>orean Adposition Semantics</title>
      <author><first>Jena D.</first><last>Hwang</last></author>
      <author><first>Hanwool</first><last>Choe</last></author>
      <author><first>Na-Rae</first><last>Han</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathan</first><last>Schneider</last></author>
      <pages>53–66</pages>
      <abstract>While many languages use adpositions to encode <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantic relationships</a> between content words in a sentence (e.g., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agent_(grammar)">agentivity</a> or temporality), the details of how adpositions work vary widely across languages with respect to both form and meaning. In this paper, we empirically adapt the SNACS framework (Schneider et al., 2018) to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Korean_language">Korean</a>, a language that is typologically distant from Englishthe language SNACS was based on. We apply the SNACS framework to annotate the highly popular novellaThe Little Prince with semantic supersense labels over allKorean postpositions. Thus, we introduce the first broad-coverage corpus annotated with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Korean_language">Korean postposition semantics</a> and provide a detailed analysis of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> with an apples-to-apples comparison between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Korean_language">Korean</a> and English annotations</abstract>
      <url hash="a692e159">2020.dmr-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>hwang-etal-2020-k</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>