<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.cmcl">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Workshop on Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Emmanuele</first><last>Chersoni</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Cassandra</first><last>Jacobs</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yohei</first><last>Oseki</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Laurent</first><last>Prévot</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Enrico</first><last>Santus</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="0f45807d">2020.cmcl-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>cmcl-2020-cognitive</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Images and Imagination : Automated Analysis of Priming Effects Related to Autism Spectrum Disorder and Developmental Language Disorder</title>
      <author><first>Michaela</first><last>Regneri</last></author>
      <author><first>Diane</first><last>King</last></author>
      <author><first>Fahreen</first><last>Walji</last></author>
      <author><first>Olympia</first><last>Palikara</last></author>
      <pages>11–27</pages>
      <abstract>Different aspects of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_processing_in_the_brain">language processing</a> have been shown to be sensitive to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priming_(psychology)">priming</a> but the findings of studies examining priming effects in adolescents with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) and Developmental Language Disorder (DLD) have been inconclusive. We present a study analysing visual and implicit semantic priming in adolescents with ASD and DLD. Based on a dataset of fictional and script-like narratives, we evaluate how often and how extensively, content of two different priming sources is used by the participants. The first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priming_(psychology)">priming source</a> was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_system">visual</a>, consisting of images shown to the participants to assist them with their storytelling. The second priming source originated from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commonsense_knowledge">commonsense knowledge</a>, using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crowdsourcing">crowdsourced data</a> containing prototypical script elements. Our results show that individuals with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autism_spectrum">ASD</a> are less sensitive to both types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priming_(psychology)">priming</a>, but show typical usage of primed cues when they use them at all. In contrast, children with DLD show mostly average priming sensitivity, but exhibit an over-proportional use of the priming cues.</abstract>
      <url hash="48db37b4">2020.cmcl-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.cmcl-1.2</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939683" />
      <bibkey>regneri-etal-2020-images</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Production-based Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</a></title>
      <author><first>Adrian</first><last>Brasoveanu</last></author>
      <author><first>Jakub</first><last>Dotlacil</last></author>
      <pages>28–37</pages>
      <abstract>We introduce a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_framework">framework</a> in which production-rule based computational cognitive modeling and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">Reinforcement Learning</a> can systematically interact and inform each other. We focus on linguistic applications because the sophisticated rule-based cognitive models needed to capture linguistic behavioral data promise to provide a stringent test suite for RL algorithms, connecting RL algorithms to both accuracy and reaction-time experimental data. Thus, we open a path towards assembling an experimentally rigorous and cognitively realistic benchmark for RL algorithms. We extend our previous work on lexical decision tasks and tabular RL algorithms (Brasoveanu and Dotlail, 2020b) with a discussion of neural-network based approaches, and a discussion of how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parsing</a> can be formalized as an RL problem.</abstract>
      <url hash="422514e9">2020.cmcl-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.cmcl-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>brasoveanu-dotlacil-2020-production</bibkey>
    <title_ar>النماذج المعرفية القائمة على الإنتاج كمجموعة اختبار لخوارزميات التعلم المعززة</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Modelos cognitivos baseados em produção como um conjunto de testes para algoritmos de aprendizado por reforço</title_pt>
      <title_es>Modelos cognitivos basados en la producción como conjunto de pruebas para algoritmos de aprendizaje por refuerzo</title_es>
      <title_fr>Modèles cognitifs basés sur la production en tant que suite de tests pour les algorithmes d'apprentissage par renforcement</title_fr>
      <title_ja>強化学習アルゴリズムのテストスイートとしての生産ベースの認知モデル</title_ja>
      <title_zh>盖生者识模为强学算法之试套件</title_zh>
      <title_hi>सुदृढीकरण सीखने एल्गोरिदम के लिए एक परीक्षण सूट के रूप में उत्पादन-आधारित संज्ञानात्मक मॉडल</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Производственные когнитивные модели как тестовый набор для алгоритмов обучения подкреплению</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Múnlaí Cognaíocha atá Bunaithe ar Tháirgeadh mar Shraith Tástála d'Algartam Foghlama Neartaithe</title_ga>
      <title_el>Γνωστικά μοντέλα βασισμένα στην παραγωγή ως σουίτα δοκιμών για αλγόριθμους μάθησης ενίσχυσης</title_el>
      <title_hu>Gyártásalapú kognitív modellek mint tesztcsomag a megerősítési tanulási algoritmusokhoz</title_hu>
      <title_ka>პროექციის დაბათი კოგენტიური მოდელები როგორც ტესტის სუტი სწავლების ალგორტიმებისთვის</title_ka>
      <title_it>Modelli cognitivi basati sulla produzione come suite di test per algoritmi di apprendimento di rinforzo</title_it>
      <title_kk>Өндіру негіздеген когнитивті үлгілер алгоритмдерді жақсарту тізімі ретінде</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Gamyba pagrįsti pažintiniai modeliai kaip mokymosi stiprinimu algoritmų bandymų rinkinys</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Production-based Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</title_ms>
      <title_mk>Production-based Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</title_mk>
      <title_ml>വീണ്ടും പഠിക്കുന്ന ആല്‍ഗോരിത്മുകള്‍ക്കുള്ള പരീക്ഷണത്തിനുള്ള സ്യൂട്ട് ആയി നിര്‍മ്മിക്കുക</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Mudelli Konjittivi bbażati fuq il-produzzjoni bħala Suite tat-Test għall-Algoritmi tat-Tagħlim tar-Rinfurzar</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Үндсэн Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for reinforcement Learning Algorithms</title_mn>
      <title_no>Produksjonsbasert kognitiv modeller som ein testpakke for forstørringsgoritme</title_no>
      <title_ro>Modele cognitive bazate pe producție ca suită de testare pentru algoritmii de învățare consolidată</title_ro>
      <title_pl>Modele poznawcze oparte na produkcji jako zestaw testowy dla algorytmów uczenia się wzmocnienia</title_pl>
      <title_sv>Produktionsbaserade kognitiva modeller som testsvit för inlärningsalgoritmer för förstärkning</title_sv>
      <title_so>Tusaale-horaadka ka soo saarista Qognitive oo ah Suurka imtixaanka waxbarashada dugsiga</title_so>
      <title_sr>Produkcija bazirani kognitivni modeli kao testni paket za pojačanje algoritma učenja</title_sr>
      <title_si>නිර්මාණය අධිර්‍යාත්මක සංවිධානය සඳහා පරීක්ෂණ සුයිට් විදියට පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා</title_si>
      <title_ta>உருவாக்கு அடிப்படையான குறியீட்டு மாதிரிகள் மீண்டும் அறிவிப்பு அல்gorithms</title_ta>
      <title_ur>پیدائش کی بنیادی Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Chế độ nhận thức sản xuất là phòng thử nghiệm cho sự phát triển học bổ sung.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Производствени базирани когнитивни модели като тест комплект за подсилване на алгоритми за обучение</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Productiegebaseerde cognitieve modellen als testsuite voor versterkingsleeralgoritmes</title_nl>
      <title_de>Produktionsbasierte kognitive Modelle als Testsuite für Reinforcement Learning Algorithmen</title_de>
      <title_id>Model Pengetahuan Berdasarkan Produsi sebagai Suite Ujian untuk Algoritma Belajar Pengesahan</title_id>
      <title_hr>Modeli kognitivnih modela na temelju proizvodnje kao testni paket za pojačanje algoritma učenja</title_hr>
      <title_da>Produktionsbaserede kognitive modeller som testpakke til forstærket læringsalgoritmer</title_da>
      <title_fa>Models Cognitive based on Production as a Test Suite for reinforcement Learning Algorithms</title_fa>
      <title_af>Produksie-gebaseerde Cognitive Models as 'n Toets Suit vir Versterking Leer Algoritme</title_af>
      <title_tr>Üýtgetmek üçin ýetişdirmek üçin test paketi olarak tabanly Cognitive Modeller</title_tr>
      <title_ko>제품의 인지 모델을 바탕으로 학습 알고리즘을 강화하는 테스트 세트로 삼다</title_ko>
      <title_am>የውይይት መድረክ</title_am>
      <title_sw>Modeli za Kitambua kilichotokana na uzalishaji kama Mkutano wa Jariba Kujifunza Uhamasifu</title_sw>
      <title_az>칖st칲nl칲k-tabanl캼 Cognitive Modell톛r 칐yr톛nm톛 Algoritl톛ri Test Sueti kimi</title_az>
      <title_bs>Produkcijski kognitivni modeli kao testni paket za pojačanje algoritma učenja</title_bs>
      <title_hy>արտադրության հիմնված կոգնիտիվ մոդելները որպես ուժեղացման սովորելու ալգորիթմների փորձարկումներ</title_hy>
      <title_sq>Production-based Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</title_sq>
      <title_ca>Production-based Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Tuotantopohjaiset kognitiiviset mallit testikokonaisuutena oppimisalgoritmien vahvistamiseen</title_fi>
      <title_bn>পুনঃসংক্রান্ত শিক্ষা অ্যালগরিদমের জন্য পরীক্ষা সাইট হিসেবে প্রজন্ম ভিত্তিক কনফিনিট মোডেল</title_bn>
      <title_cs>Kognitivní modely založené na produkci jako testovací sada pro algoritmy posílení učení</title_cs>
      <title_et>Tootmispõhised kognitiivsed mudelid kui õppe tugevdamise algoritmide testikomplekt</title_et>
      <title_jv>Manual-basa CoGNative model nganggo Test Sute kanggo Réngforcement Learning Algorithms</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Kognitivni modeli, ki temeljijo na produkciji, kot testni komplet za krepitev algoritmov učenja</title_sk>
      <title_he>מודלים קוניטיביים מבוססים על יצירה כחליפת מבחן לאלגוריתם ללמוד חיבורי</title_he>
      <title_bo>Production-based Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</title_bo>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم إطارًا يمكن فيه للنمذجة المعرفية الحاسوبية والتعلم المعزز المستندة إلى قواعد الإنتاج التفاعل بشكل منهجي وإعلام بعضهما البعض. نحن نركز على التطبيقات اللغوية لأن النماذج المعرفية المتطورة المستندة إلى القواعد اللازمة لالتقاط البيانات السلوكية اللغوية تعد بتوفير مجموعة اختبار صارمة لخوارزميات RL ، وربط خوارزميات RL بكل من الدقة والبيانات التجريبية لوقت رد الفعل. وبالتالي ، فإننا نفتح الطريق نحو تجميع معيار دقيق تجريبيًا وواقعيًا من الناحية المعرفية لخوارزميات RL. قمنا بتوسيع عملنا السابق على مهام القرار المعجمي وخوارزميات RL الجدولية (Brasoveanu and Dotlačil، 2020b) بمناقشة النهج القائمة على الشبكة العصبية ، ومناقشة كيف يمكن إضفاء الطابع الرسمي على التحليل باعتباره مشكلة RL.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos uma estrutura na qual a modelagem cognitiva computacional baseada em regras de produção e o Aprendizado por Reforço podem interagir sistematicamente e informar um ao outro. Nós nos concentramos em aplicações linguísticas porque os sofisticados modelos cognitivos baseados em regras necessários para capturar dados comportamentais linguísticos prometem fornecer um conjunto de testes rigoroso para algoritmos RL, conectando algoritmos RL a dados experimentais de precisão e tempo de reação. Assim, abrimos um caminho para a montagem de um benchmark experimentalmente rigoroso e cognitivamente realista para algoritmos de RL. Estendemos nosso trabalho anterior sobre tarefas de decisão lexical e algoritmos de RL tabulares (Brasoveanu e Dotlačil, 2020b) com uma discussão sobre abordagens baseadas em redes neurais e uma discussão de como a análise sintática pode ser formalizada como um problema de RL.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Nous introduisons un cadre dans lequel la modélisation cognitive computationnelle basée sur des règles de production et l'apprentissage par renforcement peuvent systématiquement interagir et s'informer mutuellement. Nous nous concentrons sur les applications linguistiques, car les modèles cognitifs sophistiqués basés sur des règles nécessaires pour capturer des données comportementales linguistiques promettent de fournir une suite de tests rigoureux pour les algorithmes RL, reliant les algorithmes RL aux données expérimentales de précision et de temps de réaction. Ainsi, nous ouvrons la voie vers l'assemblage d'une référence rigoureuse sur le plan expérimental et réaliste sur le plan cognitif pour les algorithmes RL. Nous élargissons nos travaux précédents sur les tâches de décision lexicales et les algorithmes RL tabulaires (Brasoveanu et Dotlačil, 2020b) avec une discussion sur les approches basées sur les réseaux neuronaux et une discussion sur la façon dont l'analyse peut être formalisée en tant que problème RL.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos un marco en el que el modelado cognitivo computacional basado en reglas de producción y el aprendizaje por refuerzo pueden interactuar e informarse sistemáticamente entre sí. Nos centramos en las aplicaciones lingüísticas porque los sofisticados modelos cognitivos basados en reglas necesarios para capturar datos de comportamiento lingüístico prometen proporcionar un conjunto de pruebas riguroso para los algoritmos de RL, conectando los algoritmos de RL con datos experimentales de precisión y tiempo de reacción. Por lo tanto, abrimos un camino hacia el ensamblaje de un punto de referencia experimentalmente riguroso y cognitivamente realista para los algoritmos de RL. Ampliamos nuestro trabajo anterior sobre las tareas de decisión léxica y los algoritmos de RL tabulares (Brasoveanu y Dotlačil, 2020b) con una discusión de enfoques basados en redes neuronales y una discusión sobre cómo se puede formalizar el análisis como un problema de RL.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>生産ルールに基づく計算認知モデリングと強化学習が体系的に相互作用し、相互に情報を伝えることができるフレームワークを紹介します。言語行動データをキャプチャするために必要な洗練されたルールベースの認知モデルは、RLアルゴリズムを正確さと反応時間の両方の実験データに接続する、RLアルゴリズムのための厳格なテストスイートを提供することを約束するため、私たちは言語学的アプリケーションに焦点を当てています。したがって、我々は、実験的に厳密で、認知的に現実的なRLアルゴリズムのベンチマークを組み立てるための道を開く。私たちは、ニューラルネットワークに基づくアプローチについての議論と、構文解析をRL問題として形式化する方法についての議論で、語彙決定タスクと表形式RLアルゴリズム（ Brasoveanu and Dotlačil, 2020 b ）に関する以前の仕事を拡張しました。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>引入一框架,于此框架中,基生业之数建模与化学相系统地相得而相告也。 臣等专于言用,以获言行数之本,杂识模形RL算法严试套件,系以RL算之准确性反应时间实验数。 因为RL算法组装实验谨识开一路。 吾扩吾前词汇决策、表格RL算法(Brasoveanu、Dotlačil、2020b),论其神经网络法,论其解析形式化为RL。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>Мы вводим структуру, в которой основанное на правилах производства когнитивное моделирование и обучение подкреплению могут систематически взаимодействовать и информировать друг друга. Мы сосредоточены на лингвистических приложениях, потому что сложные когнитивные модели, основанные на правилах, необходимые для захвата лингвистических поведенческих данных, обещают предоставить строгий набор тестов для алгоритмов RL, соединяющих алгоритмы RL с экспериментальными данными как по точности, так и по времени реакции. Таким образом, мы открываем путь к сборке экспериментально строгого и когнитивно реалистичного эталона для алгоритмов RL. Мы расширяем нашу предыдущую работу по лексическим задачам принятия решений и табличным алгоритмам RL (Brasoveanu and Dotlačil, 2020b) обсуждением нейросетевых подходов, а также обсуждением того, как синтаксический анализ может быть формализован как задача RL.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_hi>हम एक रूपरेखा पेश करते हैं जिसमें उत्पादन-नियम आधारित कम्प्यूटेशनल संज्ञानात्मक मॉडलिंग और सुदृढीकरण सीखना व्यवस्थित रूप से बातचीत कर सकता है और एक-दूसरे को सूचित कर सकता है। हम भाषाई अनुप्रयोगों पर ध्यान केंद्रित करते हैं क्योंकि भाषाई व्यवहार डेटा को कैप्चर करने के लिए आवश्यक परिष्कृत नियम-आधारित संज्ञानात्मक मॉडल आरएल एल्गोरिदम के लिए एक कठोर परीक्षण सूट प्रदान करने का वादा करते हैं, जो आरएल एल्गोरिदम को सटीकता और प्रतिक्रिया-समय प्रयोगात्मक डेटा दोनों से जोड़ते हैं। इस प्रकार, हम आरएल एल्गोरिदम के लिए एक प्रयोगात्मक रूप से कठोर और संज्ञानात्मक रूप से यथार्थवादी बेंचमार्क को इकट्ठा करने की दिशा में एक रास्ता खोलते हैं। हम लेक्सिकल निर्णय कार्यों और सारणीबद्ध आरएल एल्गोरिदम (Brasoveanu और Dotlaçil, 2020b) पर तंत्रिका-नेटवर्क आधारित दृष्टिकोणों की चर्चा के साथ अपने पिछले काम का विस्तार करते हैं, और इस बात की चर्चा करते हैं कि पार्सिंग को आरएल समस्या के रूप में कैसे औपचारिक रूप दिया जा सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Tugaimid creat isteach inar féidir le samhaltú ríomhaireachtúil bunaithe ar rialacha táirgthe agus Foghlaim Neartaithe idirghníomhú go córasach agus eolas a chur ar a chéile. Dírímid ar fheidhmchláir theangeolaíocha mar gheall ar na samhlacha cognaíocha sofaisticiúla atá bunaithe ar rialacha a theastaíonn chun sonraí iompraíochta teangeolaíocha a ghabháil geallaimid go soláthrófar sraith tástála docht d’algartaim RL, ag nascadh algartaim RL le sonraí turgnamhacha beachtas agus am freagartha. Mar sin, osclaíonn muid cosán i dtreo tagarmharcáil atá dian go turgnamhach agus atá réalaíoch go cognaíoch a chur le chéile le haghaidh halgartaim RL. Leathnaímid ár n-obair roimhe seo ar thascanna cinnteoireachta foclóireachta agus ar algartaim RL táblaí (Brasoveanu agus Dotlačil, 2020b) le plé ar chur chuige néar-bhunaithe, agus plé ar conas is féidir parsáil a chur ar bhonn foirmiúil mar fhadhb RL.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Bevezetünk egy olyan keretet, amelyben a termelési szabályokon alapuló számítástechnikai kognitív modellezés és a megerősítési tanulás szisztematikusan interakcióba léphet és tájékoztathatja egymást. A nyelvi alkalmazásokra összpontosítunk, mert a nyelvi viselkedési adatok rögzítéséhez szükséges kifinomult szabályalapú kognitív modellek szigorú tesztcsomagot biztosítanak az RL algoritmusok számára, amelyek összekapcsolják az RL algoritmusokat a pontossággal és a reakcióidővel kapcsolatos kísérleti adatokkal. Így megnyitjuk az utat az RL algoritmusok kísérletileg szigorú és kognitívan reális referenciaértékének összeállításához. Korábbi lexikális döntési feladatokkal és táblázatos RL algoritmusokkal kapcsolatos munkánkat (Brasoveanu and Dotlacil, 2020b) kiterjesztjük neurális hálózati alapú megközelítések megvitatásával, valamint arról, hogy az elemzés hogyan formalizálható RL problémaként.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Εισάγουμε ένα πλαίσιο στο οποίο η υπολογιστική γνωστική μοντελοποίηση βασισμένη σε κανόνες παραγωγής και η μάθηση ενίσχυσης μπορούν συστηματικά να αλληλεπιδρούν και να ενημερώνονται μεταξύ τους. Εστιάζουμε σε γλωσσικές εφαρμογές, επειδή τα εξελιγμένα γνωστικά μοντέλα βασισμένα σε κανόνες που απαιτούνται για τη σύλληψη γλωσσικών δεδομένων συμπεριφοράς υπόσχονται να παρέχουν μια αυστηρή σειρά δοκιμών για αλγόριθμους συνδέοντας αλγόριθμους τόσο με δεδομένα ακρίβειας όσο και με πειραματικά δεδομένα χρόνου αντίδρασης. Έτσι, ανοίγουμε μια πορεία προς τη συγκέντρωση ενός πειραματικά αυστηρού και γνωστικά ρεαλιστικού σημείου αναφοράς για αλγόριθμους RL. Επεκτείνουμε την προηγούμενη εργασία μας σχετικά με τα καθήκοντα λεξικών αποφάσεων και τους πίνακες αλγόριθμους RL (Μπρασοβέανου και Dotlacil, 2020β) με μια συζήτηση προσεγγίσεων βασισμένων σε νευρωνικά δίκτυα, και μια συζήτηση για το πώς η ανάλυση μπορεί να τυπικοποιηθεί ως πρόβλημα RL.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ ჩვენ შევცვალოთ ფრამეტრი, რომელიც პროექტიური კომპუტიური კომპუტიური მოდელირება და სწავლობა შეუძლიათ სისტემატიურად ინტერქექტირება და ინფორმაცია ერთ ჩვენ ლინგურისტიკური პროგრამებზე კონფიქტიკური კონფიგური მოდელები, რომლებიც ლინგურისტიკური ქცევის მონაცემებისთვის გავაკეთებთ, რომელიც RL ალგორიტებისთვის ძალიან სტრუქტური ტესტის სუტი, რომელიც RL ალგორიტე ამიტომ, ჩვენ გახსნა გზა როგორც ექსპერიმენტიურად ძალიან და კონციგურად რეალიჟრურად რეალიჟრურად ალგორიტიმებისთვის შესაბამისათვის. ჩვენ ჩვენი წინა სამუშაო მუშაო ლექსიკალური გადაწყვეტილების და ტაბულური RL ალგორიტიმების (Brasoveanu და Dotlacil, 2020b) განსაზღვრებით ნეიროლური ქსელის მიღებების განსაზღვრებით და განსაზღვრებით როგორ გადაწყ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Introduciamo un framework in cui la modellazione cognitiva computazionale basata su regole di produzione e il Reinforcement Learning possono interagire sistematicamente e informarsi reciprocamente. Ci concentriamo sulle applicazioni linguistiche perché i sofisticati modelli cognitivi basati su regole necessari per catturare i dati comportamentali linguistici promettono di fornire una suite di test rigorosa per gli algoritmi RL, collegando gli algoritmi RL a dati sperimentali di precisione e tempo di reazione. In questo modo, apriamo un percorso verso l'assemblaggio di un benchmark sperimentalmente rigoroso e cognitivamente realistico per gli algoritmi RL. Estendiamo il nostro precedente lavoro sui compiti decisionali lessicali e sugli algoritmi RL tabulari (Brasoveanu e Dotlacil, 2020b) con una discussione di approcci basati su reti neurali, e una discussione su come il parsing possa essere formalizzato come problema RL.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Біз жасау ережелерінде компьютерлік конифициялық модель және қайталау оқытуы жүйелік түрде бір-біріне байланысты және мәлімет беруге болады. Біз лингвистикалық қолданбаларға назар аударып тұрмыз, себебі лингвистикалық әрекеттер деректерін алгоритмдер үшін RL алгоритмдеріне жеткілікті сынақтар сәйкес беру үшін, RL алгоритмдерін дұрыс және қайталау уақытты эксперименталдық деректер Осылайша, біз RL алгоритмдер үшін тәжірибелі және конитивтік реалистикалық банк белгісін біріктіру үшін жолды ашық. Біз лексикалық шешімдерді және қойындылық RL алгоритмдерін (Brasoveanu және Dotlacil, 2020b) негіздеген неврал желінің жағдайлары туралы дискуссиясын жасап, анализ қалай RL мәселесі ретінде официалды.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Įdiegiame sistemą, pagal kurią pagal gamybos taisykles pagrįstas kompiuterinis pažintinis modeliavimas ir mokymasis stiprinimu gali sistemingai sąveikauti ir informuoti vienas kitą. Mes daugiausia dėmesio skiriame kalbiniams taikymams, nes sudėtingi taisyklėmis pagrįsti pažintiniai modeliai, reikalingi kalbiniams elgesio duomenims surinkti, žada suteikti griežtą RL algoritmų bandymų rinkinį, jungiantį RL algoritmus su tikslumu ir eksperimentiniais duomenimis apie reakcijos laiką. Taigi mes atveriame kelią eksperimentiškai griežtam ir kognityviai realistiniam RL algoritmų lyginamuoju rodikliu surinkti. Pratęsime savo ankstesnį darbą, susijusį su leksinių sprendimų užduotimis ir lenteliniais RL algoritmais (Brasoveanu ir Dotlacil, 2020b), diskutuodami apie nerviniu tinklu pagrįstus metodus ir diskutuodami apie tai, kaip analizavimą galima formalizuoti kaip RL problem ą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Ние воведуваме рамка во која компјутативното коњитивно моделирање и училиште за зајакнување базирано на производството може систематски да интерактираат и да се информираат меѓусебно. Ние се фокусираме на лингвистичките апликации бидејќи софистицираните коњитивни модели базирани на правилата потребни за заземање на лингвистичките податоци за однесување ветуваат дека ќе обезбедат строг тестовен апликација за RL алгоритми, поврзувајќи ги RL алгоритмите со точноста и експерименталните под Така, отвораме пат кон собирање експериментално строги и когнитивно реални реалгистички стандарди за алгоритмите на РЛ. Ние ја продолжуваме нашата претходна работа на лексикалните задачи за одлуки и табуларните алгоритми на РЛ (Brasoveanu и Dotlacil, 2020b) со дискусија за пристапи базирани на неурална мрежа, и дискусија за тоа како анализирањето може да се формализира како проблем на РЛ.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami memperkenalkan kerangka di mana pemodelan komputasi kognitif berdasarkan peraturan-produksi dan Pelajaran Penyukuran boleh berinteraksi secara sistematik dan memberitahu satu sama lain. Kami fokus pada aplikasi bahasa kerana model kognitif berdasarkan peraturan yang sophistik diperlukan untuk menangkap data perilaku bahasa berjanji untuk menyediakan suite ujian yang ketat untuk algoritma RL, menyambung algoritma RL dengan data percubaan akurat dan masa reaksi. Oleh itu, kita membuka jalan untuk mengumpulkan benchmark secara eksperimen yang ketat dan secara kognitif realistik untuk algoritma RL. We extend our previous work on lexical decision tasks and tabular RL algorithms (Brasoveanu and Dotlacil, 2020b) with a discussion of neural-network based approaches, and a discussion of how parsing can be formalized as an RL problem.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>We introduce a framework in which production-rule based computational cognitive modeling and Reinforcement Learning can systematically interact and inform each other.  നമ്മള്‍ ഭാഷകങ്ങളുടെ പ്രയോഗത്തില്‍ ശ്രദ്ധിക്കുന്നു. കാരണം സോഫിസ്റ്റിക്കല്‍ നിയമപരമായ കോഗ്രിനിറ്റിവ് മോഡലുകള്‍ ഭാഷകങ്ങളുടെ സ്വഭാവിക വാക്കുകള്‍ പിടിക്കേണ്ടി വന്നത അതുകൊണ്ട്, നമ്മള്‍ ഒരു പാത ത തുറന്നുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു പരീക്ഷണത്തില്‍ കഠിനമായും പരീക്ഷിക്കപ്പെടുന്ന ഒരു ബെന്‍മാര്‍ക ഞങ്ങള്‍ ലെക്സിക്കല്‍ തീരുമാനത്തിന്റെ ജോലികളെക്കുറിച്ചും പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട RL അല്‍ഗോരിത്മുകളെക്കുറിച്ചും നമ്മുടെ മുമ്പുള്ള ജോലി വിശാലമാക്കുന്നു. ബ്രാസോവെയ്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nintroduċu qafas li fih l-immudellar konjittiv komputattiv ibbażat fuq ir-regoli tal-produzzjoni u t-Tagħlim tar-Rinforz jistgħu jinteraġixxu u jinfurmaw lil xulxin b’mod sistematiku. Aħna niffokaw fuq applikazzjonijiet lingwistiċi minħabba li mudelli konjittivi sofistikati bbażati fuq ir-regoli meħtieġa biex jinqabdu dejta lingwistika dwar l-imġiba jwiegħdu li jipprovdu sett strett ta’ testijiet għall-algoritmi RL, li jgħaqqdu l-algoritmi RL kemm mad-dejta sperimentali ta’ preċiżjoni kif ukoll mal-ħin tar-reazzjoni. Thus, we open a path towards assembling an experimentally rigorous and cognitively realistic benchmark for RL algorithms.  Aħna jestendu l-ħidma preċedenti tagħna dwar kompiti ta' deċiżjoni lexika u algoritmi tabulari RL (Brasoveanu u Dotlacil, 2020b) b'diskussjoni dwar approċċi bbażati fuq netwerk newrali, u diskussjoni dwar kif l-analiżi tista' tiġi formalizzata bħala problem a RL.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Бид үйлдвэрлэлийн дүрэм дээр тооцооллын мэдээллийн модель болон нэмэгдүүлэх суралцах систематик харилцаа холбогдох боломжтой хэлбэрийг танилцуулдаг. Бид хэлний хэрэглэмжүүд дээр анхаарлаа анхаарлаа хандуулдаг. Учир нь хэлний дасгал хөдлөлийн байдлын мэдээллийг барьж, RL алгоритмын шалгалтыг ашиглах шаардлагатай, RL алгоритмыг зөв болон урвалын цагийн туршилтын мэдээллээр холбох шаардлагатай байдаг. Тэгэхээр бид туршилтын тулд жижиг, коgniцийн бодит алгоритмыг цуглуулахын тулд зам ашиглаж байна. Бид өмнөх ажлыг Лексик шийдвэрлэлийн даалгаврууд болон таблицын РЛ алгоритмын талаар (Brasoveanu, Dotlacil, 2020b) тархины сүлжээнд суурилсан ойлголтын тухай ярилцаж, харин хэрхэн хуваалцах нь RL асуудал гэж официалчлагдсан талаар ярилцаж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Vi introduserer eit rammeverk som produksjonsregel basert på databasert kognitiv modellering og forstørringar kan systematisk samarbeide og informera kvarandre. Vi fokuserer på linguistiske program fordi den sofistikerte regelsbaserte kognitive modelane trengte for å ta opp linguistiske atferdsdata for å gjera ein streng test suite for RL-algoritme, og kopla RL-algoritme til både nøyaktighet og eksperimentert data for reaksjonstid. Derfor opnar vi ein bane mot å samla inn ein eksperimentelt sterk og kognitivt realistisk benchmark for RL-algoritme. Vi utvidar vårt tidlegare arbeid på leksiske beslutningsdata og tabulære RL-algoritme (Brasoveanu og Dotlacil, 2020b) med diskusjon om nøyralnettverksbaserte tilnærmingar og diskusjon om korleis analysering kan formaliserast som eit RL-problem.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo okvir u kojem se računalno kognitivno modeliranje i učenje pojačanja može sistematski interakciji i obavijestiti jedni druge. Fokusiramo se na jezičke aplikacije jer su sofisticirani kognitivni modeli na pravilima potrebni da uhvatimo podatke o jezičkim ponašanju obećavaju da će pružiti težak test apartman za RL algoritme, povezati RL algoritme i sa tačnostima i eksperimentalnim podacima na vrijeme reakcije. Zato otvaramo put ka okupljanju eksperimentalno rigorog i kognitivno realnog kritika za RL algoritme. Proširimo naš prethodni rad o zadacima leksičke odluke i tabularnim algoritmima RL (Brasoveanu i Dotlacil, 2020b) sa diskusijom o pristupima na neuralnoj mreži, i diskusijom o tome kako se analiza može formalizirati kao problem RL.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අපි ප්‍රවෘත්තිය-නීතිය අධාරිත පරික්ෂණික පරික්ෂණ පරීක්ෂණාත්මක විද්‍යාපනය සහ ආපහු ප්‍රවෘත්තියක් ඉගෙනීම අපි භාෂාවික භාෂාවික භාෂාවික භාෂාවික භාෂාවික භාෂාවික භාෂාවික භාෂාවික භාෂාවික දත්ත අල්ලගන්න අවශ්‍ය නිසා භාෂාවික භාෂාවික භ ඉතින්, අපි පරීක්ෂණයෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් සම්බන්ධ කරනවා RL ඇල්ගෝරිත්මස් වලට පරීක්ෂණයක් සම්බන්ධ කරනවා. අපි ලෙක්සිකාලි තීරණය සහ ටැබුල් RL ඇල්ගෝරිතම් වලට අපේ කලින් වැඩ කරන්නේ (බ්‍රාසෝවෙනු සහ ඩොට්ලාසිල්, 2020b) න්‍යූරාල් ජාල ප්‍රශ්නයක් සඳහා කතා කරන්න,</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Vi introducerar ett ramverk där produktionsregelbaserad kognitiv modellering och Reinforcement Learning systematiskt kan interagera och informera varandra. Vi fokuserar på språkliga applikationer eftersom de sofistikerade regelbaserade kognitiva modeller som behövs för att fånga in språkliga beteendedata lovar att tillhandahålla en strikt testsvit för RL-algoritmer, som kopplar RL-algoritmer till både noggrannhet och reaktionstid experimentell data. På så sätt öppnar vi en väg mot att sammanställa ett experimentellt rigoröst och kognitivt realistiskt riktmärke för RL-algoritmer. Vi utökar vårt tidigare arbete med lexikala beslutsuppgifter och tabulära RL algoritmer (Brasoveanu och Dotlacil, 2020b) med en diskussion om neurala nätverksbaserade tillvägagångssätt och en diskussion om hur tolkning kan formaliseras som RL-problem.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_pl>Wprowadzamy ramy, w których oparte na regułach produkcji obliczeniowe modelowanie poznawcze i uczenie się wzmocnienia mogą systematycznie oddziaływać i informować się nawzajem. Koncentrujemy się na aplikacjach językowych, ponieważ zaawansowane modele poznawcze oparte na regułach potrzebne do przechwytywania językowych danych behawioralnych obiecują zapewnić rygorystyczny pakiet testowy dla algorytmów RL, łączący algorytmy RL zarówno z danymi eksperymentalnymi dokładności, jak i czasu reakcji. W ten sposób otwieramy drogę do zbudowania eksperymentalnie rygorystycznego i poznawczo realistycznego punktu odniesienia dla algorytmów RL. Nasze dotychczasowe prace nad zadaniami leksykalnymi decyzyjnymi i tabelarycznymi algorytmami RL (Brasoveanu i Dotlacil, 2020b) rozszerzamy o dyskusję podejść opartych na sieciach neuronowych oraz dyskusję na tym, jak parsowanie można sformalizować jako problem RL.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ta>நாம் ஒரு சட்டத்தை குறிப்பிடுகிறோம் அதில் உறுப்புவிதி குறிப்பிட்ட கணக்கீட்டு குறிப்பிட்ட மாதிரி மாதிரி மற்றும் திரும நாம் மொழிப்பாட்டு பயன்பாடுகளை கவனம் செலுத்துகிறோம். ஏனென்றால் மொழியில் உள்ள குறிப்பிட்ட குறிப்பான மாதிரிகளை பிடிக்க வேண்டும் மொழியில் நடத்தை தகவல் வாக்குறு அதனால், நாம் ஒரு சோதனையில் கடுமையான மற்றும் அறிந்து கொள்ளும் ஆர்எல் ஆல்கிரிங்களுக்கான ஒரு பாதையை திறக்கும். We extend our previous work on lexical decision tasks and tabular RL algorithms (Brasoveanu and Dotlacil, 2020b) with a discussion of neural-network based approaches, and a discussion of how parsing can be formalized as an RL problem.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ro>Introducem un cadru în care modelarea cognitivă computațională bazată pe reguli de producție și Reinforcement Learning pot interacționa sistematic și se pot informa reciproc. Ne concentrăm asupra aplicațiilor lingvistice deoarece modelele cognitive sofisticate bazate pe reguli necesare pentru captarea datelor comportamentale lingvistice promit să ofere o suită de testare strictă pentru algoritmii RL, conectând algoritmii RL atât la acuratețe, cât și la datele experimentale în timp de reacție. Astfel, deschidem calea spre asamblarea unui reper experimental riguros și cognitiv realist pentru algoritmii RL. Extindem activitatea noastră anterioară privind sarcinile decizionale lexicale și algoritmii RL tabelari (Brașoveanu și Dotlacil, 2020b) cu o discuție despre abordările bazate pe rețele neurale și o discuție despre modul în care parsarea poate fi formalizată ca o problemă RL.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu soo bandhignaynaa framework, kaas oo ku qoran sameynta koontarooyinka xisaabta iyo waxbarashada cusboonaysiinta waxay si systemic ah isula xiriiri karaan islamarkaasna isu ogeysiin karaan. Waxaynu ku kalsoonaynaa codsiyada afka, sababtoo ah modellada asalka sawirida ah oo loo baahan yahay in lagu qabto ballanqaadka danbiyada dabeecada luuqadda si uu u bixiyo hab adag oo lagu tijaabiyo algorityada RL, oo ku xiriira algorityada RL oo ku saabsan saxda iyo cadaalada dib u dhigidda. Sidaa darteed waxaynu furaynaa wado u soo ururinta qoraalka RL oo si dhab ah u adag oo aqoonta runta ah. Shaqo hore oo ku saabsan shaqooyinka go'aanka leksikada iyo qoraalka qoriga ah ee RL (Brasoveanu iyo Dotlacil, 2020b) ayaannu ku sii fidinaynaa hadal ku saabsan qaabab ku saleysan shabakadda neurada, iyo baaritaanka sida dhibaato RL looga sameeyo.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ur>ہم ایک فرمود پیش کریں گے جس میں پیدائش قانون کی بنیاد رکھتی ہے کمپیوٹریشن شناسی موڈلینگ اور دوبارہ افزایش کی تعلیم سیستماتیک طور پر اپنا اپنا معلوم کرسکتی ہے۔ ہم زبان الگوریتموں پر تمرکز کرتے ہیں کیونکہ رول الگوریتموں کے لئے ایک سخت امتحان سوئٹ کا وعدہ ہے کہ زبان الگوریتموں کے لئے رول الگوریتموں کو دقیق اور روک ٹیمٹی ٹیمٹی ڈیٹوں کے ساتھ اتصال کریں۔ اسی طرح ہم ایک طریقہ کھول دیتے ہیں RL الگوریتموں کے لئے ایک آزمائش کے ساتھ سخت اور معلومات طریقے کی بنچم مارک جمع کرنے کے لئے۔ ہم لکسیکل فیصلہ کے کاموں اور ٹیبل آل الگوریتم (Brasoveanu and Dotlacil, 2020b) کے بارے میں اگلے کام کو اضافہ کر رہے ہیں جنہیں نیورال نیٹ ورک کی طرف متوجہ ہونے والی طریقے کے ساتھ بحث کریں، اور ان کی بحث کیسے پارسی کرنا RL مسئلہ کے طور پر فرمولی کر سکتا ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Biz bir freymni anglatamiz. Bu yerda kompyuterning qoidasi asosiy kompyuterning modeli va Tahrirlash ta'limni tizim bilan boshqarish va boshqalarga aytish mumkin. Biz lingvistik dasturlariga foydalanamiz chunki sofistik qoidagi kognitiv modellari uchun lingvistik tabiiy maʼlumotni qabul qilish kerak, RL algoritlarga qiyin tizim boshqarishi mumkin, RL algoritlarini tasdiqlash va taymaviy tajriba maʼlumotga bog'lash kerak. Shunday qilib, biz RL algoritlarining tasavvur haqiqida, haqiqiqiy va haqiqiqiqiy saqlash uchun yoʻlni ochamiz. Biz oldingi leksikal xabarlar va tabiiy RL algoritlari (Brasoveanu va Dotlacil, 2020b), neyrol tarmoqning asosiy usullari haqida o'zgarishni ko'rsamiz va RL muammolari sifatida qanday bog'lash mumkin deb o'ylaymiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi giới thiệu một cơ sở để dựa trên quy tắc sản xuất để tạo mẫu nhận thức tính và phát triển học lực có thể liên hệ hệ và thông báo với nhau. Chúng tôi tập trung vào các ứng dụng ngôn ngữ vì các mô hình nhận thức quy định tinh vi cần thiết để thu thập dữ liệu về hành vi ngôn ngữ có hứa hẹn cung cấp một phòng thử nghiệm nghiêm ngặt cho các thuật to án RL, nối các thuật toán với cả độ chính xác lẫn thời gian thử nghiệm. Chúng ta mở một đường dẫn đến việc lắp đặt một tiêu chuẩn nghiên cứu khắt khe và nhận thức thực tế cho các thuật toán RL. Chúng tôi mở rộng công việc trước đây về các nhiệm vụ quyết định y học và thuật toán RL theo tính toán (Brasova và Dotlacil, 202020b) với một cuộc thảo luận về các phương pháp dựa trên mạng thần kinh, và một cuộc thảo luận xem làm thế nào phân tích có thể chính thức thành vấn đề RL.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_da>Vi introducerer en ramme, hvor produktionsregelbaseret beregningsmæssig kognitiv modellering og Reinforcement Learning systematisk kan interagere og informere hinanden. Vi fokuserer på sproglige applikationer, fordi de avancerede regelbaserede kognitive modeller, der er nødvendige for at indfange sproglige adfærdsdata, lover at levere en streng testpakke for RL algoritmer, der forbinder RL algoritmer til både nøjagtighed og reaktionstid eksperimentelle data. Således åbner vi en vej mod at samle et eksperimentelt strengt og kognitivt realistisk benchmark for RL algoritmer. Vi udvider vores tidligere arbejde med leksikalske beslutningsopgaver og tabulære RL algoritmer (Brasoveanu og Dotlacil, 2020b) med en diskussion af neurale netværksbaserede tilgange, og en diskussion om, hvordan parsing kan formaliseres som et RL problem.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Predstavljamo okvir u kojem se računalno kognitivno modeliranje i učenje pojačavanja može sistematski interakciji i obavijestiti jedni druge. Fokusiramo se na jezičke aplikacije jer su sofisticirani kognitivni modeli na pravilima potrebni za uhvatiti podatke o jezičkim ponašanjima obećavajući da će pružiti težak test apartman za RL algoritme, povezati RL algoritme i preciznim i eksperimentalnim podacima na vrijeme reakcije. Zato otvaramo put ka okupljanju eksperimentalno rigorog i kognitivno realnog kritika za RL algoritme. Proširimo naš prethodni rad o zadatkima leksičke odluke i tabularnim algoritmima RL (Brasoveanu i Dotlacil, 2020b) s raspravom o pristupima na temelju neuromreže i raspravom o tome kako se analiza može formalizirati kao problem RL.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Wir stellen ein Framework vor, in dem produktionsregelbasierte computergestützte kognitive Modellierung und Reinforcement Learning systematisch interagieren und sich gegenseitig informieren können. Wir konzentrieren uns auf linguistische Anwendungen, da die ausgeklügelten regelbasierten kognitiven Modelle, die zur Erfassung linguistischer Verhaltensdaten benötigt werden, versprechen, eine stringente Testsuite für RL-Algorithmen bereitzustellen, die RL-Algorithmen sowohl mit Genauigkeit als auch mit Reaktionszeitexperimentellen Daten verbindet. Damit eröffnen wir einen Weg zur Erstellung eines experimentell rigorosen und kognitiv realistischen Benchmarks für RL-Algorithmen. Wir erweitern unsere bisherigen Arbeiten zu lexikalischen Entscheidungsaufgaben und tabellarischen RL-Algorithmen (Brasoveanu und Dotlacil, 2020b) um eine Diskussion neuronaler Netzwerkansätze und eine Diskussion darüber, wie Parsing als RL-Problem formalisiert werden kann.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>We introduce a framework in which production-rule based computational cognitive modeling and Reinforcement Learning can systematically interact and inform each other.  Kami fokus pada aplikasi bahasa karena model kognitif berdasarkan peraturan yang sophistik yang diperlukan untuk menangkap data perilaku bahasa berjanji untuk menyediakan suite tes yang ketat untuk algoritma RL, menghubungkan algoritma RL dengan data percobaan akurasi dan waktu reaksi. Jadi, kita membuka jalan menuju mengumpulkan benchmark eksperimen yang rigor dan kognitif realistis untuk algoritma RL. We extend our previous work on lexical decision tasks and tabular RL algorithms (Brasoveanu and Dotlacil, 2020b) with a discussion of neural-network based approaches, and a discussion of how parsing can be formalized as an RL problem.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_bg>Въвеждаме рамка, в която базирано на производствени правила изчислително когнитивно моделиране и подсилващо обучение могат систематично да взаимодействат и да се информират взаимно. Фокусираме се върху лингвистичните приложения, защото усъвършенстваните, базирани на правила когнитивни модели, необходими за улавяне на лингвистични поведенчески данни обещават да осигурят строг тест за алгоритми, свързващи алгоритми както с точността, така и експерименталните данни за времето на реакция. По този начин откриваме път към сглобяване на експериментално строг и когнитивно реалистичен бенчмарк за алгоритми. Разширяваме предишната си работа по лексикални задачи за вземане на решения и таблични алгоритми (Брасовену и Дотлацил, 2020б) с дискусия за подходи, базирани на нервна мрежа, и дискусия за това как анализирането може да бъде формализирано като проблем.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We introduceren een raamwerk waarin op productieregels gebaseerde computationele cognitieve modellering en Reinforcement Learning systematisch met elkaar kunnen communiceren en elkaar kunnen informeren. We richten ons op linguïstische toepassingen omdat de geavanceerde, op regels gebaseerde cognitieve modellen die nodig zijn om linguïstische gedragsgegevens te verzamelen beloven een stringente testsuite te bieden voor RL-algoritmen, die RL-algoritmen verbinden met zowel nauwkeurigheids- als reactietijd experimentele gegevens. Zo openen we een pad naar het samenstellen van een experimenteel rigoureuze en cognitief realistische benchmark voor RL algoritmes. We breiden ons eerdere werk aan lexicale beslissingstaken en tabellaire RL algoritmes (Brasoveanu en Dotlacil, 2020b) uit met een discussie over neurale netwerkgebaseerde benaderingen, en een discussie over hoe parsen kan worden geformaliseerd als RL probleem.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaweza kutengeneza mfumo ambao utawala wa uzalishaji unaotengeneza miundo mbinu ya utambulisho na Elimu ya Ufumo unaweza kuingiliana na kutoa taarifa. Tunaweza lengo la matumizi ya lugha kwa sababu mifano yenye msingi wa utawala unahitaji kuchukua taarifa za tabia za lugha zinazoahidi kutoa matumizi makubwa ya uchunguzi kwa ajili ya algorithi za RL, inayounganisha vipimo vya RL kwa takwimu sahihi na wakati wa maoni. Kwa hiyo, tunafungua njia ya kukusanyika kwa unyanyasaji wa kisasa na kwa ujuzi wa ukweli wa misingi ya RL. Tunaendelea kazi yetu iliyopita kuhusu kazi za uamuzi wa lexico na vipimo vya RL vya kawaida (Brasoveanu na Dotlacil, 2020b) kwa mjadala wa mbinu zilizoko kwenye mtandao wa neura, na mjadala wa jinsi ubaguzi unavyoweza kuandaliwa kama tatizo la RL.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Biz üretim kurallarında sistematik bir şekilde etkileşip bir-birine haber verip biljek bir çerçeve girdik. Biz lingwistiki uygulamalara üns berip görýäris sebäbi sofistiki kural taýýarlanan cognitiv modelleri RL algoritmalar üçin gaty bir test sahypasyny bermek üçin gerekli, RL algoritmalaryny hem dogry we hem reaksiýa-wagt experimental maglumatlara baglaýarys. Bu yüzden, RL algoritmaları için deneysel derecede sert ve bilinçli bir takım şeklini toplamak için bir yolu a çıyoruz. Öňki işimizi leksiýa çözgüt görenleri we tabulýa RL algoritmalarynda (Brasoveanu we Dotlacil, 2020b) neural şebeke golaýlary barada çykyp geçirip, we bu çözümler Nähili RL mesele hökmünde formalytlanabilen diskusiýa etýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 생성식 규칙을 바탕으로 하는 계산 인지 모델링과 학습 강화가 체계적으로 상호작용하고 서로 알려줄 수 있는 구조를 소개했다.우리는 언어 응용 프로그램에 전념한다. 언어 행위 데이터 포획에 필요한 복잡한 규칙 기반 인지모델은 RL 알고리즘에 엄격한 테스트 세트를 제공하고 RL 알고리즘과 정확성과 반응 시 실험 데이터를 연결시키기로 약속했기 때문이다.따라서 우리는 RL 알고리즘을 위해 엄격한 실험과 인지 현실 기준을 조립하는 길을 열었다.우리는 신경 네트워크를 바탕으로 하는 방법에 대한 토론과 해석을 어떻게 RL로 형식화하는지에 대한 토론을 통해 어휘 결정 임무와 표 RL 알고리즘에 대한 우리의 작업(Brasoveanu와 Dotlacil, 2020b)을 확장시켰다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>ما یک چهارچوب را معرفی می کنیم که در آن مدل‌سازی شناخته‌های کامپیوتری و یادگیری افزایش‌سازی بر اساس قانون تولید می‌تواند سیستم‌پذیر و اطلاعات کند. ما روی کاربردهای زبان تمرکز می‌کنیم چون مدل‌های شناختی متفاوت بر قانون نیاز دارند تا داده‌های رفتاری زبان‌شناسی را دستگیر کنند که قول می‌دهند که یک suite سخت آزمایش برای الگوریتم‌های RL را ارتباط دهند، الگوریتم‌های RL را به داده‌های تجربه‌ی دقیق و زمان تأثیر بنابراین، ما مسیری را باز می‌کنیم که برای جمع آزمایش‌های آزمایشی یک نقشه‌بندی استوار و مفهومی واقعی برای الگوریتم‌های RL را باز می‌کنیم. ما کار قبلی را در مورد وظیفه‌های تصمیم‌گیری زبانی و الگوریتم‌های RL (Brasoveanu and Dotlacil, 2020b) گسترش می‌دهیم، با یک بحث از نزدیک‌های شبکه عصبی و بحث از چگونه بررسی‌گیری به عنوان یک مشکل RL فرمول می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Ons introduseer 'n raamwerk waarin produksie-reël gebaseer is rekenasielike kognitiewe modellering en versterking-leer kan sistematiese interaksie en mekaar inlig. Ons fokus op lingwisiese toepassings omdat die sofistike reël-gebaseerde kognitiewe modele benodig is om lingwisiese gedrag data belofte te vang om 'n stringende toets suite vir RL algoritme te verskaf, RL algoritme te koppel na beide presies en reaksie-tyd eksperimentale data. So, ons maak 'n pad oop na die versameling van 'n eksperimenteel rig en kognitief realistiese benchmark vir RL algoritme. Ons uitbrei ons vorige werk op leksiese besluit opdragte en tabulêre RL algoritme (Brasoveanu en Dotlacil, 2020b) met 'n diskusie van neuralnetwerk gebaseerde toegang, en 'n diskusie van hoe verwerking as 'n RL probleem formaliseer kan word.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>የሥርዓት ሥርዓት የተመሠረተውን አካባቢ ምሳሌ እና ትምህርት በተስማማማርና በተስማማማት ይጋጠማሉ እና እርስ በርሳቸውም ይነግራሉ፡፡ በቋንቋዊ ፕሮግራሞች ላይ እናስማምናለን ምክንያቱም የሶፊስቲክ ሥርዓት-ተመሳሳይ የቋንቋዊ ጥያቄ ዳታዎችን ለመያዝ ያስፈልጋል፡፡ RL አጎርጂትምን እና ትክክለኛ እና በጊዜው ተፈተና ዳታዎችን ለማስጠጋት የግል የሥርዓት ዳታዎችን ለመያዝ ያስፈልጋል፡፡ Thus, we open a path towards assembling an experimentally rigorous and cognitively realistic benchmark for RL algorithms.  የቀድሞው የሌክሲካዊ ፍርድ ስራዎችን እና አሌጎርቲዎችን (Brasoveanu እና Dotlacil, 2020b) የኔውራዊ መረብ ጥያቄዎችን እና የRL ጉዳይ መሆኑን እንዴት እንደምናደርገው ማነጋገር እና ማኅበረሰቢያን እናሳውቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Biz üretim hökmünü təşkil edirik ki, bir-birimizi sistematik təşkil edə bilər və bir-birimizə xəbər verirlər. Biz dillərin uyğulamalarına odaklanırıq çünki dillərin davranış məlumatlarını almaq üçün sofistikli qaydalar tabanlı kognitiv modellərin RL algoritmalarına a ğır bir sınama suiti vermək və RL algoritmalarını da tam və reaksiya-vaxtı eksperimenti məlumatlarına bağlamaq üçün lazımdır. Beləliklə, biz RL algoritmi üçün eksperimenti möhkəm və kognitiv reallı benchmark toplamaq üçün yolu a çırıq. Biz əvvəlki işimizi leksik kararlar işləri və tabular RL algoritmi (Brasoveanu and Dotlacil, 2020b) ilə nöral a ğ tərəfindən tərəfindən olanlar barəsində mübahisə edirik və RL problemi olaraq necə analizi formalizə edilə bilər?</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>We introduce a framework in which production-rule based computational cognitive modeling and Reinforcement Learning can systematically interact and inform each other.  আমরা ভাষাগত অ্যাপ্লিকেশনের দিকে মনোযোগ দিচ্ছি কারণ সাফিক্সিক শাসনের ভিত্তিক কঙ্গিনিভিত্তিক মডেলটি ভাষাগত আচরণের প্রতিশ্রুতি প্রদান করার জন্য প্রয়োজনীয় ভাষায় ভাষায় তাই আমরা এক পরীক্ষার জন্য একটি কঠোর এবং পরীক্ষার সাথে সমাবেশ করার পথ খুলে দিচ্ছি আরএল অ্যালগরিদমের জন্য। আমরা লেক্সিকাল সিদ্ধান্তের কাজ এবং ট্যাবুলাল আরএল এল্গোরিদম (ব্রাসোভেয়ান এবং ডটলাসিল, ২০২০বি) নিউরুল নেটওয়ার্ক ভিত্তিক উপায় নিয়ে আলোচনার সাথে আমাদের আগের কাজ বৃদ্</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo okvir u kojem se računalno kognitivno modeliranje i učenje pojačanja može sistematski interakciji i obavijestiti jedni druge. Fokusiramo se na jezičke aplikacije jer su sofisticirani kognitivni modeli na pravilima potrebni da uhvatimo podatke o jezičkim ponašanju obećavaju da će pružiti težak test apartman za algoritme RL-a, povezati algoritme RL-a sa preciznostima i eksperimentalnim podacima reakcije-vremena. Zato otvaramo put ka okupljanju eksperimentalno rigorog i kognitivno realnog kritika za RL algoritme. Proširimo naš prethodni rad o zadacima leksičke odluke i tabularnim algoritmima RL (Brasoveanu i Dotlacil, 2020b) sa raspravom o pristupima na osnovu neuromreže i raspravom o tome kako se analiza može formalizirati kao problem RL.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme rámec, ve kterém výpočetní kognitivní modelování založené na produkčních pravidlech a Reinforcement Learning mohou systematicky interagovat a navzájem se informovat. Zaměřujeme se na jazykové aplikace, protože sofistikované kognitivní modely založené na pravidlech potřebné pro zachycení jazykových behaviorálních dat slibují, že poskytnou přísný testovací sadu pro RL algoritmy, který propojuje RL algoritmy jak s přesností, tak s experimentálními daty v reakčním čase. Otevřeme tak cestu k sestavení experimentálně přísného a kognitivně realistického benchmarku pro RL algoritmy. Naši předchozí práci na lexikálních rozhodovacích úlohách a tabulkových RL algoritmech (Brasoveanu a Dotlacil, 2020b) rozšiřujeme o diskusi přístupů založených na neuronových sítích a diskusi o tom, jak lze parsování formalizovat jako RL problém.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_hy>We introduce a framework in which production-rule based computational cognitive modeling and Reinforcement Learning can systematically interact and inform each other.  We focus on linguistic applications because the sophisticated rule-based cognitive models needed to capture linguistic behavioral data promise to provide a stringent test suite for RL algorithms, connecting RL algorithms to both accuracy and reaction-time experimental data.  Այսպիսով, մենք բացում ենք ճանապարհ RL ալգորիթմների փորձարկվող խիստ և ճանաչողական իրականության հարաբերականների հավաքելու համար: Մենք ընդլայնում ենք մեր նախորդ աշխատանքը լեքսիկական որոշումների խնդիրների և ՌL ալգորիթմների վրա (Բրազովեանո և Դոթլացիլ, 2020b) նյարդային ցանցի հիմնված մոտեցումների քննարկումներով և քննարկումների վրա, թե ինչպես կարելի է վերլուծել վերլուծությունը որպես ՌL խնդի</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_et>Tutvustame raamistikku, kus tootmisreeglitel põhinev arvutuslik kognitiivne modelleerimine ja tugevdusõpe saavad üksteist süstemaatiliselt suhelda ja teavitada. Keskendume keelelistele rakendustele, sest keerulised reeglitel põhinevad kognitiivsed mudelid, mis on vajalikud keeleliste käitumisandmete kogumiseks, lubavad pakkuda ranget testikomplekti RL algoritmidele, ühendades RL algoritmid nii täpsuse kui ka reaktsiooniaja eksperimentaalsete andmetega. Seega avame tee RL algoritmide eksperimentaalselt range ja kognitiivselt realistliku võrdlusaluse kokkupanemisele. Laiendame oma varasemat tööd leksikaalsete otsustusülesannete ja tabeliliste RL algoritmide (Brasoveanu ja Dotlacil, 2020b) aruteluga neurovõrgupõhistest lähenemisviisidest ning aruteluga, kuidas parsimist saab vormistada RL probleemina.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esittelemme viitekehyksen, jossa tuotantosääntöön perustuva laskennallinen kognitiivinen mallinnus ja Vahvistusoppiminen voivat systemaattisesti vuorovaikutuksessa ja tiedottaa toisilleen. Keskitymme kielellisiin sovelluksiin, koska kielellisen käyttäytymistiedon tallentamiseen tarvittavat pitkälle kehitetyt sääntöpohjaiset kognitiiviset mallit lupaavat tarjota tiukan testipaketin RL-algoritmeille, jotka yhdistävät RL-algoritmit sekä tarkkuus- että reaktioajan kokeellisiin tietoihin. Näin avaamme polun kohti kokeellisesti tiukkaa ja kognitiivisesti realistista vertailuarvoa RL-algoritmeille. Laajennamme aikaisempaa lexikaalisia päätöksentekotehtäviä ja taulukkopohjaisia RL-algoritmeja koskevaa työtämme (Brasoveanu ja Dotlacil, 2020b) keskustelemalla neuroverkkopohjaisista lähestymistavoista ja keskustelemalla siitä, miten jäsentäminen voidaan formalisoida RL-ongelmana.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>We introduce a framework in which production-rule based computational cognitive modeling and Reinforcement Learning can systematically interact and inform each other.  We focus on linguistic applications because the sophisticated rule-based cognitive models needed to capture linguistic behavioral data promise to provide a stringent test suite for RL algorithms, connecting RL algorithms to both accuracy and reaction-time experimental data.  Així, obrim un camí cap a la reunió d'un punt de referència experimentalment rigor i cognitivament realista per als algoritmes RL. Estendem la nostra feina anterior sobre tasques de decisió lèxica i algoritmes de RL tabulars (Brasoveanu i Dotlacil, 2020b) amb una discussió sobre enfocaments basats en xarxes neurals, i una discussió sobre com l'analització pot ser formalitzada com un problem a de RL.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_sq>Ne futim një kuadër në të cilin modelimi kompjuterik kognitiv bazuar në rregullat e prodhimit dhe mësimi i forcimit mund të ndërveprojnë sistematikisht dhe të informojnë njëri-tjetrin. We focus on linguistic applications because the sophisticated rule-based cognitive models needed to capture linguistic behavioral data promise to provide a stringent test suite for RL algorithms, connecting RL algorithms to both accuracy and reaction-time experimental data.  Kështu, ne hapim një rrugë drejt mbledhjes së një normë eksperimentalisht rigoroze dhe njohurisht realiste për algoritmet RL. Ne zgjerojmë punën tonë të mëparshme mbi detyrat e vendimit lexik dhe algoritmet tabulare RL (Brasoveanu dhe Dotlacil, 2020b) me një diskutim të qasjeve të bazuara në rrjetin nervor dhe një diskutim se si analizimi mund të formalizohet si një problem RL.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé nggawe sistem sing dianggawe barang nggawe sistem sing bisa nguasai model sing kompatif karo nggawe barang nggawe barang sistem sing bisa ttebagakake lan ijol-ijolan winih. Awak dhéwé éntuk kang aplikasi Linguistik merang akeh sistem sing sohistiké karo model sing sampeyan nggawe barang pengguna-pengguna kuwi nggawe data maning alaman sing nyimpen kanggo nggawe sistem tentang kanggo RL Algorithm, nambah RL politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Awak dhéwé katungé awak dhéwé cara-cara sing luwih nggawe gerakno karo akeh luwih sawar nggawe RL Algorithms</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna fara wani firam, a cikinsa akwai misalin kognitive masu bincike da Shirin Haƙin da Akwai ya iya haɗi da kuma ya sanar da jũna. Tuna fokus ga shiryoyin ayukan linguistic, kwani misãlai na sofi-asanin kognitive sun buƙata dõmin a kãma danne masu aikin linguistic da ake yi wa'adi wa'adin a cikin linguistic don ya ga ga jarraba mai tsanani wa algoritm na RL, sunã haɗi algoritori ga duk taƙaitacce da data na samun-muhimmanci. Haƙĩƙa, Munã buɗe wata hanya zuwa a samura wata taƙaita mai sauri da gaskiyar na gaskiyar da ke sani na algoritun RL. Mu shimfiɗa aikinmu na gabani a kan aikin keɓar leksiya da algorituman RL (brasovieanu da Dotlacil, 2020b) da wata jayayya a kan jerin-tarayya na neural, da wata jayayya a kan parse za'a formalize shi kamar wata mataimaki na RL.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo okvir, v katerem lahko računalniško kognitivno modeliranje in ojačevalno učenje sistematično interagirata in se obveščata. Osredotočamo se na jezikovne aplikacije, saj napredni kognitivni modeli, ki temeljijo na pravilih, potrebni za zajemanje jezikovnih vedenjskih podatkov, obljubljajo, da bodo zagotovili strog testni paket za algoritme RL, ki bodo algoritme RL povezovali z natančnostjo in eksperimentalnimi podatki o reakcijskem času. Tako odpiramo pot k sestavljanju eksperimentalno strogega in kognitivno realističnega merila za algoritme RL. Naše prejšnje delo na področju leksikalnih odločitev in tabularnih algoritmov RL (Brasoveanu in Dotlacil, 2020b) razširimo z razpravo o pristopih, ki temeljijo na nevronsko omrežju, in razpravo o tem, kako lahko razčlenitev formaliziramo kot problem RL.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་ལྟ་བུའི་ནང་དུ་གློག་རྩིས་གཞི་རྟེན་ནས་གྲངས་རིག We focus on linguistic applications because the sophisticated rule-based cognitive models needed to capture linguistic behavioral data promise to provide a stringent test suite for RL algorithms, connecting RL algorithms to both accuracy and reaction-time experimental data. འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་སྐྱེས་པའི་བརྒྱུད་ལམ་ཞིག་གི་མཉམ་དུ་གཏོང་གི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་ཁ་ཕྱེ་བ་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་དེ་ཧེ་མ་གྱི་ལས་ཀ་གདམ་གསེས་ཀྱི་བྱ་འགུལ་དང་ཤོག་བྱང་གི་RL Algorithms (Brasoveanu་དང་ Dotlacil,2020b)་དང་ཕྱོགས་ཡོད་པའི་སྐོར་ལས་གནད་དོན་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་དྲ་བ་བཤད་པ་དང་། ག</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו מציגים מסגרת שבה ניתוח חיובי קוגניטיבי מבוסס על חוקי הייצור וללמוד חיבורי יכול להתקשר באופן שיטתי ולהודיע אחד את השני. We focus on linguistic applications because the sophisticated rule-based cognitive models needed to capture linguistic behavioral data promise to provide a stringent test suite for RL algorithms, connecting RL algorithms to both accuracy and reaction-time experimental data.  לכן, אנו פותחים דרך לכיוון האיסוף נקודת רמז מתוקצת ומתאימה מבחינה ניסיונית לאלגוריטמים RL. אנו ממשיכים את העבודה הקודמת שלנו על משימות ההחלטה הלקסית ואלגוריתמים RL טבלונים (Brasoveanu ודוטלסיל, 2020b) עם דיון על גישות מבוססות ברשת עצבית, ודיון על כיצד אפשר לארגן את ההעברה כבעיה RL.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>