<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nlp4if">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 3rd NLP4IF Workshop on NLP for Internet Freedom: Censorship, Disinformation, and Propaganda</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Giovanni</first><last>Da San Martino</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Chris</first><last>Brew</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Giovanni Luca</first><last>Ciampaglia</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Feldman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Chris</first><last>Leberknight</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Preslav</first><last>Nakov</last></editor>
      <publisher>International Committee on Computational Linguistics (ICCL)</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="6daf5611">2020.nlp4if-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp4if-2020-nlp4if</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Two Stage Transformer Model for COVID-19 Fake News Detection and Fact Checking<fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 Fake News Detection and Fact Checking</title>
      <author><first>Rutvik</first><last>Vijjali</last></author>
      <author><first>Prathyush</first><last>Potluri</last></author>
      <author><first>Siddharth</first><last>Kumar</last></author>
      <author><first>Sundeep</first><last>Teki</last></author>
      <pages>1–10</pages>
      <abstract>The rapid advancement of technology in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_communication">online communication</a> via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media platforms</a> has led to a prolific rise in the spread of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misinformation">misinformation</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake news</a>. Fake news is especially rampant in the current COVID-19 pandemic, leading to people believing in false and potentially harmful claims and stories. Detecting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake news</a> quickly can alleviate the spread of panic, chaos and potential health hazards. We developed a two stage automated pipeline for COVID-19 fake news detection using state of the art <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning models</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a>. The first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> leverages a novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fact-checking">fact checking algorithm</a> that retrieves the most relevant facts concerning user queries about particular COVID-19 claims. The second model verifies the level of truth in the queried claim by computing the textual entailment between the claim and the true facts retrieved from a manually curated COVID-19 dataset. The dataset is based on a publicly available knowledge source consisting of more than 5000 COVID-19 false claims and verified explanations, a subset of which was internally annotated and cross-validated to train and evaluate our models. We evaluate a series of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> based on classical text-based features to more contextual Transformer based models and observe that a model pipeline based on BERT and ALBERT for the two stages respectively yields the best results.</abstract>
      <url hash="6a49755e">2020.nlp4if-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>vijjali-etal-2020-two</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/rutvikvijjali/COVID-19-Claims-Dataset" additional="false">rutvikvijjali/COVID-19-Claims-Dataset</pwccode>
    <title_ar>نموذج محولات من مرحلتين لكشف الأخبار الوهمية COVID-19 وتقصي الحقائق</title_ar>
      <title_es>Modelo de transformador de dos etapas para detección de noticias falsas de COVID-19 y verificación de hechos</title_es>
      <title_pt>Modelo de transformador de dois estágios para detecção de notícias falsas COVID-19 e verificação de fatos</title_pt>
      <title_fr>Modèle de transformateur en deux étapes pour la détection des fausses nouvelles COVID-19 et la vérification des faits</title_fr>
      <title_hi>कोविड-19 फेक न्यूज डिटेक्शन और फैक्ट चेकिंग के लिए दो स्टेज ट्रांसफॉर्मर मॉडल</title_hi>
      <title_ja>新型コロナウイルス偽ニュース検知・事実確認用2段変圧器タイプ</title_ja>
      <title_ru>Двухступенчатая модель трансформатора для обнаружения и проверки фактов фейковых новостей о COVID-19</title_ru>
      <title_zh>以COVID-19假新闻检核二等变压器模形</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Samhail Trasfhoirmeora Dhá Chéim le haghaidh Braite Nuachta Bréige COVID-19 agus Seiceáil Fíricí</title_ga>
      <title_ka>COVID- 19 ფაქტიური გახსნა და ფაქტის შემოწმება</title_ka>
      <title_it>Modello di trasformatore a due stadi per il rilevamento di notizie false COVID-19 e il controllo dei fatti</title_it>
      <title_el>Δύο στάδια μοντέλο μετασχηματιστών για την ανίχνευση πλαστών ειδήσεων και τον έλεγχο γεγονότων</title_el>
      <title_lt>Dviejų etapų konverterio modelis COVID-19 suklastotų naujienų aptikimui ir faktų patikrinimui</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Model Penukar Dua Tahap untuk pengesan berita palsu COVID-19 dan pemeriksaan Fakta</title_ms>
      <title_ml>COVID-19 ഫെയ്ക് വാര്‍ത്തകള്‍ കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള രണ്ട് സ്റ്റേജ് പരിശോധിക്കുന്ന മോഡല്‍</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Mudell ta’ Żewġ Stadji ta’ Trasformazzjoni għal COVID-19</title_mt>
      <title_kk>COVID- 19 қалған жаңалықтарды анықтау және факты тексеру үшін екі этап түрлендіруші үлгісі</title_kk>
      <title_no>To stadformeringsmodell for COVID- 19 falske informasjon- oppdaging og faktisksjekking</title_no>
      <title_mk>Модел за трансформирање на две фази за детектирање и проверка на факти на лажни вести COVID-19</title_mk>
      <title_ro>Model de transformator în două etape pentru detectarea știrilor false COVID-19 și verificarea faptelor</title_ro>
      <title_pl>Dwustopniowy model transformatora do wykrywania fałszywych wiadomości COVID-19 i sprawdzania faktów</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Две модела трансформирања класа за фалшивну информацију и проверку факта COVID-19</title_sr>
      <title_hu>Kétfokozatú transzformátor modell a COVID-19 hamis hírek felismeréséhez és tények ellenőrzéséhez</title_hu>
      <title_so>Two Stage Transfer Model for COVID-19 Find and Fact Checking</title_so>
      <title_si>COVID- 19 වැරදි වාර්තාව පරීක්ෂණය සහ ඇත්ත පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා ස්ටේජ් වෙනස් මොඩල් දෙකName</title_si>
      <title_ta>COVID- 19 பொய் செய்தி கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்கான இரண்டு நிலை மாற்றி மாற்றும் மாதிரி பாங்கு</title_ta>
      <title_ur>COVID-19 غلط خبروں کی آشنائی اور حقیقت چک کرنے کے لئے دو سٹیج ترنسفور موڈل</title_ur>
      <title_mn>COVID-19 худлаа мэдээлэл олох болон үнэний шинжилгээний хоёр сүүлийн шинжилгээчийн загвар</title_mn>
      <title_sv>Två steg transformatormodell för COVID-19 falska nyheter detektering och faktakontroll</title_sv>
      <title_uz>Two Stage Transformer Model for COVID-19 Fake News Detection and Fact Checking</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Mô hình Biến hình 2Stage cho COVID-19 Điều tra bản tin giả và Kiểm tra thực tế.</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Tweetraps Transformator Model voor COVID-19 Nepnieuws Detectie en Fact Checking</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Dva modela transformacije faze za otkrivanje lažnih vijesti i provjeru činjenica COVID-19</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Двуетапен трансформаторен модел за откриване на фалшиви новини и проверка на факти</title_bg>
      <title_da>To trins transformatormodel til COVID-19 falske nyheder detektering og faktatkontrol</title_da>
      <title_de>Zwei-Stufen-Transformator-Modell für COVID-19 Fake News Erkennung und Fakt Checking</title_de>
      <title_fa>دو مدل تغییر‌پذیر مرحله برای بازرسی خبرهای فاعلی COVID-19</title_fa>
      <title_ko>코로나 가짜뉴스 검측과 사실 검증에 사용되는 2단계 변압기 모형</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Two Stage Transformer Model for COVID-19 Fake News Detection and Fact Checking</title_sw>
      <title_tr>COVID-19 ýalňyş Haýry Deteksi we Hat Barlamak üçin iki pake terjime Mody</title_tr>
      <title_id>Two Stage Transformer Model for COVID-19 Fake News Detection and Fact Checking</title_id>
      <title_sq>Model dy fazash i transformimit për zbulimin e lajmeve të rreme COVID-19 dhe kontrollimin e fakteve</title_sq>
      <title_am>የሁለት ደረጃ ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_az>COVID-19 sahtekar Haqq İşlənməsi və Fakat İşlənməsi üçün İki Stad Transformer Modeli</title_az>
      <title_bn>COVID-19 ফ্যাক সংবাদ সনাক্ত এবং ফ্যাক পরীক্ষার জন্য দুই স্টেগ ট্রান্সফার্নার মডেল</title_bn>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_bs>Dva faza transformatora modela za otkrivanje lažnih vijesti i provjeru činjenica COVID-19</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Two Stage Transformer Model for COVID-19 Fake News Detection and Fact Checking</title_ca>
      <title_et>Kaheastmeline transformaatori mudel COVID-19 võltsitud uudiste tuvastamiseks ja faktide kontrollimiseks</title_et>
      <title_hy>COVID-19 կեղծ նորությունների հայտնաբերման և փաստերի ստուգելու երկու փուլում</title_hy>
      <title_cs>Dvoufázový model transformátoru pro detekci falešných zpráv a kontrolu faktů COVID-19</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Kaksivaiheinen muuntaja malli COVID-19 väärennettyjen uutisten havaitsemiseen ja faktojen tarkistamiseen</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Iki Stage Transformer model kanggo CoVD-19 Fake Notify lan Ngatur Fake</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Dvostopenjski transformatorski model za odkrivanje lažnih novic COVID-19 in preverjanje dejstev</title_sk>
      <title_he>שני שלבים מודל מעברת עבור חיפוש חדשות מזויפות COVID-19 ובדיקת עובדות</title_he>
      <title_bo>COVID-19 འཆར་བའི་དྲན་འཛིན་དང་དུས་ཡིག་ཆ་ལྟ་ཞིབ་བྱེད་མཁན་ལྡན་རྣམ་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>أدى التقدم السريع للتكنولوجيا في الاتصال عبر الإنترنت عبر منصات وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي إلى ارتفاع كبير في انتشار المعلومات المضللة والأخبار المزيفة. تنتشر الأخبار الكاذبة بشكل خاص في جائحة COVID-19 الحالية ، مما يؤدي إلى اعتقاد الناس في الادعاءات والقصص الكاذبة والتي من المحتمل أن تكون ضارة. يمكن أن يؤدي اكتشاف الأخبار المزيفة بسرعة إلى التخفيف من انتشار الذعر والفوضى والمخاطر الصحية المحتملة. قمنا بتطوير خط أنابيب آلي من مرحلتين لاكتشاف الأخبار الوهمية لـ COVID-19 باستخدام أحدث نماذج التعلم الآلي لمعالجة اللغة الطبيعية. يستفيد النموذج الأول من خوارزمية جديدة للتحقق من الحقائق تسترجع الحقائق الأكثر صلة فيما يتعلق باستفسارات المستخدمين حول مطالبات معينة بشأن COVID-19. يتحقق النموذج الثاني من مستوى "الحقيقة" في الادعاء المشكوك فيه عن طريق حساب الاستنتاج النصي بين الادعاء والحقائق الحقيقية المسترجعة من مجموعة بيانات COVID-19 المنسقة يدويًا. تستند مجموعة البيانات إلى مصدر معرفة متاح للجمهور يتكون من أكثر من 5000 ادعاء كاذب COVID-19 وتفسيرات تم التحقق منها ، مجموعة فرعية منها تم شرحها داخليًا والتحقق من صحتها لتدريب وتقييم نماذجنا. نقوم بتقييم سلسلة من النماذج استنادًا إلى الميزات الكلاسيكية المستندة إلى النص إلى المزيد من النماذج السياقية القائمة على المحولات ونلاحظ أن خط الأنابيب النموذجي المستند إلى BERT و ALBERT للمرحلتين على التوالي ينتج أفضل النتائج.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>O rápido avanço da tecnologia na comunicação online por meio de plataformas de mídia social levou a um aumento prolífico na disseminação de desinformação e notícias falsas. As notícias falsas são especialmente desenfreadas na atual pandemia do COVID-19, levando as pessoas a acreditar em alegações e histórias falsas e potencialmente prejudiciais. A detecção rápida de notícias falsas pode aliviar a propagação do pânico, do caos e de possíveis riscos à saúde. Desenvolvemos um pipeline automatizado de dois estágios para detecção de notícias falsas COVID-19 usando modelos de aprendizado de máquina de última geração para processamento de linguagem natural. O primeiro modelo aproveita um novo algoritmo de verificação de fatos que recupera os fatos mais relevantes sobre consultas de usuários sobre reivindicações específicas do COVID-19. O segundo modelo verifica o nível de “verdade” na reivindicação consultada, computando a vinculação textual entre a reivindicação e os fatos verdadeiros recuperados de um conjunto de dados COVID-19 com curadoria manual. O conjunto de dados é baseado em uma fonte de conhecimento disponível publicamente que consiste em mais de 5.000 alegações falsas e explicações verificadas sobre a COVID-19, um subconjunto do qual foi anotado internamente e validado de forma cruzada para treinar e avaliar nossos modelos. Avaliamos uma série de modelos baseados em recursos clássicos baseados em texto para modelos baseados em Transformers mais contextuais e observamos que um pipeline de modelo baseado em BERT e ALBERT para os dois estágios, respectivamente, produz os melhores resultados.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>El rápido avance de la tecnología en la comunicación en línea a través de las plataformas de redes sociales ha llevado a un aumento prolífico de la difusión de información errónea y noticias falsas. Las noticias falsas están especialmente extendidas en la actual pandemia de COVID-19, lo que lleva a la gente a creer en afirmaciones e historias falsas y potencialmente dañinas. Detectar noticias falsas rápidamente puede aliviar la propagación del pánico, el caos y los posibles riesgos para la salud. Desarrollamos un canal automatizado de dos etapas para la detección de noticias falsas de COVID-19 utilizando modelos de aprendizaje automático de última generación para el procesamiento del lenguaje natural. El primer modelo aprovecha un novedoso algoritmo de verificación de datos que recupera los datos más relevantes relacionados con las consultas de los usuarios sobre afirmaciones particulares de COVID-19. El segundo modelo verifica el nivel de «verdad» en la afirmación consultada al calcular la relación textual entre la afirmación y los hechos reales recuperados de un conjunto de datos de COVID-19 curado manualmente. El conjunto de datos se basa en una fuente de conocimiento disponible públicamente que consta de más de 5000 afirmaciones falsas de COVID-19 y explicaciones verificadas, un subconjunto de las cuales se anotó internamente y se validó de forma cruzada para capacitar y evaluar nuestros modelos. Evaluamos una serie de modelos basados en características clásicas basadas en texto para modelos más contextuales basados en Transformer y observamos que una canalización de modelos basada en BERT y ALBERT para las dos etapas, respectivamente, produce los mejores resultados.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>Les progrès rapides de la technologie dans la communication en ligne via les plateformes de médias sociaux ont entraîné une augmentation prolifique de la désinformation et des fausses nouvelles. Les fausses nouvelles sont particulièrement répandues dans la pandémie actuelle de COVID-19, ce qui amène les gens à croire en des allégations et des histoires fausses et potentiellement dommageables. La détection rapide des fausses nouvelles peut atténuer la propagation de la panique, du chaos et des risques potentiels pour la santé. Nous avons développé un pipeline automatisé en deux étapes pour la détection des fausses nouvelles liées à la COVID-19 à l'aide de modèles d'apprentissage automatique de pointe pour le traitement du langage naturel. Le premier modèle utilise un nouvel algorithme de vérification des faits qui récupère les faits les plus pertinents concernant les demandes des utilisateurs concernant des allégations COVID-19 particulières. Le second modèle vérifie le niveau de « vérité » de la demande interrogée en calculant l'implication textuelle entre la déclaration et les faits réels récupérés à partir d'un ensemble de données COVID-19 organisé manuellement. L'ensemble de données est basé sur une source de connaissances accessible au public comprenant plus de 5 000 fausses allégations liées à la COVID-19 et des explications vérifiées, dont un sous-ensemble a été annoté en interne et validé de manière croisée pour former et évaluer nos modèles. Nous évaluons une série de modèles basés sur des caractéristiques textuelles classiques à des modèles plus contextuels basés sur Transformer et nous observons qu'un pipeline de modèles basé sur BERT et ALBERT pour les deux étapes respectivement donne les meilleurs résultats.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>ソーシャルメディアプラットフォームを介したオンラインコミュニケーションにおけるテクノロジーの急速な進歩は、誤った情報やフェイクニュースの拡散を生み出しました。 フェイクニュースは、現在の新型コロナウイルスのパンデミック（世界的大流行）で特に横行しており、人々は誤った、潜在的に有害な主張やストーリーを信じるようになります。 フェイクニュースをすばやく検出することで、パニック、カオス、潜在的な健康被害の拡大を緩和することができます。 自然言語処理のための最先端の機械学習モデルを使用したCOVID -19フェイクニュース検出のための2段階の自動パイプラインを開発しました。 最初のモデルは、特定のCOVID -19の申し立てに関するユーザーの問い合わせに関する最も関連性の高い事実を取得する新規の事実確認アルゴリズムを活用しています。 第２のモデルは、クレームと、手動でキュレーションされたCOVID -19データセットから取得された真の事実との間のテキストの関連性を計算することによって、クエリされたクレームの「真実」のレベルを検証する。 このデータセットは、5000を超えるCOVID -19の虚偽の申し立てと検証済みの説明からなる公開されたナレッジソースに基づいており、そのサブセットは、当社のモデルをトレーニングおよび評価するために内部的に注釈が付けられ、相互検証されています。 私たちは、古典的なテキストベースの特徴に基づく一連のモデルをよりコンテキストベースのトランスフォーマーモデルに評価し、2つの段階のBERTとALBERTに基づくモデルパイプラインがそれぞれ最良の結果をもたらすことを観察します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>सोशल मीडिया प्लेटफार्मों के माध्यम से ऑनलाइन संचार में प्रौद्योगिकी की तेजी से प्रगति ने गलत सूचना और नकली समाचारों के प्रसार में विपुल वृद्धि की है। वर्तमान कोविड -19 महामारी में नकली समाचार विशेष रूप से बड़े पैमाने पर हैं, जिससे लोग झूठे और संभावित हानिकारक दावों और कहानियों में विश्वास करते हैं। नकली खबरों का जल्दी से पता लगाने से आतंक, अराजकता और संभावित स्वास्थ्य खतरों के प्रसार को कम किया जा सकता है। हमने प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रसंस्करण के लिए अत्याधुनिक मशीन लर्निंग मॉडल का उपयोग करके कोविड-19 नकली समाचारों का पता लगाने के लिए दो चरण की स्वचालित पाइपलाइन विकसित की है। पहला मॉडल एक उपन्यास तथ्य जांच एल्गोरिथ्म का लाभ उठाता है जो विशेष कोविड -19 दावों के बारे में उपयोगकर्ता प्रश्नों से संबंधित सबसे प्रासंगिक तथ्यों को पुनः प्राप्त करता है। दूसरा मॉडल दावे और मैन्युअल रूप से क्यूरेट किए गए कोविड -19 डेटासेट से प्राप्त वास्तविक तथ्यों के बीच पाठ्य अनिवार्यता की गणना करके प्रश्न किए गए दावे में "सत्य" के स्तर को सत्यापित करता है। डेटासेट एक सार्वजनिक रूप से उपलब्ध ज्ञान स्रोत पर आधारित है जिसमें 5000 से अधिक कोविड -19 झूठे दावे और सत्यापित स्पष्टीकरण शामिल हैं, जिनमें से एक सबसेट को आंतरिक रूप से एनोटेट किया गया था और हमारे मॉडल को प्रशिक्षित करने और मूल्यांकन करने के लिए क्रॉस-मान्य किया गया था। हम शास्त्रीय पाठ-आधारित विशेषताओं के आधार पर मॉडल की एक श्रृंखला का मूल्यांकन करते हैं और अधिक प्रासंगिक ट्रांसफॉर्मर आधारित मॉडल के लिए देखते हैं और देखते हैं कि दो चरणों के लिए BERT और ALBERT पर आधारित एक मॉडल पाइपलाइन क्रमशः सबसे अच्छे परिणाम देती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Быстрый прогресс технологий в онлайн-коммуникации через социальные медиа-платформы привел к быстрому росту распространения дезинформации и фейковых новостей. Фейковые новости особенно распространены в нынешней пандемии COVID-19, что приводит к тому, что люди верят в ложные и потенциально вредные утверждения и истории. Быстрое обнаружение фейковых новостей может облегчить распространение паники, хаоса и потенциальных опасностей для здоровья. Мы разработали двухэтапный автоматизированный конвейер для обнаружения фейковых новостей COVID-19 с использованием современных моделей машинного обучения для обработки естественного языка. Первая модель использует новый алгоритм проверки фактов, который извлекает наиболее важные факты, касающиеся запросов пользователей о конкретных утверждениях о COVID-19. Вторая модель проверяет уровень «правды» в запрошенном утверждении, вычисляя текстовое влечение между утверждением и истинными фактами, извлеченными из вручную курируемого набора данных о COVID-19. Набор данных основан на общедоступном источнике знаний, состоящем из более чем 5000 ложных утверждений о COVID-19 и проверенных объяснений, подмножество которых было внутренне аннотировано и перекрестно проверено для обучения и оценки наших моделей. Мы оцениваем ряд моделей на основе классических текстовых функций для более контекстуальных моделей на основе трансформатора и наблюдаем, что модель трубопровода на основе BERT и ALBERT для двух этапов соответственно дает наилучшие результаты.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_zh>社交媒体台在线流,错误信息假新闻增广。 假新闻于时COVID-19大行尤猖獗,信虚实之声明故事。 速检假新闻可以纾恐,乱潜于健害之传。 开COVID-19假新闻检两阶自动化管道,用最先进机器学自然语言处之。 首用一新事检算法,其算法检索用户特定COVID-19索赔最关事实。 第二模以算声明与从手动谋者COVID-19数集检得实事之间,以验声明之实。 其数集于公明可用之源,其源由5000余COVID-19虚明验解,其一子集内注交验,以训估之。 论列于经文,上下文于Transformer,观于BERT、ALBERT之道,各以两端为上。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Mar gheall ar dhul chun cinn tapa na teicneolaíochta sa chumarsáid ar líne trí ardáin na meán sóisialta, tá méadú as cuimse ar scaipeadh na mífhaisnéise agus na nuachta bréige. Tá nuacht bhréige go háirithe rampant sa phaindéim reatha COVID-19, rud a fhágann go gcreideann daoine in éilimh agus scéalta bréagacha agus a d’fhéadfadh a bheith díobhálach. Má aimsítear nuacht bhréige go tapa, is féidir leathadh scaoll, anord agus guaiseacha sláinte féideartha a mhaolú. D’fhorbraíomar píblíne uathoibrithe dhá chéim le haghaidh braite nuachta bréige COVID-19 ag baint úsáide as samhlacha meaisínfhoghlama den scoth le haghaidh próiseála teanga nádúrtha. Déanann an chéad mhúnla algartam seiceála fíricí nua a ghiaráil a aisghabhann na fíricí is ábhartha a bhaineann le fiosruithe úsáideoirí faoi éilimh áirithe COVID-19. Fíoraítear leis an dara samhail leibhéal na “fírinne” san éileamh a ceistíodh tríd an eiseamláir théacsúil idir an t-éileamh agus na fíorfhíorais a fuarthas ó thacar sonraí COVID-19 arna choimeád de láimh a ríomh. Tá an tacar sonraí bunaithe ar fhoinse eolais atá ar fáil go poiblí ina bhfuil níos mó ná 5000 éileamh bréagach COVID-19 agus míniúcháin fíoraithe, ar cuireadh fo-thacar díobh anótáilte go hinmheánach agus a chros-bhailíochtú chun ár samhlacha a oiliúint agus a mheas. Déanaimid meastóireacht ar shraith samhlacha bunaithe ar ghnéithe clasaiceacha téacs-bhunaithe go samhlacha níos comhthéacsúla atá bunaithe ar an gClaochladán agus tugaimid faoi deara go dtugann píblíne samhail bunaithe ar BERT agus ALBERT don dá chéim faoi seach na torthaí is fearr.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ტექნოლოგიის ძალიან წარმოდგენა საზოგადომი მედია პლატატურებისთვის ინტერნოლიკური კომუნიკაციაში, რომლებიც სოციალური მედია პლატატურებისთვის გახს ძალიან ახალი იყო განსაკუთრებით პონდემიკაში COVID-19, რომელიც ადამიანებს, რომელიც წარმოდგენენენ False და potentially harmful claims and stories. ტალქტური ნუზების განსახულება ძალიან შეუძლია გახსნათ პანტიკის, კაოსების და პოცენტური ჯანმრთელის გარეშე. ჩვენ COVID-19 ფაქტიური აღმოჩენისთვის ორი ფეზის ავტომატიკური ფეზის განვიყენება, რომელიც გამოყენება ხელსაწყოთა მაქინის სწავლების მოდელების მოდულების მოდულების მო პირველი მოდელი ახალი ფაქტის შემოწმება ალგორიტიმა, რომელიც ყველაზე მნიშვნელოვანი ფაქტის შესახებ მომხმარებელი კითხვების შესახებ COVID- 19 წესების შესახებ. მეორე მოდელი შემოწმება 'სიმართლის' სიმართლის სიმართლის სიმართლის სიმართლის სიმართლის შესახებ ტექსტულის შესახებ გამოწმება და მართლის ფაქტების შესახებ მონაცემების COVID- 19 მონაცემების კონფიგურაციის შესაბამისი ადამიანურად ხელმისაწარმოდგენებული მეცნიერების თვის, რომლებიც 5000-ზე მეტი COVID-19 წარმოდგენებით და დარწმუნებული გამოსახულებების შესაბამისათვის, რომელიც ჩვენი მოდელები ჩვენ კლასიკური ტექსტის ფუნქციების ზოგიერთი მოდელების შესაბამისად კონტექსტურალური ტრანფორმეტურის მოდელების შესაბამისად ვუწერეთ, რომ მოდელური ფუნქცია BERT და ALBERT-ის დაბამისად ორი ფაესების შესაბა</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η ταχεία εξέλιξη της τεχνολογίας στην ηλεκτρονική επικοινωνία μέσω πλατφορμών κοινωνικών μέσων έχει οδηγήσει σε μια παραγωγική αύξηση της εξάπλωσης παραπληροφόρησης και ψεύτικων ειδήσεων. Τα ψεύτικα νέα είναι ιδιαίτερα ανεξέλεγκτα στην τρέχουσα πανδημία οδηγώντας τους ανθρώπους να πιστεύουν σε ψευδείς και δυνητικά επιβλαβείς ισχυρισμούς και ιστορίες. Η γρήγορη ανίχνευση ψεύτικων ειδήσεων μπορεί να ανακουφίσει την εξάπλωση του πανικού, του χάους και των πιθανών κινδύνων για την υγεία. Αναπτύξαμε έναν αυτοματοποιημένο αγωγό δύο σταδίων για την ανίχνευση ψεύτικων ειδήσεων χρησιμοποιώντας σύγχρονα μοντέλα μηχανικής μάθησης για επεξεργασία φυσικής γλώσσας. Το πρώτο μοντέλο χρησιμοποιεί έναν νέο αλγόριθμο ελέγχου γεγονότων που ανακτά τα πιο σχετικά γεγονότα σχετικά με ερωτήματα χρηστών σχετικά με συγκεκριμένους ισχυρισμούς. Το δεύτερο μοντέλο επαληθεύει το επίπεδο της "αλήθειας" στον ερωτηθέντα ισχυρισμό υπολογίζοντας το κείμενο μεταξύ του ισχυρισμού και των πραγματικών γεγονότων που ανακτώνται από ένα μη αυτόματο σύνολο δεδομένων. Το σύνολο δεδομένων βασίζεται σε μια δημόσια διαθέσιμη πηγή γνώσης που αποτελείται από περισσότερους από 5000 ψευδείς ισχυρισμούς και επαληθευμένες εξηγήσεις, ένα υποσύνολο των οποίων σχολιάστηκε εσωτερικά και επικυρώθηκε για να εκπαιδεύσει και να αξιολογήσει τα μοντέλα μας. Αξιολογούμε μια σειρά μοντέλων που βασίζονται σε κλασικά χαρακτηριστικά βασισμένα στο κείμενο σε μοντέλα που βασίζονται περισσότερο στο πλαίσιο και παρατηρούμε ότι ένας αγωγός μοντέλου βασισμένος σε BERT και ALBERT για τα δύο στάδια αποδίδει αντίστοιχα τα καλύτερα αποτελέσματα.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_lt>Dėl spartaus technologijų pažangos internetinėje komunikacijoje per social in ės žiniasklaidos platformas labai padidėjo klaidingos informacijos ir suklastotų naujienų sklaida. Klaidingos naujienos ypač paplitusios dabartinėje COVID-19 pandemijoje, dėl kurios žmonės tiki klaidingomis ir galimai žalingomis teiginėmis ir istorijomis. Greitai nustatyti suklastotas žinias gali palengvinti panikos, chaoso ir galimo pavojaus sveikatai plitimą. Mes sukūrėme dviejų etapų automatizuotą vamzdyną COVID-19 suklastotų naujienų aptikimui naudojant pažangiausius mašinų mokymosi modelius gamtiniam kalbų apdorojimui. Pirmasis modelis užtikrina naują faktų tikrinimo algoritmą, kuris gauna svarbiausius faktus, susijusius su vartotojų klausimais dėl konkrečių COVID-19 reikalavimų. The second model verifies the level of 'truth' in the queried claim by computing the textual entailment between the claim and the true facts retrieved from a manually curated COVID-19 dataset.  The dataset is based on a publicly available knowledge source consisting of more than 5000 COVID-19 false claims and verified explanations, a subset of which was internally annotated and cross-validated to train and evaluate our models.  Vertiname keletą modelių, pagrįstų klasikinėmis teksto savybėmis, pagal labiau kontekstinius Transformer pagrįstus modelius ir pastebime, kad modelio vamzdynas, pagrįstas BERT ir ALBERT atitinkamai dviem etapais, duoda geriausius rezultatus.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>Il rapido progresso della tecnologia nella comunicazione online attraverso le piattaforme di social media ha portato ad un aumento prolifico della diffusione di disinformazione e fake news. Le notizie false sono particolarmente dilaganti nell'attuale pandemia COVID-19, portando le persone a credere in affermazioni e storie false e potenzialmente dannose. Rilevare rapidamente notizie false può alleviare la diffusione di panico, caos e potenziali rischi per la salute. Abbiamo sviluppato una pipeline automatizzata in due fasi per il rilevamento delle fake news COVID-19 utilizzando modelli di machine learning all'avanguardia per l'elaborazione del linguaggio naturale. Il primo modello sfrutta un nuovo algoritmo di verifica dei fatti che recupera i fatti più rilevanti riguardanti le domande degli utenti su particolari reclami COVID-19. Il secondo modello verifica il livello di 'verità' nella rivendicazione interrogata calcolando il coinvolgimento testuale tra la rivendicazione e i fatti reali recuperati da un dataset COVID-19 curato manualmente. Il set di dati si basa su una fonte di conoscenza pubblicamente disponibile composta da oltre 5000 false dichiarazioni COVID-19 e spiegazioni verificate, un sottoinsieme dei quali è stato annotato internamente e convalidato per formare e valutare i nostri modelli. Valutiamo una serie di modelli basati su caratteristiche testuali classiche a modelli basati su Transformer più contestuali e osserviamo che una pipeline di modelli basata su BERT e ALBERT per le due fasi fornisce rispettivamente i migliori risultati.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Технологияның онлайн коммуникациясының тез жағдайы социалдық медиа платформалары арқылы жалғастыру және жалғастыру жаңалықтарды өзгерту үшін көптеген. Қазіргі COVID-19 пандемиясында жалғыз жаңалық жаңалықтар әсіресе жалғыз және мүмкін қауіпсіздік жаңалықтар мен оқиғаларға сенетін адамдарға көмектеседі. Жалғыз жаңалықтарды анықтау тез түрде паникалық, хаос және потенциаллық саулық қауіпсіздерін көтеруге болады. Біз COVID-19 жалғыз жаңалықтарды анықтау үшін автоматты түрде екі этап құрылдық. Біз табиғи тілді өңдеу үшін Сурет механизмінің оқыту үлгілерінің күйін қолданады. Бірінші үлгі пайдаланушылардың сұрауларының ең маңызды шындығын тексеру алгоритмін қалады. Екінші үлгі сұралған сұрақтардың 'шын' деңгейін тексереді. Сұрақтардың мәтін қатынасын есептеп, қолмен COVID- 19 деректер жиынынан алынған шын факттер арасындағы мәтін қатынасын есептеп береді. Деректер жинағы 5000 COVID- 19 дегеннен артық мәлімет көзіне негізделген, тексерілген түсініктемелердің бөлігі біздің үлгілерімізді оқыту және оқыту үшін ішкі түсініктемелері және бірнеше тексерілген. Біз классикалық мәтін негіздеген мүмкіндіктеріне негізделген бірнеше үлгілерді бағалап, контексті түрлендіруші үлгілеріне негізделген, BERT және ALBERT үлгілеріне негізделген үлгілер үлгілері екі этап ең жақсы</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Kemajuan cepat teknologi dalam komunikasi online melalui platform media sosial telah membawa kepada peningkatan yang luas dalam penyebaran salah maklumat dan berita palsu. Berita palsu terutama teruk dalam pandemi COVID-19 semasa, yang menyebabkan orang percaya pada klaim palsu dan kemungkinan berbahaya dan cerita. Mengesan berita palsu dengan cepat boleh mengurangi penyebaran panik, kekacauan dan bahaya kesehatan potensi. Kami mengembangkan saluran paip automatik dua tahap untuk pengesan berita palsu COVID-19 menggunakan model pembelajaran mesin seni untuk pemprosesan bahasa semulajadi. Model pertama menggunakan algoritma pemeriksaan fakta baru yang mengambil fakta yang paling berkaitan dengan pertanyaan pengguna mengenai klaim COVID-19 tertentu. Model kedua mengesahkan aras 'kebenaran' dalam klaim yang diminta dengan mengira penyelesaian teks antara klaim dan fakta sebenar yang diterima dari set data COVID-19 yang dikurasikan secara manual. Set data berdasarkan sumber pengetahuan yang tersedia kepada masyarakat yang terdiri dari lebih dari 5000 klaim palsu COVID-19 dan penjelasan yang disahkan, subkumpulan yang didaftar dalam dan disahkan salib untuk melatih dan menilai model kita. Kami menilai siri model berdasarkan ciri-ciri teks klasik kepada model berdasarkan Transformer yang lebih kontekstual dan memperhatikan bahawa garis paip model berdasarkan BERT dan ALBERT untuk kedua-dua tahap berdasarkan satu sama lain memberikan keputusan terbaik.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Брзото напредување на технологијата во онлајн комуникацијата преку платформи на социјалните медиуми доведе до пролифичен зголемување на ширењето на погрешни информации и лажни вести. Лажните вести се особено расипани во сегашната пандемија на COVID-19, што води до луѓето кои веруваат во лажни и потенцијално штетни тврдења и приказни. Брзо детектирање лажни вести може да го олесни ширењето на паниката, хаосот и потенцијалните опасности за здравјето. Развивме две фази автоматизиран гасовод за детекција на лажни вести COVID-19 користејќи модели за научување на најсовремени машини за природно обработување јазици. Првиот модел користи нов алгоритм за проверка на факти кој ги добива најрелевантните факти во врска со прашањата на корисниците за одредени тврдења на COVID-19. Вториот модел го потврдува нивото на „вистина“ во запрашаното тврдење со обчистување на текстуалното вмешање помеѓу тврдењето и вистинските факти извадени од рачно променет COVID-19 датотек. Податоците се базирани на јавно достапен извор на знаење кој се состои од повеќе од 5000 лажни тврдења на COVID-19 и верификувани објаснувања, од кои потсетот беше внатре анотиран и крстовалидиран за обука и оценка на нашите модели. Ние ја проценуваме серијата модели базирани на класични текстови карактеристики на поконтекстни трансформирани модели и забележуваме дека моделниот гасовод базиран на BERT и ALBERT за двете фази, односно, дава најдобри резултати.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>സോഷ്യല്‍ മീഡിയ പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോമുകള്‍ മുഖാനുപയോഗിച്ച് ഓണ്‍ലൈന്‍ സാങ്കേതികവിദ്യയുടെ വേഗത്തിലുള്ള സാങ്കേതികവിദ്യയു നിലവിലുള്ള കോവിഡി-19 പേടിയില്‍ വെറുതെ വാര്‍ത്തകള്‍ പ്രത്യേകിച്ച് കഥകളില്‍ വിശ്വസിക്കുന്ന ആളുകളെ കൊണ്ട് വരുത്തുന് കള്ള വാര്‍ത്തകള്‍ കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നത് പെട്ടെന്ന് വേഗം പേടിപ്പിക്കുന്നതും, കുഴപ്പമും സാധ്യതയുള്ള ആരോഗ്യത സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള കലാക്ഷ മെഷീന്‍ പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്ന മോഡലുകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ച് കോവിഡി-19 കള്ളസംസാ The first model leverages a novel fact checking algorithm that retrieves the most relevant facts concerning user queries about particular COVID-19 claims.  രണ്ടാമത്തെ മോഡല്‍ ചോദിക്കപ്പെട്ട കാര്യത്തില്‍ 'സത്യം' എന്ന നിലയില്‍ നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കുന്നു. കോവിഡി-19 ഡാറ്റാസെറ്റില്‍ നിന്നും കൈമുഖ്യൂട്ട ഈ ഡാറ്റാസെറ്റിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്താണ് 5000 കോവിഡി-19 കൂടുതല്‍ വ്യാജത്തിന്റെയും വിശദീകരണങ്ങളില്‍ ഉള്ള ഒരു പ്രസ്താവികമായ അറിവ് സ്രോതസ്സിന്റെ ക്ലാസിക്കല്‍ ടെക്സ്റ്റ് അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ അടിസ്ഥാനമാക്കിയ ഒരു സിരിക്കല്‍ മോഡലുകള്‍ നമ്മള്‍ വിലാസപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു. കൂടുതല്‍ ക്ലാസ്റ്റര്‍ ട്രാന്‍സ്ഫോര്‍മാ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Den raske avanserten av teknologien i nettkommunikasjonen via sosiale mediaplattformar har ført til ein utvida økning i spreidinga av feil informasjon og falske nyhetar. Falske nyhetar er spesielt rampant i den gjeldande pandemiske COVID-19, som fører til folk som tror på falske og potensielt skadelige antar og historiar. Å oppdage falske nyhetar kan fortsette spreidinga av panikk, kaos og potensielle helsefarger. Vi utvikla ein to stadig automatisk røyrlinje for COVID-19 falske informasjon ved hjelp av tilstanden til kunstmaskinelæringsmodeller for naturspråksbehandling. Den første modellen leverer eit nytt faktum for å sjekka algoritmen som hentar dei mest relevante faktane om brukaren spørjingar om spesielle COVID- 19-tiltak. Den andre modellen kontrollerer nivået « sannheit » i den spørsmålet ved å rekna ut tekstinnstillinga mellom oppgåva og sanne fakta som er henta frå ei manuelt korrigert COVID- 19 datasett. Datasettet er basert på ein offentlig tilgjengeleg kjelde for kunnskap som inneheld fleire enn 5000 COVID-19 feilsøknadar og verifiserte forklaringar. Dette er ein underdelen av dei internt oppmerkte og kryssverdisert for å trenga og evaluera modelane våre. Vi evaluerer ein serie modeller basert på klassiske tekstbaserte funksjonar til meir kontekst- transformeringsbaserte modeller og observerer at ein modell- røyrlinje basert på BERT og ALBERT for dei to stadene gjev de beste resultatene.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Szybki postęp technologii w komunikacji online za pośrednictwem platform mediów społecznościowych doprowadził do płodnego wzrostu rozprzestrzeniania się dezinformacji i fałszywych wiadomości. Fałszywe wiadomości są szczególnie szerokie w obecnej pandemii COVID-19, prowadząc do wiary ludzi w fałszywe i potencjalnie szkodliwe twierdzenia i historie. Szybkie wykrywanie fałszywych wiadomości może złagodzić rozprzestrzenianie się paniki, chaosu i potencjalnych zagrożeń dla zdrowia. Opracowaliśmy dwustopniowy zautomatyzowany rurociąg do wykrywania fałszywych wiadomości COVID-19 z wykorzystaniem najnowocześniejszych modeli uczenia maszynowego do przetwarzania języka naturalnego. Pierwszy model wykorzystuje nowy algorytm sprawdzania faktów, który pobiera najbardziej istotne fakty dotyczące zapytań użytkowników dotyczących poszczególnych roszczeń COVID-19. Drugi model weryfikuje poziom "prawdy" w kwestionowanym roszczeniu poprzez obliczenie tekstowego związku między roszczeniem a prawdziwymi faktami pobranymi z ręcznie kurowanego zbioru danych COVID-19. Zestaw danych opiera się na publicznie dostępnym źródłu wiedzy składającym się z ponad 5000 fałszywych oświadczeń COVID-19 i zweryfikowanych wyjaśnień, z których podzbiór został wewnętrznie adnotacjonowany i krzyżowo zweryfikowany w celu szkolenia i oceny naszych modeli. Oceniamy serię modeli opartych na klasycznych funkcjach tekstowych do bardziej kontekstowych modeli opartych na Transformerze i obserwujemy, że model pipeline oparty na BERT i ALBERT dla dwóch etapów daje odpowiednio najlepsze rezultaty.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_hu>A közösségi média platformokon keresztül történő online kommunikáció technológiájának gyors fejlődése a félrevezető információk és a hamis hírek terjedésének termékeny növekedéséhez vezetett. A hamis hírek különösen elterjedtek a jelenlegi COVID-19 járványban, így az emberek hisznek hamis és potenciálisan káros állításokban és történetekben. A hamis hírek gyors felismerése enyhítheti a pánik, a káosz és a potenciális egészségügyi veszélyek terjedését. Kifejlesztettünk egy kétlépcsős automatizált csővezetéket a COVID-19 hamis hírek felismeréséhez, amelyek korszerű gépi tanulási modelleket használnak a természetes nyelvfeldolgozáshoz. Az első modell egy új tényező-ellenőrző algoritmust használ, amely lekérdezi a legfontosabb tényeket az egyes COVID-19 állításokkal kapcsolatos felhasználói lekérdezésekkel kapcsolatban. A második modell ellenőrzi az "igazság" szintjét a megkérdezett állításban azáltal, hogy kiszámítja az állítás és a kézzel kezelt COVID-19 adatkészletből származó valódi tények közötti szöveges vonatkozást. Az adatkészlet egy nyilvánosan hozzáférhető tudásforráson alapul, amely több mint 5000 COVID-19 hamis állításból és hitelesített magyarázatból áll, amelyek egy részhalmazát belső megjegyzésekkel és keresztvalidálták modelleink képzéséhez és értékeléséhez. A klasszikus szövegalapú funkciók alapján számos modellt értékelünk kontextuálisabb transzformátor alapú modellekre, és megfigyeljük, hogy a BERT és ALBERT modellcsővezeték a két szakaszban a legjobb eredményt hozza.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_sr>Brzo napredovanje tehnologije u internetskoj komunikaciji preko socijalnih medijskih platformi dovelo je do produženog porasta širenja nepravde informacije i lažnih vesti. Lažne vijesti su posebno u trenutnoj pandemiji COVID-19, koji vodi do ljudi koji veruju u lažne i potencijalno štetne tvrdnje i priče. Otkrivanje lažnih vijesti brzo može smanjiti širenje panike, haosa i potencijalnih zdravstvenih opasnosti. Razvili smo dve faze automatske kanalizacije za lažno otkrivanje novosti COVID-19 koristeći stanje modela učenja umjetnosti za prirodno obrađivanje jezika. Prvi model utiče na novu činjenicu provjeravanja algoritma koji prima najvažnije činjenice o pitanju korisnika o određenim tvrdnjama COVID-19. Drugi model potvrđuje nivo 'istine' u pitanoj tvrdnji računaljući tekstualnu želju između tvrdnje i prave činjenice koje su dobile iz ručno zakrivene komplete podataka COVID-19. Podaci podataka su temeljeni na javno dostupnom izvoru znanja koja se sastoji od preko 5000 lažnih tvrdnja COVID-19 i potvrđenih objašnjenja, od kojih je podskupina unutrašnje annotirana i cross-validaterana kako bi obučila i procenila naše modele. Procjenjujemo seriju model a baziranih na klasičnom tekstu osnovanim karakteristikama na modelima koji bazuju na kontekstualnom transformatoru i posmatramo da model naftovod baziran na BERT i ALBERT za dve faze, odgovarajući, daje najbolje rezultate.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>සාමාජික මාධ්‍යමාධ්‍යම ප්‍රවේශයෙන් අන්තර්ජාත්මක සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉක්මනට ප්‍රවේශනය ප්‍රවේශනය විසින් විසි බොරු වාර්තාවක් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශ්වාස කරනවා වගේ COVID-19 පැන්ඩේමික් වලින් විශ්වාස කරනවා. බොරු වාර්තාව හොයාගන්න පුළුවන් ඉක්මනින් ප්‍රසිද්ධ වෙන්න පුළුවන් ප්‍රශ්නයක්, චායෝස් සහ අපි ස්ටේජ් දෙකක් ස්වයංක්‍රියාත්මක විදියට COVID-19 වැරදි වාර්තාව හොයාගන්න සඳහා ස්වයංක්‍රියාවක් පරීක්ෂණය පළමුවෙනි මොඩේල් එකේ අල්ගෝරිතම් පරීක්ෂණයක් පරීක්ෂණය කරන්න පුළුවන් විශේෂ COVID-19 කිරීම ගැන ප්‍රශ්නයක් ගැන අ දෙවෙනි මොඩේල් හරියට ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා 'ඇත්ත' කියලා ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් විතරයි, ප්‍රශ්නයක් සහ ඇත්ත ඇත්ත අතර පරික්ෂණය ක The data set is based on a Public Avatar Known source that comprises more than 5000 COVID-19 error calls and verified clarification, a subgroup of them is domesticated and cross-verified to train and evalute our Models. අපි පරීක්ෂාත්මක පාළුවක් අධාරිත විශේෂතාවක් අධාරිත විශේෂතාවක් විසින් පරික්ෂාත්මක විසින් අධාරිත විසින් පරික්ෂාවක විසින</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Dhaqso u horumarinta teknolojiga internetka ee ku saabsan shabakada shabakadda bulshada waxaa sababtay kordhiska macluumaadka khaladda ah iyo warbixinta been ah. Fake news is especially rampant in the current COVID-19 pandemic, leading to people believing in false and potentially harmful claims and stories.  Si dhaqso ah u ogaashada wararka beenta ah wuxuu u fududeyn karaa kala firaafka cabsi, rabshad iyo khatarka caafimaadka ee suurtagalka ah. Waxaannu horumarinnay qoraal labo iskuul oo si gaar ah loo qoray COVID-19 warqad been ah oo loo baaraandegay si ay u isticmaalaan qaababka barashada machine-machine-tacliinta afka dabiicadda ah. Tusaale-kii ugu horeeyay wuxuu soo bandhigaa warqada warqada ah oo ka fiirsanaya algoritka, kaasoo soo celinaya waxyaabaha ugu muhiimsan ee la xiriira su'aalaha ku saabsan codsiga COVID-19. Tusaale labaad wuxuu xaqiijiyaa heerka ''runta' ee la xiriiray, iyadoo lagu xisaabinayaa aqoonta qoraalka ee uu u dhexeeyo dacwadda iyo xaqiiqyada uu ka soo qaaday qoraalka COVID-19. Taariikhda macluumaadku waxay ku saleysan tahay nooc aqoon ah oo ka badan 5000 COVID-19 dacwado been ah iyo caddayn xaqiijiyey, waxaana laga dhigay koob ka mid ah hoosta internetka la dhibaataysiiyey, si loo barto oo loo qiimeeyo modelalkayaga. Waxaan qiimeynaynaa tusaalo kala duduwan oo ku saleysan tababaro qoraal ah oo ku qoran tusaalooyin badan oo ku saabsan qoraalka tarshadda ah, waxaana fiirinaynaa in dabeecada muusikada ku saleysan BERT iyo ALBERT labada darajadooda waxay soo bixisaa midhihii ugu wanaagsan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_mt>L-avvanz rapidu tat-teknoloġija fil-komunikazzjoni onlajn permezz ta’ pjattaformi tal-midja soċjali wassal għal żieda prolifika fit-tixrid ta’ informazzjoni ħa żin a u aħbarijiet foloz. L-aħbarijiet foloz huma speċjalment f’daqqa fil-pandemija attwali COVID-19, li twassal għal nies li jemmnu f’dikjarazzjonijiet u storji foloz u potenzjalment ta’ ħsara. Is-sejba ta’ aħbarijiet foloz malajr tista’ tnaqqas it-tixrid tal-paniku, il-kaos u l-perikli potenzjali għas-saħħa. Żviluppajna pipeline awtomatizzat f’żewġ stadji għall-individwazzjoni ta’ a ħbarijiet foloz COVID-19 bl-użu ta’ mudelli ta’ tagħlim tal-magni tal-aktar avvanzati għall-ipproċessar naturali tal-lingwi. L-ewwel mudell iħeġġeġ algoritmu ġdid ta’ verifika tal-fatti li jikseb l-aktar fatti rilevanti dwar mistoqsijiet tal-utenti dwar talbiet partikolari tal-COVID-19. It-tieni mudell jivverifika l-livell ta’ “verità” fit-talba mistoqsija billi jikkalkula l-involviment testwali bejn it-talba u l-fatti reali miksuba minn sett tad-dejta COVID-19 ikkurat manwalment. Is-sett tad-dejta huwa bbażat fuq sors ta’ għarfien disponibbli għall-pubbliku li jikkonsisti f’aktar minn 5000 talba falza COVID-19 u spjegazzjonijiet ivverifikati, li sottosett minnhom ġie annotat internament u vvalidat b’mod inkroċjat biex jitħarrġu u jevalwaw il-mudelli tagħna. Aħna jevalwaw serje ta’ mudelli bbażati fuq karatteristiċi klassiċi bbażati fuq it-test għal mudelli aktar kuntestwali bbażati fuq it-Trasformaturi u ninservaw li pipeline mudell ibbażat fuq BERT u ALBERT għa ż-żewġ stadji rispettivament jagħti l-aħjar riżultati.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Нийгмийн мэдээллийн платформаар онлайн харилцааны технологийн хурдан хөгжлийн хөгжлийн давхар нь буруу мэдээг болон хуурамч мэдээг нэмэгдүүлсэн. Хуудлалтай мэдээ нь ялангуяа одоогийн COVID-19 давхар халдвартай. Хуудлалтай, магадгүй аюултай утга, түүхийг итгэдэг хүмүүст хүргэдэг. хуурамч мэдээг олох нь хурдан аймшигтай, гайхалтай, эрүүл мэндийн аюулуудыг багасгаж чадна. Бид COVID-19 хуурамч мэдээг олохын тулд автоматжуулагдсан хоёр давхар хөдөлгөөн хөгжүүлсэн байгалийн хэл үйлдвэрлэхийн тулд урлаг машин суралцах загваруудыг ашиглаж байдаг. Эхний загвар нь хэрэглэгчийн асуултын тухай хамгийн чухал зүйлсийг хэрэглэгчийн тухай COVID-19 хэлэлцээний тухай шинэ зүйлийг шалгах алгоритмыг ашигладаг. Хоёр дахь загвар нь хүлээн зөвшөөрөгдсөн хүлээн зөвшөөрөгдсөн хүлээн зөвшөөрөгдсөн жинхэнэ зүйлсийг тооцоолж, хүлээн зөвшөөрөгдсөн хүлээн зөвшөөрөгдсөн хүлээн зөвшөөрөгдөг. Өгөгдлийн санг нийтэд ашиглах мэдлэг эх үүсвэрээр үндсэн. 5000 COVID-19-аас илүү худлаа хэлэлцдэг, шийдвэрлэгдсэн тайлбар, үүнийг дотор нь анхаарсан, бидний загваруудыг суралцаж, үнэлдэг. Бид классик текст суурилсан хэдэн загварыг илүү contextual Transformer суурилсан загвар дээр үндэслэж, BERT болон ALBERT дээр суурилсан загварын хоолойн шугам нь хамгийн сайн үр дүнг гаргадаг гэдгийг анзаарлаа.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Avansarea rapidă a tehnologiei în comunicarea online prin intermediul platformelor de social media a dus la o creștere prolifică a răspândirii dezinformării și a știrilor false. Știrile false sunt în special dilatante în actuala pandemie COVID-19, conducând la oameni care cred în afirmații și povești false și potențial dăunătoare. Detectarea rapidă a știrilor false poate atenua răspândirea panicii, haosului și potențialele pericole pentru sănătate. Am dezvoltat o conductă automată în două etape pentru detectarea știrilor false COVID-19 folosind modele de învățare automată de ultimă generație pentru procesarea limbilor naturale. Primul model utilizează un algoritm nou de verificare a faptelor care recuperează cele mai relevante fapte referitoare la interogările utilizatorilor despre anumite afirmații COVID-19. Al doilea model verifică nivelul de "adevăr" în afirmația interogată prin calcularea implicației textuale dintre afirmație și faptele reale recuperate dintr-un set de date COVID-19 curatoriat manual. Setul de date se bazează pe o sursă de cunoștințe accesibilă publicului, constând în peste 5000 de afirmații false COVID-19 și explicații verificate, dintre care un subset a fost adnotat intern și validat încrucișat pentru a instrui și evalua modelele noastre. Evaluăm o serie de modele bazate pe caracteristici clasice bazate pe text la modele mai contextuale bazate pe Transformer și observăm că o conductă de modele bazată pe BERT și ALBERT pentru cele două etape oferă cele mai bune rezultate.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_ta>தொழில்நுட்பமான தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் முன்னேற்றம் தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் முன்னேற்றம் சமூக ஊடகங்கள் தளங்கள் மூலம் தொழில் தகவல பொய் செய்தி தற்போதைய COVID-19 துக்கத்தில் குறிப்பாக உள்ளது, பொய் மற்றும் சாத்தியமான கூறுகள் மற்றும் கதைகள் நம்புகிறார்கள பொய் செய்திகளை கண்டுபிடிப்பது விரைவில் பயம், குழப்பம் மற்றும் சாத்தியமான உடல் பிரச்சினைகளை நீக்க முடி நாங்கள் COVID-19 பொய் செய்தி கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்கான இரண்டு நிலையில் தானாகவே தானாகவே துணுக்குகிறது இயற்கை மொழி செயல்படுத்தல் மாத முதல் மாதிரி ஒரு புதிய உண்மை சரிபார்ப்பு முறைமையை வழங்குகிறது, அது பயனர் கேள்விகள் குறிப்பிட்ட COVID-19 கேள்விகளை பற்றி மிகவ இரண்டாவது மாதிரி கேள்வி கேட்கப்பட்ட கோரிக்கையில் 'உண்மை' நிலையை சரிபார் இந்த தகவல் அமைப்பு 5,000 க்கு மேற்பட்ட அறிவு மூலத்தில் உள்ளது பொது அறிவு மூலத்திற்கு மேல் உள்ளது பொய் கூறுகள் மற்றும் சரிபார்க்கப்பட்ட விளக்கங்கள் உள்ளிருந்த நாம் கிளாசிக்கல் உரை அடிப்படையிலான தன்மைகளை அடிப்படையில் சில மாதிரிகளை மதிப்பிடுகிறோம் மாதிரிகளை மற்றும் பிரெட் மற்றும் ALBERT அடிப்படையிலான மாதிரி பை</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>سوسیل میڈیا پٹرومٹوں کے ذریعے ٹیکنالوجی کی سریع تغییر اضافہ کی سوسیل میڈیا پٹرومٹوں کے ذریعے بہت زیادہ اضافہ کی ہے۔ غلط خبریں مخصوصاً موجود COVID-19 pandemic میں پھٹ پڑی ہیں، اور لوگوں کو جھوٹی باتوں اور کہانیاں پر یقین رکھتے ہیں۔ جھوٹی خبروں کی تلاش کی جلدی مضطرب، کھیل اور امکانات سلامتی خطرات کے گھیرنے کو آسان کر سکتی ہے۔ ہم نے COVID-19 فعلی خبروں کا اظہار کرنے کے لئے ایک دوسری سٹیج اتوماٹ پیپ لین ایجاد کیا ہے کہ آرت ماشین کی تعلیم مدلکوں کے استعمال کر رہے ہیں طبیعی زبان پرسس کے لئے۔ پہلی موڈل ایک نوی حقیقت کو آلگوریٹم کی چک کرنے کی جگہ دیتا ہے جو کارساز کے بارے میں بہترین معاملہ حقیقت حاصل کرتا ہے۔ دوسری موڈل سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سچی سٹ سے حاصل کیا گیا ہے ڈاٹ سٹ ایک ظاہر موجود علم سورس پر بنیاد ہے جو 5000 COVID-19 سے زیادہ غلط تعلیمات اور تصدیق کی تعلیمات میں ہے، جس کے ایک سٹ میں ہمارے مدل کی تعلیم اور ارزیابی کے لئے داخلی طور پر اظہار کی گئی اور کروس-validated تھی. ہم نے کلاسیک ٹیکسٹ بنیاد پر بنیاد رکھے ہوئے موڈلوں کی ایک سری کا ارزش کرتا ہے اور دیکھتے ہیں کہ ایک موڈل پیپ لین BERT اور ALBERT پر بنیاد رکھتا ہے ان دو مرحلے کے لئے بہترین نتیجے اٹھاتا ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_sv>Den snabba utvecklingen av teknik inom onlinekommunikation via sociala medier har lett till en produktiv ökning av spridningen av vilseledande och falska nyheter. Falska nyheter är särskilt utbredda i den nuvarande COVID-19-pandemin, vilket leder till att människor tror på falska och potentiellt skadliga påståenden och berättelser. Att snabbt upptäcka falska nyheter kan lindra spridningen av panik, kaos och potentiella hälsorisker. Vi utvecklade en tvåstegs automatiserad pipeline för COVID-19 falska nyheter med hjälp av toppmoderna maskininlärningsmodeller för behandling av naturligt språk. Den första modellen utnyttjar en ny faktakontroll algoritm som hämtar de mest relevanta fakta om användarfrågor om specifika COVID-19-anspråk. Den andra modellen verifierar nivån av "sanning" i det ifrågasatta påståendet genom att beräkna den textmässiga innebörden mellan påståendet och de verkliga fakta som hämtats från ett manuellt kuraterat COVID-19-dataset. Datauppsättningen bygger på en allmänt tillgänglig kunskapskälla bestående av mer än 5000 COVID-19 falska påståenden och verifierade förklaringar, varav en delmängd internt kommenterades och korsvaliderades för att utbilda och utvärdera våra modeller. Vi utvärderar en serie modeller baserade på klassiska textbaserade funktioner till mer kontextuella Transformer-baserade modeller och observerar att en modellpipeline baserad på BERT respektive ALBERT för de två stegen ger bästa resultat.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_uz>Name Joriy COVID-19 pandemiyatda faqqat xabar bo'ladi, bu o'sha odamlar yolg'on va o'zaro qo'llangan so'zlar va hikoyalarni ishlatadi. Ботил хабарларни аниқлаб, тезда хавфсирлик, суҳбат ва қонунликли самовий хафаларини камайтириш мумкин. Biz COVID-19 haqida xabar aniqlash usuli bilan ikkita darajaga avtomatik foydalanib, asosiy tilni boshqarish uchun sanam mashinasi o'rganish modellari bilan foydalanishni yaratdik. Birinchi model algoritni tekshirish uchun novel haqida qoʻllaydi. Foydalanuvchi soʻrovlari haqida xabar beradi. Ikkinchi modeli qoʻlbola qoʻlbola qoʻllangan COVID-19 maʼlumotlar tizimdan olingan matn taʼlumotni hisoblash mumkin. Name We evaluate a series of models based on classical text-based features to more contextual Transformer based models and observe that a model pipeline based on BERT and ALBERT for the two stages respectively yields the best results.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Sự tiến bộ nhanh chóng của công nghệ trong giao tiếp trực tuyến qua các nền truyền thông xã hội đã dẫn đến một tăng vọt phát tán tin sai lầm và tin giả tạo. Tin giả đặc biệt nổi cuồng trong đại dịch COVID-19 hiện nay, khiến người ta tin vào giả thuyết và truyện nguy hiểm. Việc phát hiện tin giả nhanh chóng có thể làm giảm sự lan rộng của hoảng loạn, hỗn loạn và nguy cơ sức khỏe. Chúng tôi đã phát triển một đường ống tự động hai giai đoạn để phát hiện tin giả COVID-19 bằng máy tạo tác nghệ thuật để tìm hiểu ngôn ngữ tự nhiên. Người mẫu đầu tiên sử dụng thuật toán kiểm tra thực tế mới có những dữ liệu liên quan nhất về các yêu cầu của người dùng về COVID-19. Người mẫu thứ hai kiểm tra mức độ "sự thật" trong yêu cầu được đặt câu hỏi bằng cách tính toán kết cấu giữa yêu cầu và thực tế được lấy từ một bộ dữ liệu CO2-19 được cung cấp bằng tay. Bộ dữ liệu dựa trên một nguồn hiểu biết công khai có nhiều hơn 5000C COVID-19 giả thuyết và đã được kiểm tra giải thích, một nhóm trong đó được ghi chú nội bộ và kiểm tra chéo để huấn luyện và đánh giá mẫu của chúng ta. Chúng tôi đánh giá một loạt các mô hình dựa trên các mô hình văn bản cổ điển để làm các mô hình transformer còn nền lục soát hơn và quan sát rằng một ống dẫn mô hình dựa trên giao kèo BERT và ALBERT cho hai giai đoạn này đạt kết quả tốt nhất.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Бързият напредък на технологиите в онлайн комуникацията чрез платформите на социалните медии доведе до плодородно нарастване на разпространението на дезинформация и фалшиви новини. Фалшивите новини са особено бурни в сегашната пандемия, което кара хората да вярват в фалшиви и потенциално вредни твърдения и истории. Откриването на фалшиви новини бързо може да облекчи разпространението на паника, хаос и потенциални рискове за здравето. Разработихме двуетапен автоматизиран тръбопровод за откриване на фалшиви новини, използвайки най-съвременни модели за машинно обучение за обработка на естествен език. Първият модел използва нов алгоритъм за проверка на фактите, който извлича най-важните факти относно потребителските запитвания за конкретни твърдения. Вторият модел проверява нивото на "истина" в запитаното твърдение, като изчислява текстовата обвързаност между твърдението и действителните факти, извлечени от ръчно подбран набор от данни. Наборът от данни се основава на публично достъпен източник на знания, състоящ се от повече от 5000 неверни твърдения и проверени обяснения, част от които е вътрешно анотирана и кръстосано валидирана за обучение и оценка на нашите модели. Ние оценяваме серия от модели, базирани на класически текстово-базирани функции към по-контекстуални модели, базирани на трансформатори, и наблюдаваме, че моделен тръбопровод, базиран на BERT и ALBERT за двата етапа съответно дава най-добри резултати.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Brzi napredak tehnologije u internetskoj komunikaciji putem socijalnih medijskih platformi doveo je do produženog porasta širenja nepravde informacije i lažnih vijesti. Lažne vijesti su posebno u trenutnoj pandemiji COVID-19, što dovodi do ljudi koji vjeruju u lažne i potencijalno štetne tvrdnje i priče. Otkrivanje lažnih vijesti brzo može smanjiti širenje panike, haosa i potencijalnih zdravstvenih opasnosti. Razvili smo dvije faze automatski cjevin za lažno otkrivanje vijesti COVID-19 koristeći stanje modela učenja umjetničkih strojeva za prirodnu obradu jezika. Prvi model utiče na novu činjenicu provjeravanja algoritma koji prima najvažnije činjenice u vezi pitanja korisnika o posebnim tvrdbama COVID-19. Drugi model potvrđuje razinu 'istine' u pitanoj tvrdnji izračunavajući tekstualnu želju između zahtjeva i istine činjenice koje su dobile iz ručno izliječene komplete podataka COVID-19. Podaci podataka su temeljeni na javno dostupnom izvoru znanja koja se sastoji od preko 5000 lažnih tvrdnja COVID-19 i potvrđenih objašnjenja, od kojih je podskupina unutarnje annotirana i cross-validaterana kako bi obučila i procijenila naše modele. Procjenjujemo niz model a baziranih na klasičnoj tekstu osnovanoj karakteristici na više modela temeljenih na kontekstu transformera i posmatramo da model cijevi baziran na BERT i ALBERT-u za dvije faze, odgovarajući, daje najbolje rezultate.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Den hurtige udvikling af teknologi inden for onlinekommunikation via sociale medieplatforme har ført til en produktiv stigning i spredningen af misinformation og fake news. Falske nyheder er især voldsomme i den nuværende COVID-19 pandemi, hvilket fører til, at folk tror på falske og potentielt skadelige påstande og historier. At opdage falske nyheder hurtigt kan lindre spredningen af panik, kaos og potentielle sundhedsrisici. Vi udviklede en totrins automatiseret pipeline til COVID-19 fake news detektion ved hjælp af state of te art maskinlæringsmodeller til behandling af naturligt sprog. Den første model udnytter en ny fact checking algoritme, der henter de mest relevante fakta vedrørende brugerforespørgsler om bestemte COVID-19-krav. Den anden model verificerer niveauet af 'sandhed' i den forespørgslede påstand ved at beregne tekstforholdet mellem påstanden og de sande fakta hentet fra et manuelt kurateret COVID-19 datasæt. Datasættet er baseret på en offentligt tilgængelig videnkilde bestående af mere end 5000 COVID-19 falske påstande og verificerede forklaringer, hvoraf et delsæt blev internt noteret og krydsgoderet for at træne og evaluere vores modeller. Vi evaluerer en række modeller baseret på klassiske tekstbaserede funktioner til mere kontekstuelle Transformer-baserede modeller og observerer, at en model pipeline baseret på BERT og ALBERT for henholdsvis de to faser giver de bedste resultater.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Der rasante technologische Fortschritt in der Online-Kommunikation über Social-Media-Plattformen hat zu einem produktiven Anstieg der Verbreitung von Fehlinformationen und Fake News geführt. Fake News sind in der aktuellen COVID-19-Pandemie besonders weit verbreitet und führen dazu, dass Menschen an falsche und potenziell schädliche Behauptungen und Geschichten glauben. Das schnelle Erkennen von Fake News kann die Ausbreitung von Panik, Chaos und potenziellen Gesundheitsrisiken lindern. Wir haben eine zweistufige automatisierte Pipeline für die Erkennung von COVID-19 Fake News unter Verwendung modernster maschineller Lernmodelle für die Verarbeitung natürlicher Sprache entwickelt. Das erste Modell nutzt einen neuartigen Faktenprüfungsalgorithmus, der die relevantesten Fakten zu Nutzeranfragen zu bestimmten COVID-19-Ansprüchen abruft. Das zweite Modell verifiziert den Grad der "Wahrheit" in dem abgefragten Anspruch, indem es die textuelle Bedeutung zwischen dem Anspruch und den wahren Fakten berechnet, die aus einem manuell kuratierten COVID-19-Datensatz abgerufen werden. Der Datensatz basiert auf einer öffentlich zugänglichen Wissensquelle, bestehend aus mehr als 5000 COVID-19 falschen Behauptungen und verifizierten Erklärungen, von denen ein Teil intern kommentiert und kreuzvalidiert wurde, um unsere Modelle zu trainieren und zu bewerten. Wir evaluieren eine Reihe von Modellen basierend auf klassischen textbasierten Features zu kontextuelleren Transformer-basierten Modellen und beobachten, dass eine Modellpipeline basierend auf BERT und ALBERT für die beiden Phasen jeweils die besten Ergebnisse liefert.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kemajuan cepat teknologi dalam komunikasi online melalui platform media sosial telah menyebabkan peningkatan prolifik dalam penyebaran salah informasi dan berita palsu. Berita palsu khususnya berkembang dalam pandemia COVID-19 saat ini, yang menyebabkan orang percaya pada klaim palsu dan potensi berbahaya dan cerita. Mengeteksi berita palsu dengan cepat bisa mengurangi penyebaran panik, kekacauan dan berbahaya kesehatan potensial. Kami mengembangkan dua tahap pipa otomatis untuk deteksi berita palsu COVID-19 menggunakan model belajar mesin seni untuk proses bahasa alam. The first model leverages a novel fact checking algorithm that retrieves the most relevant facts concerning user queries about particular COVID-19 claims.  Model kedua mengkonfirmasi tingkat 'kebenaran' dalam klaim yang diminta dengan menghitung keterlibatan tekstual antara klaim dan fakta sebenarnya yang diterima dari set data COVID-19 yang direksi secara manual. Seting data berdasarkan sumber pengetahuan yang tersedia publik yang terdiri dari lebih dari 5000 klaim palsu COVID-19 dan penjelasan yang diperbolehkan, sebuah subset yang didalam annotasi dan cross-validated untuk melatih dan mengevaluasi model kami. Kami mengevaluasikan serangkaian model berdasarkan fitur klasik berdasarkan teks ke model berdasarkan Transformer yang lebih kontekstual dan memperhatikan bahwa saluran pipa model berdasarkan BERT dan ALBERT untuk kedua tahap secara berdasarkan memberikan hasil terbaik.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_nl>De snelle vooruitgang van technologie in online communicatie via sociale media platforms heeft geleid tot een productieve toename van de verspreiding van verkeerde informatie en fake news. Nepnieuws is vooral woedend in de huidige COVID-19 pandemie, waardoor mensen geloven in valse en potentieel schadelijke claims en verhalen. Snel nepnieuws detecteren kan de verspreiding van paniek, chaos en potentiële gezondheidsrisico's verlichten. We ontwikkelden een tweetraps geautomatiseerde pijplijn voor COVID-19 fake news detectie met behulp van state-of-the-art machine learning modellen voor natuurlijke taalverwerking. Het eerste model maakt gebruik van een nieuw fact checking algoritme dat de meest relevante feiten over gebruikersvragen over bepaalde COVID-19 claims haalt. Het tweede model verifieert het niveau van 'waarheid' in de aangevraagde claim door de tekstuele implicatie te berekenen tussen de claim en de werkelijke feiten die zijn opgehaald uit een handmatig samengestelde COVID-19 dataset. De dataset is gebaseerd op een publiek beschikbare kennisbron bestaande uit meer dan 5000 COVID-19 valse claims en geverifieerde verklaringen, waarvan een subset intern geannoteerd en kruisgevalideerd is om onze modellen te trainen en te evalueren. We evalueren een reeks modellen op basis van klassieke tekstgebaseerde functies naar meer contextuele Transformer gebaseerde modellen en observeren dat een model pipeline gebaseerd op BERT en ALBERT voor de twee fasen respectievelijk de beste resultaten oplevert.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_ko>소셜미디어 플랫폼을 통한 온라인 커뮤니케이션 기술이 급속히 발전하면서 허위정보와 가짜뉴스의 전파가 급증했다.당면한 코로나 팬데믹(세계적 대유행) 속에서 특히 허위 뉴스가 기승을 부리면서 사람들이 허위와 해로울 수 있는 주장과 이야기를 믿게 됐다.가짜 뉴스를 신속하게 발견하면 공황, 혼란, 잠재적인 건강 위해의 전파를 완화시킬 수 있다.우리는 최첨단 자연언어처리기기 학습 모델을 사용해 코로나-19 가짜뉴스 검출을 위한 2단계 자동화 파이프라인을 개발했다.첫 번째 모델은 사용자가 특정한 COVID-19 성명에 대한 가장 관련 사실을 검색하는 새로운 사실 검사 알고리즘을 이용했다.두 번째 모델은 클레임과 인공적으로 기획한 코로나 데이터세트에서 검색한 진실 사실 사이의 텍스트 내포를 계산해 조회한 클레임 중'진실'정도를 검증한다.이 데이터 세트는 5천여개의 코로나-19 허위 성명과 경험증에 대한 설명으로 구성된 공개된 지식원을 바탕으로 하며, 이 지식원 중 하나는 내부 주석과 교차 검증을 거쳐 우리의 모델을 훈련하고 평가하는 데 사용된다.우리는 고전적인 텍스트 특징을 바탕으로 하는 일련의 모델과 상하문 전환을 바탕으로 하는 모델을 평가했고 버트와 알버트를 바탕으로 하는 모델 파이프라인이 각각 이 두 단계에서 가장 좋은 결과를 얻었다는 것을 관찰했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_tr>Soýunlar medýä platformlarynyň ýüzünde tehnologiýanyň çalt gelişmesi bolup ýalňyşlyk we ýalňyş haberlerin döwletlerini üýtgedi. Köwürler häzirki COVID-19 pandemiýasynda ýalňyş we ýalňyş sözlerine we hekaýalara ynanýanlara mejbur edýär. Sahyp haberler tapmakda çalt panik, haos we sowgatyň döwletlerini azaltyp biler. Biz COVID-19 ýalňyş haber tapylmak üçin iki stadij awtomatik pipelini tebigy dil işlemek üçin sungat maşynyň öwrenmesi nusgalaryny ullanýardyk. Ilkinji nusga Ullançy COVID-19 soraglary barada iñ möhüm faktalary almak üçin bir taýdan barlama algoritmini süýtgedýär. The second model verifies the level of 'truth' in the queried claim by computing the textual entailment between the claim and the true facts retrieved from a manually curated COVID-19 dataset. Veri setir 5000-den fazla COVID-19 ýalňyş iddialar we soraglaryň içinde halkara meňzeş bilim çeşmesine dayalýar. Bu sahypalaryň içinden daşarda täzeliklendirildi we nusgalarymyzy öwretmek we çözümleşmek üçin hasaplanýardy. Biz klasik metin tabanly örneklerine daşarylan bir dizi modelleri daha konsekst terjime eden modellere değerlendirip BERT we ALBERT tabanly bir model pipeline iki taýdan üstün netijeleri getirir.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>The rapid advancement of technology in online communication via social media platforms has led to a prolific rise in the spread of misinformation and fake news.  Habari za uongo hususani zilikuwa na ugonjwa wa sasa wa COVID-19, na zinasababisha watu wanaoamini uongo na wanaodhalilisha madai na hadithi. Kugundua habari potofu kwa haraka inaweza kusababisha kusambaza kwa hofu, chaga na hatari za afya. Tumeunda hatua mbili yenyewe kwa ajili ya kutambua habari bandia za COVID-19 kwa kutumia hali ya mfumo wa kujifunza mashine ya sanaa kwa ajili ya upasuaji wa lugha asili. Mfano wa kwanza unaelezea ukweli wa kitabu kinachochungulia utambulisho ambao unapata ukweli muhimu zaidi kuhusu maswali ya watumiaji kuhusu madai maalum ya COVID-19. The second model verifies the level of 'truth' in the queried claim by computing the textual entailment between the claim and the true facts retrieved from a manually curated COVID-19 dataset.  Taarifa hiyo inategemea chanzo cha habari kinachopatikana hadharani kinachojumuisha zaidi ya madai ya uongo 5000 COVID-19 na maelezo yaliyothibitishwa, kipande ambacho kilikasirishwa ndani na kilichothibitishwa ili kufundisha na kutathmini mifano yetu. Tutathmini mfululizo wa mifano kwa kutumia vipengele vya maandishi vya klassical kwa mifano yenye msingi wa zamani wa Transformer na kuangalia kuwa pipeline ya modeli inayotumiwa na BERT na ALBERT kwa hatua hizo mbili kwa namna moja hutoa matokeo bora.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_am>የመስኮት ማኅበራዊ አውታር ሚዲያ ፕላውንቶች በመጠቀም የመግለጫ ፈጥኖ የስህተት መረጃዎችንና የሐሰት ዜናዎችን በመዘርጋት የሚያሳውቅ ጉዳይ አግኝቷል፡፡ የውሸት ዜና በተቃወመ COVID-19 ፍርሃት ውስጥ ነው፤ በሐሰት እና በቻለ ጉዳይ እና ታሪክ የሚያምኑ ሰዎች የሚያሳስቱ ነው፡፡ የሐሰት ዜናዎች ማግኘት ፈጥኖ የፍርሃት፣ ሽንገላ እና የቻልነት የጤና መከራን ማቅረብ ይችላል፡፡ ለCOVID-19 የሐሰት ዜና ማሳተሚያ ሞዴል ለፍጥረት ቋንቋ ማስተማር ሞዴላዎችን ለመጠቀም የሁለት ደረጃዎች የተለየን የኮቪዲ-አሥር የሐሰት ዜና አግኝተን ነበር፡፡ የመጀመሪያው ሞዴል የአልጎርጂምን መምረጥ የሚያስፈልገውን የኮቪD-19 ጥያቄዎችን ስለተጠቃሚው ጥያቄዎች የሚያስፈልገውን አዋቂ ውሸት የሚያስፈልጋል፡፡ ሁለተኛው ዓይነት ከCOVID-19 ዳታ የተገኘውን የጽሑፍ ማውቀት እና እውነተኛውን ውሸት በመቀበል በሚያረጋግጥ የ'እውነት' ደረጃውን ያረጋግጣል፡፡ የዳታ ደረጃው 5,000 በላይ COVID-19 የሐሰት ጥያቄዎች እና የተፈጸመ ትርጓሜዎችን ለማስተማርና ለማስተካከል የተገኘ እውቀት ምንጭ የተገኘ ነው፡፡ በክላሲካዊ ጽሑፍ ላይ የተመሳሳይ የፊደል ዓይነቶች እና በሁለቱ ደረጃዎች ላይ BERT እና ALBERT የተመሠረተውን የሞዴል ፊደል እናስተዋልታለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Տեխնոլոգիայի արագ զարգացումը առցանց հաղորդակցման մեջ սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցների միջոցով հանգեցրեց սխալ տեղեկատվության և կեղծ նորությունների տարածման աճի: Կատար նորությունները հատկապես զարմացնում են COVID-19-ի ներկայիս համաճարակի ընթացքում, ինչը հանգեցնում է մարդկանց հավատալու սխալ և պոտենցիալ վնասավոր հայտարարություններին և պատմություններին: Detecting fake news quickly can alleviate the spread of panic, chaos and potential health hazards.  Մենք ստեղծեցինք COVID-19-ի երկու փուլում ավտոմատիկ խողովակաշար կեղծ նորությունների հայտնաբերման համար օգտագործելով լավագույն մեքենայի սովորելու մոդելներ բնական լեզվի վերլուծության համար: The first model leverages a novel fact checking algorithm that retrieves the most relevant facts concerning user queries about particular COVID-19 claims.  Երկրորդ մոդելը ստուգում է հարցում գտնվող ճշմարտության մակարդակը՝ հաշվարկելով հաղորդակցման և իրական փաստերի միջև գտնվող հաղորդակցված COVID-19 տվյալների համակարգում: The dataset is based on a publicly available knowledge source consisting of more than 5000 COVID-19 false claims and verified explanations, a subset of which was internally annotated and cross-validated to train and evaluate our models.  Մենք գնահատում ենք մի շարք մոդելներ, որոնք հիմնված են դասական տեքստի հիմնված հատկությունների վրա ավելի կոնտեքստոնալ տրանսֆորմային հիմնված մոդելների վրա և հետևում ենք, որ BER-ի և ALBER-ի վրա հիմնված մոդելների խողովակաշարը երկու փուլերի համար, համա</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_fa>پیشرفت سریع تکنولوژی در ارتباطات آنلاین از طریق پلاکترم رسانه‌های اجتماعی به افزایش زیادی در گسترش خبرهای غلط و دروغگویی رسید. خبرهای دروغگویی مخصوصا در پاندمیک اکنون COVID-19 است که به مردم باور دارند به ادعاهای دروغگو و potentially harmful و داستان‌ها باور دارند. شناسایی اخبار دروغی سریع می‌تواند گسترش خطر، خرابی و خطر سلامتی محتمل را کمتر کند. ما یک لوله دومرحله اتوماتیک برای شناسایی اخبار دروغ COVID-19 را با استفاده از موقعیت مدل یادگیری ماشین هنر برای پرداخت زبان طبیعی توسعه کردیم. اولین مدل یک حقیقت جدید را تحقیق الگوریتم می‌کند که بیشترین حقیقت مربوط به سوال‌های کاربر در مورد ادعا COVID-19 خاص را می‌گیرد. مدل دوم سطح "حقیقت" در ادعای پرسیده با محاسبه کردن ارتباط متن بین ادعا و حقیقت حقیقی که از یک مجموعه داده‌های COVID-19 را دستگیر کرده است، ثابت می‌کند. این مجموعه داده ها بر اساس یک منبع علمی که در دسترس عمومی موجود است که بیش از ۵۰۰ نفر از ادعا غلط COVID-۱۹ و توضیح‌های تصدیق شده است، یک جمعه از آن در داخل توضیح داده شده است و برای آموزش و ارزیابی مدل‌های ما تحقیق شده است. ما یک سری مدل بر اساس ویژه‌های متن کلاسیک بر اساس مدل‌های متن‌سازی بیشتر متن‌سازی را ارزیابی می‌کنیم و مشاهده می‌کنیم که یک خط لوله‌های مدل بر اساس BERT و ALBERT برای دو مرحله‌ها بهترین نتیجه‌های ارزیابی می‌دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_bn>সামাজিক প্রচার মাধ্যমের প্লাটফর্মের মাধ্যমে অনলাইন যোগাযোগে প্রযুক্তির দ্রুত উন্নয়নের ফলে ভুল তথ্য এবং ভুয়া সংবাদ ছড় মিথ্যা এবং সম্ভাব্য ক্ষতিগ্রস্ত দাবি এবং গল্পের প্রতি বিশ্বাস করে মিথ্যা এবং বিশ্বাস করে মিথ্যা সংবাদ বিশ্বাস করে বর্তমান মিথ্যা সংবাদ সনাক্ত করতে দ্রুত তাড়াতাড়ি ভীত, দুর্ঘটনা এবং সম্ভাব্য স্বাস্থ্যের বিপদের বিস্তৃতি কমিয়ে দে কোভিড-১৯ মিথ্যা সংবাদ আবিষ্কারের জন্য আমরা একটি দুই স্টেডে স্বয়ংক্রিয় পাইপেলাইন তৈরি করেছি প্রাকৃতিক ভাষা প্রক্রিয়ার জন প্রথম মডেলটি একটি উপন্যাস পরীক্ষা করা সত্য পরীক্ষা করা হয়েছে যা ব্যবহারকারীদের প্রশ্নের সবচেয়ে গুরুত্বপূর্ণ তথ্য পুনরুদ্ধার কর The second model verifies the level of 'truth' in the queried claim by computing the textual entailment between the claim and the true facts retrieved from a manually curated COVID-19 dataset.  The dataset is based on a publicly available knowledge source consisting of more than 5000 COVID-19 false claims and verified explanations, a subset of which was internally annotated and cross-validated to train and evaluate our models.  আমরা ক্লাসিক্যাল টেক্সট ভিত্তিক বৈশিষ্ট্যান্সফ্রান্সের ভিত্তিক কিছু মডেলের মূল্য মূল্যায়ন করি এবং দেখি যে এই দুটি পর্যায়ে ভিত্তিক একটি মডেল পাইপেল</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_sq>Përparimi i shpejtë i teknologjisë në komunikimin online nëpërmjet platformeve të medias sociale ka çuar në një rritje të madhe në përhapjen e informacioneve të gabuara dhe lajmeve të rreme. Fake news is especially rampant in the current COVID-19 pandemic, leading to people believing in false and potentially harmful claims and stories.  Gjetja e lajmeve të rreme shpejt mund të lehtësojë shpërndarjen e panikut, kaosit dhe rreziqeve të mundshme shëndetësore. Kemi zhvilluar një tubacion të automatizuar dy fazash për zbulimin e lajmeve të rreme COVID-19 duke përdorur modelet e mësimit të makinave më të larta për procesimin natyror të gjuhës. Modeli i parë shfrytëzon një algoritëm të ri të verifikimit të fakteve që merr faktet më të rëndësishëm lidhur me pyetjet e përdoruesve rreth pretendimeve të veçanta COVID-19. Modeli i dytë verifikon nivelin e 'të vërtetës' në pretendimin e pyetur duke llogaritur lidhjen tekstuale midis pretendimit dhe fakteve të vërteta të marrë nga një set të dhënash COVID-19 të kuruar manualisht. Të dhënat bazohen në një burim të njohurive të disponueshme publikisht që përbëhet nga më shumë se 5000 pretendime të rreme COVID-19 dhe shpjegime të verifikuara, një nëngrup i të cilëve u shënua brenda dhe u kryqëzua për të trajnuar dhe vlerësuar modelet tona. Ne vlerësojmë një seri modelesh bazuar në karakteristika klasike të tekstit për modele më kontekstuale të bazuar në Transformer dhe vëzhgojmë se një tubacion model bazuar në BERT dhe ALBERT për të dy fazat respektivisht jep rezultatet më të mira.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_az>Sosyal media platformlarńĪ vasit…ôsil…ô onlayn …ôlaq…ôl…ôrind…ô teknolojinin tez ilerlemesi yanlńĪŇü Ňü…ôkild…ô v…ô sahte x…ôb…ôrl…ôrin yayńĪlmasńĪna √ßox y√ľks…ôk yol g√∂st…ôrdi. Ňěimdiki COVID-19 pandemik i√ßind…ô yalan x…ôb…ôrl…ôr m√ľs…ôlmanlńĪq edir, insanlarńĪ yalan v…ô potensiallńĪ z…ôr…ôr iddialarńĪ v…ô hekay…ôl…ôr…ô inanńĪrlar. YaxŇüńĪ x…ôb…ôrl…ôr tapmaq tezlikl…ô panik, haos v…ô potensial sańülńĪńüńĪn t…ôhl√ľk…ôsini azaldńĪr. Biz COVID-19 sahte x…ôb…ôrl…ôr keŇüfetm…ôsi √ľ√ß√ľn iki f…ôrz avtomatik pipeline t…ôhsil etdik v…ô t…ôbi…ôtli dil iŇül…ôm…ôsi √ľ√ß√ľn sanat makinel…ôrin √∂yr…ônm…ô modell…ôrinin durumu il…ô istifad…ô etdik. ńįlk modell…ôr COVID-19 iddialarńĪ bar…ôsind…ôki …ôn m√∂vcuddur faktlarńĪnńĪ alńĪr. ńįkinci modell…ôr t…ôl…ôb edil…ôn iddiasńĪnda 'h…ôqiq…ôt' s…ôviyy…ôsini t…ôsdiql…ôyir, t…ôl…ôb etm…ôk v…ô t…ôl…ôb etm…ôk arasńĪndakńĪ h…ôqiq…ôt faktlarńĪn …ôlind…ôn alńĪnan COVID-19 veri qutusundan hesablayńĪr. Veri qurńüularńĪ 5000-d…ôn fazla COVID-19 yalan iddialarńĪndan v…ô t…ôsdiql…ônmiŇü a √ßńĪqlamalardan daxil edil…ôn elm kaynańüńĪna dayandńĪrńĪlńĪr. BunlarńĪn bir d…ôst…ôsi modell…ôrimizi t…ôhsil etm…ôk v…ô deńüerlendirm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn daxil edil…ôn v…ô √ßox t…ôsdiql…ônmiŇü. Biz klasik metin tabanlńĪ √∂zellikl…ôrin…ô dayanan bir seriy…ô modell…ôri daha m√ľxt…ôlif Transformer tabanlńĪ modell…ôr…ô t…ôŇükil edirik v…ô bu iki d…ôf…ô BERT v…ô ALBERT tabanlńĪ modell…ôrin …ôn yaxŇüńĪ sonu√ßlarńĪnńĪ verir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_cs>Rychlý pokrok technologií v online komunikaci prostřednictvím sociálních médií vedl k plodnému nárůstu šíření dezinformací a falešných zpráv. Falešné zprávy jsou obzvláště šířivé v současné pandemii COVID-19, což vede k tomu, že lidé věří v falešná a potenciálně škodlivá tvrzení a příběhy. Rychlé odhalování falešných zpráv může zmírnit šíření paniky, chaosu a potenciálních zdravotních rizik. Vyvinuli jsme dvoustupňový automatizovaný potrubí pro detekci falešných zpráv COVID-19 s využitím nejmodernějších modelů strojového učení pro zpracování přirozeného jazyka. První model využívá nový algoritmus kontroly faktů, který získává nejdůležitější fakta týkající se dotazů uživatelů ohledně konkrétních nároků na COVID-19. Druhý model ověřuje úroveň "pravdy" v dotazovaném tvrzení výpočtem textového souvislosti mezi tvrzením a skutečnými fakty získanými z ručně kurovaného datového souboru COVID-19. Datová sada je založena na veřejně dostupném zdroji znalostí skládajícím se z více než 5000 falešných tvrzení COVID-19 a ověřených vysvětlení, z nichž podmnožina byla interně anotována a křížově ověřena za účelem tréninku a hodnocení našich modelů. Vyhodnocujeme řadu modelů založených na klasických textových prvcích na kontextovějších modelech založených na Transformeru a sledujeme, že modelové potrubí založené na BERT a ALBERT pro obě fáze přináší nejlepší výsledky.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>El ràpid avançament de la tecnologia en la comunicació on-line a través de plataformes de mitjans socials ha portat a un prolífic augment en la difusió de la mala informació i les notícies falses. Les notícies falses són especialment revoltants en la actual pandèmia COVID-19, que porta a la gent que creu en afirmacions i històries falses i potencialment nocives. La detecció ràpida de notícies falses pot alleviar la difusió del pànic, el caos i els riscos potencials per a la salut. Vam desenvolupar un tub automatitzat de dos etapes per a la detecció de notícies falses COVID-19 utilitzant models d'aprenentatge màquina d'última generació per al processament natural de llenguatges. El primer model aprofita un algoritme de verificació de fets nou que recupera els fets més rellevants sobre preguntes d'usuari sobre determinades reclamacions COVID-19. El segon model verifica el nivell de "veritat" de la reclamació preguntada calculant l'involucració textual entre la reclamació i els veritables fets recuperats d'un conjunt de dades COVID-19 curat manualment. El conjunt de dades està basat en una font de coneixement públicament disponible que consisteix en més de 5000 reclamacions falses COVID-19 i explicacions verificades, un subconjunt dels quals va ser anotat internament i cruzad per a entrenar i evaluar els nostres models. Evaluam una sèrie de models basats en característiques clàssiques basades en text a models més contextuals basats en Transformer i observem que un tub model basat en BERT i ALBERT per les dues etapes, respectivament, dóna els millors resultats.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Tehnoloogia kiire areng internetisuhtluses sotsiaalmeedia platvormide kaudu on viinud valeinfo ja valeuudiste leviku viljaka suurenemiseni. Valeuudised on praeguses COVID-19 pandeemias eriti levinud, mistõttu inimesed usuvad valedesse ja potentsiaalselt kahjulikesse väitetesse ja lugudesse. Valeuudiste kiire tuvastamine võib leevendada paanika, kaose ja võimalike terviseohtude levikut. Töötasime välja COVID-19 valeuudiste tuvastamiseks kaheastmelise automatiseeritud toru, kasutades looduskeele töötlemiseks kaasaegseid masinõppe mudeleid. Esimene mudel kasutab uut faktikontrolli algoritmi, mis toob välja kõige olulisemad faktid seoses kasutaja päringutega konkreetsete COVID-19 väidete kohta. Teine mudel kontrollib päritava väite "tõetaset", arvutades välja tekstilise seose väite ja käsitsi kureeritud COVID-19 andmekogumist saadud tegelike faktide vahel. Andmekogum põhineb avalikult kättesaadaval teabeallikal, mis koosneb enam kui 5000 COVID-19 valeväidetest ja kontrollitud selgitustest, mille alamhulk on sisemiselt märgitud ja ristvalideeritud meie mudelite koolitamiseks ja hindamiseks. Hindame klassikalistel tekstipõhistel funktsioonidel põhinevaid mudeleid kontekstipõhisematele Transformer-põhistele mudelitele ning täheldame, et BERT-il ja ALBERT-il põhinev mudelite juhtmestik kahe etapi jaoks annab parimad tulemused.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Teknologian nopea kehittyminen verkkoviestinnässä sosiaalisen median alustojen kautta on johtanut virheellisen tiedon ja valeuutisten leviämisen hedelmälliseen kasvuun. Väärät uutiset ovat erityisen raivoisia nykyisessä COVID-19-pandemiassa, mikä johtaa siihen, että ihmiset uskovat vääriin ja mahdollisesti haitallisiin väitteisiin ja tarinoihin. Vääräuutisten nopea havaitseminen voi lievittää paniikin, kaaoksen ja mahdollisten terveysriskien leviämistä. Kehitimme kaksivaiheisen automaattisen putkiston COVID-19-fake news -tunnistukseen käyttäen uusimpia koneoppimismalleja luonnollisen kielen käsittelyyn. Ensimmäisessä mallissa hyödynnetään uutta faktojen tarkistusalgoritmia, joka hakee olennaisimmat faktat käyttäjien kyselyistä tietyistä COVID-19-väitteistä. Toinen malli todentaa "totuuden" tason tiedustelussa väitteessä laskemalla väitteen ja manuaalisesti kuratoidusta COVID-19-aineistosta poimittujen tosiasioiden välisen tekstiyhteyden. Aineisto perustuu julkisesti saatavilla olevaan tietolähteeseen, joka koostuu yli 5000 COVID-19 vääristä väitteistä ja todennetuista selityksistä, joista osa on sisäisesti merkitty ja ristivalidoitu malliemme kouluttamiseksi ja arvioimiseksi. Arvioimme klassisiin tekstipohjaisiin ominaisuuksiin perustuvia malleja kontekstuaalisempiin Transformer-pohjaisiin malleihin ja havaitsimme, että BERT- ja ALBERT-malliputki molemmille vaiheille tuottaa parhaat tulokset.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bs>Brz napredak tehnologije u internetskoj komunikaciji putem socijalnih medijskih platformi doveo je do produženog porasta širenja nepravde informacije i lažnih vijesti. Lažne vijesti su posebno u trenutnoj pandemiji COVID-19, koji vodi do ljudi koji vjeruju u lažne i potencijalno štetne tvrdnje i priče. Otkrivanje lažnih vijesti brzo može smanjiti širenje panike, haosa i potencijalnih zdravstvenih opasnosti. Razvili smo dvije faze automatski cijevi za lažno otkrivanje vijesti COVID-19 koristeći stanje modela učenja umjetnosti za prirodno obradivanje jezika. Prvi model utiče na novu činjenicu provjeravanja algoritma koji prima najvažnije činjenice u vezi pitanja korisnika o posebnim tvrdnjima COVID-19. Drugi model potvrđuje nivo 'istine' u pitanoj tvrdnji izračunavajući tekstualnu želju između tvrdnji i pravih činjenica koje su dobile iz ručno izliječenog kompeta podataka COVID-19. Podatak se temelji na javno dostupnom izvoru znanja koja se sastoji od preko 5000 lažnih tvrdnja COVID-19 i potvrđenih objašnjenja, od kojih je podskupina unutrašnje annotirana i prekovjerena kako bi obučila i procenila naše modele. Procjenjujemo niz model a baziranih na klasičnom tekstu osnovanim karakteristikama na modelima temeljenim na kontekstualnom transformatoru i posmatramo da model cijevi baziran na BERT i ALBERT za dvije faze, odgovarajući, daje najbolje rezultate.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_af>Die vinnige vordering van teknologie in aanlyn kommunikasie deur sosiale media platforme het 'n uitbreiding verhoog in die verspreiding van verkeerde informasie en falske nuus gelei. Vergelyke nuus is besonderlik rampant in die huidige pandemie van COVID-19, wat lei na mense wat glo in valse en potensielle skandelike aansoek en stories. Die verspreiding van valse nuus kan vinnig die verspreiding van panik, kaos en potensieele gesondheidshazardes allerhande maak. Ons het 'n twee stadige outomatiese pyplyn ontwikkel vir COVID-19 falske nuusbeskrywing gebruik staat van die kuns masjien leer modele vir natuurlike taal verwerking. Die eerste model verwyder 'n nuwe feit om algoritme te kontroleer wat die mees relevante fakte oor gebruiker vrae oor spesifieke COVID- 19 vrae ontvang. Die tweede model bevestig die vlak van 'waarheid' in die gevraagde aandrukking deur die tekstuele aanhouding tussen die aandrukking en die waarde fakte wat ontvang is van 'n handaanklik gekruisigde COVID- 19 datastel. Die datastel is gebaseer op 'n openbaar beskikbaar kennisbron wat bestaan van meer as 5000 COVID-19 valse aansoeklinge en verifiseerde uitduidelings, 'n subartikel waarvan binneste aanbeteken en kruis-geldigheid was om ons modele te trein en te evalueer. Ons evalueer 'n reeks van modele gebaseer op klassieke teks-gebaseerde funksies na meer konteksual Transformer gebaseerde modele en observer dat 'n model pyplin gebaseer op BERT en ALBERT vir die twee stadige respektief die beste resultate gee.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé éntuk akses ditulaké teknôlogi ning komunikasi online, nik nganggep sistem media sotiki, nik awak dhéwé isih perusahaan pakan-perusahaan kanggo mbelaké informasi sing gak dhéwé. Yatiyawih luwih apik ngomong nik sakjane kanggo masara urip nglanggar aturan CLOPID-19, dadi ono wong liyané sing ngregani kuwi mau sing luwih apik lan ijol-ijolan sing perusahaan banget ngregani uwong. Awak dhéwé luwih sing beraksi maneh iso nglanggar ujuran pangan, pangan lan nganggo dolanan sing beraksi. Awakdhéwé éntuk sistem durung sembarang sistem sistem sing otomatik kanggo nggawe barang kelas corita-19 kuwi basa perusahaan kuwi duluran sistem ingkang sampeyan perusahaan bangsa. Samsul model sing digawe dadi un barêng nggawe Algoritmi sing ditambah akeh barang nggawe barang nggawe kesempatan mung sabên kelas corita-19. Display routing dataset Awak dhéwé éntuk sistem sing dadi model sing basa batasan karo pernik sing basa gambar n' a textual Transformer dumadhi sing bisa bantêr nggawe sistem sing bisa model sing basa saben karo BERT lan AlBERT dumadhi sing bisa langgar sampek dhéwé, perusahaan langgar sampek langgar sampek langgar sampek.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>התקדמות המהירה של הטכנולוגיה בתקשורת באינטרנט באמצעות פלטפורמות התקשורת החברתית הובילה לגידול גדול בהפיצה של מידע לא נכון וחדשות מזויפות. חדשות מזויפות הן במיוחד מפורסמות בפנדמיה COVID-19 הנוכחית, שמובילות לאנשים שמאמינים בתבועות וסיפורים מזיקים ופוטנציאליים. בחיפוש חדשות מזויפות במהירות יכול להקל על התפשטות של פאניקה, תוהו וסכנות בריאות פוטנציאליות. פיתחנו צינור אוטומטי בשתי שלבים עבור גילוי חדשות מזויפות COVID-19 בשימוש מודלים למידה של מכונות אומנות למעבד שפה טבעי. המודל הראשון משתמש באלגוריתם לבדוק עובדות חדשות שמחזיר את העובדות הרלוונטיות ביותר בנוגע לשאלות משתמשים על טענות מסוימות COVID-19. הדוגמא השנייה מאשרת את רמת האמת בתבועה המבקשת על ידי חישוב את הקשור הרקסטולי בין התבועה לעובדות האמיתיות שנוצאות ממערכת נתונים COVID-19 שטופלת ידנית. קבוצת המידע מבוססת על מקור ידע זמין לציבור שמתכיל מעל 5000 טענות שווא COVID-19 והסברים מאושרים, שבתוך קבוצה נכתבה פנימית ומאושרת לחצות כדי לאמן ולעריך את הדוגמנים שלנו. אנו מעריכים סדרה של דוגמנים מבוססים על תכונות טקסטים קלאסיים למודלים מבוססים על טרנספורטרים קונטקסטיים יותר ונצפים שצינור דוגמנים מבוסס על BERT ו ALBERT לשני השלבים בהתאם מובילים את התוצאות הטובות ביותר.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>དྲ་རྒྱའི་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་དང་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་གྱི་འཕེལ་རིམ་གྱི་འཕེལ་རྒྱས་འགྲོ་བཞིན་ཡིན་པས། སྐྱོན་བརྗོད་འདི་ལྟ་བུའི་གནད་དོན་མཁན་གྱི་COVID-19 ཟུར་བ་བཀོད་སྣང་མེད་མང་པོ་ཞིག་ཡིན་པས། མི་མང་གིས་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་ ལྟ་བུའི་བརྡ་ཞིག་བཙལ་མ་ཚུགས་གྱིས་འཕེལ ང་ཚོས་COVID གཟུགས་རིས་དང་པོ་དེ་ནི་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་རྗེས་སྐོར་གྱི་ཆ་རྐྱེན་དུ་གཏོང་གི་སྐྱེན་ཚད་ལྟ་ཞིབ་བྱེད་པའི་སྐྱེན The second model verifies the level of "truth" in the queried claim by computing the textual entailment between the claim and the true facts retrieved from a manually curated COVID-19 dataset. སྒྲིག་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག We evaluate a series of models based on classical text-based features to more contextual Transformer based models and observe that a model pipeline based on BERT and ALBERT for the two stages respectively yields the best results.</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_sk>Hiter napredek tehnologije v spletni komunikaciji prek platform socialnih medijev je pripeljal do plodnega porasta širjenja napačnih informacij in lažnih novic. Lažne novice so še posebej divje v sedanji pandemiji COVID-19, zaradi česar ljudje verjamejo v lažne in potencialno škodljive trditve in zgodbe. Hitro odkrivanje lažnih novic lahko ublaži širjenje panike, kaosa in morebitnih nevarnosti za zdravje. Razvili smo dvostopenjski avtomatizirani cevovod za odkrivanje lažnih novic COVID-19 z uporabo najsodobnejših modelov strojnega učenja za obdelavo naravnega jezika. Prvi model uporablja nov algoritem za preverjanje dejstev, ki pridobi najpomembnejša dejstva v zvezi z uporabniškimi poizvedbami o določenih trditvah COVID-19. Drugi model preverja stopnjo "resnice" v poizvedovani trditvi z izračunom besedilne posledice med trditvijo in resničnimi dejstvi, pridobljenimi iz ročno urejenega nabora podatkov COVID-19. Zbirka podatkov temelji na javno dostopnem viru znanja, sestavljenem iz več kot 5000 lažnih trditev COVID-19 in preverjenih pojasnil, katerih podskupina je bila notranje označena in navzkrižno potrjena za usposabljanje in ocenjevanje naših modelov. Ocenjujemo serijo modelov, ki temeljijo na klasičnih besedilnih funkcijah za bolj kontekstualne modele, ki temeljijo na transformatorjih, in ugotavljamo, da model pipeline, ki temelji na BERT in ALBERT za obe fazi, prinaša najboljše rezultate.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Kayan gaugãwa ga technical in kommuni na Online through platforms of mitandaki na jamii sun led'an na ƙara a cikin shari da information na ƙarya. Habari na ƙarya yana da haske cikin wata cutar COV-19 da ake kai yanzu, kuma yana ƙara wa mutane su yi ĩmãni da ƙarya da mai yiwuwa masu cũtar zato da lãbãri. Akwai ganin lãbãri na ƙarya don a iya sauƙaƙara gaura wa firgita, kiyaye da mataimaki ga halin afya. We developed a two stage automated pipeline for COVID-19 fake news detection using state of the art machine learning models for natural language processing.  @ action: button Moden na biyu na gaskata daraja na "gaske" a cikin zato da aka tambaye shi, yana ƙidãya masu sani na matsayin da gaskiyar da aka samu daga tsarin data da aka samu da hannun. An daidaita shi a kan wani salon da ake iya bayani da kunnuwa wanda ke iya samar da shi na ƙari 5,000 na COKID-19 yana da kuma an tabbatar da fassarar ƙarya da kuma an gaskata, wani ƙarshen da aka buga shi a guda, kuma aka korce-inganci dõmin ya yi tafiyar da kuma ya ƙayyade misalinmu. Ana ƙaddara wasu masu motsi a kan karatun matsayin mai classical zuwa masu ƙaranci misãlai na Transformer a ƙidãya masu husũma kuma Muke gane cewa wata misalin ayuka a kan BERT da AIBERT kan daraja biyu, yana fitar da mafi kyaun matsala.</abstract_ha>
      </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Measuring Alignment to Authoritarian State Media as Framing Bias</title>
      <author><first>Timothy</first><last>Niven</last></author>
      <author><first>Hung-Yu</first><last>Kao</last></author>
      <pages>11–21</pages>
      <abstract>We introduce what is to the best of our knowledge a new task in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a> : measuring alignment to authoritarian state media. We operationalize alignment in terms of sociological definitions of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Media_bias">media bias</a>. We take as a case study the alignment of four <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Media_of_Taiwan">Taiwanese media outlets</a> to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_media">Chinese Communist Party state media</a>. We present the results of an initial investigation using the frequency of words in psychologically meaningful categories. Our findings suggest that the chosen word categories correlate with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Framing_(social_sciences)">framing choices</a>. We develop a calculation method that yields reasonable results for measuring <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequence_alignment">alignment</a>, agreeing well with the known labels. We confirm that our method does capture event selection bias, but whether it captures <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Framing_bias">framing bias</a> requires further investigation.</abstract>
      <url hash="08146601">2020.nlp4if-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>niven-kao-2020-measuring</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/doublethinklab/nlp4if2020p" additional="false">doublethinklab/nlp4if2020p</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>