<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.louhi">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 11th International Workshop on Health Text Mining and Information Analysis</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Eben</first><last>Holderness</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Antonio</first><last>Jimeno Yepes</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alberto</first><last>Lavelli</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anne-Lyse</first><last>Minard</last></editor>
      <editor><first>James</first><last>Pustejovsky</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Fabio</first><last>Rinaldi</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="323b7822">2020.louhi-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>louhi-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Simple Hierarchical Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title>
      <author><first>Maciej</first><last>Wiatrak</last></author>
      <author><first>Juha</first><last>Iso-Sipila</last></author>
      <pages>12–17</pages>
      <abstract>Recognising and linking entities is a crucial first step to many tasks in biomedical text analysis, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relation_extraction">relation extraction</a> and target identification. Traditionally, biomedical entity linking methods rely heavily on heuristic rules and predefined, often domain-specific features. The features try to capture the properties of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entity–relationship_model">entities</a> and complex multi-step architectures to detect, and subsequently link entity mentions. We propose a significant simplification to the biomedical entity linking setup that does not rely on any heuristic methods. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> performs all the steps of the entity linking task jointly in either single or two stages. We explore the use of hierarchical multi-task learning, using mention recognition and entity typing tasks as auxiliary tasks. We show that hierarchical multi-task models consistently outperform single-task models when trained tasks are homogeneous. We evaluate the performance of our models on the biomedical entity linking benchmarks using MedMentions and BC5CDR datasets. We achieve state-of-theart results on the challenging MedMentions dataset, and comparable results on BC5CDR.</abstract>
      <url hash="99622a41">2020.louhi-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.louhi-1.2</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940048" />
      <bibkey>wiatrak-iso-sipila-2020-simple</bibkey>
    <title_ar>رابط كيان عصبي بسيط متعدد المهام هرمي للنص الطبي الحيوي</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Liaison d'entités neuronales multitâches hiérarchiques simples de bout en bout pour le texte biomédical</title_fr>
      <title_es>Enlace jerárquico simple de entidades neuronales de extremo a extremo para texto biomédico</title_es>
      <title_pt>Vinculação de entidade neural de ponta a ponta simples hierárquica multitarefa para texto biomédico</title_pt>
      <title_ja>生物医学テキストのための単純な階層的マルチタスクニューラルエンドツーエンドエンティティリンク</title_ja>
      <title_zh>生物医学文本简分多任务神经端到端实体链接</title_zh>
      <title_hi>बायोमेडिकल पाठ के लिए सरल पदानुक्रमित बहु-कार्य तंत्रिका एंड-टू-एंड एंटिटी लिंकिंग</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Простая иерархическая многозадачная нейронная связь между конечными объектами для биомедицинского текста</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Aonán Simplí Ordlathach Il-Tasc Néarach ó cheann ceann go ceann a nascadh le haghaidh Téacs Bithleighis</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ბიომედიციო ტექსტისთვის ერთადერთი ჰიერარიქული მრავალური ნეიროლური დასრულება</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Egyszerű hierarchikus többfeladatú neurális end-to-end entitás összekapcsolása Bioorvosi szöveghez</title_hu>
      <title_el>Απλή ιεραρχική πολλαπλή-εργασία νευρωνική τελική σύνδεση οντοτήτων για βιοιατρικό κείμενο</title_el>
      <title_it>Semplice collegamento gerarchico multi-task neurale end-to-end di entità per testo biomedico</title_it>
      <title_lt>Paprastas hierarchinis daugiafunkcinis neurologinis subjektas, susietas su biomedicininiu tekstu</title_lt>
      <title_kk>Биомедикалық мәтін үшін қарапайым гиерархикалық көп- тапсырмалар нейралық соңындағы нысандарды сілтемелеу</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Name</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Entiti Akhir-Ke-Akhir Neural Hierarkik Mudah untuk Teks Biomedik</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ബൈയോമിഡിക്കല്‍ പദാവലിക്കുള്ള ലിങ്ങിങ്ങിനുള്ള എളുപ്പമായ മറ്റൊരു ജോലിയുടെ നെയുറല്‍ അവസാനം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Entità Newrali Semplika b’Ħidma Multi-Ħidma Nikkollegaw għal Test Bijomediku</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Биомедицины текстийн энгийн гиеррахик олон-үйл ажиллагааны мэдрэлийн төгсгөл-төгсгөл нэгж</title_mn>
      <title_no>Enkelt hierarkisk fleire oppgåver nøyralt slutt- til- slutt- einingslinking for biomedisk tekst</title_no>
      <title_pl>Proste hierarchiczne wielozadaniowe neuronowe końcowe łączenie jednostek dla tekstu biomedycznego</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Simplu Hierarhic Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking pentru text biomedical</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Jednostavno hijerarhičko višezadatačno neurološko završeno povezanje entiteta za biomedicinski tekst</title_sr>
      <title_si>සාමාන්‍ය හියාර්චිකල් ගොඩක් ක්‍රියාව නිර්මාණ අවසානය අවසානය අවසානය සඳහා ජීවිත වෛද්‍ය පාළුව</title_si>
      <title_so>Simple Hierarchical Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title_so>
      <title_sv>Enkel hierarkisk Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking för biomedicinsk text</title_sv>
      <title_ta>பையோமிடிக் உரைக்கான சுலபமான பல- பணி நெயுரல் முடிவு- முடிவு- முடிவு உள்ளீடு இணைப்பு</title_ta>
      <title_ur>ساده حیرارشیک Multi-Task Neural End-to-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Truyền liên kết về văn bản sinh học</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_bg>Проста йерархична многозадача неврална връзка от край до край за биомедицински текст</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Eenvoudige hiërarchische Multi-Task Neural End-to-End Entity Koppeling voor Biomedische Tekst</title_nl>
      <title_da>Enkel hierarkisk Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking til biomedicinsk tekst</title_da>
      <title_hr>Jednostavna hijerarhička multizadatačna neuronska konačna pojava za biomedicinski tekst</title_hr>
      <title_de>Einfache hierarchische Multi-Task Neurale End-to-End Entity Verknüpfung für biomedizinische Texte</title_de>
      <title_id>Simple Hierarchical Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title_id>
      <title_ko>생물 의학 텍스트의 간단한 층별 다중 임무 신경 끝에서 끝까지의 실체 링크</title_ko>
      <title_fa>متن بیولوژیکی ساده‌ای که متن‌های بیولوژیکی‌</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Uunganishaji rahisi wa Hierarchical Multi-Task Neural End-to-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Biomedical metin üçin Basit Hierarhiýal Çoklu-Taýgy Neýral Ahyry-Başlama Entity Baglaýyş</title_tr>
      <title_af>Eenvoudige hierarkies Multi-Task Neural End-to-End Entity Linking vir Biomedical Text</title_af>
      <title_am>Multi-Task Neural End-to-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title_am>
      <title_hy>Simple Hierarchical Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title_hy>
      <title_az>Biyomedicini məktub üçün asanlıq hierarşik çox-iş nöral son-to-end Entity Linking</title_az>
      <title_bn>Name</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Jednostavna hijerarhička multizadatačna neuronska konačna jedinica povezivanja za biomedicinski tekst</title_bs>
      <title_sq>Njësia e thjeshtë hierarkike me shumë detyra nervore që lidh njësinë përfundimtare për tekstin biomjekësor</title_sq>
      <title_et>Lihtne hierarhiline mitme ülesandega neuroalne otsast otsani olemi seostamine biomeditsiinilise teksti jaoks</title_et>
      <title_fi>Yksinkertainen hierarkinen monitehtävä Neuraalinen End-to-End Entity Linking Biomedical Text</title_fi>
      <title_cs>Jednoduché hierarchické Multi-Task Neurální End-to-End Entity linking pro biomedicínský text</title_cs>
      <title_ca>Simple Hierarchical Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title_ca>
      <title_jv>Cyrillic</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Enostavno hierarhično večopravilno nevralno povezovanje entitete od konca do konca za biomedicinsko besedilo</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>יחסים הייררכיים פשוטים של יחסים נוירואלים רבים במשימות סוף-סוף לטקסט ביורפואי</title_he>
      <title_bo>Simple Hierarchical Multi-Task Neural End-To-End Entity Linking for Biomedical Text</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>يعد التعرف على الكيانات وربطها خطوة أولى حاسمة للعديد من المهام في تحليل النص الطبي الحيوي ، مثل استخراج العلاقة وتحديد الهدف. تقليديًا ، تعتمد طرق ربط الكيانات الطبية الحيوية بشكل كبير على قواعد الكشف عن مجريات الأمور والميزات المحددة مسبقًا والمخصصة للمجال في كثير من الأحيان. تحاول الميزات التقاط خصائص الكيانات والبنى المعقدة متعددة الخطوات للكشف عنها ، وبالتالي ربط الكيانات المذكورة. نقترح تبسيطًا كبيرًا للكيان الطبي الحيوي الذي يربط الإعداد الذي لا يعتمد على أي طرق إرشادية. يقوم النظام بتنفيذ جميع خطوات الكيان الذي يربط المهمة بشكل مشترك إما في مرحلتين أو مرحلتين. نستكشف استخدام التعلم الهرمي متعدد المهام ، باستخدام مهام التعرف على الإشارة وكتابة الكيان كمهام مساعدة. نظهر أن النماذج الهرمية متعددة المهام تتفوق باستمرار على نماذج المهام الفردية عندما تكون المهام المدربة متجانسة. نقوم بتقييم أداء نماذجنا على الكيان الطبي الحيوي الذي يربط المعايير باستخدام MedMentions ومجموعات بيانات BC5CDR. لقد حققنا نتائج رائعة في مجموعة بيانات MedMentions الصعبة ، ونتائج مماثلة على BC5CDR.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Reconhecer e vincular entidades é um primeiro passo crucial para muitas tarefas na análise de textos biomédicos, como extração de relações e identificação de alvos. Tradicionalmente, os métodos de vinculação de entidades biomédicas dependem muito de regras heurísticas e recursos predefinidos, geralmente específicos de domínio. Os recursos tentam capturar as propriedades de entidades e arquiteturas complexas de várias etapas para detectar e, posteriormente, vincular menções de entidade. Propomos uma simplificação significativa para a configuração de vinculação de entidades biomédicas que não depende de nenhum método heurístico. O sistema executa todas as etapas da tarefa de vinculação de entidades conjuntamente em um ou dois estágios. Exploramos o uso do aprendizado multitarefa hierárquico, usando reconhecimento de menção e tarefas de digitação de entidade como tarefas auxiliares. Mostramos que os modelos hierárquicos multitarefa superam consistentemente os modelos de tarefa única quando as tarefas treinadas são homogêneas. Avaliamos o desempenho de nossos modelos na entidade biomédica vinculando benchmarks usando conjuntos de dados MedMentions e BC5CDR. Alcançamos resultados de última geração no desafiador conjunto de dados MedMentions e resultados comparáveis no BC5CDR.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Reconnaître et relier des entités est une première étape cruciale pour de nombreuses tâches d'analyse de textes biomédicaux, telles que l'extraction de relations et l'identification de cibles. Traditionnellement, les méthodes de liaison d'entités biomédicales reposent largement sur des règles heuristiques et des fonctionnalités prédéfinies, souvent spécifiques à un domaine. Les fonctionnalités tentent de capturer les propriétés des entités et des architectures complexes en plusieurs étapes pour détecter, puis lier les mentions d'entités. Nous proposons une simplification significative de la configuration de la liaison d'entités biomédicales qui ne repose sur aucune méthode heuristique. Le système exécute toutes les étapes de la tâche de liaison d'entités conjointement en une ou deux étapes. Nous explorons l'utilisation de l'apprentissage multitâche hiérarchique, en utilisant des tâches de reconnaissance de mentions et de saisie d'entités comme tâches auxiliaires. Nous montrons que les modèles multitâches hiérarchiques surpassent systématiquement les modèles à tâche unique lorsque les tâches entraînées sont homogènes. Nous évaluons la performance de nos modèles sur l'entité biomédicale en reliant les benchmarks à l'aide des ensembles de données MedMentions et BC5CDR. Nous obtenons des résultats de pointe sur l'ensemble de données difficile MedMentions, et des résultats comparables sur BC5CDR.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Reconocer y vincular entidades es un primer paso crucial en muchas tareas del análisis de textos biomédicos, como la extracción de relaciones y la identificación de objetivos. Tradicionalmente, los métodos de vinculación de entidades biomédicas se basan en gran medida en reglas heurísticas y características predefinidas, a menudo específicas del dominio. Las funciones intentan capturar las propiedades de las entidades y arquitecturas complejas de varios pasos para detectar y, posteriormente, vincular las menciones de entidades. Proponemos una simplificación significativa de la configuración de enlace de la entidad biomédica que no se basa en ningún método heurístico. El sistema realiza todos los pasos de la tarea de vinculación de la entidad de forma conjunta en una o dos etapas. Exploramos el uso del aprendizaje jerárquico multitarea, utilizando las tareas de reconocimiento de menciones y escritura de entidades como tareas auxiliares. Mostramos que los modelos jerárquicos multitarea superan sistemáticamente a los modelos de una sola tarea cuando las tareas capacitadas son homogéneas Evaluamos el rendimiento de nuestros modelos en la entidad biomédica que vincula los puntos de referencia mediante los conjuntos de datos de MedMentions y BC5CDR. Logramos resultados de vanguardia en el desafiante conjunto de datos de MedMentions y resultados comparables en BC5CDR.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_zh>夫知链接实体者,生物医学文本析中多务之要,如关提挈。 古者,生物医学实体链接法甚赖于启发式则预定义者(常特定于域之征)。 试得检测之多步骤体系结构,随而链接之。 臣等议生物医学实体链接设以大简,宜置不依启发式法。 系统于单或两段中同行实体链接所有步骤。 求多任务学之用,以知为佐。 吾明同质之时,分多任务终始。 吾以MedMentions与BC5CDR数集评吾形于生物医学体链接基准之性也。 吾于挑战性MedMentions数集上得先进,而取比于BC5CDR。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ja>エンティティを認識し、リンクすることは、関係抽出やターゲット識別などの生物医学テキスト分析における多くのタスクの重要な最初のステップです。 伝統的に、生物医学的実体のリンク方法は、ヒューリスティックルールと事前定義された、しばしばドメイン固有の特徴に大きく依存している。 これらの機能は、検出するエンティティのプロパティと複雑なマルチステップアーキテクチャをキャプチャし、その後エンティティのメンションをリンクしようとします。 ヒューリスティックな方法に依存しないバイオメディカルエンティティリンクの設定を大幅に簡略化することを提案します。 システムは、エンティティリンクタスクのすべてのステップを単一または2段階で共同で実行します。 私たちは、言及認識とエンティティタイピングタスクを補助タスクとして使用して、階層的マルチタスク学習の使用を探求します。 階層型マルチタスクモデルは、訓練されたタスクが均質である場合、単一タスクモデルよりも一貫して優れていることを示しています。 私たちは、MedMentionsとBC 5 CDRデータセットを使用して、ベンチマークをリンクする生物医学エンティティにおけるモデルのパフォーマンスを評価します。 当社は、挑戦的なMedMentionsデータセットで最先端の結果を達成し、BC 5 CDRで同等の結果を達成します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>संस्थाओं को पहचानना और जोड़ना बायोमेडिकल टेक्स्ट विश्लेषण में कई कार्यों के लिए एक महत्वपूर्ण पहला कदम है, जैसे कि संबंध निष्कर्षण और लक्ष्य पहचान। परंपरागत रूप से, बायोमेडिकल एंटिटी लिंकिंग विधियां हेरिस्टिक नियमों और पूर्वनिर्धारित, अक्सर डोमेन-विशिष्ट सुविधाओं पर बहुत अधिक निर्भर करती हैं। सुविधाएँ पता लगाने के लिए एंटिटी और जटिल मल्टी-स्टेप आर्किटेक्चर के गुणों को कैप्चर करने का प्रयास करती हैं, और बाद में एंटिटी का उल्लेख लिंक करती हैं। हम सेटअप को जोड़ने वाली बायोमेडिकल इकाई के लिए एक महत्वपूर्ण सरलीकरण का प्रस्ताव करते हैं जो किसी भी हेरिस्टिक विधियों पर भरोसा नहीं करता है। सिस्टम या तो एकल या दो चरणों में संयुक्त रूप से जोड़ने वाले कार्य को जोड़ने वाली इकाई के सभी चरणों को निष्पादित करता है। हम सहायक कार्यों के रूप में उल्लेख पहचान और एंटिटी टाइपिंग कार्यों का उपयोग करके, पदानुक्रमित बहु-कार्य सीखने के उपयोग का पता लगाते हैं। हम दिखाते हैं कि पदानुक्रमित बहु-कार्य मॉडल लगातार एकल-कार्य मॉडल से आगे निकलते हैं जब प्रशिक्षित कार्य सजातीय होते हैं। हम मेडमेंटियन और BC5CDR डेटासेट का उपयोग करके बेंचमार्क को जोड़ने वाली बायोमेडिकल इकाई पर अपने मॉडल के प्रदर्शन का मूल्यांकन करते हैं। हम चुनौतीपूर्ण MedMentions डेटासेट पर राज्य के theart परिणाम प्राप्त करते हैं, और BC5CDR पर तुलनीय परिणाम।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Распознавание и связывание сущностей является важным первым шагом для многих задач в биомедицинском анализе текста, таких как извлечение отношений и идентификация целей. Традиционно методы связывания биомедицинских сущностей в значительной степени зависят от эвристических правил и предопределенных, часто специфических для домена признаков. Функции пытаются зафиксировать свойства сущностей и сложных многоступенчатых архитектур для обнаружения, а затем связывают упоминания сущностей. Мы предлагаем значительное упрощение биомедицинской сущности, связывающей установку, которая не опирается на какие-либо эвристические методы. Система выполняет все этапы задачи связывания сущности совместно в один или два этапа. Мы исследуем использование иерархического многозадачного обучения, используя распознавание упоминаний и задачи типизации сущностей в качестве вспомогательных задач. Показано, что иерархические многозадачные модели последовательно превосходят однозадачные модели при однородности обученных задач. Мы оцениваем эффективность наших моделей на биомедицинском объекте, связывающем контрольные показатели, с использованием наборов данных MedMentions и BC5CDR. Мы достигли самых современных результатов по сложному набору данных MedMentions и сопоставимых результатов по BC5CDR.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Is céim ríthábhachtach é eintitis a aithint agus a nascadh le go leor tascanna in anailís ar théacs bithleighis, amhail eastóscadh caidreamh agus sainaithint sprice. Go traidisiúnta, bíonn modhanna nasctha eintiteas bithleighis ag brath go mór ar rialacha heorastúla agus ar ghnéithe réamhshainithe a bhaineann go sonrach leis an bhfearann. Déanann na gnéithe iarracht airíonna na n-eintiteas agus ailtireachtaí casta ilchéime a ghabháil chun a bhrath, agus ina dhiaidh sin nascann tráchtanna aonáin. Molaimid simpliú suntasach ar an eintiteas bithleighis a nascann thus nach bhfuil ag brath ar aon mhodhanna heorastúla. Comhlíonann an córas na céimeanna go léir de thasc nasctha an eintitis le chéile in aon chéim amháin nó dhá chéim. Déanaimid iniúchadh ar úsáid na foghlama ordlathach il-tasc, ag baint úsáide as aithint lua agus tascanna clóscríobh aonáin mar thascanna cúnta. Léirímid go n-éiríonn níos fearr le samhlacha ordlathacha ilthascanna go seasta ná samhlacha aon tasc amháin nuair a bhíonn tascanna oilte aonchineálach. Déanaimid measúnú ar fheidhmíocht ár samhlacha ar an aonán bithleighis a nascann tagarmharcanna ag baint úsáide as tacar sonraí MedMentions agus BC5CDR. Bainimid torthaí úrscothacha amach ar thacar sonraí dúshlánach MedMentions, agus torthaí inchomparáide ar BC5CDR.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ელექტურების განაცნობა და დაკავშირება უფრო მნიშვნელოვანი პირველი ნაწილია ბიომედიციური ტექსტის ანალიზაციაში, როგორც შესახებ ექსტრაქცია და მიზეზი ინ ტრადიციონალურად, ბიომედიციური ინტერტიკა, რომელსაც მეტები დაკავშირებულია, ძალიან ძალიან ჰეურისტიური წესებით და უფრო განსაზღვრებული, დიომინურ ინტერტიების და კომპლექსიკოლექტური მრავალური აქტიქტიქტურების შესახებ განახსნა და შემდეგ ინტერტიქტურების შესახებ დაკავშირება. ჩვენ მნიშვნელოვანი განსხვავება ბიომედიციური ინტერტიკაზე, რომელიც კონფიგურაციას არ დააყენებს ყველა ჰერისტიური მეტისტებზე. სისტემა გავაკეთებს ყველა მონაცემები, რომელიც ერთადერთი ან ორი მონაცემებში დაკავშირებულია. ჩვენ იერაქტიკალური მრავალური დასწავლების გამოყენებას გამოყენებთ, გამოყენებთ განაცნობა და ინტერტიკალური დასწავლა დავალებების გამოყენება. ჩვენ ჩვენ აჩვენებთ, რომ ჰიერაქტიკური მრავალ დავალების მოდელები შემდეგ ერთადერთი დავალების მოდელების შემდეგ, როდესაც განსწავლებული დავალებები ჰომოგენეულია. ჩვენ მოდელების გამოყენება ბიომედიციური ინტერტიკის ბენქმარკების გამოყენება MedMentions და BC5CDR ინტერტიკის გამოყენებაში. ჩვენ მივიღეთ სახელსაწყისი წარმოდგენების შესაძლებელი MedMentions მონაცემების სახელსაწყისი და BC5CDR-ის შემდგენელი წარმოდგენების შემდეგ.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η αναγνώριση και η σύνδεση οντοτήτων είναι ένα κρίσιμο πρώτο βήμα για πολλά καθήκοντα στην ανάλυση βιοϊατρικού κειμένου, όπως η εξαγωγή σχέσεων και ο προσδιορισμός στόχων. Παραδοσιακά, οι μέθοδοι σύνδεσης βιοϊατρικών οντοτήτων βασίζονται σε μεγάλο βαθμό σε heuristικούς κανόνες και προκαθορισμένα, συχνά ειδικά χαρακτηριστικά του τομέα. Οι δυνατότητες προσπαθούν να συλλάβουν τις ιδιότητες οντοτήτων και σύνθετων αρχιτεκτονικών πολλαπλών βημάτων για να εντοπίσουν και στη συνέχεια να συνδέσουν αναφορές οντοτήτων. Προτείνουμε μια σημαντική απλούστευση του συστήματος σύνδεσης βιοϊατρικής οντότητας που δεν βασίζεται σε καμία heuristική μέθοδο. Το σύστημα εκτελεί όλα τα βήματα της οντότητας που συνδέει την εργασία από κοινού σε ένα ή δύο στάδια. Εξετάζουμε τη χρήση της ιεραρχικής μάθησης πολλαπλών εργασιών, χρησιμοποιώντας εργασίες αναγνώρισης αναφορών και πληκτρολόγησης οντοτήτων ως βοηθητικές εργασίες. Δείχνουμε ότι ιεραρχικά μοντέλα πολλαπλών εργασιών ξεπερνούν σταθερά τα μοντέλα μιας εργασίας όταν οι εκπαιδευμένες εργασίες είναι ομοιογενείς. Αξιολογούμε την απόδοση των μοντέλων μας στη βιοϊατρική οντότητα που συνδέει δείκτες αναφοράς χρησιμοποιώντας σύνολα δεδομένων MedMentions και BC5CDR. Επιτυγχάνουμε σύγχρονα αποτελέσματα στο απαιτητικό σύνολο δεδομένων και συγκρίσιμα αποτελέσματα στο BC5CDR.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az entitások felismerése és összekapcsolása kulcsfontosságú első lépés az orvosbiológiai szövegelemzés számos feladatához, mint például a kapcsolatkivonás és a célazonosítás. Hagyományosan az orvosbiológiai szervezetek összekapcsolási módszerei nagymértékben heurisztikai szabályokra és előre meghatározott, gyakran tartományspecifikus jellemzőkre támaszkodnak. A funkciók megpróbálják rögzíteni az entitások és komplex többlépéses architektúrák tulajdonságait, hogy felismerjék és ezt követően összekapcsolják az entitásmegnevezéseket. Jelentős egyszerűsítést javasolunk a heurisztikai módszerekre nem támaszkodó orvosbiológiai szervezet számára. A rendszer a feladatokat összekapcsoló entitás összes lépését egyetlen vagy két szakaszban közösen hajtja végre. Feltárjuk a hierarchikus többfeladatos tanulás használatát, kiegészítő feladatként említések felismerésével és entitás-gépelési feladatokkal. Megmutatjuk, hogy a hierarchikus többfeladatos modellek következetesen felülmúlják az egyfeladatos modelleket, ha a képzett feladatok homogén. Modelljeink teljesítményét a MedMentions és BC5CDR adatkészletek segítségével értékeljük a referenciaértékek összekapcsolására vonatkozó biomedicinális entitásokon. A kihívást jelentő MedMentions adatkészleten korszerű eredményeket érünk el, és összehasonlítható eredményeket érünk el a BC5CDR-n.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Riconoscere e collegare le entità è un primo passo cruciale per molti compiti nell'analisi biomedica del testo, come l'estrazione delle relazioni e l'identificazione del target. Tradizionalmente, i metodi di collegamento delle entità biomediche si basano fortemente su regole euristiche e su caratteristiche predefinite, spesso specifiche del dominio. Le funzionalità cercano di catturare le proprietà di entità e architetture complesse multi-step per rilevare e successivamente collegare le menzioni di entità. Proponiamo una significativa semplificazione all'entità biomedica che collega setup che non si basa su alcun metodo euristico. Il sistema esegue tutti i passaggi dell'entità che collega l'attività congiuntamente in singole o due fasi. Esploriamo l'uso dell'apprendimento multi-task gerarchico, utilizzando le attività di riconoscimento delle menzioni e di digitazione delle entità come attività ausiliarie. Mostriamo che i modelli gerarchici multi-task superano costantemente i modelli single-task quando le attività addestrate sono omogenee. Valutiamo le prestazioni dei nostri modelli sull'entità biomedica che collega i benchmark utilizzando MedMentions e BC5CDR dataset. Otteniamo risultati all'avanguardia sull'impegnativo set di dati MedMentions e risultati comparabili su BC5CDR.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Įstaigų pripažinimas ir susiejimas yra esminis pirmasis žingsnis atliekant daugelį užduočių biomedicinės teksto analizėje, pavyzdžiui, santykių gavyba ir tikslų nustatymas. Tradiciškai biomedicinos įmonės, jungiančios metodus, labai remiasi heuristinėmis taisyklėmis ir iš anksto apibrėžtomis, dažnai konkrečioms sritims būdingomis savybėmis. Šios charakteristikos bando surinkti subjektų savybes ir sudėtingas daugiapakopes architektūras, kad būtų galima nustatyti ir vėliau susieti subjekto paminėjimus. Mes siūlome labai supaprastinti biomedicinos įstaigą, susiejančią struktūrą, kuri nesiremia jokiais heuristiniais metodais. Sistema vykdo visus ūkio subjekto, jungiančio užduotį, etapus vienu ar dviem etapais. Mes tiriame hierarchinio daugiafunkcinio mokymosi naudojimą, paminėdami pripažinimo ir subjekto įrašymo užduotis kaip pagalbines užduotis. Mes rodome, kad hierarchiniai daugiafunkciniai modeliai nuosekliai viršija vienos užduoties modelius, kai apmokytos užduotys yra vienodos. Vertiname savo modelių rezultatus biomedicinos įmonėse, jungiančiose lyginamuosius rodiklius naudojant MedMentions ir BC5CDR duomenų rinkinius. Mes pasiekiame aktualius MedMentions duomenų rinkinio rezultatus ir palyginamus BC5CDR rezultatus.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Признавањето и поврзувањето на ентитетите е клучен прв чекор во многу задачи во биомедицинската текстова анализа, како што се извлекувањето на односите и идентификацијата на целите. Традиционално, биомедицинскиот ентитет кој ги поврзува методите силно зависи од хеористичките правила и преддефинирани, честопати специфични карактеристики на домените. Овие карактеристики се обидуваат да ги фатат сопственостите на ентитетите и комплексните мултичекорни архитектури за детектирање, а потоа да ги поврзат спомените на ентитетот. Предложуваме значително поедноставување на биомедицинскиот ентитет кој поврзува поставување кое не се зависи од никакви хеористички методи. Системот ги извршува сите чекори на ентитетот кои заеднички ја поврзуваат задачата во една или две фази. Го истражуваме искористувањето на хиерархиското мултизадачно учење, користејќи го споменувањето на препознавањето и впишувањето на ентитетите како помошни задачи. Ние покажуваме дека хиерархичните мултизадачни модели постојано ги надминуваат моделите на една задача кога обучените задачи се хомогени. Ги проценуваме изведувањата на нашите модели на биомедицинскиот ентитет кој ги поврзува benchmarks користејќи MedMentions и BC5CDR податоци. We achieve state-of-theart results on the challenging MedMentions dataset, and comparable results on BC5CDR.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Pengenalan dan menyambung entiti adalah langkah pertama penting untuk banyak tugas dalam analisis teks biomedikal, seperti ekstraksi hubungan dan pengenalisan sasaran. Secara tradisional, entiti biomedikal yang menghubungkan kaedah bergantung dengan peraturan heuristik dan ciri-ciri tertentu, sering tertentu domain. Ciri-ciri cuba menangkap ciri-ciri entiti dan arkitektur berbilang-langkah kompleks untuk dikesan, dan kemudian paut entity sebutan. Kami cadangkan kemudahan yang signifikan kepada entiti biomedis yang menghubungkan seting yang tidak bergantung pada mana-mana kaedah heuristik. Sistem melaksanakan semua langkah entiti yang menghubungkan tugas secara sama ada dalam satu atau dua tahap. Kami mengeksplorasi penggunaan pembelajaran berbilang-tugas hierarkis, menggunakan pengenalan sebut dan tugas menaip entiti sebagai tugas bantuan. Kami menunjukkan bahawa model berbilang-tugas hierarkis secara konsisten melebihi model-tugas tunggal apabila tugas dilatih adalah homogen. Kami menilai prestasi model kami pada entiti biomedis yang menghubungkan tanda referensi menggunakan MedMentions dan set data BC5CDR. Kami mencapai keputusan keadaan teater pada set data MedMentions yang menantang, dan keputusan yang sama pada BC5CDR.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_kk>Бағдарламаларды анықтау мен сілтемелеу - биомедикалық мәтін анализиясындағы көптеген тапсырмалардың бірінші қадамы, мысалы, тарқату мен мақсатты идентификациясы. Дәстүрлі, биомедикалық тәсілдерді сілтемелеу әдістері геуристік ережелеріне және алдыңғы анықталған, көптеген доменге арнаулы мүмкіндіктеріне тәуелді. Бұл мүмкіндіктер бірліктер мен көпқадамды архитектуралардың қасиеттерін анықтау үшін түсінуге тырысқан және содан кейін бірлікті мәліметтерді сілтемелеу үшін. Біз биомедицина бағдарламасына қосылу үшін бір еуристикалық әдістеріне сенбейтін бағдарламасын қарапайым көмектесетін. Жүйелік тапсырманы бір не екі этапда біріктіру нысанның барлық қадамдарын орындайды. Біз иерархикалық көп тапсырмаларды оқытуды зерттеп, тапсырмаларды анықтау және бірлік тапсырмаларды көмекші тапсырмалар ретінде келтіріп көрдік. Біз иерархикалық көп тапсырма үлгілерін бір тапсырма үлгілерінен бір тапсырма үлгілерінен бірдей болатынын көрсетедік. Біз MedMentions және BC5CDR деректер қорларын қолдану үлгілеріміздің биомедицина құрылымызды бағалаймыз. Біз MedMentions деректер жиынының күй- жайы нәтижелерін жеткіземіз, және BC5CDR-нің салыстырмалы нәтижелерін жеткіземіз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ml>ബൈവിമെഡിക്കല്‍ ടെക്സ്റ്റ് വിശദീകരണത്തിലേക്കുള്ള പല ജോലികളുടെയും അടിസ്ഥാനങ്ങളെയും തിരിച്ചറിയുകയും ചെയ്യുന്നത് ബാവ സാഹചര്യത്തില്‍, ജീവിയ മെഡിക്കല്‍ വസ്തുക്കളുടെ ബന്ധപ്പെടുത്തുന്ന രീതികള്‍ ഹൂരിസ്റ്റിക്ക് നിയമങ്ങളിലും മുന്‍കൂട്ട വസ്തുക്കളുടെ ഗുണഗണങ്ങള്‍ പിടികൂടുവാന്‍ ശ്രമിക്കുന്നു ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഒരു പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട എളുപ്പമുള്ള ബൈവിമെഡിക്കല്‍ വസ്തുക്കള്‍ക്ക് ബന്ധപ്പെടുത്താന്‍ പ്രായശ്ചിത്തമാണ് പ്രാ സിസ്റ്റത്തില്‍ ഒന്നോ രണ്ടോ സ്റ്റേജില്‍ ബന്ധിക്കുന്ന വസ്തുക്കളുടെ എല്ലാ പടികളും പ്രവര്‍ത്തിക്കുന്നു. ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഹീരാര്‍ക്കിക്കല്‍ പല്ലിട്ട് ജോലി പഠിക്കുന്നതിന്‍റെ ഉപയോഗം പരിശോധിക്കുന്നു, തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നതിനെയും സാധാ We show that hierarchical multi-task models consistently outperform single-task models when trained tasks are homogeneous.  ബെന്‍മാര്‍ക്കുകള്‍ ബന്ധപ്പെടുത്തുന്ന ബെന്‍മെന്‍സുകളും ബിസി5CDR ഡാറ്റാസറ്റുകളും ഉപയോഗിച്ച് നമ്മുടെ മോഡലുകളുടെ പ്രഭാ മെഡ്മെന്റിന്റെ ഡാറ്റാസെറ്റിന്റെ വിലപിടിക്കുന്ന സ്റ്റേറ്റ് സ്റ്റേറ്റ് ഫോള്‍ട്ട് ഫോള്‍ട്ട് ഞങ്ങള്‍ നേടുന</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Ir-rikonoxximent u r-rabta tal-entitajiet huma l-ewwel pass kruċjali għal ħafna kompiti fl-analiżi tat-test bijomediku, bħall-estrazzjoni tar-relazzjonijiet u l-identifikazzjoni tal-mira. Tradizzjonalment, l-entità bijomedika li torbot il-metodi tiddependi ħafna fuq regoli ewristiċi u karatteristiċi predefiniti, spiss speċifiċi għad-dominju. Il-karatteristiċi jippruvaw jaqbdu l-proprjetajiet ta’ entitajiet u arkitetturi kumplessi f’diversi stadji biex jinstabu, u sussegwentement jorbtu s-semmiet tal-entità. Aħna nipproponu simplifikazzjoni sinifikanti għall-entità bijomedika li tgħaqqad l-istruttura li ma tiddependix fuq l-ebda metodu ewristiku. Is-sistema twettaq il-passi kollha tal-entità li torbot il-kompitu b’mod konġunt fi stadju wieħed jew żewġ stadji. Aħna nesploraw l-użu ta’ tagħlim ġerarkiku b’ħafna kompiti, billi nsemmu kompiti ta’ rikonoxximent u ta’ tipifikazzjoni ta’ entitajiet bħala kompiti awżiljarji. Aħna nuru li mudelli ġerarkiċi b’ħafna kompiti b’mod konsistenti jaqbżu mudelli b’kompitu wieħed meta kompiti mħarrġa jkunu omoġenji. Aħna jevalwaw il-prestazzjoni tal-mudelli tagħna dwar l-entità bijomedika li torbot punti ta’ riferiment bl-użu ta’ settijiet ta’ dejta MedMentions u BC5CDR. Aħna nilħqu riżultati attwali dwar is-sett ta’ dejta MedMentions sfidanti, u riżultati komparabbli dwar BC5CDR.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Kjenning og lenking av einingar er ein viktig første steg til mange oppgåver i biomedisinsk tekstanalyse, som relasjon til ekstrahering og mål-identifisering. Tradisjonelt er biomedisinske entitet som lenkjer metodar kraftig på heuristiske reglar og foredefinerte, ofte domenespesifikke funksjonar. Funksjonane prøver å henta eigenskapane til einingar og komplekse fleirsteg-arkitekturar som skal oppdagast, og etterpå lenkje opp einingar. Vi foreslår ein betydelig forenkling til biomedisinsk entitet som lenkjer oppsettet som ikkje er på nokon heuristiske metodar. Systemet utfører alle stegane på eininga som koplar oppgåva sammen i anten enkelt eller to stader. Vi undersøker bruken av hierarkisk fleire oppgåver med gjenkjenning av oppgåver og oppgåver som hjelpeoppgåver. Vi viser at hierarkiske fleire oppgåver- modeller konsistent utfører enkelte oppgåver når oppgåver trengte er homogeneske. Vi evaluerer utviklinga av modelane våre på biomedisinske entitetet som koplar benchmarker med MedMentions og BC5CDR-datasett. Vi oppnår sammenlignbare resultat på det vanskelege datasettet med MedMentions, og sammenlignbare resultat på BC5CDR.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Rozpoznawanie i łączenie podmiotów jest kluczowym pierwszym krokiem do wielu zadań biomedycznej analizy tekstu, takich jak ekstrakcja relacji i identyfikacja celów. Tradycyjnie metody łączenia jednostek biomedycznych opierają się w dużej mierze na regułach heurystycznych i predefiniowanych, często specyficznych dla domeny cechach. Funkcje starają się uchwycić właściwości jednostek i złożonych architektur wieloetapowych w celu wykrycia, a następnie łączenia wzmianek o jednostkach. Proponujemy znaczące uproszczenie jednostki biomedycznej, która nie opiera się na żadnych metodach heurystycznych. System wykonuje wszystkie etapy podmiotu łączącego zadanie wspólnie w pojedynczych lub dwóch etapach. Badamy wykorzystanie hierarchicznego wielozadaniowego uczenia się, wykorzystując zadania rozpoznawania wzmianek i typowania jednostek jako zadania pomocnicze. Pokazujemy, że hierarchiczne modele wielozadaniowe konsekwentnie przewyższają modele jednozadaniowe, gdy przeszkolone zadania są jednolite. Oceniamy wydajność naszych modeli na podmiocie biomedycznym łączącym benchmarki za pomocą zbiorów danych MedMentions i BC5CDR. Osiągamy aktualne wyniki na wymagającym zbiorze danych MedMentions oraz porównywalne wyniki na BC5CDR.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Биологийн медицинский текст шинжилгээнд хүлээн зөвшөөрөх болон холбоотой байгууллагууд нь хамгийн чухал алхам юм. Эхлээд биологийн эмчилгээний байгууллагын аргыг холбож буй байгууллагын хууль болон өмнө тодорхойлогдсон, ихэвчлэн тодорхойлогдсон байгууллагууд дээр маш чухал байдаг. Олон алхам архитектуруудын шинж чанарыг олж мэдэх болон дараагийн дараа нь биетийн хэлэлцээг холбох боломжтой. Бид биологийн эмнэлгийн бүтээгдэхүүнд хамааралтай байгууллага холбогдох чухал хялбарчлал санал өгдөг. Энэ систем ажлыг нэг эсвэл хоёр дахь талаар холбоотой бүх алхам замыг ажилладаг. Бид ихэнх ажлын сургалтын хэрэглээ судалж, нэр тодорхойлолт болон нэгж бичсэн ажлыг тусламжтай ажил болгон ашиглаж байна. Бид хичээлийн олон даалгаварын загварууд сургалтын даалгаварууд нь нэг даалгаварын загвараас илүү ижил байдаг гэдгийг харуулж байна. Бид MedMentions болон BC5CDR өгөгдлийн сангуудыг ашиглан биологийн эмнэлгийн бүтээгдэхүүний загварын үр дүнг үнэлдэг. Бид MedMentions өгөгдлийн сангийн шаардлагатай байдлын үр дүнг, BC5CDR-ын харьцуулагдмал үр дүнг гаргадаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Recunoașterea și conectarea entităților reprezintă un prim pas crucial pentru multe sarcini în analiza textului biomedical, cum ar fi extragerea relațiilor și identificarea țintelor. În mod tradițional, metodele de legătură a entităților biomedicale se bazează în mare măsură pe reguli euriste și pe caracteristici predefinite, adesea specifice domeniului. Caracteristicile încearcă să capteze proprietățile entităților și ale arhitecturilor complexe în mai multe etape pentru a detecta și, ulterior, să conecteze mențiunile entităților. Propunem o simplificare semnificativă a entității biomedicale care leagă configurația care nu se bazează pe nicio metodă euristică. Sistemul efectuează toți pașii entității care leagă sarcina în comun, fie în două etape. Explorăm utilizarea învățării ierarhice multi-task, utilizând activitățile de recunoaștere a mențiunilor și tastare a entităților ca sarcini auxiliare. Aratăm că modelele ierarhice multi-sarcină depășesc în mod constant modelele single-sarcină atunci când sarcinile instruite sunt omogene. Evaluăm performanța modelelor noastre privind entitatea biomedicală care leagă criteriile de referință folosind seturile de date MedMentions și BC5CDR. Obținem rezultate de ultimă oră pe setul de date MedMentions provocator și rezultate comparabile pe BC5CDR.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Recognising and linking entities is a crucial first step to many tasks in biomedical text analysis, such as relation extraction and target identification.  Sida caadiga ah, qaababka xiriirka dhakhaatiirta ayaa si adag u saaran sharciyada horumarka iyo horumarinta, sida badan waxaa lagu sharraxayaa qeyb gaar ah ee gudaha. Xiriiriyadu waxay isku dayaan in ay qabsadaan hantidii ay leeyihiin iyo qalcadaha qalcadaha qalabka kala duduwan si ay u ogaadaan, waxaana sidoo kale la xiriiraa macluumaadka shaqaalaha. Waxaynu soo jeedaynaa fududeyn dhakhtarka dhakhaatiirta ah oo ku xiran alaabta aan ku tiirsanayn noocyo caafimaad ah. nidaamka wuxuu sameeyaa tallaabooyin walba oo uu ku xiriirayo shaqada si wada jir ah ama hal ama labo marladood. Waxaynu baaraannaa isticmaalka waxbarashada hierarkiisa ah oo shaqo kala duduwan, waxaynu isticmaalaynaa aqoonsiga iyo shaqooyinka qorsheynta shaqada sida shaqaalaha ku habboon. Waxaynu tusnaynaa in tusaalooyin badan oo shaqo ah ay ku sameynayaan qaabab kaliya, marka shaqo la tababaray ay yihiin isku mid ah. Waxaynu qiimeynaynaa sameynta qaabilaadaheenna oo ku saabsan dhakhaatiirta dhakhaatiirta ee ku xiriira bangiyada isticmaalka MedMentions iyo BC5CDR. Waxaynu heli karnaa arimaha xaaladda farshaxanka oo ku saabsan tartanka macluumaadka MedMentions iyo resultiyada u eg BC5CDR.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>Prepoznavanje i povezivanje entitata je ključni prvi korak za mnoge zadatke u analizi biomedicinskih tekstova, poput odnosa na ekstrakciju i ciljnu identifikaciju. Tradicionalno, biomedicinska entiteta koja povezuje metode se teško oslanja na heuristička pravila i predodređena, često posebna domena. Objekti pokušavaju da uhvati vlasništvo entiteta i kompleksnog multikoraka arhitekture za otkrivanje, a posle toga spominju entitet. Predlažemo značajno jednostavljenje biomedicinskom entitetu koja povezuje postavku koja se ne oslanja na nijednu heurističku metodu. Sistem obavlja sve korake entiteta koja povezuje zadatak zajedno u jednom ili dva faza. Istražujemo korištenje hijerarhijskog učenja multizadataka, koristeći spominjanje priznanja i zadataka za pisanje entiteta kao pomoćne zadatake. Pokazujemo da hijerarhijski multizadatakovi modeli konsekventno nadmađuju jednozadatakove modele kada su obučeni zadatak homogenezan. Procjenjujemo provedbu naših modela na biomedicinskoj entiteti koji povezuje kriterije koristeći MedMentions i BC5CDR datasete. Postignemo rezultate stanja umetnosti na izazovnom setu podataka za MedMentions i usporedbljive rezultate BC5CDR-a.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Att känna igen och länka samman enheter är ett viktigt första steg för många uppgifter inom biomedicinsk textanalys, såsom relationsextraktion och målidentifiering. Traditionellt förlitar sig biomedicinska enhetskopplingsmetoder i hög grad på heuristiska regler och fördefinierade, ofta domänspecifika egenskaper. Funktionerna försöker fånga egenskaperna hos entiteter och komplexa flerstegsarkitekturer för att upptäcka och därefter länka entitetsomnämnanden. Vi föreslår en betydande förenkling av den biomedicinska enheten som länkar setup som inte förlitar sig på några heuristiska metoder. Systemet utför alla steg i enheten som sammankopplar uppgiften gemensamt i antingen ett eller två steg. Vi undersöker användningen av hierarkiskt flerfunktionslärande, med hjälp av omnämningsigenkänning och entitetstypningsuppgifter som hjälpuppgifter. Vi visar att hierarkiska fleruppgiftsmodeller konsekvent överträffar enkeluppgiftsmodeller när utbildade uppgifter är homogena. Vi utvärderar prestandan hos våra modeller på den biomedicinska enheten som länkar referensvärden med hjälp av MedMentions och BC5CDR dataset. Vi uppnår toppmoderna resultat på den utmanande MedMentions datauppsättningen och jämförbara resultat på BC5CDR.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>පිළිගන්න සහ සම්බන්ධ විදිහට සම්බන්ධ විදිහට පළමු පැත්තෙක් ජීවිත වෛද්‍ය විශ්ලේෂණයෙන් විශ්ලේෂණයේ ව සාමාන්‍ය විදියටම, ජීවිත වෛද්‍යාවක් විදියට සම්බන්ධ විදියට හෙයුරිස්ටික් නීතිය සහ ප්‍රතිරීක්ෂි විශේෂතාවල් පරීක්ෂණය කරන්න පුළුවන් විශේෂතාවක් සහ සංසුද්ධ විශේෂතාවක් පරීක්ෂණය කරන්න, සහ පස්සේ පරීක අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා ජීවිත වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාත්මක ප්‍රශ්නයක් සම්බන්ධ කරනවා කියලා කිසිම විද්‍යාවක් නොව පද්ධතිය ප්‍රවේශනය සම්බන්ධ වැඩක් එක්කෙන් එක්කෙන් එක්කෙන් එක්කෙන් එක්කෙන් එක්කෙන් එක්කෙන්  අපි පරීක්ෂණය කරන්නේ විශේෂ විශේෂ ගොඩක් වැඩක් ඉගෙන ගන්න, මතක පරීක්ෂණය සහ විශේෂ වැඩක් ලිපින්නේ උදව්වක් ව අපි පෙන්වන්නේ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විධාරණය සාම අපි බියෝමෙන්ස් වලින් බෙන්ච්මාර්ක් එක්කන් බෙන්ච්මාර්ක්ස් වලින් අපේ මොඩේල්ස් වලින් විශ්වාස කරනවා. අපිට ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්නේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්නේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්නේ. ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්න</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>தொடர்பு பிரிப்பு மற்றும் இலக்கு அடையாளம் போன்ற பல பணிகளுக்கு முக்கியமான முதல் படியாகும். பாரம்பரிய, biomedical entity linking methods heavily rely on heuristic rules and predefined, often domain- specific features. தன்மைகள் பொருளின் பண்புகளை பிடிக்க முயற்சி மற்றும் சிக்கலான பல- படி அடிப்படை உருவாக்குகளை கண்டுபிடி நாம் ஒரு முக்கியமான எளிதாக்கத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளோம் ஜியோமருத்துவ பொருள்களுக்கு இணைப்பு அமைப்புகளை தொ கணினியில் ஒரு அல்லது இரண்டு நிலைகளில் இணைக்கப்பட்ட செயலை அனைத்து படிகளையும் செயல்படுத்துகிறது. நாங்கள் பல பணி கற்றுக்கொள்ள பயன்பாட்டினை பயன்படுத்துகிறோம், குறிப்பிட்ட அடையாளம் மற்றும் உடன் உள்ளீடு பணிகளை உள்ளிடுதல் ச பயிற்சி செய்யப்பட்ட பணிகளுக்கு ஒரே செயல் மாதிரிகளை செயல்படுத்தும் பொழுதும் பல பணி மாதிரிகளை காட்டுகிறோம். நாங்கள் மெட்மென்ஸ் மற்றும் BC5CDR தரவு அமைப்புகளை பயன்படுத்தி இணைக்கும் உயிரிய மருத்துவ பொருளின் மாதிரியின் செயல்பாட We achieve state-of-theart results on the challenging MedMentions dataset, and comparable results on BC5CDR.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>انٹیزوں کی شناخت اور ارتباط کرنا ایک نہایت اہم قدم ہے جیسے بیویڈیسی ٹیکسٹ تحلیل میں بہت سے کاموں کے لئے، جیسے ارتباط اٹھانے اور موجب شناخت. پیغمبر، بیوڈیسٹی ایٹینٹی جو روش بندی کرتی ہے، ہوریسٹی قوانین اور پہلے معلوم ہوئی، اکثر ڈیمین ویسٹی ویسٹی ویسٹی ویسٹیوں پر اضافہ کرتی ہے. ویٹیوں کی ویٹیوں اور پیچیدہ متعدد-سپے معماریوں کی ویٹیوں کو پکڑنے کی کوشش کرتی ہیں اور اس کے بعد انٹیوں کے ذریعہ لینک کرتی ہیں. ہم ایک بڑی سادگی پیشنهاد کرتے ہیں بیولوڈیسی انٹیسٹ کے ساتھ جو سٹاپ کو متصل کرتی ہے جو کسی طریقے پر اعتماد نہیں کرتی۔ سیسٹم ایک یا دو مرحلے میں تکلیف کے تمام قدم کام کرتا ہے۔ ہم تعلیم کی تعلیم کی استعمال کررہے ہیں، ذکر کی شناسایی اور اتنی تائیپ کی استعمال کررہے ہیں. ہم دکھاتے ہیں کہ تعلیم کیے ہوئے کاموں کے موقع تک تک ایک کام کی مدل سے زیادہ مشابہ ہیں ہم نے مدینسوں اور BC5CDR ڈیٹ سٹ کے مطابق بانچمارک بانچمارک کے باندھنے کے ذریعے اپنی مدینلوں کی عملکرد کا ارزش کیا ہے ہم نے مڈمنسی ڈیٹ سٹ کے مشکل جہالت کا نتیجہ پہنچایا اور BC5CDR کے مقایسہ نتیجے پہنچائے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Birinchi darajada, biomedical matn analyzerida bir necha vazifalarni aniqlash va bogʻlash quyidagi narsalarni aniqlash mumkin. Anʼanaviy, biomedical tibbiy bogʻlash usullari heuristik qoidalariga va oldin ishlatilgan, ko'pincha domen-specific imkoniyatlariga murakkab ishlatadi. Name Biz heuritik usullarda ishlatmaydigan biomediya tizimga bir muhim soddalik qilamiz. Name Biz bir necha vazifalar o'rganishni foydalanamiz, tashkilotni tashkilotlar sifatida qo'llash va tizimni yozish vazifalar sifatida foydalanamiz. Biz bir necha vazifa modellarini ko'rsatishimiz mumkin, o'rganilgan vazifalar homogen bo'lganda bir vazifa modellarini o'zgartiradi. Biz modelimizning natijasi haqida qiymatimiz MedMentions va BC5CDR maʼlumotlar tarkibi bilan bogʻ'liqchi bogʻ'liqlar haqida. Biz MedMentions maʼlumotlarini qiziqarli holat natijalarini bajaramiz va BC5CDR bilan mos keladigan natijalarini bajaramiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Nhận biết và kết nối các thực thể là bước đầu tiên quan trọng trong nhiều nhiệm vụ phân tích văn bản sinh học, như cách hấp thụ các mối quan hệ và xác định mục tiêu. Theo truyền thống, sinh học liên kết các phương pháp phụ thuộc vào luật phi thần và tính năng sẵn sàng, thường là miền. Các tính năng cố nắm bắt các tính chất của các thực thể và các kiến trúc đa bước phức tạp để phát hiện, và sau đó liên kết các thực thể nhắc tới. Chúng tôi đề nghị một sự đơn giản đáng kể đến cơ thể sinh học liên kết các thiết lập không dựa trên phương pháp thần kinh nào. Hệ thống thực hiện tất cả các bước của thực thể liên kết nhiệm vụ cùng nhau trong một hoặc hai giai đoạn. Chúng tôi khám phá việc sử dụng các tập tin đa nhiệm vụ theo thứ tự, sử dụng công việc nhận dạng và đánh máy như các công việc phụ trợ. Chúng tôi cho thấy các mô- đun đa nhiệm vụ phân biệt hệ thống vượt trội các mô- trình mô- nhiệm-đơn khi các công việc huấn luyện đồng bộ. Chúng tôi đánh giá khả năng của các mô hình về thực thể sinh học liên kết điểm tiêu biểu sử dụng các tập tin MedMentions và BC5CDO. Chúng ta đạt được kết quả hoàn hảo trên tập tin đầy thử thách về MedMentions, và kết quả tương ứng với BC5CDO.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Разпознаването и свързването на субекти е решаваща първа стъпка към много задачи в биомедицинския анализ на текста, като извличане на връзки и идентифициране на целите. Традиционно биомедицинските методи за свързване на обекти разчитат силно на евристични правила и предварително определени, често специфични за домейна характеристики. Функциите се опитват да уловят свойствата на обекти и сложни многостъпални архитектури за откриване и впоследствие да свързват споменаванията на обекти. Предлагаме значително опростяване на биомедицинската структура, която не разчита на никакви евристични методи. Системата изпълнява всички стъпки на задачата за свързване на субекта съвместно на един или два етапа. Изследваме използването на йерархично многозадачно обучение, като използваме задачи за разпознаване и въвеждане на обекти като спомагателни задачи. Показваме, че йерархичните многозадачи модели последователно превъзхождат моделите с една задача, когато обучените задачи са хомогенни. Ние оценяваме ефективността на нашите модели върху биомедицински субекти, свързващи бенчмаркове, като използваме набор от данни. Постигаме актуални резултати на предизвикателния набор от данни и сравними резултати на БК5СДР.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Anerkendelse og sammenkædning af enheder er et afgørende første skridt til mange opgaver inden for biomedicinsk tekstanalyse, såsom relationsudvinding og målidentifikation. Traditionelt er biomedicinske enhedsforbindelsesmetoder meget afhængige af heuristiske regler og foruddefinerede, ofte domænespecifikke funktioner. Funktionerne forsøger at indfange egenskaberne for enheder og komplekse flertrinsarkitekturer til at registrere og efterfølgende sammenkæde enhedsnævnelser. Vi foreslår en betydelig forenkling af den biomedicinske enhed, der forbinder setup, der ikke er afhængig af nogen heuristiske metoder. Systemet udfører alle trin i enheden, der forbinder opgaven i fællesskab i enten enkelte eller to trin. Vi undersøger brugen af hierarkisk multi-opgave læring ved hjælp af nævnelsesgenkendelse og enhedstastning opgaver som hjælpeopgaver. Vi viser, at hierarkiske multi-task modeller konsekvent overgår single-task modeller, når trænede opgaver er homogene. Vi evaluerer ydeevnen af vores modeller på den biomedicinske enhed, der linker benchmarks ved hjælp af MedMentions og BC5CDR datasæt. Vi opnår topresultater på det udfordrende MedMentions datasæt og sammenlignelige resultater på BC5CDR.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Prepoznavanje i povezivanje subjekta je ključni prvi korak za mnoge zadatke u analizi biomedicinskog teksta, poput odnosa na ekstrakciju i ciljnu identifikaciju. Tradicionalno, biomedicinska entiteta koja povezuje metode teško se oslanja na heurističke pravila i predodređene, često specifične karakteristike domena. Običnosti pokušavaju uhvatiti vlasništvo entiteta i kompleksnih multikoracijskih arhitektura za otkrivanje te nakon toga spominju entitet. Predlažemo značajnu pojednostavljivanju biomedicinskog entiteta koja povezuje postavku koja se ne oslanja na nijednu heurističku metodu. Sistem obavlja sve korake entiteta koja povezuje zadatak zajedno na jednom ili dva faza. Istražujemo korištenje hijerarhijskog učenja multizadataka, koristeći spominjanje priznanja i zadatke pisanja entitata kao pomoćne zadatke. Pokazujemo da hijerarhijski multizadatačni modeli konsekventno nadmađuju jednozadatačne modele kada su obučeni zadatak homogenetni. Procjenjujemo učinkovitost naših modela na biomedicinskom entitetu povezivajući kriterije koristeći MedMentions i BC5CDR podatke. Postignemo rezultate o stanju umjetnosti na izazovnom sastavu podataka MedMentions i usporedbenim rezultatima BC5CDR-a.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_id>Pengenalan dan menghubungkan entitas adalah langkah pertama penting untuk banyak tugas dalam analisis teks biomedis, seperti ekstraksi hubungan dan identifikasi sasaran. Secara tradisional, entitas biomedis yang menghubungkan metode bergantung sangat pada aturan heuristik dan terdefinisi, sering karakteristik domain-spesifik. Karakteristik mencoba untuk menangkap properti entitas dan arsitektur kompleks multi-langkah untuk mendeteksi, dan kemudian menghubungkan entity menyebutkan. Kami mengusulkan kesederhanaan yang signifikan untuk entitas biomedis yang menghubungkan seting yang tidak bergantung pada metode heuristik apapun. Sistem melaksanakan semua langkah dari entitas yang menghubungkan tugas bersama dalam satu atau dua tahap. Kami mengeksplorasi penggunaan pembelajaran hierarkis multi-tugas, menggunakan pengenalan menyebutkan dan mengetik tugas entitas sebagai tugas bantuan. Kami menunjukkan bahwa model hierarkis multi-tugas secara konsisten melebihi model tugas tunggal ketika tugas terlatih adalah homogen. Kami mengevaluasi prestasi model kami pada entitas biomedis yang menghubungkan benchmark menggunakan MedMentions dan BC5CDR dataset. Kami mencapai hasil negara-teater pada set data MedMentions yang menantang, dan hasil yang dibandingkan pada BC5CDR.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Die Erkennung und Verknüpfung von Entitäten ist ein entscheidender erster Schritt für viele Aufgaben in der biomedizinischen Textanalyse, wie Beziehungsextraktion und Zielidentifikation. Traditionell basieren biomedizinische Entitätenverknüpfungsmethoden stark auf heuristischen Regeln und vordefinierten, oft domänenspezifischen Merkmalen. Die Features versuchen, die Eigenschaften von Entitäten und komplexen mehrstufigen Architekturen zu erfassen, um Entitätserwähnungen zu erkennen und anschließend zu verknüpfen. Wir schlagen eine deutliche Vereinfachung des biomedizinischen Entitätenverknüpfungssystems vor, das auf keine heuristischen Methoden angewiesen ist. Das System führt alle Schritte der Entity-Verknüpfungsaufgabe in einem oder zwei Stufen gemeinsam aus. Wir untersuchen den Einsatz von hierarchischem Multi-Task-Lernen, wobei Erwähnungserkennung und Entity-Typing Aufgaben als Hilfsaufgaben verwendet werden. Wir zeigen, dass hierarchische Multitask-Modelle bei homogenen trainierten Aufgaben durchwegs Einzeltask-Modelle übertreffen. Wir bewerten die Leistung unserer Modelle auf der biomedizinischen Entität, die Benchmarks mit MedMentions und BC5CDR-Datensätzen verknüpft. Wir erzielen aktuelle Ergebnisse auf dem anspruchsvollen MedMentions Datensatz und vergleichbare Ergebnisse auf BC5CDR.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_sw>Kutambua na kuunganisha vifaa ni hatua muhimu ya kwanza kwa kazi nyingi katika uchambuzi wa teknolojia za kitabibu, kama vile utoaji wa uhusiano na utambulisho wa malengo. Kwa kawaida, njia za kuunganisha vifaa vya kitabibu vinategemea vikubwa kwenye sheria za heuristi na zile zilizotanguliwa, mara nyingi hususani za ndani. Tamko hizo zinajaribu kupata vifaa vya vifaa na majengo muhimu ya hatua mbalimbali ili kutambua, na baadae kuunganisha majina ya vyombo. Tunazipendekeza urahisi mkubwa kwa vifaa vya kitabibu vinavyounganisha taasisi ambazo hazitegemea njia yoyote ya hekima. Mfumo unafanya hatua zote za entity inayounganisha kazi kwa pamoja katika hatua moja au mbili. Tunaendelea matumizi ya elimu ya kazi nyingi, kwa kutumia kutambua utambulisho na vyombo vinavyoandika kazi za ushirikiano. Tunaonyesha kuwa mifano ya kazi nyingi kwa ujumla hufanya mifano ya kazi pekee pale ambapo kazi za mafunzo ni pamoja. Tunatathmini ufanisi wa mifano yetu katika vifaa vya biotics vinavyounganisha bendera kwa kutumia MedMentions na seti za data za BC5CDR. Tumepata matokeo ya hali ya sanaa juu ya seti ya taarifa za MedMentions, na matokeo yanayofanana na BC5CDR.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_ko>실체를 식별하고 연결하는 것은 생물의학 텍스트 분석에서 많은 임무의 관건적인 첫걸음이다. 예를 들어 관계 추출과 목표 식별이다.전통적으로 생물의학 실체 링크 방법은 계발식 규칙과 미리 정의된 특정한 분야의 특징에 심각하게 의존한다.이러한 특성은 실체의 속성과 복잡한 다단계 체계 구조를 포획하여 검측을 하고 그 다음에 실체를 연결하려고 한다.우리는 생물의학 실체 링크 설정을 현저하게 간소화할 것을 건의합니다. 이 설정은 어떠한 계발식 방법에도 의존하지 않습니다.시스템은 솔리드 링크 임무의 모든 단계를 한 단계 또는 두 단계에서 함께 수행합니다.우리는 층별 다중 임무 학습의 사용을 탐색하고 식별과 실체 유형 임무를 언급하는 것을 보조 임무로 사용했다.우리는 훈련 임무가 동질일 때 층별 다중 임무 모델이 시종 단일 임무 모델보다 우수하다는 것을 발견했다.우리는 MedInetries와 BC5CDR 데이터 집합을 사용하여 우리의 모델이 생물의학 실체 링크 기준에서의 성능을 평가했다.우리는 도전적인 MEDDERTIONS 데이터 세트에서 가장 선진적인 결과를 얻었고 BC5CDR에서 비교할 수 있는 결과를 얻었다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>شناختن و ارتباط شرکتها یک قدم اول مهم برای بسیاری از کارها در تحلیل متن زیست پزشکی است، مانند ارتباط استخراج و شناسایی هدف. معمولاً شرکت زیست پزشکی که روش‌های ارتباط با ارتباط به قوانین حوریستی و ویژگی‌های مخصوص حوریستی بسیار سنگین است. ویژگی‌ها سعی می‌کنند ویژگی‌های واژه‌ها و معماری‌های چندین قدم پیچیده را برای شناسایی، و بعدش ارتباطات واژه‌ها را ارتباط دهند. ما پیشنهاد می‌کنیم یک ساده‌سازی بزرگی برای شرکت بیولوپزشکی که مرتبط ساختمان است که بر هیچ روش‌های حوریست اعتماد ندارد. این سیستم تمام قدم‌هایی از یک واحد و دو مرحله را اجرا می‌کند که کار را با هم متصل می‌کند. ما استفاده از تعلیم تعلیم زیادی کار را تحقیق می کنیم، با استفاده از تشخیص یادآوری و تایپ کردن وضعیت را به عنوان وضعیت کمک می کنیم. ما نشان می‌دهیم که مدل‌های متعدد فعالیت‌های زیادی از مدل‌های تک فعالیت در زمان آموزش آموزش همجنس هستند. ما عملکرد مدل‌هایمان را بر روی شرکت بیولوپزشکی که با استفاده از مدن‌ها و دسته‌های داده‌های BC5CDR متصل می‌کنیم ارزیابی می‌کنیم. ما نتیجه‌های وضعیت هنری را در مجموعه داده‌های مشکل‌کننده‌ی مدینه‌ها و نتیجه‌های قابل مقایسه در BC5CDR می‌رسانیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Biretleri tanamak we baglaşdyrmak biomedical metin analyzasynda birnäçe zada örän möhüm adımdır, şeýle bir şekilde tapylmak we maksadyň kimligidir. Adatça, biomedical bir zat hiýuristik düzgünlere gaty bir şekilde hasaplanýar. Hassalar birnäçe häsiýetleri we karmaşık bir multi-adım arhitektarlaryň hasaplamagyna synanyşýar, we soňra birnäçe barlaýyşlaryny barlaýarlar. Biz biomedical taýýarlaryna bir hereket edip bilmeýän bir hereket taýýarlamasyny önerdik. Sistem zadynyň bir ýa-da iki taýýarda bir gabdaly baglaýan ähli adımlaryny ýerine ýetir. Biz iýerarhiýaly köp-täblik öwrenmeniň ullanyşyny keşfedýäris, agzalaryň tanyşy we barlygyny kömek gören hökmünde ýazmak üçin tapylýarys. Biz iýerarhiýalyk multi-täblik nusgalarynyň ýeke-täblik nusgalaryndan hemişe eşit däldigini görkeýäris. MedMentions we BC5CDR veri setirlerini ulanan biomedical bir zatda örneklerimizi çykýarys Biz MedMentions verilerini çözýän ýagdaýynyň durumynda ýakynlaşyk netijelerini başarýarys we BC5CDR'de ýakynlaşyk netijelerini çykarýarys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_nl>Het herkennen en koppelen van entiteiten is een cruciale eerste stap voor veel taken in biomedische tekstanalyse, zoals relatieonderzoek en doelidentificatie. Traditioneel zijn biomedische entiteitslinkmethoden sterk afhankelijk van heuristische regels en vooraf gedefinieerde, vaak domeinspecifieke kenmerken. De functies proberen de eigenschappen van entiteiten en complexe meerstapsarchitecturen vast te leggen om entiteitsvermeldingen te detecteren en vervolgens te koppelen. We stellen een aanzienlijke vereenvoudiging voor voor de biomedische entiteit linking setup die geen heuristische methoden gebruikt. Het systeem voert alle stappen van de entiteit die taak koppelt gezamenlijk uit in één of twee fasen. We onderzoeken het gebruik van hiërarchisch leren met meerdere taken, waarbij vermeldingsherkenning en entiteitentypen worden gebruikt als hulptaken. We laten zien dat hiërarchische multi-task modellen consistent beter presteren dan single-task modellen wanneer getrainde taken homogeen zijn. We evalueren de prestaties van onze modellen op de biomedische entiteit die benchmarks koppelt met behulp van MedMentions en BC5CDR datasets. We bereiken state-of-the-art resultaten op de uitdagende MedMentions dataset en vergelijkbare resultaten op BC5CDR.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_af>Herkenning en verbinding van entiteite is 'n belangrike eerste stap na baie opdragte in biomediese teks analisie, soos verwanting van uitpakking en doel identifikasie. Tradisjoneel, biomediese entiteite wat metodes verkoppel, is swaar op heuristiese reëls en vooraf definieerde, dikwels domein-spesifieke funksies. Die funksies probeer om die eienskappe van entiteite en kompleks multistappe-arkitektuure te neem om te ontdek, en volgende skakel entiteite bepaalde. Ons voorstel 'n betekende eenvoudiging aan die biomediese entiteit wat verbind opstelling wat nie op enige heuristiese metodes vertrou nie. Die stelsel uitvoer al die stappe van die entiteit wat die taak koppel in of een of twee stappe. Ons ondersoek die gebruik van hierarkies multi-taak-leer, gebruik die herkening en einditeit wat taak as hulpbrukke opdragte tik. Ons wys dat hierarkies multi-taak modele konsistentlik een-taak-modele uitvoer wanneer opgelei taak homogeen is. Ons evalueer die prestasie van ons modele op die biomediese entiteit wat benchmarke verbind met MedMentions en BC5CDR datastelle. Ons bereik staat-van-die kunsten resultate op die belangrike MedMentions datastel en vergelykbare resultate op BC5CDR.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Njohja dhe lidhja e njësive është një hap i parë vendimtar në shumë detyra në analizën biomedikale të tekstit, të tilla si nxjerrja e marrëdhënieve dhe identifikimi i objektivëve. Tradicionalisht, njësia biomedikale që lidh metodat mbështetet shumë në rregullat heuristike dhe karakteristikat e paracaktuara, shpesh specifike për domenin. Karakteristikat përpiqen të kapin pronat e njësive dhe arkitekturat komplekse me shumë hapa për të zbuluar dhe më pas lidhin përmendimet e njësisë. We propose a significant simplification to the biomedical entity linking setup that does not rely on any heuristic methods.  The system performs all the steps of the entity linking task jointly in either single or two stages.  Ne eksplorojmë përdorimin e mësimit hierarkik me shumë detyra, duke përdorur përmendjen e njohjes dhe shkrimit të detyrave të njësisë si detyra ndihmëse. Ne tregojmë se modelet hierarkikë me shumë detyra vazhdimisht tejkalojnë modelet me një detyrë kur detyrat e trajnuara janë homogjene. Ne vlerësojmë performancën e modeleve tona në njësinë biomedikale që lidh parametrat duke përdorur MedMentions dhe BC5CDR. Ne arrijmë rezultate shtetërore në bazën e të dhënave të sfidueshme të MedMentions dhe rezultate të krahasueshme në BC5CDR.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bn>বায়োমেডিকেল টেক্সট বিশ্লেষণের জন্য অনেক কাজের প্রথম পদক্ষেপ, যেমন সম্পর্ক বের করা এবং লক্ষ্য পরিচয়ের মত। ঐতিহ্যবাহীতভাবে, বায়োমেডিকেল বৈশিষ্ট্যের যোগাযোগ মাধ্যমের মাধ্যমে হারিস্টিক নিয়ম এবং পূর্বে নির্ধারিত, প্র এই বৈশিষ্ট্য বস্তুর বৈশিষ্ট্য এবং কমপ্লিক্স মাল্টিটি স্থাপত্য সনাক্ত করতে এবং পরবর্তীতে বস্তুর উল্লেখ করার জন্য লিঙ্ক করার চ আমরা বায়োমেডিকেল বৈশিষ্ট্যের সংযুক্ত বস্তুর কাছে গুরুত্বপূর্ণ সুস্পষ্ট প্রস্তাব করছি যা কোন হারিস্টিক পদ্ধত সিস্টেম একত্র অথবা দুই পর্যায়ের মধ্যে যোগাযোগ করে বস্তুর কাজের সকল পদক্ষেপ প প্রদর্শন করে। আমরা হিয়ারার্কিয়ার্কিল মাল্টিক কাজ শিক্ষা ব্যবহার করি, স্বীকৃতি এবং বৈশিষ্ট্যের কাজ হিসেবে টাইপ করা যায়। আমরা দেখাচ্ছি যে প্রশিক্ষিত কাজ সমকামীন হলে হিরেরার্কিল বহুক্ষেত্রের মডেল একক ক কাজের মডেল প্রদর্শন করে। We evaluate the performance of our models on the biomedical entity linking benchmarks using MedMentions and BC5CDR datasets.  আমরা চ্যালেঞ্জ মেডমেনেশন ডাটাসেটের উপর রাষ্ট্র-অফ থিয়ার্ট ফলাফল অর্জন করি এবং বিসি৫সিডিআরের তুলনায় ফলাফল অর্জন করি।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_am>አካላትን በማወቅ እና ማግኘት የግንኙነት አካሄዱን ለማሳወቅ የብዙዎች የጥያቄ ጽሑፍ ማረፊያ፣ እንደግንኙነት አካባቢ እና የግንኙነት ማውጣት እና የማግኘት መግለጫ ነው፡፡ በባሕላዊው፣ የbiomedical አካል ግንኙነት ሥርዓቶችን እና በተወሰነ ጊዜ ብዙ ጊዜም ዶሜን-ፍጥረት ላይ ይታመናል፡፡ The features try to capture the properties of entities and complex multi-step architectures to detect, and subsequently link entity mentions.  በሀሪክኛ መንገድ በማይታመን የሚታመን የbiomedical አካሄድ ማቀናቀል እናስፈልጋለን፡፡ ሲስተም የአካባቢውን ሥራ በአንድ ወይም በሁለት ደረጃዎች ላይ የሚጠያየቅ ደረጃዎችን ሁሉ ያስተካክላል። የአራርተርክ ብዙዎች-ስራ ትምህርት ማድረግ፣ ማስታወቂያውን እና አካባቢነትን እንደተጨማሪ ስራዎችን በመጠቀም እንፈልጋለን፡፡ ብዙ ሥርዓት ሞዴሌዎች በተማረ ጊዜ የተማሩት ስራዎችን በሙሉ የሚወስዱ ናቸው ብለን እናሳያቸዋለን፡፡ የሞዴላዎቻችንን ድምፅ በማድረግ እና የBC5CDR ዳታተሮች በመጠቀም የቢዩ መድኃኒት አካባቢ አካላትን እናስተዋልታለን፡፡ የሜድMentions ዳታ ማዕከላዊ እና የBC5CDR ፍሬዎችን እናስተካከላለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Բիոբիոբժշկական տեքստի վերլուծության մեջ բազմաթիվ խնդիրների առաջին քայլն է, ինչպիսիք են հարաբերությունների վերացումը և նպատակի հայտնաբերումը: Հաճախ, կենսաբժշկական առանձնահատկությունը, որը կապում է մեթոդները, շատ կախված է հորիստիկ կանոններից և նախկինում սահմանափակված, հաճախ բնագավառի հատկություններից: Այս առանձնահատկությունները փորձում են վերցնել միավորների առանձնահատկությունները և բարդ բազմաքային ճարտարապետական կառուցվածքները, որպեսզի հայտնաբերեն և հետագայում կապեն միավորների մասին: We propose a significant simplification to the biomedical entity linking setup that does not rely on any heuristic methods.  The system performs all the steps of the entity linking task jointly in either single or two stages.  We explore the use of hierarchical multi-task learning, using mention recognition and entity typing tasks as auxiliary tasks.  Մենք ցույց ենք տալիս, որ հիերարխիկ բազմախնդիրների մոդելները մշտապես գերազանցում են միախնդիրների մոդելները, երբ վարժեցված խնդիրները միանգամայն են: Մենք գնահատում ենք մեր մոդելների արտադրողականությունը կենսաբժշկական էության վրա, որը կապում է հարաբերական նշաններ օգտագործելով Մեդեմենցիաներ և BC5CDR տվյալների համակարգեր: Մենք հասնում ենք թատրոնային արդյունքներ այն մարտահրավերների միջոցով, որոնք հանդիսանում են Մեդիմենցիայի տվյալների համակարգում, և BC5CDR-ի համեմատական արդյունքներ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ca>El reconeixement i l'enllaç d'entitats és un primer pas crucial a moltes tasques en l'anàlisi de textos biomèdics, com l'extracció de relacions i l'identificació d'objectius. Tradicionalment, les entitats biomèdiques que enllacen mètodes es basan fortament en normes heurístiques i característiques predefinides, sovint específices per domini. Les característiques intenten capturar les propietats d'entitats i arquitectures complexes a molts passos per detectar, i després enllaçar les mencions d'entitats. Proposem una simplificació significativa a l'entitat biomèdica que vincula una estructura que no es basa en mètodes heurístics. El sistema fa totes les etapes de l'entitat enllaçant la tasca conjuntament en una o dues etapes. Explorem l'ús de l'aprenentatge jeràrquic multitasca, utilitzant el reconeixement de mencions i la tipulació de tasques d'entitats com tasques auxiliars. Ens demostram que els models jeràrquics de múltiples tasques superen constantment els models d'una tasca única quan les tasques entrenades són homogènes. Evaluam el rendiment dels nostres models sobre l'entitat biomèdica que enllaça els punts de referència utilitzant els conjunts de dades MedMentions i BC5CDR. Obtenim resultats actuals en el conjunt de dades MedMentions desafiant, i resultats comparables en BC5CDR.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_az>Birlikləri tanıma və bağlama ilk dəfə biomedical mətn analizi ilə çoxluğuna ilk dəfə mövcuddur, həmçin in əlaqələr çıxarılması və məqsəd kimlikləri kimi. Adətli olaraq, biomedical entity linking metodları heuristik qaydalarına və əvvəlcə belə təyin edilmiş, çox çox domain-specific özelliklərinə təvəkkül edir. Bütün xüsusiyyətlər bir növünün və kompleks çoxlu-adım arhitektarının xüsusiyyətlərini tapmağa çalışır və sonradan bir növünün sözlərini bağlayır. Bizim biomediciyal təhsil etdiyimiz məsələlərə heç bir heuristik metodlara təvəkkül edilməyən təhsil etmək üçün çox asanlaşdırma təklif edirik. Sistem hər bir ya da iki dəfə işləri birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə olan entitənin bütün adımlarını gerçəkləşdirir. Biz hiyerarşik çoxlu işlər öyrənməsini keşfetirik, yada salmaq və məlumat işlərini kömək işləri kimi yazmaq üçün istifadə edirik. Biz hiyerarşik çoxlu işlər modellərinin təhsil edilmiş işlər homogeneyy olduğu zaman təhsil edilən tək işlər modellərindən üstün olduğunu göstəririk. Biz MedMentions və BC5CDR veri qurmaqlarını istifadə edən biomedical entitətlərin performansını değerləşdiririk. Biz MedMentions verilənlərin çətinlikləri və BC5CDR ilə müqayisədə müəyyən sonuçlarını başa düşürük.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Prepoznavanje i povezivanje subjekta je ključni prvi korak za mnoge zadatke u analizi biomedicinskih tekstova, poput odnosa na ekstrakciju i ciljnu identifikaciju. Tradicionalno, biomedicinska entiteta koja povezuje metode teško se oslanja na heuristička pravila i predodređena, često specifična domena. Objekti pokušavaju uhvatiti vlasništvo entiteta i kompleksnih multikoracijskih arhitektura za otkrivanje, i nakon toga spominju entitet. Predlažemo značajno jednostavljenje biomedicinskom entitetu koja povezuje postavku koja se ne oslanja na nijednu heurističku metodu. Sistem obavlja sve korake entiteta koja povezuje zadatak zajedno na jednom ili dva faza. Istražujemo korištenje hijerarhijskog učenja multizadataka, koristeći spominjanje priznanja i zadatke za pisanje entiteta kao pomoćne zadatke. Pokazujemo da hijerarhijski multizadatačni modeli konsekventno nadmađuju jednozadatačne modele kada su obučeni zadatak homogenezan. Procjenjujemo učinkovitost naših modela na biomedicinskom entitetu povezivajući kriterije koristeći MedMentions i BC5CDR dataset. Postignemo rezultate stanja umjetnosti na izazovnom sastavu podataka za MedMentions i usporedbenim rezultatima BC5CDR-a.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_fi>Yksiköiden tunnistaminen ja linkittäminen on ensiaskel moniin biolääketieteellisen tekstianalyysin tehtäviin, kuten yhteyksien poimimiseen ja kohteiden tunnistamiseen. Perinteisesti biolääketieteelliset entiteettilinkitysmenetelmät perustuvat vahvasti heuristisiin sääntöihin ja ennalta määriteltyihin, usein toimialueekohtaisiin ominaisuuksiin. Ominaisuudet yrittävät vangita entiteettien ja monimutkaisten monivaiheisten arkkitehtuurien ominaisuudet havaitakseen ja linkittää sen jälkeen entiteettimainintoja. Ehdotamme merkittävää yksinkertaistamista biolääketieteellisen kokonaisuuden linkittämiseen, joka ei perustu heuristisiin menetelmiin. Järjestelmä suorittaa kaikki linkitystehtävän vaiheet yhdessä joko yhdessä tai kahdessa vaiheessa. Tutkimme hierarkkisen monitehtäväoppimisen käyttöä käyttämällä aputehtävinä mainintojen tunnistus- ja entiteettikirjoitustehtäviä. Osoitamme, että hierarkkiset monitehtävämallit suoriutuvat johdonmukaisesti yhden tehtävän malleista, kun koulutetut tehtävät ovat homogeenisia. Arvioimme malliemme suorituskykyä biolääketieteellisten kokonaisuuksien linkittämisessä MedMentions- ja BC5CDR-aineistojen avulla. Haastavasta MedMentions-aineistosta saadaan huipputason tuloksia ja BC5CDR:stä vertailukelpoisia tuloksia.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_cs>Rozpoznání a propojení entit je klíčovým prvním krokem k mnoha úkolům v biomedicínské analýze textu, jako je extrakce vztahů a identifikace cílů. Metody propojení biomedicínských entit tradičně spoléhají na heuristických pravidlech a předem definovaných, často specifických vlastnostech domény. Funkce se snaží zachytit vlastnosti entit a složitých vícestupňových architektur k detekci a následně propojení zmínek entit. Navrhujeme výrazné zjednodušení biomedicínské entity propojující nastavení, které není spoléháno na žádné heuristické metody. Systém provádí všechny kroky entity propojující úkol společně buď v jednom, nebo dvou fázích. Prozkoumáme využití hierarchického víceúkolového učení s využitím úkolů rozpoznávání zmínek a zadávání entit jako pomocných úkolů. Ukazujeme, že hierarchické modely více úkolů konzistentně překonávají modely jednotlivých úkolů, pokud jsou trénované úkoly homogenní. Hodnotíme výkonnost našich modelů na biomedicínské entitě propojující benchmarky pomocí datových sad MedMentions a BC5CDR. Dosahujeme aktuálních výsledků na náročném datovém souboru MedMentions a srovnatelných výsledků na BC5CDR.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Üksuste tunnustamine ja sidumine on esmatähtis samm paljude biomeditsiinilise tekstianalüüsi ülesannete puhul, nagu seoste väljatöötamine ja sihtmärgi tuvastamine. Traditsiooniliselt tuginevad biomeditsiinilised üksuste sidumise meetodid suurel määral heuristilistele reeglitele ja eelnevalt määratletud, sageli domeenispetsiifilistele omadustele. Funktsioonid püüavad tuvastada olemite ja keerukate mitmeastmeliste arhitektuuride omadusi ning seejärel siduda olemi mainimised. Me teeme ettepaneku oluliseks lihtsustamiseks biomeditsiinilise üksuse ühendamise seadistus, mis ei tugine heuristilistele meetoditele. Süsteem täidab kõik üksuse siduva ülesande etapid ühiselt kas ühes või kahes etapis. Uurime hierarhilise mitmeülesandelise õppe kasutamist, kasutades lisaülesannetena mainimise ja olemi tippimise ülesandeid. Näitame, et hierarhilised mitmeülesandelised mudelid ületavad pidevalt ühe ülesandega mudeleid, kui koolitatud ülesanded on homogeensed. Hindame oma mudelite tulemuslikkust biomeditsiinilise üksuse ühendamisel, kasutades MedMentions ja BC5CDR andmekogumeid. Me saavutame väljakutsuva MedMentions andmekogumi ja võrreldavad tulemused BC5CDR kohta.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>Attribute Tradisyonal, biyoterap Enty sing nggunakake sistem wis nggawe ng hekuristik usul lan predefined, often domain-special songs. Perintah sing dipunangguna kuwi nggawe perintah karo atit lan architecture multi-pas sing dumadhi kanggo anawa, lan nganggo structural navigation Awak dhéwé ngerasah akeh seneng dipun-seneng nggawe barang nggawe gerakan ingkang ambang, kuwi mau. Sistem iso ngewehke kabeh kelompok Entète nang nggawe operasi dadi saboh sekang karo cadasara Packages Awak dhéwé ngerasakno karo akeh multi-task model sing isiterkanti nggawe bakal-task model sing dituruti cara-cara sing dirakno. We assertive Awak dhéwé iso nglanggar stad-karcis dadi sing dikarepaké medMentions, lan nganggo gambarang barang kanggo kowe mbédaké B5-CDR</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>זיהוי ומקשר יחידות הוא צעד ראשון קריטי למשימות רבות בניתוח טקסט ביורפואי, כמו חיפוש יחסים וזיהוי מטרה. באופן מסורתי, יחידה ביו-רפואית שמקשרת שיטות תלויה בכבד על חוקים היוריסטיים ומגדולים מראש, לעתים קרובות תואר ספציפי. המאפיינים מנסים לתפוס את תכונות היחידות וארכיטקטורות מורכבות במספר צעדים כדי לגלות, ולאחר מכן לקשר היחידות מזכירות. אנחנו מציעים שיטה משמעותית ליחידת הביומודיקה שמקשרת את המערכת שלא תלוי בשיטות היוריסטיות. המערכת מבצעת את כל הצעד של היחידה שמקשרת משימה יחד בשלבים אחדים או שניים. אנו חוקרים את השימוש של הלימוד היררכי במשימות רבות, בשימוש זיהוי מזכיר ומשימות הכתיבה של ישויות כמשימות עזריות. אנחנו מראים שדוגמנים היררכיים עם משימות רבות עולים באופן קבוע על דוגמנים משימות אחת כאשר משימות מאומנות הן הומוגנות. We evaluate the performance of our models on the biomedical entity linking benchmarks using MedMentions and BC5CDR datasets.  We achieve state-of-theart results on the challenging MedMentions dataset, and comparable results on BC5CDR.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Prepoznavanje in povezovanje subjektov je ključen prvi korak pri številnih nalogah v biomedicinski analizi besedila, kot sta pridobivanje povezav in identifikacija ciljev. Tradicionalno so metode povezovanja biomedicinskih entitet močno odvisne od heurističnih pravil in vnaprej določenih, pogosto domensko specifičnih značilnosti. Funkcije poskušajo zajeti lastnosti entitet in kompleksnih večstopenjskih arhitektur za zaznavanje in nato povezati omembe entitet. Predlagamo znatno poenostavitev nastavitve povezovanja biomedicinskih entitet, ki se ne zanaša na heuristične metode. Sistem izvaja vse korake subjekta, ki povezujejo nalogo, skupaj v eni ali dveh fazah. Raziskujemo uporabo hierarhičnega večopravilnega učenja z uporabo nalog prepoznavanja omenjanja in tipkanja entitet kot pomožnih nalog. Pokazujemo, da hierarhični večopravilni modeli dosledno presegajo enoopravilne modele, kadar so usposobljena opravila homogena. Učinkovitost naših modelov ocenjujemo na biomedicinskem subjektu, ki povezuje referenčne vrednosti z uporabo naborov podatkov MedMentions in BC5CDR. Dosežemo najnovejše rezultate na zahtevnem naboru podatkov MedMentions in primerljive rezultate na BC5CDR.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>Recognising and linking entities is a crucial first step to many tasks in biomedical text analysis, such as relation extraction and target identification. Traditionally, biomedical entity linking methods rely heavily on heuristic rules and predefined, often domain-specific features. The features try to capture the properties of entities and complex multi-step architectures to detect, and subsequently link entity mentions. We propose a significant simplification to the biomedical entity linking up a setup that does not rely on any heuristic methods. མ་ལག་གིས་ཤོག་ཚད་གཅིག་ཡང་ན་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ནང་ནས་དབུལ་གྱི་རྐྱེན་ཚད་ཡོངས་རྫོགས་ལ་སྦྲེལ་བ་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་དབུས་གཞུང་གི་སྣ་མང་ལས་ཀ་སྦྱོར་བའི་སྐོར་ལས་རྩོལ་བ་ཞིབ་ཀྱང་མཐོང་བ་དང་། འུ་ཅག་གིས་སྟངས་འཛིན་གྱི་མི་སྣ་མང་བྱ་འགུལ་གྱི་མིག་གཟུགས་རྣམས་ལས་སྦྱོར་བ་ཡིན་ན་ཏེ། ང་ཚོས་ཀྱིས་MedMentions དང BC5CDR གནད་སྡུད་ཚན་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་གླེང་བའི་མིག་གཟུགས་རྟགས་ཀྱི་ལས་འགན ང་ཚོས་དཀའ་ངལ་ཆེན་ཡིག་ཆ་སྒྲིག་འགོད་བྱེད་པའི་གནས་སྟངས་གནས་སྟངས་མང་ཙམ་འབྲས་བ་རེད།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_ha>Ana gane da kuma masu haɗi da abubuwa na muhimu ne a kwance wa aikin mãsu yawa a analyza matsayin bajirai, kamar shirin zartar da kuma shaidar jigon. A kan ƙidãya, hanyoyin linking masu nau'i masu nau'in da kuma ana ƙayyade, ko da yawa masu hususann Domen-Specific. Furofati sun yi jarraba ka kãma properties wa abun, da kuma an sami matsayin wasu na'ura masu haɗi dõmin su gane, kuma a bayan su haɗi sunan abun. Munã goyya da sauƙi mai muhimmin zuwa ma'abun da aka samar da shi da tsari wanda ba ta dõgara ga wasu hanyõyin heuristic ba. @ action: button Tuna ƙidãya amfani da masu amfani da shiryarwa masu ƙaranci masu aikin aiki da ke amfani da sunan da abun da za'a rubũta aikin da aka lissafa. Tuna nũna cewa misãlai masu yin hierrchical multi-aikin sambata ke tafiyar misãlai masu yin aiki guda idan an sanar da aikin su su samo. Ana ƙaddara cikakken misalinmu a kan abubuwa da aka yi amfani da matsayin ayuka na MedMentions da BC5CDR. Tuna sami fassarar-halin-sanatarwa a kan kanana na MedMentions, da sami matsala na BC5CDR.</abstract_ha>
      </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Evaluation of Machine Translation Methods applied to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medical_terminology">Medical Terminologies</a></title>
      <author><first>Konstantinos</first><last>Skianis</last></author>
      <author><first>Yann</first><last>Briand</last></author>
      <author><first>Florent</first><last>Desgrippes</last></author>
      <pages>59–69</pages>
      <abstract>Medical terminologies resources and standards play vital roles in clinical data exchanges, enabling significantly the services’ interoperability within healthcare national information networks. Health and medical science are constantly evolving causing requirements to advance the terminologies editions. In this paper, we present our evaluation work of the latest machine translation techniques addressing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medical_terminology">medical terminologies</a>. Experiments have been conducted leveraging selected statistical and neural machine translation methods. The devised procedure is tested on a validated sample of ICD-11 and ICF terminologies from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a> with promising results.</abstract>
      <url hash="4241ab53">2020.louhi-1.7</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.louhi-1.7</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940042" />
      <bibkey>skianis-etal-2020-evaluation</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/dbpedia">DBpedia</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Defining and Learning Refined Temporal Relations in the Clinical Narrative</title>
      <author><first>Kristin</first><last>Wright-Bettner</last></author>
      <author><first>Chen</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Timothy</first><last>Miller</last></author>
      <author><first>Steven</first><last>Bethard</last></author>
      <author><first>Dmitriy</first><last>Dligach</last></author>
      <author><first>Martha</first><last>Palmer</last></author>
      <author><first>James H.</first><last>Martin</last></author>
      <author><first>Guergana</first><last>Savova</last></author>
      <pages>104–114</pages>
      <abstract>We present refinements over existing temporal relation annotations in the Electronic Medical Record clinical narrative. We refined the THYME corpus annotations to more faithfully represent nuanced temporality and nuanced temporal-coreferential relations. The main contributions are in re-defining CONTAINS and OVERLAP relations into CONTAINS, CONTAINS-SUBEVENT, OVERLAP and NOTED-ON. We demonstrate that these refinements lead to substantial gains in learnability for state-of-the-art transformer models as compared to previously reported results on the original THYME corpus. We thus establish a baseline for the automatic extraction of these refined temporal relations. Although our study is done on clinical narrative, we believe it addresses far-reaching challenges that are corpus- and domain- agnostic.</abstract>
      <url hash="4f1bb59f">2020.louhi-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.louhi-1.12</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940047" />
      <bibkey>wright-bettner-etal-2020-defining</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Context-Aware Automatic Text Simplification of Health Materials in Low-Resource Domains</title>
      <author><first>Tarek</first><last>Sakakini</last></author>
      <author><first>Jong Yoon</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Aditya</first><last>Duri</last></author>
      <author><first>Renato F.L.</first><last>Azevedo</last></author>
      <author><first>Victor</first><last>Sadauskas</last></author>
      <author><first>Kuangxiao</first><last>Gu</last></author>
      <author><first>Suma</first><last>Bhat</last></author>
      <author><first>Dan</first><last>Morrow</last></author>
      <author><first>James</first><last>Graumlich</last></author>
      <author><first>Saqib</first><last>Walayat</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Hasegawa-Johnson</last></author>
      <author><first>Thomas</first><last>Huang</last></author>
      <author><first>Ann</first><last>Willemsen-Dunlap</last></author>
      <author><first>Donald</first><last>Halpin</last></author>
      <pages>115–126</pages>
      <abstract>Healthcare systems have increased patients’ exposure to their own health materials to enhance patients’ health levels, but this has been impeded by patients’ lack of understanding of their health material. We address potential barriers to their comprehension by developing a context-aware text simplification system for health material. Given the scarcity of annotated parallel corpora in healthcare domains, we design our system to be independent of a parallel corpus, complementing the availability of data-driven neural methods when such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpora</a> are available. Our system compensates for the lack of direct supervision using a biomedical lexical database : Unified Medical Language System (UMLS). Compared to a competitive prior approach that uses a tool for identifying biomedical concepts and a consumer-directed vocabulary list, we empirically show the enhanced accuracy of our system due to improved handling of ambiguous terms. We also show the enhanced <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> over directly-supervised neural methods in this low-resource setting. Finally, we show the direct impact of our system on laypeople’s comprehension of health material via a human subjects’ study (n=160).</abstract>
      <url hash="50778ff7">2020.louhi-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.louhi-1.13</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940053" />
      <bibkey>sakakini-etal-2020-context</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Identifying Personal Experience Tweets of Medication Effects Using Pre-trained RoBERTa Language Model and Its Updating<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>a Language Model and Its Updating</title>
      <author><first>Minghao</first><last>Zhu</last></author>
      <author><first>Youzhe</first><last>Song</last></author>
      <author><first>Ge</first><last>Jin</last></author>
      <author><first>Keyuan</first><last>Jiang</last></author>
      <pages>127–137</pages>
      <abstract>Post-market surveillance, the practice of monitoring the safe use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medication">pharmaceutical drugs</a> is an important part of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pharmacovigilance">pharmacovigilance</a>. Being able to collect personal experience related to pharmaceutical product use could help us gain insight into how the human body reacts to different medications. Twitter, a popular social media service, is being considered as an important alternative data source for collecting personal experience information with medications. Identifying personal experience tweets is a challenging classification task in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a>. In this study, we utilized three methods based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook">Facebook</a>’s Robustly Optimized BERT Pretraining Approach (RoBERTa) to predict personal experience tweets related to medication use : the first one combines the pre-trained RoBERTa model with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a>, the second combines the updated pre-trained RoBERTa model using a corpus of unlabeled tweets with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a>, and the third combines the RoBERTa model that was trained with our unlabeled tweets from scratch with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> too. Our results show that all of these approaches outperform the published methods (Word Embedding + LSTM) in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a> performance (p   0.05), and updating the pre-trained language model with tweets related to medications could even improve the performance further.</abstract>
      <url hash="0e26c93c">2020.louhi-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.louhi-1.14</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940051" />
      <bibkey>zhu-etal-2020-identifying</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>