<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.insights">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Insights from Negative Results in NLP</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Rogers</last></editor>
      <editor><first>João</first><last>Sedoc</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Rumshisky</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="6e7b4663">2020.insights-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>insights-2020-insights</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Which Matters Most? Comparing the Impact of Concept and Document Relationships in Topic Models</title>
      <author><first>Silvia</first><last>Terragni</last></author>
      <author><first>Debora</first><last>Nozza</last></author>
      <author><first>Elisabetta</first><last>Fersini</last></author>
      <author><first>Messina</first><last>Enza</last></author>
      <pages>32–40</pages>
      <abstract>Topic models have been widely used to discover hidden topics in a collection of documents. In this paper, we propose to investigate the role of two different types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relational_model">relational information</a>, i.e. document relationships and concept relationships. While exploiting the document network significantly improves <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coherence_(linguistics)">topic coherence</a>, the introduction of concepts and their relationships does not influence the results both quantitatively and qualitatively.</abstract>
      <url hash="7068a284">2020.insights-1.5</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="97511234">2020.insights-1.5.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.insights-1.5</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940792" />
      <bibkey>terragni-etal-2020-matters</bibkey>
    <title_ar>أيهما أكثر أهمية؟ مقارنة تأثير علاقات المفهوم والوثيقة في نماذج الموضوعات</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Qu'est-ce qui compte le plus ? Comparaison de l'impact des relations entre les concepts et les documents dans les modèles thématiques</title_fr>
      <title_pt>O que mais importa? Comparando o Impacto dos Relacionamentos de Conceitos e Documentos em Modelos de Tópicos</title_pt>
      <title_es>¿Qué es lo más importante? Comparación del impacto de las relaciones entre conceptos y documentos en modelos de temas</title_es>
      <title_ja>最も重要なのは、トピックモデルにおけるコンセプトとドキュメントの関係の影響を比較することです</title_ja>
      <title_zh>孰为重? 校其名与文档,在於题模</title_zh>
      <title_hi>कौन सा सबसे ज्यादा मायने रखता है? विषय मॉडल में अवधारणा और दस्तावेज़ संबंधों के प्रभाव की तुलना करना</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Что имеет наибольшее значение? Сравнение влияния концептуальных и документарных отношений в тематических моделях</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Cé acu Rudaí is mó? Comparáid a dhéanamh idir Tionchar Coincheapa agus Caidrimh Doiciméid i Múnlaí Ábhair</title_ga>
      <title_ka>კჲთ ვ ნაი-დჲლვმთრვ? კონცექტის და დოკუმენტის შესახებების შესახებ ტემიკური მოდელში</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Melyik számít a legjobban? A koncepció és dokumentum kapcsolatok hatásának összehasonlítása a téma modellekben</title_hu>
      <title_el>Ποιο έχει μεγαλύτερη σημασία; Σύγκριση των επιπτώσεων της έννοιας και των σχέσεων εγγράφων σε θεματικά μοντέλα</title_el>
      <title_it>Che importa di piu'? Confronto dell'impatto delle relazioni concettuali e documentali nei modelli tematici</title_it>
      <title_kk>Кейбір нәрсе? Нақыштар үлгілерінде концепция мен құжат қатынастарының нәтижесін салыстыру</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Што е најважно? Споредување на влијанието на концептот и врските со документите во темските модели</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Which Matters Most?  Koncepcijos ir dokumentų santykių poveikio teminiams modeliams palyginimas</title_lt>
      <title_ml>ഏത് കാര്യം? കോണ്‍സെപ്റ്റിന്റെയും രേഖയുടെയും ബന്ധങ്ങളുടെയും പ്രഭാവം സമര്‍പ്പിക്കുക</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Apa yang paling penting? Comparing the Impact of Concept and Document Relationships in Topic Models</title_ms>
      <title_mn>Хамгийн их асуудал вэ? Тодорхойлолт болон Документын харилцааны нөлөөлөлийг харьцуулах нь</title_mn>
      <title_mt>Liema Materji l-Aktar? Tqabbil tal-Impatt tar-Relazzjonijiet tal-Kunċett u tad-Dokument fil-Mudelli Tematiċi</title_mt>
      <title_no>Kva ting mest? Sammenliknar effekten av konsept og dokumentrelasjon i temamodeller</title_no>
      <title_pl>Co jest najważniejsze? Porównanie wpływu relacji koncepcyjnych i dokumentowych w modelach tematycznych</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Koja je najveća stvar? U usporedbi utjecaja koncepta i odnosa dokumenta u temskim modelima</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Care contează cel mai mult? Compararea impactului relaţiilor concepte şi documente în modelele tematice</title_ro>
      <title_si>මොන විදිහක්ද? ප්‍රශ්නය සහ විද්‍යාපති සම්බන්ධතාවයේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් සම්බන්ධතාවය සම්බන්ධතාව</title_si>
      <title_so>Waxyaabaha ugu badan? Comparing the Impact of Concept and Document Relationships in Topic Models</title_so>
      <title_sv>Vilket betyder mest? Jämföra effekten av koncept- och dokumentrelationer i ämnesmodeller</title_sv>
      <title_ta>எந்த விஷயங்களில் பெரும்பாலானது? Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>کس چیز میں زیادہ؟ توسط موڈل میں تفصیل اور سند رابطہ کا اثر مقایسہ کرتا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Qancha muhim? Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Điều quan trọng nhất? Đối chiếu ảnh hưởng của mối quan hệ giữa văn bản và tài liệu trong mẫu chính</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Кое е най-важно? Сравняване на въздействието на концепцията и документните взаимоотношения в тематичните модели</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Wat doet er het meest toe? Vergelijking van de impact van concept- en documentrelaties in topic modellen</title_nl>
      <title_da>Hvad betyder mest? Sammenligning af begrebs- og dokumentrelationer i emnemodeller</title_da>
      <title_hr>Koje stvari najviše? U usporedbi utjecaja koncepta i odnosa dokumenta u temskim modelima</title_hr>
      <title_de>Was zählt am meisten? Vergleich der Auswirkungen von Konzept- und Dokumentenbeziehungen in Themenmodellen</title_de>
      <title_ko>뭐가 제일 중요해요?주제 모델에서의 개념과 문서 관계의 영향 비교</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Ni mambo gani zaidi? Kulinganisha Impact of Concept and Document Relations in Models of Topic</title_sw>
      <title_tr>The grammatical type of a word Mazmunlar we Sened Derjesini Mazmunlar</title_tr>
      <title_af>Watter Matters mees? Vergelyking van die Impact van Concept en DokumentRelasies in Tema Modelle</title_af>
      <title_am>ምንኛው ጉዳይ? ዶሴ `%s'ን ማስፈጠር አልተቻለም፦ %s</title_am>
      <title_id>Yang paling penting? Comparing the Impact of Concept and Document Relations in Topic Models</title_id>
      <title_fa>کدوم مشکلي هست؟ در مقایسه تاثیر تفسیر و ارتباطات سند در مدل موضوع</title_fa>
      <title_hy>Ո՞րն է ամենակարևորը: Համեմատելով թեմային մոդելների գաղափարի և փաստաթղթերի հարաբերությունների ազդեցությունը</title_hy>
      <title_az>Neçə məsələlər? Mevzu Modüllərində Konceptör və Dəstə İlişkilərinin İlişkilərini</title_az>
      <title_bn>কোন ব্যাপার? বিষয় মডেলে কনসেপ্ট এবং নথি সম্পর্কের প্রভাব তুলনা করুন</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Koja je najveća stvar? U usporedbi utjecaja koncepta i odnosa dokumenta u temskim modelima</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Què importa més? Comparar l'impacte de les relacions conceptuals i documentals als models temàtics</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Na čem záleží nejvíc? Porovnání vlivu koncepčních a dokumentových vztahů v tématických modelech</title_cs>
      <title_et>Mis on kõige olulisem? Kontseptsiooni ja dokumentide seoste mõju võrdlemine teemamudelites</title_et>
      <title_sq>Cila është më e rëndësishme? Duke krahasuar ndikimin e lidhjeve me konceptin dhe dokumentet në modelet tematike</title_sq>
      <title_fi>Mikä on tärkeintä? Konsepti- ja asiakirjasuhteiden vaikutusten vertailu aihemalleissa</title_fi>
      <title_jv>align-reference-type string" in "context_BAR_stringLink</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Kaj je najbolj pomembno? Primerjava vpliva konceptnih in dokumentskih odnosov v tematskih modelih</title_sk>
      <title_he>מה הכי חשוב? השוואה של השפעה של יחסי מושג ומסמך במודלים נושאיים</title_he>
      <title_ha>QDialogButtonBox @ action</title_ha>
      <title_bo>ཡིན་ནའི་དོན་ཚན་གང་ཞིག་ཡིན་ནམ། Comparing the Impact of Concept and Document Relationships in Topic Models</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تم استخدام نماذج الموضوعات على نطاق واسع لاكتشاف الموضوعات المخفية في مجموعة من المستندات. في هذه الورقة ، نقترح التحقيق في دور نوعين مختلفين من المعلومات العلائقية ، أي علاقات الوثيقة وعلاقات المفهوم. بينما يؤدي استغلال شبكة المستندات إلى تحسين تماسك الموضوع بشكل كبير ، فإن إدخال المفاهيم وعلاقاتها لا يؤثر على النتائج من الناحيتين الكمية والنوعية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Los modelos de temas se han utilizado ampliamente para descubrir temas ocultos en una colección de documentos. En este artículo, proponemos investigar el papel de dos tipos diferentes de información relacional, es decir, las relaciones documentales y las relaciones conceptuales. Si bien la explotación de la red documental mejora significativamente la coherencia de los temas, la introducción de conceptos y sus relaciones no influye en los resultados tanto cuantitativa como cualitativamente.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Os modelos de tópicos têm sido amplamente utilizados para descobrir tópicos ocultos em uma coleção de documentos. Neste artigo, propomos investigar o papel de dois tipos diferentes de informações relacionais, ou seja, relacionamentos de documentos e relacionamentos de conceitos. Embora a exploração da rede de documentos melhore significativamente a coerência dos tópicos, a introdução de conceitos e suas relações não influencia os resultados quantitativa e qualitativamente.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Les modèles de sujets ont été largement utilisés pour découvrir des sujets cachés dans une collection de documents. Dans cet article, nous proposons d'étudier le rôle de deux types différents d'informations relationnelles, à savoir les relations entre documents et les relations conceptuelles. Bien que l'exploitation du réseau documentaire améliore considérablement la cohérence des sujets, l'introduction de concepts et de leurs relations n'influence pas les résultats tant quantitativement que qualitativement.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>トピックモデルは、ドキュメントコレクションの隠されたトピックを発見するために広く使用されています。本稿では，関係情報の2つの異なるタイプ，すなわち文書関係と概念関係の役割について検討することを提案する．ドキュメントネットワークを利用することで、トピックの一貫性が大幅に向上する一方で、概念とその関係性の導入は、定量的および定性的の両方の結果に影響を与えません。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>大显模形已博见文档合中隐题。 本文者,所以论信息者,文档名也。 虽用文档网络可以显一致性,而名入于数定性也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>विषय मॉडल का व्यापक रूप से दस्तावेजों के संग्रह में छिपे हुए विषयों की खोज करने के लिए उपयोग किया गया है। इस पेपर में, हम दो अलग-अलग प्रकार की संबंधपरक जानकारी की भूमिका की जांच करने का प्रस्ताव करते हैं, यानी दस्तावेज़ संबंध और अवधारणा संबंध। जबकि दस्तावेज़ नेटवर्क का शोषण काफी विषय सुसंगतता में सुधार करता है, अवधारणाओं और उनके संबंधों की शुरूआत परिणामों को मात्रात्मक और गुणात्मक रूप से प्रभावित नहीं करती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Модели тем широко используются для обнаружения скрытых тем в коллекции документов. В данной работе мы предлагаем исследовать роль двух различных типов реляционной информации, т.е. взаимосвязей документов и концептуальных взаимосвязей. Хотя использование сети документов значительно повышает согласованность тем, внедрение концепций и их взаимосвязей не влияет на результаты как в количественном, так и в качественном отношении.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Baineadh leas go forleathan as samhlacha topaice chun topaicí ceilte a aimsiú i mbailiúchán doiciméad. Sa pháipéar seo, tá sé beartaithe againn imscrúdú a dhéanamh ar an ról atá ag dhá chineál éagsúla faisnéise choibhneasta, i.e. caidrimh doiciméad agus caidrimh choincheapa. Cé go gcuirtear feabhas suntasach ar chomhleanúnachas na n-ábhar trí leas a bhaint as an ngréasán doiciméad, ní bhíonn tionchar cainníochtúil agus cáilíochtúil ag tabhairt isteach coincheapa agus a ngaolmhaireachtaí.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ტემიკური მოდელები დიდი გამოყენებული დოკუმენტების კოლექციაში დახმარებული თემენტების აღმოჩენისთვის. ამ დოკუმენტში ჩვენ მინდომენეთ ორი განსხვავებული განსხვავებული შესახებ ინფორმაციის პროლის შესახებ, ანუ დოკუმენტის შესახებ და კონცექტის შესახებ დოკუმენტის ქსელის გამოყენება მნიშვნელოვანად აღმოქმედება ტემენტიკური თანასწორობას, კონცეტების და მათი გრძნობების შესახებ არ აღმოქმედება წარმოქმედების კონტ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Τα μοντέλα θεμάτων έχουν χρησιμοποιηθεί ευρέως για την ανακάλυψη κρυφών θεμάτων σε μια συλλογή εγγράφων. Στην παρούσα εργασία, προτείνουμε να διερευνηθεί ο ρόλος δύο διαφορετικών τύπων σχεσιακών πληροφοριών, δηλαδή των σχέσεων εγγράφων και των εννοιολογικών σχέσεων. Ενώ η αξιοποίηση του δικτύου εγγράφων βελτιώνει σημαντικά τη συνοχή των θεμάτων, η εισαγωγή εννοιών και των σχέσεων τους δεν επηρεάζει τα αποτελέσματα τόσο ποσοτικά όσο και ποιοτικά.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A téma modelleket széles körben használják a dokumentumok gyűjteményében rejtett témák felfedezésére. Jelen tanulmányban két különböző típusú relációs információ szerepének vizsgálatát javasoljuk, azaz dokumentált kapcsolatok és fogalmi kapcsolatok szerepét. Miközben a dokumentumhálózat kihasználása jelentősen javítja a témakör koherenciáját, a fogalmak bevezetése és kapcsolataik mennyiségi és minőségi szempontból egyaránt nem befolyásolja az eredményeket.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>I modelli di argomenti sono stati ampiamente utilizzati per scoprire argomenti nascosti in una collezione di documenti. In questo articolo, proponiamo di indagare il ruolo di due diversi tipi di informazioni relazionali, cioè relazioni documentali e relazioni concettuali. Pur sfruttando la rete documentale migliora significativamente la coerenza degli argomenti, l'introduzione dei concetti e delle loro relazioni non influisce sui risultati sia quantitativamente che qualitativamente.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Topic models have been widely used to discover hidden topics in a collection of documents.  Šiame dokumente siūlome i štirti dviejų skirtingų rūšių santykinės informacijos vaidmenį, t. y. dokumentų santykius ir koncepcinius santykius. Dokumentų tinklo naudojimas gerokai pagerina temų nuoseklumą, tačiau sąvokų įvedimas ir jų santykiai neturi įtakos rezultatams tiek kiekybiniu, tiek kokybiniu požiūriu.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ml>രേഖകളുടെ ഒരു സംഘത്തില്‍ ഒളിഞ്ഞിരിക്കുന്ന പ്രമേയങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടുപിടിക്കാന്‍ വിശാലമായി ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു. ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍, രണ്ടു തരം വ്യത്യസ്ത വിവരങ്ങളുടെ പങ്ക് പരിശോധിക്കാന്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ ആലോചിക്കുന്നു, അതായത് രേഖയുടെ ബന്ധങ്ങളും സങ്കേ രേഖയുടെ ശേഖരം ഉപയോഗിക്കുമ്പോള്‍ പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട വിഭാഗത്തിന്റെ കൂട്ടത്തില്‍ മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്തുന്നതാണ്, ആശയങ്ങളുടെയും ബന്ധങ്ങളുടെയ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_ms>Model topik telah digunakan secara luas untuk menemui topik tersembunyi dalam koleksi dokumen. Dalam kertas ini, kami cadangkan untuk menyelidiki peran dua jenis maklumat relatif yang berbeza, iaitu hubungan dokumen dan hubungan konsep. Sementara mengeksploitasi rangkaian dokumen meningkatkan konsistensi topik secara signifikan, perkenalan konsep dan hubungan mereka tidak mempengaruhi keputusan baik kuantitatif maupun kualitif.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mn>Сүүлийн загварууд баримтын цуглуулалт нуугдмал сэдвүүдийг олохын тулд ихэвчлэн хэрэглэгдсэн. Энэ цаасан дээр бид хоёр өөр төрлийн харилцааны мэдээллийн үүрэг, яг баримт харилцаа, ойлголтын харилцааны үүрэг шийдэхийг санал болно. Документын сүлжээг ашиглан сэдвээс хамааралтай байдлыг илүү сайжруулдаг ч, ойлголт болон харилцааны танилцуулалт нь хэмжээст болон квалификацийн үр дүнд нөлөөлөхгүй.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mt>Il-mudelli tematiċi ntużaw b’mod wiesa’ biex jinstabu suġġetti moħbija f’ġabra ta’ dokumenti. F’dan id-dokument, qed nipproponu li ninvestigaw ir-rwol ta’ żewġ tipi different i ta’ informazzjoni relattiva, jiġifieri relazzjonijiet ta’ dokumenti u relazzjonijiet ta’ kunċett. Filwaqt li l-isfruttament tan-netwerk tad-dokumenti jtejjeb b’mod sinifikanti l-koerenza tas-suġġetti, l-introduzzjoni ta’ kunċetti u r-relazzjonijiet tagħhom ma tinfluwenzawx ir-riżultati kemm kwantitattivament kif ukoll kwalitattivament.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Emne- modeller er vast brukte for å oppdaga gøymde emne i eit samling av dokument. I denne papiret foreslår vi å undersøke rolen på to ulike typar relasjonelle informasjon, t.d. dokumentrelasjonar og konseptrelasjonar. Med å bruka dokumentnettverket er det betydelig forbetra temakoherens, introdusjonen av konseptar og forbindelsane sine ikkje påvirkar resultatene både kvantitativ og kvalitativ.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Modele tematyczne są szeroko stosowane do odkrywania ukrytych tematów w zbiorze dokumentów. W artykule proponujemy zbadanie roli dwóch różnych rodzajów informacji relacyjnych, tj. relacji dokumentowych i relacji koncepcyjnych. Podczas gdy wykorzystanie sieci dokumentów znacząco poprawia spójność tematów, wprowadzenie pojęć i ich relacji nie wpływa na wyniki zarówno ilościowo, jak i jakościowo.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mk>Темските модели се широко употребени за откривање скриени теми во колекција документи. In this paper, we propose to investigate the role of two different types of relational information, i.e. document relationships and concept relationships.  Иако искористувањето на мрежата на документи значително ја подобрува темата на кохеренцијата, воведувањето на концепти и нивните односи не влијае на резултатите како квантитивно, така и квалитетно.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ro>Modelele subiectelor au fost utilizate pe scară largă pentru a descoperi subiecte ascunse într-o colecție de documente. În această lucrare, propunem să investigăm rolul a două tipuri diferite de informații relaționale, și anume relațiile documentelor și relațiile conceptuale. Deși exploatarea rețelei de documente îmbunătățește semnificativ coerența subiectelor, introducerea conceptelor și relațiile acestora nu influențează rezultatele atât cantitativ, cât și calitativ.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Temski modeli su široko korišteni za otkrivanje skrivenih tema u kolekciji dokumenta. U ovom papiru predlažemo da istražimo ulogu dve različite vrste odnosanih informacija, tj. dokumentovanih odnosa i odnosa koncepta. Iako iskorištavanje mreže dokumenta značajno poboljšava saskaņonost teme, uvođenje koncepta i njihovih odnosa ne utiču na rezultate kvantitativno i kvalitativno.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_kk>Құжаттар жинағында жасырылған нақыштарды табу үшін мақыштар үлгіледі. Бұл қағазда, біз екі түрлі қатынастық мәліметтің рөлін зерттеу үшін, мысалы, құжаттың қатынасын және концепциялық қатынасын зерттеу үшін ұсынамыз. Құжаттардың желіне қолданып тұрғанда нақыштардың тегіздігін өзгертеді, концепциялардың және қатынастарының енгізімі санаттық және квалификациялық нәтижелеріне әсер етеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_si>විශේෂ මොඩේල් ලොකු විදිහට හොයාගන්න ලොකු විදිහට භාවිත කරලා තියෙනවා. මේ පත්තරේ අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා වෙනස් වර්ගයක් සම්බන්ධ තොරතුරු දෙකක් ගැන ප්‍රශ්නයක් පරීක්ෂණය කරන්න, ඉතින්  විද්‍යාපෘතිය ජාලය ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්නේ විද්‍යාපෘතිය සම්බන්ධතාවක් විශේෂයෙන් වැඩ කරනවා නමුත්, ප්‍රයෝජනය සහ ඔවුන්ග</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Tusaale-tijaabada waxaa si ballan ah loogu isticmaalay inaad hesho maadooyin qarsoon oo lagu soo ururiyo dukumentiyada. Warqaddan waxaan ka soo jeedaynaa inaan baaritaanno qaybaha labada nooc oo kala duduwan macluumaadka xiriirka, tusaale ahaan xiriirka dukumentiga iyo xiriirka fikirka. Inta lagu isticmaalayo shabakadda dukumentiga ayaa si weyn u hagaajiya islamarkaasna, soo saaridda fikrada iyo xiriirkoodu saameyn uma laha arimaha qiyaasta iyo qiyaastiisa.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Ämnesmodeller har använts ofta för att upptäcka dolda ämnen i en samling dokument. I denna uppsats föreslår vi att undersöka rollen av två olika typer av relationell information, dvs dokumentrelationer och konceptrelationer. Genom att utnyttja dokumentnätverket förbättras ämnessamstämmigheten avsevärt, men införandet av begrepp och deras relationer påverkar inte resultaten både kvantitativt och kvalitativt.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>பொருள் மாதிரிகள் ஆவணங்களின் தொகுப்பில் மறைந்த தலைப்புகளை கண்டுபிடிக்க பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. இந்த காகிதத்தில், நாம் இரண்டு வித்தியாசமான தொடர்பு தகவலின் பங்கை ஆய்வு செய்ய வேண்டும், அதாவது ஆவண உறவுகள் மற்றும் கருத்து  ஆவண வலைப்பின்னலை பயன்படுத்தும் பொழுது தலைப்புகளின் இணைப்பை மேம்படுத்தும் போது, கருத்துக்கள் மற்றும் அவர்களுடைய உறவுகள் குறிப்பிடும் மற்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>موضوع مدلکوں کو دکھانے کے مجموعہ میں چھپائے ہوئے موضوعوں کو کھولنے کے لئے وسیع طور پر استعمال کیا گیا ہے. ہم اس کاغذ میں دو مختلف طریقوں کی نسبت معلومات کی رول تحقیق کرنے کے لئے پیشنهاد کرتے ہیں، یعنی سند رابطہ اور معلومات رابطہ. دفتر نیٹورک کا استعمال کرنا ضروری طور پر موضوع کی تعلق سے زیادہ اضافہ کرتا ہے، نظریں اور ان کی تعلقات کا معلوم کرنا ثواب کے طور پر اور کفایت کے طور پر اضافہ نہیں کرتا.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Bu hujjatda biz ikki xil boshqa ma'lumot turlarining xususiyatini o'rganamiz, balki hujjatning bog'liqlari va fikr munosabatlarini o'rganamiz. Hujjatning tarmoqda foydalanishda mavzu birlashtirishni juda katta yaxshi ko'ra oshirish mumkin, g'oyalar va ularning huquqlari natijalariga qiymati va kvalifik natijalariga influensa olmaydi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Các mô hình chủ đề được sử dụng rộng rãi để tìm các chủ đề ẩn trong một bộ sưu tập tài liệu. Trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi đề nghị đi ều tra vai trò của hai loại thông tin liên quan khác nhau, đó là các mối quan hệ tài liệu và các mối quan hệ khái niệm. Sử dụng mạng lưới tài liệu cải thiện quan điểm đồng nhất, nhưng việc đưa ra các khái niệm và mối quan hệ của họ không ảnh hưởng đến kết quả về mặt lượng và chất lượng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Тематичните модели са широко използвани за откриване на скрити теми в колекция от документи. В настоящата статия предлагаме да се проучи ролята на два различни вида релационна информация, т.е. документиране на взаимоотношенията и концептуални взаимоотношения. Докато експлоатирането на документалната мрежа значително подобрява тематичната съгласуваност, въвеждането на концепции и техните взаимоотношения не влияе на резултатите както количествено, така и качествено.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Emnemodeller er blevet udbredt til at opdage skjulte emner i en samling af dokumenter. I denne artikel foreslår vi at undersøge rollen af to forskellige typer relationelle oplysninger, dvs. dokumentrelationer og konceptrelationer. Udnyttelsen af dokumentnetværket forbedrer emnetsammenhængen betydeligt, men indførelsen af begreber og deres relationer påvirker ikke resultaterne både kvantitativt og kvalitativt.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Topic modellen zijn veel gebruikt om verborgen onderwerpen in een verzameling documenten te ontdekken. In dit artikel stellen we voor om de rol van twee verschillende soorten relationele informatie te onderzoeken, namelijk documentrelaties en conceptrelaties. Hoewel het gebruik van het documentennetwerk de samenhang van onderwerpen aanzienlijk verbetert, heeft de introductie van concepten en hun relaties geen invloed op de resultaten, zowel kwantitatief als kwalitatief.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Themenmodelle wurden häufig verwendet, um versteckte Themen in einer Sammlung von Dokumenten zu entdecken. In diesem Beitrag schlagen wir vor, die Rolle von zwei verschiedenen Arten von relationalen Informationen zu untersuchen, d.h. Dokumentbeziehungen und Konzeptbeziehungen. Während die Nutzung des Dokumentennetzwerks die Themenkohärenz signifikant verbessert, beeinflusst die Einführung von Konzepten und deren Zusammenhängen die Ergebnisse sowohl quantitativ als auch qualitativ nicht.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>테마 모델은 문서 집합에 숨겨진 테마를 발견하는 데 광범위하게 사용된다.본고에서 우리는 두 가지 서로 다른 유형의 관계 정보의 작용, 즉 문서 관계와 개념 관계를 연구할 것을 건의한다.문서 네트워크를 이용하면 주제의 일관성을 현저히 높일 수 있으나 개념의 도입과 그 관계는 수량과 질에 영향을 미치지 않는다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>مدل‌های موضوع برای کشف موضوع مخفی در یک مجموعه سند وسیع استفاده شده‌اند. در این کاغذ، ما پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که نقش دو نوع اطلاعات متفاوتی را تحقیق کنیم، یعنی رابطه‌های سند و رابطه‌های مفهوم. در حالی که استفاده از شبکه سند به طور معنی هماهنگی موضوع را بهتر می‌کند، معرفی مفهوم‌ها و رابطه‌هایشان نتیجه‌ها را به اندازه‌ای و کیفیت تأثیر نمی‌دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Mradi wa mada umetumiwa sana kupata mada zilizofichikana katika mkusanyiko wa nyaraka. Katika karatasi hii, tunapendekeza kuchunguza jukumu la aina mbili tofauti za taarifa za mahusiano, yaani mahusiano ya nyaraka na mahusiano ya dhana. Wakati kutumia mitandao ya dokumentari inabadilisha ushirikiano wa mada, utekelezaji wa mawazo na mahusiano yao hauathiri matokeo hayo kwa kiasi kikubwa na kwa kiasi kikubwa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Senedler bilen gizli temalary a çmak üçin nusgala alyp bilýär Bu kagyzda, biz iki dürli görnüş maglumatyň, diýp görnüşleri we düşünjän baglaýyşlaryň tärini maslahat etmegi teklip edýäris. Senediň syýalanyny ulanyp meýdanlaryň ýerleşligini has gowy görkezýär, düşünjelerin we ilişkileriniň girişinde netijeleri hem quantitatik we hili görnüşde täsirleýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Onderwerp model is vaste gebruik om versteke onderwerpe in 'n versameling van dokumente te ontdek. In hierdie papier voorstel ons om die rol van twee verskillende tipe relasionele inligting te ondersoek, bv. dokument verhouding en konsepte verhouding. Terwyl die dokumentnetwerk uitgebruik word betekeurig onderwerp koherens verbeter, het die inligting van konsepte en hul verwantighede nie die resultate as kvantitatiewe en kwaliteit nie influens nie.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Modelet tematike janë përdorur gjerësisht për të zbuluar temat e fshehura në një koleksion dokumentesh. Në këtë letër, propozojmë të hetojmë rolin e dy llojeve të ndryshme të informacionit marrëdhënies, që do të thotë marrëdhëniet dokumentore dhe marrëdhëniet konceptive. Ndërsa shfrytëzimi i rrjetit të dokumenteve përmirëson ndjeshëm konsiderueshmërinë e temës, futja e koncepteve dhe marrëdhëniet e tyre nuk ndikon në rezultatet si kuantitativisht ashtu edhe kualitativisht.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hr>Temski modeli su široko korišteni za otkrivanje skrivenih tema u skupini dokumenta. U ovom papiru predlažemo istražiti ulogu dvije različite vrste odnosanih informacija, tj. dokumentacijskih odnosa i konceptnih odnosa. Iako iskorištavanje mreže dokumenta značajno poboljšava usklađenost teme, uvođenje koncepta i njihovih odnosa ne utječe na rezultate kvantitativno i kvalitativno.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_am>የተሰወረውን ጉዳዮች በሰብሰብ ውስጥ ለማግኘት የተጠቃሚ ሞዴል ተደረገ። በዚህ ገጽ፣ የሁለት ዓይነቶች የግንኙነት መረጃዎችን እና ምናልባት የሰነድ ግንኙነት እና የግንኙነት ግንኙነት እና መፍጠር እናዘጋጅታለን፡፡ ሰነዱን መረብ በመጠቀም ጊዜ የጉዳዩ አካባቢ ትክክል ማድረግ ባደረገ ጊዜ፣ አካባቢዎቹን እና ግንኙነታቸውን በመጠቀም ፍሬዎቹንም በትክክል እና በመስፋት አያጎድልም፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Mevzu modelləri gizli məsələləri belə bir məsələdə keçmək üçün genişliyinə istifadə edilmişdir. Bu kağızda, iki müxtəlif məlumatın rolünü incitmək üçün təklif edirik, məsələn belə məlumat bağlantıları və məlumat bağlantılarının rolünü. Dökümət şəbəkəsini istifadə etmək məsələlərin konseptlərin və ilişkilərin təşkil edilməsini çox yaxşılaşdırır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_id>Model topik telah digunakan secara luas untuk menemukan topik tersembunyi dalam koleksi dokumen. Dalam kertas ini, kami mengusulkan untuk menyelidiki peran dua jenis informasi relatif yang berbeda, yaitu hubungan dokumen dan hubungan konsep. Sementara mengeksploitasi jaringan dokumen meningkatkan konsistensi topik secara signifikan, penemuan konsep dan hubungan mereka tidak mempengaruhi hasil baik kuantitatif maupun kualitatif.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_bn>ডকুমেন্টের সংগ্রহে লুকিয়ে রাখা বিষয় আবিষ্কার করার জন্য ব্যাপক মডেল ব্যবহার করা হয়েছে। এই কাগজটিতে আমরা প্রস্তাব করছি যে দুটি ধরনের সম্পর্ক তথ্যের ভূমিকা তদন্ত করতে পারি, যেমন নথিপত্রের সম্পর্ক এবং ধারণা সম্পর্ক। ডকুমেন্ট নেটওয়ার্ক ব্যবহার করার সময় বিষয়বস্তুর সম্পর্কে গুরুত্বপূর্ণ উন্নতি প্রদান করে, কিন্তু ধারণা এবং তাদের সম্পর্কের প্রযুক্তি পরিমাণ এবং</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>Els models temàtics s'han utilitzat ampliament per descobrir temes ocults en una col·lecció de documents. En aquest paper, proposem investigar el paper de dos tipus diferents d'informació relacional, és a dir, relacions documentals i relacions conceptuals. Mentre que l'explotació de la xarxa de documents millora significativament la coherencia del tema, l'introducció de conceptes i les seves relacions no influeix en els resultats tant quantitativament com qualitativament.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tématické modely byly široce používány k odhalování skrytých témat ve sbírce dokumentů. V tomto článku navrhujeme zkoumat roli dvou různých typů relačních informací, tj. dokumentových vztahů a koncepčních vztahů. Zatímco využití dokumentové sítě výrazně zlepšuje soudržnost témat, zavedení konceptů a jejich vztahů nemá vliv na výsledky jak kvantitativně, tak kvalitativně.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Teemamudeleid on laialdaselt kasutatud varjatud teemade avastamiseks dokumentide kogus. Käesolevas töös teeme ettepaneku uurida kahte erinevat tüüpi relatsiooniinformatsiooni rolli, st dokumenteerida suhteid ja kontseptsioonilisi suhteid. Dokumendivõrgustiku kasutamine parandab oluliselt teemasidusust, kuid kontseptsioonide ja nende seoste kasutuselevõtt ei mõjuta tulemusi nii kvantitatiivselt kui kvalitatiivselt.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Aihemalleja on käytetty laajalti piilotettujen aiheiden löytämiseen dokumenttien kokoelmassa. Tässä työssä pyrimme selvittämään kahden erilaisen relaatioinformaation roolia, eli dokumentointisuhteita ja käsitesuhteita. Dokumenttiverkoston hyödyntäminen parantaa merkittävästi aihepiirin johdonmukaisuutta, mutta käsitteiden käyttöönotto ja niiden suhteet eivät vaikuta tuloksiin sekä määrällisesti että laadullisesti.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bs>Temski modeli su široko korišteni za otkrivanje skrivenih tema u kolekciji dokumenta. U ovom papiru predlažemo istražiti ulogu dvije različite vrste odnosanih informacija, tj. dokumentovanih odnosa i konceptnih odnosa. Iako iskorištavanje mreže dokumenta značajno poboljšava saskaņonost teme, uvođenje koncepta i njihovih odnosa ne utječe na rezultate kvantitativno i kvalitativno.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_hy>Տեմական մոդելները լայնորեն օգտագործվել են փաստաթղթերի հավաքածում թաքնված թեմաներ բացահայտելու համար: Այս թղթի մեջ մենք առաջարկում ենք ուսումնասիրել հարաբերական տեղեկատվության երկու տարբեր տեսակների դերը, այն է՝ փաստաթղթերի հարաբերությունները և գաղափարի հարաբերությունները: Մինչդեռ փաստաթղթի ցանցի օգտագործումը նշանակալիորեն բարելավում է թեմայի համապատասխանությունը, գաղափարների և դրանց հարաբերությունների ներդրումը չի ազդում արդյունքներին քանակական և որակային առումով:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_he>Topic models have been widely used to discover hidden topics in a collection of documents.  בעיתון הזה, אנחנו מציעים לחקור את התפקיד של שני סוגים שונים של מידע מערכת יחסים, כלומר מערכות יחסים ומחשבות יחסים. בעוד ניצל את רשת המסמכים משפר באופן משמעותי את התקבלות הנושאית, ההערכה של מושג ומערכותיהם לא משפיעה על התוצאות באופן כמוני ואיכותי.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Menu item to Open 'Search for Open Files' dialog Nang paper iki, kéné supoyo nggunakake karo perusahaan langgar sampeyan karo informasi sing wis dipun Awak dhéwé seneng nglanggar aturan dokumen sing beraksi luwih basa sing nyelehake tarjamahan, akeh nggawe barang nggawe barang nggawe barang dhéwé ora seneng pisan akeh dhéwé, lan basa sing apik sing paling dhéwé.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Tematski modeli so bili pogosto uporabljeni za odkrivanje skritih tem v zbirki dokumentov. V prispevku predlagamo raziskovanje vloge dveh različnih vrst relacijskih informacij, tj. dokumentiranih odnosov in konceptnih odnosov. Medtem ko izkoriščanje mreže dokumentov bistveno izboljšuje skladnost teme, uvedba konceptov in njihovih odnosov ne vpliva na rezultate tako kvantitativno kot kvalitativno.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>An yi amfani da motsalan maɓallin abun cikin mai haɗa takardun takardun. Daga wannan takardan, Munã kwaɗayin mu yi ƙidãya a cikin rolin wasu nau'i biyu masu husũma, misali, dangantaka da dangantaka na takardar. While exploiting the document network significantly improves topic coherence, the introduction of concepts and their relationships does not influence the results both quantitatively and qualitatively.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>གནད་དོན་མིག་དཔེ་བརྗོད་དོན་དག་གི་ཡིག་ཆ་སྒྲིག་པར་ཡིབ་ཡོད་པའི་གནད་དོན་རྙེད་ཐུབ་པ ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་འུ་ཅག་གིས་བློ་གཏོང་དང་འབྲེལ་བ་གཉིས་མིན་འདུག ཡིག་གེའི་དྲ་བ་ལག་སྟར་བྱེད་དུ་གནད་དོན་མཉམ་དུ་གཏན་ཚུལ་དང་མཐུན་འབྲེལ་བ་ནི་གྲངས་འབོར་དང་སྒྲིག</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>On Task-Level Dialogue Composition of Generative Transformer Model</title>
      <author><first>Prasanna</first><last>Parthasarathi</last></author>
      <author><first>Sharan</first><last>Narang</last></author>
      <author><first>Arvind</first><last>Neelakantan</last></author>
      <pages>41–47</pages>
      <abstract>Task-oriented dialogue systems help users accomplish <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a> such as booking a movie ticket and ordering food via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversation">conversation</a>. Generative models parameterized by a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep neural network</a> are widely used for next turn response generation in such systems. It is natural for users of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> to want to accomplish multiple tasks within the same conversation, but the ability of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_model">generative models</a> to compose multiple tasks is not well studied. In this work, we begin by studying the effect of training human-human task-oriented dialogues towards improving the ability to compose multiple tasks on Transformer generative models. To that end, we propose and explore two solutions : (1) creating synthetic multiple task dialogue data for training from human-human single task dialogue and (2) forcing the encoder representation to be invariant to single and multiple task dialogues using an auxiliary loss. The results from our experiments highlight the difficulty of even the sophisticated variant of transformer model in learning to compose multiple tasks from single task dialogues.</abstract>
      <url hash="ec3767f7">2020.insights-1.6</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="2a607f54">2020.insights-1.6.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.pdf</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.insights-1.6</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940793" />
      <bibkey>parthasarathi-etal-2020-task</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ppartha03/Dialogue-Compositionality-of-Generative-Transformer" additional="false">ppartha03/Dialogue-Compositionality-of-Generative-Transformer</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Label Propagation-Based Semi-Supervised Learning for Hate Speech Classification</title>
      <author><first>Ashwin Geet</first><last>D’Sa</last></author>
      <author><first>Irina</first><last>Illina</last></author>
      <author><first>Dominique</first><last>Fohr</last></author>
      <author><first>Dietrich</first><last>Klakow</last></author>
      <author><first>Dana</first><last>Ruiter</last></author>
      <pages>54–59</pages>
      <abstract>Research on hate speech classification has received increased attention. In real-life scenarios, a small amount of labeled hate speech data is available to train a reliable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a>. Semi-supervised learning takes advantage of a small amount of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labeled_data">labeled data</a> and a large amount of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labeled_data">unlabeled data</a>. In this paper, label propagation-based semi-supervised learning is explored for the task of hate speech classification. The quality of labeling the unlabeled set depends on the input representations. In this work, we show that pre-trained representations are label agnostic, and when used with label propagation yield poor results. Neural network-based fine-tuning can be adopted to learn task-specific representations using a small amount of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labeled_data">labeled data</a>. We show that fully fine-tuned representations may not always be the best representations for the label propagation and intermediate representations may perform better in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semi-supervised_learning">semi-supervised setup</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="469cea02">2020.insights-1.8</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.insights-1.8</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940795" />
      <bibkey>dsa-etal-2020-label</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Layout-Aware Text Representations Harm Clustering Documents by Type</title>
      <author><first>Catherine</first><last>Finegan-Dollak</last></author>
      <author><first>Ashish</first><last>Verma</last></author>
      <pages>60–65</pages>
      <abstract>Clustering documents by typegrouping invoices with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invoice">invoices</a> and articles with articlesis a desirable first step for organizing large collections of document scans. Humans approaching this task use both the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a> of the text and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Page_layout">document layout</a> to assist in grouping like documents. LayoutLM (Xu et al., 2019), a layout-aware transformer built on top of BERT with state-of-the-art performance on document-type classification, could reasonably be expected to outperform regular BERT (Devlin et al., 2018) for document-type clustering. However, we find experimentally that BERT significantly outperforms LayoutLM on this task (p 0.001). We analyze clusters to show where layout awareness is an asset and where it is a liability.</abstract>
      <url hash="7664a7ce">2020.insights-1.9</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.insights-1.9</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940796" />
      <bibkey>finegan-dollak-verma-2020-layout</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/rvl-cdip">RVL-CDIP</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>