<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.framenet">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the International FrameNet Workshop 2020: Towards a Global, Multilingual FrameNet</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Tiago T.</first><last>Torrent</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Collin F.</first><last>Baker</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Oliver</first><last>Czulo</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kyoko</first><last>Ohara</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Miriam R. L.</first><last>Petruck</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-58-0</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9b12a8db">2020.framenet-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>framenet-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Finding Corresponding Constructions in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese</a> in a TED Talk Parallel Corpus using Frames-and-Constructions Analysis<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish and <fixed-case>J</fixed-case>apanese in a <fixed-case>TED</fixed-case> Talk Parallel Corpus using Frames-and-Constructions Analysis</title>
      <author><first>Kyoko</first><last>Ohara</last></author>
      <pages>8–12</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports on an effort to search for corresponding constructions in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese</a> in a TED Talk parallel corpus, using frames-and-constructions analysis (Ohara, 2019 ; Ohara and Okubo, 2020 ; cf. Czulo, 2013, 2017). The purpose of the paper is two-fold : (1) to demonstrate the validity of frames-and-constructions analysis to search for corresponding constructions in typologically unrelated languages ; and (2) to assess whether the Do schools kill creativity? TED Talk parallel corpus, annotated in various languages for Multilingual FrameNet, is a good starting place for building a multilingual constructicon. The analysis showed that similar to our previous findings involving texts in a Japanese to English bilingual children’s book, the TED Talk bilingual transcripts include pairs of constructions that share similar pragmatic functions. While the TED Talk parallel corpus constitutes a good resource for frame semantic annotation in multiple languages, it may not be the ideal place to start aligning constructions among typologically unrelated languages. Finally, this work shows that the proposed method, which focuses on heads of sentences, seems valid for searching for corresponding constructions in transcripts of spoken data, as well as in written data of typologically-unrelated languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="4a76dec0">2020.framenet-1.2</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>ohara-2020-finding</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Greek within the Global FrameNet Initiative : Challenges and Conclusions so far<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>reek within the Global <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>rame<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et Initiative: Challenges and Conclusions so far</title>
      <author><first>Voula</first><last>Giouli</last></author>
      <author><first>Vera</first><last>Pilitsidou</last></author>
      <author><first>Hephaestion</first><last>Christopoulos</last></author>
      <pages>48–55</pages>
      <abstract>Large coverage lexical resources that bear deep linguistic information have always been considered useful for many natural language processing (NLP) applications including Machine Translation (MT). In this respect, Frame-based resources have been developed for many languages following Frame Semantics and the Berkeley FrameNet project. However, to a great extent, all those efforts have been kept fragmented. Consequentially, the Global FrameNet initiative has been conceived of as a joint effort to bring together <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FrameNet">FrameNets</a> in different languages. The proposed paper is aimed at describing ongoing work towards developing the Greek (EL) counterpart of the Global FrameNet and our efforts to contribute to the Shared Annotation Task. In the paper, we will elaborate on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation methodology</a> employed, the current status and progress made so far, as well as the problems raised during <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="ec031005">2020.framenet-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>giouli-etal-2020-greek</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Exploring Crosslinguistic Frame Alignment</title>
      <author><first>Collin F.</first><last>Baker</last></author>
      <author><first>Arthur</first><last>Lorenzi</last></author>
      <pages>77–84</pages>
      <abstract>The FrameNet (FN) project at the International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), which documents the core vocabulary of contemporary English, was the first lexical resource based on Fillmore’s theory of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frame_semantics_(linguistics)">Frame Semantics</a>. Berkeley FrameNet has inspired related projects in roughly a dozen other languages, which have evolved somewhat independently ; the current Multilingual FrameNet project (MLFN) is an attempt to find alignments between all of them. The alignment problem is complicated by the fact that these projects have adhered to the Berkeley FrameNet model to varying degrees, and they were also founded at different times, when different versions of the Berkeley FrameNet data were available. We describe several new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> for finding relations of similarity between semantic frames across languages. We will demonstrate ViToXF, a new tool which provides interactive visualizations of these cross-lingual relations, between frames, lexical units, and frame elements, based on resources such as multilingual dictionaries and on shared distributional vector spaces, making clear the strengths and weaknesses of different alignment methods.</abstract>
      <url hash="05813073">2020.framenet-1.11</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>baker-lorenzi-2020-exploring</bibkey>
    <title_ar>استكشاف محاذاة الإطار المتقاطعة</title_ar>
      <title_es>Exploración de la alineación interlingüística</title_es>
      <title_pt>Explorando o alinhamento de quadros linguísticos</title_pt>
      <title_fr>Exploration de l'alignement des cadres</title_fr>
      <title_ja>クロスリンギスティックフレームアライメントの探索</title_ja>
      <title_zh>探跨语框架对齐</title_zh>
      <title_ru>Изучение выравнивания перекрестных лингвистических рамок</title_ru>
      <title_hi>क्रॉसलिंग्विस्टिक फ़्रेम संरेखण की खोज</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Ailíniú Fráma Trastheangach a Iniúchadh</title_ga>
      <title_hu>Nyelvközi keretigazítás feltárása</title_hu>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Εξερεύνηση της οριζόντιας ευθυγράμμισης πλαισίου</title_el>
      <title_it>Esplorare l'allineamento interlinguistico dei quadri</title_it>
      <title_kk>Қослингвистикалық фрейм туралауын зерттеу</title_kk>
      <title_ml>ക്രോസ്ലിന്‍ഗിസ്റ്റിക്ക് ഫ്രെയിമിന്റ് സജ്ജീകരിക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Exploring Crosslinguistic Frame Alignment</title_ms>
      <title_mk>Истражување на крослингвистичка рамка</title_mk>
      <title_mn>Төрсөн хэлний фрэйм тодруулалт</title_mn>
      <title_lt>Tarptautinės kalbos sistemos suderinimo tyrimas</title_lt>
      <title_no>Utforskar kryslingvisk rammejustering</title_no>
      <title_pl>Badanie wyrównywania ramek między językami</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Explorarea alinierii cadrelor translingvistice</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Ispitivanje krstolingvističkog okvira</title_sr>
      <title_mt>L-Esplorazzjoni tal-Allinjament tal-Qafas Translingwistiku</title_mt>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>Tilmaamaha Crosslinguistic Frame Alignment</title_so>
      <title_sv>Utforska gränsöverskridande ramjustering</title_sv>
      <title_ur>کروس زبان کی فرم الیزانیٹ کی تحقیق کی جاتی ہے</title_ur>
      <title_ta>மொழிமாற்று சட்டத்தின் ஒழுங்குப்படுத்தல்</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Language</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Khám phá kết nối ngôn ngữ</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Изследване на междулингвистичното подравняване на рамките</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Ispitivanje krstolingvističkog okvira</title_hr>
      <title_da>Undersøger tværgående rammejustering</title_da>
      <title_nl>Crosslinguïstische frame uitlijning verkennen</title_nl>
      <title_id>Menjelaskan Jajaran Bingkai Crosslinguistic</title_id>
      <title_de>Untersuchung der sprachübergreifenden Rahmenausrichtung</title_de>
      <title_ko>다중 언어 프레임워크 정렬 연구</title_ko>
      <title_fa>تحقیق تنظیم چشمه‌های عبور زبان‌شناسی</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Çapraz Dilli Çagtylamak</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Kuelezea Uchambaji wa Kimataifa</title_sw>
      <title_af>Vertoon Kryslingwisiese Raam Oplyn</title_af>
      <title_sq>Shqyrtim</title_sq>
      <title_bn>ক্রোসলিঙ্গিস্টিক ফ্রেমের একত্রিত করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_az>X톛rcl톛ndirici 칂er칞ive 캻zl톛m톛si</title_az>
      <title_am>language</title_am>
      <title_bs>Ispitivanje krstolingvističkog okvira</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Prozkoumání crosslingvistického zarovnání rámců</title_cs>
      <title_et>Ristlingvistilise raami joondamise uurimine</title_et>
      <title_fi>Tutkitaan monikielistä kehystä</title_fi>
      <title_hy>Հետազոտություն</title_hy>
      <title_ca>Explorar l'allinjament translingüístic del marc</title_ca>
      <title_jv>Jejaring</title_jv>
      <title_he>מחקר התאמת המסגרת הצלבית</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Raziskovanje medjezikovne poravnave okvirjev</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Crosslinguistic Frame Alignment Exploring Crosslinguistic Frame Alignment</title_bo>
      <abstract_fr>Le projet FrameNet (FN) de l'Institut international d'informatique de Berkeley (ICSI), qui documente le vocabulaire de base de l'anglais contemporain, a été la première ressource lexicale basée sur la théorie de la sémantique des cadres de Fillmore. Berkeley FrameNet a inspiré des projets connexes dans une douzaine d'autres langues, qui ont évolué de manière quelque peu indépendante ; le projet Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) actuel tente de trouver des alignements entre eux. Le problème d'alignement est compliqué par le fait que ces projets ont adhéré au modèle Berkeley FrameNet à des degrés divers, et qu'ils ont également été créés à différentes époques, lorsque différentes versions des données Berkeley FrameNet étaient disponibles. Nous décrivons plusieurs nouvelles méthodes pour trouver des relations de similitude entre des trames sémantiques dans différents langages. Nous présenterons VitoXF, un nouvel outil qui fournit des visualisations interactives de ces relations interlinguistiques, entre des cadres, des unités lexicales et des éléments de cadre, sur la base de ressources telles que des dictionnaires multilingues et des espaces vectoriels distributionnels partagés, en mettant en évidence les forces et les faiblesses de différentes méthodes d'alignement.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>El proyecto FrameNet (FN) del Instituto Internacional de Ciencias de la Computación en Berkeley (ICSI), que documenta el vocabulario básico del inglés contemporáneo, fue el primer recurso léxico basado en la teoría de la semántica de marcos de Fillmore. Berkeley FrameNet ha inspirado proyectos relacionados en aproximadamente una docena de idiomas, que han evolucionado de forma independiente; el actual proyecto FrameNet multilingüe (MLFN) es un intento de encontrar alineamientos entre todos ellos. El problema de alineación se complica por el hecho de que estos proyectos se han adherido al modelo FrameNet de Berkeley en diversos grados, y también se fundaron en diferentes momentos, cuando estaban disponibles diferentes versiones de los datos de FrameNet de Berkeley. Describimos varios métodos nuevos para encontrar relaciones de similitud entre marcos semánticos en todos los idiomas. Demostraremos VitoXF, una nueva herramienta que proporciona visualizaciones interactivas de estas relaciones interlingüísticas, entre marcos, unidades léxicas y elementos de marco, basadas en recursos como diccionarios multilingües y en espacios vectoriales de distribución compartidos, dejando en claro los puntos fuertes y débiles de diferentes métodos de alineación.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>O projeto FrameNet (FN) do International Computer Science Institute em Berkeley (ICSI), que documenta o vocabulário central do inglês contemporâneo, foi o primeiro recurso lexical baseado na teoria da Semântica de Quadros de Fillmore. Berkeley FrameNet inspirou projetos relacionados em aproximadamente uma dúzia de outras linguagens, que evoluíram de forma um tanto independente; o atual projeto Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) é uma tentativa de encontrar alinhamentos entre todos eles. O problema de alinhamento é complicado pelo fato de que esses projetos aderiram ao modelo Berkeley FrameNet em vários graus, e também foram fundados em momentos diferentes, quando diferentes versões dos dados Berkeley FrameNet estavam disponíveis. Descrevemos vários novos métodos para encontrar relações de similaridade entre quadros semânticos entre linguagens. Demonstraremos o ViToXF, uma nova ferramenta que fornece visualizações interativas dessas relações multilíngues, entre quadros, unidades lexicais e elementos de quadro, com base em recursos como dicionários multilíngues e em espaços vetoriais de distribuição compartilhados, deixando claros os pontos fortes e fracos de diferentes métodos de alinhamento.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_zh>伯克利国际计算机科学研究所(ICSI)之FrameNet(FN)目记当世英语之核词汇,一基于Fillmore之框架语义理词汇资也。 Berkeley FrameNet启十余语,独立某种程度上。 时多语言框架阙目(MLFN)试求其对齐。 齐甚杂,以其项目循Berkeley FrameNet,而亦异时而立,时有不同本者Berkeley FrameNet数可也。 述数新法,以求跨语义框架之相似性。 将示 ViToXF,此一新器也,盖多言词典资与共布向量间,供其语言、帻、词法单元、元素之交互式可视化,以明齐法之善恶。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>बर्कले में अंतर्राष्ट्रीय कंप्यूटर विज्ञान संस्थान (आईसीएसआई) में फ्रेमनेट (एफएन) परियोजना, जो समकालीन अंग्रेजी की मूल शब्दावली का दस्तावेजीकरण करती है, फ्रेम शब्दार्थ के फिलमोर के सिद्धांत पर आधारित पहला लेक्सिकल संसाधन था। बर्कले फ्रेमनेट ने लगभग एक दर्जन अन्य भाषाओं में संबंधित परियोजनाओं को प्रेरित किया है, जो कुछ हद तक स्वतंत्र रूप से विकसित हुए हैं; वर्तमान बहुभाषी फ़्रेमनेट परियोजना (MLFN) उन सभी के बीच संरेखण खोजने का एक प्रयास है। संरेखण समस्या इस तथ्य से जटिल है कि इन परियोजनाओं ने बर्कले फ्रेमनेट मॉडल का अलग-अलग डिग्री तक पालन किया है, और वे अलग-अलग समय पर भी स्थापित किए गए थे, जब बर्कले फ्रेमनेट डेटा के विभिन्न संस्करण उपलब्ध थे। हम भाषाओं में शब्दार्थ फ्रेम के बीच समानता के संबंधों को खोजने के लिए कई नए तरीकों का वर्णन करते हैं। हम ViToXF का प्रदर्शन करेंगे, एक नया उपकरण जो इन क्रॉस-लिंगुअल संबंधों के इंटरैक्टिव विज़ुअलाइज़ेशन प्रदान करता है, फ्रेम, लेक्सिकल इकाइयों और फ्रेम तत्वों के बीच, बहुभाषी शब्दकोशों जैसे संसाधनों के आधार पर और साझा वितरण वेक्टर रिक्त स्थान पर, विभिन्न संरेखण विधियों की ताकत और कमजोरियों को स्पष्ट करता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ar>كان مشروع FrameNet (FN) في المعهد الدولي لعلوم الكمبيوتر في بيركلي (ICSI) ، والذي يوثق المفردات الأساسية للغة الإنجليزية المعاصرة ، أول مصدر معجمي قائم على نظرية فيلمور عن دلالات الإطار. لقد ألهمت Berkeley FrameNet المشاريع ذات الصلة بما يقرب من اثنتي عشرة لغة أخرى ، والتي تطورت بشكل مستقل إلى حد ما. يعد مشروع FrameNet متعدد اللغات الحالي (MLFN) محاولة للعثور على محاذاة بينها جميعًا. مشكلة المحاذاة معقدة بسبب حقيقة أن هذه المشاريع قد التزمت بنموذج Berkeley FrameNet بدرجات متفاوتة ، كما تم تأسيسها في أوقات مختلفة ، عندما توفرت إصدارات مختلفة من بيانات Berkeley FrameNet. نصف طرقًا جديدة عديدة لإيجاد علاقات التشابه بين الإطارات الدلالية عبر اللغات. سنعرض ViToXF ، وهي أداة جديدة توفر تصورات تفاعلية لهذه العلاقات عبر اللغات ، بين الإطارات والوحدات المعجمية وعناصر الإطار ، بناءً على موارد مثل القواميس متعددة اللغات وعلى مساحات ناقلات التوزيع المشتركة ، مما يوضح نقاط القوة والضعف في طرق المحاذاة المختلفة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_ja>現代英語の中核的な語彙を文書化するバークレーの国際コンピュータサイエンス研究所（ ICSI ）のFrameNet （ FN ）プロジェクトは、フィルモアのフレームセマンティクス理論に基づいた最初の語彙リソースでした。 Berkeley FrameNetは、ほぼ十数の他の言語で関連するプロジェクトにインスピレーションを与えてきました。これらの言語はある程度独立して進化しています。現在のMultilingual FrameNetプロジェクト（ MLFN ）は、それらすべての言語間のアライメントを見つける試みです。 アライメントの問題は、これらのプロジェクトがバークレーFrameNetモデルにさまざまな程度に固執しており、また、バークレーFrameNetデータのさまざまなバージョンが利用可能であった異なる時期に設立されたことにより、複雑になっています。 言語間のセマンティックフレーム間の類似関係を見つけるためのいくつかの新しい方法について説明します。 多言語辞書や共有分布ベクトル空間などのリソースに基づいて、フレーム、語彙単位、フレーム要素間のこれらのクロスリンガル関係のインタラクティブな視覚化を提供する新しいツールであるViToXFをデモンストレーションし、異なるアライメント方法の長所と短所を明確にします。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ga>Ba é an tionscadal FrameNet (FN) ag an Institiúid Idirnáisiúnta Ríomheolaíochta i Berkeley (ICSI), a dhoiciméadaíonn stór focal lárnach an Bhéarla chomhaimseartha, an chéad acmhainn foclóireachta bunaithe ar theoiric Fillmore ar Frame Semantics. Tá Berkeley FrameNet tar éis tionscadail ghaolmhara a spreagadh i thart ar dhosaen teangacha eile, atá tagtha chun cinn go neamhspleách; is iarracht é an tionscadal Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) atá ann faoi láthair chun ailíniúcháin a aimsiú eatarthu go léir. Is casta an fhadhb ailínithe toisc gur chloígh na tionscadail seo de mhéideanna éagsúla le samhail Berkeley FrameNet, agus bunaíodh iad freisin ag amanna éagsúla, nuair a bhí leaganacha éagsúla de shonraí Berkeley FrameNet ar fáil. Déanaimid cur síos ar roinnt modhanna nua chun caidreamh cosúlachta a aimsiú idir frámaí shéimeantacha trasna teangacha. Taispeánfaimid ViToXF, uirlis nua a sholáthraíonn léirshamhlú idirghníomhach ar na caidrimh thrasteangacha seo, idir frámaí, aonaid léacsacha, agus eilimintí fráma, bunaithe ar acmhainní mar fhoclóirí ilteangacha agus ar spásanna veicteoirí dáileacháin roinnte, ag soiléiriú láidreachtaí agus laigí na bhfoclóirí. modhanna ailínithe éagsúla.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ru>Проект FrameNet (FN) в Международном институте компьютерных наук в Беркли (ICSI), который документирует основной словарный запас современного английского языка, был первым лексическим ресурсом, основанным на теории семантики фреймов Филлмора. Berkeley FrameNet вдохновил смежные проекты примерно на десятке других языков, которые развивались несколько независимо; текущий проект Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) является попыткой найти выравнивания между всеми ними. Проблема выравнивания осложняется тем фактом, что эти проекты в различной степени придерживаются модели "Беркли фреймнет", и они также были основаны в разное время, когда были доступны различные версии данных "Беркли фреймнет". Описаны несколько новых методов нахождения отношений сходства между семантическими фреймами между языками. Мы продемонстрируем ViToXF, новый инструмент, который обеспечивает интерактивную визуализацию этих кросс-лингвистических отношений, между кадрами, лексическими единицами и элементами фрейма, на основе таких ресурсов, как многоязычные словари и общие дистрибутивные векторные пространства, проясняя сильные и слабые стороны различных методов выравнивания.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_el>Το έργο FrameNet (FN) στο Διεθνές Ινστιτούτο Πληροφορικής στο Μπέρκλεϊ (ICSI), το οποίο τεκμηριώνει το βασικό λεξιλόγιο των σύγχρονων Αγγλικών, ήταν ο πρώτος λεξικός πόρος βασισμένος στη θεωρία του Φίλμορ για τη Σημαντική Πλαίσιο. Το Berkeley FrameNet ενέπνευσε συναφή έργα σε περίπου δώδεκα άλλες γλώσσες, τα οποία εξελίχθηκαν κάπως ανεξάρτητα. Το τρέχον έργο Πολυγλωσσικού FrameNet (MLFN) είναι μια προσπάθεια εύρεσης ευθυγράμμισης μεταξύ όλων αυτών. Το πρόβλημα ευθυγράμμισης περιπλέκεται από το γεγονός ότι αυτά τα έργα έχουν προσκολληθεί στο μοντέλο Berkeley FrameNet σε διαφορετικό βαθμό, και επίσης ιδρύθηκαν σε διαφορετικές περιόδους, όταν ήταν διαθέσιμες διαφορετικές εκδόσεις των δεδομένων Berkeley FrameNet. Περιγράφουμε αρκετές νέες μεθόδους για την εύρεση σχέσεων ομοιότητας μεταξύ σημασιολογικών πλαισίων σε διάφορες γλώσσες. Θα παρουσιάσουμε ένα νέο εργαλείο που παρέχει διαδραστικές απεικονίσεις αυτών των διαγώνιων σχέσεων, μεταξύ πλαισίων, λεξικών μονάδων και στοιχείων πλαισίου, με βάση πόρους όπως πολυγλωσσικά λεξικά και κοινόχρηστους διανεμητικούς διανυσματικούς χώρους, καθιστώντας σαφές τα δυνατά και αδύνατα σημεία των διαφορετικών μεθόδων ευθυγράμμισης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A Berkeley-i Nemzetközi Számítástechnikai Intézet (ICSI) FrameNet (FN) projekt volt az első lexikai forrás, amely a Fillmore Frame Semantics elméletén alapul. A Berkeley FrameNet nagyjából tucat más nyelven inspirálta a kapcsolódó projekteket, amelyek kissé önállóan fejlődtek ki; A jelenlegi Multilingual FrameNet projekt (MLFN) egy kísérlet arra, hogy összehangolást találjon mindegyik között. Az igazítási problémát bonyolítja az a tény, hogy ezek a projektek különböző mértékben ragaszkodtak a Berkeley FrameNet modellhez, és különböző időpontokban alakultak meg, amikor a Berkeley FrameNet adatok különböző verziói álltak rendelkezésre. Számos új módszert ismertetünk a szemantikai keretek közötti hasonlóság kapcsolatainak megtalálására a nyelvek között. Bemutatjuk a ViToXF-et, egy új eszközt, amely interaktív megjelenítést nyújt ezekről a nyelvközi kapcsolatokról, keretek, lexikális egységek és keretelemek között, olyan erőforrásokon alapulva, mint a többnyelvű szótárak és a megosztott elosztási vektorterek, tisztázva a különböző igazítási módszerek erősségeit és gyengeségeit.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>FrameNet (FN) პროექტი ინტერნეციონალური კომპიუტერული მეცნიერების ინტერტისტი ბერკელეში (ICSI), რომელიც დოკუმენტირებულია მდგომარეობითი ანგლისური სიტყვებულაში, იყო პირველი ლექსიკა ბერკლის ტრამენეტი იქნება დაკავშირებული პროექტებით დაახლოებით სხვა ენებით, რომლებიც განვითარებულია რამდენიმე განსხვავებული პროექტებით; მიმდინარე მრავალენგური FrameNet პროექტი (MLFN) არის ყველას შორის წყვეტილების ძებნა. პრობლემა განსხვავებული გრადუსებისთვის, როდესაც Berkeley FrameNet მოდელის განსხვავებული გრადუსებისთვის განსხვავებული გრადუსების განსხვავებული გრადუსების განსხვავებული გრადუსები იყო. ჩვენ განახსოვრებთ რამდენიმე ახალი მეტოვები სიმენტიკური ფრამების განმავლობაში სიმენტიკური ფრამების განმავლობაში. ჩვენ ViToXF, ახალი საქაღალდე, რომელიც ინტერექტურად ვიზუალებს ამ მრავალური შესახებების შესახებ, ფრამების, ლექსიკალური ერთეულების და ფრამების ელემენტების შორის, რომელიც მრავალენგური სიკუქტორიები და გაყოფილი განსაზღვრული გვექტორის სი</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Il progetto FrameNet (FN) presso l'Istituto Internazionale di Informatica di Berkeley (ICSI), che documenta il vocabolario di base dell'inglese contemporaneo, è stata la prima risorsa lessicale basata sulla teoria della Semantica Frame di Fillmore. Berkeley FrameNet ha ispirato progetti correlati in circa una dozzina di altre lingue, che si sono evolute in modo indipendente; L'attuale progetto Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) è un tentativo di trovare degli allineamenti tra tutti. Il problema dell'allineamento è complicato dal fatto che questi progetti hanno aderito al modello Berkeley FrameNet in vari gradi, e sono stati anche fondati in tempi diversi, quando erano disponibili diverse versioni dei dati Berkeley FrameNet. Descriviamo diversi nuovi metodi per trovare relazioni di somiglianza tra cornici semantiche attraverso le lingue. Mostreremo ViToXF, un nuovo strumento che fornisce visualizzazioni interattive di queste relazioni cross-lingual, tra frame, unità lessicali ed elementi frame, basate su risorse come dizionari multilingue e su spazi vettoriali distributivi condivisi, evidenziando i punti di forza e di debolezza dei diversi metodi di allineamento.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Беркли (ICSI) Халықаралық Компьютерлік ғылым институтындағы FrameNet (FN) жобасы, қазіргі ағылшын тілінің негізгі сөздерін құжаттау үшін Fillmore фрейм семантикалық теориясынан негізделген алғашқы лексикалық ресур Беркли Фреймнетті бірнеше тілдерге сәйкес жұмыс жобаларды түсіндіреді, олар бірнеше тәуелсіздік өзгертілген. Қолданыстағы Мультингілік FrameNet жобасы (MLFN) барлығының арасындағы тәртібін табу әрекеті. Бұл жобалар Berkeley FrameNet моделіне түрлі градус түрлі түрлі деңгейіне қатысты, сондай-ақ олар Баркли FrameNet деректерінің әртүрлі нұсқаларының түрлі уақытта құрылған. Біз бірнеше жаңа әдістерді тілдер арасындағы семантикалық фреймдер қатынасын табу үшін таңдаймыз. Біз ViToXF дегенді көрсетейміз, бұл көптілік қатынастарды интерактивті визуализациялау құралы, фреймдер, лексикалық бірліктер мен фрейм элементтерінің арасында, көптілік сөздік сөздіктеріне негізделген ресурстар мен бөлек тарату векторлық бос орындарына негіздел</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Projek FrameNet (FN) di Institut Sains Komputer antarabangsa di Berkeley (ICSI), yang dokumen vokbulari utama Inggeris kontemporari, adalah sumber leksikal pertama berdasarkan teori Semantik Bingkai Fillmore. Berkeley FrameNet telah menginspirasikan projek berkaitan dalam sekitar lusin bahasa lain, yang telah berkembang secara independen; projek FrameNet berbilang bahasa semasa (MLFN) adalah cubaan untuk mencari penyesuaian diantara mereka semua. Masalah penyesuaian adalah rumit dengan fakta bahawa projek-projek ini telah mematuhi model Berkeley FrameNet untuk darjah berbeza, dan mereka juga didirikan pada masa yang berbeza, apabila versi berbeza bagi data Berkeley FrameNet tersedia. Kami menggambarkan beberapa kaedah baru untuk mencari hubungan persamaan antara bingkai semantik melalui bahasa. Kami akan menunjukkan ViToXF, alat baru yang menyediakan visualisasi interaktif hubungan saling bahasa ini, antara bingkai, unit leksikal, dan unsur bingkai, berdasarkan sumber seperti kamus berbilang bahasa dan ruang vektor berkongsi, menjadikan jelas kekuatan dan kelemahan kaedah penyesuaian yang berbeza.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>The FrameNet (FN) project at the International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), which documents the core vocabulary of contemporary English, was the first lexical resource based on Fillmore's theory of Frame Semantics.  Berkeley FrameNet инспирираше поврзани проекти на околу десетина други јазици, кои еволуираа некако независно; актуелниот Мултијазичен проект FrameNet (MLFN) е обид да се пронајдат уреди меѓу сите нив. Проблемот со прилагодувањето е комплициран од фактот дека овие проекти се придржуваат на моделот Berkeley FrameNet во различни степени, а тие, исто така, беа основани во различни времиња, кога беа достапни различни верзии на податоците Berkeley FrameNet. Опишуваме неколку нови методи за пронаоѓање на односи на сличност помеѓу семантичните рамки преку јазици. Ќе демонстрираме ViToXF, нова алатка која обезбедува интерактивни визуализации на овие меѓујазични односи, меѓу рамките, лексичките единици и рамките елементи, базирани на ресурси како што се мултијазичните речници и на заедничките дистрибутивни векторни простори, јаснувајќи ги силните и слабостите на различн</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>The FrameNet (FN) project at the International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), which documents the core vocabulary of contemporary English, was the first lexical resource based on Fillmore's theory of Frame Semantics.  Berkeley FrameNet has inspired related projects in roughly a dozen other languages, which have evolved somewhat independently;  dabartinis daugiakalbis FrameNet projektas (MLFN) yra bandymas rasti suderinimus tarp visų jų. Suderinimo problema sudėtinga dėl to, kad šie projektai įvairiais laipsniais laikėsi Berkeley FrameNet modelio, ir jie taip pat buvo pagrįsti skirtingais laikais, kai buvo prieinamos skirtingos Berkeley FrameNet duomenų versijos. We describe several new methods for finding relations of similarity between semantic frames across languages.  Mes parodysime ViToXF, naują priemonę, kuri teikia interaktyvią šių tarpkalbinių santykių vizualizaciją tarp rėmų, leksinių vienetų ir rėmų elementų, grindžiamą ištekliais, pavyzdžiui, daugiakalbiais žodynais ir bendrais paskirstymo vektorių skyriais, aiškiai nurodydami įvairių derinimo metodų stiprumus ir trūkumus.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ml>ബെര്‍ക്കെലിയിലെ ആന്തരാഷ്ട്ര കമ്പ്യൂട്ടര്‍ ശാസ്ത്ര ഇന്റിസ്റ്റിറ്റിയിലെ ഫ്രെമെന്‍റ് (FN) പ്രോജക്റ്റ് ഫില്‍മോര്‍ട്ടിന്‍റെ ഫ്രെയിം സെമാന്‍ടിക്സിന്‍റെ തിയറ Berkeley FrameNet has inspired related projects in roughly a dozen other languages, which have evolved somewhat independently;  ഇപ്പോഴത്തെ പല ഭാഷാ ഫ്രെമിനെറ്റ് പ്രോജക്റ്റ് (MLFN) എല്ലാവര്‍ക്കും ഇടയിലുള്ള സങ്കീര്‍ണ്ണങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടെത്താന്‍  ബെര്‍ക്കെലി ഫ്രെമെന്റ് മോഡലിനെ വ്യത്യസ്തമാക്കാന്‍ ഈ പ്രോജക്ടുകള്‍ ബെര്‍ക്കെലി ഫ്രെമെന്റ് മോഡലിലേക്ക് ചേര്‍ന്നിരിക്കുന്നു എന്നും വ്യത്യസ്ത സെമാന്റിക് ഫ്രെയിമുകള്‍ക്കിടയില്‍ ഒരുപോലുള്ള ബന്ധങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടെത്താന്‍ വേണ്ടി പല പുതിയ രീതികളെയും ഞങ്ങള വിടോഎക്സ്എഫിനെ ഞങ്ങള്‍ പുതിയ ഉപകരണത്തെ കാണിച്ചുകൊടുക്കും. ഈ ക്രിസ്ലിങ്കുകളുടെ ബന്ധങ്ങള്‍ക്കിടയില്‍, ഫ്രെയിമ്മില്‍, ലെക്സിക്കല്‍ യൂണിറ്റുകള്‍, ഫ്രെയിമിനുകള്‍</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-proġett FrameNet (FN) fl-Istitut Internazzjonali tax-Xjenza tal-Kompjuter f’Berkeley (ICSI), li jiddokumenta l-vokabulari ewlieni tal-Ingliż kontemporanju, kien l-ewwel riżorsa lexika bbażata fuq it-teorija ta’ Fillmore dwar is-Semanti tal-Qafas. Berkeley FrameNet ispirat proġetti relatati f’madwar tnax-il lingwa oħra, li żviluppaw xi ftit b’mod indipendenti; il-proġett Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) attwali huwa tentattiv biex jinstabu allinjamenti bejniethom kollha. Il-problema tal-allinjament hija kkumplikata mill-fatt li dawn il-proġetti aderew għall-mudell tal-Berkeley FrameNet sa gradi differenti, u kienu wkoll fondati fi żminijiet differenti, meta kienu disponibbli verżjonijiet differenti tad-dejta tal-Berkeley FrameNet. Aħna niddeskrivu diversi metodi ġodda biex jinstabu relazzjonijiet ta’ similarità bejn oqfsa semantiċi bejn il-lingwi. Ser nippruvaw ViToXF, għodda ġdida li tipprovdi viżwalizzazzjonijiet interattivi ta' dawn ir-relazzjonijiet interlingwi, bejn oqfsa, unitajiet lexiċi, u elementi ta' oqfsa, ibbażati fuq riżorsi bħad-dikjararji multilingwi u fuq spazji ta' distribuzzjoni kondiviżi ta' vetturi, li jiċċaraw il-qawwiet u d-dgħufijiet ta' metodi ta' allinjament differenti.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Бэркли (ICSI) дэх Олон улсын Компьютерийн Шинжлэх ухааны Институтын FrameNet (FN) төсөл, орчин үеийн Англи хэлний үндсэн үг бичсэн бөгөөд Fillmore-ын Фрейм Semantics онолын үндсэн анхны лексикийн баялаг байсан. Беркли Фреймнет холбоотой төслүүдийг ойролцоогоор хэдэн хэл дээр урам зориулсан. Тэдгээр нь тусгаарлагдмал хөгжүүлсэн. одоогийн олон хэлний FrameNet төсөл (MLFN) нь тэдний бүх хүмүүсийн хоорондоо тохиромжтой байдлыг олох хичээл юм. Эдгээр төслүүд Berkeley FrameNet загвар дээр өөр хэмжээтэй холбогдсон. Баркли FrameNet өгөгдлийн өөр өөр хувилбаруудыг олон удаа бүтээсэн. Бид хэл дээр ижил хэмжээний фрэймүүдийн хоорондох холбоотой холбоотой шинэ арга замыг тайлбарлаж байна. Бид ViToXF-г харуулах хэрэгсэл болно. Энэ нь олон хэлний үгүйлтийн үгүйлтийн, хуваарилах вектор орон нутгийнхаа хамаарал, фрэйм, лексик нэгж болон фрэйм элементүүдийн хоорондын интерактив үзүүлэлтийг гаргадаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Projektet FrameNet (FN) på internasjonal datavitenskap- institusjonen i Berkeley (ICSI), som dokumenterer kjerneordboka til samtidige engelsk, var den første leksiske ressursen basert på fylmore- teorien om rammesemantikk. Berkeley FrameNet har inspirert relaterte prosjekt i omtrent tusen andre språk, som har utvikla litt uavhengig. Det gjeldande Multilingual FrameNet- prosjektet (MLFN) er eit forsøk å finna justeringar mellom alle dei. Problemet med justeringa er komplisert av det faktum at desse prosjektene har vedført til Berkeley FrameNet-modellen til ulike gradar, og dei var også basert på ulike tidar, når ulike versjonar av Berkeley FrameNet-data vart tilgjengelege. Vi beskriver fleire nye metodar for å finna forholdet mellom semantiske rammer på språk. Vi vil demonstrere ViToXF, eit nytt verktøy som tilbyr interaktive visualiseringar av desse krysspråksrelasjonane, mellom ramma, leksiske einingar og rammeelementa, basert på ressursar som fleirspråksbokstavar og delte distribusjonsvektormellomrom, som gjer klar styrkene og tyrke av ulike justeringsmetodar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Proiectul FrameNet (FN) de la Institutul Internațional de Informatică din Berkeley (ICSI), care documentează vocabularul de bază al limbii engleze contemporane, a fost prima resursă lexicală bazată pe teoria Semanticei Frame a lui Fillmore. Berkeley FrameNet a inspirat proiecte conexe în aproximativ o duzină de alte limbi, care au evoluat oarecum independent; Actualul proiect Multilingval FrameNet (MLFN) este o încercare de a găsi alinieri între toate acestea. Problema alinierii este complicată de faptul că aceste proiecte au aderat la modelul Berkeley FrameNet în grade diferite și au fost, de asemenea, fondate în momente diferite, atunci când diferite versiuni ale datelor Berkeley FrameNet au fost disponibile. Descriem mai multe metode noi de găsire a relațiilor de similitudine între cadrele semantice între limbi. Vom demonstra ViToXF, un nou instrument care oferă vizualizări interactive ale acestor relații interlingve, între cadre, unități lexicale și elemente de cadru, bazate pe resurse precum dicționare multilingve și spații vectoriale distribuționale partajate, clarificând punctele forte și punctele slabe ale diferitelor metode de aliniere.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>Projekt FrameNet (FN) w Międzynarodowym Instytucie Informatyki w Berkeley (ICSI), dokumentujący podstawowe słownictwo współczesnego języka angielskiego, był pierwszym zasobem leksykalnym opartym na teorii Semantyki ramowej Fillmore'a. Berkeley FrameNet zainspirował powiązane projekty w około kilkunastu innych językach, które ewoluowały nieco niezależnie; Obecny projekt Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) jest próbą znalezienia dopasowań między nimi wszystkimi. Problem wyrównania komplikuje fakt, że projekty te w różnym stopniu przylegały do modelu Berkeley FrameNet, a także powstały w różnych czasach, kiedy dostępne były różne wersje danych Berkeley FrameNet. Opisujemy kilka nowych metod wyszukiwania relacji podobieństwa pomiędzy ramkami semantycznymi w różnych językach. Przedstawimy ViToXF, nowe narzędzie, które zapewnia interaktywne wizualizacje tych relacji między klatkami, jednostkami leksykalnymi i elementami ramki, w oparciu o zasoby takie jak wielojęzyczne słowniki i wspólne przestrzenie wektorowe dystrybucyjne, wyjaśniając mocne i słabe strony różnych metod wyrównywania.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sv>FrameNet (FN) projektet vid International Computer Science Institute i Berkeley (ICSI), som dokumenterar kärnan av samtida engelska, var den första lexikala resursen baserad på Fillmore teori om ramsemantik. Berkeley FrameNet har inspirerat relaterade projekt på ungefär ett dussin andra språk, som utvecklats något självständigt; Det nuvarande flerspråkiga FrameNet-projektet (MLFN) är ett försök att hitta anpassningar mellan dem alla. Justeringsproblemet kompliceras av det faktum att dessa projekt har följt Berkeley FrameNet-modellen i varierande grad, och de grundades också vid olika tidpunkter, när olika versioner av Berkeley FrameNet-data fanns tillgängliga. Vi beskriver flera nya metoder för att hitta likhetsrelationer mellan semantiska ramar över språk. Vi kommer att demonstrera ViToXF, ett nytt verktyg som ger interaktiva visualiseringar av dessa tvärspråkliga relationer, mellan ramar, lexikala enheter och ramelement, baserat på resurser som flerspråkiga ordböcker och delade distributionsvektorutrymmen, vilket klargör styrkorna och svagheterna hos olika justeringsmetoder.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>බෙර්ක්ලී (ICSI) වල ජාතික පරිගණක විද්‍යාප්‍රේෂණ සංස්ථානයේ ෆ්‍රේම්නෙට් (FN) ප්‍රෝජේක්ටර් විද්‍යාප්‍රේෂණ සංස්ථානයේ ප්‍රධා බෙර්ක්ලී ෆ්‍රේම්නෙට් එක්ක සම්බන්ධ ව්‍යාපෘතියක් අනිත් භාෂාවක් දහයක් තියෙනවා, ඒ වගේම මොකක් ස ප්‍රස්තූත විශේෂ භාෂාවික ෆ්‍රේම්නෙට් ව්‍යාපෘතිය (MLFN) තමයි ඔවුන්ගේ හැමෝම අතර සම්බන්ධතා මේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය බෙර්ක්ලි ෆ්‍රේම්නෙට් මොඩේල් එක්ක වෙනස් විදියට සම්බන්ධ වෙලා තියෙන ප්‍රශ්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් සංස්ථාපනය කරලා තියෙනව අපි අළුත් විදිහාවක් විස්තර කරනවා භාෂාවක් වලින් සිමාන්තික ප්‍රමාණය හොයාගන්න. අපි ViToXF පෙන්වන්නම්, අළුත් උපකරණයක් දෙන්නේ මේ ක්‍රීස් භාෂාවක් සම්බන්ධතාවක් සම්බන්ධතාවක් සඳහා ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට, ප්‍රති</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sr>Projekt FrameNet (FN) u Međunarodnom kompjuterskom naučnom institutu u Berkeleyu (ICSI), koji dokumentuje temeljni rečenik contemporarnog engleskog jezika, bio je prvi leksički resurs baziran na Fillmorovoj teoriji okvirnog semantika. Berkeley FrameNet je inspirisao povezane projekte na otprilike desetak drugih jezika, koji su se malo razvili nezavisno; trenutni Multilingual FrameNet projekat (MLFN) je pokušaj pronaći poravnanje između svih njih. Problem usklađenja je komplikovan činjenicom da su ovi projekti pridržali model Berkeley FrameNet na različitim stupnjevima, a oni su takođe osnovani u različitim vremenima, kada su dostupne različite verzije podataka Berkeley FrameNet-a. Opišemo nekoliko novih metoda za pronalaženje odnosa sličnosti između semantičkih okvira na jezicima. Pokazaæemo ViToXF, novi alat koji pruža interaktivne vizualizacije ovih međujezičkih odnosa, između ramova, leksičkih jedinica i okvirnih elementa, na osnovu resursa poput multijezičkih diktorija i na zajedničkih distribucijskih vektorskih prostora, èistimo snage i slabosti različitih metoda usklađenja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>பெர்கெலியில் உள்ள International Computer Science Institute (ICSI) திட்டத்தில் உள்ள சட்டத்தின் (FN) திட்டம், அது தற்போதைய ஆங்கிலத்தின் மூல சொல்வளத்தை ஆவணப்படுத்துகிறது, அது ஃபில்மோரின் சட்டத்தின பெர்கெலி ஃப்ரெம்நெட்ட் தொடர்புடைய திட்டங்களை வழக்கமாக பத்தான மற்ற பல மொழிகளில் inspire inspired, அது சில தனிப்பட்டதாக வளர்ந்து தற்போதைய பல்மொழி சட்டத்தின் வலை திட்டத்தை (MLFN) எல்லாவற்றுக்கும் இடையே ஒழுங்குப்படுத்த முயற்சிக்கிறது. ஒழுங்குபடுத்தல் பிரச்சினையால் சிக்கலாகும் இந்த திட்டங்கள் பெர்கெலி சட்டத்தின் மாதிரியில் சேர்ந்துள்ளார்கள் மற்றும் வேறு நேரங்களில் அவை நிறுவ நாம் பல புதிய முறைகளை விவரிக்கிறோம் மொழிகளில் இருந்து பாதிப்பு சட்டங்களுக்கு இடையே உள்ள தொடர்புகளை கண் நாம் விடோக்ஸ்எக்ஸ் புதிய கருவியை காட்டுவோம். இது பல மொழி அகராதிகள் மற்றும் பங்கீட்டு வெக்டார் இடைவெளியில் உள்ள செயல்பாட்டுகளை காண்பிக்கும் சட்டங்கள், லெக்சிக்சியல் அலகுகள் மற்றும் ச</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_so>The FrameNet (FN) project at the International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), which documents the core vocabulary of contemporary English, was the first lexical resource based on Fillmore's theory of Frame Semantics.  Berkeley FrameNet wuxuu ku waxyooday waxyaabo la xiriira oo ku qoran qiyaastii toban luuqadood oo kale, kuwaas oo si xor ah u horumariyey; shabakadda FrameNet ee hada ah (MLFN) waa isku dayo in uu helo isbedelyo u dhexeeya dhammaantood. Dhibaatada isbedelka waxaa la adag yahay in dhaqdhaqaaqyadaasu ay ku leeyihiin muusikada Berkeley FrameNet si ay u kala duwan yihiin shahaado, waana la aasaasay waqtiyada kala duduwan, marka laga helay warqado kala duduwan oo ku qoran taariikhda Berkeley FrameNet. Waxaannu qoraynaa qaabab cusub si aan u helno xiriir isku mid ah oo kala duwan luqadaha oo dhan. Waxaan muujinnaa ViToXF oo ah qalabka cusub, kaas oo fidiya muuqashada xiriirka luuqadaha kala duduwan, qashinka, qaybaha leksikada iyo qashinka, taasoo ku saleysan rasmiga, tusaale ahaan kaliyooyinka luuqadaha kala duduwan iyo goobaha qeybaha kala duduwan, si loo caddayn karo xoogga iyo itaaldarrada qaababka isbedelka kala duduwan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ur>برکلی (ICSI) میں بین المللی کمپیوٹر سائنس انٹیسٹ (FN) کی پروژہ، جس نے مدینہ انگلیسی کی اصلی آواز سنائی تھی، فیلمور کی نظریہ فیلمورک سیمانٹیکس کی اولین لکسیکل سراسر تھا. برکلی فرمینٹ نے تقریباً ایک دوسری زبانوں میں رابطہ دار پروژیکوں کو الهام دی ہے، جو تھوڑی سی طرح تغییر کی گئی ہیں۔ موجود Multilingual FrameNet Project (MLFN) یہ ایک کوشش ہے کہ ان سب کے درمیان برابری تلاش کریں۔ ان پروژیکوں نے برکلی فرمینٹ موڈل کو متفاوت درجے کے لئے پیدا کیا ہے، اور وہ بھی مختلف زمانوں میں بنائے گئے ہیں، جب برکلی فرمینٹ ڈیٹ کے مختلف نسخے موجود تھے. ہم بہت سی نو طریقے بیان کرتے ہیں کہ زبانوں میں سیمنٹی فرموں کے درمیان برابری کا ارتباط تلاش کریں۔ ہم ViToXF کو دکھائیں گے، ایک نئی ابزار جو ان کرس زبان رابطہ کی interactive visualizations دیتا ہے، فرموں، لکسیکل یونیٹوں اور فرموں کے درمیان، متعدد زبان کی لکھائی باتوں پر بنیاد رکھتا ہے، جیسے متعدد زبان کی لکھائی اور مشترک تقسیم ویکتور جگہ پر، مختلف تضامین طریقوں کی قوت اور ضعیفیں مف</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>The khungNet (FN) project at the International Máy tính Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), which documents the core language of modern English, was the first lexical resort based on Fillmore's theory of khuon Semantics. Berkeley FrangNet đã tạo ra các dự án liên quan tại khoảng chục ngôn ngữ khác mà đã phát triển một cách độc lập; Sự hợp nhất của giải đố đa ngôn ngữ (MLFN) là một nỗ lực tìm sự liên minh giữa họ. Sự thẳng hàng của các dự án này rất phức tạp vì những dự án này đã liên kết với mô hình của Berkeley khungNet, và cũng được tạo ra ở những thời điểm khác nhau, khi có nhiều phiên bản khác nhau trong dữ liệu về Berkeley khungNet. Chúng tôi mô tả vài phương pháp mới để tìm ra mối quan hệ giống nhau giữa các khung ngữ pháp. Chúng tôi sẽ chứng minh ViToXF, một công cụ mới cung cấp hình ảnh tương tác của các mối quan hệ ngôn ngữ khác nhau, giữa các khung hình, các đơn vị ngôn ngữ, và các nguyên tố khung, dựa trên các nguồn lực như các từ điển đa dạng và các khoảng phân phối rộng rãi, làm rõ điểm mạnh và yếu của các phương pháp phối hợp khác nhau.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Name Berkeley FrameNet taʼminlovchi projektlarni bir necha necha tillar bilan imkoniyat qiladi. Bu bir necha necha tillardan bir necha xil tilda o'zgartiradi. Joriy bir nechta til freymNet loyihasi (MLFN) hamma narsalarning orasidagi tenglashni topish jarayon. Tekislashtirish muammosi shu loyihalar Berkeley FrameNet modeliga o'zgartirilgan darajaga murakkab, va ular boshqa paytlarda qo'llangan, bir xil paytida Berkeley FrameNet maʼlumotining boshqa versiyalari mavjud boʻlganda. Biz har bir necha yangi usullarni o'ylaymiz, har bir tillar orasidagi semantik freymlar orasidagi bir xil usullarni topish uchun. Biz ViToXF, har bir xil lugʻatlarga va bir necha lugʻatlarga qayta boʻlgan vektorlar joyidagi rasmlarni ko'rsatadigan yangi asboblarni ko'rsatamiz va har hil tillar huquqlarining orasidagi interaktiv munosabatlarni ko'rsatadigan asboblarni ko'rsatamiz, har xil tarkiblar orasidagi rasmlar, leksikal bir tarkibi elementlar orasidagi rasmlarning asosida ko'rsa</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Проектът към Международния институт по компютърни науки в Бъркли (ICSI), който документира основния речник на съвременния английски език, е първият лексикален ресурс, основан на теорията на Филмор за семантиката на рамката. Бъркли FrameNet е вдъхновил свързани проекти на около дузина други езици, които са еволюирали донякъде самостоятелно; Настоящият многоезичен проект е опит да се намерят подравнения между всички тях. Проблемът с подравняването се усложнява от факта, че тези проекти са се придържали към модела на Berkeley FrameNet в различна степен и те също са били основани в различни времена, когато различни версии на данните на Berkeley FrameNet са били налични. Описваме няколко нови метода за намиране на връзки на сходство между семантични рамки в различните езици. Ще демонстрираме нов инструмент, който предоставя интерактивни визуализации на тези междуезични отношения, между рамки, лексикални единици и елементи на рамката, въз основа на ресурси като многоезични речници и споделени разпределителни векторни пространства, като изясни силните и слабите страни на различните методи за подравняване.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Projekt FrameNet (FN) u Međunarodnom institutu računalne nauke u Berkeleyu (ICSI), koji dokumentira temeljni riječ contemporarnog engleskog jezika, bio je prvi leksički resurs na temelju Fillmorove teorije okvirne semantike. Berkeley FrameNet je inspirisao povezane projekte na otprilike desetak drugih jezika, koji su se malo razvili nezavisno; trenutni Multilingual FrameNet projekt (MLFN) je pokušaj pronaći poravnanje između svih njih. Problem s usklađenjem je kompliciran činjenicom da su ovi projekti pridržali model Berkeley FrameNet na različitim stupnjevima, te su također osnovani u različitim vremenima, kada su dostupne različite verzije podataka Berkeley FrameNet-a. Opisujemo nekoliko novih metoda za pronalaženje odnosa sličnosti između semantičkih okvira na jezicima. Pokazat ćemo ViToXF, novi alat koji pruža interaktivne vizualizacije ovih međujezičkih odnosa, između okvira, leksičkih jedinica i okvirnih elementa, temeljenog na resursima poput multijezičkih diktorija i na zajedničkih distribucijskih vektorskih prostora, čišćenje snage i slabosti različitih metoda prilagodbe.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>FrameNet (FN) projektet ved International Computer Science Institute i Berkeley (ICSI), som dokumenterer kernefordforrådet i nutidens engelsk, var den første leksikalske ressource baseret på Fillmore teori om rammesemantik. Berkeley FrameNet har inspireret relaterede projekter på omkring et dusin andre sprog, som har udviklet sig noget uafhængigt; Det nuværende Multilingual FrameNet projekt (MLFN) er et forsøg på at finde justeringer mellem dem alle. Tilpasningsproblemet kompliceres af, at disse projekter i varierende grad har overholdt Berkeley FrameNet-modellen, og at de også blev grundlagt på forskellige tidspunkter, hvor forskellige versioner af Berkeley FrameNet-data var tilgængelige. Vi beskriver flere nye metoder til at finde lighedsrelationer mellem semantiske rammer på tværs af sprog. Vi vil demonstrere ViToXF, et nyt værktøj, der giver interaktive visualiseringer af disse tværsprogede relationer, mellem rammer, leksikalske enheder og rammeelementer, baseret på ressourcer som flersprogede ordbøger og på delte distributionsmæssige vektorrum, hvilket tydeliggør styrkerne og svaghederne ved forskellige justeringsmetoder.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Het FrameNet (FN) project van het International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), dat de kernwoordenschat van het hedendaagse Engels documenteert, was de eerste lexicale bron gebaseerd op Fillmore's theorie van Frame Semantics. Berkeley FrameNet heeft gerelateerde projecten geïnspireerd in ongeveer een dozijn andere talen, die enigszins onafhankelijk zijn geëvolueerd; Het huidige Multilingual FrameNet project (MLFN) is een poging om onderlinge afstemming te vinden. Het uitlijningsprobleem wordt gecompliceerd door het feit dat deze projecten zich in verschillende mate hebben gehouden aan het Berkeley FrameNet model, en ze zijn ook opgericht op verschillende momenten, toen verschillende versies van de Berkeley FrameNet data beschikbaar waren. We beschrijven verschillende nieuwe methoden voor het vinden van overeenkomsten tussen semantische frames in verschillende talen. We zullen ViToXF demonstreren, een nieuwe tool die interactieve visualisaties biedt van deze cross-lingual relaties, tussen frames, lexicale eenheden en framelementen, gebaseerd op bronnen zoals meertalige woordenboeken en gedeelde distributionele vectorruimten, om de sterke en zwakke punten van verschillende uitlijningsmethoden duidelijk te maken.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Das FrameNet (FN) Projekt am International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), das das Kernvokabular des zeitgenössischen Englischen dokumentiert, war die erste lexikalische Ressource basierend auf Fillmores Theorie der Frame Semantics. Berkeley FrameNet hat verwandte Projekte in etwa einem Dutzend anderen Sprachen inspiriert, die sich etwas unabhängig voneinander entwickelt haben; Das aktuelle Multilingual FrameNet Projekt (MLFN) ist ein Versuch, Alignments zwischen allen zu finden. Das Ausrichtungsproblem wird dadurch erschwert, dass diese Projekte sich in unterschiedlichem Maße an das Berkeley FrameNet-Modell halten und auch zu unterschiedlichen Zeiten gegründet wurden, als verschiedene Versionen der Berkeley FrameNet-Daten verfügbar waren. Wir beschreiben mehrere neue Methoden, um Ähnlichkeitsbeziehungen zwischen semantischen Frames über Sprachen hinweg zu finden. Wir werden ViToXF demonstrieren, ein neues Tool, das interaktive Visualisierungen dieser sprachübergreifenden Beziehungen zwischen Frames, lexikalischen Einheiten und Frame-Elementen bietet, basierend auf Ressourcen wie mehrsprachigen Wörterbüchern und gemeinsamen Verteilungsvektorräumen, um die Stärken und Schwächen verschiedener Ausrichtungsmethoden deutlich zu machen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Proyek FrameNet (FN) di Institut Internasional Ilmu Komputer di Berkeley (ICSI), yang mendokumentasikan vokabular utama Inggris kontempor, adalah sumber daya leksik pertama berdasarkan teori Fillmore tentang Frame Semantics. Berkeley FrameNet telah menginspirasi proyek terkait dalam sekitar lusin bahasa lain, yang telah berevolusi secara independen; proyek FrameNet berbilang bahasa (MLFN) saat ini adalah percobaan untuk menemukan penyesuaian antara mereka semua. Masalah penyesuaian adalah rumit dengan fakta bahwa proyek-proyek ini telah mematuhi model Berkeley FrameNet untuk berbagai derajat, dan mereka juga didirikan pada waktu yang berbeda, ketika versi berbeda dari data Berkeley FrameNet tersedia. Kami menggambarkan beberapa metode baru untuk menemukan hubungan yang sama antara bingkai semantis melalui bahasa. We will demonstrate ViToXF, a new tool which provides interactive visualizations of these cross-lingual relations, between frames, lexical units, and frame elements, based on resources such as multilingual dictionaries and on shared distributional vector spaces, making clear the strengths and weaknesses of different alignment methods.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>버클리 국제컴퓨터과학연구소(ICSI)의 프레임넷(FN) 프로젝트는 현대 영어의 핵심 어휘를 기록해 필모 프레임워크 어의학 이론을 바탕으로 한 최초의 어휘 자원이다.버클리 프레임워크 네트워크(Berkeley FrameNet)는 약 10여 가지 다른 언어에서 관련 프로젝트를 계발했는데 이런 언어는 어느 정도에 독립적으로 발전했다.현재 MLFN(Multi-Language Fracture Network) 항목은 모든 프레임망 사이에 정렬점을 찾으려고 합니다.이 항목들은 어느 정도에 버클리 프레임워크 네트워크 모델을 따랐고 그것들도 서로 다른 시간에 만들어졌다. 당시 버클리 프레임워크 네트워크 데이터의 버전이 다르기 때문에 정렬 문제가 복잡해졌다.우리는 다중 언어의 의미 구조 간의 비슷한 관계를 찾는 몇 가지 새로운 방법을 묘사했다.ViToXF를 보여 드리겠습니다. 이것은 다중 언어 사전과 공유 분포 벡터 공간 등 자원을 바탕으로 프레임워크, 어휘 단원과 프레임워크 요소 간의 이러한 크로스 언어 관계의 상호작용을 가시화하고 서로 다른 정렬 방법의 장단점을 명확히 하는 새로운 도구입니다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Mradi wa FrameNet (FN) katika Taasisi ya Sayansi ya Kimataifa ya Kompyuta huko Berkeley (ICSI), ambayo inaweka kumbukumbu muhimu ya lugha ya Kiingereza ya sasa, ulikuwa rasilimali ya kwanza za za lexico kwa msingi wa nadharia ya Fillmore ya Mfumo wa Semantics. Berkeley FrameNet amewahamasisha miradi yanayohusiana kwa takriban lugha kumi nyingine, ambazo zimeendelea kidogo huru; Mradi wa Mtandao wa Kilugha wa sasa (MLFN) ni jaribio la kutafuta usawa kati ya wote. The alignment problem is complicated by the fact that these projects have adhered to the Berkeley FrameNet model to varying degrees, and they were also founded at different times, when different versions of the Berkeley FrameNet data were available.  Tunaelezea njia kadhaa mpya za kutafuta mahusiano yanayofanana kati ya mifumo ya sekunde katika lugha mbalimbali. Tutaonyesha ViToXF, zana mpya ambayo inatoa maoni ya uhusiano huu wa lugha tofauti, kati ya mifumo, vitengo vya lexico na vifaa vya mfumo, kwa kutumia rasilimali kama vile dictiona za lugha nyingine na kwenye maeneo ya usambazaji, ikionyesha nguvu na udhaifu wa njia mbalimbali za usambazaji.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>پروژه FrameNet (FN) در موسسه علم کامپیوتر بین المللی در برکلی (ICSI) که مدرک کلمات اصلی انگلیسی اکنون را ثبت می‌کند، اولین منابع لکسیکی بر اساس نظریه فیلمور سیمانتیک فرم بود. برکلی فرم‌نیت پروژه‌های ارتباطی را در حدود دوازده زبان دیگر الهام داده است که به طور مستقل تکامل داده اند. پروژه FrameNet Multilingual (MLFN) یک تلاش برای پیدا کردن تنظیم بین همه آنها است. مشکل تنظیم با این حقیقت پیچیده شده است که این پروژه‌ها به مدل برکلی FrameNet متفاوت درجه‌های متفاوت متصل شده‌اند، و همچنین آنها در زمان متفاوت، زمانی که نسخه‌های متفاوت داده‌های برکلی FrameNet در دسترس بودند. ما چند روش جدید برای پیدا کردن رابطه‌های شبیه بین فرم‌های semantic در زبانها توصیف می‌کنیم. ما ویتوXF را نشان خواهیم داد، یک ابزار جدید که تصویر های متفاوتی از این رابطه های متفاوت زبان، بین فرم، واحدهای زبانی و عناصر فرم، بر اساس منابع مثل واژه‌های متفاوت زبان و فضای واژه‌های متفاوت تقسیم می‌کند، که قدرت و ضعیفیت روش‌های متفاوت تطبیق می‌کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Berkeley (ICSI) Halkara Kompýuter Ilmi Institutynda FrameNet (FN) döwleti. Bu häzirki wagtyň iňlisçe s özleriniň esasy sözleridir. Fillmore'yň Frem Semantikleriň teoriýasyna daýanýan ilkinji leksik çeşmesi. Berkeley FrameNet birnäçe düzine başga dillerde ýakyn ýagdaýda ýakynlaşyk taslaýyşlara ruhlandyrdy. Olar birnäçe özbaşdak şekilde öwrüldi; Häzirki Multilingual FrameNet projesi (MLFN) hemmesiniň arasynda çyzyglary tapmak synanyşdyr. Ýagtym meselesi Berkeley FrameNet Modeline üýtgeşik derejesinden çykarylýar. Olar birnäçe gezek Berkeley FrameNet verileriniň üýtgeşikleri bolan wagtlar üçin guruldylar. Biz semantik çerämeler arasynda bir näçe täze yöntemi dillerde meňzeşlikleri tapmak üçin tasvir edip görýäris. Biz ViToXF'i, bu çarpaz dil baglaşyklarynyň, çerätleri, leksiýet we frame elementleriniň arasynda täze bir aralygy görkezip biljek täze bir aralygy görkezip biljek bolýarys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>የፍሬሜኔት (FN) ፕሮጀክት የፊልሞር የፍሬም ሴማንቲክስ ታሪክ ላይ በሚደረገው የአቀፍ ኮምፒዩተር የሳይንስ ኢንተርቴት (ICSI) በቤርክሌ (አቀፍ ኮምፒዩተር የኢንተርኔት ቋንቋ) በመጀመሪያው የፍልሞር ዝርዝር ላይ የተገኘ የፊልሞር ዝና ነው፡፡ ቤርክሊ ፍሬሜኔት የግንኙነት ፕሮጀክቶችን በተለየ አእላፍ ሌሎችን ቋንቋዎች ያሳውቃቸዋል፡፡ የአሁኑ የቋንቋ ቋንቋዎች የፎርማት ፕሮጀክት (MLFN) በሁሉም መካከል ክፍተቶችን ለማግኘት ይፈልጋል። የግንኙነት መከራ እነዚህ ፕሮጀክቶች የቤርክሊ ፍሬሜኔት ሞዴል ለልዩ ደረጃዎች እንዲቀላቀሉ ተጨማሪ ነው፡፡ በቋንቋዎች መካከል የsemantic frame መካከል ግንኙነትን ለማግኘት ብዙ አዲስ ሥርዓቶችን እናሳውቃለን፡፡ እነዚህን የቋንቋዎች ግንኙነት፣ ፍሬም፣ ሌክሲካዊ የክፍሎች እና ፍሬም አካላት፣ ብዙዎች ቋንቋዎች እና በተካፈለ የክፍለ መንገዶች እና በተካፈለ የክፍለ ልዩ ቋንቋዎች እና በተካፈለ የዌብ ቦታዎች ላይ የተመሳሳይ ሀብትን እናሳያቸዋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>Die FrameNet (FN) projek by die Internasionale Rekenaar Wetenskaplike Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), wat dokumenteer die eerste woordeboek van contemporary Engels, was die eerste leksiese hulpbron gebaseer op Fillmore se teoriee van Raam Semantieke. Berkeley FrameNet het verwante projekte inspireer in omtrent 'n dusin ander tale wat iets onveilig ontwikkeld het; Die huidige Multilingual FrameNet projek (MLFN) is 'n probeer na soek oplyn tussen almal hulle. Die belyning probleem is kompliseer deur die feit dat hierdie projekte aan die Berkeley FrameNet model aangehou het om verskillende grade te verander, en hulle is ook in verskillende tyde gefundeer wanneer verskillende weergawes van die Berkeley FrameNet data beskikbaar was. Ons beskryf verskeie nuwe metodes om relasies van gelykheid te vind tussen semantiese rame oor tale. Ons sal ViToXF 'n nuwe gereedskap wys wat interaktiewe visualisasies van hierdie kruistale verwantings verskaf, tussen rame, leksiese eenhede en raam elemente, gebaseer op hulpbronne soos multitaalslike woordeboekvorms en op gedeelde verspreidingsvektorspasies, maak die sterkte en swakhedes van verskillende verskillende lyn metodes skoon.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Projekti FrameNet (FN) në Institutin Ndërkombëtar të Shkencës s ë Kompjuterit në Berkeley (ICSI), i cili dokumenton fjalorin thelbësor të anglisht bashkëkohor, ishte burimi i parë lexik bazuar në teorinë e Fillmores për Semantikat e Kuadrave. Berkeley FrameNet ka frymëzuar projekte të lidhura në rreth një duzinë gjuhësh të tjera, të cilat kanë evoluar disi në mënyrë të pavarur; Projekti aktual Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) është një përpjekje për të gjetur përputhje midis të gjithë atyre. Problemi i përshtatjes është i komplikuar nga fakti se këto projekte kanë adhuruar modelin Berkeley FrameNet në shkalla të ndryshme dhe ato u themeluan gjithashtu në kohë të ndryshme, kur versione të ndryshme të të dhënave Berkeley FrameNet ishin në dispozicion. We describe several new methods for finding relations of similarity between semantic frames across languages.  We will demonstrate ViToXF, a new tool which provides interactive visualizations of these cross-lingual relations, between frames, lexical units, and frame elements, based on resources such as multilingual dictionaries and on shared distributional vector spaces, making clear the strengths and weaknesses of different alignment methods.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_az>Berkeley (ICSI) Uluslararası Kompüter Bilim Enstitüs ünün FrameNet (FN) layihəsi, ki, günəşin İngilizlərin əsas sözlərini belə dökülər, Fillmore'in Frame Semantics teoriyasına dayanan ilk leksik kaynağı idi. Berkeley FrameNet müxtəlif tədbirləri bir neçə dildə təşkil etdi və bu tədbirləri təkrar təkrar dəyişdirdi. Şimdiki Multilingual FrameNet layihəsi (MLFN) onların hamısının arasında tərəflər tapmağa çalışır. Bu proqramların Berkeley FrameNet modelinin dəyişiklik dəyişikliklərinə bağlı olduğu və bu proqramların Berkeley FrameNet verilənlərin müxtəlif versiyonların də müxtəlif vaxtlarda qurulduğu təqdirdə belə karmaşdırılmışdır. Biz çox yeni metodları dillərin arasında semantik framlar arasında bənzər ilişkisini tapmaq üçün təfsir edirik. Biz ViToXF'i göstərəcəyik, bu çoxlu dil sözləri və paylaşıb vektör uzaqlarına dayanıb, müxtəlif düzəltmə metodlarının qüvvətlərini və zəifliklərini aydınlaşdırır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>বার্কেলি ইন্টারন্যাশনাল কম্পিউটার বিজ্ঞান ইনস্টিটিউটের ফ্রেমেনেট (এফএন) প্রকল্প, যা বর্তমান ইংরেজীর মূল শব্দভাণ্ডার নথিভুক্ত করে, ফিল্মরের ফ্রেম সেম্যান Berkeley FrameNet has inspired related projects in roughly a dozen other languages, which have evolved somewhat independently;  বর্তমান মাল্টিভাষী ফ্রেমেন্ট প্রকল্প (এমএলএফএন) হচ্ছে এগুলোর মধ্যে প্রতিনিধি খুঁজে বের করার চেষ্টা। প্রজেক্ট বার্কেলি ফ্রেমেনেট মডেলের সাথে বিভিন্ন ডিগ্রীর সাথে যোগ দিয়েছে এবং তারা বিভিন্ন সময়ে প্রতিষ্ঠান করেছে, যখন বার্কেলি ফ্রেমেনেটের বিভিন আমরা বেশ কয়েকটি নতুন পদ্ধতি বর্ণনা করি সারা ভাষার মধ্যে সেমান্টিক ফ্রেম খুঁজে বের করার জন্য। আমরা ভিটোএক্সএফ, একটি নতুন টুল, যা ক্রীম, লেক্সিক্সিক্যাল ইউনিট এবং ফ্রেম মেন্টের মধ্যে কার্যক্রমের দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি দেখতে পাচ্ছে, যেমন বহুভাষার অভিধান এবং ভাগাভাগি ভেক্টরের স্থানে ভিত্তিত</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Projekt FrameNet (FN) u Međunarodnom institutu kompjuterske nauke u Berkeleyu (ICSI), koji dokumentira temeljni rečenik contemporarnog engleskog jezika, bio je prvi leksički resurs na temelju Fillmorove teorije okvirnog semantika. Berkeley FrameNet je inspirisao povezane projekte na oko desetak drugih jezika, koji su se malo razvili nezavisno; trenutni Multilingual FrameNet projekat (MLFN) je pokušaj pronaći poravnanje između svih njih. Problem s usklađenjem je komplikovan činjenicom da su ovi projekti pridržali model Berkeley FrameNet na različitim stupnjevima, te su također osnovani u različitim vremenima, kada su dostupne različite verzije podataka Berkeley FrameNet-a. Opišemo nekoliko novih metoda za pronalaženje odnosa sličnosti između semantičkih okvira na jezicima. Pokazat ćemo ViToXF, novi alat koji pruža interaktivne vizualizacije ovih međujezičkih odnosa, između okvira, leksičkih jedinica i okvirnih elementa, na temelju resursa poput multijezičkih diktorija i na zajedničkih distribucijskih vektorskih prostora, čistimo snage i slabosti različitih metoda usklađenja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>El projecte FrameNet (FN) de l'International Computer Science Institute de Berkeley (ICSI), que documenta el vocabulari central de l'anglès contemporani, va ser el primer recurso lexical basat en la teoria de Frame Semantics de Fillmore. Berkeley FrameNet ha inspirat projectes relacionats en aproximadament una dotzena d'altres llengües, que han evolucionat de manera independent; the current Multilingual FrameNet project (MLFN) is an attempt to find alignments between all of them.  El problema d'allinjament és complicat pel fet que aquests projectes han adherit al model Berkeley FrameNet a diferents nivells, i també van ser fundats en diferents moments, quan estaven disponibles diferents versions de les dades Berkeley FrameNet. Descrevem diversos nous mètodes per trobar relacions de similitud entre els marcs semàntics a través de les llengües. Demostrarem ViToXF, una nova eina que proporciona visualitzacions interactives d'aquestes relacions translingües, entre marcs, unitats lexiques i elements de marc, basades en recursos com els diccionaris multilingües i en espais compartits de distribució de vectors, explicant les forces i debilitats de diferents mètodes d'alliniament.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Projekt FrameNet (FN) na Mezinárodním ústavu informatiky v Berkeley (ICSI), který dokumentuje základní slovní zásobu současné angličtiny, byl prvním lexikálním zdrojem založeným na Fillmorově teorii rámové sémantiky. Berkeley FrameNet inspiroval související projekty zhruba v desítce dalších jazyků, které se vyvinuly poněkud nezávisle; Současný projekt Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) je pokusem najít sladění mezi všemi z nich. Problém zarovnávání je komplikován skutečností, že tyto projekty dodržovaly model Berkeley FrameNet v různé míře a byly také založeny v různých dobách, kdy byly k dispozici různé verze dat Berkeley FrameNet. Popisujeme několik nových metod pro nalezení vztahů podobnosti mezi sémantickými rámci napříč jazyky. Předvedeme ViToXF, nový nástroj, který poskytuje interaktivní vizualizaci těchto vícejazyčných vztahů mezi rámci, lexikálními jednotkami a prvky rámců, založený na zdrojích, jako jsou vícejazyčné slovníky a sdílené distribuční vektorové prostory, čímž objasní silné a slabé stránky různých metod zarovnávání.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Rahvusvahelise Arvutiteaduse Instituudi (ICSI) FrameNet (FN) projekt, mis dokumenteerib kaasaegse inglise keele põhisõnavara, oli esimene Fillmore'i raamsemantika teoorial põhinev leksikaalne ressurss. Berkeley FrameNet on inspireerinud seotud projekte umbes tosinas teises keeles, mis on arenenud mõnevõrra iseseisvalt; Praegune mitmekeelne FrameNet projekt (MLFN) püüab leida nende kõigi vahel vastavust. Ühtlustamise probleem on keeruline asjaolu, et need projektid on järginud Berkeley FrameNet mudelit erineval määral, ja need asutati ka erinevatel aegadel, kui erinevad versioonid Berkeley FrameNet andmed olid kättesaadavad. Kirjeldame mitmeid uusi meetodeid semantiliste raamide sarnasuse suhete leidmiseks keeltes. Näitame ViToXF-i, uut tööriista, mis pakub interaktiivseid visualiseerimisi nendest keeleülestest suhetest raamide, leksikaalsete üksuste ja raamelementide vahel, tuginedes sellistele ressurssidele nagu mitmekeelsed sõnaraamatud ja jagatud jaotusvektoriruumidele, selgitades erinevate joondamismeetodite tugevusi ja nõrkusi.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>FrameNet (FN) -projekti International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), joka dokumentoi nykyisen englannin ydinsanaston, oli ensimmäinen Fillmoren Frame Semantiikan teoriaan perustuva sanasto. Berkeley FrameNet on inspiroinut aiheeseen liittyviä projekteja noin tusinalla muulla kielellä, jotka ovat kehittyneet jonkin verran itsenäisesti; Nykyinen monikielinen FrameNet-projekti (MLFN) on yritys löytää linjauksia niiden kaikkien välillä. Yhdenmukaistamisongelmaa mutkistaa se, että nämä hankkeet ovat noudattaneet Berkeley FrameNet -mallia vaihtelevassa määrin, ja ne on myös perustettu eri aikoina, kun Berkeley FrameNet -datan eri versioita oli saatavilla. Kuvailemme useita uusia menetelmiä semanttisten kehysten samankaltaisuussuhteiden löytämiseksi eri kielillä. Esittelemme ViToXF:n, uuden työkalun, joka tarjoaa vuorovaikutteisia visualisointeja näistä monikielisistä suhteista kehysten, leksikaalisten yksiköiden ja kehyseelementtien välillä käyttäen resursseja, kuten monikielisiä sanakirjoja ja jaettuja vektoriavaruuksia, ja tekee selväksi eri linjausmenetelmien vahvuudet ja heikkoudet.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_hy>The FrameNet (FN) project at the International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), which documents the core vocabulary of contemporary English, was the first lexical resource based on Fillmore's theory of Frame Semantics.  Berkeley FrameNet has inspired related projects in roughly a dozen other languages, which have evolved somewhat independently;  the current Multilingual FrameNet project (MLFN) is an attempt to find alignments between all of them.  Խնդիրը հարմարեցման համար բարդ է այն պատճառով, որ այս նախագծերը համապատասխանել են Բերկլին Ֆրամենեթ մոդելին տարբեր աստիճաններով, և դրանք նաև հիմնված են տարբեր ժամանակներում, երբ Բերկլին Ֆրամենեթ տվյալների տարբեր տարբերակները հասանելի էին: Մենք նկարագրում ենք մի քանի նոր մեթոդներ, որոնք օգնում են գտնել լեզուների միջև սեմանտիկ շրջանների նմանության հարաբերությունները: Մենք կցուցադրենք ViToXF-ը, մի նոր գործիք, որը տրամադրում է ինտերակտիվ վիզուալիզացիաներ այս լեզվային հարաբերությունների միջև, շրջանների, լեքսիկական միավորների և շրջանների տարրերի միջև, հիմնված այնպիսի ռեսուրսների վրա, ինչպիսիք են բառալեզու բառարանները, և տարածված տարածական տարածքների վրա, պարզաբան</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ha>The FrameNet (FN) Projem at the International Composite Installation of Sayansi in Berkely (ICSA), which documents the essence of the current language English, was the first Lex resource based on Fillmor's theory of Frame Semantics. Berkely FrameNet ya yi wahayi zuwa wasu wasu mistakardu masu husũma cikin harshen dubu guda, da suka tsẽfo abu kaɗan da huru; @ action: button QNetworkAccessFileBackend We describe several new methods for finding relations of similarity between semantic frames across languages.  Za nuna wa video ToXF, wata zanci na yanzu wanda ke samar da masu haɗi na haɗi cikin harshen-harshen, tsakanin firam, masu shiryi, da ƙanshi masu lokaci da kuma firam, a kan asalin rasmi, kamar manyan dictionaries masu mulki-lingui da kuma a kan filayenai masu gauraya, yana bayyana ƙarfi da rauni na shiryoyin ayuka daban-dabam.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Proyek frame net Berkley frame net dumadhine kapan pangan sing dumadhi kanggo sampeyan wisata luwih dumateng, sing wis evoluwih akeh lan sampeyan akeh dumadhi; akeh populer Multilanguage text-box-mode Awak dhéwé éntukno karo akeh sistem sing gak nggawe gerakan karo sampeyan karo semanti karo dilané. Awak dhéwé iso nggambar VisToXF, alat sing wis nggawe tarjamahan karo ngono langgambar kelas telas, nggambar frame, unani lewat karo karo eleman karo frame, supoyo sak sistem sing dikarolan karo diktualisar luwih akeh lan sak oleh bantuan vector nggawe, nggawe nyimpen nggawe kesèhke lan nguwis kuwi nggawe nguasar luwih sabanjur</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>The FrameNet (FN) project at the International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), which documents the core vocabulary of contemporary English, was the first lexical resource based on Fillmore's theory of Frame Semantics.  ברקלי פרמינט השראה פרוייקטים קשורים בערך תריסר שפות אחרות, שהתפתחו באופן עצמאי. the current Multilingual FrameNet project (MLFN) is an attempt to find alignments between all of them.  בעיית התאמה מסובכת על ידי העובדה שהפרוייקטים האלה התייחסו לדוגמא ברקלי FrameNet למדרגות שונות, והם נוסדו גם בזמנים שונים, כאשר גרסאות שונות של נתוני ברקלי FrameNet היו זמינות. אנחנו מתארים כמה שיטות חדשות למצוא יחסים של דמיון בין מסגרות סמנטיות ברחבי שפות. אנחנו נצג ViToXF, כלי חדש שמספק ויזואליזציות אינטראקטיביות של מערכות יחסים בין השפה, בין מסגרות, יחידות לקסיקות, ואלימנטים מסגרת, מבוססים על משאבים כמו מילונים רבות שפות וחלל ויקטורים משותפים, ומברחים את החזקות וחלשות של שיטות התאמה שונות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Projekt FrameNet (FN) na Mednarodnem inštitutu za računalništvo v Berkeleyju (ICSI), ki dokumentira osrednji besednjak sodobne angleščine, je bil prvi leksikalni vir, ki temelji na Fillmorovi teoriji Frame Semantike. Berkeley FrameNet je navdihnil sorodne projekte v približno ducatu drugih jezikov, ki so se razvili nekoliko neodvisno; Trenutni projekt Multilingual FrameNet (MLFN) je poskus najti usklajenosti med vsemi. Problem usklajevanja je zapleteno zaradi dejstva, da so ti projekti v različnih stopnjah upoštevali Berkeley FrameNet model in so bili ustanovljeni tudi v različnih časih, ko so bile na voljo različne različice podatkov Berkeley FrameNet. Opisujemo več novih metod za iskanje relacij podobnosti med semantičnimi okvirji med jeziki. Predstavili bomo ViToXF, novo orodje, ki omogoča interaktivne vizualizacije teh medjezičnih odnosov med okvirji, leksikalnimi enotami in elementi okvirjev, ki temelji na virih, kot so večjezični slovarji in skupni distribucijski vektorski prostori, s čimer bomo pojasnili prednosti in slabosti različnih metod poravnave.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>The FrameNet (FN) project at the International Computer Science Institute of Berkeley (ICSI)which documents the core vocabulary of contemporary English, was the first lexical resource based on Fillmore's theory of Frame Semantics. Berkeley FrameNet དེ་གིས་སྐད་རིགས་གཞན་མང་པོ་ཞིག་གི་ནང་དུ་འབྲེལ་བའི་ལས་འགུལ་གྱི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡོད་པ་ཡིན། ད་ལྟོའི་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་གྲངས་ཀྱི་FrameNet (MLFN)ལས་འགུལ་འདི་དག་ཚང་མའི་དབར་གྱི་གྲལ་སྒྲིག་རྣམས་བློ་གཏོང་བ The alignment problem is complicated by the fact that these projects have adhered to the Berkeley FrameNet model to varying degrees, and they were also founded at different times, when different versions of the Berkeley FrameNet data were available. འུ་ཅག་གིས་སྐད་རིགས་དབྱིབས་མཐུན་དང་འདྲ་བའི་མཐུན་འབྲེལ་བའི་ལམ་ལུགས་གསརཔ་སོ་སོར་བ། We will demonstrate ViToXF, a new tool which provides interactive visualizations of these cross-lingual relations, between frames, lexical units, and frame elements, based on resources such as multilingual dictionaries and on shared distributional vector spaces, making clear the strengths and weaknesses of different alignment methods.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>