<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.ltedi">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-04-19">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Language Technology for Equality, Diversity and Inclusion</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Manel</first><last>Zarrouk</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kalika</first><last>Bali</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Paul</first><last>Buitelaar</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Kyiv</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="bdaa4076">2021.ltedi-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>ltedi-2021-language</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Impact of COVID-19 in Natural Language Processing Publications : a Disaggregated Study in Gender, Contribution and Experience<fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 in Natural Language Processing Publications: a Disaggregated Study in Gender, Contribution and Experience</title>
      <author><first>Christine</first><last>Basta</last></author>
      <author><first>Marta R.</first><last>Costa-jussa</last></author>
      <pages>1–6</pages>
      <abstract>This study sheds light on the effects of COVID-19 in the particular field of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">Computational Linguistics</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a> within <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence">Artificial Intelligence</a>. We provide an inter-sectional study on gender, contribution, and experience that considers one school year (from August 2019 to August 2020) as a pandemic year. August is included twice for the purpose of an inter-annual comparison. While the trend in publications increased with the crisis, the results show that the ratio between female and male publications decreased. This only helps to reduce the importance of the female role in the scientific contributions of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">computational linguistics</a> (it is now far below its peak of 0.24). The pandemic has a particularly negative effect on the production of female senior researchers in the first position of authors (maximum work), followed by the female junior researchers in the last position of authors (supervision or collaborative work).</abstract>
      <url hash="3e3f01c0">2021.ltedi-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>basta-costa-jussa-2021-impact</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>hBERT + BiasCorp-Fighting Racism on the Web<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> + <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>ias<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>orp - Fighting Racism on the Web</title>
      <author><first>Olawale</first><last>Onabola</last></author>
      <author><first>Zhuang</first><last>Ma</last></author>
      <author><first>Xie</first><last>Yang</last></author>
      <author><first>Benjamin</first><last>Akera</last></author>
      <author><first>Ibraheem</first><last>Abdulrahman</last></author>
      <author><first>Jia</first><last>Xue</last></author>
      <author><first>Dianbo</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Yoshua</first><last>Bengio</last></author>
      <pages>26–33</pages>
      <abstract>Subtle and overt racism is still present both in physical and online communities today and has impacted many lives in different segments of the society. In this short piece of work, we present how we’re tackling this societal issue with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a>. We are releasing BiasCorp, a dataset containing 139,090 comments and news segment from three specific sources-Fox News, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breitbart_News">BreitbartNews</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube">YouTube</a>. The first batch (45,000 manually annotated) is ready for publication. We are currently in the final phase of manually labeling the remaining <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazon_Mechanical_Turk">Amazon Mechanical Turk</a>. BERT has been used widely in several downstream tasks. In this work, we present hBERT, where we modify certain layers of the pretrained BERT model with the new Hopfield Layer. hBert generalizes well across different distributions with the added advantage of a reduced model complexity. We are also releasing a JavaScript library 3 and a Chrome Extension Application, to help developers make use of our trained model in web applications (say chat application) and for users to identify and report racially biased contents on the web respectively</abstract>
      <url hash="d39effc3">2021.ltedi-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>onabola-etal-2021-hbert</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>An Overview of Fairness in Data   Illuminating the Bias in Data Pipeline</title>
      <author><first>Senthil Kumar</first><last>B</last></author>
      <author><first>Aravindan</first><last>Chandrabose</last></author>
      <author><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></author>
      <pages>34–45</pages>
      <abstract>Data in general encodes human biases by default ; being aware of this is a good start, and the research around how to handle it is ongoing. The term ‘<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a>’ is extensively used in various contexts in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP systems</a>. In our research the focus is specific to biases such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender">gender</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racism">racism</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religion">religion</a>, demographic and other intersectional views on biases that prevail in text processing systems responsible for systematically discriminating specific population, which is not ethical in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a>. These <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">biases</a> exacerbate the lack of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_equality">equality</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiculturalism">diversity</a> and inclusion of specific population while utilizing the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP applications</a>. The tools and technology at the intermediate level utilize <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias_(statistics)">biased data</a>, and transfer or amplify this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias_(statistics)">bias</a> to the downstream applications. However, it is not enough to be colourblind, gender-neutral alone when designing a unbiased technology   instead, we should take a conscious effort by designing a unified framework to measure and benchmark the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a>. In this paper, we recommend six measures and one augment measure based on the observations of the bias in data, annotations, text representations and debiasing techniques.</abstract>
      <url hash="6b831c7c">2021.ltedi-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>b-etal-2021-overview</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/winobias">WinoBias</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>GEPSA, a tool for monitoring social challenges in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_media">digital press</a><fixed-case>GEPSA</fixed-case>, a tool for monitoring social challenges in digital press</title>
      <author><first>Iñaki</first><last>San Vicente</last></author>
      <author><first>Xabier</first><last>Saralegi</last></author>
      <author><first>Nerea</first><last>Zubia</last></author>
      <pages>46–50</pages>
      <abstract>This papers presents a platform for monitoring press narratives with respect to several social challenges, including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_equality">gender equality</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_migration">migrations</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minority_language">minority languages</a>. As narratives are encoded in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language</a>, we have to use natural processing techniques to automate their analysis. Thus, crawled news are processed by means of several NLP modules, including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named-entity_recognition">named entity recognition</a>, keyword extraction, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_classification">document classification</a> for social challenge detection, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a>. A Flask powered interface provides <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_visualization">data visualization</a> for a user-based analysis of the data. This paper presents the architecture of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> and describes in detail its different components. Evaluation is provided for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modular_design">modules</a> related to extraction and classification of information regarding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_issue">social challenges</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="f8e7ae96">2021.ltedi-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>san-vicente-etal-2021-gepsa</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Finding Spoiler Bias in Tweets by Zero-shot Learning and Knowledge Distilling from Neural Text Simplification</title>
      <author><first>Avi</first><last>Bleiweiss</last></author>
      <pages>51–60</pages>
      <abstract>Automatic detection of critical plot information in reviews of media items poses unique challenges to both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_computing">social computing</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">computational linguistics</a>. In this paper we propose to cast the problem of discovering spoiler bias in online discourse as a text simplification task. We conjecture that for an item-user pair, the simpler the user review we learn from an item summary the higher its likelihood to present a spoiler. Our neural model incorporates the advanced transformer network to rank the severity of a spoiler in user tweets. We constructed a sustainable high-quality movie dataset scraped from unsolicited review tweets and paired with a title summary and meta-data extracted from a movie specific domain. To a large extent, our quantitative and qualitative results weigh in on the performance impact of named entity presence in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plot_(graphics)">plot summaries</a>. Pretrained on a split-and-rephrase corpus with knowledge distilled from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_Wikipedia">English Wikipedia</a> and fine-tuned on our movie dataset, our neural model shows to outperform both a language modeler and monolingual translation baselines.</abstract>
      <url hash="cb3c8c3f">2021.ltedi-1.7</url>
      <attachment type="Dataset" hash="2e3925d5">2021.ltedi-1.7.Dataset.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>bleiweiss-2021-finding</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/bshalem/mst" additional="false">bshalem/mst</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>IIITT@LT-EDI-EACL2021-Hope Speech Detection : There is always hope in Transformers<fixed-case>IIITT</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>LT</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EDI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021-Hope Speech Detection: There is always hope in Transformers</title>
      <author><first>Karthik</first><last>Puranik</last></author>
      <author><first>Adeep</first><last>Hande</last></author>
      <author><first>Ruba</first><last>Priyadharshini</last></author>
      <author><first>Sajeetha</first><last>Thavareesan</last></author>
      <author><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></author>
      <pages>98–106</pages>
      <abstract>In a world with serious challenges like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Climate_change">climate change</a>, religious and political conflicts, global pandemics, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terrorism">terrorism</a>, and racial discrimination, an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet">internet</a> full of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hate_speech">hate speech</a>, abusive and offensive content is the last thing we desire for. In this paper, we work to identify and promote positive and supportive content on these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computing_platform">platforms</a>. We work with several transformer-based models to classify social media comments as hope speech or not hope speech in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, and Tamil languages. This paper portrays our work for the Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion at LT-EDI 2021- EACL 2021. The codes for our best submission can be viewed.</abstract>
      <url hash="35a0ebf4">2021.ltedi-1.13</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="b54b3da8">2021.ltedi-1.13.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>puranik-etal-2021-iiitt</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/karthikpuranik11/Hope-Speech-Detection-" additional="false">karthikpuranik11/Hope-Speech-Detection-</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>ZYJ@LT-EDI-EACL2021 : XLM-RoBERTa-Based Model with Attention for Hope Speech Detection<fixed-case>ZYJ</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>LT</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EDI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021:<fixed-case>XLM</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>a-Based Model with Attention for Hope Speech Detection</title>
      <author><first>Yingjia</first><last>Zhao</last></author>
      <author><first>Xin</first><last>Tao</last></author>
      <pages>118–121</pages>
      <abstract>Due to the development of modern computer technology and the increase in the number of online media users, we can see all kinds of posts and comments everywhere on the internet. Hope speech can not only inspire the creators but also make other viewers pleasant. It is necessary to effectively and automatically detect hope speech. This paper describes the approach of our team in the task of hope speech detection. We use the attention mechanism to adjust the weight of all the output layers of XLM-RoBERTa to make full use of the information extracted from each layer, and use the weighted sum of all the output layers to complete the classification task. And we use the Stratified-K-Fold method to enhance the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training data set</a>. We achieve a weighted average F1-score of 0.59, 0.84, and 0.92 for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English language</a>, ranked 3rd, 2nd, and 2nd.</abstract>
      <url hash="9c6805ad">2021.ltedi-1.16</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="ce5760dc">2021.ltedi-1.16.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>zhao-tao-2021-zyj</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>TeamUNCC@LT-EDI-EACL2021 : Hope Speech Detection using Transfer Learning with Transformers<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>eam<fixed-case>UNCC</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>LT</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EDI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Hope Speech Detection using Transfer Learning with Transformers</title>
      <author><first>Khyati</first><last>Mahajan</last></author>
      <author><first>Erfan</first><last>Al-Hossami</last></author>
      <author><first>Samira</first><last>Shaikh</last></author>
      <pages>136–142</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we describe our approach towards utilizing pre-trained models for the task of hope speech detection. We participated in Task 2 : Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity and Inclusion at LT-EDI-2021 @ EACL2021. The goal of this task is to predict the presence of hope speech, along with the presence of samples that do not belong to the same language in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>. We describe our approach to fine-tuning RoBERTa for Hope Speech detection in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and our approach to fine-tuning XLM-RoBERTa for Hope Speech detection in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, two low resource Indic languages. We demonstrate the performance of our approach on classifying text into hope-speech, non-hope and not-language. Our approach ranked 1st in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> (F1 = 0.93), 1st in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a> (F1 = 0.61) and 3rd in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a> (F1 = 0.83).</abstract>
      <url hash="b7e23c3d">2021.ltedi-1.20</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="dea413ca">2021.ltedi-1.20.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>mahajan-etal-2021-teamuncc</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hopeedi">HopeEDI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Autobots@LT-EDI-EACL2021 : One World, One Family : Hope Speech Detection with BERT Transformer Model<fixed-case>LT</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EDI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: One World, One Family: Hope Speech Detection with <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> Transformer Model</title>
      <author><first>Sunil</first><last>Gundapu</last></author>
      <author><first>Radhika</first><last>Mamidi</last></author>
      <pages>143–148</pages>
      <abstract>The rapid rise of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_social_networking_websites">online social networks</a> like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube">YouTube</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a> allows people to express their views more widely online. However, at the same time, it can lead to an increase in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conflict_(process)">conflict</a> and hatred among consumers in the form of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_speech">freedom of speech</a>. Therefore, it is essential to take a positive strengthening method to research on encouraging, positive, helping, and supportive social media content. In this paper, we describe a Transformer-based BERT model for Hope speech detection for equality, diversity, and inclusion, submitted for LT-EDI-2021 Task 2. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> achieves a weighted averaged f1-score of 0.93 on the test set.</abstract>
      <url hash="ca01867b">2021.ltedi-1.21</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="d95ae8fa">2021.ltedi-1.21.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>gundapu-mamidi-2021-autobots</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hopeedi">HopeEDI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Hopeful NLP@LT-EDI-EACL2021 : Finding Hope in YouTube Comment Section<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>LT</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EDI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Finding Hope in <fixed-case>Y</fixed-case>ou<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ube Comment Section</title>
      <author><first>Vasudev</first><last>Awatramani</last></author>
      <pages>164–167</pages>
      <abstract>The proliferation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hate_speech">Hate Speech</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misinformation">misinformation</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> is fast becoming a menace to society. In compliment, the dissemination of hate-diffusing, promising and anti-oppressive messages become a unique alternative. Unfortunately, due to its complex nature as well as the relatively limited manifestation in comparison to hostile and neutral content, the identification of Hope Speech becomes a challenge. This work revolves around the detection of Hope Speech in Youtube comments, for the Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_equality">Equality</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiculturalism">Diversity</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inclusion_(disability_rights)">Inclusion</a>. We achieve an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-score">f-score</a> of 0.93, ranking 1st on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glossary_of_French_expressions_in_English">leaderboard</a> for English comments.</abstract>
      <url hash="9ea81a68">2021.ltedi-1.24</url>
      <bibkey>awatramani-2021-hopeful</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hopeedi">HopeEDI</pwcdataset>
    <title_es>PNL esperanzada @LT -EDI-EACL2021: Encontrando esperanza en la sección de comentarios de YouTube</title_es>
      <title_pt>Hopeful NLP@LT-EDI-EACL2021: Encontrando esperança na seção de comentários do YouTube</title_pt>
      <title_fr>Hopeful NLP @LT -EDI-EACL2021 : Trouver de l'espoir dans la section de commentaires YouTube</title_fr>
      <title_ar>أمل NLP @ LT-EDI-EACL2021: البحث عن الأمل في قسم التعليقات على YouTube</title_ar>
      <title_hi>आशावादी NLP@LT-EDI-EACL2021: YouTube टिप्पणी अनुभाग में आशा ढूँढना</title_hi>
      <title_ja>Hopeful NLP @ LT - EDI - EACL 2021: YouTubeコメントセクションで希望を見つける</title_ja>
      <title_ru>Надежный NLP@LT-EDI-EACL2021: Поиск надежды в разделе комментариев YouTube</title_ru>
      <title_zh>ĺ……ć»ˇĺ¸Śćś›äą‹NLP@LT-EDI-EACL2021:ć±‚čŻ¸YouTubeč®ş</title_zh>
      <title_ga>NLP@LT-EDI-EACL2021 dóchasach: Dóchas a Fháil i Rannóg Tráchtanna YouTube</title_ga>
      <title_ka>მედილობა NLP@LT - EDI- EACL2021: YouTube კომენტაქტის მონაცემების სექციაში მოიძებნა</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Remélem NLP@LT EDI-EACL2021: Remény megtalálása a YouTube Megjegyzés Szekció</title_hu>
      <title_it>Sperante NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Trovare la speranza in YouTube</title_it>
      <title_kk>Мүмкін NLP@LT - EDI- EACL2021: YouTube комментарий бөлімінде үміт табу</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Tikėtina NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: Tikimosi suradimas YouTube komentarų skyriuje</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Hopeful  NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: Најдување надеж во одделот за коментари на YouTube</title_mk>
      <title_el>Ελπίζω NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Βρίσκοντας ελπίδα στο τμήμα σχολίων στο YouTube</title_el>
      <title_ms>Hopeful  NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Mencari harapan dalam seksyen Komen YouTube</title_ms>
      <title_ml>പ്രതീക്ഷിക്കുന്നു NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: യൂട്ടബിലെ പ്രതീക്ഷ കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Speranti NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Is-Sezzjoni tas-Sezzjoni tal-Kummenti fuq YouTube għas-Sezzjoni ta’ Spera</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Найдвар NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: YouTube-ын Түсэглэгчийн хэсэгт найдвар олох</title_mn>
      <title_ro>Speranţă NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Găsirea speranței în YouTube Comentariu Secțiunea</title_ro>
      <title_si>හිතන්න NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: YouTube Comment</title_si>
      <title_so>Rajaynaya NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: Finding Hope in YouTube Comment</title_so>
      <title_pl>Nadzieja NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Znalezienie nadziei w sekcji komentarza YouTube</title_pl>
      <title_sv>Hoppsfull NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Att hitta hopp i YouTube Kommentar Avsnitt</title_sv>
      <title_no>Forhåpent NLP@LT - EDI- EACL2021: Finn håp i YouTube- kommentarsseksjon</title_no>
      <title_sr>Nadam se. NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: pronalaženje nade u sekciji komentara YouTube</title_sr>
      <title_ta>நம்பிக்கை NLP@LT - EDI- EACL2021: YouTube நம்பிக்கையை கண்டுபிடிக்கும் Comment</title_ta>
      <title_ur>امید ہے NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: یوٹیوب کی کمانٹ سکس میں امید تلاش کرتا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Namuna NLP@LT - EDI- EACL2021: Youtubdagi umumani topishComment</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Hy vọng NLP@LT -Edit-EAM-EAM: Tìm Hope trong mục Chú thích trên YouTube</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Hopelijk NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Hoop vinden in YouTube Commentaar Sectie</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Nadam se. NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Naći nadu u odjelu za komentar YouTube-a</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Надежден NLP@LT -Откриване на надежда в раздел Коментари</title_bg>
      <title_da>Håbefuld NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Finde håb i YouTube Kommentar Sektion</title_da>
      <title_de>Hoffnungsvoll NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Hoffnung finden in YouTube Kommentar Abschnitt</title_de>
      <title_id>Berharap NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Mencari harapan di bagian komentar YouTube</title_id>
      <title_sw>Hopeful  NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Kutafuta matumaini kwenye mtandao wa YouTube Comment</title_sw>
      <title_ko>희망이 충만하다NLP@LT- EDI-EACL 2021: YouTube 리뷰에서 희망 찾기</title_ko>
      <title_tr>Umyt NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021</title_tr>
      <title_af>Hopeful NLP@LT - EDI- EACL2021: Finding Hope in YouTube Comment Section</title_af>
      <title_hy>Հույս ունեմ, NLP@LT -ԷԴI-ԷԿԼ2021: Հույսի գտնելը YouTube-ի մեկնաբանության հատվածում</title_hy>
      <title_sq>Shpresoj NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Gjetja e Shpresës në Secionin e Komentarëve të YouTube</title_sq>
      <title_am>ተስፋ ያደርጋል NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: በዩቱዩብ ውስጥ ተስፋ ማግኘት</title_am>
      <title_az>Umar캼m NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: YouTube T톛rc칲m톛 B칬l칲m칲nd톛 칲mid tapmaq</title_az>
      <title_fa>اميدوارم NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: پیدا کردن امید در بخش توضیح YouTube</title_fa>
      <title_bs>Nadam se. NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Pronaći nadu u odjelu komentara YouTube-a</title_bs>
      <title_bn>আশাবাদী NLP@LT - EDI-EACL2021: ইউটিউবে আশা খুঁজে বের করা হবে</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Esperable NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Trobar esperança a la secció de comentaris de YouTube</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Nadějný NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Hledání naděje v YouTube Komentář Sekce</title_cs>
      <title_et>Loodetav NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Lootuse leidmine YouTube Kommentaaride sektsioon</title_et>
      <title_fi>Toivollinen NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Toivoa YouTubessa Kommenttiosio</title_fi>
      <title_sk>Upanje NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Iskanje upanja v YouTubu Oddelek komentarjev</title_sk>
      <title_ha>QShortcut NLP@LT - EDi-EacL2021: Finding Hope in YouTube, section</title_ha>
      <title_he>מקווה NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021: Finding Hope in YouTube Comment Section</title_he>
      <title_jv>Validity NLP@LT -ESTI-ETCL2020:Finding Espee in YouTube Name section</title_jv>
      <title_bo>རེ་འདོད་པ NLP@LT -EDI-EACL2021:Youtube དྲ་བརྗེད་མཁན་གྱི་རེ་བ་ལ་བཙལ་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_fr>La prolifération des discours haineux et de la désinformation sur les réseaux sociaux est en train de devenir une menace pour la société. En complément, la diffusion de messages haineux, prometteurs et anti-oppressifs devient une alternative unique. Malheureusement, en raison de sa nature complexe et de sa manifestation relativement limitée par rapport à un contenu hostile et neutre, l'identification de Hope Speech devient un défi. Ce travail s'articule autour de la détection du discours d'espoir dans les commentaires Youtube, pour la tâche partagée sur la détection du discours d'espoir pour l'égalité, la diversité et l'inclusion. Nous obtenons un score f de 0,93, ce qui nous place au premier rang du classement pour les commentaires en anglais.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>La proliferación de discursos de odio y desinformación en las redes sociales se está convirtiendo rápidamente en una amenaza para la sociedad. Como complemento, la difusión de mensajes que difunden el odio, prometedores y antiopresivos se convierten en una alternativa única. Desafortunadamente, debido a su naturaleza compleja, así como a la manifestación relativamente limitada en comparación con el contenido hostil y neutral, la identificación del Discurso de Esperanza se convierte en un desafío. Este trabajo gira en torno a la detección del discurso de esperanza en los comentarios de Youtube, para la tarea compartida sobre la detección del discurso de esperanza para la igualdad, la diversidad y la inclusión. Logramos una puntuación f de 0,93, ocupando el primer lugar en la clasificación de comentarios en inglés.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ar>أصبح انتشار خطاب الكراهية والمعلومات المضللة في وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي تهديدًا سريعًا للمجتمع. وإكمالًا لذلك ، أصبح نشر الرسائل الواعدة والمناهضة للقمع التي تنشر الكراهية بديلاً فريدًا. لسوء الحظ ، نظرًا لطبيعته المعقدة بالإضافة إلى المظهر المحدود نسبيًا مقارنة بالمحتوى العدائي والحيادي ، يصبح تحديد خطاب الأمل تحديًا. يدور هذا العمل حول اكتشاف Hope Speech في تعليقات Youtube ، للمهمة المشتركة حول اكتشاف كلام الأمل من أجل المساواة والتنوع والشمول. لقد حققنا درجة f 0.93 ، لتحتل المرتبة الأولى في قائمة المتصدرين للتعليقات باللغة الإنجليزية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>A proliferação de discurso de ódio e desinformação nas mídias sociais está rapidamente se tornando uma ameaça para a sociedade. Em complemento, a divulgação de mensagens difusoras de ódio, promissoras e antiopressoras torna-se uma alternativa única. Infelizmente, devido à sua natureza complexa, bem como à manifestação relativamente limitada em relação ao conteúdo hostil e neutro, a identificação do Hope Speech torna-se um desafio. Este trabalho gira em torno da detecção de Hope Speech em comentários do Youtube, para a Tarefa Compartilhada de Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion. Alcançamos uma pontuação f de 0,93, ficando em 1º lugar na tabela de classificação para comentários em inglês.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>ソーシャルメディアにおけるヘイトスピーチや誤った情報の拡散は、社会にとって急速に脅威となっています。褒め言葉として、憎悪を拡散する、有望で反抑圧的なメッセージの普及は、ユニークな代替手段となります。残念ながら、その複雑な性質と、敵対的かつ中立的なコンテンツと比較して比較的限定的な表示のため、ホープスピーチの特定は課題となります。この作業は、平等、多様性、およびインクルージョンのための希望の発言検出に関する共有タスクのためのYoutubeコメントでの希望の発言の検出を中心としています。英語コメントのランキングで1位となるfスコア0.93を達成しました。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ru>Распространение ненавистнических высказываний и дезинформации в социальных сетях быстро становится угрозой для общества. В качестве комплимента можно отметить, что распространение разжигающих ненависть, многообещающих и антирепрессивных посланий становится уникальной альтернативой. К сожалению, из-за его сложного характера, а также относительно ограниченного проявления по сравнению с враждебным и нейтральным содержанием, идентификация Речи Надежды становится проблемой. Эта работа основана на обнаружении речи надежды в комментариях Youtube для общей задачи по обнаружению речи надежды для равенства, разнообразия и интеграции. Мы получаем f-балл 0,93, занимая 1-е место в таблице лидеров по английским комментариям.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_zh>社交媒体仇言错误信息之滥,方速为患。 恭维者,传布仇雠,冀与反压迫之信独异也。 不幸者,以其复杂性敌中立有限,愿言其识为一挑战。 其事绕Youtube论检Hope Speech,以望语音检平等,多样性与包容性共同任务。 吾f分0.93,英语论排行榜第一。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हेट स्पीच का प्रसार और सोशल मीडिया में गलत सूचना तेजी से समाज के लिए खतरा बनता जा रहा है। प्रशंसा में, नफरत-विसर्पण, होनहार और विरोधी दमनकारी संदेशों का प्रसार एक अनूठा विकल्प बन जाता है। दुर्भाग्य से, इसकी जटिल प्रकृति के साथ-साथ शत्रुतापूर्ण और तटस्थ सामग्री की तुलना में अपेक्षाकृत सीमित अभिव्यक्ति के कारण, आशा भाषण की पहचान एक चुनौती बन जाती है। यह काम YouTube टिप्पणियों में आशा भाषण का पता लगाने के चारों ओर घूमता है, समानता, विविधता और समावेशन के लिए आशा भाषण का पता लगाने पर साझा कार्य के लिए। हम 0.93 का एफ-स्कोर प्राप्त करते हैं, अंग्रेजी टिप्पणियों के लिए लीडरबोर्ड पर 1 वें स्थान पर हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Tá an t-iomadú fuatha cainte agus mífhaisnéise sna meáin shóisialta ag éirí ina bhagairt don tsochaí. Mar chomhlánú air sin, is rogha uathúil é scaipeadh teachtaireachtaí fuath-idirleata, gealltanais agus frith-leathránach. Ar an drochuair, mar gheall ar a nádúr casta chomh maith leis an léiriú sách teoranta i gcomparáid le hábhar naimhdeach agus neodrach, déantar dúshlán Hope Speech a aithint. Baineann an obair seo le braite Hope Speech i dtuairimí Youtube, don Tasc Comhroinnte ar Bhrath Cainte Dóchais ar mhaithe le Comhionannas, Éagsúlacht agus Cuimsiú. Bainimid amach f-scór de 0.93, ag rangú 1ú ar an gclár ceannairí le haghaidh tuairimí Béarla.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Ο πολλαπλασιασμός της ομιλίας μίσους και της παραπληροφόρησης στα μέσα κοινωνικής δικτύωσης γίνεται γρήγορα απειλή για την κοινωνία. Ως κομπλιμέντο, η διάδοση μηνυμάτων διασποράς μίσους, υποσχόμενων και αντι-καταπιεστικών γίνεται μια μοναδική εναλλακτική λύση. Δυστυχώς, λόγω της πολύπλοκης φύσης του καθώς και της σχετικά περιορισμένης εκδήλωσης σε σύγκριση με το εχθρικό και ουδέτερο περιεχόμενο, η αναγνώριση του Λόγου Ελπίδας γίνεται πρόκληση. Αυτή η εργασία περιστρέφεται γύρω από την ανίχνευση της ομιλίας ελπίδας στα σχόλια του για την κοινή εργασία για την ανίχνευση ομιλίας ελπίδας για την ισότητα, την ποικιλομορφία και την ένταξη. Επιτυγχάνουμε βαθμολογία 0.93, με την πρώτη θέση στην κατάταξη των Αγγλικών σχολίων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A gyűlöletbeszéd elterjedése és a téves információ a közösségi médiában gyorsan veszélyt jelent a társadalomra nézve. A gyűlöletelterjesztő, ígéretes és elnyomásellenes üzenetek terjesztése egyedülálló alternatívává válik. Sajnos bonyolult jellege, valamint az ellenséges és semleges tartalomhoz képest viszonylag korlátozott megnyilvánulása miatt a Reményszó azonosítása kihívást jelent. Ez a munka a Hope Speech felismeréséről szól a Youtube megjegyzésekben, a Hope Speech Detection az egyenlőség, a sokszínűség és a befogadás érdekében. 0,93 pontszámot érünk el, az angol nyelvű kommentek listáján az első helyen.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>სოციალური მედიაში წარმოადგენების სიტყვების და შეცდომარების გაფართვა ძალიან გახდება საზოგადოებას. კომპლიმენტებით, განსხვავება მპატის განსხვავებას, საუბველობა და ანტი-დაბრუქებული შეტყობინებების განსხვავება იქნება უნიკალური ალტენტებით. მართლად, მისი კომპლექსი ნათობით და მისი პარამეტრებულად დაფარულებული მონაცემენტის შემდეგ საღირებელი და ნეიროლური შემდგომარებისთვის იდენტიფიკაცია იქნება განსაზღვ ეს სამუშაო მუშაოდ Youtube-ში მომენტებების მომენტების განახსნა, სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო განახსნა, განსხვავებას და დასაწყებას. ჩვენ მივიღეთ f-score 0.93, რომელიც 1 წერტილი ინგლისური კომენტრებებისთვის ლიდერბორეში.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>La proliferazione di discorsi d'odio e disinformazione nei social media sta rapidamente diventando una minaccia per la società. In complimento, la diffusione di messaggi di diffusione dell'odio, promettenti e anti-oppressivi diventa un'alternativa unica. Purtroppo, a causa della sua natura complessa e della manifestazione relativamente limitata rispetto ai contenuti ostili e neutri, l'identificazione del discorso della speranza diventa una sfida. Questo lavoro ruota intorno alla rilevazione del Speech di Speranza nei commenti di Youtube, per il compito condiviso sulla rilevazione del Speech di Speranza per uguaglianza, diversità e inclusione. Otteniamo un f-score di 0.93, posizionandoci 1 ° nella classifica per i commenti in inglese.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Nekenčiųjų kalbų plitimas ir neteisinga informacija social in ėje žiniasklaidoje greitai tampa grėsme visuomenei. Be to, neapykantą skleidžiančių, žadančių ir priešspaudinčių žinių sklaida tampa unikali alternatyva. Deja, dėl sudėtingo pobūdžio ir palyginti su priešišku ir neutraliu turiniu santykinai nedidelės manifestacijos Hope Speech nustatymas tampa iššūkiu. Šis darbas susijęs su Hope Speech Youtube komentaruose aptikimu, siekiant bendros užduoties, susijusios su Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity and Inclusion. We achieve an f-score of 0.93, ranking 1st on the leaderboard for English comments.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>The proliferation of Hate Speech and misinformation in social media is fast becoming a menace to society.  Како комплимент, ширењето на пораки против омразата, ветувачките и антиупресивните станува уникатна алтернатива. За жал, поради нејзината комплексна природа, како и релативно ограничена манифестирација во споредба со непријателската и неутралната содржина, идентификацијата на говорот на надежта станува предизвик. Оваа работа се врти околу откривањето на говорот на Хоуп на Јутјуб коментари, за заедничката задача за откривање на говорот на надеж за еднаквост, различност и вклучување. Ние постигнуваме ф-оценка од 0,93, рангирајќи се на првата на водечката табла за англиски коментари.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Жарамсыз сөйлеу және әлеуметтік медиақтардағы жарамсыз түрлендірудің көтерілуі жылдам қоғамдылығына қарсы болады. Түсініктемесімен, қарсылық тарқату, үміт беру және қарсылық хаттардың тарқатуы бірнеше альтернативті болды. Кешіріңіз, өзінің комплексті табиғаттың себебі және қарсы шектелген мазмұның салыстырылық мен нейтралды мазмұнымен салыстыру үшін, үміттік сөйлеудің идентификациясы мәселе Бұл жұмыс Юtub түсініктерінде, бірнеше тең, бірнеше және қатынау үшін Ортақ тапсырмалар үшін Ортақ тапсырмалар үшін Ортақ тапсырмасын анықтау үшін қайталады. Біз ағылшынша түсініктемелер үшін бірінші реттік батырмасында 0,93 f-нұсқасы жеткіздік.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ml>വെറുപ്പ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നതും തെറ്റായ വിവരങ്ങളും സാമൂഹിക മീഡിയില്‍ വെച്ച് വേഗത്തില്‍ സമൂഹത്തിന് ഒരു മാന് സമ്മതിക്കുമ്പോള്‍ വെറുപ്പുകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത്, വാഗ്ദാനം ചെയ്യുന്നതും പീഡിപ്പിക്കുന്ന സന്ദേശങ്ങള്‍ എതിര്‍ത് നിര്‍ഭാഗ്യവശാല്‍, അതിന്റെ പ്രകൃതിയാലും അതിന്റെ പ്രകൃതിയാലും ശത്രുക്കളുടെയും ന്യൂറലിന്റെയും ഉള്ളടക്കത്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചും പരിധിയുള്ള വ ഈ ജോലി യൂട്ടൂബിലെ പ്രതീക്ഷ സംസാരം കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നതിന് ചുറ്റും പ്രവര്‍ത്തിക്കുന്നു. പ്രതീക്ഷയുടെ പ്രസംഗം, സമവിഭാഗവും, വ്യത്യാസ നമ്മള്‍ 0.93 ന്റെ ഫ്രോക്ക് എത്തുന്നു. ആദ്യത്തെ നേതാവില്‍ നിന്നും ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് കാര്യങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് വേണ്ടി റാങ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-proliferazzjoni ta’ diskors ta’ mibegħda u informazzjoni ħa żin a fil-midja soċjali qed isiru malajr theddida għas-soċjetà. B’kompliment, it-tixrid ta’ messaġġi li jxerrdu l-mibegħda, promettenti u kontra l-oppressjoni jsir alternattiva unika. Sfortunatament, minħabba n-natura kumplessa tiegħu kif ukoll minħabba l-manifestazzjoni relattivament limitata meta mqabbla mal-kontenut ostili u newtrali, l-identifikazzjoni tal-Speech tat-Tpera ssir sfida. Dan ix-xogħol idur madwar id-detezzjoni ta’ Speech of Hope f’kummenti fuq Youtube, għat-Task Konġunt dwar l-Iskopru ta’ Speech of Hope għall-Ugwaljanza, id-Diversità, u l-Inklużjoni. Aħna nilħqu punteġġ f ta’ 0.93, u nqasmu l-ewwel fuq it-tabella ewlenija għall-kummenti Ingliżi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Perluasan ucapan kebencian dan salah maklumat dalam media sosial cepat menjadi ancaman bagi masyarakat. Sebagai pujian, penyebaran mesej pembenci, berjanji dan anti-menekan menjadi alternatif unik. Malangnya, disebabkan sifat kompleks dan demonstrasi relatif terbatas dibandingkan dengan kandungan musuh dan neutral, pengenalan Speech Harapan menjadi cabaran. Kerja ini berputar-putar sekitar pengesan Speech Hope dalam komentar Youtube, untuk Tugas Berkongsi pengesan Speech Hope untuk Persamaan, Perbezaan, dan Inclusion. Kami mencapai skor f 0.93, peringkat pertama di papan pemimpin untuk komentar Inggeris.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_no>Utvidelsen av hatespråk og feilformasjon i sosiale medier er raskt å bli ein mengd til samfunnet. I kompliment blir disseminasjonen av hate-diffusion, promessande og anti-oppressive meldingar ein unikt alternativ. Dessverre, på grunn av komplekse natur og relativt begrenset manifestasjon i sammenligning med hostile og nøytralt innhald, blir identifikasjonen av håpetspråk eit utfordring. Dette arbeidet går rundt oppdaginga av håp-tale i Youtube-kommentarar, for delt oppgåve om håp-taleoppdaging for likhet, diversitet og inkludering. Vi oppnår ein f-poeng med 0,93, som rankerer f ørste på lederbordet for engelske kommentarar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Rozprzestrzenianie się mowy nienawiści i dezinformacji w mediach społecznościowych szybko staje się zagrożeniem dla społeczeństwa. W uznaniu rozpowszechnianie nienawiści, obiecujących i anty-opresyjnych przesłań staje się wyjątkową alternatywą. Niestety, ze względu na jego złożony charakter oraz stosunkowo ograniczoną manifestację w porównaniu do wrogiej i neutralnej treści, identyfikacja Mowy Nadziei staje się wyzwaniem. Praca ta koncentruje się wokół wykrywania mowy nadziei w komentarzach Youtube, dla wspólnego zadania wykrywania mowy nadziei dla równości, różnorodności i integracji. Osiągamy wynik f 0.93, zajmując pierwsze miejsce w rankingu angielskich komentarzy.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Нийгмийн мэдээллийн хувьд үзэн ядуурлын яриа, буруу хэлбэрүүдийн нэмэлт нь нийгэмд хурдан аюултай болж байна. Баярлалаа, үзэн ядах, амлах, хүчирхийллийн эсрэг сэтгэл хөдлөл нь нэг өөрчлөлт болж байна. Харамсалтай нь түүний комплекс байгаль болон харьцангуй хязгаарлагдсан харилцааны харьцангуй хоорондоо хоорондоо хоорондоо хоорондоо хоорондоо хоорондоо хоорондоо хоорондоо хоорондоо хоорондоо хооронд Энэ ажил Youtube-д итгэл найдварын яриаг олохын тулд, итгэл найдварын ярианы талаар тэнцүү байдал, олон төрлийн, нэмэлт гэх мэт хуваалцагдсан ажил. Бид 0.93-ийн f-тоо хүртэл, Англи хэл дээр англи хэлэлцээний удирдагч дээр 1-р ангид байдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Proliferarea discursului de ură și dezinformare în rețelele sociale devin rapid o amenințare pentru societate. În compliment, diseminarea mesajelor care difuzează ura, promițătoare și anti-opresive devin o alternativă unică. Din păcate, datorită naturii sale complexe, precum și a manifestării relativ limitate în comparație cu conținutul ostil și neutru, identificarea Speech Hope devine o provocare. Această lucrare se învârte în jurul detectării discursului speranței în comentariile Youtube, pentru sarcina partajată privind detectarea discursului speranței pentru egalitate, diversitate și incluziune. Obținem un scor f de 0.93, clasamentul 1 în clasament pentru comentariile în limba engleză.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Proširenje govora mržnje i pogrešne informacije u društvenim medijima brzo postaje opasnost društvu. U komplimentu, širenje mržnje-širenja, obećavajućih i protivnotežavajućih poruka postaje jedinstvena alternativa. Nažalost, zbog složene prirode, kao i relativno ograničene manifestacije u usporedbi s neprijateljskim i neutralnim sadržajem, identifikacija govora nade postaje izazov. Ovaj rad se okreće oko otkrivanja govora nade u komentarima Youtube, za zajednički zadatak o otkrivanju govora nade za jednakost, raznolikost i uključenje. Postigli smo f-rezultat 0,93, prvi red na vodećoj tabli za engleske komentare.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>සාමාජික මාධ්‍යමත්වයේ විශාලනය සහ වැරැද්ධ විශාලනය සාමාජිකයට ප්‍රතිචාරයක් වෙනවා. සම්පූර්ණයෙන්, ප්‍රශ්නයක්, ප්‍රශ්නයක්, ප්‍රශ්නයක් සහ ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් වෙනස් වෙනුවෙන් වෙන අවාසනාවෙන්න, එයාගේ සංශ්‍ය ස්වභාවිතය සහ සමාන්‍යයෙන්ම සීමාවිත ප්‍රදේශය සඳහා විරුද්ධ සහ නිර්දේශ සාමාන්ත්‍රය සමඟ මේ වැඩය යුටුබුවේ හොයාගන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් හොයාගන්න, හොයාගන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් සඳහා සාමාන්‍ය වැඩක් සඳහා සාමාන්‍ය විශ්වාස ස්ථා අපි ඉංග්‍රීසි කිරීම් සඳහා පළවෙනි ප්‍රමාණයක් තියෙන්නේ.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Hadal nacayb ah iyo macluumaad khaldan oo ku saabsan shabakadda bulshada ayaa si dhaqso ah u noqdaya bulshada. Isbuuxsano, kala soocmaalidda cadaawayaasha, ballanqaadka iyo farriinta ka geesta ah ee cadaawayaashu waxay noqdeen alternati aan kala duwan. Nasiib xumaatooyinkiisa adag darteed iyo muuqashada qaraabada ee la xiriira cadaawayaasha iyo waxyaabaha neutriga ah, aqoonsashada hadalka rajada waxay noqotaa dhibaato. This work revolves around the detection of Hope Speech in Youtube comments, for the Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion.  Waxaynu helnaa koox 0.93 oo lagu sameynayo hogaamiyaha ugu horeeyay afka ingiriisiga comments.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>வெறுப்பு பேச்சின் வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் சமூக ஊடகங்களில் தவறான தகவல்கள் வேகமாக சமூகத்திற்கு ஒரு முன்னேறும். பிரச்சனையில், வெறுப்பு வெளிப்பாடு, வாக்குறுதி மற்றும் அச்சுறுத்தல் செய்திகள் வெளிப்பாடு ஒரு தனிப்பட்ட மா துரதிர்ஷ்டவசமாக, அதன் சிக்கலான இயற்கையினாலும் மற்றும் சார்ந்த வரையறையினாலும் எதிர்பார்ப்பு மற்றும் நியுயமான உள்ளடக்கங்களை ஒப்பிடு இந்த வேலை நம்ப பேச்சை கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்கு சுற்றியுள்ளது, யூட்பி குறிப்புகளில், நம்ப ப பேச்சு பேச்சு கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்கு, சமம், வேறுபாடு,  நாம் 0.93 புள்ளியை பெறுகிறோம், ஆங்கிலத்தின் குறிப்புகளுக்கு தலைப்புபலகையில் தலைமுறையில் முதல் வரி</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>سراسر میڈیا میں دشمنی بات اور غلطی کی گھیر گھیر جاتی ہے کہ سراسر جامعہ کے لئے ایک خطرہ ہو جاتا ہے. تعریف کے ساتھ، نفرت کے پھیلانے، وعدہ دینے اور ظلم کرنے والی پیغامات کا پھیلانا ایک الفاظ بن گیا ہے۔ بدبختی، اس کی پیچیدہ طبیعت کے باعث اور مقابلہ مقدار محدود ظاہر کے باعث دشمنی اور ناکامی موجود کے مقابلہ میں، امید کی بات کی شناسایی ایک چال ہو جاتی ہے. یہ کام یوٹیوب میں آرزوؤں کی بات کی تلاش کی اطلاعات کے اطراف میں گھیر جاتی ہے، برابر، مختلف اور انشام کے لئے شریک ٹاکس کے لئے۔ ہم 0.93 کے f-اسکور پہنچ رہے ہیں، انگلیسی ٹیپورٹوں کے لئے لیڈربورڈ پر پہلی مرتبہ پہنچ رہے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_sv>Spridningen av hattal och desinformation i sociala medier håller snabbt på att bli ett hot mot samhället. Som komplimang blir spridningen av hatspridande, lovande och anti-förtryckande budskap ett unikt alternativ. Tyvärr blir identifieringen av Hope Speech en utmaning på grund av dess komplexa natur och den relativt begränsade manifestationen jämfört med fientligt och neutralt innehåll. Detta arbete kretsar kring upptäckt av Hope Speech i Youtube kommentarer, för den delade uppgiften om Hope Speech Detection för jämställdhet, mångfald och inkludering. Vi uppnår en f-poäng på 0,93, rankad 1:a på rankningslistan för engelska kommentarer.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_uz>Name Ko'pchilik paytda, yolg'on va ta'minlovchi xabarlarni ajratish o'zgarishni o'zgartirish o'zgartiradi. Unfortunately, due to its complex nature as well as the relatively limited manifestation in comparison to hostile and neutral content, the identification of Hope Speech becomes a challenge.  Name Biz ingliz izohlari uchun boshqaruvchidagi boshqaruvchida 0.93 darajaga o'tganmiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Sự gia tăng ngôn ngữ căm ghét và thông tin sai lầm trên các phương tiện xã hội đang trở thành mối đe dọa cho xã hội. Để khen ngợi, sự truyền bá thù hận, đầy hứa hẹn và không áp bức trở thành một lựa chọn độc đáo. Thật không may, do bản chất phức tạp của nó cũng như sự hiện diện tương đối giới hạn so với nội dung thù địch và trung lập, nhận diện hy vọng Ngôn trở thành một thử thách. Việc này xoay quanh việc phát hiện hy vọng Ngôn ngữ trong câu nói của Youtube, cho tập đoàn "Việc phát hiện" về hy vọng về nói chuyện về bình đẳng, đa dạng, và tham gia. Chúng ta đạt được điểm danh 0.93, thứ nhất trên bảng xếp hạng để ghi chú tiếng Anh.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Разпространението на речта на омразата и дезинформацията в социалните медии бързо се превръща в заплаха за обществото. В комплимент разпространението на разпространяващи омраза, обещаващи и антипотиснически послания се превръща в уникална алтернатива. За съжаление, поради сложната си природа, както и относително ограничената проява в сравнение с враждебно и неутрално съдържание, идентифицирането на речта на Надеждата се превръща в предизвикателство. Тази работа се върти около откриването на речта на надеждата в коментарите на споделената задача за откриване на речта на надеждата за равенство, многообразие и приобщаване. Постигнахме f-резултат от 0.93, класирайки се на първо място в класацията за английски коментари.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Proširenje govora mržnje i pogrešne informacije u društvenim medijima brzo postaje opasnost društvu. Uz kompliment, širenje mržnje-širenja, obećavajućih i protivnotežavajućih poruka postaje jedinstvena alternativa. Nažalost, zbog složene prirode, kao i relativno ograničene manifestacije u usporedbi s neprijateljskim i neutralnim sadržajem, identifikacija govora nade postaje izazov. Ovaj rad se okreće oko otkrivanja govora nade u komentarima Youtube, za zajednički zadatak o otkrivanju govora nade za jednakost, raznolikost i uključenje. Postigli smo f-rezultat 0,93, na prvom mjestu na vodećoj tabli za engleske komentare.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Spredningen af hadefuldtale og misinformation i sociale medier er hurtigt ved at blive en trussel for samfundet. Som kompliment bliver udbredelsen af had-spredende, lovende og anti-undertrykkende budskaber et unikt alternativ. På grund af dets komplekse natur samt den relativt begrænsede manifestation i forhold til fjendtligt og neutralt indhold bliver identifikationen af Hope Speech desværre en udfordring. Dette arbejde drejer sig om detektering af Hope Speech i Youtube kommentarer, til delt opgave om håb Speech Detection for lighed, mangfoldighed og inklusion. Vi opnår en f-score på 0,93 og rangerer 1. på ranglisten for engelske kommentarer.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>De proliferatie van haatspraak en misinformatie in sociale media wordt snel een bedreiging voor de samenleving. Als compliment wordt de verspreiding van haatverspreidende, veelbelovende en anti-onderdrukkende boodschappen een uniek alternatief. Helaas wordt het identificeren van Hope Speech vanwege de complexe aard en de relatief beperkte manifestatie in vergelijking met vijandige en neutrale inhoud een uitdaging. Dit werk draait om de detectie van Hope Speech in Youtube commentaren, voor de Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity en Inclusion. We behalen een f-score van 0.93, met als eerste plaats op het klassement voor Engelse commentaren.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Perluasan pembicaraan kebencian dan informasi salah dalam media sosial cepat menjadi ancaman bagi masyarakat. Dalam pujian, penyebaran pesan-pesan kebencian yang menyebar, berjanji dan anti-oppressif menjadi alternatif unik. Sayangnya, karena sifat kompleks dan demonstrasi relatif terbatas dibandingkan dengan konten musuh dan netral, identifikasi Hope Speech menjadi tantangan. This work revolves around the detection of Hope Speech in Youtube comments, for the Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion.  Kami mencapai nilai f 0,93, peringkat pertama di papan pemimpin untuk komentar Inggris.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Die Verbreitung von Hassreden und Fehlinformationen in sozialen Medien wird schnell zu einer Bedrohung für die Gesellschaft. Als Kompliment wird die Verbreitung hasserverbreitender, vielversprechender und anti-repressiver Botschaften zu einer einzigartigen Alternative. Leider wird die Identifikation von Hope Speech aufgrund ihrer Komplexität sowie der relativ begrenzten Manifestation im Vergleich zu feindlichen und neutralen Inhalten zu einer Herausforderung. Diese Arbeit dreht sich um die Erkennung von Hope Speech in Youtube Kommentaren, für die gemeinsame Aufgabe zur Hope Speech Detection für Gleichheit, Vielfalt und Inklusion. Wir erreichen eine f-Punktzahl von 0.93 und belegen damit den ersten Platz in der Bestenliste für englische Kommentare.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>소셜미디어에서 혐오 발언과 잘못된 정보의 확산이 사회에 대한 위협으로 급부상하고 있다.칭찬으로 증오, 희망, 반압박의 메시지를 퍼뜨리는 것이 독특한 선택이 되었다.불행하게도 복잡한 성격과 적대적이고 중립적인 내용에 비해 상대적으로 제한된 표현 형식 때문에 강연의 식별이 도전이 되기를 바란다.이 작업은 Youtube 댓글의 희망 음성 검출을 둘러싸고 평등하고 다양하며 포용적인 희망 음성 검출 공유 임무를 실현하기 위한 것이다.우리의 f 점수는 0.93으로 영어 평론 랭킹 1위에 올랐다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>گسترش سخنرانی از نفرت و تغییر دادن در رسانه های اجتماعی سریع به جامعه خطر می شود. توسط تعریف، گسترش پیام های متنفر، قول دادن و ضد ظلم کننده یک انتخاب متفاوتی تبدیل می شود. متاسفانه، به دلیل طبیعت پیچیده‌اش و نسبتا محدودیت در مقایسه با محتوای دشمنی و ناتوانی، شناسایی سخنرانی امید یک چالش می‌شود. این کار در اطراف کشف سخنرانی امید در یوتیوب، برای کشف مشترک سخنرانی امید برای عدالت، مختلف و شامل است. ما به یک امتیاز f-score 0.93 رسیدیم که در صفحه اول در صفحه رهبر برای توضیح انگلیسی است.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Nötünç sözleriniň ýagdaýynyň we sosyal mediýalarynda ýalňyşlyk döwletleriniň ýagdaýynyň azalyşynyň jemgyýeti üçin tehdit bolup geçýär. Tebrikler bolsa, ýigrenýän-döwletleriniň a çylygy, söz bermegi we basygly mesajlaryň açylygy beýleki bir seçenek bolup başlaýar. Gynansakda, öz karmaşık tebigatynyň we düşman we neutral maglumaty bilen görä relativ çykyş görünüşleri sebäbi umyt dilini tanyşdyrmak kynçylyk bolar. Bu iş Youtube'da umyt sözleriniň esasy tarapyndan, beýleki sözleriniň beýleki sözleriniň esasy üçin beýleki zady tarapyndan çykarýar. Biz 0,93-njy f अंतर taýýarlapdyk, iňlisçe terjimeler üçin 1-nji derejä taýýarlapdyk.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Kuongezeka kwa Hotuba ya Hati na taarifa zisizo za uovu katika mitandao ya kijamii kwa haraka inageuka kuwa mtazamo wa jamii. Kwa heshima, kusambaza ujumbe wa kuchochea chuki, kuahidi na kupinga ukandamizaji ulikuwa mbadala wa kipekee. Kwa bahati mbaya, kwa sababu ya asili yake ya tatizo pamoja na ilani yenye kiwango kidogo ukilinganisha na maudhui ya maadui na asili ya katikati, utambulisho wa Hope Speech unakuwa changamoto. Kazi hii inazungumzia kutambua Hope Hope Hope katika maoni ya Youtube, kwa ajili ya Tamko la Kuhusu Hotuba Kutafuta Usawa, Utawala na Kujumuisha. Tunaweza kupata nafasi ya 0.93, yenye rangi ya kwanza kwenye kiongozi wa Kiingereza kwa maoni ya Kiingereza.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Die uitbreiding van Hate Speech en verkeerde formasie in sosiale media is vinnig om 'n menas te word aan samelewing. In kompliment word die verspreiding van haat-verspreiding, belofte en anti-verdrukking boodskappe 'n unieke alternatief geword. Ongelukkig, vanweë sy kompleks natuur en die relativies beperkte manifestasie in vergelyking met teëstandige en neutrale inhoud, word die identifikasie van hoop spreek 'n uitdrukking. Hierdie werk vertrek rondom die opdekking van hoop spreek in Youtube kommentaar, vir die deelde taak op hoop spreek opdekking vir gelykheid, Diversiteit en Inklusie. Ons bereik 'n f-telling van 0.93, ranking 1 op die leierbord vir Engels kommentaar.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Përhapja e fjalës së urrejtjes dhe keqinformimi në mediat shoqërore po bëhet shpejt një kërcënim për shoqërinë. Në kompliment, shpërndarja e mesazheve kundër urrejtjes, premtuese dhe kundërshtuese bëhet një alternativë unike. Fatkeqësisht, për shkak të natyrës së saj komplekse si dhe manifestimit relativisht të kufizuar në krahasim me përmbajtjen armike dhe neutrale, identifikimi i Fjalës së Shpresës bëhet një sfidë. This work revolves around the detection of Hope Speech in Youtube comments, for the Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion.  Ne arrijmë një pikë-f prej 0.93, renditjen e parë në tabelën kryesore për komentet angleze.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>የጥል ንግግር እና የስሕተት መረጃዎች በማኅበራዊ አውታር ላይ ፈጥኖ ለማኅበራዊ ጉዳይ ሆነዋል፡፡ በጥላቻ፣ ተስፋ የሚያደርጉና የሚያስጨንቀውን መልእክት በማፍረስ የተለየ መመለስ ሆነዋል፡፡ በተቃራኒ እና በጥላቻ እና የውይይት ውይይት በማስተካከል፣ በተጨማሪው ግንኙነት እና በተቃራኒ ግንኙነት ምክንያት የተስፋ ንግግር ማረጋገጥ ጥቃት ሆነዋል፡፡ This work revolves around the detection of Hope Speech in Youtube comments, for the Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion.  በንግግሊዝኛ ትርጓሜዎች ላይ የመጀመሪያውን የ.93 ነጥብ አግኝተናል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>সামাজিক প্রচার মাধ্যমে ঘৃণা ভাষার বৃদ্ধি এবং ভুল তথ্য দ্রুত সমাজের প্রতি প্রতিষ্ঠান হয়ে যাচ্ছে। সম্মানে ঘৃণা ব্যবহার, প্রতিশ্রুতি এবং অত্যাচার বিরুদ্ধে বার্তা প্রকাশ করার বিকল্প হয়ে গেছে। দুর্ভাগ্যবশতঃ তার জটিল প্রকৃতির কারণে এবং তাদের শত্রুতা এবং নিরপেক্ষ বিষয়বস্তুর তুলনায় সীমিত প্রকাশের কারণে আশা বিষয়টির পরিচয় চ্যাল এই কাজ ইউটিউবে হোপ বক্তৃতা আবিষ্কারের চারপাশে প্রতিষ্ঠিত হয়েছে, আশা ভাষণের জন্য সামান্য, বৈষম্য এবং অন্তর্ভুক্ত করার জন্য। ইংরেজি মন্তব্যের জন্য নেতৃবোর্ডে প্রথম র‍্যাঙ্কিং হয়েছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Հատելու ելույթի տարածումը և սխալ տեղեկատվությունը սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցներում արագ դառնում է հասարակության համար վտանգ: Փորձառությամբ, ատելություն տարածող, խոստացնող և հակաճնշող հաղորդագրությունների տարածումը դարձնում է յուրահատուկ այլընտրանք: Unfortunately, due to its complex nature as well as the relatively limited manifestation in comparison to hostile and neutral content, the identification of Hope Speech becomes a challenge.  This work revolves around the detection of Hope Speech in Youtube comments, for the Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion.  Մենք հասնում ենք 0.93-ի f-գնահատականի, որը առաջին գնահատականն է անգլերեն մեկնաբանությունների համար:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Sosyal media içində nifrət sözünün və yanlışlıqlarının genişlənməsi tezliklə toplumğa tehdit edir. Tərəbbürlük olaraq, nifrət-fəsad yayılması, vəd vermək və təcavüzlük müqabilində istifadə edən ismarışların təkrar bir alternatifi oldu. Maalesef ki, onun kompleks təbiətinin və düşmənçilik və nötrəlik məlumatlarının qarşısında relativi sınırlı göstərilməsinin səbəbi umut sözünün tanıması çətinliklərə bənzəyir. Bu işin Youtube'da Hope Speech'in keşfini, İkinlik, Müxtəlif və İnşallarının paylaşılmış Özünün Özünü keşfetməsi üçün təşkil edir. Biz 0.93 dəf ə f-score tapırıq, İngilizce şəhadətləri üçün ilk dəfə liderboarda.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>La proliferació del discurs d'odi i la mala informació dels mitjans socials s'està convertint ràpidament en una mena per a la societat. En compliment, la disseminació de missatges anti-opressius i difusius de l'odi es converteix en una alternativa única. Malauradament, a causa de la seva complexitat i de la manifestació relativament limitada en comparació amb continguts hostils i neutrals, l'identificació de l'Hope Speech es converteix en un repte. Aquesta feina gira al voltant de la detecció de Hope Speech a Youtube comentaris, per la Task Shared on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion. Obtenim una puntuació f de 0,93, la primera a la taula principal per comentaris anglesos.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Šíření nenávisti a dezinformací v sociálních médiích se rychle stává hrozbou pro společnost. Šíření nenávistných, slibných a protiutlačujících sdělení se stává jedinečnou alternativou. Bohužel vzhledem k jeho složité povaze a relativně omezenému projevu ve srovnání s nepřátelským a neutrálním obsahem se identifikace řeči naděje stává výzvou. Tato práce se zabývá detekcí řeči naděje v komentářích Youtube pro sdílený úkol detekce řeči naděje pro rovnost, rozmanitost a inkluzi. V žebříčku pro anglické komentáře dosahujeme f-skóre 0.93.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Vihakõne ja valeinformatsiooni levik sotsiaalmeedias on kiiresti muutumas ühiskonnale ohuks. Komplimendiks muutub vihkamist levivate, paljutõotavate ja rõhuvastaste sõnumite levitamine ainulaadseks alternatiiviks. Kahjuks muutub Lootuskõne identifitseerimine väljakutseks nii keerulise olemuse kui ka suhteliselt piiratud avaldumise tõttu vaenuliku ja neutraalse sisuga võrreldes. Käesolev töö keskendub lootuskõne tuvastamisele Youtube kommentaarides lootuskõne tuvastamisele võrdsuse, mitmekesisuse ja kaasatuse jaoks. Me saavutame f-skoori 0,93, edetabelis esimese koha inglise kommentaaride osas.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>Proširenje govora mržnje i pogrešne informacije u društvenim medijima brzo postaje opasnost društvu. Uz kompliment, širenje mržnje-širenja, obećavajućih i protivnotežavajućih poruka postaje jedinstvena alternativa. Nažalost, zbog složene prirode, kao i relativno ograničene manifestacije u usporedbi s neprijateljskim i neutralnim sadržajem, identifikacija govora nade postaje izazov. Ovaj rad se okreće oko otkrivanja govora nade u komentarima Youtube, za zajednički zadatak o otkrivanju govora nade za jednakost, raznolikost i uključenje. Postigli smo f-rezultat 0,93, na prvom mjestu na vodećoj tabli za engleske komentare.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_fi>Vihanpuheen ja väärän tiedon leviäminen sosiaalisessa mediassa on nopeasti muuttumassa uhkaksi yhteiskunnalle. Vihaa levittävien, lupaavien ja sortoa vastustavien viestien levittämisestä tulee ainutlaatuinen vaihtoehto. Valitettavasti Toivopuheen tunnistaminen muuttuu haasteeksi monimutkaisen luonteensa ja suhteellisen rajallisen ilmentymisen vuoksi vihamieliseen ja neutraaliin sisältöön verrattuna. Tämä työ keskittyy toivopuheen havaitsemiseen Youtube-kommenteissa tasa-arvon, monimuotoisuuden ja osallisuuden toivopuheen tunnistamista käsittelevään yhteiseen tehtävään. Saavutamme f-pisteen 0,93, sijoittuen ykköseksi englanninkielisten kommenttien tulostaulukossa.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Tatanan kanggo ngilanggar Kasunyatan lan sumelang kuwi media sotiki iki dadi kapan kuwi nggawe ngupakakan kanggo cebadhakan Awak dhéwé sing komplit, kuwi tindah kejahatan wis nguasai, njuk-uwong lan kelas anti-alam sing gawe jiné Alternate. Nglanggar-langgar, dadi kapan langgar sampeyan wigatining ketahan karo perusahaan langgar sampeyan karo perusahaan dumadhi karo ingkang nesaturan karo iso nggawe tarjamahan, kedanguasai Panjenengan langgar Awakdhéwé iki bakal nggawe gerambut nang nggawe Panjenengan Espee Kemerdekaan ning YouTube komentar, kanggo nggawe Tarjamahan nggo Espee Kemerdekaan kanggo Kebebasan, Daerahing lan Inclusyon. Awak dhéwé iso nglanggar f-toles sing 0.9, dadi 1 ing barang kanggo nyengké Inggris barang.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Širjenje sovražnega govora in napačnih informacij v družbenih medijih hitro postaja grožnja za družbo. Razširjanje sporočil, ki širijo sovraštvo, obetavnih in proti zatiranju, postane edinstvena alternativa. Žal zaradi svoje kompleksne narave in relativno omejene manifestacije v primerjavi s sovražnimi in nevtralnimi vsebinami identifikacija govora upanja postane izziv. Delo se vrti okoli odkrivanja govora upanja v komentarjih Youtube za skupno nalogo o odkrivanju govora upanja za enakost, raznolikost in vključevanje. Dosegli smo f-rezultat 0,93 in se uvrstili na prvo mesto na lestvici lestvic za angleške komentarje.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Kifo-faɗin magana na Hati da data na ƙarya a cikin mitandai na jamii yana kasancẽwa ta zama mazaunin jamii. Ga da cikakken, salon da za'a rarrabe haske, wa'adi da ake yi wa'adi da kuma a kange-isticmi, za'a zama wata dabam'a mai dabam. Babu'am, dõmin da mazauninsa mai adadi da kuma da nuni wanda ya ƙayyade shi yana sammeni da tsarin da ke haɗi da takarda da tsakanin-tsammani, shaidar hotai na Hope zai kasance wata tsãwa. Wannan aikin yana tafiyar da bayani na gano Hope Spelling in Youtube, dõmin the Shared Tafiyar da Kyaushe na Hope Spelling for Eawa, Diversity, da Inclusion. Muna sami wani f-score na 0.93, mai ranar ta kwanza a kan shaidar ayukan Ingiriya.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>ההתפשטות של נאום השנאה והמידע הלא נכון בתקשורת חברתית הופכת מהר לאיום לחברה. בתור מחמאה, ההפיצה של הודעות שנאה-מפוצצות, מבטיחות ואנטי-דיכאות הופכות לאחרונה מיוחדת. למרבה הצער, בגלל הטבע המורכב שלה וגם ההופעה המגובלת יחסית בהשוואה לתוכן עוין ונטרלי, זיהוי נאום הופך לאתגר. העבודה הזו מסתובבת סביב גילוי נאום הופ בתגובות יוטיוב, עבור המשימה המשותפת על גילוי נאום הופ לשוואות, שוויון, ושילוב. אנחנו משיגים נקודת F של 0.93, מדרגה ראשונה על הלוח המנהיג עבור הערות אנגלית.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་དྲ་ཐོག་གི་རྗེས་འདས་པ་དང་འགྱུར་རྒྱུན་མེད་དུ་ཆེ་འཕྱུར་མྱུར་སོང་། གསལ་རྗེས་སུ་ཕོག་པའི་གནད་དོན་འགྱུར་བ་ཞིག་ཡིན་པའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་རིས་གཞན་ཞིག་ཆགས་པ་རེད། ཡིན་ནའང་མི་མངོན་གསལ་བོ་ཞིག་དང་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་པའི་རང་བཞིན་སྒྲིག་རྒྱུ་བྱས་ན། རྩ་བ་སྐྱེས་པའི་ནང་དོན་དང་ཐད་ཀར་བ་བསྐྱེད་པའི་ནང་དོན་དང This work revolves around the detection of Hope Speech in Youtube comments, for the Shared Task on Hope Speech Detection for Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion. ང་ཚོས་དབྱིན་ཡིག་ཅིག་གི་འགོ་བཙུགས་སྐབས་ཀྱི་ཨང་ཀིའི་ཚད་དང་ཨང་ཀི་འགོ་བཙུགས་ཐུབ་པ་ཡིན།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="25">
      <title>NLP-CUET@LT-EDI-EACL2021 : Multilingual Code-Mixed Hope Speech Detection using Cross-lingual Representation Learner<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>CUET</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>LT</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EDI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Multilingual Code-Mixed Hope Speech Detection using Cross-lingual Representation Learner</title>
      <author><first>Eftekhar</first><last>Hossain</last></author>
      <author><first>Omar</first><last>Sharif</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammed Moshiul</first><last>Hoque</last></author>
      <pages>168–174</pages>
      <abstract>In recent years, several systems have been developed to regulate the spread of negativity and eliminate aggressive, offensive or abusive contents from the online platforms. Nevertheless, a limited number of researches carried out to identify positive, encouraging and supportive contents. In this work, our goal is to identify whether a social media post / comment contains hope speech or not. We propose three distinct models to identify hope speech in English, Tamil and Malayalam language to serve this purpose. To attain this goal, we employed various machine learning (SVM, LR, ensemble), deep learning (CNN+BiLSTM) and transformer (m-BERT, Indic-BERT, XLNet, XLM-R) based methods. Results indicate that XLM-R outdoes all other techniques by gaining a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weighted_arithmetic_mean">weighted f_1-score</a> of 0.93, 0.60 and 0.85 respectively for English, Tamil and Malayalam language. Our team has achieved 1st, 2nd and 1st rank in these three <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a> respectively.</abstract>
      <url hash="11b16ff6">2021.ltedi-1.25</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="53b2858d">2021.ltedi-1.25.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>hossain-etal-2021-nlp-cuet</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/eftekhar-hossain/CUET_NLP-EACL_2021" additional="false">eftekhar-hossain/CUET_NLP-EACL_2021</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="28">
      <title>Spartans@LT-EDI-EACL2021 : Inclusive Speech Detection using Pretrained Language Models<fixed-case>LT</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EDI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Inclusive Speech Detection using Pretrained Language Models</title>
      <author><first>Megha</first><last>Sharma</last></author>
      <author><first>Gaurav</first><last>Arora</last></author>
      <pages>188–192</pages>
      <abstract>We describe our system that ranked first in Hope Speech Detection (HSD) shared task and fourth in Offensive Language Identification (OLI) shared task, both in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil language</a>. The goal of HSD and OLI is to identify if a code-mixed comment or post contains hope speech or offensive content respectively. We pre-train a transformer-based model RoBERTa using synthetically generated code-mixed data and use it in an ensemble along with their pre-trained ULMFiT model available from iNLTK.</abstract>
      <url hash="0c7a2996">2021.ltedi-1.28</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="6b9ae7c3">2021.ltedi-1.28.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>sharma-arora-2021-spartans</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>