<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.triton">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2022-01-11">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Translation and Interpreting Technology Online Conference</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ruslan</first><last>Mitkov</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Vilelmini</first><last>Sosoni</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Julie Christine</first><last>Giguère</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elena</first><last>Murgolo</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Deysel</last></editor>
      <publisher>INCOMA Ltd.</publisher>
      <address>Held Online</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="26951116">2021.triton-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="df7cadab">2021.triton-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>triton-2021-translation</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Remote Interpreting : Platform Testing in a University Setting</title>
      <author><first>Francesco</first><last>Saina</last></author>
      <pages>57–67</pages>
      <abstract>This work is based on the testing of a remote interpreting (RI) delivery platform conducted a year before the disruptive COVID-19 pandemic outbreak, and aimed at assessing the use and experience of such systems in a university setting. A survey was administered to the different groups of users (interpreters, audience, and speakers) involved in two tests to collect their responses and remarks, and assess trends and perceptions in their experience. According to emerging findings of the research project, RI was already considered to be an indisputable yet burgeoning resource for conference settings with potential convenience and benefits for each group of users. However, participants’ remarks early suggested that all the parties involved in the industry need to collaborate to effectively improve and enhance such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Service_(economics)">services</a>. Specific training on RI modalities would also appear to be increasingly necessary for interpreters to adapt to new raising working conditions and meet a thriving demandand training institutions would ever more have to offer adequate solutions, while this technological shift also requires receptiveness and adaptability to an abruptly diversifying and evolving profession.</abstract>
      <url hash="5110b92c">2021.triton-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>saina-2021-remote</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>SmarTerp : A CAI System to Support Simultaneous Interpreters in Real-Time<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>mar<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>erp: A <fixed-case>CAI</fixed-case> System to Support Simultaneous Interpreters in Real-Time</title>
      <author><first>Susana</first><last>Rodriguez</last></author>
      <author><first>Roberto</first><last>Gretter</last></author>
      <author><first>Marco</first><last>Matassoni</last></author>
      <author><first>Alvaro</first><last>Alonso</last></author>
      <author><first>Oscar</first><last>Corcho</last></author>
      <author><first>Mariano</first><last>Rico</last></author>
      <author><first>Falavigna</first><last>Daniele</last></author>
      <pages>102–109</pages>
      <abstract>We present a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> to support simultaneous interpreting in specific domains. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is going to be developed through a strong synergy among technicians, mostly experts on both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_processing">speech and text processing</a>, and end-users, i.e. professional interpreters who define the requirements and will test the final product. Some preliminary encouraging results have been achieved on benchmark tests collected with the aim of measuring the performance of single components of the whole system, namely : automatic speech recognition (ASR) and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named-entity_recognition">named entity recognition</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="6cd7adf7">2021.triton-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>rodriguez-etal-2021-smarterp</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Sign Language Translation in a Healthcare Setting</title>
      <author><first>Floris</first><last>Roelofsen</last></author>
      <author><first>Lyke</first><last>Esselink</last></author>
      <author><first>Shani</first><last>Mende-Gillings</last></author>
      <author><first>Anika</first><last>Smeijers</last></author>
      <pages>110–124</pages>
      <abstract>Communication between healthcare professionals and deaf patients is challenging, and the current COVID-19 pandemic makes this issue even more acute. Sign language interpreters can often not enter hospitals and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Face_mask">face masks</a> make <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lip_reading">lipreading</a> impossible. To address this urgent problem, we developed a system which allows healthcare professionals to translate sentences that are frequently used in the diagnosis and treatment of COVID-19 into Sign Language of the Netherlands (NGT). Translations are displayed by means of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_clip">videos</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avatar_(computing)">avatar animations</a>. The architecture of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is such that it could be extended to other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software">applications</a> and other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_language">sign languages</a> in a relatively straightforward way.</abstract>
      <url hash="4eecfce4">2021.triton-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>roelofsen-etal-2021-sign</bibkey>
    <title_ar>ترجمة لغة الإشارة في أحد إعدادات الرعاية الصحية</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Traduction en langue des signes dans un établissement de santé</title_fr>
      <title_es>Traducción de lenguaje de señas en un entorno sanitario</title_es>
      <title_pt>Tradução da Língua de Sinais em um Ambiente de Saúde</title_pt>
      <title_ja>医療現場での手話翻訳</title_ja>
      <title_zh>医疗保健境中手语译</title_zh>
      <title_hi>एक हेल्थकेयर सेटिंग में साइन लैंग्वेज ट्रांसलेशन</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Перевод языка жестов в медицинских учреждениях</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Aistriúchán Teanga Chomharthaíochta i Suíomh Cúraim Sláinte</title_ga>
      <title_el>Μετάφραση Νοηματικής Γλώσσας σε περιβάλλον υγειονομικής περίθαλψης</title_el>
      <title_hu>Jelnyelvi fordítás egészségügyi beállításban</title_hu>
      <title_it>Traduzione del linguaggio dei segni in un ambiente sanitario</title_it>
      <title_kk>Қолтаңбалау тілінің аудармасыName</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Sign Language translation in a healthcare setting</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Потпиши го преведувањето на јазикот во поставување на здравствена заштита</title_mk>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_ms>Tandatangan Terjemahan Bahasa dalam Tetapan Kesehatan</title_ms>
      <title_ml>Sign Language Translation in a Healthcare Setting</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Iffirma t-Traduzzjoni tal-Lingwa f’Setting tal-Kura tas-Saħħa</title_mt>
      <title_no>Signspråk- omsetjing i ei hjelpeloppsett</title_no>
      <title_ro>Traducerea limbii semnelor într-o setare medicală</title_ro>
      <title_pl>Tłumaczenie języka migowego w otoczeniu opieki zdrowotnej</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Prevod znakova jezika u zdravstvenom setu</title_sr>
      <title_so>Six turjumista luqada ee rugta daryeelka caafimaadka</title_so>
      <title_si>සලකුණු භාෂාව භාවිතය හොඳින් බලාපොරොත්තු සැකසුම් වලට</title_si>
      <title_sv>Översättning av teckenspråk i en vårdmiljö</title_sv>
      <title_ta>உடல் பராமரிப்பு அமைப்பில் மொழி மொழிபெயர்ப்பை கையெழுது</title_ta>
      <title_mn>Хүсэглэгч хэл хөгжүүлэлт</title_mn>
      <title_ur>سیگن زبان کا ترجمہ سلامتی حفاظت میں</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Tilni tarjima qilish</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Ký Ngôn ngữ Dịch trong Hệ thống chữa bệnh</title_vi>
      <title_hr>Prevod znakova jezika u zdravstvenom postavljanju</title_hr>
      <title_da>Oversættelse af tegnsprog i en sundhedsplejeindstilling</title_da>
      <title_bg>Превод на жестов език в здравна обстановка</title_bg>
      <title_de>Gebärdensprache Übersetzung im Gesundheitswesen</title_de>
      <title_id>Tanda Tanda Perjemahan Bahasa dalam Pengaturan Kesehatan</title_id>
      <title_nl>Vertaling van gebarentaal in de gezondheidszorg</title_nl>
      <title_fa>ترجمه زبان نشانی در تنظیمات سلامتی</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Wagtlaýyn Ça şyrymy</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Tafsiri ya lugha katika mazingira ya afya</title_sw>
      <title_ko>의료 환경에서의 수화 번역</title_ko>
      <title_af>Teken Taal Vertaling in 'n Healthcare Opstelling</title_af>
      <title_sq>Zgjidh përkthimin e gjuhës në një rregullim shëndetësor</title_sq>
      <title_am>Sign Language Translation in a Healthcare Setting</title_am>
      <title_bn>স্বাস্থ্য সেবা সংস্থায় ভাষার অনুবাদ স্বাক্ষর করুন</title_bn>
      <title_az>İşaret Dili Tərcümə</title_az>
      <title_bs>Prevod znakova jezika u zdravstvenom stanju</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Překlad znakového jazyka ve zdravotnickém prostředí</title_cs>
      <title_hy>Ստորագրել լեզվի թարգմանությունը առողջապահության մեջ</title_hy>
      <title_ca>Sign Language Translation in a Healthcare Setting</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Viittomakielen käännös terveydenhuollon ympäristössä</title_fi>
      <title_et>Viipekeele tõlge tervishoiu keskkonnas</title_et>
      <title_jv>Ngubah Kanal Terjamahan kanggo Kemerdekaan kapan-kapan</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Prevajanje znakovnega jezika v zdravstvenem okolju</title_sk>
      <title_he>Sign Language Translation in a Healthcare Setting</title_he>
      <title_bo>རྨང་ཚད་ལྟ་སྟངས་ཀྱི་སྒྲིག་སྟངས་ནང་མིང་རྟགས་སྐད་ཡིག་ཚིག་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་</title_bo>
      <title_ha>@ label</title_ha>
      <abstract_ar>يمثل التواصل بين المتخصصين في الرعاية الصحية والمرضى الصم تحديًا ، كما أن جائحة COVID-19 الحالي يجعل هذه المشكلة أكثر حدة. غالبًا ما لا يتمكن مترجمي لغة الإشارة من دخول المستشفيات ، كما أن أقنعة الوجه تجعل قراءة الشفاه أمرًا مستحيلًا. لمعالجة هذه المشكلة العاجلة ، قمنا بتطوير نظام يسمح لأخصائيي الرعاية الصحية بترجمة الجمل التي تُستخدم بشكل متكرر في تشخيص وعلاج COVID-19 إلى لغة الإشارة في هولندا (NGT). يتم عرض الترجمات عن طريق مقاطع الفيديو والصور المتحركة. إن بنية النظام يمكن أن تمتد إلى التطبيقات الأخرى ولغات الإشارة الأخرى بطريقة مباشرة نسبيًا.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>La comunicación entre los profesionales de la salud y los pacientes sordos es un desafío, y la actual pandemia de COVID-19 agudiza aún más este problema. Los intérpretes de lenguaje de señas a menudo no pueden ingresar a los hospitales y las mascarillas hacen imposible leer los labios. Para abordar este problema urgente, desarrollamos un sistema que permite a los profesionales de la salud traducir frases que se utilizan con frecuencia en el diagnóstico y el tratamiento de COVID-19 al lenguaje de señas de los Países Bajos (NGT). Las traducciones se muestran mediante vídeos y animaciones de avatares. La arquitectura del sistema es tal que podría extenderse a otras aplicaciones y otros lenguajes de signos de una manera relativamente sencilla.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>La communication entre les professionnels de santé et les patients sourds est difficile, et la pandémie actuelle de COVID-19 rend ce problème encore plus aigu. Les interprètes en langage des signes ne peuvent souvent pas entrer dans les hôpitaux et les masques faciaux rendent impossible la lecture sur les lèvres. Pour faire face à ce problème urgent, nous avons développé un système qui permet aux professionnels de la santé de traduire les phrases fréquemment utilisées dans le diagnostic et le traitement de la COVID-19 en langue des signes néerlandaise (NGT). Les traductions sont affichées au moyen de vidéos et d'animations d'avatar. L'architecture du système est telle qu'il pourrait être étendu à d'autres applications et à d'autres langues des signes d'une manière relativement simple.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_pt>A comunicação entre profissionais de saúde e pacientes surdos é desafiadora, e a atual pandemia de COVID-19 torna essa questão ainda mais aguda. Intérpretes de linguagem de sinais muitas vezes não podem entrar em hospitais e máscaras faciais impossibilitam a leitura labial. Para resolver este problema urgente, desenvolvemos um sistema que permite aos profissionais de saúde traduzir frases que são frequentemente usadas no diagnóstico e tratamento da COVID-19 para a Língua de Sinais da Holanda (NGT). As traduções são exibidas por meio de vídeos e animações de avatar. A arquitetura do sistema é tal que pode ser estendida a outras aplicações e outras linguagens de sinais de maneira relativamente direta.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>医療従事者と聴覚障害者とのコミュニケーションは困難であり、現在の新型コロナウイルスのパンデミックにより、この問題はさらに深刻になっています。手話通訳者はしばしば病院に入ることができず、フェイスマスクは唇の読み取りを不可能にします。この緊急の問題に対処するために、医療従事者がCOVID -19の診断と治療で頻繁に使用される文章をオランダ手話（ NGT ）に翻訳できるシステムを開発しました。翻訳は、ビデオやアバターアニメーションによって表示されます。システムのアーキテクチャは、比較的簡単な方法で他のアプリケーション及び他の手話に拡張することができるようになっている。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>医疗保健业聋喑之通有挑战性,时COVID-19大行而益锐。 手语译常不得入医院,口罩使唇读不可得。 开一统,许医疗保健业人将COVID-19诊治中常用句翻译成荷兰手语(NGT)。 译以视频象动画显。 其系统者体系结构使得以对直广其应用程序手语。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>स्वास्थ्य देखभाल पेशेवरों और बहरे रोगियों के बीच संचार चुनौतीपूर्ण है, और वर्तमान कोविड -19 महामारी इस मुद्दे को और भी तीव्र बनाती है। सांकेतिक भाषा दुभाषिया अक्सर अस्पतालों में प्रवेश नहीं कर सकते हैं और फेस मास्क लिपरीडिंग को असंभव बनाते हैं। इस तत्काल समस्या को हल करने के लिए, हमने एक प्रणाली विकसित की है जो स्वास्थ्य देखभाल पेशेवरों को उन वाक्यों का अनुवाद करने की अनुमति देती है जो अक्सर कोविड -19 के निदान और उपचार में उपयोग किए जाते हैं नीदरलैंड की सांकेतिक भाषा (एनजीटी)। अनुवाद वीडियो और अवतार एनिमेशन के माध्यम से प्रदर्शित कर रहे हैं. सिस्टम की वास्तुकला ऐसी है कि इसे अपेक्षाकृत सरल तरीके से अन्य अनुप्रयोगों और अन्य संकेत भाषाओं तक बढ़ाया जा सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Общение между медицинскими работниками и глухими пациентами является сложной задачей, и нынешняя пандемия COVID-19 делает эту проблему еще более острой. Переводчики жестового языка часто не могут войти в больницы, а лицевые маски делают чтение по губам невозможным. Для решения этой неотложной проблемы мы разработали систему, которая позволяет медицинским работникам переводить предложения, которые часто используются в диагностике и лечении COVID-19, на язык жестов Нидерландов (NGT). Переводы отображаются с помощью видео и анимации аватара. Архитектура системы такова, что она может быть распространена на другие приложения и другие языки жестов относительно простым способом.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Tá an chumarsáid idir gairmithe cúram sláinte agus othair bodhra dúshlánach, agus cuireann an phaindéim reatha COVID-19 an tsaincheist seo níos géire fós. Is minic nach mbíonn ateangairí teanga chomharthaíochta in ann dul isteach in ospidéil agus ní féidir léamh liopaí a dhéanamh le maisc aghaidhe. Chun aghaidh a thabhairt ar an bhfadhb phráinneach seo, d’fhorbraíomar córas a ligeann do ghairmithe cúram sláinte abairtí a úsáidtear go minic chun COVID-19 a dhiagnóisiú agus a chóireáil a aistriú go Teanga Chomharthaíochta na hÍsiltíre (NGT). Taispeántar aistriúcháin trí fhíseáin agus beochan avatar. Tá ailtireacht an chórais chomh mór sin go bhféadfaí é a leathnú chuig feidhmeanna eile agus chuig teangacha comharthaíochta eile ar bhealach réasúnta simplí.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_it>La comunicazione tra professionisti sanitari e pazienti sordi è impegnativa e l'attuale pandemia COVID-19 rende questo problema ancora più acuto. Gli interpreti del linguaggio dei segni spesso non possono entrare negli ospedali e le maschere facciali rendono impossibile il lipreading. Per affrontare questo problema urgente, abbiamo sviluppato un sistema che consente agli operatori sanitari di tradurre frasi che sono frequentemente utilizzate nella diagnosi e nel trattamento del COVID-19 nella lingua dei segni dei Paesi Bassi (NGT). Le traduzioni vengono visualizzate tramite video e animazioni avatar. L'architettura del sistema è tale che potrebbe essere estesa ad altre applicazioni e ad altri linguaggi dei segni in modo relativamente semplice.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_el>Η επικοινωνία μεταξύ επαγγελματιών υγείας και κωφών ασθενών αποτελεί πρόκληση και η τρέχουσα πανδημία καθιστά το ζήτημα αυτό ακόμη πιο έντονο. Οι διερμηνείς νοηματικής γλώσσας συχνά δεν μπορούν να εισέλθουν σε νοσοκομεία και οι μάσκες προσώπου καθιστούν αδύνατη τη χρήση λιπιδίων. Για να αντιμετωπιστεί αυτό το επείγον πρόβλημα, αναπτύξαμε ένα σύστημα που επιτρέπει στους επαγγελματίες υγείας να μεταφράσουν προτάσεις που χρησιμοποιούνται συχνά στη διάγνωση και τη θεραπεία του στη Νοηματική Γλώσσα των Κάτω Χωρών. Οι μεταφράσεις εμφανίζονται μέσω βίντεο και κινούμενων σχεδίων avatar. Η αρχιτεκτονική του συστήματος είναι τέτοια ώστε να μπορεί να επεκταθεί σε άλλες εφαρμογές και άλλες νοηματικές γλώσσες με σχετικά απλό τρόπο.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az egészségügyi szakemberek és a süket betegek közötti kommunikáció kihívást jelent, és a jelenlegi COVID-19 járvány még súlyosabbá teszi ezt a problémát. A jelnyelvi tolmácsok gyakran nem léphetnek be a kórházba, az arcmaszkok pedig lehetetlenné teszik a felszámolást. Ennek a sürgős problémának a megoldása érdekében kifejlesztettünk egy olyan rendszert, amely lehetővé teszi az egészségügyi szakemberek számára, hogy a COVID-19 diagnózisában és kezelésében gyakran használt mondatokat fordítsák le Hollandia jelnyelvére (NGT). A fordításokat videók és avatar animációk segítségével jelenítik meg. A rendszer architektúrája olyan, hogy viszonylag egyszerűen kiterjeszthető más alkalmazásokra és más jelnyelvekre is.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_lt>Communication between healthcare professionals and deaf patients is challenging, and the current COVID-19 pandemic makes this issue even more acute.  Žymenų kalbos vertėjai dažnai negali patekti į ligonines, o veido kaukės neleidžia skaityti lūpų. Siekdami išspręsti šią skubią problem ą, sukūrėme sistemą, leidžiančią sveikatos priežiūros specialistams dažnai naudojamus sakinius COVID-19 diagnostikoje ir gydyme paversti Nyderlandų ženklų kalba (NGT). Vertimai rodomi vaizdo įrašais ir avatarinėmis animacijomis. Sistemos struktūra yra tokia, kad ji galėtų būti gana paprastai išplėsta į kitas programas ir kitas ženklų kalbas.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ka>სიჯანმრთო პროფეციალების და ძლიერი პოციენტების კომუნიკაცია შესაძლებელია, და მიმდინარე COVID-19 პოციენტების კომუნიკაცია ამ პროფეციას უფრო აკუტირება სიმბოლო ენერგიის ინტერპორტერები ზოგიერთად არ შეიძლება ბოლობოლობში გადატანა და მასკების გამოსახულება შეუძლებელია სიმბოლობი. ამ ძალიან წარმოდგენელი პრობლემების გარეშე, ჩვენ განვითარეთ სისტემა, რომელიც საშუალოდ გამოყენება ჯანმრთელო პროფეციალებს, რომელიც ბევრად გამოყენებულია COVID-19-ის დიაგონგიზ ვიდეო და ავარას ანიმეციების გამოყენება ჩვენებულია. სისტემის არქტიქტურაცია იგივეა, რომ ის შეიძლება გადატანა სხვა პროგრამებზე და სხვა სიმბოლოების ენების შესაბამისი მხოლოდ განმავლობით.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_mk>Комуникацијата помеѓу здравствените професионалци и глувите пациенти е предизвикувачка, а сегашната пандемија на COVID-19 го прави ова прашање уште посакувано. Преведувачите на знакови јазици честопати не можат да влезат во болниците и маските на лицето прават читање на усни невозможно. За да го решиме овој итен проблем, развивме систем кој им овозможува на здравствените професионалци да преведат реченици кои често се користат за дијагностика и третман на COVID-19 во знак јазик на Холандија (НГТ). Преведувањата се прикажуваат преку видеа и аватарни анимации. Архитектурата на системот е таква што може да се прошири на други апликации и други јазици на знаци на релативно едноставен начин.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Komunikasi antara profesional rawatan kesehatan dan pesakit pekak adalah menantang, dan pandemi COVID-19 semasa membuat isu ini lebih akut. Peninterpreter bahasa tandatangan sering tidak boleh masuk ke hospital dan topeng muka membuat pembacaan bibir mustahil. Untuk menangani masalah penting ini, kami mengembangkan sistem yang membolehkan profesional rawatan kesehatan menerjemahkan kalimat yang sering digunakan dalam diagnosis dan rawatan COVID-19 ke Bahasa Tanda Belanda (NGT). Terjemahan dipaparkan melalui video dan animasi avatar. The architecture of the system is such that it could be extended to other applications and other sign languages in a relatively straightforward way.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ആത്മാര്‍ഗ്ഗസേവനത്തിന്റെയും ബധിരന്‍മാര്‍ക്കും ഇടയിലുള്ള ബന്ധപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു. ഇപ്പോള്‍ ഇപ്പോഴത്തെ കോവിഡി-19 പാന്‍ഡ ഭാഷ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നവര്‍ക്ക് ആശുപത്രിയില്‍ പ്രവേശിക്കാന്‍ സാധ്യമല്ല. മുഖം മുഖം മുഖം വായിക്ക ഈ ഉടനെ പ്രശ്നം വിശദീകരിക്കാന്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഒരു സിസ്റ്റത്തെ നിര്‍മ്മിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. അത് സൌഖ്യ പരിശീലകന്‍മാര്‍ക്ക് ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന വാക്കുകള്‍ പരിഭാഷ വീഡിയോകളും ആവാതര്‍ ആനിമേഷനുകളുമായി പരിഭാഷകള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു. സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ ആര്‍ക്കിച്ചിട്ടുണ്ടെങ്കില്‍ മറ്റു പ്രയോഗങ്ങള്‍ക്കും മറ്റു ചിഹ്നങ്ങള്‍ക്കും വിശേഷിപ്പിക്കാന</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Kommunikasjon mellom helseforskere og døyre pasienter er vanskeleg, og den gjeldande pandemien COVID-19 gjer dette problemet enda akkurat. Signspråk-tolkarar kan ofte ikkje skriva inn systolar og ansiktmasker gjera liplesing umulig. For å løse denne vanskelige problemen, utvikla vi eit systemet som tillater helseforskere å oversette setningar som ofte brukar i diagnosen og behandlinga av COVID-19 til signspråk i Nederland (NGT). Omsetjingar vert viste med videoar og avataranimasjonar. Arkitekturen av systemet er slik at den kan utvidast til andre program og andre signspråk på relativt enkelt måte.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Komunikacja między pracownikami służby zdrowia a pacjentami niesłyszącymi jest wyzwaniem, a obecna pandemia COVID-19 sprawia, że problem ten jest jeszcze bardziej ostry. Tłumacze języka migowego często nie mogą wejść do szpitali, a maski na twarz uniemożliwiają lipreading. Aby rozwiązać ten pilny problem, opracowaliśmy system umożliwiający personelowi medycznemu tłumaczenie zdań, które są często używane w diagnostyce i leczeniu COVID-19 na język migowy Holandii (NGT). Tłumaczenia są wyświetlane za pomocą filmów i animacji awatarowych. Architektura systemu jest taka, że w stosunkowo prosty sposób można go rozszerzyć o inne aplikacje i inne języki migowe.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mt>Il-komunikazzjoni bejn il-professjonisti tal-kura tas-saħħa u l-pazjenti sordi hija sfida, u l-pandemija COVID-19 attwali tagħmel din il-kwistjoni aktar akuta. L-interpreti tal-lingwa tas-sinjali ta’ spiss ma jistgħux jidħlu fl-isptarijiet u l-maskri tal-wiċċ jagħmlu l-qari tax-xofftejn impossibbli. Biex nindirizzaw din il-problem a urġenti, żviluppajna sistema li tippermetti lill-professjonisti fil-qasam tal-kura tas-saħħa jittraduċu sentenzi li jintużaw ta’ spiss fid-dijanjosi u t-trattament ta’ COVID-19 fil-Lingwa tas-Sinjali tal-Pajjiżi l-Baxxi (NGT). It-traduzzjonijiet jintwerew permezz ta’ vidjows u animazzjonijiet avatari. L-arkitettura tas-sistema hija tali li tista’ tiġi estiża għal applikazzjonijiet oħra u lingwi oħra tas-sinjali b’mod relattivament sempliċi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ro>Comunicarea dintre profesioniștii din domeniul sănătății și pacienții surzi este o provocare, iar pandemia actuală de COVID-19 face această problemă și mai acută. Interpreţii limbajului semnelor nu pot intra adesea în spitale, iar măştile fac imposibilă lipirea. Pentru a aborda această problemă urgentă, am dezvoltat un sistem care permite profesioniștilor din domeniul sănătății să traducă propozițiile care sunt frecvent utilizate în diagnosticul și tratamentul COVID-19 în limba semnelor olandeze (NGT). Traducerile sunt afișate prin intermediul videoclipurilor și animațiilor avatar. Arhitectura sistemului este de așa natură încât ar putea fi extinsă la alte aplicații și alte limbi de semne într-un mod relativ simplu.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Komunikacija između zdravstvenih profesionalaca i gluh pacijenata je izazovna, a trenutna pandemija COVID-19 čini ovaj problem još akutnijim. Interpretatori znakova jezika često ne mogu ući u bolnice i maske lica čine nemoguće čitati usne. Da bi se riješili ovaj hitni problem, razvili smo sistem koji omogućava zdravstvenim profesionalcima da prevode rečenice koje se često koriste u dijagnozi i liječenju COVID-19 u znak jezika Holandske (NGT). Prevodi se pokazuju video i avatarskim animacijama. Arhitektura sistema je tako da se može proširiti na druge aplikacije i druge znakove na relativno jednostavan način.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Wargelinta xirfadaha daryeelka caafimaadka iyo kuwa dhega la'aanta ah waa dhibaatooyin, cudurada COVID-19 ee hada la joogo waxay arrintan ka dhigtaa mid aad u xasaran. Turjubaanada luqada ah inta badan ma geli karaan isbitaalada, maskaha wejigana waa suurtagal in la akhriyo afka. Si aan u xambaarano dhibaatadan degdega ah, waxaan horumarinnay nidaam ay u ogolaan karto xirfadaha caafimaadka si ay u tarjumaan hadalka inta badan lagu isticmaalo diagnostiga iyo baaritaanka COVID-19 si uu u dhigo Signaha Luqada Netherlands (NGT). Translations are displayed by means of videos and avatar animations.  Tirada nidaamka waa in si toos ah loo sii wadi karo codsiyada kale iyo luuqadaha kale oo calaamad lagu qorayo.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>ස්වාස්ත්වකාරිය සහ බහුරු රෝගියෝ අතර සම්බන්ධ විදියට සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා, ඒ වගේම දැන් ප්‍ර ස්වාක්ෂි භාෂාව අනුවර්තකයෝ හොස්පිටල් වලට ඇතුලට යන්න බෑ සහ මුහුණු මුහුණු මුහුණු ප අපි මේ ප්‍රශ්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් විදිහට විශ්වාස කරනවා, ඒකෙන් ස්වාස්ථාවක ව්‍යාපාරිත්වයන්ට ප්‍රශ්නය කරන්න පුළුවන් විදිහට කිරීම සහ වීඩියෝ සහ අවතාර් ජීවිතය සඳහා භාවිතය පෙන්වන්නේ. පද්ධතියේ ස්ථාපනය තමයි ඒක අනිත් ප්‍රයෝජනය සහ අනිත් සලකුණු භාෂාවට සම්බන්ධයෙන්ම සිද්ධ විදිහට ව</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Kommunikationen mellan vårdpersonal och döva patienter är utmanande och den nuvarande COVID-19-pandemin gör denna fråga ännu mer akut. Teckenspråkstolkar kan ofta inte komma in på sjukhus och ansiktsmasker gör det omöjligt att lipa. För att ta itu med detta brådskande problem utvecklade vi ett system som gör det möjligt för vårdpersonal att översätta meningar som ofta används vid diagnos och behandling av COVID-19 till Nederländernas teckenspråk (NGT). Översättningar visas med hjälp av videor och avatar animationer. Systemets arkitektur är sådan att det kan utvidgas till andra applikationer och andra teckenspråk på ett relativt okomplicerat sätt.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>உடல் பராமரிப்பு தொழில்நுட்பவர்களுக்கும் செவிடர்களுக்கும் இடையே தொடர்பு சவாலாக இருக்கிறது, தற்போதைய COVID-19 துன்பத்தி மொழி மொழி மொழிபெயர்ப்பாளர்கள் பெரும்பாலும் மருத்துவமனைகளில் நுழைய முடியாது மற்றும் முகத்த இந்த விரைவான பிரச்சனையை தேர்ந்தெடுக்க, நாங்கள் ஒரு அமைப்பை உருவாக்கினோம், அது நல்ல பரிசுத்துரைப்பாளர்களை மொழிமாற்ற அனுமதிக்கும். அது பொதுவா விடியோ மற்றும் avatar அசைவூட்டத்தின் மூலம் மொழிபெயர்ப்புகள் காட்டப்படுகின்றன. அமைப்பின் கட்டுப்பாடு இது மற்ற பயன்பாடுகளுக்கும் மற்ற மொழிகளுக்கும் விரிவாக்கப்படும் பொருள் நேராக நேராக வழியி</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>صحیح حفاظت پرسفال اور بہرے بیماروں کے درمیان تعامل مشکل ہے اور موجود COVID-19 pandemic نے اس مسئلہ کو اضافہ کردیا ہے۔ سیگن زبان تفسیر کرنے والوں کو اکثر بیمارستان میں داخل نہیں کرسکتے اور ماسک کے چہرے لپ پڑھنے کو غیر ممکن بنا سکتے ہیں. ہم نے اس اضطراری مسئلہ کے بارے میں ایک سیستم پیدا کیا ہے جو سلامتی حفاظت کرنے والوں کو اجازت دیتا ہے کہ کلمات کو اغلب طریقے سے نوشتے جاتے ہیں اور COVID-19 کو نیڈلند کی سیگن زبان (NGT) میں استعمال کیا جاتا ہے۔ ویڈیو اور آواٹر انیمیٹ کے ذریعے ترجمہ دکھائے جاتے ہیں. سیسٹم کی معماری ایسی ہے کہ یہ دوسری کاربریاں اور دوسری نشانیوں کی زبانیں ایک نسبتا سادھے طریقے سے پھیلائے جائیں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_mn>Эрүүл мэндийн эрүүл мэндийн мэргэжилтэн болон дүүрэн өвчтөн хоорондын харилцаа хэцүү болж байна. Одоо байгаа COVID-19 пандемик энэ асуудлыг илүү хүчтэй болгодог. Хүсэглэгч хэл хэлэгчид эмнэлэгт орж чадахгүй, нүүрэн зурагтай нүүрэг уншиж чадахгүй. Энэ шаардлагатай асуудлыг олохын тулд бид эрүүл мэндийн мэргэжилтнүүд ихэвчлэн COVID-19-г Нидерландын шинж тэмдэгтийн хэл (NGT) болгон ашигладаг өгүүлбэрүүдийг хөгжүүлэх системийг бүтээсэн. Үйлдлийг бичлэг, аватар анимацийн аргаар харуулдаг. Энэ системийн архитектур нь бусад хэрэглэгүүд болон бусад тэмдэглэгчдийн хэлд харьцангуй энгийн аргаар нэмэгдэж болно.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_kk>Саулық сақтау кәсіпшіліктері мен тышқы пациенттер арасындағы байланысты қиындық, және қазіргі COVID-19 пандемиясы осы мәселеді артық болады. Қолтаңбалау тілінің интерпретерлері көп ауруханаларды келтіруге болмайды және қалқалары lipreading мүмкін болады. Бұл жетпей мәселеге шешіміз үшін, біз Нидерландия (NGT) диагностикасында және COVID-19 дегенді қолтаңбалау тіліне аударуға мүмкіндік беретін саулық кәсіпшіліктерінің жүйесін жасадық. Аудармалар видео мен avatar анимациялары арқылы көрсетіледі. Жүйеңіздің архитектурасы, ол басқа қолданбаларға және басқа белгілер тілдеріне сәйкес түрде жұмыс істей алады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_uz>Name Tilni tarjima qilishi odatda qo'llanmagan qo'llanmagan qo'shiq qo'shib qo'yish mumkin. Bu muhim muammolarni boshqarish uchun, biz sog'lom taʼminlovchi soniyalarni o'rganish va ko'pincha COVID-19 tizimga (NGT) tilidan imkoniyat qilishiga ruxsat beradi. Translations are displayed by means of videos and avatar animations.  Tizimning architektari - bu dasturlar va boshqa nishonchaning tillariga bogʻliq to ʻgʻri yozilishi mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Sự liên lạc giữa các chuyên gia chăm sóc y tế và những bệnh nhân bị điếc là một thử thách, và bệnh dịch COVID-19 hiện nay làm cho vấn đề này thêm cấp tính. Nhân viên dịch tiếng biển có thể không vào bệnh viện và mặt nạ làm mặt nạ không thể đọc sách. Để giải quyết vấn đề cấp bách này, chúng tôi đã phát triển một hệ thống cho phép những chuyên gia chăm sóc y tế dịch những câu thường được sử dụng trong chẩn đoán và chữa bệnh COVID-19 vào Ngôn ngữ Kí của Hà Lan (NGT). Dịch vụ được hiển thị qua các đoạn phim và ảnh Avatar. Cấu trúc của hệ thống có khả năng mở rộng cho các ứng dụng khác và các ngôn ngữ ký tự khác, tương đối dễ dàng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Комуникацията между здравните специалисти и глухите пациенти е предизвикателство и настоящата пандемия прави този проблем още по-остър. Преводачите на жестов език често не могат да влизат в болници и маските за лице правят устните невъзможни. За да се справим с този спешен проблем, разработихме система, която позволява на здравните специалисти да превеждат изречения, които често се използват при диагностицирането и лечението на на жестовия език на Холандия (НГТ). Преводите се показват чрез видеоклипове и аватарни анимации. Архитектурата на системата е такава, че тя може да бъде разширена към други приложения и други жестови езици по относително прост начин.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Kommunikation mellem sundhedspersonale og døve patienter er udfordrende, og den nuværende COVID-19 pandemi gør dette problem endnu mere akut. Tegnsprogstolke kan ofte ikke komme ind på hospitaler, og ansigtsmasker gør lipning umulig. For at løse dette presserende problem har vi udviklet et system, der gør det muligt for sundhedspersonale at oversætte sætninger, der ofte anvendes til diagnosticering og behandling af COVID-19, til tegnsprog i Holland (NGT). Oversættelser vises ved hjælp af videoer og avatar animationer. Systemets arkitektur er sådan, at det kan udvides til andre applikationer og andre tegnsprog på en relativt ligetil måde.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Communicatie tussen zorgprofessionals en dove patiënten is een uitdaging en de huidige COVID-19 pandemie maakt dit probleem nog acuter. Geberentaaltolken kunnen vaak geen ziekenhuizen binnenkomen en gezichtsmaskers maken lipreading onmogelijk. Om dit dringende probleem aan te pakken hebben we een systeem ontwikkeld waarmee zorgprofessionals zinnen die vaak worden gebruikt bij de diagnose en behandeling van COVID-19 kunnen vertalen naar Geberentaal van Nederland (NGT). Vertalingen worden weergegeven door middel van video's en avatar animaties. De architectuur van het systeem is zodanig dat het op een relatief eenvoudige manier kan worden uitgebreid naar andere toepassingen en andere gebarentalen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Komunikacija između zdravstvenih profesionalaca i gluvih bolesnika je izazovna, a trenutna pandemija COVID-19 čini ovaj problem još akutnijim. Interpretatori znakova jezika često ne mogu ući u bolnice i maske lica čine nemogućnim čitanjem usna. Da bi se riješili ovaj hitni problem, razvili smo sustav koji omogućava zdravstvenim profesionalcima prevoditi rečenice koje se često koriste u dijagnozi i liječenju COVID-19 u znak jezika Nizozemske (NGT). Prevodi se pokazuju putem video i avatarnih animacija. Arhitektura sustava je tako da se može proširiti na druge primjene i druge jezike znakova na relativno jednostavan način.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Die Kommunikation zwischen Angehörigen des Gesundheitswesens und gehörlosen Patienten ist eine Herausforderung, und die aktuelle COVID-19-Pandemie macht dieses Problem noch akuter. Gebärdensprachdolmetscher können oft nicht in Krankenhäuser eintreten und Gesichtsmasken machen das Lippenlesen unmöglich. Um dieses dringende Problem anzugehen, haben wir ein System entwickelt, mit dem medizinische Fachkräfte Sätze, die häufig bei der Diagnose und Behandlung von COVID-19 verwendet werden, in Gebärdensprache der Niederlande (NGT) übersetzen können. Übersetzungen werden mittels Videos und Avataranimationen angezeigt. Die Architektur des Systems ist so, dass es relativ unkompliziert auf andere Anwendungen und andere Gebärdensprachen erweitert werden kann.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Communication between healthcare professionals and deaf patients is challenging, and the current COVID-19 pandemic makes this issue even more acute.  Peninterpreter bahasa tanda sering tidak bisa masuk ke rumah sakit dan topeng wajah membuat pembacaan bibir mustahil. Untuk mengatasi masalah mendesak ini, kami mengembangkan sebuah sistem yang memungkinkan para profesional perawatan kesehatan untuk menerjemahkan kalimat yang sering digunakan dalam diagnosis dan perawatan COVID-19 ke Bahasa Tanda Belanda (NGT). Terjemahan dipaparkan melalui video dan animasi avatar. Arkitektur sistem seperti itu bisa diperlimbahkan ke aplikasi lain dan bahasa tanda lainnya secara relatif sederhana.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Mawasiliano kati ya wataalamu wa afya na wagonjwa viziwi yanachangamoto, na ugonjwa wa sasa wa COVID-19 unafanya suala hili kuwa na dharura zaidi. Watafsiri wa lugha huwezi mara nyingi kuingia hospitali na nyuso za uso hufanya kusoma maneno yasiyowezekana. Ili kukabiliana na tatizo hili la dharura, tulitengeneza mfumo ambao unaruhusu wataalamu wa afya kutafsiri sentensi ambazo mara nyingi hutumiwa katika uchunguzi na matibabu ya COVID-19 katika lugha ya saini ya Uholanzi (NGT). Tafsiri zinaonyesha kwa njia ya video na taswira za avatar. Ujengo wa mfumo ni kwamba utaongezeka kwa matumizi mengine na lugha nyingine za saini kwa njia moja kwa moja.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>ارتباط بین حرفه‌ای از مراقبت سلامتی و بیماران کره سخت‌تر است، و پاندمیک اکنون COVID-19 این مسئله را بیشتر دقت می‌کند. ترجمه‌کننده‌های زبان نشان می‌دهند اغلب نمی‌توانند به بیمارستان وارد شوند و ماسک‌های صورت را غیرممکن می‌سازند. برای حل این مشکل فوری، ما سیستم را توسعه کردیم که به حرفه‌ای از مراقبت سلامتی اجازه می‌دهد که جمله‌ها که اغلب در تشخیص و درمان COVID-19 به زبان نشانه‌های هلندی (NGT) استفاده می‌شوند. ترجمه‌ها به وسیله ویدئو و انیمیاتر نمایش داده می‌شوند. معماری سیستم این است که می‌تواند به کاربردهای دیگر و زبانهای علامت دیگر در راهی نسبتا مستقیم گسترده شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Kommunikasie tussen gesondsers profesionales en doof pasiënte is moeilik, en die huidige pandemie van COVID-19 maak hierdie probleem nog meer akkuraat. Sign language interpreters kan dikwels nie hospitals in en gesig maskers maak liplesing onmoontlik nie. Om hierdie stragtige probleem te raak, ontwikkel ons 'n stelsel wat die gesondsversoek profesionales laat toe om te vertaal setinge wat dikwels gebruik word in die diagnosis en behandeling van COVID-19 in teken taal van die Nederland (NGT). Vertalings word vertoon deur videos en avatar animasies. Die arkitektuur van die stelsel is sodat dit kan uitbrei word na ander toepassings en ander tekentale op 'n relativies eenvoudige manier.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_ko>의료진과 농아 환자 간 소통은 도전인데, 현재의 코로나 대유행은 이 문제를 더욱 첨예하게 만들고 있다.수화 통역사는 통상 병원에 들어갈 수 없고, 마스크는 입술을 읽는 것을 불가능하게 만든다.이 긴박한 문제를 해결하기 위해 의료진이 코로나를 진단하고 치료할 때 자주 사용하는 문장을 네덜란드 수화(NGT)로 번역할 수 있도록 시스템을 개발했다.번역은 영상과 화신 애니메이션을 통해 나타난다.이 시스템의 체계 구조는 상대적으로 간단한 방식으로 다른 응용 프로그램과 다른 수화로 확장될 수 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sq>Komunikimi midis profesionistëve të kujdesit shëndetësor dhe pacientëve të shurdhër është sfidues dhe pandemia aktuale COVID-19 e bën këtë çështje edhe më akute. Shpesh interpretuesit e gjuhës së sinjalit nuk mund të hyjnë në spitale dhe maskat e fytyrës e bëjnë të pamundur leximin e buzëve. Për të trajtuar këtë problem urgjent, zhvilluam një sistem që lejon profesionistët e kujdesit shëndetësor të përkthejnë fjalët që përdoren shpesh në diagnostikën dhe trajtimin e COVID-19 në gjuhën e shenjave të Hollandës (NGT). Përkthimet shfaqen nëpërmjet videove dhe animacioneve avatare. Arkitektura e sistemit është e tillë që mund të zgjerohet në aplikime të tjera dhe gjuhë të tjera të shenjave në një mënyrë relativisht të thjeshtë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Առողջապահության մասնագետների և խուլ հիվանդների միջև հաղորդակցվելը դժվար է, և ներկայիս COVID-19 համաճարակը դարձնում է այս խնդիրը ավելի ծանր: Գործողական լեզվի թարգմանիչները հաճախ չեն կարող հիվանդանոցներ մտնել, և դեմքի դիմակները հնարավոր են դարձնում լապը կարդալ: Այս անհրաժեշտ խնդիրը լուծելու համար մենք զարգացրեցինք մի համակարգ, որը թույլ է տալիս առողջապահության մասնագետներին վերածել նախադասություններ, որոնք հաճախ օգտագործվում են COVID-19-ի ախտորոշության և բուժման ժամանակ Նիդելանդական լեզու Թարգմանությունները ցույց են տալիս տեսահոլովակների և վատավար անիմացիաների միջոցով: Այս համակարգի ճարտարապետությունը նման է, որ այն կարող է հարաբերականորեն պարզ ձևով ընդլայնվել այլ ծրագրերի և այլ նշանների լեզուների վրա:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>በጤና ባለሞያ እና በደንቆሮዎች መካከል ግንኙነት ይጨቃጫል፣ አሁንም COVID-19 ደዌብ ይጨምርበታል፡፡ የቋንቋ አስተርጓሚዎች ብዙ ጊዜ ወደ hospital መግባት አይችሉም፥ የፊትም አካባቢ ሊነበብ አይችሉም። ይህንን አስቸኳይ ጉዳይ ለመግለጽ፣ የጤና ባለሞግዚቶችን በመግለጫ እና በCOVID-19 በተጠቃሚ መግለጫ ወደኔርዳኖስ መግለጫ ቋንቋ (NGT) የሚደረጉትን መግለጫ እንዲፈቅድ የጤና ሞክራተኞችን ስርዓት አግኝተናል፡፡ ትርጉም በቪዲዮ እና በአባታር ምርጫዎች ይታያል። የሲስተም መሠረት መሠረት እንዲህ ነው፣ ለሌሎች ፕሮግራሞች እና ለሌሎች ምልክቶች ቋንቋዎች በአስቸጋሪ መንገድ ይዘረጋል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>স্বাস্থ্য সেবা পেশাদার এবং বধির রোগীদের মধ্যে যোগাযোগ চ্যালেঞ্জ করছে এবং বর্তমান কোভিড-১৯ প্যানেডিমের মধ্যে এই বি ভাষার অনুবাদ প্রায়শই হাসপাতালে প্রবেশ করতে পারে না এবং মুখোশ মুখোশের মুখোশ লিপিপডি অসম্ভব করে। To address this urgent problem, we developed a system which allows healthcare professionals to translate sentences that are frequently used in the diagnosis and treatment of COVID-19 into Sign Language of the Netherlands (NGT).  ভিডিও এবং অ্যাভাটার অ্যানিমেশনের মাধ্যমে অনুবাদ প্রদর্শন করা হয়। সিস্টেমের প্রতিষ্ঠানটি হচ্ছে যে এটি অন্যান্য অ্যাপ্লিকেশন এবং অন্যান্য স্বাক্ষরের ভাষায় প্রসারিত হতে পারে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>La comunicació entre professionals de la salut i pacients sords és un repte, i la pandèmia COVID-19 actual fa que aquest problema sigui encara més acut. Els intérprets del llenguatge de signes sovint no poden entrar als hospitals i les màscares facials impossibilitzen el llegir les labies. Per abordar aquest problem a urgent, vam desenvolupar un sistema que permet als professionals de la salut traduir frases que sovint s'utilitzen en el diagnòstic i el tractament de COVID-19 a Sign Language of the Netherlands (NGT). Translations are displayed by means of videos and avatar animations.  L'arquitectura del sistema és de tal manera que es pugui estendre a altres aplicacions i altres llengües de senyals d'una manera relativament senzilla.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_tr>Sağlık gözetimleri bilen karlar hastalar arasynda görüşmek çözümlidir ve şu anda COVID-19 pandemik bu meseleyi daha abarttır. Wagtlaýyn dil terjimeleri hasaplançylara girip bilmeýär we ýüz maskeleri lip okamak mümkin edip bilenok. Bu gyssagly meselede çözmek üçin, saglyk alyşlaryň köplenç sözleri olaryň diagnostiki we tedavisinde COVID-19 Nişanlaryň (NGT) a ýratynda gol diline terjime etmäge rugsat berýän bir sistemany geliştirdik. Çevirmeler wideo we avatar animasyonlary bilen görkezilýär Sistemiň arhitekturmasy be ýleki uygulamalara we beýleki işaret dillerine düz bir şekilde uzatlanabilir.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_bs>Komunikacija između zdravstvenih profesionalaca i gluh pacijenata je izazovna, a trenutna pandemija COVID-19 čini ovaj problem još akutnijim. Interpretatori znakova jezika često ne mogu ući u bolnice i maske lica čine nemoguće čitanje usne. Da bi se riješili ovaj hitni problem, razvili smo sistem koji omogućava zdravstvenim profesionalcima da prevode rečenice koje se često koriste u dijagnozi i liječenju COVID-19 u znak jezika Nizozemske (NGT). Prevodi se pokazuju video i avatarnim animacijama. Arhitektura sistema je tako da se može proširiti na druge aplikacije i druge znakove na relativno jednostavan način.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_az>Sağlam təhsil sahibləri və sağır hastalar arasındakı iletişim çətindir, və şu anda COVID-19 pandemik bu məsələyi daha ağırlaşdırır. İşaret dillərinin yorumlayıcıları sık-sık xəstələrə girməz və üz maskələri lipreading mümkün olmaz. Bu acil problemi çəkmək üçün, Növerlandiyanın (NGT) İşaret dilinə COVID-19-in diagnosis və təhsil edilən cümlələri təqdim edən sağlam təhsil təhsil sahibləri üçün sistemi təhsil etdik. Tərcümələr videolar və avatar animasyonları vasitəsilə göstərilir. Sistemin arhitekturumu, başqa uyğulamalara və başqa işarə dillərinə çox düz yolla genişlənir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_cs>Komunikace mezi zdravotnickými pracovníky a neslyšícími pacienty je náročná a současná pandemie COVID-19 tento problém ještě akutnější. Tlumočníci znakového jazyka často nemohou vstoupit do nemocnic a obličejové masky znemožňují lipreading. Pro řešení tohoto naléhavého problému jsme vyvinuli systém, který umožňuje zdravotnickým pracovníkům překládat věty, které se často používají při diagnostice a léčbě COVID-19, do znakového jazyka Nizozemska (NGT). Překlady jsou zobrazeny pomocí videí a avatarových animací. Architektura systému je taková, že by mohla být relativně jednoduchým způsobem rozšířena na další aplikace a další znakové jazyky.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Terveydenhuollon ammattilaisten ja kuurojen potilaiden välinen viestintä on haastavaa, ja nykyinen COVID-19-pandemia tekee tästä ongelmasta entistäkin akuutimman. Viittomakielen tulkit eivät usein pääse sairaaloihin ja kasvonaamiot tekevät huulien puhumisesta mahdotonta. Tämän kiireellisen ongelman ratkaisemiseksi kehitimme järjestelmän, jonka avulla terveydenhuollon ammattilaiset voivat kääntää COVID-19:n diagnosoinnissa ja hoidossa usein käytettyjä lauseita Alankomaiden viittomakielelle (NGT). Käännökset näytetään videoiden ja avatar-animaatioiden avulla. Järjestelmän arkkitehtuuri on sellainen, että sitä voitaisiin laajentaa muihin sovelluksiin ja muihin viittomakieliin suhteellisen yksinkertaisella tavalla.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Tervishoiutöötajate ja kurtide patsientide vaheline suhtlemine on keeruline ning praegune COVID-19 pandeemia muudab selle probleemi veelgi teravamaks. Viipekeele tõlkid ei saa sageli haiglasse siseneda ja näomaskid muudavad huulepäramise võimatuks. Selle kiireloomulise probleemi lahendamiseks töötasime välja süsteemi, mis võimaldab tervishoiutöötajatel tõlkida lauseid, mida sageli kasutatakse COVID-19 diagnoosimiseks ja raviks Madalmaade viipekeelde (NGT). Tõlked kuvatakse videote ja avatari animatsioonide abil. Süsteemi arhitektuur on selline, et seda saaks suhteliselt lihtsalt laiendada teistele rakendustele ja viipekeeltele.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>Komunikasyon karo perbudhakan-perbudhakan kanggo masalah sakjane sampeyan karo akeh basa sing gak bênêr, lan kabèh panemik nggawe cora-19 kuwi susahé sakjane kuwi. Ngubah kang basa bangkat dipunangé ora bisa teka sabanjur karo pasangan karo nganggo layang Ngawe ngubah perbudhakan langkung iki, awak dhéwé nggawe sistem sing bisa perusahaan kanggo langgar aturan surat sing isiné kanggo ngertuakake kapan kanggo ngerasakno kanggo ngerasakno dianggap karo nggawe CVD-19 kanggo langgambar Sicile Jagad (NGT). Jejaring Arkturatura sistem iki dadi sing bisa metu supaya aplikasi liyane lan uga siji-sijih lan langgar liyane sing larang, lan padha apik sing susahé awak dhéwé.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Komunikacija med zdravstvenimi delavci in gluhi bolniki je izziv, zaradi sedanje pandemije COVID-19 pa je to vprašanje še bolj akutno. Tolmači znakovnega jezika pogosto ne morejo vstopiti v bolnišnice, maske obraza pa onemogočajo ustvarjanje. Za reševanje tega nujnega problema smo razvili sistem, ki zdravstvenim delavcem omogoča prevajanje stavkov, ki se pogosto uporabljajo pri diagnosticiranju in zdravljenju COVID-19, v znakovni jezik Nizozemske (NGT). Prevodi so prikazani s pomočjo videoposnetkov in avatarskih animacij. Arhitektura sistema je takšna, da bi ga lahko razmeroma enostavno razširili na druge aplikacije in druge znakovne jezike.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Communication tsakanin mafafiki da kure na saurãre ne, kuma bukon COV-19 na yanzu yana ƙaranci wannan masu cikin kashfa. Wata fassarar da harshe bã zã su iya shiga matsayin ayuka ba kuma fuskar kwamfyuta ba su iya karatun littãfi ba. To, dõmin a yi tambaya ga wannan masu hushi na ƙayyade, mun developed wani na'urar tsarin da ke yarda su rarraba wasu kalmõmi da ake yi amfani da su ko da yawa a cikin diagnoni da kuma a yi amfani da COV-19 zuwa Sign in Lugha na Uƙasan (NGT). Ana nuna Fassarori da za'a yi amfani da masu motsi na video da masu motsi. The architecture of the system is such that it could be extended to other applications and other sign languages in a relatively straightforward way.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>Communication between healthcare professionals and deaf patients is challenging, and the current COVID-19 pandemic makes this issue even more acute.  מתרגמים שפת סימנים לעתים קרובות לא יכולים להיכנס לבית החולים ומסכות פנים הופכות לקרוא שפתים בלתי אפשריים. כדי להתמודד עם הבעיה הדחופה הזו, פיתחנו מערכת שמאפשרת למקצועי טיפול בריאות לתרגם משפטים שמשתמשים לעתים קרובות באבחנה וטיפול של COVID-19 לשפת סימנים של ההולנדים (NGT). התרגשות מוצגות באמצעות וידאו ואוטר אנימציות. הארכיטקטורה של המערכת היא כזו שיכולה להתרחב לתוכניות אחרות ולשפות סימנים אחרות בדרך די פשוט.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>སྨོ་བའི་ཞབས་ཞུ་བ་དང་གཟུགས་པ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འདི་ཚོར་བ་ཁག་ཅིག་ཡོད་པ་དང་ད་ལྟོའི་སྐྱོན་བརྗོད་ཀྱི་ཞབས་ཞུ་བའི་ནད་དོན་ རྟགས་བཀོད་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་དཔྱད་པ་ཚོས་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་ཁང་ནང་འཛུགས་མི་ཐུབ་པ་དང་གདོང འུ་ཚོས་མཚམས་ཁག་གྱི་དཀའ་ངལ་འདི་ལ་བསླབ་ན་ང་ཚོས་རང་བཞིན་གྱི་ཞབས་སྐྱོར་གྱི་སྨན་ཚོགས་ལ་སྤྲོད་ཡོད་པའི་ཚིག ཡིག་སྣོད་བརྙན་རིས་དང་གཟུགས་རིས་ཀྱི་སྐད་བསྟུན་ནས་མངོན་འཆར་བྱེད་པ ད་ལྟ་མ་ལག་གི་བཟོ་བཀོད་པ་དེ་ནི་ཉེར་སྤྱོད་གཞན་དང་མིང་རིགས་སྤྱོད་གཞན་ཞིག་ལ་ཁྱད་ནས་ཕལ་ཆེར་འཕགས་རིས་འདུག</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>What Makes a Concept Complex? Measuring Conceptual Complexity as a Precursor for Text Simplification</title>
      <author><first>Anne</first><last>Eschenbruecher</last></author>
      <pages>154–160</pages>
      <abstract>Advancements within the field of text simplification (TS) have primarily been within syntactic or lexical simplification. However, conceptual simplification has previously been identified as another field of TS that has the potential to significantly improve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reading_comprehension">reading comprehension</a>. A first step to measuring conceptual simplification is the classification of concepts as either complex or simple. This research-in-progress paper proposes a new definition of conceptual complexity alongside a simple machine-learning approach that performs a binary classification task to distinguish between simple and complex concepts. It is proposed that this be a first step when developing new text simplification models that operate on a conceptual level.</abstract>
      <url hash="2a4d4a75">2021.triton-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>eschenbruecher-2021-makes</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Feedback in Online Translation Courses and the Covid Era</title>
      <author><first>Miguel A.</first><last>Jimenez-Crespo</last></author>
      <pages>208–215</pages>
      <abstract>The Covid pandemic upended translation teaching globally. The forced move to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Educational_technology">online teaching</a> represented a gargantuan challenge for anyone only experienced in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Face-to-face_interaction">face-to-face teaching</a>. Online translation teaching requires distinct approaches to guarantee that students can reach the targeted learning goals. This paper presents a literature review on the provision of effective <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feedback">feedback</a> in the light of these drastic changes in translation teaching as well as a description as how existing research on online feedback for translation training has been applied to the design of online courses at the translation program at Rutgers University.</abstract>
      <url hash="8461d671">2021.triton-1.24</url>
      <bibkey>jimenez-crespo-2021-feedback</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>