<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.codi">
  <volume id="main" ingest-date="2021-11-01">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 2nd Workshop on Computational Approaches to Discourse</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Chloé</first><last>Braud</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Christian</first><last>Hardmeier</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Junyi Jessy</first><last>Li</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Annie</first><last>Louis</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Michael</first><last>Strube</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Amir</first><last>Zeldes</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Punta Cana, Dominican Republic and Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="5c380ae2">2021.codi-main.0</url>
      <bibkey>codi-2021-approaches</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Developing Conversational Data and Detection of Conversational Humor in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a><fixed-case>T</fixed-case>elugu</title>
      <author><first>Vaishnavi</first><last>Pamulapati</last></author>
      <author><first>Radhika</first><last>Mamidi</last></author>
      <pages>12–19</pages>
      <abstract>In the field of humor research, there has been a recent surge of interest in the sub-domain of Conversational Humor (CH). This study has two main objectives. (a) develop a conversational (humorous and non-humorous) dataset in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>. (b) detect <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methylene_bridge">CH</a> in the compiled <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>. In this paper, the challenges faced while collecting the data and experiments carried out are elucidated. Transfer learning and non-transfer learning techniques are implemented by utilizing pre-trained models such as FastText word embeddings, BERT language models and Text GCN, which learns the word and document embeddings simultaneously of the corpus given. State-of-the-art results are observed with a 99.3 % <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> and a 98.5 % f1 score achieved by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BERT">BERT</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="0ae5fcbe">2021.codi-main.2</url>
      <bibkey>pamulapati-mamidi-2021-developing</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.codi-main.2</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Comparison of methods for explicit discourse connective identification across various domains</title>
      <author><first>Merel</first><last>Scholman</last></author>
      <author><first>Tianai</first><last>Dong</last></author>
      <author><first>Frances</first><last>Yung</last></author>
      <author><first>Vera</first><last>Demberg</last></author>
      <pages>95–106</pages>
      <abstract>Existing parse methods use varying approaches to identify explicit discourse connectives, but their performance has not been consistently evaluated in comparison to each other, nor have they been evaluated consistently on text other than newspaper articles. We here assess the performance on explicit connective identification of three parse methods (PDTB e2e, Lin et al., 2014 ; the winner of CONLL2015, Wang et al., 2015 ; and DisSent, Nie et al., 2019), along with a simple heuristic. We also examine how well these systems generalize to different datasets, namely written newspaper text (PDTB), written scientific text (BioDRB), prepared spoken text (TED-MDB) and spontaneous spoken text (Disco-SPICE). The results show that the e2e parser outperforms the other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parse methods</a> in all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a>. However, performance drops significantly from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PDTB">PDTB</a> to all other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a>. We provide a more fine-grained analysis of domain differences and connectives that prove difficult to parse, in order to highlight the areas where gains can be made.</abstract>
      <url hash="0b025329">2021.codi-main.9</url>
      <bibkey>scholman-etal-2021-comparison</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.codi-main.9</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Revisiting Shallow Discourse Parsing in the PDTB-3 : Handling Intra-sentential Implicits<fixed-case>PDTB</fixed-case>-3: Handling Intra-sentential Implicits</title>
      <author><first>Zheng</first><last>Zhao</last></author>
      <author><first>Bonnie</first><last>Webber</last></author>
      <pages>107–121</pages>
      <abstract>In the PDTB-3, several thousand implicit discourse relations were newly annotated within individual sentences, adding to the over 15,000 implicit relations annotated across adjacent sentences in the PDTB-2. Given that the position of the arguments to these intra-sentential implicits is no longer as well-defined as with inter-sentential implicits, a discourse parser must identify both their location and their sense. That is the focus of the current work. The paper provides a comprehensive analysis of our results, showcasing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_simulation">model</a> performance under different scenarios, pointing out limitations and noting future directions.</abstract>
      <url hash="5e65bfe2">2021.codi-main.10</url>
      <bibkey>zhao-webber-2021-revisiting</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.codi-main.10</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>discopy : A Neural System for Shallow Discourse Parsing</title>
      <author><first>René</first><last>Knaebel</last></author>
      <pages>128–133</pages>
      <abstract>This paper demonstrates discopy, a novel framework that makes it easy to design components for end-to-end shallow discourse parsing. For the purpose of demonstration, we implement recent neural approaches and integrate contextualized word embeddings to predict explicit and non-explicit discourse relations. Our proposed neural feature-free system performs competitively to systems presented at the latest Shared Task on Shallow Discourse Parsing. Finally, a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Front_and_back_ends">web front end</a> is shown that simplifies the inspection of annotated documents. The source code, documentation, and pretrained models are publicly accessible.</abstract>
      <url hash="2de58919">2021.codi-main.12</url>
      <bibkey>knaebel-2021-discopy</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.codi-main.12</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/rknaebel/discopy" additional="false">rknaebel/discopy</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Capturing document context inside sentence-level neural machine translation models with self-training</title>
      <author><first>Elman</first><last>Mansimov</last></author>
      <author><first>Gábor</first><last>Melis</last></author>
      <author><first>Lei</first><last>Yu</last></author>
      <pages>143–153</pages>
      <abstract>Neural machine translation (NMT) has arguably achieved human level parity when trained and evaluated at the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_(linguistics)">sentence-level</a>. Document-level neural machine translation has received less attention and lags behind its sentence-level counterpart. The majority of the proposed document-level approaches investigate ways of conditioning the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> on several source or target sentences to capture <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context_(language_use)">document context</a>. These approaches require training a specialized NMT model from scratch on parallel document-level corpora. We propose an approach that does n’t require training a specialized <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> on parallel document-level corpora and is applied to a trained sentence-level NMT model at decoding time. We process the document from left to right multiple times and self-train the sentence-level model on pairs of source sentences and generated translations. Our approach reinforces the choices made by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a>, thus making it more likely that the same choices will be made in other sentences in the document. We evaluate our approach on three document-level datasets : NIST Chinese-English, WMT19 Chinese-English and OpenSubtitles English-Russian. We demonstrate that our approach has higher BLEU score and higher human preference than the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline</a>. Qualitative analysis of our approach shows that choices made by model are consistent across the document.</abstract>
      <url hash="92f91b85">2021.codi-main.14</url>
      <bibkey>mansimov-etal-2021-capturing</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.codi-main.14</doi>
    </paper>
    </volume>
  <volume id="sharedtask" ingest-date="2021-10-28">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared Task on Anaphora, Bridging, and Discourse Deixis in Dialogue</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Sopan</first><last>Khosla</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ramesh</first><last>Manuvinakurike</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Vincent</first><last>Ng</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Massimo</first><last>Poesio</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Michael</first><last>Strube</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Carolyn</first><last>Rosé</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Punta Cana, Dominican Republic</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ac624928">2021.codi-sharedtask.0</url>
      <bibkey>codicrac-2021-codi</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Anaphora Resolution in Dialogue : Description of the DFKI-TalkingRobots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task<fixed-case>DFKI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>alking<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>obots System for the <fixed-case>CODI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>CRAC</fixed-case> 2021 Shared-Task</title>
      <author><first>Tatiana</first><last>Anikina</last></author>
      <author><first>Cennet</first><last>Oguz</last></author>
      <author><first>Natalia</first><last>Skachkova</last></author>
      <author><first>Siyu</first><last>Tao</last></author>
      <author><first>Sharmila</first><last>Upadhyaya</last></author>
      <author><first>Ivana</first><last>Kruijff-Korbayova</last></author>
      <pages>32–42</pages>
      <abstract>We describe the system developed by the DFKI-TalkingRobots Team for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task on anaphora resolution in dialogue. Our system consists of three subsystems : (1) the Workspace Coreference System (WCS) incrementally clusters mentions using semantic similarity based on embeddings combined with lexical feature heuristics ; (2) the Mention-to-Mention (M2 M) coreference resolution system pairs same entity mentions ; (3) the Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) system employs a Siamese Network to detect discourse anaphor-antecedent pairs. WCS achieved F1-score of 55.6 % averaged across the evaluation test sets, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wildlife_Conservation_Society">M2 M</a> achieved 57.2 % and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wildlife_Conservation_Society">DDR</a> achieved 21.5 %.</abstract>
      <url hash="5a6d3cc9">2021.codi-sharedtask.3</url>
      <bibkey>anikina-etal-2021-anaphora</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.codi-sharedtask.3</doi>
    <title_ar>حل الجناس في الحوار: وصف نظام DFKI-TalkingRobots لـ CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Résolution sur l'anaphore en dialogue : Description du système de robots parlants DFKI pour la tâche partagée CODI-CRAC 2021</title_fr>
      <title_pt>Resolução Anáfora em Diálogo: Descrição do Sistema DFKI-TalkingRobots para a Tarefa Compartilhada CODI-CRAC 2021</title_pt>
      <title_es>Resolución anáfora en diálogo: descripción del sistema DFKI-TalkingRobots para la tarea compartida CODI-CRAC 2021</title_es>
      <title_ja>Anaphora Resolution in Dialogue: CODI - CRAC 2021共有タスクのためのDFKI - TalkingRobotsシステムの説明</title_ja>
      <title_zh>å…¶Anaphoraè®®æ›°:CODI-CRAC 2021å…±äº‹è€…DFKI-Talkingæœºå™¨äººç»Ÿä¹Ÿ</title_zh>
      <title_hi>संवाद में Anaphora संकल्प: CODI-CRAC 2021 साझा-कार्य के लिए DFKI-TalkingRobots सिस्टम का विवरण</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Anaphora Resolution in Dialogue: Description of the DFKI-TalkingRobots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Rún Anaphora in Agallamh: Cur síos ar an gCóras DFKI-TalkingRobots le haghaidh Tasc Comhroinnte CODI-CRAC 2021</title_ga>
      <title_ka>დიალოგიში ანაფორის რეზიოციო: CODI-CRAC 2021 shared-Task სისტემა DFKI-საუბრობის განსაზღვრება</title_ka>
      <title_el>Ψήφισμα Ανάφορας στον Διάλογο: Περιγραφή του Συστήματος Μιλώντας Ρομπότ για την Κοινή Εργασία</title_el>
      <title_hu>Anaphora megoldás párbeszédben: A DFKI-TalkingRobots rendszer leírása a CODI-CRAC 2021 megosztott feladathoz</title_hu>
      <title_it>Risoluzione Anaphora in dialogo: Descrizione del sistema DFKI-TalkingRobots per il compito condiviso CODI-CRAC 2021</title_it>
      <title_kk>Диалогтың Anaphora Айырымдылығы: CODI-CRAC 2021 ортақтастырылған тапсырманың DFKI-TalkingRobots жүйесінің сипаттамасы</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Anaphora Resolution in Dialogue: Description of the DFKI-TalkingRobots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Resolusi Anafora dalam Dialog: Keterangan Sistem Robot-Bercakap DFKI untuk Tugas Berkongsi CODI-CRAC 2021</title_ms>
      <title_lt>Anaforos pertvarkymas dialoge: DFKI-TalkingRobots sistemos CODI-CRAC 2021 bendros užduoties aprašymas</title_lt>
      <title_mt>Anaphora Resolution in Dialogue: Description of the DFKI-TalkingRobots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_mt>
      <title_no>Anaforoppløysing i dialogvindauget: Beskrivelse av DFKI-talkingrobotsystemet for CODI-CRAC 2021 delt oppgåve</title_no>
      <title_ro>Rezoluția Anaphora în dialog: Descrierea sistemului DFKI-TalkingRobots pentru sarcina partajată CODI-CRAC 2021</title_ro>
      <title_pl>Rozwiązanie anafory w dialogu: Opis systemu DFKI-TalkingRobots dla CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_pl>
      <title_ml>ഡയലോഗിലെ അനാഫോറ റ റിസ്റ്റല്‍: Description of the DFKI- Talking Robots System for the CODI- CRAC 2021 Shared- Task</title_ml>
      <title_sr>Anafora Rezolucija u dijalogu: opis DFKI-govornog robotskog sustava za CODI-CRAC 2021 podeljeni zadatak</title_sr>
      <title_mn>CODI-CRAC 2021 хуваалтын ажлын DFKI-ярианы робот системийн тодорхойлолт</title_mn>
      <title_si>සංවාදයේ Anaphora resolution: CODI-CRAC 2021 සමාගත වැඩක් විස්තර DFKI-TalkingRobots පද්ධතිය</title_si>
      <title_ta>Anaphora Resolution in Dialogue: Description of the DFKI-TalkingRobots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_ta>
      <title_ur>ڈیلوگو میں آنافورا ریزیزول: CODI-CRAC 2021 شریک-ٹاکس کے لئے DFKI-Talking روبوٹ سیسٹم کی توصیح</title_ur>
      <title_so>Description of the DFKI-Talking Robots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_so>
      <title_sv>Anaphora Resolution in Dialogue: Beskrivning av DFKI-TalkingRobots System för CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_sv>
      <title_uz>Robots System for the CODI- CRAC 2021 Shared- Task</title_uz>
      <title_vi>phân giải Anaphora trong phần tử: mô tả hệ thống Mô tả Bo Tử nằm vùng cho CODI-CRAC 2021, đã chia sẻ-Task</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Резолюция на анафората в диалог: Описание на системата за говорещи роботи за споделената задача</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Anafora Rezolucija u dijalogu: opis DFKI-govornog robotskog sustava za CODI-CRAC 2021. zajednički zadatak</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Anafora Resolutie in Dialoog: Beschrijving van het DFKI-TalkingRobots Systeem voor de CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_nl>
      <title_de>Anaphora Resolution im Dialog: Beschreibung des DFKI-TalkingRobots Systems für den CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_de>
      <title_ko>대화의 반지름 해석: CODI-CRAC 2021 공유 작업에 사용되는 DFKI Talking Robots 시스템 설명</title_ko>
      <title_id>Resolusi Anafora dalam Dialog: Deskripsi sistem robot DFKI-TalkingRobots untuk CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_id>
      <title_fa>Resolution Anaphora in Dialog: Description of the DFKI-Talking Robots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Tafsiri ya Mfumo wa DFKI-Talking Robots kwa ajili ya CODI-CRAC 2021</title_sw>
      <title_sq>Rezolucioni i anaforës në dialog: Përshkrimi i Sistemit DFKI-TalkingRobots për CODI-CRAC 2021-Task-Shared</title_sq>
      <title_am>Robots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_am>
      <title_da>Anaphora Resolution in Dialogue: Beskrivelse af DFKI-TalkingRobots System til CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_da>
      <title_az>Dialogda Anafora Çözünürlük: CODI-CRAC 2021 paylaşılmış-Task sisteminin DFKI-TalkingRobots Sisteminin tərzi</title_az>
      <title_tr>CODI-CRAC 2021 Mazmunlar-Taýgynyň DFKI-Gürüş Robotlaryň Waspy</title_tr>
      <title_bn>ডায়ালগে আনাফোরা রিসুলেশন: DFKI- Talking Robots সিস্টেমের Description of the DFKI- Talking Robots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Tasks</title_bn>
      <title_af>Anafora Resolusie in Dialoog: Beskrywing van die DFKI- Praat- Robots Stelsel vir die CODI- CRAC 2021 Gedeelde- Opdrag</title_af>
      <title_bs>Anafora Rezolucija u dijalogu: opis DFKI-govornog robotskog sustava za CODI-CRAC 2021.</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Resolució d'anafòra en Diàleg: Descripció del sistema DFKI-TalkingRobots del CODI-CRAC 2021</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Anaforické řešení v dialogu: Popis systému DFKI-TalkingRobots pro CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_cs>
      <title_hy>Անաֆորայի վերլուծություն դասախոսում. COD-Crac 2021-ի ընդհանուր հանձնարարության DFKI-Talking ռոբոտների համակարգի նկարագրությունը</title_hy>
      <title_et>Anafoora lahendamine dialoogis: DFKI-TalkingRobots süsteemi kirjeldus CODI-CRAC 2021 jagatud ülesande jaoks</title_et>
      <title_fi>Anafora Resolution in Dialogue: Kuvaus DFKI-TalkingRobots-järjestelmästä CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_fi>
      <title_ha>Description of the DFKI-Talk</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Reševanje anafore v dialogu: Opis sistema DFKI-TalkingRobots za CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_sk>
      <title_he>פתרון אנאפורה בדיולוג: תיאור של מערכת רובוטים מדברים DFKI עבור משימה משותפת CODI-CRAC 2021</title_he>
      <title_bo>Anaphora Resolution in Dialog: DFKI-TalkingRobots System for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task</title_bo>
      <title_jv>Anaphora Resolution Teko Dialog: Gambaran DFKi-TalkingJobot System kanggo cordi-criterion 2020 1 shared-task</title_jv>
      <abstract_ar>نحن نصف النظام الذي طوره فريق DFKI-TalkingRobots لـ CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task بشأن دقة الجاذبية في الحوار. يتكون نظامنا من ثلاثة أنظمة فرعية: (1) يقوم نظام Coreference الخاص بمساحة العمل (WCS) بتجميع الإشارات بشكل تدريجي باستخدام التشابه الدلالي المستند إلى حفلات الزفاف جنبًا إلى جنب مع الاستدلال على السمات المعجمية ؛ (2) أزواج نظام حل المرجع من الإشارة إلى الإشارة (M2M) التي ذكرها نفس الكيان ؛ (3) يستخدم نظام Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) شبكة سيامية لاكتشاف أزواج الخطاب السابقات والجانبي. حققت WCS درجة F1 بنسبة 55.6٪ في المتوسط عبر مجموعات اختبار التقييم ، وحققت M2M 57.2٪ وحققت DDR 21.5٪.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Descrevemos o sistema desenvolvido pela equipe DFKI-TalkingRobots para o CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task sobre resolução de anáfora em diálogo. Nosso sistema consiste em três subsistemas: (1) o Workspace Coreference System (WCS) agrupa menções incrementalmente em clusters usando similaridade semântica baseada em embeddings combinados com heurísticas de recursos lexicais; (2) o sistema de resolução de correferência Menção-a-Menção (M2M) emparelha as mesmas menções de entidade; (3) o sistema Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) emprega uma rede siamesa para detectar pares anáfora-antecedentes de discurso. WCS alcançou F1-score de 55,6% em média nos conjuntos de testes de avaliação, M2M alcançou 57,2% e DDR alcançou 21,5%.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Describimos el sistema desarrollado por el equipo DFKI-TalkingRobots para la tarea compartida del CODI-CRAC 2021 sobre la resolución de anáforas en el diálogo. Nuestro sistema consta de tres subsistemas: (1) el Sistema de Correferencia del Espacio de Trabajo (WCS) agrupa de forma incremental las menciones usando similitud semántica basada en incrustaciones combinadas con heurística de características léxicas; (2) el sistema de resolución de correferencia Mención a mención (M2M) empareja menciones de la misma entidad; (3) el Discurso El sistema Deixis Resolution (DDR) emplea una red siamesa para detectar pares de anáfora-antecedente del discurso. El WCS obtuvo una puntuación F1 del 55,6% promediada en todos los conjuntos de pruebas de evaluación, M2M alcanzó el 57,2% y DDR alcanzó el 21,5%.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>Nous décrivons le système développé par l'équipe DFKI-TalkingRobots pour la tâche partagée CODI-CRAC 2021 sur la résolution des anaphores en dialogue. Notre système se compose de trois sous-systèmes : (1) le système de coréférence de l'espace de travail (WCS) regroupe de manière incrémentielle les mentions en utilisant la similarité sémantique basée sur des intégrations combinées à des heuristiques de caractéristiques lexicales ; (2) le système de résolution de coréférence Mention-to-Mention (M2M) associe les mêmes mentions d'entité ; (3) le Discourse Le système Deixis Resolution (DDR) utilise un réseau siamois pour détecter les couples anaphre-antécédent de discours. WCS a obtenu un score F1 de 55,6 % en moyenne sur l'ensemble des ensembles de tests d'évaluation, M2M a obtenu 57,2 % et DDR 21,5 %.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>DFKI - TalkingRobotsチームがCODI - CRAC 2021 Shared - Taskのために開発した対話型アナフォラ解決システムについて説明します。当社のシステムは、次の3つのサブシステムで構成されています。（ 1 ） Workspace Coreference System （ WCS ）は、語彙特徴ヒューリスティックと組み合わせた埋め込みに基づいて、セマンティックの類似性を使用してクラスタを増分的に言及します。（ 2 ） M 2 M （ M 2 M ）コアファレンスレゾリューションシステムは、同じエンティティが言及したペアをペアにします。（ 3 ） Discourse Deixis Resolution （ DDR ）システムは、Siamese Networkを使用して、発話の類推前置ペアを検出します。ＷＣＳは、評価試験セット全体で平均５ ５ ． ６ ％のＦ １スコアを達成し、Ｍ ２ Ｍは５ ７ ． ２ ％、ＤＤＲは２ １ ． ５ ％を達成した。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>言DFKI-TalkingRobots团队为CODI-CRAC 2021共事,当系于言anaphora。 臣等统由三子系统:(1)事区协同系统(WCS)用基于嵌入语义相似性与词汇特征启发式法,增量聚类提及。 (2)提及提及(M2M)共推理解析系统将同实体提及配对; (3)语Deixis Resolution(DDR)统用暹罗网络检语前验是。 WCS估会之均F1分为55.6%,M2M及57.2%,DDR及21.5%。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम DFKI-TalkingRobots टीम द्वारा CODI-CRAC 2021 साझा-कार्य के लिए विकसित प्रणाली का वर्णन करते हैं जो संवाद में एनाफोरा रिज़ॉल्यूशन पर है। हमारे सिस्टम में तीन उपप्रणालियों होते हैं: (1) वर्कस्पेस कोरेफेरेंस सिस्टम (डब्ल्यूसीएस) वृद्धिशील रूप से क्लस्टर लेक्सिकल फीचर ह्यूरिस्टिक्स के साथ संयुक्त एम्बेडिंग के आधार पर शब्दार्थ समानता का उपयोग करके उल्लेख करता है; (2) उल्लेख-से-उल्लेख (M2M) coreference संकल्प प्रणाली जोड़े एक ही इकाई का उल्लेख करता है; (3) प्रवचन Deixis संकल्प (DDR) प्रणाली प्रवचन anaphor-पूर्ववर्ती जोड़े का पता लगाने के लिए एक सियामी नेटवर्क नियोजित करता है। डब्ल्यूसीएस ने मूल्यांकन परीक्षण सेटों में औसतन 55.6% का एफ 1-स्कोर हासिल किया, एम 2 एम ने 57.2% और डीडीआर ने 21.5% हासिल किया।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Мы описываем систему, разработанную командой DFKI-TalkingRobots для совместной задачи CODI-CRAC 2021 по разрешению анафоры в диалоге. Наша система состоит из трех подсистем: (1) система Workspace Coreference System (WCS) постепенно упоминает семантическое сходство, основанное на вложениях в сочетании с лексической эвристикой признаков; (2) система разрешения ядра «Упоминание - Упоминание» (M2M) сочетает в себе одно и то же упоминание сущности; (3) система Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) использует сиамскую сеть для обнаружения пар анафора-антецедент дискурса. WCS достигла показателя F1 в 55,6%, усредненного по оценочным наборам испытаний, M2M достигла 57,2%, а DDR достигла 21,5%.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Déanaimid cur síos ar an gcóras a d’fhorbair Foireann DFKI-TalkingRobots le haghaidh Tasc Comhroinnte CODI-CRAC 2021 ar réiteach anafóra san idirphlé. Tá trí fhochóras inár gcóras: (1) luann an Córas Croíthagartha Spás Oibre (WCS) go hincriminteach úsáid a bhaint as cosúlacht shéimeantach bunaithe ar leabaithe in éineacht le heuristics gnéithe foclóireachta; (2) a luann an t-aonán céanna sa chóras réitigh croí-luaite um Lua go Lua (M2M); (3) Fostaíonn an córas um Réiteach Dioscúrsa Deixis (DDR) Líonra Siamese chun péirí anaphor-réamhtheachtaí dioscúrsa a bhrath. Ghnóthaigh WCS scór F1 de 55.6% ar an meán thar na tacair tástála meastóireachta, ghnóthaigh M2M 57.2% agus ghnóthaigh DDR 21.5%.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ სისტემა, რომელიც DFKI-საუბრობო პრობოტების ჯგუფის განვითარებული CODI-CRAC 2021-ის განსაზღვრებული დავალება ანაფორის განსაზღვრებით დიალოგიში. ჩვენი სისტემა არის სამი სპესტისტემები: (1) სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო კორეფერენციის სისტემა (WCS) ინტერემენტალურად კლასტერების გამოყენება სმენტიკური similarity გამოყენება, რომელიც ლე (2) Mention-to-Mention (M2M) coreference resolution system pairs are the same entity mentioned; and (3) Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) სისტემა სიამის ქსელის გამოყენება დისკურსის ანაფორ- ანტეცენტის პარამეტრების გამოყენება. WCS მიიღეთ განსაზღვრებული ტესტის განსაზღვრებით 55,6%-ის განსაზღვრებით, M2M მიიღეთ 57,2% და DDR მიიღეთ 21,5%.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Leírjuk a DFKI-TalkingRobots Team által a CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task számára kifejlesztett rendszert az anafóra megoldására párbeszédben. Rendszerünk három alrendszerből áll: (1) a Workspace Coreference System (WCS) növekményesen említi a klasztereket beágyazásokon alapuló szemantikai hasonlóság használatával kombinált lexikai jellemzők heurisztikájával; (2) a Mention-to-Mention (M2M) coreferencia szanálási rendszer ugyanazokat a jogalanyokat párosítja; (3) A Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) rendszer egy sziámi hálózatot alkalmaz a diskurzus anafór-előző párok felismerésére. A WCS 55,6%-os F1 pontszámot ért el az értékelő tesztkészletek átlagában, az M2M 57,2%-ot, a DDR 21,5%-ot ért el.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Περιγράφουμε το σύστημα που αναπτύχθηκε από την Ομάδα Μιλώντας Ρομπότ για την Κοινή Εργασία για την επίλυση της αναφορής σε διάλογο. Το σύστημά μας αποτελείται από τρία υποσυστήματα: (1) το Σύστημα Συγκέντρωσης Χώρου Εργασίας (Το Σύστημα Συγκέντρωσης Εργασιακού Χώρου (Το Σύστημα Συγκέντρωσης Εργασιακού Χώρου (Το Σύστημα Συγκέντρωσης Εργασιακού Χώρου) αναφέρει βαθμιαία τη χρήση σημασιολογικής ομοιότητας βασισμένης σε ενσωματώσεις σε συνδυασμό με λεξική heuristική χαρακτηριστικών. (2) το σύστημα εξυγίανσης συναρτήσεων μεταξύ αναφοράς (M2M) ζευγαρώνει την ίδια οντότητα, (3) το σύστημα Επίλυσης της Διξίδας Λόγου χρησιμοποιεί ένα Σιαμέζικο Δίκτυο για την ανίχνευση αναφορών-προγενέστερων ζευγαριών λόγου. Το WCS πέτυχε F1-βαθμολογία 55,6% κατά μέσο όρο στα σύνολα δοκιμών αξιολόγησης, το M2M πέτυχε 57,2% και το DDR πέτυχε 21,5%.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_kk>Біз DFKI-TalkingRobots тобы (CODI-CRAC 2021) диалогындағы анафора айырмашылығында ортақ тапсырмалар үшін жасалған жүйені таңдадық. Біздің жүйеміз үш ішкі жүйелерден тұрады: (1) Жұмыс жерлерді баптау жүйесі (WCS) лексикалық функциялармен біріктірілген ендірімдерге негізделген семантикалық ұқсастықтығын қолданады. (2) Мәзірден мәзірге (M2M) мәзірдегі айырмашылық жүйесінің екеуі бір нәтижесін айтылады; NAME OF TRANSLATORS (3) Дискурстардың Дейкс Айырымдылығы (DDR) жүйесі дискурстардың анафор- антецедентті екеуін анықтау үшін сиамез желіне қолданылады. WCS бағалау сынақтарында орташа 55,6% F1 деңгейін жетті, M2M 57,2% және DDR 21,5% дегенді жетті.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_it>Descriviamo il sistema sviluppato dal team DFKI-TalkingRobots per il CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task sulla risoluzione anafora in dialogo. Il nostro sistema è composto da tre sottosistemi: (1) il Workspace Coreference System (WCS) menziona incrementalmente cluster utilizzando somiglianze semantiche basate su incorporazioni combinate con euristica lessicale; (2) il sistema di risoluzione della coreferenza Mention-to-Mention (M2M) accoppia le stesse menzioni dell'entità; (3) il sistema Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) impiega una Rete Siamese per rilevare coppie anafore-antecedenti del discorso. WCS ha ottenuto il punteggio F1 del 55,6% medio tra i set di test di valutazione, M2M ha raggiunto il 57,2% e DDR il 21,5%.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Го опишуваме системот развиен од страна на ДФКИ-Зборувачкиот Роботски тим за CODI-CRAC 2021 Соделена задача за решавање на анафората во дијалогот. Our system consists of three subsystems: (1) the Workspace Coreference System (WCS) incrementally clusters mentions using semantic similarity based on embeddings combined with lexical feature heuristics;  (2) системот за резолуција на соодветната резолуција на споменувањето (M2M) ги споменува истите ентитети; (3) Системот за резолуција на дискорската дексија (ДДР) користи сијамска мрежа за детектирање на парови од дискорска анафора. WCS achieved F1-score of 55.6% averaged across the evaluation test sets, M2M achieved 57.2% and DDR achieved 21.5%.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Mes apibūdiname sistemą, kurią parengė DFKI-TalkingRobots grupė CODI-CRAC 2021 bendrai užduotims dėl anaforos pertvarkymo dialoge. Mūsų sistemą sudaro trys posistemiai: 1) darbo erdvės koreferencijos sistema (WCS) palaipsniui minima grupių, naudojančių semantinį panašumą, pagrįstą įterptimis kartu su leksiniais bruožais heuristika; (2) paminėjimo į paminėjimą (M2M) koreferencijos pertvarkymo sistema paminėja tą patį subjektą; (3) diskurso deiksijos pertvarkymo (DDR) sistema naudoja Siamo tinklą diskurso anaforos ankstesnių porų aptikimui. WCS achieved F1-score of 55.6% averaged across the evaluation test sets, M2M achieved 57.2% and DDR achieved 21.5%.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Kami menggambarkan sistem yang dikembangkan oleh Pasukan Robot DFKI-TalkingRobots untuk Tugas Berkongsi CODI-CRAC 2021 pada resolusi anafora dalam dialog. Our system consists of three subsystems: (1) the Workspace Coreference System (WCS) incrementally clusters mentions using semantic similarity based on embeddings combined with lexical feature heuristics;  (2) sistem resolusi keterangan-ke-keterangan (M2M) pasangan entiti yang sama disebut; (3) Sistem Resolusi Deiks Perhubungan (DDR) menggunakan Rangkaian Siama untuk mengesan pasangan anafora-sebelumnya. WCS mencapai skor-F1 55.6% rata-rata dalam set ujian penilaian, M2M mencapai 57.2% dan DDR mencapai 21.5%.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഡിഎഫ്‌കി-സംസാരിക്കുന്ന റോബോട്ട് ടീം നിര്‍മ്മിച്ചിരിക്കുന്ന സിസ്റ്റം ഞങ്ങള്‍ വിവരിച്ചുകൊടുക്കുന്നു. കോഡിഐ-CRAC 2021- ഞങ്ങളുടെ സിസ്റ്റത്തില്‍ മൂന്നു സബ്സിസ്റ്റമുണ്ട്: (1) വേര്‍പ്പ് കോര്‍ഫെന്‍സ് സിസ്റ്റം (WCS) ലെക്സിക്കല്‍ ഗുണഗണങ്ങളുടെ കൂടെ കൂട്ടിചേര്‍ത്ത്  (2) മെനെന്നേഷന്‍ - മെനെന്‍- മെന്‍ഷന്‍ (M2M) കോര്‍ഫെന്‍സ് റിസ്റ്റേഷന്‍ സിസ്റ്റം ഒരേ വസ്തുവിന്റെ പേരുകള്‍; (3) the Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) system employs a Siamese Network to detect discourse anaphor-antecedent pairs.  വിവില പരീക്ഷണത്തിന്റെ സജ്ജീകരണങ്ങളിലൂടെ എഫ്‌എസിസില്‍ 55. 6% എഫ്‌1 സ്കോര്‍ എത്തി. എം2M 57. 2% പ്രാപിച്ചു. DDR 21.5%.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Бид CODI-CRAC 2021-ийн DFKI-ярианы Роботын багийнхаа хөгжсөн системийг анафора шийдвэрлэлийн талаар хуваалцан ажлыг тайлбарлаж байна. Бидний систем гурван субсистем байдаг: (1) Ажиллалтын орон зайд хамгийн их хэмжээний систем (WCS) нь лексикийн хувьцааны хэмжээний хюристик холбогдолтоос багтаж байгаа семантик төстэй байдал ашигладаг. (2) Mention-to-Mention (M2M) сайхан шийдвэрлэлтийн системийн хоёр нь ижил нэгж хэлж байна. (3) Дэйксис шийдвэрлэл (DDR) систем нь ярианы алдартай хоёрыг олохын тулд Сиамийн сүлжээний сүлжээг ашигладаг. WCS шалгалтын туршилтын дундаж 55.6% нь F1 оноо хүртсэн. M2M 57.2% болон DDR 21.5% хүртсэн.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna niddeskrivu s-sistema żviluppata mit-Tim DFKI-TalkingRobots għall-CODI-CRAC 2021 Kompitu Konġunt dwar ir-riżoluzzjoni tal-anafora fid-djalogu. Is-sistema tagħna tikkonsisti minn tliet sottosistemi: (1) is-Sistema ta’ Koreferenza fl-Ispazju tax-Xogħol (WCS) issemmi inkrementalment raggruppamenti bl-użu ta’ similarità semantika bbażata fuq inkorporazzjonijiet ikkombinati ma’ ġewristiċi ta’ karatteristiċi lexiċi; (2) is-sistema tar-riżoluzzjoni tal-korreferenza Menzzjoni-Menzzjoni (M2M) tissemma l-istess entità; (3) the Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) system employs a Siamese Network to detect discourse anaphor-antecedent pairs.  WCS kiseb punteġġ F1 ta’ 55.6% medju fis-settijiet tat-testijiet ta’ evalwazzjoni, M2M kiseb 57.2% u DDR kiseb 21.5%.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Opisujemy system opracowany przez zespół DFKI-TalkingRobots dla CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task na temat rozwiązywania anafory w dialogu. Nasz system składa się z trzech podsystemów: (1) przyrostowo klastrów Workspace Coreference System (WCS) wymienia wykorzystując podobieństwo semantyczne oparte na osadzeniach w połączeniu z heurystyką cech leksykalnych; (2) system rozwiązywania współreferencji współreferencyjnej (M2M) paruje wspomniane wymienienia podmiotów; (3) System Discurse Deixis Resolution (DDR) wykorzystuje sieć syjamską do wykrywania par anaforowo-poprzednich dyskursów. WCS osiągnął wynik F1 55,6% uśredniony w zestawach testowych oceniających, M2M 57,2% i DDR 21,5%.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_si>අපි DFKI-TalkingRobots කණ්ඩායමේ පද්ධතිය විස්තර කරනවා CODI-CRAC 2021 සඳහා අනාෆෝරා විස්තරයේ සංවාදයේ සමාගත විස්තර කරනවා. අපේ පද්ධතිය සබ් පද්ධතිය තුනක් තියෙන්නේ: (1) වැඩක්ෂේත්‍ර කොරෙෆෙරෙන්ස් පද්ධතිය (WCS) විශේෂයෙන් සැමැන්තික සමාන්‍යතාවය භාවිත කරන්න ප (2) Mention-to-Mention (M2M) කෝරෙෆරෙන්ස් විශේෂණ පද්ධතිය සමහර අයිතියක් කියන්න; (3) සියාමිස් ජාලය පද්ධතියේ විස්තර දෙයික්ස් විශේෂණය (DDR) පද්ධතිය සියාමිස් ජාලය ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා කතාවක් අනා WCS පරීක්ෂණ පරීක්ෂණ සෙට්ටුවෙන් සාමාන්‍යය 55.6% කුණු F1-ප්‍රමාණය ලබාගත්තා, M2M එක 57.2% සහ DDR එක 21.5% ලබාගත්තා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu qoraynaa nidaamka oo u soo hormariyey DFKI-Talking Robots Team for the CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task on resolution anaphora dialogue. nidaamka waxaa ka mid ah saddex hoos-dumiyeed: (1) Isticmaalka shaqaalaha (WCS) oo si kordha ah u soo bandhigaa xujooyinka lagu isticmaalayo isku mid ahaanshaha semantika oo ku saleysan meelaha la isku mid ah ee la xiriira xeryaha lexicka; (2) Isticmaalka isbedelka kooxaha (M2M) ee isbedelka nidaamka isku wasakhda ah oo isku mid ah; (3) the Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) system employs a Siamese Network to detect discourse anaphor-antecedent pairs.  WCS waxay gaadhay iskuul F1 oo ah 55.6% oo ku dhexaysay kooxda imtixaanka qiimeynta, M2M wuxuu gaadhay 57.2% iyo DDR waxay gaadhay 21.5%.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ro>Descriem sistemul dezvoltat de echipa DFKI-TalkingRobots pentru sarcina partajată CODI-CRAC 2021 privind rezolvarea anaforei în dialog. Sistemul nostru este format din trei subsisteme: (1) Sistemul de Coreferență a Spațiului de lucru (WCS) menționează treptat clusterele folosind similaritatea semantică bazată pe încorporări combinate cu euristica caracteristicilor lexicale; (2) sistemul de rezoluție a corefențelor menționate (M2M) cuplează aceleași mențiuni ale entității; (3) Sistemul de rezoluție a discursului Deixis (DDR) utilizează o rețea siameză pentru a detecta perechile anafore-antecedente ale discursului. WCS a obținut un scor F1 de 55,6% mediu în seturile de teste de evaluare, M2M a obținut 57,2% și DDR a obținut 21,5%.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sv>Vi beskriver det system som utvecklats av DFKI-TalkingRobots Team för CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task om anaforalösning i dialog. Vårt system består av tre delsystem: (1) Workspace Coreference System (WCS) nämner stegvis kluster med hjälp av semantisk likhet baserad på inbäddningar kombinerade med lexikal funktionsheuristik; (2) Koreferensresolutionssystemet Mention-to-Mention (M2M) parar ihop samma företag som nämns. (3) Diskurse Deixis Resolution (DDR) systemet använder ett siamesiskt nätverk för att upptäcka diskursanafora-föregångare par. WCS uppnådde F1-poäng på 55,6% i genomsnitt över utvärderingstesten, M2M uppnådde 57,2% och DDR uppnådde 21,5%.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Opišemo sistem razvijen od strane DFKI-govornog robotskog tima za CODI-CRAC 2021. podeljeni zadatak o rezoluciji anafore u dijalogu. Naš sistem se sastoji od tri podsustava: (1) sustav korisnosti radnog prostora (WCS) povećavajući skupove koristeći semantičku sličnost na osnovu ugrađenja kombinacije sa heuristikom leksičkih karakteristika; (2) Par sistema rezolucije dobrodošlosti (M2M) spominje isto područje; (3) Sistem diskursa Deixis Resolution (DDR) koristi Siamejsku mrežu za otkrivanje parova anafora-antecedent a diskursa. WCS je postigao srednji rezultat F1 od 55,6% u razdoblju testova za procjenu, M2M je postigao 57,2% i DDR je postigao 21,5%.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>CODI-CRAC 2021 க்கான DFKI-Talking Robots குழு உருவாக்கப்பட்ட முறைமையை நாம் விவரிக்கிறோம் பேச்சில் ஒளிக்கோடு தெளிவுத்திறன் மீது. எங்கள் அமைப்பு மூன்று துணை அமைப்புகளில் உள்ளது: (1) வேலை விளையாட்டு முறைமை அமைப்பு (WCS) கூடுதலாக குறிப்புகளை ஒத்திசைப்படுத்தும் பொருள்களை மூலம்  (2) குறிப்பு தெளிவுத்திறன் அமைப்பு ஜோடி ஒன்று பொருள் குறிப்புகள்: (3) வடிவமைப்பு டிக்ஸ் திரைத்திறன் (DDR) அமைப்பு சியமர் பிணையத்தை கண்டுபிடிக்கும் பேச்சு anaphor- antecedent ஜோடிகளை பயன்படுத்தும். WCS மதிப்பு சோதனைக்கு முழுவதும் 55. 6% சராசரியான F1- score அடைந்தது, M2M 57. 2% அடைந்தது DDR 21. 5%.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم نے سیسٹم کو DFKI-Talking روبوٹ تیم کے ذریعہ توصیح دیتے ہیں CODI-CRAC 2021 کے لئے آنفورا ریزیولوشن کے ذریعہ شریک ٹاکس کے لئے۔ ہمارے سیستم میں تین سوسسٹیموں کا سامان ہے: (1) کارسپیس کورفرنس سیستم (WCS) اضافہ کلسٹر مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید مزید لکسیکل فوجیٹ ہوریستیک کے ساتھ (2) Mention-to-Mention (M2M) coreference resolution system pairs same entity mentions; (3) ڈیکسس ریزیزول (DDR) سیسٹم ایک سیامی نیٹورک کا استعمال کرتا ہے کہ صحبت نافور-آنٹیسڈینٹ جوڑوں کو پہچان سکے۔ WCS نے 55.6% کے F1-اسکور کو آزمائش تست سٹوں میں متوسط کیا، M2M 57.2% تک پہنچ گیا اور DDR 21.5% تک پہنچ گیا۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_no>Vi beskriver systemet utvikla av DFKI-TalkingRobots-gruppa for CODI-CRAC 2021 Delt oppgåve på anaforoppløysing i dialogen. Sistemet vårt inneheld tre undersystemer: (1) Arbeidsområde- koreferens- systemet (WCS) minner aukande grupper med semantisk likning basert på innbygging kombinert med hekuristisk funksjonar i teksten. (2) menyen-til-menyen (M2M) oppløysingssystemet for oppløysingssystemet gjev samme oppløysingssystemet; og (3) Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) systemet brukar ein Siamese Nettverk for å oppdaga diskursar anaforantesentant par. WCS har oppnådd F1- poeng med 55,6% gjennomsnittlig i evalueringstestsettet, M2M har oppnådd 57,2% og DDR har oppnådd 21,5%.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_uz>Biz muloqat oynasidagi anafora resolution uchun CODI-CRAC 2021 bo'lgan vazifa DFKI-Talking Robots jamoasi yaratgan tizimni anglatamiz. Bizning tizimimizda uchta sub-tizim bo'ladi: (1) Ish vazifa koreference tizimi (WCS) davomida, lektikal imkoniyatlar heuritik bilan bir qanday bog'liq bo'lgan paytlarni qo'yish uchun semantik bir xil qo'llanmalar bilan ishlatiladi; (2) Tashkilot (3) the Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) system employs a Siamese Network to detect discourse anaphor-antecedent pairs.  Comment</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi mô tả hệ thống được tạo ra bởi Đội Mô Tử Xà cho CODI-CRAC 2021 sẻ chia sẻ Nhiệm vụ giải quyết Anaphora trong cuộc đối thoại. Hệ thống của chúng ta gồm ba hệ thống: 1) Hệ thống Điều tra phòng không Việc làm (WCS) liên tục nhắc đến việc sử dụng nét giống nhau theo ngữ pháp kết hợp với thần mạch chữ. (2) Hệ thống giải quyết khả năng hạn chế (M2M) cặp với một thực thể cùng nhắc đến; (3) Hệ thống phân giải Discourse Deixis (DDR) sử dụng một mạng lưới Xiêm để phát hiện các cặp ngôn ngữ. Kết quả WCS đã đạt được con số F1 của 505.6 quá cao hơn so với số thử nghiệm, M22M đã đạt được 57.2=. và DDR đã đạt được 21.5 Name</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>Opišemo sustav razvijen od strane DFKI-govornog robotskog tima za CODI-CRAC 2021. zajednički zadatak o rezoluciji anafore u dijalogu. Naš sustav se sastoji od tri podsustava: (1) sustav korisnosti radnog prostora (WCS) povećavajući skupine koristeći semantičku sličnost na osnovu ugrađenja kombiniranih s hekurističkim funkcijama. (2) Pari sustava za rješavanje pristojnosti (M2M) spominju isto područje;  (3) sustav diskursa Deixis Resolution (DDR) koristi Siamejsku mrežu za otkrivanje parova anafora-antecedent a diskursa. WCS je postigao srednji rezultat F1 od 55,6% u razdoblju testova za procjenu, M2M je postigao 57,2% i DDR postigao 21,5%.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Описваме системата, разработена от екипа на Говорещите роботи за Споделена задача за решаване на анафора в диалог. Нашата система се състои от три подсистеми: (1) Системата за кореференция на работното пространство (WCS) постепенно клъстери споменават, използващи семантична сходство въз основа на вграждания, комбинирани с лексикална характеристика евристика; (2) системата за преструктуриране на съвместни референции (М2M) се свързва с едно и също предприятие; (3) системата за резолюция на дискурсния деиксис (ДДР) използва сиамска мрежа за откриване на дискурсните анафорни двойки. WCS постига средна оценка от 55,6% във всички тестови комплекти за оценка, M2M постига 57,2% и DDR достига 21,5%.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Vi beskriver systemet udviklet af DFKI-TalkingRobots Team til CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task om anaphora løsning i dialog. Vores system består af tre delsystemer: (1) Workspace Coreference System (WCS) trinvist nævner klynger ved hjælp af semantisk lighed baseret på indlejringer kombineret med leksikalsk funktionsheuristik; (2) Mention-to-Mention (M2M) coreferenceafviklingssystemet parrer samme enhedsnævnelser (3) Diskurse Deixis Resolution (DDR) systemet anvender et siamesisk netværk til at detektere diskursanaphor-foregående par. WCS opnåede F1-score på 55,6% i gennemsnit på tværs af evalueringstestsættene, M2M opnåede 57,2% og DDR opnåede 21,5%.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Kami menggambarkan sistem yang dikembangkan oleh Tim Robot DFKI-Talkinguntuk CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task tentang resolusi anafora dalam dialog. Sistem kita terdiri dari tiga subsistem: (1) Sistem Koreferensi Ruang Kerja (WCS) secara incremental menyebutkan kumpulan menggunakan similaritas semantis berdasarkan embedding berkombinan dengan karakteristik lexik heuristik; (2) sistem resolusi koreferensi Mention-to-Mention (M2M) sepasang entitas yang sama menyebutkan; (3) Sistem Resolusi Deiksi Disors (DDR) menggunakan Jaringan Siama untuk mendeteksi pasangan anafora-sebelumnya diskors. WCS mencapai skor F1 55,6% rata-rata di seluruh set tes evaluasi, M2M mencapai 57,2% dan DDR mencapai 21,5%.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_nl>We beschrijven het systeem ontwikkeld door het DFKI-TalkingRobots Team voor de CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task over anafora resolutie in dialoog. Ons systeem bestaat uit drie subsystemen: (1) het Workspace Coreference System (WCS) incrementele clusters vermeldt semantische gelijkenis gebaseerd op embeddings gecombineerd met lexicale feature heuristics; (2) het systeem voor coreferentieresolutie tussen verwijzingen en verwijzingen (M2M) koppelt dezelfde entiteitsvermeldingen; (3) het Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) systeem maakt gebruik van een Siamees Netwerk om discoursanafore-antecedent paren te detecteren. WCS behaalde F1-score van 55,6% gemiddeld over de evaluatietestsets, M2M bereikte 57,2% en DDR bereikte 21,5%.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_ko>DFKI Talking Robots팀이 CODI-CRAC 2021 대화에서 공유 임무를 분석하기 위해 개발한 시스템을 설명합니다.우리의 시스템은 세 개의 서브시스템으로 구성된다. (1) 작업공간 공지시스템(WCS)은 삽입된 의미의 유사성을 바탕으로 어휘특징 계발법을 결합하여 언급을 증량 분류한다.(2) 언급 언급(M2M)은 모두 해소 시스템이 같은 실체에 대한 언급을 가리킨다.(3) 언어 지시 해소(DDR) 시스템은 연결 네트워크를 이용하여 말의 반지 선행어 쌍을 측정한다.WCS는 전체 평가 테스트가 집중된 F1에서 평균 55.6%, M2M 57.2%, DDR 21.5%의 점수를 받았다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaelezea mfumo uliotengenezwa na timu ya DFKI-Talking Robots kwa ajili ya CODI-CRAC 2021 Kushirikiana na jukumu la upasuaji wa picha katika mazungumzo. Mfumo wetu unajumuisha mifumo mitatu ya chini: (1) Mfumo wa Shirika la Kazini (WCS) unaongezea kuongezeka kwa kutaja tamaa kwa kutumia usawa wa kimapenzi kwa kutumia vifaa vinavyoungana na vizuri vya lexico; (2) Mfumo wa suluhisho linalohusiana na Mention-to-Mention (M2M) utambulisho wa mfumo wa suluhisho wa majina yanayofanana; (3) Mfumo wa Utetezi Deixis Hudumu (DDR) unatumia Mtandao wa Siamese kutambua mazungumzo yanayozungumzia wanandoa. WCS ilipata kiwango cha F1 cha wastani wa asilimia 55.6 katika seti za uchunguzi, M2M ilipata asilimia 57.2 na DDR ilipata asilimia 21.5.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_de>Wir beschreiben das vom DFKI-TalkingRobots Team entwickelte System für den CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task zur Anaphora-Auflösung im Dialog. Unser System besteht aus drei Subsystemen: (1) Das Workspace Coreference System (WCS) nennt inkrementelle Cluster, die semantische Ähnlichkeit basierend auf Einbettungen in Kombination mit lexikalischen Merkmalsheuristiken verwenden; (2) das M2M-Coreferenz-Resolutionssystem (Mention-to-Mention) paart dieselben Entitätenangaben; (3) Das Diskurse Deixis Resolution (DDR) System verwendet ein Siamesisches Netzwerk, um Diskursanalaphor-antecedente Paare zu erkennen. WCS erzielte einen F1-Score von 55,6% gemittelt über die Evaluationstestsätze, M2M erreichte 57,2% und DDR erreichte 21,5%.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>ما سیستم توسط تیم DFKI-Talking Robots برای CODI-CRAC 2021 مشخص می‌کنیم، که توسط تیم مشخص‌کننده روبات‌های مشخص شده است. سیستم ما از سه سیستم زیر سیستم است: (۱) سیستم تغییرات فضای کاری (WCS) با استفاده از شباهت semantic based on embeddings combined with lexical features heuristics را یاد می‌کند. (۲) سیستم حل رضایت یادآوری به یادآوری (M2M) جفتهای همان شرکت را یادآوری می‌کند. (۳) سیستم حل Deixis (DDR) گفتگو یک شبکه سیامی را برای شناسایی جفت‌های پیش‌بینی سخنرانی استفاده می‌کند. WCS با نمونه‌های F1 از 55.6% متوسط در مجموعه‌های امتحان ارزیابی رسید، M2M به 57.2% رسید و DDR به 21.5% رسید.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sq>Ne e përshkruajmë sistemin e zhvilluar nga ekipi DFKI-TalkingRobots për CODI-CRAC 2021-Task-Shared mbi zgjidhjen e anaforës në dialog. Sistemi ynë përbëhet nga tre nënsisteme: (1) grupet e Sistemit të Koreferencës në hapësirën e Punës (WCS) përmendin në mënyrë graduale duke përdorur ngjashmërinë semantike bazuar në përfshirje të kombinuara me heoristikën e karakteristikave lexike; (2) Sistemi i zgjidhjes së përkujtimit (M2M) përmend të njëjtën njësi; (3) Sistemi i Rezolucionit të Deksisit të Diskutit (DDR) përdorë një rrjet Siamese për të zbuluar çifte anaforike të diskursit. WCS arriti një rezultat F1 prej 55.6% mesatar në të gjithë grupet e testimeve të vlerësimit, M2M arriti 57.2% dhe DDR arriti 21.5%.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Biz sistemi CODI-CRAC 2021'iň anafora çözümlenmesi barada döwletlenmiş Biziň sistemimiz üç alt sistemlerden olup: (1) Iş ýerleşdirim sistemasy (WCS) iň köp görnüşler semantik ýaly çykyşlyklar bilen birleştirilýän guramlardan daşarylýar. (2) Mensiýet-tä Mensiýet (M2M) karýeterlik sistemi çözümlenmesi üçin bir eşit agzalaýar; (3) Gezgini Deixis Çözümleri (DDR) sistemi sözlerini anafür-öňkili çiftleri a ňlamak üçin bir syamy aňlap işleýär. WCS deňlenme testiň arasynda F1 अंश 55,6% tapdy, M2M 57,2% we DDR 21,5% tapdy.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>የCODI-CRAC 2021 የክፍለ ሥርዓት በናፎራ ውይይት ላይ የተሰራጨውን ስርዓት እናሳውቃለን፡፡ (1) የWorkspace Coreference System (2) ምርጫዎች (3) የDiscourse Deixis Resolution የWCS ቁጥር 55.6 በመቶ ቁጥር አግኝቷል፤ M2M 57.2 በመቶ አግኝቷል፤ DDR 21.5 በመቶ አግኝቷል።</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք նկարագրում ենք համակարգը, որը ստեղծվել է DFKI-Talking Ռոբոտների թիմի կողմից CODKI-Crac 2021 թվականի համագործակցային հանձնարարությունը անաֆորայի լուծման համար: Our system consists of three subsystems: (1) the Workspace Coreference System (WCS) incrementally clusters mentions using semantic similarity based on embeddings combined with lexical feature heuristics;  (2) Միշել-մինչև-Միշել (M2M) համակարգը հարաբերությունների լուծման համակարգը զուգավորում է նույն անհատականությունը: (3) Դեքսուրս Դեքսի Ռեզոլուցիայի (DDD) համակարգը օգտագործում է սիամական ցանց, որպեսզի հայտնաբերի խոսքի անաֆորային նախկին զույգեր: ՀՀԿ-ն հասավ 55.6 տոկոսի F1-ի արդյունքի, որը հաշվի առկա էր գնահատման փորձարկումների ընթացքում, M2M-ը հասավ 57.2 տոկոսի, իսկ DDD-ը հասավ 21.5 տոկոսի:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Biz CODI-CRAC 2021 üçün DFKI-Talking Robot Takımı təhsil etdiyi sistemi anafora çözünürlüyü barəsində paylaşır. Bizim sistemimiz üç altsistem içindədir: (1) İş alanı Koreferens Sistemi (WCS) çox çox çox soxurlar, leksik özellikləri heuristik ilə birləşdirilmiş inbinglərə dayanan semantik similarlığı istifadə edir; (2) Mention-to-Mention (M2M) mərhəmət çəkişmə sisteminin cütləri istifadə edir; (3) Diskusiya Deixis Resolution (DDR) sistemi söhbətləri anafori-antezident çiftləri keşfetmək üçün Siamlı Ağ istifadə edir. WCS değerləşdirmə sınaqları arasında ortalama 55,6% F1 dəyişdi, M2M 57,2% və DDR 21,5% oldu.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_af>Ons beskrywe die stelsel wat deur die DFKI-Praat-Robots-Skep ontwikkeld is vir die CODI-CRAC 2021 Gedeelde-Opdrag op anafora-resolusie in dialoog. Ons stelsel bestaan van drie substelsels: (1) die Werkskerm Koreferensie Stelsel (WCS) inkremensielik klassters met gebruik van semantiese gelykenis gebaseer op inbêdings gekombineer met leksiese funksie heuristiek; ons stelsel bestaan van drie substelsels: (2) die Kieslys-na-Kieslys (3) die Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) stelsel gebruik 'n Siamese Netwerk om diskursie anaphor- antecedent paar te ontdek. WCS het F1- telling van 55. 6% gemiddeld deur die evaluering toets stel, M2M het 57. 2% en DDR 21. 5% bereik.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_bn>ডিএফকিআই-ট্যাকিং রোবট ট টিম দ্বারা উন্নয়নের সিস্টেমের বর্ণনা করেছি কোডিআই-CRAC ২০২১ সালের বিভিন্ন সিস্টেমের বিভিন্ন ড আমাদের সিস্টেমের মধ্যে তিনটি সাবসিস্টেম রয়েছে: (১) কার্যস্পেস কোরিফারেন্স সিস্টেম (উইডিসি) বাড়তে থাকে সেমেন্টিক সমতা ব্যবহার করে লেক্সিক্সি (2) মেনুষ- থেকে মেনুন (M2M) কোরেফেন্স সিস্টেমের রিলেশন সিস্টেমের জোড়া একই বস্তুর উল্লেখ; (3) ডিস্কোর্স ডেইক্সিস রিপলেশন (ডিডিআর) সিয়ামের নেটওয়ার্ক ব্যবস্থা চালাচ্ছে যাতে কথোপকথন ব্যানাফার-এন্টেসেডেন্ট জ উইএসএস মূল্য পরীক্ষা সেটের মধ্যে ৫৫. ৬% স্কোর অর্জন করেছে, এম২এম ৫৭. ২% অর্জন করেছে এবং ডিডিআর ২১.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Opišemo sistem razvijen od strane DFKI-govornog robotskog tima za CODI-CRAC 2021. zajednički zadatak o rezoluciji anafore u dijalogu. Naš sistem se sastoji od tri podsustava: (1) sustav korisnosti radnog prostora (WCS) povećavajući skupove upotrebljavajući semantičku sličnost na osnovu ugrađenja kombiniranih sa heurističkim funkcijama leksičke funkcije; (2) Par sustava za rješavanje pristojnosti (M2M) koji se spominju isto područje; (3) Sistem diskursa Deixis Resolution (DDR) koristi Siamejsku mrežu za otkrivanje parova anafora-antecedent a diskursa. WCS je postigao srednji rezultat F1 od 55,6% u razdoblju testova za procjenu, M2M je postigao 57,2% i DDR postigao 21,5%.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Descrivem el sistema desenvolupat per l'equip DFKI-TalkingRobots del CODI-CRAC 2021 Task Shared on anaphora resolution en diàleg. El nostre sistema consisteix en tres subsistemes: (1) el Sistema de Coreferència de l'espai de treball (WCS) menciona incrementalment agrupaments fent servir similitud semàntica basada en incorporacions combinades amb heurística de característiques lècsiques; (2) el sistema de resolució de coreferència Menció a Menció (M2M) es parella amb la mateixa entitat; (3) el sistema de resolució del deix de discurs (DDR) utilitza una xarxa siamese per detectar parells anafòrics. La WCS va aconseguir una puntuació F1 del 55,6% mitjana en els conjunts de tests d'evaluació, el M2M va aconseguir un 57,2% i el DDR va aconseguir un 21,5%.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Popisujeme systém vyvinutý DFKI-TalkingRobots Team pro CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task na řešení anafory v dialogu. Náš systém se skládá ze tří subsystémů: (1) systém Workspace Coreference System (WCS) inkrementálně shlukuje zmínky za použití sémantické podobnosti založené na vložení kombinované s lexikální heuristikou prvků; (2) systém řešení koreferencí mezi zmínkami (M2M) páruje stejnou entitu zmínku; (3) Diskurse Deixis Resolution (DDR) systém využívá siamskou síť k detekci párů anafory a předcházejících diskursů. WCS dosáhl F1 skóre 55,6% průměrného v hodnotících testovacích sadách, M2M dosáhl 57,2% a DDR 21,5%.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Kirjeldame DFKI-TalkingRobots Team poolt CODI-CRAC 2021 jagatud ülesande jaoks välja töötatud süsteemi anafoori lahendamiseks dialoogis. Meie süsteem koosneb kolmest alamsüsteemist: (1) tööruumi koreferensi süsteem (WCS) järjestikuselt klastrid märgivad semantilist sarnasust, mis põhineb manustamisel kombineeritud leksikaalsete omaduste heuristikal; (2) märkimisväärse kriisilahenduse süsteem (M2M) paarides sama üksuse mainib; (3) Diskursuse Deixis Resolution (DDR) süsteem kasutab diskursuse anafoori-eelnevate paaride tuvastamiseks Siiami võrgustikku. WCS saavutas F1-skoori 55,6%, M2M saavutas 57,2% ja DDR 21,5%.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Kuvaamme DFKI-TalkingRobots -tiimin CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task -ohjelmalle kehitt瓣m瓣瓣 j瓣rjestelm瓣瓣 anaforan ratkaisuun dialogissa. J瓣rjestelm瓣mme koostuu kolmesta osaj瓣rjestelm瓣st瓣: (1) Workspace Coreference System (WCS) ker瓣瓣 vaiheittain mainintoja k瓣ytt瓣en semanttista samankaltaisuutta, joka perustuu upotuksiin yhdistettyn瓣 leksikaaliseen ominaisuusheuristiikkaan; (2) Mainittu-maininnalle (M2M) -yhteisferenssikriisinratkaisuj瓣rjestelm瓣 parittaa saman yksik繹n maininnat; (3) Diskursse Deixis Resolution (DDR) -j瓣rjestelm瓣 k瓣ytt瓣瓣 siamilaista verkostoa diskurssianaforin ja edelt瓣vien parien havaitsemiseen. WCS saavutti F1-pisteen 55,6% kaikissa arviointitestisarjoissa, M2M saavutti 57,2% ja DDR 21,5%.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו מתארים את המערכת שפותחת על ידי צוות רובוטים מדברים DFKI עבור משימה משותפת CODI-CRAC 2021 על פתרון אנפורה בדיולוג. Our system consists of three subsystems: (1) the Workspace Coreference System (WCS) incrementally clusters mentions using semantic similarity based on embeddings combined with lexical feature heuristics;  (2) מערכת פתרון התאמה הזכרה-לזכרה (M2M) זוגות את אותה יחידה הזכרה; (3) מערכת פיתרון דיסקרס דיקסי (DDR) משתמשת ברשת סיאמית כדי לגלות זוגות anaphor-קודמות דיסקרס. WCS achieved F1-score of 55.6% averaged across the evaluation test sets, M2M achieved 57.2% and DDR achieved 21.5%.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Opisujemo sistem, ki ga je razvila ekipa DFKI-TalkingRobots za skupno nalogo CODI-CRAC 2021 o reševanju anafore v dialogu. Naš sistem je sestavljen iz treh podsistemov: (1) sistem delovnega prostora Coreference System (WCS) postopoma združuje omembe z uporabo semantične podobnosti, ki temelji na vdelavah v kombinaciji z leksikalno funkcijsko heuristiko; (2) sistem reševanja jedrske reference z omenjanjem (M2M) je naveden v paru istega subjekta; (3) sistem Diskurze Deixis Resolution (DDR) uporablja siamsko mrežo za odkrivanje diskurznih anaforskih parov. WCS je dosegel rezultat F1 55,6% v povprečju med vrednotenjskimi preskusnimi sklopi, M2M 57,2% in DDR 21,5%.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Awakdhéwé ngerwih sistem nggawe Daftar DFKi-TalkingJobot Group nggawe cordi-crit 2020 1 Joined-task nang resolusi anaphora neng dialog Sistem awak dhéwé mulai telu babaran.(1) Workspace corefensi System (2) Mention-to-Mention (M2M) corefection System Resolution (3) Sistem Diskurasi Dextir Resolusi (DDra) kang sistem sistem sistem gunakake Siamsi Network nggawe perintah kejahatan anaphor-antacedent. Where</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna bayyana na'urar da aka buɗe na DFKI-Talkin Robot Team wa the CODA-CRac 2021 Shared-Tafiyar da yin fassarar masu motsi cikin zauren akwatin bayani. Tsarinmu na ƙunsa da nau'i uku:(1) Shirin Ayuka na Shirin aiki (WSA) na ƙara ƙaranci da ake amfani da sunan-zane ta zama daidaici da kwamfyutan da aka haɗa da takardar heuristics; (2) Babbar-mazaɓa-zuwa-mazaɓa (M2M) sunayen sunayen ayuka na'ura masu nau'in abun ɗaya; (3) Cikakken Bayanci na Deikis (DDR) na amfani da Shiamese ɗin zai iya gano nau'in-biyu. WSA ya kai F1-score na 55.6% mai tsakanin kowace a matsayin evaluation, M2M ya kai 57.2% kuma DDR ya kai 21.5%.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་མ་ལག་གི་དབྱིབས་DFKI-TalkingRobots Team་ལ་སྤྱོད་པའི་རྩིས་ཐོག་གླེང་སྒྲོམ་ནང་དུ་CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared-Task སྒྲིག་གཏོང་བ Our system consists of three subsystems: (1) the Workspace Coreference System (WCS) incrementally clusters mentions using semantic similarity based on embeddings combined with lexical feature heuristics; and (2) འདེམས་ཐོག་ལས་འདེམས་ཐོག་གནང་བའི་དབྱིབས་སྒྲིག་གི་མ་ལག་གི་མཐུན་གྲངས་ཀ་གཅིག་མཚུངས་ཡིན། (3) the Discourse Deixis Resolution (DDR) system employs a Siamese Network to detect discourse anaphor-antecedent pairs. WCS achieved F1-score of 55.6% averaged across the evaluation test sets, M2M achieved 57.2% and DDR achieved 21.5%.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>The CODI-CRAC 2021 Shared Task on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anaphora_(linguistics)">Anaphora</a>, Bridging, and Discourse Deixis Resolution in Dialogue : A Cross-Team Analysis<fixed-case>CODI</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>CRAC</fixed-case> 2021 Shared Task on Anaphora, Bridging, and Discourse Deixis Resolution in Dialogue: A Cross-Team Analysis</title>
      <author><first>Shengjie</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <author><first>Hideo</first><last>Kobayashi</last></author>
      <author><first>Vincent</first><last>Ng</last></author>
      <pages>71–95</pages>
      <abstract>The CODI-CRAC 2021 shared task is the first shared task that focuses exclusively on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anaphora_(linguistics)">anaphora resolution</a> in dialogue and provides three tracks, namely entity coreference resolution, bridging resolution, and discourse deixis resolution. We perform a cross-task analysis of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> that participated in the shared task in each of these tracks.</abstract>
      <url hash="e549ffdc">2021.codi-sharedtask.8</url>
      <bibkey>li-etal-2021-codi</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.codi-sharedtask.8</doi>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>