<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.tacl">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Volume 9</booktitle>
      <editor><last>Roark</last><first>Brian</first></editor>
      <editor><last>Nenkova</last><first>Ani</first></editor>
      <publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
      <address>Cambridge, MA</address>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Revisiting Multi-Domain Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>MinhQuang</first><last>Pham</last></author>
      <author><first>Josep Maria</first><last>Crego</last></author>
      <author><first>François</first><last>Yvon</last></author>
      <doi>10.1162/tacl_a_00351</doi>
      <abstract>When building <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation systems</a>, one often needs to make the best out of heterogeneous sets of parallel data in training, and to robustly handle inputs from unexpected domains in testing. This multi-domain scenario has attracted a lot of recent work that fall under the general umbrella of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">transfer learning</a>. In this study, we revisit multi-domain machine translation, with the aim to formulate the motivations for developing such systems and the associated expectations with respect to performance. Our experiments with a large sample of multi-domain systems show that most of these expectations are hardly met and suggest that further work is needed to better analyze the current behaviour of multi-domain systems and to make them fully hold their promises.</abstract>
      <pages>17–35</pages>
      <url hash="d31dab0a">2021.tacl-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>pham-etal-2021-revisiting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Conversation Graph : Data Augmentation, Training, and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialogue Management</title>
      <author><first>Milan</first><last>Gritta</last></author>
      <author><first>Gerasimos</first><last>Lampouras</last></author>
      <author><first>Ignacio</first><last>Iacobacci</last></author>
      <doi>10.1162/tacl_a_00352</doi>
      <abstract>Task-oriented dialogue systems typically rely on large amounts of high-quality training data or require complex handcrafted rules. However, existing datasets are often limited in size con- sidering the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complexity">complexity</a> of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue">dialogues</a>. Additionally, conventional training signal in- ference is not suitable for non-deterministic agent behavior, namely, considering multiple actions as valid in identical dialogue states. We propose the Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), a graph-based representation of dialogues that can be exploited for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_augmentation">data augmentation</a>, multi- reference training and evaluation of non- deterministic agents. ConvGraph generates novel dialogue paths to augment data volume and diversity. Intrinsic and extrinsic evaluation across three datasets shows that data augmentation and/or multi-reference training with ConvGraph can improve dialogue success rates by up to 6.4 %.</abstract>
      <pages>36–52</pages>
      <url hash="15fc1f8e">2021.tacl-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>gritta-etal-2021-conversation</bibkey>
    <title_fr>Graphique de conversation : augmentation des données, formation et évaluation pour la gestion de dialogue non déterministe</title_fr>
      <title_ar>الرسم البياني للمحادثة: زيادة البيانات والتدريب والتقييم لإدارة الحوار غير الحتمي</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Gráfico de conversação: aumento de dados, treinamento e avaliação para gerenciamento de diálogo não determinístico</title_pt>
      <title_es>Gráfico de conversación: aumento de datos, capacitación y evaluación para la gestión del diálogo no determinista</title_es>
      <title_ja>会話グラフ：非決定論的対話管理のためのデータ拡張、トレーニング、および評価</title_ja>
      <title_zh>对话图:非确定性对数增强、训练、评估</title_zh>
      <title_ru>Диалоговый график: расширение данных, обучение и оценка для управления недетерминированным диалогом</title_ru>
      <title_hi>वार्तालाप ग्राफ़: गैर-नियतात्मक संवाद प्रबंधन के लिए डेटा संवर्धन, प्रशिक्षण, और मूल्यांकन</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Graf Comhrá: Méadú ar Shonraí, Oiliúint agus Measúnú le haghaidh Bainistíocht Neamhchinntitheach Agallaimh</title_ga>
      <title_ka>პარაუზაცია გრაფიკა: მონაცემები აგგენტირება, განაწყვება და განაწყვება არ განაწყვეტირებულ დიალოგის მართვის</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Beszélgetési grafikon: Adatbővítés, képzés és értékelés a nem meghatározó párbeszédkezeléshez</title_hu>
      <title_it>Grafico di conversazione: Aumento dei dati, formazione e valutazione per la gestione del dialogo non deterministico</title_it>
      <title_el>Γράφημα συνομιλίας: Επέκταση δεδομένων, εκπαίδευση και αξιολόγηση για τη διαχείριση μη-αποφασιστικού διαλόγου</title_el>
      <title_kk>Сөйлесу график: Деректерді өзгерту, оқыту және бағалау диалогты басқару үшін деректерді өзгерту</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Граф за конверзација: Агментација на податоците, обука и евалуација за менаџмент на дијалогот без одредување</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Perskaičiavimo grafikas: duomenų didinimas, mokymas ir vertinimas, susijęs su dialogo valdymu ne determinacijomis</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Graf Perbualan: Pengembangan Data, Latihan, dan Evaluasi untuk Pengurusan Dialog Tidak Deterministik</title_ms>
      <title_ml>സംസാരം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Grafika ta’ Konverżjoni: Żieda fid-Dejta, Taħriġ u Evalwazzjoni għall-Ġestjoni tad-Djalogu Mhux Deterministiku</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Conversation Graph: Data Augmentation, Training, and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialog Management</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Wykres konwersacji: Rozszerzenie danych, szkolenie i ocena dla niedeterministycznego zarządzania dialogiem</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Graficul conversației: Augmentarea datelor, instruirea și evaluarea pentru managementul dialogului non-determinist</title_ro>
      <title_si>සංවාදය ග්‍රාෆ්: දත්ත විශාලනය, ප්‍රධානය, සහ අවශ්‍යාත්මක සංවාදය පාලනය සඳහා දත්ත විශාලනය</title_si>
      <title_so>Graph la xiriirka: Aqoonsiga macluumaadka, Waxbarashada iyo kaartaynta diyaariga aan la aqoonin</title_so>
      <title_sv>Konversationsdiagram: dataförstärkning, utbildning och utvärdering för icke-deterministisk dialog hantering</title_sv>
      <title_ta>பேச்சு வரைப்படம்:</title_ta>
      <title_ur>تبلیغ گراف: ڈاٹا اگنٹمنٹ، ٹرینینگ، اور مطالعہ غیر معلوم ڈیلوگو منظورت کے لئے</title_ur>
      <title_sr>Graf razgovora: Povećavanje podataka, obuka i procjena za upravljanje neodređenim dijalogima</title_sr>
      <title_no>Samtalegraf: Data Augmentation, Training and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialog Management</title_no>
      <title_uz>Dialog boshqaruvchisi uchun maò¥lumot bogò£lash, taò¥minlovchi va taò¥minlovchi darajasi</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Máy tính đối thoại: gia tăng dữ liệu, đào tạo và đánh giá đối phó</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Графика за разговори: Увеличаване на данни, обучение и оценка за управление на недетерминистичен диалог</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Gespreksgrafiek: Data Augmentation, Training en Evaluatie voor niet-deterministisch dialoogbeheer</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Graf razgovora: Povećanje podataka, obuka i procjena za upravljanje nedodređenim dijalogima</title_hr>
      <title_da>Conversation Graph: Dataudvidelse, uddannelse og evaluering til ikke-deterministisk dialog styring</title_da>
      <title_ko>대화도: 비확정적 대화 관리의 데이터 확충, 교육과 평가</title_ko>
      <title_fa>گراف گفتگو: افزایش داده‌ها، آموزش و ارزیابی برای مدیریت گفتگوی غیر معلوم</title_fa>
      <title_de>Konversationsgrafik: Datenerweiterung, -training und -auswertung für nicht-deterministisches Dialogmanagement</title_de>
      <title_sw>Conversation Graph: Data Augmentation, Training, and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialogue Management</title_sw>
      <title_id>Graf konversasi: Data Augmentation, Training, and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialogue Management</title_id>
      <title_tr>New conversations Graph: Data Augmentation, Training, and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialog Management</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Grafi i konversimit: rritja e të dhënave, stërvitja dhe vlerësimi për menazhimin e dialogut jo-determinativ</title_sq>
      <title_af>Gespraak Graf: Data Augmentation, Training, en Evaluering vir Non- Deterministic Dialog Management</title_af>
      <title_hy>Խոսակցության գրաֆիկ. տվյալների աճը, պատրաստվածությունը և գնահատումը ոչ որոշող պատմությունների ղեկավարման համար</title_hy>
      <title_az>Qonuşma Grafiki: Data Augmentation, Training and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialog Management</title_az>
      <title_am>Conversation Graph: Data Augmentation, Training, and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialogue Management</title_am>
      <title_bn>আলোচনা</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Graf razgovora: povećanje podataka, obuka i procjena za upravljanje nedodređenim dijalogima</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Konverzační graf: Rozšíření dat, školení a hodnocení pro nederministické řízení dialogu</title_cs>
      <title_et>Vestlusgraafik: andmete täiendamine, koolitus ja hindamine mittedeterministliku dialoogi haldamiseks</title_et>
      <title_fi>Keskustelukuvio: Tiedon lisääminen, koulutus ja arviointi ei-deterministisen vuoropuhelun hallintaa varten</title_fi>
      <title_ca>Gràfic de conversació: augment de dades, formació i evaluació de la gestió del diàleg no determinant</title_ca>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>Graph Conversation: Data Augmentation, Training, and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialogue Management</title_he>
      <title_sk>Graf pogovora: Povečanje podatkov, usposabljanje in vrednotenje za upravljanje nedeterminističnega dialoga</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Conversation Graph: Data Augmentation, Training and Evaluation for Non-Deterministic Dialog Management</title_bo>
      <title_jv>New</title_jv>
      <abstract_ar>تعتمد أنظمة الحوار الموجه نحو المهام عادةً على كميات كبيرة من بيانات التدريب عالية الجودة أو تتطلب قواعد معقدة مصنوعة يدويًا. ومع ذلك ، غالبًا ما تكون مجموعات البيانات الحالية محدودة الحجم نظرًا لتعقيد الحوارات. بالإضافة إلى ذلك ، فإن إشارة التدريب التقليدية ليست مناسبة لسلوك الوكيل غير الحتمي ، أي اعتبار الإجراءات المتعددة صالحة في حالات الحوار المتطابقة. نقترح الرسم البياني للمحادثة (ConvGraph) ، وهو تمثيل قائم على الرسم البياني للحوارات يمكن استغلاله لزيادة البيانات والتدريب متعدد المراجع وتقييم العوامل غير الحتمية. ينشئ ConvGraph مسارات حوار جديدة لزيادة حجم البيانات والتنوع. يُظهر التقييم الداخلي والخارجي عبر ثلاث مجموعات بيانات أن زيادة البيانات و / أو التدريب متعدد المراجع باستخدام ConvGraph يمكن أن يحسن معدلات نجاح الحوار بنسبة تصل إلى 6.4٪.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Os sistemas de diálogo orientados a tarefas geralmente dependem de grandes quantidades de dados de treinamento de alta qualidade ou exigem regras complexas feitas à mão. No entanto, os conjuntos de dados existentes são frequentemente limitados em tamanho, considerando a complexidade dos diálogos. Além disso, a inferência de sinal de treinamento convencional não é adequada para o comportamento não determinístico do agente, ou seja, considerando múltiplas ações como válidas em estados de diálogo idênticos. Propomos o Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), uma representação gráfica de diálogos que pode ser explorada para aumento de dados, treinamento multirreferência e avaliação de agentes não determinísticos. O ConvGraph gera novos caminhos de diálogo para aumentar o volume e a diversidade de dados. A avaliação intrínseca e extrínseca em três conjuntos de dados mostra que o aumento de dados e/ou treinamento multirreferência com o ConvGraph pode melhorar as taxas de sucesso do diálogo em até 6,4%.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Los sistemas de diálogo orientados a tareas suelen basarse en grandes cantidades de datos de formación de alta calidad o requieren reglas complejas elaboradas a mano. Sin embargo, los conjuntos de datos existentes a menudo tienen un tamaño limitado, teniendo en cuenta la complejidad de los diálogos. Además, la interferencia de señales de entrenamiento convencional no es adecuada para el comportamiento no determinista del agente, es decir, considerar múltiples acciones como válidas en estados de diálogo idénticos. Proponemos el Gráfico de conversación (ConvGraph), una representación gráfica de diálogos que se puede aprovechar para el aumento de datos, el entrenamiento de múltiples referencias y la evaluación de agentes no deterministas. ConvGraph genera nuevas vías de diálogo para aumentar el volumen y la diversidad de los datos. La evaluación intrínseca y extrínseca en tres conjuntos de datos muestra que el aumento de datos o la capacitación en múltiples referencias con ConvGraph pueden mejorar las tasas de éxito de los diálogos hasta en un 6,4%.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>Les systèmes de dialogue axés sur les tâches reposent généralement sur de grandes quantités de données d'entraînement de haute qualité ou nécessitent des règles artisanales complexes. Cependant, les ensembles de données existants sont souvent de taille limitée compte tenu de la complexité des dialogues. De plus, l'interférence de signal d'entraînement conventionnelle ne convient pas au comportement non déterministe d'un agent, c'est-à-dire que l'on considère que plusieurs actions sont valides dans des états de dialogue identiques. Nous proposons le graphique de conversation (ConvGraph), une représentation graphique des dialogues qui peut être exploitée pour l'augmentation des données, la formation multi-références et l'évaluation d'agents non déterministes. ConvGraph génère de nouveaux chemins de dialogue pour augmenter le volume et la diversité des données. L'évaluation intrinsèque et extrinsèque de trois ensembles de données montre que l'augmentation des données et/ou la formation multi-références avec ConvGraph peuvent améliorer les taux de réussite des dialogues jusqu'à 6,4 %.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>タスク指向の対話システムは、通常、大量の高品質のトレーニングデータに依存するか、複雑な手作りルールを必要とします。しかし、既存のデータセットは、ダイアログの複雑さを考慮してサイズが制限されていることが多い。さらに、従来のトレーニング信号は、非決定論的なエージェントの行動、すなわち、複数のアクションを同一の対話状態で有効であると見なすことには適していない。データ拡張、マルチリファレンスのトレーニング、非決定論的エージェントの評価に利用できるダイアログのグラフベースの表現である会話グラフ（ ConvGraph ）を提案します。ConvGraphは、新しいダイアログパスを生成して、データ量と多様性を増大させます。3つのデータセットにわたる内在的および外在的評価は、ConvGraphを使用したデータ拡張および/またはマルチレファレンストレーニングが、対話成功率を最大6.4%向上させることができることを示しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>向任之对,常依大高质量训练,或须杂手工作法。 然见数集大小,往往限之,与对语之复杂性也。 又旧法训号不宜非确定性摄行,即以为多同对。 臣等发对图(ConvGraph),盖图之对,可施于数,多参练非确定性之评。 ConvGraph生新语路,以增数据量多样性。 三集之内,外之评明,ConvGraph之增/,参之训练,可以成功率6.4%。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>कार्य-उन्मुख संवाद प्रणाली आमतौर पर उच्च गुणवत्ता वाले प्रशिक्षण डेटा की बड़ी मात्रा पर भरोसा करती है या जटिल हस्तशिल्प नियमों की आवश्यकता होती है। हालांकि, मौजूदा डेटासेट अक्सर संवादों की जटिलता को दरकिनार करते हुए आकार में सीमित होते हैं। इसके अतिरिक्त, पारंपरिक प्रशिक्षण संकेत गैर-नियतात्मक एजेंट व्यवहार के लिए उपयुक्त नहीं है, अर्थात्, समान संवाद राज्यों में मान्य के रूप में कई कार्यों पर विचार करना। हम वार्तालाप ग्राफ (ConvGraph) का प्रस्ताव करते हैं, जो संवादों का एक ग्राफ-आधारित प्रतिनिधित्व है जिसका उपयोग डेटा वृद्धि, बहु-संदर्भ प्रशिक्षण और गैर-नियतात्मक एजेंटों के मूल्यांकन के लिए किया जा सकता है। ConvGraph डेटा की मात्रा और विविधता को बढ़ाने के लिए उपन्यास संवाद पथ उत्पन्न करता है। तीन डेटासेट में आंतरिक और बाह्य मूल्यांकन से पता चलता है कि ConvGraph के साथ डेटा वृद्धि और / या बहु-संदर्भ प्रशिक्षण 6.4% तक संवाद सफलता दर में सुधार कर सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Системы диалога, ориентированные на решение конкретных задач, как правило, опираются на большой объем высококачественных учебных данных или требуют сложных правил, разработанных вручную. Тем не менее, существующие наборы данных часто ограничены по размеру, учитывая сложность диалогов. Кроме того, обычная последовательность тренировочных сигналов не подходит для недетерминированного поведения агента, а именно, считая несколько действий действительными в идентичных диалоговых состояниях. Мы предлагаем Диалоговый Граф (ConvGraph), графическое представление диалогов, которое может быть использовано для увеличения данных, многоцелевого обучения и оценки недетерминированных агентов. ConvGraph создает новые диалоговые пути для увеличения объема и разнообразия данных. Внутренняя и внешняя оценка трех наборов данных показывает, что расширение данных и/или мультиреференсное обучение с помощью ConvGraph может улучшить показатели успеха диалога до 6,4%.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Go hiondúil bíonn córais dialóige atá dírithe ar thascanna ag brath ar mhéideanna móra sonraí oiliúna ardchaighdeáin nó éilíonn siad rialacha casta lámhdhéanta. Mar sin féin, is minic a bhíonn na tacair sonraí atá ann faoi láthair teoranta ó thaobh méide de ag cur san áireamh castacht na gcomhphlé. Ina theannta sin, níl tátail chomhartha traenála traidisiúnta oiriúnach d'iompar oibreora neamhchinntitheach, eadhon, ilghníomhaíochtaí a mheas mar ghníomhartha bailí i stáit chomhphlé comhionann. Molaimid an Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), léiriú graf-bhunaithe ar chomhphlé ar féidir leas a bhaint as chun sonraí a mhéadú, oiliúint il-tagartha agus meastóireacht a dhéanamh ar ghníomhairí neamhchinntitheacha. Gineann ConvGraph conairí núíosacha idirphlé chun cur le méid sonraí agus éagsúlacht. Léiríonn meastóireacht intreach agus eistreach thar thrí thacar sonraí gur féidir le méadú sonraí agus/nó oiliúint il-tagartha le ConvGraph rátaí ratha idirphlé a fheabhsú suas le 6.4%.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>სამუშაო დიალოგის სისტემები, როგორც ტიპულად უფრო დიდი სამუშაო სამუშაო მონაცემების მონაცემებისთვის, ან უნდა დაჭირდება კომპლე მაგრამ არსებობს მონაცემების კომპლექსიტეტი დიალოგების კომპლექსიტეტის ზომაში უფრო დაფარდება. დამატებით, კონტუნციონალური განაცემის სიგნალის ინფერენცია არ შესაძლებელია განსაზღვრული ადვნენტის ქცევისთვის, ანუ, რაც მრავალური მოქმედება იდენტიკური დიალოგის ღ ჩვენ შეგიძლიათ განსაუბრება გრაფიკა (ConvGraph), დიალოგების გრაფიკური გამოსახულება, რომელიც შეიძლია გამოიყენება მონაცემების აგგენტაციისთვის, მრავალური განსახულება და არ განსაზღვრული ადვნ Name სამი მონაცემების განსაზღვრებაში ინტერრინსიკური და ექსტრინსიკური განსაზღვრება ჩვენებს, რომ მონაცემები აზექტირება და/ან მრავალური განსაზღვრების განსაზღვრება ConvGraph-ის შესაძ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Τα συστήματα διαλόγου προσανατολισμένα στις εργασίες βασίζονται συνήθως σε μεγάλες ποσότητες υψηλής ποιότητας δεδομένα κατάρτισης ή απαιτούν πολύπλοκους χειροποίητους κανόνες. Ωστόσο, τα υπάρχοντα σύνολα δεδομένων είναι συχνά περιορισμένα σε μέγεθος λαμβάνοντας υπόψη την πολυπλοκότητα των διαλόγων. Επιπλέον, η συμβατική μετάδοση σήματος εκπαίδευσης δεν είναι κατάλληλη για μη ντετερμινιστική συμπεριφορά παραγόντων, δηλαδή, θεωρώντας πολλαπλές ενέργειες έγκυρες σε πανομοιότυπες καταστάσεις διαλόγου. Προτείνουμε το γράφημα συνομιλίας (μια απεικόνιση διαλόγων βασισμένων σε γραφήματα που μπορούν να αξιοποιηθούν για την αύξηση δεδομένων, την εκπαίδευση πολλαπλών αναφορών και την αξιολόγηση μη ντετερμινιστικών παραγόντων. Το παράγει καινοτόμες διαδρομές διαλόγου για να αυξήσει τον όγκο και την ποικιλομορφία δεδομένων. Η εσωτερική και εξωτερική αξιολόγηση σε τρία σύνολα δεδομένων δείχνει ότι η αύξηση δεδομένων ή/και η εκπαίδευση πολλαπλών αναφορών με ConvGraph μπορεί να βελτιώσει τα ποσοστά επιτυχίας διαλόγου μέχρι 6.4%.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A feladatorientált párbeszédrendszerek jellemzően nagy mennyiségű, kiváló minőségű képzési adatokra támaszkodnak, vagy bonyolult kézműves szabályokat igényelnek. A meglévő adatkészletek azonban gyakran korlátozott méretűek, tekintettel a párbeszédek összetettségére. Ezenkívül a hagyományos edzési jel in- ferencia nem alkalmas nem determinisztikus ügynök viselkedésére, nevezetesen több műveletet tekintve ugyanazon párbeszédállapotokban érvényesnek. Javasoljuk a Conversation Graph (ConvGraph) párbeszédek grafikon alapú ábrázolását, amely adatbővítésre, többreferencia képzésre és nem determinisztikus szereplők értékelésére használható. A ConvGraph új párbeszédutakat hoz létre az adatok mennyiségének és sokszínűségének növelésére. A három adatkészleten végzett belső és külső értékelés azt mutatja, hogy a ConvGraph segítségével végzett adatbővítés és/vagy többreferencia-képzés akár 6,4%-kal is javíthatja a párbeszédek sikerességét.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>I sistemi di dialogo orientati alle attività di solito si basano su grandi quantità di dati formativi di alta qualità o richiedono complesse regole artigianali. Tuttavia, i set di dati esistenti sono spesso limitati in termini di dimensioni, tenuto conto della complessità dei dialoghi. Inoltre, il segnale di addestramento convenzionale non è adatto al comportamento non deterministico dell'agente, vale a dire considerare azioni multiple come valide in stati di dialogo identici. Proponiamo il Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), una rappresentazione grafica di dialoghi utilizzabili per l'aumento dei dati, la formazione multi-riferimento e la valutazione di agenti non deterministici. ConvGraph genera nuovi percorsi di dialogo per aumentare il volume e la diversità dei dati. La valutazione intrinseca ed estrinseca su tre set di dati mostra che l'aumento dei dati e/o la formazione multi-riferimento con ConvGraph possono migliorare i tassi di successo dei dialoghi fino al 6,4%.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Тапсырмалар бағытталған диалог жүйелері кәдімгі сапатты оқыту деректерінің үлкен сандарына тәуелді немесе комплексті қолдану ережелерін талап етеді. Бірақ бар деректер жиындары диалогтардың көпшілігін бағыттау үшін шектелген болады. Сонымен қатар, кәдімгі оқыту сигналы бір диалог күйінде бірнеше әрекеттерді дұрыс деп қарай алатын агенттердің қасиеттері үшін дефицистикалық емес. Біз мәліметтерді көбейту, көптеген сілтемелерді оқыту және дефицистикалық емес агенттер үшін қолданылатын диалогтардың графика негізінде негізделген сұлбатын график (ConvGraph) деп ұсынамыз. ConvGraph деректер үнділігін және әртүрлігін көтеру үшін жаңа диалог жолдарын құрады. Үш деректер жинағында ішкі және сыртқы оқиғалар ConvGraph деген деректерді көбейту және/немесе көбейтік сілтемелер оқиғаларының диалог сәттілігін 6,4% деп жақсартуға болады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Į užduotis orientuotos dialogo sistemos paprastai grindžiamos dideliu kokybiško mokymo duomenų kiekiu arba reikalauja sudėtingų rankinių taisyklių. Tačiau esami duomenų rinkiniai dažnai yra riboti atsižvelgiant į dialogų sudėtingumą. Be to, įprastinis mokymo signalo sutrikimas netinka nenustatytų veiksnių elgesiui, būtent, atsižvelgiant į tai, kad keli veiksmai galioja vienodomis dialogo sąlygomis. Siūlome konversacijos grafiką (ConvGraph), grafiškai pagrįstą dialogų, kurie gali būti naudojami duomenų didinimui, daugiamečiam mokymui ir nenustatyvių veikėjų vertinimui. ConvGraph sukuria naujus dialogo būdus, kuriais didinamas duomenų kiekis ir įvairovė. Intrinsic and extrinsic evaluation across three datasets shows that data augmentation and/or multi-reference training with ConvGraph can improve dialogue success rates by up to 6.4%.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Системите на дијалог ориентирани на задачите обично зависат од големи количини на висококвалитетни податоци за обука или бараат комплексни рачно направени правила. Сепак, постојните датотеки честопати се ограничени со оглед на комплексноста на дијалозите. Покрај тоа, конвенционалниот сигнал на тренинг не е соодветен за однесувањето на недефинистички агент, имено, сметајќи дека повеќе акции се валидни во идентични дијалози. Предложуваме конверзациски граф (ConvGraph), графско засновано претставување на дијалози кои може да се искористат за зголемување на податоците, мултиреференциска обука и евалуација на недеterminatистичките агенти. ConvGraph генерира нови патишта за дијалог за зголемување на обемот на податоци и разновидноста. Интринска и екстринзичка проценка во трите податоци покажува дека зголемувањето на податоците и/или мултиреференциска обука со ConvGraph може да ги подобри стапките на успех на дијалогот за 6,4 отсто.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mn>Тапсыг дамжуулах диалог системүүд ихэвчлэн өндөр чанарын дасгал өгөгдлийн маш их хэмжээтэй байдаг эсвэл комплекс гар бүтээгдэхүүний хууль хэрэгтэй. Гэвч суурилсан өгөгдлийн сангууд диалогуудын цогцолтой хэмжээнд хязгаарлагддаг. Үүнээс гадна олон үйл ажиллагааг адилхан диалог хэлбэрээр зөв гэж үзэх аргагүй байдаг. Бид ярилцлагын график (ConvGraph), график дээр суурилсан диалогуудын үзүүлэлт, өгөгдлийн нэмэгдүүлэлт, олон тохиромжтой сургалтын сургалтыг, тогтоомжгүй агентуудын үнэлгээ хийх боломжтой. ConvGraph нь өгөгдлийн хэмжээ болон олон төрлийг нэмэгдүүлэхэд шинэ диалог зам үүсгэдэг. Гурван өгөгдлийн хэлбэрээр суурь болон гадна дүгнэлт нь ConvGraph-ын өгөгдлийн нэмэгдүүлэлт болон/эсвэл олон дасгал дасгал сургалт нь диалогын амжилтын хувьд 6.4%.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ms>Sistem dialog bertujuan tugas biasanya bergantung pada jumlah besar data latihan kualiti tinggi atau memerlukan peraturan yang kompleks. Namun, set data yang wujud sering terbatas dalam saiz mengingati kompleksiti dialog. Lagipun, isyarat latihan konvensional tidak sesuai untuk perilaku ejen bukan-menentukan, iaitu, mempertimbangkan tindakan berbilang sebagai sah dalam keadaan dialog yang sama. Kami cadangkan Graf Perbualan (ConvGraph), perwakilan berdasarkan graf bagi dialog yang boleh dieksploitasi untuk peningkatan data, latihan rujukan berbilang dan penilaian ejen bukan-determinasi. ConvGraph generates novel dialogue paths to augment data volume and diversity.  Evaluasi dalaman dan luar melalui tiga set data menunjukkan peningkatan data dan/atau latihan rujukan-berbilang dengan ConvGraph boleh meningkatkan kadar kesuksesan dialog sehingga 6.4%.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ജോലി തിരിച്ചറിയപ്പെട്ട ഡയലോഗ് സിസ്റ്റം സാധാരണ വലിയ വിവരങ്ങളില്‍ ആശ്രയിക്കുന്നു However, existing datasets are often limited in size con- sidering the complexity of the dialogues.  കൂടുതലായി, സാധാരണ ട്രെയിനിസ്റ്റന്‍ സിഗ്നല്‍ ഇന്‍ ഫെയര്‍നെന്‍സില്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നത് നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കാത്ത ഏജന്‍റിന്റെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ നമ്മള്‍ സംസാരിക്കുന്ന സംഭാഷണ ഗ്രാഫ് (കോണ്‍വ്ഗ്രാഫ്), ഡേറ്റാ കൂട്ടുന്നതിന് വേണ്ടിയും, പല-reference പരിശീലിപ്പിനും നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കാത്ത ജെന്‍റുകളു കോണ്‍വ്ഗ്രാഫ് നോവല്‍ ഡയലോഗ് വഴികള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കുന്നു. ഡേറ്റാ വ്യത്യാസവും കൂടുതല്‍ വ്യത്യാസവുമാണ്. മൂന്നു ഡാറ്റാസറ്റുകളില്‍ മുഴുവന്‍ ഇന്റ്രിനിസിക്കും വിലാസവും കാണിക്കുന്നുണ്ടെങ്കില്‍ കോണ്‍വ്ഗ്രാഫിനോടൊപ്പം ഡേറ്റാവിന്റെ കൂടു</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Task-oriented dialogue systems typically rely on large amounts of high-quality training data or require complex handcrafted rules.  Madankollu, settijiet ta’ dejta eżistenti ta’ spiss huma limitati fid-daqs meta wieħed iqis il-kumplessità tad-djalogi. Barra minn hekk, is-sinjal konvenzjonali ta’ taħriġ in-ferenza mhuwiex adattat għall-imġiba ta’ aġent mhux determinanti, jiġifieri, meta jitqiesu diversi azzjonijiet bħala validi fi stati ta’ djalogu identiċi. Aħna nipproponu l-Grafika ta’ Konverżjoni (ConvGraph), rappreżentanza bbażata fuq il-grafika ta’ djalogi li jistgħu jiġu sfruttati għal żieda fid-dejta, taħriġ b’ħafna referenzi u evalwazzjoni ta’ a ġenti mhux determinanti. ConvGraph jiġġenera mogħdijiet ġodda ta’ djalogu biex iżid il-volum tad-dejta u d-diversità. Evalwazzjoni interna u esterna fi tliet settijiet ta’ dejta turi li ż-żieda fid-dejta u/jew taħriġ b’ħafna referenzi ma’ ConvGraph jistgħu jtejbu r-rati ta’ suċċess tad-djalogu b’sa 6.4%.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Systemy dialogu zorientowanego na zadania zazwyczaj opierają się na dużych ilościach wysokiej jakości danych szkoleniowych lub wymagają złożonych ręcznie opracowanych reguł. Jednakże istniejące zbiory danych są często ograniczone pod względem złożoności dialogów. Dodatkowo konwencjonalny sygnał treningowy nie jest odpowiedni dla niedeterministycznych zachowań agentów, a mianowicie uznawania wielu działań za ważne w identycznych stanach dialogu. Proponujemy Konwersacyjny Graph (ConvGraph), reprezentację dialogów opartą na wykresie, która może być wykorzystywana do powiększania danych, szkolenia wielodniesienia i oceny czynników niedeterministycznych. ConvGraph generuje nowe ścieżki dialogowe w celu zwiększenia wolumenu i różnorodności danych. Ocena wewnętrzna i zewnętrzna w trzech zbiorach danych pokazuje, że powiększanie danych i/lub szkolenie wielu referencji za pomocą ConvGraph może poprawić wskaźnik sukcesu dialogu o nawet 6,4%.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Sistemele de dialog orientate spre sarcini se bazează, de obicei, pe cantități mari de date de formare de înaltă calitate sau necesită reguli complexe realizate manual. Cu toate acestea, seturile de date existente sunt adesea limitate ca dimensiune, având în vedere complexitatea dialogurilor. În plus, semnalul convenţional de instruire nu este potrivit pentru comportamentul agentului non-determinist, şi anume, considerând acţiuni multiple ca valabile în stări identice de dialog. Vă propunem Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), o reprezentare bazată pe grafice a dialogurilor care pot fi exploatate pentru mărirea datelor, instruirea multi-referință și evaluarea agenților non-determiniști. ConvGraph generează noi căi de dialog pentru a mări volumul și diversitatea datelor. Evaluarea intrinsecă și extrinsă a trei seturi de date arată că mărirea datelor și/sau formarea cu mai multe referințe cu ConvGraph pot îmbunătăți ratele de succes ale dialogului cu până la 6,4%.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Sistemi dijaloga orijentirani na zadatke obično se oslanjaju na velike količine podataka o kvalitetnoj obuci ili zahtevaju kompleksne pravila napravljene rukama. Međutim, postojeće kompleksnosti podataka često su ograničene u veličini koji se povezuje kompleksnost dijaloga. Osim toga, konvencionalni signal obuke u ferenciji nije odgovarajući za ponašanje bez određenih agenata, a to je, s obzirom na višestruke akcije koje su validne u identičnim državama dijaloga. Predlažemo grafiku razgovora (ConvGraph), zasnovanu na grafiku predstavu dijaloga koji se mogu iskoristiti za povećanje podataka, multireferentno obuku i procjenu nedefinističkih agenata. ConvGraph stvara nove puteve dijaloga do povećanja voluma podataka i raznolikosti. Unutrašnja i ekstrinska procjena u tri kompleta podataka pokazuje da povećanje podataka i/ili multireferenčna obuka sa ConvGraph može poboljšati stope uspeha dijaloga do 6,4%.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_no>Oppgåveorienterte dialogsystemar brukar normalt på stor mengdar av høg kvalitetøvingsdata eller krev komplekse reglar med høg- kvalitet. Det eksisterande datasettet er ofte begrenset i storleiken ved å slå på kompleksiteten av dialogvindauga. I tillegg er det ikkje tilgjengeleg for ikkje-deterministisk agent-oppførsel, dvs. for å sjå på fleire handlingar som gyldig i identiske dialogtilstandar. Vi foreslår samtalegrafen (ConvGraph), eit grafikkbasert representasjon av dialogar som kan brukast for data augmentasjon, fleire referanser- trening og evaluering av ikkje- deterministiske agentar. ConvGraph lager nye dialogstigar til å auka datavolum og mangfold. Intrinsic and extrinsic evaluation across three datasets shows that data increase and/or multi reference training with ConvGraph can improve dialog success rates by up to 6.4%.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_so>Sida caadiga ah nidaamka diyaarinta shaqada waxay ku xiran yihiin maadooyin badan oo waxbarashada tacliinta sare ama waxay u baahan yihiin qaynuunno adag oo gacmaha qabatay. However, existing datasets are often limited in size con- sidering the complexity of the dialogues.  Sidoo kale sawirka waxbarashada ee caadiga ah ee ku haboon habboon dabeecada shaqaalaha aan aqoonsiga aheyn, sida loo eego shaqooyin badan oo ay ku shaqeyn yihiin wadamada diyaarinta saxda ah. Waxaan soo jeedaynaa Graph conversations (ConvGraph), kaas oo ku qoran samooyin sawir ah, kaas oo loo isticmaali karo kordhiska macluumaadka, waxbarashada farsamada badan iyo qiimeynta shaqaalaha aan aqoonin. ConvGraph wuxuu sameeyaa waddooyin ku qoran diyaarinta saxda ah si loo kordhiyo tirada macluumaadka iyo kala duduwan. Qiimeynta caadiga iyo dibadda ah ee saddexda databaseeti ka mid ah waxay muuqataa in waxbarashada kordhinta data iyo/ama waxbarashada farsamada badan ee ConvGraf lagu baranayo uu beddeli karo heerka guulaysta bulshada badnaanta 6.4 boqolkiiba.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>සාමාන්‍ය විශේෂ ප්‍රධානය සංවාද පද්ධතිය සංවාද ප්‍රමාණය විශේෂ විශාල ප්‍රධානයක් තොරතුරු ගැන හෝ නමුත්, තියෙන්න තියෙන තොරතුරු සේට් සාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රමාණය සඳහා ප්‍රමාණය සඳහා සංවාදයේ සංකේත සං ඉතින්, සාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රශ්නය සංඥාවක් සංඥාවක් වෙනුවෙන් නිර්ධාරිත නියෝජිත ව්‍යාපෘතිකරණය සඳහා යුක්තිය නෑ, ම අපි කතා කරන්න ග්‍රාෆ් (ConvGraph) යෝජනා කරනවා, ග්‍රාෆ් අධාරිත සංවාදයේ සංවාදය සංවාදය සංවාදය සඳහා ප්‍රයෝජන වෙන්න පුළුවන් විදි Name ඉන්ධ්‍රින්සික් සහ ප්‍රශ්නයක් දත්ත සෙට් තුනක් විසින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් පෙන්වන්නේ ConvGraph එක්ක දත්ත විශාලනය සහ/සම්ප්‍රශ්නයක</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Uppgiftsinriktade dialogsystem är vanligtvis beroende av stora mängder högkvalitativ utbildningsdata eller kräver komplexa handgjorda regler. De befintliga datauppsättningarna är dock ofta begränsade till storlek med tanke på dialogernas komplexitet. Dessutom är konventionell träningssignal- ferens inte lämplig för icke- deterministiskt agentbeteende, nämligen att betrakta flera åtgärder som giltiga i identiska dialogtillstånd. Vi föreslår konversationsgrafen (ConvGraph), en grafbaserad representation av dialoger som kan utnyttjas för dataökning, flerreferensutbildning och utvärdering av icke-deterministiska agenter. ConvGraph genererar nya dialogvägar för att öka datavolym och mångfald. Intrinsk och extern utvärdering över tre datauppsättningar visar att dataökning och/eller flerreferensutbildning med ConvGraph kan förbättra dialogens framgång med upp till 6,4%.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>பணி திருத்தப்பட்ட உரையாடல் அமைப்புகள் வழக்கமாக உயர்தரமான பயிற்சி தரவை சார்ந்து கொள்ளும் அல்லது சிக்கலான கைமுறை விதிகள However, existing datasets are often limited in size con- sidering the complexity of the dialogues.  கூடுதலாக, வழக்கமான பயிற்சி குறியீடு தீர்மானிக்கப்படாத நடைமுறைக்கு பொருத்தமானது, அதாவது, பல செயல்கள் அடையாளம் உரையாடல் நாடுகளில் செல்லு நாம் உரையாடல் வரைப்படத்தை (கான்வ்கிராப்) பரிந்துரைக்கிறோம், தகவல் அதிகப்படுத்தல், பல- குறிப்பு பயிற்சி மற்றும் தீர்மானிக்காத மேலாளர்களை மதிப்பி ConvGraph புதிய உரையாடல் பாதைகளை உருவாக்குகிறது தரவு ஒலி மற்றும் பலவீதம். மூன்று தகவல் அமைப்புகளில் உள்ளுணர்வு மற்றும் வெளியீட்டு மதிப்பினை கான்வ் குறிப்பில் தரவு அதிகரிப்பு மற்றும்/அல்லது பல குறிப்பு பயிற்சி</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ٹاکس کی سمجھی دیالوگ سیسٹم معمولاً زیادہ گوارت ترینس ڈیٹا پر اعتماد رکھتے ہیں یا پیچیدہ ہاندکریٹ کے قانون کی ضرورت رکھتے ہیں. However, existing datasets are often limited in size con- sidering the complexity of the dialogues. اور اضافہ، منطقی ترینسی سیگنالہ، فرنس میں غیر منطقی اگنٹ رفتار کے لئے مناسب نہیں ہے، یعنی، بہت سی اقدامات کو ایک ہی سیگنالہ کی حالت میں مفید سمجھتے ہیں. ہم رابطہ گراف (ConvGraph) کو پیشنهاد کریں گے، ایک گراف بنیاد دار ڈالیلوگوں کی تصویر جو ڈاٹا اضافہ کرنے کے لئے استعمال کر سکتے ہیں، بہت سی رابطہ تطارین اور غیر منطقی اگنٹوں کا ارزش کرنا ہے. ConvGraph produces new dialog paths to increase data volume and diversity. تین ڈاٹ سٹ میں داخلی اور خارجی ارزیابی دکھاتی ہے کہ ConvGraph کے ساتھ ڈاٹ افزایش اور/یا بہت سی ارتباط تطالب کی سفارش 6.4%.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Faqat, mavjud maʼlumot tugmalari dialogning murakkablarini oʻlchamiga oʻzgartiriladi. @ info: whatsthis We propose the Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), a graph-based representation of dialogues that can be exploited for data augmentation, multi- reference training and evaluation of non- deterministic agents.  Name Uchta maʼlumotlar tarkibida qiymatni ko'rsatish mumkin, KonvGraph bilan muloqat taʼminlovchi maʼlumot soʻzlashtirish va/yoki muloqat bogʻlanish imkoniyatini 6.4 foizlik darajasini oshirish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Các hệ thống đối thoại chuyên nghiệp thường dựa trên một lượng lớn dữ liệu đào tạo chất lượng cao hoặc đòi hỏi quy định kỹ thuật phức tạp. Tuy nhiên, các tập tin tồn tại thường bị hạn chế về kích thước cân nhắc sự phức tạp của các ca- trình. Hơn nữa, tín hiệu huấn luyện thông thường không phù hợp với hành vi đặc vụ không phân biệt động, cụ thể là xem nhiều hành động hợp lệ trong các bang giống nhau. Chúng tôi đề xuất đồ thị cho cấu hình đối thoại (Convhraph), một mô tả biểu tượng biểu đồ của các ca được khai thác dữ liệu, huấn luyện đa tham khảo và đánh giá các đặc vụ không phân biệt. Biểu đồ hình sự tạo ra những đường dẫn mới để tăng lượng dữ liệu và đa dạng. Sự nghiên cứu kỹ lưỡng và dứt khoát trong ba tập tin cho thấy khả năng gia tăng dữ liệu và/hay đào tạo đa ngành tham khảo có thể cải tiến tỉ lệ thành công của cuộc đối thoại</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>Taakgerichte dialoogsystemen zijn meestal afhankelijk van grote hoeveelheden trainingsgegevens van hoge kwaliteit of vereisen complexe handgemaakte regels. Bestaande datasets zijn echter vaak beperkt in omvang gezien de complexiteit van de dialogen. Bovendien is conventionele trainingssignaalinterferentie niet geschikt voor niet-deterministisch gedrag van agenten, namelijk het beschouwen van meerdere acties als geldig in identieke dialoogstaten. We stellen de Conversation Graph (ConvGraph) voor, een grafiekgebaseerde weergave van dialogen die kan worden gebruikt voor data augmentatie, multi-reference training en evaluatie van niet-deterministische agenten. ConvGraph genereert nieuwe dialoogpaden om datavolume en diversiteit te vergroten. Intrinsieke en extrinsieke evaluatie over drie datasets toont aan dat gegevensvergroting en/of multi-reference training met ConvGraph de succespercentages van dialoog met maximaal 6,4%.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Sistemi dijaloga orijentirani na zadatke obično se oslanjaju na velike količine podataka o visokokvalitetnoj obuci ili zahtijevaju kompleksne pravila napravljene ruke. Međutim, postojeće sete podataka često su ograničene u veličini s kojima se pokazuje kompleksnost dijaloga. Osim toga, konvencionalni znak obuke u ferenciji nije odgovarajući za ponašanje bez određenih agenata, a to je, s obzirom na višestruke akcije koje su vrijedne u identičnim dijalogskim državama. Predlažemo grafiku razgovora (ConvGraph), zasnovanu na grafiku predstavu dijaloga koje se mogu iskoristiti za povećanje podataka, multireferentni obuku i procjenu nedodređujućih agenata. ConvGraph stvara nove puteve dijaloga do povećanja volumena podataka i raznolikosti. Intrinsicna i ekstrinsicna procjena u tri podataka pokazuje da povećanje podataka i/ili višereferentni trening s ConvGraph može poboljšati stope uspjeha dijaloga do 6,4%.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Системите за диалог, ориентирани към задачите, обикновено разчитат на големи количества висококачествени данни за обучение или изискват сложни ръчно изработени правила. Съществуващите набори от данни обаче често са ограничени по размер предвид сложността на диалоговите прозорци. Освен това конвенционалният тренировъчен сигнал не е подходящ за недетерминистично поведение на агента, а именно, разглеждане на множество действия като валидни в идентични състояния на диалог. Предлагаме диалогова графика, базирана на графика, която може да бъде експлоатирана за увеличаване на данните, мултиреферентно обучение и оценка на недетерминистични агенти. Генерира нови диалогови пътища за увеличаване на обема и разнообразието на данните. Вътрешната и външната оценка на три набора данни показва, че увеличаването на данните и/или многореферентното обучение с могат да подобрят процента на успех на диалога с до 6,4%.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Opgaveorienterede dialogsystemer er typisk afhængige af store mængder træningsdata af høj kvalitet eller kræver komplekse håndlavede regler. De eksisterende datasæt er dog ofte begrænset i størrelse i betragtning af dialogernes kompleksitet. Derudover er konventionelle træningssignaler ikke egnede til ikke-deterministisk agentadfærd, nemlig at betragte flere handlinger som gyldige i identiske dialogtilstande. Vi foreslår Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), en grafbaseret repræsentation af dialoger, der kan udnyttes til dataforøgelse, multi-reference træning og evaluering af ikke-deterministiske agenter. ConvGraph genererer nye dialogstier til at øge datavolumen og mangfoldighed. Indgående og ekstern evaluering på tværs af tre datasæt viser, at dataforøgelse og/eller multi-reference træning med ConvGraph kan forbedre dialogens succesrater med op til 6,4%.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Aufgabenorientierte Dialogsysteme basieren typischerweise auf großen Mengen hochwertiger Trainingsdaten oder erfordern komplexe, handgefertigte Regeln. Allerdings sind vorhandene Datensätze aufgrund der Komplexität der Dialoge häufig in ihrer Größe begrenzt. Darüber hinaus eignet sich herkömmliche Trainingssignal-Intervention nicht für nicht-deterministisches Agentenverhalten, d.h. multiple Aktionen als gültig in identischen Dialogzuständen zu betrachten. Wir schlagen das Conversation Graph (ConvGraph) vor, eine graphenbasierte Darstellung von Dialogen, die für die Datenaufwandlung, das Training mit mehreren Referenzen und die Bewertung von nicht deterministischen Agenten genutzt werden kann. ConvGraph generiert neuartige Dialogpfade, um das Datenvolumen und die Vielfalt zu erhöhen. Intrinsische und extrinsische Auswertungen über drei Datensätze zeigen, dass die Datenerweiterung und/oder das Multireferenztraining mit ConvGraph die Dialogerfolgsraten um bis zu 6,4%.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>سیستم‌های محاورۀ مشاوره‌ای که به دنبال وظیفه‌ها می‌باشند معمولاً بر مقدار زیادی از داده‌های آموزش کیفیت بالا استفاده می‌کنند یا نیاز به قانون‌های پیچیده‌ای دارند. با این حال، مجموعه‌های داده‌های موجود اغلب در اندازه‌ای محدود می‌شوند که پیچیدگی‌های گفتگوها را محدود می‌کنند. علاوه بر این، سیگنال آموزشی معمولی در تفاوت برای رفتار مامور غیر تصمیم‌گیری مناسب نیست، یعنی با توجه به فعالیت‌های تعدادی که در وضعیت‌های محاورۀ یکسان استفاده می‌کنند. ما پیشنهاد می‌کنیم گراف گفتگوی (ConvGraph) یک نمایش بنیاد گراف از گفتگوهای که می‌توانند برای افزایش داده‌ها استفاده شود، آموزش متعدد مربوط و ارزیابی ماموران غیر تصمیم‌کننده استفاده شود. Name ارزیابی داخلی و خارجی در سه مجموعه اطلاعات نشان می دهد که افزایش داده ها و/یا آموزش متعدد مربوط با ConvGraph می تواند سرعت موفقیت دیalog را تا 6.4 درصد بهتر کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>임무를 위한 대화 시스템은 대량의 고품질 교육 데이터에 의존하거나 복잡한 수동 규칙이 필요하다.그러나 대화의 복잡성을 감안하면 기존 데이터 집합의 크기는 한계가 있다.그 밖에 전통적인 훈련 신호 인용은 비확정적인 에이전트 행위에 적용되지 않는다. 즉, 여러 동작이 같은 대화 상태에서 효과적이라고 생각하는 것이다.우리는 대화도(ConvGraph)를 제시했는데 이것은 그림을 바탕으로 하는 대화로 데이터 확장, 다중 참고 훈련과 비확정적 대리에 대한 평가에 사용할 수 있음을 나타낸다.ConvGraph는 데이터 양과 다양성을 높이기 위해 새로운 대화 경로를 생성합니다.세 개의 데이터 집합에 대한 내재와 외재 평가에 따르면 콘브그라프를 이용하여 데이터 확충과/또는 다중 참고 훈련을 하면 대화 성공률을 6.4% 높일 수 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Mfumo wa mazungumzo yenye kazi hutegemea kwa kawaida kiasi kikubwa cha data za mafunzo yenye kiwango cha juu au unahitaji kanuni tata zilizo mikononi. Hata hivyo, seti za taarifa zinazopo mara nyingi zinazuiwa kwa kiwango kikubwa, kwa kuzingatia utata wa mazungumzo. Kwa kuongezea, alama ya mafunzo ya kawaida katika kipindi hiki si sahihi kwa tabia za wateja wasio na uthibitisho, yaani, ikichukua hatua mbalimbali kama ilivyo sahihi katika mazungumzo yanayofanana. Tunazipendekeza Graph ya Mazungumzo (ConvGraph), mwakilishi wa mazungumzo yenye picha ambayo yanaweza kutumiwa kwa ajili ya kuongeza data, mafunzo ya maoni mengi na tathmini ya maafisa wasio na uthibitisho. ConvGraph inatengeneza njia za mazungumzo ya kitaifa ili kuongeza ujazo wa data na utofauti. Utafiti wa msingi na wa nje katika seti tatu za takwimu zinaonyesha kuwa mafunzo ya kuongeza data na/au mafunzo ya maoni mengi na ConvGraph yanaweza kuongeza kiwango cha mafanikio ya mazungumzo kwa takribani asilimia 6.4.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Opdrag-orienteerde dialoog stelsels tipies vertrou op groot hoë-kwaliteit-onderwerking data of benodig kompleks handkryfde reëls. Maar bestaande datastelle word dikwels beperk in grootte con- sidering die kompleksiteit van die dialoog. Additionally, conventional training signal in- ference is not suitable for non- deterministic agent behavior, namely, considering multiple actions as valid in identical dialog states. Ons voorstel die Gespraak Graf (ConvGraph), ân graafgebaseerde verteenwoordigheid van dialoog wat kan uitgebruik word vir data augmentasie, multi- verwysing onderwerking en evaluering van nie- deterministiese agente. ConvGraph genereer nuwe dialoog pad na vergroot data volume en diversiteit. Intrinsic en extrinsic evaluasie oor drie datastelle vertoon dat data augmentasie en/of multi-verwysing onderwerking met ConvGraph die dialoog sukseshoeveelheid van tot 6.4%.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Görevlerden berilen dijalog sistemalary adatça ýokary kwalitet eğitim maglumatlaryna ynanýarlar ýa-da karmaşık elimden gelen kararlar gerek. Ýöne bolan veri düzümleri köplenç diýip çarpylýar. Beýleki, diňe-de, adil okuwçy sened- ferenziýa takyksyzlyk etmek üçin ýeterli däldir. Birnäçe hereketler birnäçe dijalog durumlarda geçerli bir hereket diýip pikir edýär. Biz Conversation Graph'u (ConvGraph) ConvGraf maglumaty we çeşitliklerini azaltmak üçin täze dynç yollary döredir. Çaltylyk we çäri çykyş 3 datasetlerde maglumat ýetişdirmegi we/ýa ConvGraph bilen çoklu referens okuwçylygy barlamak üçin 6.4% ýagdaýa çenli dijalogyň üstünlik häzirini gowurap biler.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Sistemet e dialogut të orientuar ndaj detyrave zakonisht mbështeten në sasi të mëdha të dhënash të trajnimit të cilësisë së lartë apo kërkojnë rregulla komplekse të ndërtuar me dorë. Megjithatë, grupet e të dhënave ekzistuese janë shpesh të kufizuara në madhësinë duke marrë parasysh kompleksitetin e dialogeve. Përveç kësaj, sinjali konvencional i trajnimit në diferencë nuk është i përshtatshëm për sjelljen e agjentit jo-përcaktues, veçanërisht, duke konsideruar veprime të shumta si të vlefshme në shtetet e dialogut identik. Ne propozojmë grafikun e konversimit (ConvGraph), një përfaqësim i dialogut me bazë në grafik që mund të shfrytëzohet për rritjen e të dhënave, trajnimin e shumëreferencave dhe vlerësimin e agjentëve jo-vendosës. ConvGraph gjeneron rrugë të reja dialogu për të rritur volumin e të dhënave dhe diversitetin. Vlerësimi i brendshëm dhe i jashtëm nëpërmjet tre grupeve të dhënash tregon se rritja e të dhënave dhe/ose trajnimi me shumë referenca me ConvGraph mund të përmirësojë normat e suksesit të dialogut me deri në 6.4%.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_id>Sistem dialog oriented tugas biasanya bergantung pada jumlah besar data pelatihan kualitas tinggi atau memerlukan peraturan yang kompleks. Namun, set data yang ada sering terbatas dalam ukuran mengingat kompleksitas dialog. Selain itu, sinyal pelatihan konvensional di-ference tidak cocok untuk perilaku agen non-deterministic, yaitu, mempertimbangkan beberapa tindakan sebagai valid dalam keadaan dialog yang sama. Kami mengusulkan Graf Conversation (ConvGraph), sebuah representation berdasarkan grafik dari dialog yang dapat dieksploitasi untuk peningkatan data, pelatihan multi-referensi dan evaluasi agen non-deterministic. ConvGraph menghasilkan laluan dialog baru untuk meningkatkan volum dan diversitas data. Intrinsic and extrinsic evaluation across three datasets shows that data augmentation and/or multi-reference training with ConvGraph can improve dialogue success rates by up to 6.4%.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_hy>Պատասխաններով հիմնված հաղորդակցման համակարգերը սովորաբար հիմնված են բարձր որակի ուսումնասիրության տվյալների մեծ քանակությամբ կամ պահանջում են բարդ ձեռագործված կանոններ: Այնուամենայնիվ, գոյություն ունեցող տվյալների համակարգերը հաճախ սահմանափակված են, հաշվի առնելով պատկերացումների բարդությունը: Ավելին, ավանդական ուսումնասիրության ազդանշանները չեն համապատասխանում ոչ որոշող գործոնների վարքագիծին, հատկապես, հաշվի առնելով բազմաթիվ գործողությունները որպես ճիշտ նույն երկրներում։ Մենք առաջարկում ենք հաղորդակցման գրաֆը (հաղորդակցման գրաֆը), գրաֆի հիմնված պատկերացում, որը կարող է օգտագործվել տվյալների բարձրացման, բազմահամեմատական ուսումնասիրության և ոչ որոշող գործոնների գնահատման համար: Կանվագրաֆը ստեղծում է նոր միջոցներ, որոնք օգնում են աճել տվյալների ծավալը և բազմազանությունը: Ինտրինսիկ և արտաքին գնահատումը երեք տվյալների համակարգերում ցույց է տալիս, որ տվյալների բարձրացման և (կամ) բազմահամեմատական վարժեցման համակարգով Կանֆրաֆ-ի միջոցով կարող է բարելավել հաջողության ցուցանիշները մինչև 6.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>ቦታ However, existing datasets are often limited in size con- sidering the complexity of the dialogues.  በተጨማሪም፣ የግንኙነት ማጠቃለያ በ-ፋርስ - ለጥያቄ አካባቢ ድርጊት አይጠቅምም፣ ብዙዎች ተግባር እንደ ጥያቄ በማስተካከል በአካባቢ አካባቢ አካሄድ ጥያቄ በመስጠት አይገባም፡፡ ለዳታ ማጠቃለያ፣ ለብዙ መልዕክት ማጠቃለያ እና የማይታወቀው ተሟጋቾች ማሰናከል የሚችሉትን አካባቢ አካባቢ አካሄል እና ማስተምር እና ማሳየት የሚችሉትን የግንኙነቶችን መክፈት እናሳስባታለን፡፡ ConvGraph አዲስ ዶሴ ፍጠር በሦስት ዳታ ማውጣት ላይ የኢንተርኔክና የውጭ ማስታወቂያ ከConvGraph ጋር የዳታ ማጨመር እና/ወይም በብዙ የሥልጣን ትምህርት ማድረግ 6.4 በመቶ ማድረግ ማሻሻል ይችላል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Gözmək tərəfindən təhsil edilən dijalog sistemləri genellikle yüksək kaliteli təhsil məlumatlarının çoxluğuna təvəkkül edir və ya kompleks əl yaratdığı qaydalara ehtiyac edir. Halbuki, mevcut verilən qurğular dialogların qarışıqlığını dəyişdirirlər. Üstəlik, fərenci müxtəlif təhsil sinyali təhsil etməyə uyğun deyil. Bu da, çoxlu eyni danışma durumlarında çoxlu eyni olaraq təhsil etmək üçün uyğun deyil. Biz məlumatları artırmaq üçün istifadə edilə biləcək məlumatların grafik-tabanlı rəsmini, çoxlu-referens təhsil və deterministik olmayan ajanların değerlendirməsini təklif edirik. ConvGraph məlumatların səviyyəsini və çeşitliyini artırmaq üçün yeni dialoq yollarını yaradır. Üç verilən qurğuların içindəki və ekstrinsic değerlendirmələri ConvGraph ilə verilən məlumatlar artırması və/və çox-referens təhsil təhsil etməsi 6,4%-ə qədər müvəffəqiyyəti düzəltə bilər.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Sistemi dijaloga orijentirani na zadatke obično se oslanjaju na velike količine podataka o kvalitetnoj obuci ili zahtijevaju kompleksne pravila napravljene ruke. Međutim, postojeće kompleksnosti podataka često su ograničene u veličini koji se navodi na kompleksnost dijaloga. Osim toga, konvencionalni signal obuke u ferenciji nije odgovarajući za ponašanje bez određenih agenata, a to je, s obzirom na višestruke akcije koje su vrijedne u identičnim državama dijaloga. Predlažemo grafiku konverzacije (ConvGraph), grafičku zastupnicu dijaloga koji se mogu iskoristiti za povećanje podataka, multireferentni obuku i procjenu nedodredističkih agenata. ConvGraph stvara nove puteve dijaloga do povećanja voluma podataka i raznolikosti. Intrinsicna i ekstrinsicna procjena u tri podataka pokazuje da povećanje podataka i/ili multireferenčna obuka s ConvGraph može poboljšati stope uspjeha dijaloga do 6,4%.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Ülesannetele orienteeritud dialoogisüsteemid tuginevad tavaliselt suurele hulgale kvaliteetseid koolitusandmeid või nõuavad keerukaid käsitööeeskirju. Kuid olemasolevad andmekogumid on dialoogide keerukust arvestades sageli piiratud. Lisaks sellele ei sobi tavapärane treeningsignaal mittedeterministliku agendi käitumiseks, nimelt arvestades mitmeid toiminguid kehtivaks identsetes dialoogiseisundites. Pakume välja vestlusgraafiku (ConvGraph), mis on dialoogide graafiline esitus, mida saab kasutada andmete suurendamiseks, mitmeviiteliseks koolituseks ja mittedeterministlike tegurite hindamiseks. ConvGraph loob uudseid dialoogiviise andmete mahu ja mitmekesisuse suurendamiseks. Kolme andmekogumi sise- ja välishindamine näitab, et andmete suurendamine ja/või mitmevõrdluskoolitus ConvGraphiga võib parandada dialoogi edukust kuni 6,4%.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bn>Task-oriented dialogue systems typically rely on large amounts of high-quality training data or require complex handcrafted rules.  তবে বিদ্যমান ডাটাসেট প্রায়শই মাপ কন- পাশে সীমাবদ্ধ করা হয় ডায়ালগের জটিলতা। এছাড়াও, সাধারণ প্রশিক্ষণের সিগন্যাল ইন- ফেয়ারেন্স নির্ধারিত এজেন্টের আচরণের জন্য যথাযথ নয়, যেমন একই সাথে ডায়ালগের রাস্তায় বৈধ বিভি আমরা কথোপকথন গ্রাফ (কনভ্রাফ) প্রস্তাব করছি, একটি গ্রাফ ভিত্তিক আলোচনার প্রতিনিধিত্ব, যা ডাটা যোগাযোগের জন্য ব্যবহার করা যাবে, বহুল-referenced প্রশিক্ষণ এবং অন কনভ- গ্রাফ তথ্যের ভলিউম এবং বৈচিত্র্যের জন্য নভেল ডায়ালগের পাথ তৈরি করেছেন। তিনটি ডাটাসেটের মধ্যে ইন্ট্রিনিসিক এবং বিদেশী মূল্যায়ন দেখাচ্ছে যে কনভ্রাফের সাথে তথ্য বৃদ্ধি এবং/অথবা বহুগুরুত্বপূর্ণ প্রশিক্ষণের ম</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_fi>Tehtävälähtöiset vuoropuhelujärjestelmät perustuvat yleensä suuriin määriin korkealaatuista koulutustietoa tai vaativat monimutkaisia käsityönä tehtyjä sääntöjä. Nykyiset tietoaineistot ovat kuitenkin usein kooltaan rajallisia dialogien monimutkaisuuden vuoksi. Lisäksi perinteinen harjoitussignaali ei sovellu ei-deterministiseen agenttien käyttäytymiseen, nimittäin useiden toimien pitämiseen pätevinä identtisissä dialogitiloissa. Ehdotamme Conversation Graphia (ConvGraph), graafista dialogien esitystä, jota voidaan hyödyntää tiedon lisäämisessä, moniviitekoulutuksessa ja ei-determinististen tekijöiden arvioinnissa. ConvGraph luo uusia vuoropuhelupolkuja datan määrän ja monimuotoisuuden lisäämiseksi. Kolmen aineiston sisäinen ja ulkoinen arviointi osoittaa, että datan lisääminen ja/tai monireferenssikoulutus ConvGraphilla voivat parantaa dialogin onnistumisastetta jopa 6,4%.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>Task-oriented dialogue systems typically rely on large amounts of high-quality training data or require complex handcrafted rules.  However, existing datasets are often limited in size con- sidering the complexity of the dialogues.  A més, la senyal d'entrenament convencional no és adequada per al comportament de l'agent no determinant, és a dir, considerant múltiples accions válides en estats de diàleg idèntics. We propose the Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), a graph-based representation of dialogues that can be exploited for data augmentation, multi- reference training and evaluation of non- deterministic agents.  ConvGraph genera noves víes de diàleg per augmentar el volum de dades i la diversitat. L'evaluació intrínsica i extrínsica en tres conjunts de dades mostra que l'augment de les dades i/o l'entrenament multireferència amb ConvGraph poden millorar els nivells d'èxit del diàleg fins al 6,4%.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Dialogové systémy orientované na úkoly obvykle spoléhají na velké množství vysoce kvalitních tréninkových dat nebo vyžadují složitá ručně vytvořená pravidla. Stávající datové sady jsou však často omezeny velikostí s ohledem na složitost dialogů. Navíc konvenční tréninkový signál není vhodný pro nederministické chování agentů, konkrétně považovat více akcí za platné ve stejných dialogových stavech. Navrhujeme konverzační graf (ConvGraph), grafové zobrazení dialogů, které lze využít pro rozšíření dat, multireferenční školení a hodnocení nederministických agentů. ConvGraph generuje nové dialogové cesty ke zvýšení objemu dat a rozmanitosti. Intrinsické a extrinzické vyhodnocení napříč třemi datovými sadami ukazuje, že rozšíření dat a/nebo vícereferenční trénink s ConvGraphem může zlepšit míru úspěšnosti dialogu až o 6,4%.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_he>מערכות דיאלוג ממוקדות למשימות תלויות בדרך כלל על כמויות גדולות של נתונים אימונים באיכות גבוהה או דורשות חוקים מורכבים. עם זאת, קבוצות נתונים קיימות לעתים קרובות מוגבלות בגודל בהתחשב במרכיבות הדיולוגים. בנוסף, סימן אימון קונבנציונלי בתנועה אינו מתאים להתנהגות של סוכנים לא קבועים, כלומר, בהתחשב בפעולות רבות בתנאים של דיאלוג זהים. אנו מציעים את גרף השיחה (ConvGraph), מייצג מבוסס על גרף של דיאלוגים שיכולים לנצל עבור גידול נתונים, אימונים רבים-התייחסות והעריכה של סוכנים לא קבועים. Name הערכה פנימית וחיצונית בשלושה קבוצות נתונים מראה שגידול נתונים ו/או אימון רבי-התייחסות עם ConvGraph יכול לשפר את שיעורי ההצלחה של דיאלוג עד 6.4%.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Ana ƙayyade tsarin zauren akwatin aiki da aka juyi wa zauren akwatin bayanin akwatin bayani na bayani na ɗabi'a, yana dõgara ko kuma yana daidai da kiman ƙidãya masu tsari na nau'in-nau'i ko kuma ana ƙayyade Rubuwan da hannayen da aka samu da Amma, ana ƙayyade daidaita maɓallin da ke jira a ƙayyade girma-bayanin zauren akwatin bayanin zauren akwatin bayani. Ƙaramiwa, Simbolin mafarinta na ɗabi'a cikin-fence bai da daidai wa aikin mai zartar da shi ba na-daki, misali, idan an yi tunãni ga masu yawa kamar aikin aiki masu inganci cikin zauren zauren akwatin bayanin zauren akwatin bayani. Munã buɗa karatun mazaɓa na ConvGraf (ConvGraf), wani masana na ƙayyade zauren zauren akwatin bayani wanda za'a iya amfani da wa ɗa ɗaɗarwa ga data, wa'adin multi-Reference da evaluation ga masu tsari na-daki. ConvGraf na ƙãga hanyõyi na zauren zauren akwatin bayani na yanzu don a ƙara saurin danne da baƙaƙƙe. Ana ƙari na Intrinci da bakin bayani na tsari uku, yana nuna cewa, shirin ƙaramako na data da/ko shirin multi-Reference na ConvGraf yana iya ƙara fassarar mafaniki na zauren zauren akwatin bayani da up to 6.4%.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>Task-oriented dialog systems typically rely on large amounts of high-quality training data or require complex handcrafted rules. ཡིན་ནའང་། གནས་ཡུལ་སྒྲིག་ཆ་འཕྲིན་གྱི་ཆེ་ཆུང་ལ་སྒྲིག་ཡིག་ཆའི་གླེང་སྒྲོམ་གྱི་དཀའ་ངལ་གཏོང་བ Additionally, conventional training signal in- ference is not suitable for non-deterministic agent behavior, namely, considering multiple actions as valid in identical dialog states. We propose the Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), a graph-based representation of dialogues that can be exploited for data augmentation, multi-reference training and evaluation of non-deterministic agents. ConvGraph་ཡིས་སྐྱེས་ཆ་དང་སྣེ་ཚོགས་ཆེ་ཆུང་བར་གཏོང་བའི་གསར་བ་གླེང་སྒྲོམ་བརྡ་གཏོང་བ Intrinsic and extrinsic evaluation across three datasets shows that data augmentation and/or multi-reference training with ConvGraph can improve dialog success rates by up to 6.4%.</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_sk>Sistemi dialoga, usmerjeni v naloge, običajno temeljijo na velikih količinah visokokakovostnih podatkov o usposabljanju ali zahtevajo zapletena ročno izdelana pravila. Vendar pa so obstoječi nabori podatkov pogosto omejeni glede na zapletenost pogovorov. Poleg tega običajni signal usposabljanja ni primeren za nedeterministično vedenje agentov, namreč glede večkratnih dejanj kot veljavnih v identičnih dialognih stanjih. Predlagamo Conversation Graph (ConvGraph), grafično predstavitev dialogov, ki ga je mogoče izkoristiti za povečanje podatkov, večreferenčno usposabljanje in vrednotenje nedeterminističnih dejavnikov. ConvGraph ustvarja nove poti dialoga za povečanje obsega in raznolikosti podatkov. Notranja in zunanja ocena v treh naborih podatkov kaže, da lahko povečanje podatkov in/ali večreferenčno usposabljanje s programom ConvGraph izboljša stopnjo uspešnosti dialoga za do 6,4%.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>dialog-direction slot politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Awak dhéwé nggunakake conversations Graph (conv Graph), gambar dipunangé diagram sing basa gambar ditambah sing bisa jewis nggawe nggawe data ogwektualangan, aku multi-reference curuwing karo cara-jewis antar uwong. (c) Language</abstract_jv>
      </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Efficient Content-Based Sparse Attention with Routing Transformers</title>
      <author><first>Aurko</first><last>Roy</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammad</first><last>Saffar</last></author>
      <author><first>Ashish</first><last>Vaswani</last></author>
      <author><first>David</first><last>Grangier</last></author>
      <doi>10.1162/tacl_a_00353</doi>
      <abstract>Self-attention has recently been adopted for a wide range of sequence modeling problems. Despite its effectiveness, self-attention suffers from quadratic computation and memory requirements with respect to sequence length. Successful approaches to reduce this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complexity">complexity</a> focused on attending to local sliding windows or a small set of locations independent of content. Our work proposes to learn dynamic sparse attention patterns that avoid allocating computation and memory to attend to content unrelated to the query of interest. This work builds upon two lines of research : It combines the modeling flexibility of prior work on content-based sparse attention with the efficiency gains from approaches based on local, temporal sparse attention. Our model, the Routing Transformer, endows self-attention with a sparse routing module based on online k-means while reducing the overall <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_complexity_theory">complexity</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attention">attention</a> to O(n1.5d) from O(n2d) for sequence length n and hidden dimension d. We show that our model outperforms comparable sparse attention models on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language modeling</a> on Wikitext-103 (15.8 vs 18.3 perplexity), as well as on image generation on ImageNet-64 (3.43 vs 3.44 bits / dim) while using fewer self-attention layers. Additionally, we set a new state-of-the-art on the newly released PG-19 data-set, obtaining a test perplexity of 33.2 with a 22 layer Routing Transformer model trained on sequences of length 8192. We open-source the code for Routing Transformer in Tensorflow.1</abstract>
      <pages>53–68</pages>
      <url hash="b06612dd">2021.tacl-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>roy-etal-2021-efficient</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Deciphering Undersegmented Ancient Scripts Using Phonetic Prior</title>
      <author><first>Jiaming</first><last>Luo</last></author>
      <author><first>Frederik</first><last>Hartmann</last></author>
      <author><first>Enrico</first><last>Santus</last></author>
      <author><first>Regina</first><last>Barzilay</last></author>
      <author><first>Yuan</first><last>Cao</last></author>
      <doi>10.1162/tacl_a_00354</doi>
      <abstract>Most undeciphered lost languages exhibit two characteristics that pose significant decipherment challenges : (1) the scripts are not fully segmented into words ; (2) the closest known language is not determined. We propose a decipherment model that handles both of these challenges by building on rich linguistic constraints reflecting consistent patterns in historical sound change. We capture the natural phonological geometry by learning <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Character_encoding">character embeddings</a> based on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Phonetic_Alphabet">International Phonetic Alphabet (IPA)</a>. The resulting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_model">generative framework</a> jointly models <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_segmentation">word segmentation</a> and cognate alignment, informed by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phonology">phonological constraints</a>. We evaluate the model on both deciphered languages (Gothic, Ugaritic) and an undeciphered one (Iberian). The experiments show that incorporating phonetic geometry leads to clear and consistent gains. Additionally, we propose a measure for language closeness which correctly identifies related languages for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gothic_language">Gothic</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ugaritic">Ugaritic</a>. For <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iberian_language">Iberian</a>, the method does not show strong evidence supporting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basque_language">Basque</a> as a related language, concurring with the favored position by the current scholarship.1</abstract>
      <pages>69–81</pages>
      <url hash="3c1203d1">2021.tacl-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>luo-etal-2021-deciphering</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Recursive Non-Autoregressive Graph-to-Graph Transformer for Dependency Parsing with Iterative Refinement</title>
      <author><first>Alireza</first><last>Mohammadshahi</last></author>
      <author><first>James</first><last>Henderson</last></author>
      <doi>10.1162/tacl_a_00358</doi>
      <abstract>We propose the Recursive Non-autoregressive Graph-to-Graph Transformer architecture (RNGTr) for the iterative refinement of arbitrary graphs through the recursive application of a non-autoregressive Graph-to-Graph Transformer and apply it to syntactic dependency parsing. We demonstrate the power and effectiveness of RNGTr on several dependency corpora, using a refinement model pre-trained with BERT. We also introduce Syntactic Transformer (SynTr), a non-recursive parser similar to our refinement model. RNGTr can improve the accuracy of a variety of initial parsers on 13 languages from the Universal Dependencies Treebanks, English and Chinese Penn Treebanks, and the German CoNLL2009 corpus, even improving over the new state-of-the-art results achieved by SynTr, significantly improving the state-of-the-art for all corpora tested.</abstract>
      <pages>120–138</pages>
      <url hash="d5fc315a">2021.tacl-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>mohammadshahi-henderson-2021-recursive</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>