<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.nuse">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Narrative Understanding</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Nader</first><last>Akoury</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Faeze</first><last>Brahman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Snigdha</first><last>Chaturvedi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Clark</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mohit</first><last>Iyyer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Lara J.</first><last>Martin</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Virtual</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.nuse-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="d9b091ca">2021.nuse-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nuse-2021-narrative</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Document-level Event Extraction with Efficient End-to-end Learning of Cross-event Dependencies</title>
      <author><first>Kung-Hsiang</first><last>Huang</last></author>
      <author><first>Nanyun</first><last>Peng</last></author>
      <pages>36–47</pages>
      <abstract>Fully understanding narratives often requires identifying events in the context of whole documents and modeling the event relations. However, document-level event extraction is a challenging task as it requires the extraction of event and entity coreference, and capturing arguments that span across different sentences. Existing works on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Event_extraction">event extraction</a> usually confine on extracting events from single sentences, which fail to capture the relationships between the event mentions at the scale of a document, as well as the event arguments that appear in a different sentence than the event trigger. In this paper, we propose an end-to-end model leveraging Deep Value Networks (DVN), a structured prediction algorithm, to efficiently capture cross-event dependencies for document-level event extraction. Experimental results show that our approach achieves comparable performance to CRF-based models on ACE05, while enjoys significantly higher computational efficiency.</abstract>
      <url hash="ea52ccfa">2021.nuse-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nuse-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>huang-peng-2021-document</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories<fixed-case>GPT</fixed-case>-3 Generated Stories</title>
      <author><first>Li</first><last>Lucy</last></author>
      <author><first>David</first><last>Bamman</last></author>
      <pages>48–55</pages>
      <abstract>Using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Topic_modeling">topic modeling</a> and lexicon-based word similarity, we find that stories generated by GPT-3 exhibit many known <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_role">gender stereotypes</a>. Generated stories depict different topics and descriptions depending on GPT-3’s perceived gender of the character in a prompt, with feminine characters more likely to be associated with family and appearance, and described as less powerful than masculine characters, even when associated with high power verbs in a prompt. Our study raises questions on how one can avoid unintended social biases when using large language models for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storytelling">storytelling</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="06782ba9">2021.nuse-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nuse-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>lucy-bamman-2021-gender</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/lucy3/gpt3_gender" additional="false">lucy3/gpt3_gender</pwccode>
    <title_fr>Biais de genre et de repr챕sentation dans les histoires g챕n챕r챕es par GPT-3</title_fr>
      <title_ar>التحيز الجنساني والتمثيل في القصص المولدة من GPT-3</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Viés de gênero e representação em histórias geradas pela GPT-3</title_pt>
      <title_es>Sesgo de género y representación en historias generadas por GPT-3</title_es>
      <title_ja>GPT -3生成ストーリーにおける性別と表現バイアス</title_ja>
      <title_zh>GPT-3成故事性别代表性偏见</title_zh>
      <title_ru>Предвзятое отношение к полу и представленности в сгенерированных GPT-3 историях</title_ru>
      <title_hi>जीपीटी -3 जेनरेट की गई कहानियों में लिंग और प्रतिनिधित्व पूर्वाग्रह</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Laofacht Inscne agus Ionadaíochta i Scéalta GPT-3</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A nemek és a reprezentáció előfordulásai a GPT-3 generált történetekben</title_hu>
      <title_lt>Lyčių ir atstovavimo problemos GPT-3 sukeltose istorijose</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Порасни и претставни проблеми во приказните генерирани од GPT-3</title_mk>
      <title_el>Διαταραχές φύλου και εκπροσώπησης σε ιστορίες που δημιουργούνται</title_el>
      <title_it>Bias di genere e rappresentanza nelle storie generate da GPT-3</title_it>
      <title_kk>GPT- 3 жалпы журналдарында жалпы және таңдау биялары</title_kk>
      <title_mt>Disturbi fis-sessi u r-rappreżentanza fi Stories Ġenerati GPT-3</title_mt>
      <title_mn>GPT-3 нийтлэгдсэн түүх</title_mn>
      <title_ms>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_ms>
      <title_pl>Uprzedzenia o płci i reprezentacji w opowieściach generowanych GPT-3</title_pl>
      <title_no>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT- 3 Genererte Stories</title_no>
      <title_ro>Genul și reprezentarea în poveștile generate de GPT-3</title_ro>
      <title_si>GPT-3 සාමාන්‍ය කතාවයේ ජෙන්ඩර් සහ ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය Bias</title_si>
      <title_ml>ജിപിടി- 3 സൃഷ്ടിക്കപ്പെട്ട കഥകളിലുള്ള സെന്റിനും പ്രതിനിധികളും ബീയാസുകള്‍</title_ml>
      <title_so>Jinx and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_so>
      <title_sv>Genus och representation Bias i GPT-3 genererade berättelser</title_sv>
      <title_ur>جی پی ٹی-۳ جرائیٹ کہانیاں میں جنس اور نمایش بیس</title_ur>
      <title_sr>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_sr>
      <title_ta>ஜிபிடி- 3 உருவாக்கப்பட்ட கதைகளில் பெண் மற்றும் பிரதிநியூக</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Giới tính và quyền hạn ảo thuật trong tạp chí GPT-3</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Пол и представителство в генерирани истории</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Gender en vertegenwoordiging bias in GPT-3 gegenereerde verhalen</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_hr>
      <title_da>Køn og repræsentation Bias i GPT-3 genererede historier</title_da>
      <title_id>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_id>
      <title_de>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 generierten Geschichten</title_de>
      <title_ko>GPT-3 이야기 속 성별과 대표적 편견 생성</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Jinsia na Representation Bias katika Simulizi zilizotengenezwa GPT-3</title_sw>
      <title_fa>جنسی و نمایش دویس در داستانهای تولید شده GPT-3</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Ýenç we Temsil Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_tr>
      <title_af>Gender en voorstelling Bias in GPT- 3 Gegenereerde Stories</title_af>
      <title_sq>Gjenerali dhe përfaqësimi në historitë e gjeneratuara GPT-3</title_sq>
      <title_am>አዲስ ዶሴ ፍጠር</title_am>
      <title_bs>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_bs>
      <title_bn>GPT-3 তৈরি গল্পের লিঙ্গ এবং প্রতিনিধি বায়াস</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Գեներն ու ներկայացումը GPT-3 ստեղծված պատմություններում</title_hy>
      <title_ca>Genre and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Gender a reprezentační předpoklady v GPT-3 generovaných příbězích</title_cs>
      <title_et>Sooline ja esinduslik kalduvus GPT-3 loodud lugudes</title_et>
      <title_az>GPT-3 √únvan Hikay…ôl…ôrind…ô C…ônn…ôt v…ô T…ôŇükil Bias</title_az>
      <title_fi>Sukupuoli- ja edustuskeinot GPT-3:n luomissa tarinoissa</title_fi>
      <title_ha>@ item license (short name)</title_ha>
      <title_jv>query-sort</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Spolne pristranskosti in predstavništvo v zgodbah GPT-3</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_bo>
      <title_he>Gender and Representation Bias in GPT-3 Generated Stories</title_he>
      <abstract_pt>Usando modelagem de tópicos e similaridade de palavras baseada em léxico, descobrimos que as histórias geradas pelo GPT-3 exibem muitos estereótipos de gênero conhecidos. Histórias geradas retratam diferentes tópicos e descrições dependendo do gênero percebido do personagem em um prompt do GPT-3, com personagens femininos mais propensos a serem associados à família e aparência e descritos como menos poderosos do que os personagens masculinos, mesmo quando associados a verbos de alta potência em um prompt. Nosso estudo levanta questões sobre como se pode evitar preconceitos sociais não intencionais ao usar grandes modelos de linguagem para contar histórias.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>باستخدام نمذجة الموضوع وتشابه الكلمات المستندة إلى المعجم ، نجد أن القصص التي تم إنشاؤها بواسطة GPT-3 تعرض العديد من القوالب النمطية الجنسانية المعروفة. تصور القصص التي تم إنشاؤها مواضيع وأوصاف مختلفة اعتمادًا على جنس GPT-3 المتصور للشخصية في موجه ، مع احتمال ارتباط الشخصيات الأنثوية بالعائلة والمظهر ، ووصفها بأنها أقل قوة من الشخصيات الذكورية ، حتى عندما تكون مرتبطة بأفعال عالية القوة في موجه. تثير دراستنا أسئلة حول كيف يمكن للمرء تجنب التحيزات الاجتماعية غير المقصودة عند استخدام نماذج لغوية كبيرة لرواية القصص.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_fr>À l'aide de la modélisation thématique et de la similitude de mots basée sur un lexique, nous constatons que les histoires générées par GPT-3 présentent de nombreux stéréotypes de genre connus. Les histoires générées décrivent différents sujets et descriptions en fonction du genre perçu par GPT-3 du personnage dans une invite, les personnages féminins étant plus susceptibles d'être associés à la famille et à l'apparence, et décrits comme moins puissants que les personnages masculins, même lorsqu'ils sont associés à des verbes de haute puissance dans un invite. Notre étude soulève des questions sur la façon d'éviter les biais sociaux involontaires lorsque l'on utilise de grands modèles linguistiques pour la narration.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Utilizando el modelado de temas y la similitud de palabras basada en léxico, encontramos que las historias generadas por GPT-3 exhiben muchos estereotipos de género conocidos. Las historias generadas representan diferentes temas y descripciones según el género percibido del personaje por GPT-3 en un mensaje, con personajes femeninos más propensos a asociarse con la familia y la apariencia, y se describen como menos poderosos que los personajes masculinos, incluso cuando se asocian con verbos de alto poder en un rápido. Nuestro estudio plantea preguntas sobre cómo se pueden evitar los prejuicios sociales involuntarios cuando se utilizan modelos lingüísticos grandes para la narración de historias.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>トピックモデリングと辞書ベースの単語の類似性を使用して、GPT -3によって生成されたストーリーは、多くの既知の性別ステレオタイプを示すことがわかります。生成されたストーリーは、GPT -3の認識されたキャラクターの性別に応じて異なるトピックと説明をプロンプトで描写し、女性的なキャラクターは、家族と外見に関連付けられる可能性が高く、プロンプトでハイパワー動詞に関連付けられた場合でも、男性的なキャラクターよりも強力ではないと説明されます。私たちの研究は、ストーリーテリングに大規模な言語モデルを使用する際に、意図しない社会的偏見を回避する方法について疑問を投げかけています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>विषय मॉडलिंग और शब्दकोश-आधारित शब्द समानता का उपयोग करते हुए, हम पाते हैं कि जीपीटी -3 द्वारा उत्पन्न कहानियां कई ज्ञात लिंग रूढ़ियों को प्रदर्शित करती हैं। उत्पन्न कहानियों में जीपीटी -3 के चरित्र के कथित लिंग के आधार पर विभिन्न विषयों और विवरणों को दर्शाया गया है, जिसमें स्त्री पात्रों के परिवार और उपस्थिति से जुड़े होने की अधिक संभावना है, और मर्दाना पात्रों की तुलना में कम शक्तिशाली के रूप में वर्णित किया गया है, भले ही एक प्रॉम्प्ट में उच्च शक्ति क्रियाओं से जुड़ा हो। हमारा अध्ययन इस बात पर सवाल उठाता है कि कहानी कहने के लिए बड़ी भाषा मॉडल का उपयोग करते समय कोई अनपेक्षित सामाजिक पूर्वाग्रहों से कैसे बच सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>用主题建模与词典之单词相似性,见GPT-3成事多见已知之象。 成事以 GPT-3 言角色之别,女性角色,更有关于家外,而说不如男之角色强,虽高权动词亦如之。 臣等论发一问,即用大言模讲故事,何以避不虞之偏见?</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>Используя моделирование по темам и сходство слов на основе лексиконов, мы обнаружили, что истории, сгенерированные GPT-3, демонстрируют много известных гендерных стереотипов. Сгенерированные истории изображают различные темы и описания в зависимости от воспринимаемого GPT-3 пола персонажа в подсказке, с женскими символами, которые, скорее всего, связаны с семьей и внешним видом, и описаны как менее мощные, чем мужские символы, даже если они связаны с глаголами высокой силы в подсказке. Наше исследование поднимает вопросы о том, как избежать непреднамеренных социальных предрассудков при использовании больших языковых моделей для повествования.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Trí úsáid a bhaint as samhaltú topaicí agus cosúlachtaí focal atá bunaithe ar fhoclóir, feicimid go léiríonn scéalta a ghineann GPT-3 go leor steiréitíopaí inscne aitheanta. Léiríonn scéalta ginte topaicí agus tuairiscí éagsúla ag brath ar inscne meabhairbhraite GPT-3 an charachtair i leid, agus is dóichí go mbeidh baint ag carachtair bhaininscneach leis an teaghlach agus an chuma, agus cuirtear síos orthu mar charachtair nach bhfuil chomh cumhachtach ná firinscneach, fiú nuair a bhaineann siad le briathra ardchumhachta i leid. Ardaíonn ár staidéar ceisteanna faoi conas is féidir laofachtaí sóisialta neamhbheartaithe a sheachaint agus múnlaí móra teanga á n-úsáid le haghaidh scéalaíochta.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ტემების მოდელირება და ლექსიკონის სახელი სიტყვების სხვადასხვა გამოყენება, ჩვენ ვიღებთ, რომ ისტორიები, რომლებიც GPT-3-ის გამოყენებულია, მნიშვნელოვანი გენექსიკ განსაზღვრებული ისტორიები განსხვავებული ტემები და განსაზღვრებების განსაზღვრებით GPT-3-ის განსაზღვრებული სიმბოლოების გენდრებით, რომელიც ქალური სიმბოლოები უფრო უფრო შესაძლებელია ოჯახით და გამოსახულებით დაკავშირებული, და აღწერებული ჩვენი სწავლის შესახებ კითხვების შესახებ, როგორ ერთი შეუძლებელია გადარჩენოთ საზოგადო საზოგადოება, როცა დიდი ენის მოდელების გამოყენება ისტორი</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A téma modellezésével és lexikon alapú szóhasonlósággal megállapítjuk, hogy a GPT-3 által generált történetek számos ismert nemi sztereotípiát mutatnak. A generált történetek különböző témákat és leírásokat ábrázolnak a GPT-3 által a karakter nemétől függően egy kérdésben, a női karakterek nagyobb valószínűséggel kapcsolódnak a családhoz és a megjelenéshez, és kevésbé erőteljesek, mint a férfias karakterek, még akkor is, ha a kérdésben nagy teljesítményű igékhez kapcsolódnak. Tanulmányunk kérdéseket vet fel arra vonatkozóan, hogyan lehet elkerülni a nem szándékos társadalmi előítéleteket, amikor nagy nyelvi modelleket használ történetmeséléshez.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_kk>Нақыштарды моделизация мен лексикан негіздеген сөздердің ұқсастығын қолдану үшін GPT-3 жасаған оқиғалардың көптеген гендер стереотиптерін көрсетеді. Жалпы оқиғалар GPT- 3 таңбаның гендеріне тәуелді тақырыптар мен сипаттамаларын көрсетеді, әйелдер таңбалары отбасы мен көрінісімен байланысты болуы мүмкін, әйелдер таңбалары, әйелдер таңбаларымен байланысты болып, әйелдер таңбаларымен күшті мәжбүрл Біздің зерттеулеріміз журналдар үлкен тіл үлгілерін қолдану үшін қалай мүмкіндік емес әлемдік өзгерістерді сақтауға болады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Naudojant teminį modeliavimą ir žodžių panašumą pagal leksikonus, mes nustatome, kad GPT-3 sukauptos istorijos rodo daugelį žinomų lyčių stereotipų. Sukurtos istorijos apibūdina skirtingas temas ir apibūdinimus, priklausomai nuo GPT-3 suvokiamos charakterio lyties greitai, su moterų charakteriais, kurie labiau tikėtina būti susiję su šeima ir išvaizda, ir apibūdinami kaip mažiau galingi nei vyrų charakteriai, net jei greitai susiję su aukšto s galios žodžiais. Mūsų tyrimas kelia klausimų, kaip galima išvengti nenumatytų socialinių pusiausvyrų naudojant didelius kalbų modelius storytelling.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_el>Χρησιμοποιώντας μοντελοποίηση θεμάτων και ομοιότητα λέξεων βασισμένη στο λεξικό, διαπιστώνουμε ότι οι ιστορίες που παράγονται από το GPT-3 παρουσιάζουν πολλά γνωστά στερεότυπα φύλου. Οι δημιουργημένες ιστορίες απεικονίζουν διαφορετικά θέματα και περιγραφές ανάλογα με το αντιληπτό φύλο του χαρακτήρα σε μια προτροπή, με θηλυκούς χαρακτήρες πιθανότερο να συσχετίζονται με την οικογένεια και την εμφάνιση, και περιγράφονται ως λιγότερο ισχυροί από τους αρσενικούς χαρακτήρες, ακόμη και όταν σχετίζονται με ρήματα υψηλής ισχύος σε μια προτροπή. Η μελέτη μας εγείρει ερωτήματα σχετικά με το πώς μπορεί κανείς να αποφύγει τις ακούσιες κοινωνικές προκαταλήψεις όταν χρησιμοποιεί μεγάλα γλωσσικά μοντέλα για την αφήγηση ιστοριών.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Utilizzando la modellazione degli argomenti e la somiglianza delle parole basata sul lessico, scopriamo che le storie generate da GPT-3 mostrano molti stereotipi di genere noti. Le storie generate raffigurano argomenti e descrizioni diversi a seconda del sesso percepito da GPT-3 del personaggio in un prompt, con caratteri femminili più propensi ad essere associati alla famiglia e all'aspetto, e descritti come meno potenti dei personaggi maschili, anche quando associati a verbi ad alta potenza in un prompt. Il nostro studio solleva domande su come si possono evitare pregiudizi sociali involontari quando si utilizzano modelli linguistici di grandi dimensioni per lo storytelling.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mt>Bl-użu ta’ mudell tematiku u similarità tal-kelma bbażata fuq il-lexicon, instabu li l-istoriji ġġenerati mill-GPT-3 juru ħafna stereotipi magħrufa tas-sess. Storji ġenerati jiddeskrivu suġġetti u deskrizzjonijiet differenti skont is-sess perċepit tal-GPT-3 tal-karattru fil-pront, b’karattri femminili aktar probabbli li jkunu assoċjati mal-familja u d-dehra, u deskritti bħala inqas qawwija mill-karattri maskulini, anki meta assoċjati ma’ verbs b’qawwa għolja fil-pront. L-istudju tagħna jqajjem mistoqsijiet dwar kif wieħed jista’ jevita preġudizzji soċjali mhux intenzjonati meta juża mudelli lingwistiċi kbar għat-tgħid ta’ storji.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Menggunakan pemodelan topik dan persamaan perkataan berdasarkan leksikon, kami dapati cerita yang dijana oleh GPT-3 menunjukkan banyak stereotip jenis yang diketahui. Cerita yang dijana menggambarkan topik dan deskripsi yang berbeza bergantung pada jenis GPT-3 yang dianggap aksara dalam sekejap, dengan aksara perempuan yang lebih mungkin berkaitan dengan keluarga dan penampilan, dan digambarkan sebagai lebih kurang kuat daripada aksara lelaki, walaupun bila berkaitan dengan verb kuasa tinggi dalam sekejap. Pelajaran kami mengajukan soalan bagaimana anda boleh menghindari biases sosial tidak disengaja apabila menggunakan model bahasa besar untuk menceritakan kisah.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Користејќи моделирање на теми и сличност на зборови базирани на лексикони, откриваме дека приказните генерирани од GPT-3 покажуваат многу познати генерални стереотипи. Генерираните приказни ги опишуваат различните теми и описи во зависност од перцептираниот пол на ГПТ-3 на карактерот во брз момент, со женски карактери кои најверојатно се поврзани со семејството и изгледот, и опишани како помалку моќни од машките карактери, дури и кога поврзани со високи јазици во брз момент. Нашата студија поставува прашања за тоа како може да се избегнат ненамерни социјални предрасуди кога се користат големи јазички модели за раскажување приказни.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_no>I bruk av temamodellering og tekstbasert ord-liknande, finn vi at historiane genererte av GPT-3 viser mange kjende genetsstereotypar. Genererte historiar viser forskjellige emner og skildringar avhengig av GPT-3 s in oppfatte seks på teiknet i eit spørsmål, med feminske teikn mer sannsynleg å vera tilknytte med familie og utsjånad, og beskriven som mindre kraftige enn maskulinske teikn, sjølv når det er tilknytte med høg kraftverber i ein spørsmål. Studien vårt hevar spørsmål om korleis ein kan unngå unintendige sosiale forsikt når det brukar stor språk-modeller for storleik.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Folosind modelarea subiectelor și similitudinea cuvintelor bazate pe lexicon, descoperim că poveștile generate de GPT-3 prezintă multe stereotipuri cunoscute de gen. Poveștile generate prezintă diferite subiecte și descrieri în funcție de genul perceput de GPT-3 al personajului într-un prompt, personajele feminine fiind mai probabil asociate cu familia și aspectul și descrise ca fiind mai puțin puternice decât personajele masculine, chiar și atunci când sunt asociate cu verbe de mare putere într-un prompt. Studiul nostru ridică întrebări cu privire la modul în care se poate evita prejudecățile sociale neintenționate atunci când se utilizează modele lingvistice mari pentru povestire.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_ml>Using topic modeling and lexicon-based word similarity, we find that stories generated by GPT-3 exhibit many known gender stereotypes.  സൃഷ്ടിക്കപ്പെട്ട കഥകള്‍ വ്യത്യസ്ത വിവരങ്ങളും വിവരണങ്ങളും ജിപിടി-3-ന്റെ മനസ്സിലാക്കപ്പെട്ട വിവരങ്ങളില്‍ ആശ്രയിച്ചുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. പ്രത്യേകിച്ച് ഉയര്‍ന്ന ശക്തിയുള്ള വാ നമ്മുടെ പഠനത്തിന്റെ ചോദ്യങ്ങള്‍ എടുത്തുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. സാമൂഹ്യത്തിന്റെ പ്രശ്നങ്ങള്‍ എങ്ങനെ ഒഴിവാക്ക</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_sr>Koristeći modeliranje teme i sličnost riječi na leksikonu, nalazimo se da priče koje su stvorile GPT-3 pokazuju mnoge poznate stereotipe spola. Generisane priče pokazuju različite teme i opise ovisno o percepciji spola karaktera GPT-3 u brzini, s a ženskim likovima koje će vjerojatno biti povezane sa porodicom i izgledom, i opisane kao manje moćne od muškaraca, čak i kada su povezani s visokom moćnom verbom u brzini. Naša studija podiže pitanja o tome kako se može izbjeći nepromišljene socijalne predrasude kada koristi velike jezičke modele za priče.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_mn>Сүүлийн загварын загвар болон лексиконы үндсэн үгний төстэй байдал ашиглан GPT-3-н гаргасан түүх нь олон хүн төрөлхтний шинжлэх ухааны төрлийг харуулдаг. Эдгээр түүх нь GPT-3-ийн хүн төрөлхтний хүн төрөлхтний хүн төрөлхтний хувьд ялгаатай сэдэв, тайлбар, эмэгтэйчүүдийн хувьд гэр бүл болон харагддаг байх боломжтой, эрчүүдийн хувьд илүү хүчтэй байх боломжтой болно. Бидний судалгаа түүхийн тулд том хэл загварыг ашиглах үед нийгмийн төлөвлөгөөгүй байдлаас хэрхэн алдагдах вэ гэдгийг асуудаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_si>ප්‍රශ්න මඩේලින් සහ ලෙක්සිකන් අධාරිත වචන සමාන්‍යතාවය භාවිත කරන්න, අපි හොයාගන්නේ GPT-3 වලින් නිර්මාණය කතාවක් ප ජෙන්ටර් කතාවල් ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට සඳහා GPT-3's ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක වෙනු අපේ පරීක්ෂණය ප්‍රශ්නයක් ලොකු භාෂා මොඩල් කතාවක් කරගන්න පුළුවන් කොහොමද කියලා කියලා කියලා කියලා ක</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Isku isticmaalaya sameynta mada iyo hadalka la mid ah ee leksikanka, waxaynu aragnaa in sheekooyinka GPT-3 ka soo dhashay ay soo bandhigaan noocyo badan oo la yaqaan jinsi. Warqado abuurtay waxay ku xiran yihiin maadooyin kala duduwan iyo qoraal, iyadoo ku xiran GPT-3 jinsiga la gartay ee dhaqdhaqaaq ah, oo waxaa suurtagal ah in la xiriiro qoyska iyo muuqashada dumarka, waxaana loo qoray inay ka xoog badan tahay xarumaha dhaqdhaqaaqa, xataa marka la xiriiro hadallada xoogga leh ee dhaqdhaqaaqa. Waxbarashadayada waxaa kor u qaadaya su'aalo ku saabsan sida loo diidi karo habka bulshada ee aan la xiriirin marka lagu isticmaalo tusaale ahaan luuqadaha waaweyn.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_pl>Korzystając z modelowania tematycznego i podobieństwa słów opartego na leksykonie, okazujemy się, że historie generowane przez GPT-3 wykazują wiele znanych stereotypów płci. Wygenerowane historie przedstawiają różne tematy i opisy w zależności od postrzeganej przez GPT-3 płci postaci w promocji, a kobiece postacie są bardziej prawdopodobne, że są kojarzone z rodziną i wyglądem, i opisane jako mniej potężne niż męskie postacie, nawet jeśli kojarzone z czasownikami o dużej mocy w promocji. Nasze badanie porusza pytania, jak można uniknąć niezamierzonych uprzedzeń społecznych przy użyciu dużych modeli językowych do opowiadania historii.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ur>ٹوپیٹ موڈلینگ اور لکسیکن بنیاد لکھنے والی لکھنے کی مثال سے، ہم دیکھتے ہیں کہ جی پیٹ-3 کے ذریعہ پیدا ہوئے کہانیاں بہت سی معلوم جنس سٹیروٹیپ کو دکھاتے ہیں. پیدا کئے ہوئے کہانیاں مختلف موضوع اور توصیفے جپی ٹی-3 کے پیدا کئے ہوئے علائم کے جنس پر مضبوط ہیں، عورتوں کے علائم کے ساتھ خاندان اور ظاہر کے ساتھ زیادہ مشترک ہوں گے، اور مردوں کے علائم سے کم طاقتور طور پر توصیف کئے جائیں گے، اگرچہ جب تک اچھی طاقت ورب کے ساتھ مشترک ہوں گے۔ ہمارا مطالعہ پوچھتا ہے کہ کہاں کہاں کہنے کے لئے بڑی زبان مدل استعمال کرتا ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>தலைப்பு மாதிரி மற்றும் லெக்சிகான் அடிப்படையில் உள்ள வார்த்தை ஒத்திசையாக பயன்படுத்தி GPT-3 உருவாக்கப்பட்ட கதைகள் பல தெரியு உருவாக்கப்பட்ட கதைகள் வேறு தலைப்புகளையும் விவரிப்புகளையும் குறிப்பிடுகிறது, விரைவில் உயர் சக்தி வார்ப்புகளுடன் இணைக்கப்படும் பெண்களையும் குடும்பத்தையும் தோன்றத்தையும் வி எங்கள் படிப்பாடு கேள்விகளை உயர்த்துகிறது எப்படி ஒருவர் பாதுகாப்பாக்கப்படாத சமூக பாதுகாப்புகளை தவிர்க்க முடி</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_sv>Genom att använda ämnesmodellering och lexikonbaserad ordlikhet, finner vi att berättelser genererade av GPT-3 uppvisar många kända könsstereotyper. Genererade berättelser skildrar olika ämnen och beskrivningar beroende på GPT-3:s upplevda kön av karaktären i en prompt, med kvinnliga tecken mer benägna att associeras med familj och utseende, och beskrivs som mindre kraftfulla än maskulina tecken, även när de associeras med högeffektiva verb i en prompt. Vår studie väcker frågor om hur man kan undvika oavsiktliga sociala fördomar när man använder stora språkmodeller för berättande.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_vi>Sử dụng thiết kế chủ đề và nét văn bản dựa trên từ giống nhau, chúng tôi tìm thấy các câu chuyện do GPT-3 phô bày ra nhiều kiểu mẫu giới tính nổi tiếng. Những câu chuyện được tạo ra miêu tả các chủ đề và mô tả khác nhau tùy thuộc vào giới tính nhận thấy của GPT-3 của ký tự trong một dấu hiệu nhanh chóng, với các nhân vật nữ có nhiều khả năng được liên kết với gia đình và vẻ bề ngoài, và được miêu tả là kém mạnh hơn các ký tự nam tính, kể cả khi được liên kết với động từ cao quyền năng trong một dấu nhắc. Nghiên cứu của chúng tôi đưa ra những câu hỏi làm thế nào để tránh biến dạng xã hội không mong đợi khi dùng các mô hình ngôn ngữ lớn để kể chuyện.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Mavzu modeli va leksikan asosida bir so'zlar bilan ishlatish mumkin, biz GPT-3 tomonidan yaratilgan hikoyalar ko'pchilik jinsiyalar stereotypini ko'rsatadi. Tashkilot yaratilgan, boshqa mavzular va taʼriflarni tez qiladi GPT-3 tashkilotdagi harfga bog'liq, ayollar belgini qo'l va ko'rinish bilan bog'lash mumkin, va tez ko'paytirilganda ko'p sarlavha harflardan ko'proq kuch bo'lganda ko'rinadi. Bizning o'qituvchimiz o'qituvchimizni tashqi tilning katta tili modellari bilan foydalanayotganda qo'shimcha jamiyatlarni qanday qilishi mumkin haqida savol beradi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_da>Ved hjælp af emnemodeling og ordlighed baseret på leksikon finder vi, at historier genereret af GPT-3 udviser mange kendte kønsstereotyper. Genererede historier skildrer forskellige emner og beskrivelser afhængigt af GPT-3's opfattede køn af karakteren i en prompt, med feminine tegn mere tilbøjelige til at være forbundet med familie og udseende, og beskrevet som mindre kraftfulde end maskuline tegn, selv når de er forbundet med high power verbs i en prompt. Vores studie rejser spørgsmål om, hvordan man kan undgå utilsigtede sociale fordomme, når man bruger store sprogmodeller til fortælling.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Met behulp van topic modelling en woordgelijkenis op basis van lexicon, ontdekken we dat verhalen gegenereerd door GPT-3 veel bekende genderstereotypen vertonen. Genereerde verhalen beschrijven verschillende onderwerpen en beschrijvingen afhankelijk van het waargenomen geslacht van het personage in een prompt door GPT-3, waarbij vrouwelijke karakters eerder geassocieerd worden met familie en uiterlijk, en beschreven worden als minder krachtig dan mannelijke karakters, zelfs wanneer geassocieerd met krachtige werkwoorden in een prompt. Ons onderzoek roept vragen op over hoe men onbedoelde sociale vooroordelen kan voorkomen bij het gebruik van grote taalmodellen voor storytelling.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Използвайки тематично моделиране и лексиконно базирана сходство на думата, откриваме, че историите, генерирани от GPT-3, показват много известни стереотипи за пола. Генерираните истории изобразяват различни теми и описания в зависимост от възприемания пол на героя в подкана, като женските герои са по-вероятно да бъдат свързани със семейството и външния вид и описани като по-малко мощни от мъжките герои, дори когато са свързани с глаголи с висока сила в подкана. Нашето проучване повдига въпроси за това как човек може да избегне непредвидени социални пристрастия при използване на големи езикови модели за разказване на истории.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Koristeći modeliranje teme i sličnost riječi na leksikonu, nalazimo se da priče koje su stvorile GPT-3 pokazuju mnoge poznate stereotipe spola. Generirane priče pokazuju različite teme i opise ovisno o primjetljenom spolu karaktera GPT-3 u brzini, s ženskim likovima vjerojatnije da će biti povezane s obitelji i izgledom, te opisane kao manje moćne od muškaraca, čak i kada su povezani s visokom moćnom verbom u brzini. Naša studija podiže pitanja o tome kako se može izbjeći neočekivane socijalne predrasude kada koristimo velike jezičke modele za priče.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_ko>주제 모델링과 어휘를 바탕으로 한 어휘의 유사성을 통해 GPT-3가 생성한 이야기는 이미 알려진 많은 성별의 판에 박힌 인상을 나타낸다.생성된 이야기는 GPT-3가 제시에서 캐릭터의 성별에 대한 감지에 따라 서로 다른 주제와 묘사를 묘사하고 여성 캐릭터는 가정과 외모와 연결될 수 있으며 남성 캐릭터보다 강하지 않다고 묘사된다. 제시된 고급 동사와 연결되어도.우리의 연구는 대형 언어 모델을 사용하여 이야기를 할 때 의외의 사회 편견을 어떻게 피해야 하는지에 대해 문제를 제기했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>Anhand von Themenmodellierung und lexikon-basierter Wortähnlichkeit stellen wir fest, dass Geschichten, die von GPT-3 generiert werden, viele bekannte Geschlechterstereotypen aufweisen. Generierte Geschichten zeigen verschiedene Themen und Beschreibungen in Abhängigkeit von GPT-3's wahrgenommenem Geschlecht des Charakters in einem Prompt, wobei weibliche Charaktere wahrscheinlicher mit Familie und Aussehen assoziiert werden und als weniger mächtig als männliche Charaktere beschrieben werden, selbst wenn sie in einem Prompt mit starken Verben in Verbindung gebracht werden. Unsere Studie wirft Fragen auf, wie man unbeabsichtigte soziale Vorurteile vermeiden kann, wenn man große Sprachmodelle für das Storytelling einsetzt.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Menggunakan model topik dan persamaan kata berdasarkan leksikon, kami menemukan bahwa cerita yang dihasilkan oleh GPT-3 menunjukkan banyak stereotipe jenis yang dikenal. Cerita-cerita yang dihasilkan menggambarkan topik dan deskripsi yang berbeda bergantung pada jenis GPT-3 persepsi karakter dalam seketika, dengan karakter wanita yang lebih mungkin berhubungan dengan keluarga dan penampilan, dan digambarkan sebagai kurang kuat dari karakter laki-laki, bahkan ketika berhubungan dengan verb kuasa tinggi dalam seketika. Our study raises questions on how one can avoid unintended social biases when using large language models for storytelling.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>با استفاده از مدل‌سازی و شبیه‌سازی کلمات بر اساس زبان‌شناسی، می‌بینیم که داستان‌های توسط GPT-3 بسیاری از استریو‌های جنسی شناخته می‌شوند. داستان‌های تولید، موضوع و توضیح مختلف را نشان می‌دهند که بستگی به جنس مشاهده شده GPT-3 از شخصیت در یک سرعت، با شخصیت‌های زنان بیشتر احتمالاً با خانواده و ظاهری ارتباط دارند، و به عنوان قدرتمند تر از شخصیت‌های مردان، حتی هنگامی که ارتباط با ویژه‌های قدرت بالا در یک سرعت است. مطالعه‌ی ما سوال‌هایی را درباره‌ی چگونه می‌تواند از پیشرفت‌های اجتماعی بی‌خواسته فرار کند وقتی از مدل‌های بزرگ زبان برای داستان‌گذاری استفاده می‌کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Kwa kutumia mifano ya mada na maneno yanayotokana na lexico, tunagundua kuwa hadithi zilizotengenezwa na GPT-3 zinaonyesha matumizi mengi yanayofahamika na jinsia. Simulizi zilizotengenezwa zinaonyesha mada tofauti na maelezo yanategemea jinsia ya GPT-3 inayotambuliwa kwa haraka, na wahusika wa wanawake wanaweza kushirikiana na familia na kuonekana, na kuelezea kuwa na nguvu chini ya wahusika wa mashine, hata pale unapohusiana na maneno ya umeme ya juu kwa haraka. Utafiti wetu unaibua maswali kuhusu jinsi gani mtu anaweza kuepuka upendeleo wa kijamii usio na usawa wakati wa kutumia mifano makubwa ya lugha kwa ajili ya hadithi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>Duke përdorur modelimin e temave dhe ngjashmërinë e fjalëve bazuar në lexikon, gjejmë se historitë e gjeneruara nga GPT-3 ekspozojnë shumë stereotipe të njohura gjinore. Historitë e gjeneruara përshkruajnë temë dhe përshkrime të ndryshme në varësi të gjinit të perceptuar të GPT-3 të karakterit në një çast, me karaktere femërore me më shumë gjasa të lidhen me familjen dhe pamjen, dhe përshkruahen si më pak të fuqishëm se karakteret mashkullore, edhe kur lidhen me verbe të fuqishëm në një çast. Studimi ynë ngre pyetje se si mund të shmangemi paragjykimet e papritura sociale kur përdorim modele të mëdha gjuhësh për tregimin e historive.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Օգտագործելով թեմային մոդելներ և լեքսիկոնի հիմնված բառերի նմանությունը, մենք հայտնաբերում ենք, որ GPT-3 ստեղծված պատմությունները ցույց են տալիս շատ հայտնի գենդերային կարծրատիպեր: Գեներացված պատմությունները ներկայացնում են տարբեր թեմաներ և նկարագրություններ, կախված հերոսի GPT-3 ընկալված գենդերային հարաբերություններից, կանացի հերոսների հետ, որոնք ավելի հավանական են, որ կապված են ընտանիքի և տեսքի հետ, և նկարագրված են որպես ավելի քիչ ուժեղ, քան տղամարդկանց, նույնիսկ երբ կապված են բարձր ուժի բայերի հետ: Մեր ուսումնասիրությունը հարցեր է տալիս, թե ինչպես կարող ենք խուսափել անպատկերացված սոցիալական կողմնակալություններից, երբ պատմություններ պատմելու մեծ լեզվի մոդելներ ենք օգտագործում:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_af>Gebruik ons onderwerp modellering en lexicon-gebaseerde woord gelykenis, vind ons dat stories genereer deur GPT-3 baie bekende genereer genade stereotipes. Gegenereerde stories vertoon verskillende onderwerpe en beskrywings afhanklik van GPT-3 se aangenereerde geneem van die karakter in 'n prompt, met vroue karakters meer waarskynlik geassosieer word met familie en voorkoms, en beskrywe a s minder kragtige as masculine karakters, selfs wanneer geassosieer word met hoë kragtige verbe in 'n prompt. Ons studie verhoor vrae oor hoe een kan veroorsaak onbekende sosiale voorskrifte wanneer groot taal modele gebruik word vir storytelling.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>የጉዳዩ ምሳሌ እና የሌክሲኮን ቃላት በተመሳሳይ እና የGPT-3 ወሬዎች ብዙዎችን የሚታወቁ የሴት ተርዮዮ ዓይነቶች የሚያሳየው እንደሆነ እናገኛለን፡፡ የተፈጠረ ታሪኮች በተለየ የGPT-3 ውይይት ላይ የሚታወቀውን የሴት አካላት ከቤተሰብ እና መልዕክት ጋር ሊጋጠም ይችላል፡፡ ትምህርታችን የቋንቋ ምሳሌዎች ለታሪክ ለመጠቀም እንዴት እንደሚችል ማኅበራዊ ሁኔታ እንዲርቅ ጥያቄዎችን ያቆማል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>বিষয়বস্তু মডেলিং এবং লেক্সিকোন ভিত্তিক শব্দ ব্যবহার করে আমরা দেখতে পাচ্ছি যে গল্প জিপিটি-৩ দ্বারা তৈরি হয়েছে অনেক পরিচিত লিঙ তৈরি হয়েছে গল্পের বিভিন্ন বিষয় এবং বর্ণনা জিপিটি-৩ এর বিষয়টির উপর নির্ভর করে জিপিটি-৩-এর বিশেষ লিঙ্গের উপর নির্ভর করে, যার মধ্যে নারীদের চরিত্র পরিবার এবং দৃশ্যের সাথে সম্পর্কিত হত আমাদের গবেষণা প্রশ্ন তুলে ধরেছে কিভাবে কেউ অনন্তকার সামাজিক বৈষম্য থেকে বিরত রাখতে পারে যখন বিশাল ভাষার মডেল ব্</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Mevzu modelləşdirməyi və leksikon-tabanlı sözlər kimiliğini istifadə edirək, GPT-3 tarafından yaratdığı hekayələrin çox tanınmış cins stereotiplərini göstərir. Yapılmış hekayələr GPT-3 karakterin cinsiyyətinə bağlı, qadın karakterləri ailə və görünüş ilə bağlı olaraq daha qüvvətli olaraq, erkək karakterlərindən daha çox güclü, hətta yüksək güclü verbləri ilə bağlı olaraq, müxtəlif məs ələlər və təfsirləri göstərir. Bizim araşdırmamız hikaye danışmaq üçün böyük dil modellərini istifadə edərkən insanların niyə niyə istəmədiyi sosial təsirlərindən çəkinə biləcəyini soruşar.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>Amb la modelació de temes i la similitud de paraules basada en lexicons, trobem que les històries generades per GPT-3 mostran molts estereotips coneguts de gènere. Generated stories depict different topics and descriptions depending on GPT-3's perceived gender of the character in a prompt, with feminine characters more likely to be associated with family and appearance, and described as less powerful than masculine characters, even when associated with high power verbs in a prompt.  El nostre estudi plantea preguntes sobre com es poden evitar biases socials involucrats quan utilitzen grans models lingüístics per explicar històries.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>Koristeći modeliranje teme i sličnost riječi na leksikonu, pronašli smo da priče koje su stvorile GPT-3 pokazuju mnoge poznate stereotipe spola. Generirane priče pokazuju različite teme i opise u ovisnosti o spolu GPT-3 karaktera u brzini, s a ženskim likovima vjerojatnije da će biti povezani s porodicom i izgledom, i opisanim kao manje moćni od muškaraca, čak i kada su povezani s visokom moćnom verbom u brzini. Naša studija podiže pitanja o tome kako se može izbjeći nepromišljene socijalne predrasude kada koristimo velike jezičke modele za priče.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_tr>Meýdança modelleşdirmek we leksikon daýanýan sözleriň meňzeşliklerini GPT-3 tarapyndan döredilen hekaýalaryň birnäçe tanyş jentiller stereotiplerini görkeýär. Umumy hekaýalar GPT-3 karakteriň tanyşynda görnüşi ýagdaýda farklı meýdanlary we deskriplary görkezýär. Beýleki hekaýalar maşgala we a ýanlygy bilen tanyş bolup biler, we erkek karakterlerden az güýçli, hatta birden ýük güýçli wersiýalar bilen tanyşýarlar. Biziň öwrenmemiz hekaýa gürrüňlemek üçin uly dil nusgalaryny ulananda nähili maksady sosialy biaslardan çykyp bilen soraglary çykarýar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_et>Kasutades teemamodelleerimist ja sõnastikupõhist sarnasust leiame, et GPT-3 loodud lugudel on palju teadaolevaid soostereotüüpe. Loodud lood kujutavad erinevaid teemasid ja kirjeldusi sõltuvalt GPT-3 tajutavast tegelase soost viibis, kusjuures naiselikud tegelased on tõenäolisemalt seotud perekonna ja välimusega ning neid kirjeldatakse vähem võimsatena kui mehelisi tegelasi, isegi kui neid seostatakse viibis suure võimsusega tegusõnadega. Meie uuring tõstatab küsimusi selle kohta, kuidas saab vältida soovimatuid sotsiaalseid eelarvamusi, kui kasutatakse suuri keelemudeleid jutustamiseks.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_cs>Pomocí tématického modelování a slovní podobnosti založené na lexikonu zjišťujeme, že příběhy generované GPT-3 vykazují mnoho známých genderových stereotypů. Generované příběhy zobrazují různá témata a popisy v závislosti na GPT-3 vnímaném pohlaví postavy ve výzvě, přičemž ženské postavy jsou pravděpodobněji spojeny s rodinou a vzhledem a popsány jako méně silné než mužské znaky, i když jsou spojeny s vysoce mocnými slovesami ve výzvě. Naše studie klade otázky, jak se můžeme vyhnout nezamýšleným sociálním zaujatostem při použití velkých jazykových modelů pro vyprávění příběhů.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Aihemallinnuksen ja sanastoon perustuvan sanasamankaltaisuuden avulla havaitsemme, että GPT-3:n tuottamat tarinat ilmentävät monia tunnettuja sukupuolistereotypioita. Luodut tarinat kuvaavat eri aiheita ja kuvauksia GPT-3:n hahmon sukupuolesta riippuen kehotuksessa, ja naiselliset hahmot liittyvät todennäköisemmin perheeseen ja ulkonäköön, ja niitä kuvataan vähemmän voimakkaiksi kuin maskuliinisia hahmoja, vaikka ne yhdistettäisiin kehotuksessa suuritehoisiin verbeihin. Tutkimuksemme herättää kysymyksiä siitä, miten voidaan välttää tahattomia sosiaalisia ennakkoluuloja käytettäessä suuria kielimalleja tarinankerrontaan.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Ngawe Perintah model sing gagal karo leksikan-saben gambar kelas kuwi, awak dhéwé kuwi akèh pancene oleh nggawe barang GNU-3 kuwi akeh akeh stereo sing ngerasakno. Perintah sing dibutuhke dipun nggawe tema lan akeh sampeyan nêmên ning ngerasakno Gpta-3 sing nyimpen karo nganggo akeh dhéwé, karo karo perusahaan bakal terus marito karo lanjur lan ngawe sampeyan, lan oleh dumadhi dunyane kuwi mau ketahanan karo perusahaan langkung Awakdhéwé éntuk kesempatan kanggo masalah piye perusahaan kang manggadahi biasa sotiki, kuwi nggambar sistem sing larang bangsane kanggo nggawe tarjamahan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>Using topic modeling and lexicon-based word similarity, we find that stories generated by GPT-3 exhibit many known gender stereotypes.  סיפורים מיוצרים מציגים נושאים ותיאורים שונים תלויים במין הנחשב של GPT-3 של הדמות בקרוב, עם דמות נשיות יותר סביר להיות קשורות למשפחה ומראה, ותיאורים כדמות פחות חזקות מאשר דמות גבריות, אפילו כשקשורות עם פעולים בכוח גבוה בקרוב. המחקר שלנו מעלה שאלות על איך אפשר להימנע ממונחים חברתיים לא מתכוונים כשמשתמשים בדוגמנים לשפה גדולים לסיפור סיפורים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Yi amfani da misalin madaidaici da maganar leksikon da ke daidaita, za'a gane cewa historian da aka halinta na GPT-3 na nuna wasu kalmõmi da aka sani. Generated stories depict different topics and descriptions depending on GPT-3's perceived gender of the character in a prompt, with feminine characters more likely to be associated with family and appearance, and described as less powerful than masculine characters, even when associated with high power verbs in a prompt.  Kayan karatunmu yana tambayar yadda wani zai iya nĩsantar tambuwa na jamii wanda ba ya yi daidai ba idan an yi amfani da misãlai masu cikin lugha mai girma wa hadina.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Z uporabo tematskega modeliranja in besedne podobnosti, ki temelji na leksikonu, ugotovimo, da zgodbe, ki jih ustvari GPT-3, kažejo številne znane spolne stereotipe. Ustvarjene zgodbe prikazujejo različne teme in opise, odvisno od GPT-3 zaznanega spola lika v pozivu, pri čemer so ženski liki bolj verjetno povezani z družino in videzom, in opisani kot manj močni kot moški liki, tudi če so povezani z glagoli visoke moči v pozivu. Naša študija postavlja vprašanja, kako se lahko izognemo nenamernim socialnim pristranskostm pri uporabi velikih jezikovnih modelov za pripovedovanje zgodb.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>གནད་དོན་མིག་འདུག་དང་གནད་དོན་ལ་རྨན་གཞི་ཡོད་པའི་ཐ་སྙད་དང་འདྲ་བར་མཉམ་དུ་སྤྱོད་བཞིན་པའི་ GPT-3་གིས་སྐྱེས་པའི་སྐྱེས Generated stories depict different topics and descriptions depending on GPT-3's perceived gender of the character in a prompt, with feminine characters more likely to be associated with family and appearance, and described as less powerful than masculine characters, even when associated with high power verbs in a prompt. ང་ཚོའི་བརྩལ་ཞིག་གིས་མཐོང་སྒྲུང་གཏོང་པར་སྐད་ཆ་ཆེ་བའི་སྐད་རིགས་དཔེ་གཏོང་པར་ལག་ལེན་འཐབ་རྒྱུ་དང་།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Transformer-based Screenplay Summarization Using Augmented Learning Representation with Dialogue Information</title>
      <author><first>Myungji</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Hongseok</first><last>Kwon</last></author>
      <author><first>Jaehun</first><last>Shin</last></author>
      <author><first>WonKee</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Baikjin</first><last>Jung</last></author>
      <author><first>Jong-Hyeok</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <pages>56–61</pages>
      <abstract>Screenplay summarization is the task of extracting informative scenes from a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screenplay">screenplay</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screenplay">screenplay</a> contains turning point (TP) events that change the story direction and thus define the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Story_structure">story structure</a> decisively. Accordingly, this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(computing)">task</a> can be defined as the TP identification task. We suggest using dialogue information, one attribute of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screenplay">screenplays</a>, motivated by previous work that discovered that TPs have a relation with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue">dialogues</a> appearing in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screenplay">screenplays</a>. To teach a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> this characteristic, we add a dialogue feature to the input embedding. Moreover, in an attempt to improve the model architecture of previous studies, we replace LSTM with Transformer. We observed that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> can better identify TPs in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screenplay">screenplay</a> by using dialogue information and that a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> adopting Transformer outperforms LSTM-based models.</abstract>
      <url hash="75f5ca3f">2021.nuse-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nuse-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>lee-etal-2021-transformer</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/tripod">TRIPOD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Plug-and-Blend : A Framework for Controllable Story Generation with Blended Control Codes</title>
      <author><first>Zhiyu</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Riedl</last></author>
      <pages>62–71</pages>
      <abstract>We describe a Plug-and-Play controllable language generation framework, Plug-and-Blend, that allows a human user to input multiple control codes (topics). In the context of automated story generation, this allows a human user lose or fine grained control of the topics that will appear in the generated story, and can even allow for overlapping, blended topics. We show that our framework, working with different generation models, controls the generation towards given continuous-weighted control codes while keeping the generated sentences fluent, demonstrating strong blending capability.</abstract>
      <url hash="89fbed11">2021.nuse-1.7</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nuse-1.7</doi>
      <bibkey>lin-riedl-2021-plug</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/xxbidiao/plug-and-blend" additional="false">xxbidiao/plug-and-blend</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>