<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.cmcl">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Workshop on Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Emmanuele</first><last>Chersoni</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Cassandra</first><last>Jacobs</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yohei</first><last>Oseki</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Laurent</first><last>Prévot</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Enrico</first><last>Santus</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="0f45807d">2020.cmcl-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>cmcl-2020-cognitive</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Images and Imagination : Automated Analysis of Priming Effects Related to Autism Spectrum Disorder and Developmental Language Disorder</title>
      <author><first>Michaela</first><last>Regneri</last></author>
      <author><first>Diane</first><last>King</last></author>
      <author><first>Fahreen</first><last>Walji</last></author>
      <author><first>Olympia</first><last>Palikara</last></author>
      <pages>11–27</pages>
      <abstract>Different aspects of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_processing_in_the_brain">language processing</a> have been shown to be sensitive to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priming_(psychology)">priming</a> but the findings of studies examining priming effects in adolescents with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) and Developmental Language Disorder (DLD) have been inconclusive. We present a study analysing visual and implicit semantic priming in adolescents with ASD and DLD. Based on a dataset of fictional and script-like narratives, we evaluate how often and how extensively, content of two different priming sources is used by the participants. The first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priming_(psychology)">priming source</a> was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_system">visual</a>, consisting of images shown to the participants to assist them with their storytelling. The second priming source originated from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commonsense_knowledge">commonsense knowledge</a>, using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crowdsourcing">crowdsourced data</a> containing prototypical script elements. Our results show that individuals with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autism_spectrum">ASD</a> are less sensitive to both types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priming_(psychology)">priming</a>, but show typical usage of primed cues when they use them at all. In contrast, children with DLD show mostly average priming sensitivity, but exhibit an over-proportional use of the priming cues.</abstract>
      <url hash="48db37b4">2020.cmcl-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.cmcl-1.2</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939683" />
      <bibkey>regneri-etal-2020-images</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Production-based Cognitive Models as a Test Suite for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</a></title>
      <author><first>Adrian</first><last>Brasoveanu</last></author>
      <author><first>Jakub</first><last>Dotlacil</last></author>
      <pages>28–37</pages>
      <abstract>We introduce a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_framework">framework</a> in which production-rule based computational cognitive modeling and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">Reinforcement Learning</a> can systematically interact and inform each other. We focus on linguistic applications because the sophisticated rule-based cognitive models needed to capture linguistic behavioral data promise to provide a stringent test suite for RL algorithms, connecting RL algorithms to both accuracy and reaction-time experimental data. Thus, we open a path towards assembling an experimentally rigorous and cognitively realistic benchmark for RL algorithms. We extend our previous work on lexical decision tasks and tabular RL algorithms (Brasoveanu and Dotlail, 2020b) with a discussion of neural-network based approaches, and a discussion of how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parsing</a> can be formalized as an RL problem.</abstract>
      <url hash="422514e9">2020.cmcl-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.cmcl-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>brasoveanu-dotlacil-2020-production</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>