<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.socialnlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-06-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Eighth International Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Lun-Wei</first><last>Ku</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Cheng-Te</first><last>Li</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <url hash="57dbb390">2020.socialnlp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="0bba0f3b">2020.socialnlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>socialnlp-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Enhancing Bias Detection in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_journalism">Political News</a> Using Pragmatic Presupposition</title>
      <author><first>Lalitha</first><last>Kameswari</last></author>
      <author><first>Dama</first><last>Sravani</last></author>
      <author><first>Radhika</first><last>Mamidi</last></author>
      <pages>1–6</pages>
      <abstract>Usage of presuppositions in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> and news discourse can be a powerful way to influence the readers as they usually tend to not examine the truth value of the hidden or indirectly expressed information. Fairclough and Wodak (1997) discuss <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presupposition">presupposition</a> at a discourse level where some implicit claims are taken for granted in the explicit meaning of a text or utterance. From the Gricean perspective, the presuppositions of a sentence determine the class of contexts in which the sentence could be felicitously uttered. This paper aims to correlate the type of knowledge presupposed in a news article to the bias present in it. We propose a set of guidelines to identify various kinds of presuppositions in news articles and present a dataset consisting of 1050 articles which are annotated for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a> (positive, negative or neutral) and the magnitude of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presupposition">presupposition</a>. We introduce a supervised classification approach for detecting bias in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_journalism">political news</a> which significantly outperforms the existing systems.</abstract>
      <url hash="a1f1aabf">2020.socialnlp-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.socialnlp-1.1</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929901" />
      <bibkey>kameswari-etal-2020-enhancing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>NARMADA : Need and Available Resource Managing Assistant for Disasters and Adversities<fixed-case>NARMADA</fixed-case>: Need and Available Resource Managing Assistant for Disasters and Adversities</title>
      <author><first>Kaustubh</first><last>Hiware</last></author>
      <author><first>Ritam</first><last>Dutt</last></author>
      <author><first>Sayan</first><last>Sinha</last></author>
      <author><first>Sohan</first><last>Patro</last></author>
      <author><first>Kripa</first><last>Ghosh</last></author>
      <author><first>Saptarshi</first><last>Ghosh</last></author>
      <pages>15–24</pages>
      <abstract>Although a lot of research has been done on utilising <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">Online Social Media</a> during disasters, there exists no system for a specific task that is critical in a post-disaster scenario   identifying resource-needs and resource-availabilities in the disaster-affected region, coupled with their subsequent matching. To this end, we present NARMADA, a semi-automated platform which leverages the crowd-sourced information from social media posts for assisting post-disaster relief coordination efforts. The system employs <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a> and Information Retrieval techniques for identifying resource-needs and resource-availabilities from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microblogging">microblogs</a>, extracting resources from the posts, and also matching the needs to suitable availabilities. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is thus capable of facilitating the judicious management of resources during <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergency_management">post-disaster relief operations</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="c75f139f">2020.socialnlp-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.socialnlp-1.3</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929903" />
      <bibkey>hiware-etal-2020-narmada</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/OSM-DM-KGP/Narmada" additional="false">OSM-DM-KGP/Narmada</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>