<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.sigtyp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Computational Research in Linguistic Typology</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Vylomova</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Edoardo M.</first><last>Ponti</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Eitan</first><last>Grossman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Arya D.</first><last>McCarthy</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yevgeni</first><last>Berzak</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Haim</first><last>Dubossarsky</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ivan</first><last>Vulić</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Roi</first><last>Reichart</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Korhonen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ryan</first><last>Cotterell</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="f8c29d83">2020.sigtyp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sigtyp-2020-research</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>SIGTYP 2020 Shared Task : Prediction of Typological Features<fixed-case>SIGTYP</fixed-case> 2020 Shared Task: Prediction of Typological Features</title>
      <author><first>Johannes</first><last>Bjerva</last></author>
      <author><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Salesky</last></author>
      <author><first>Sabrina J.</first><last>Mielke</last></author>
      <author><first>Aditi</first><last>Chaudhary</last></author>
      <author><first>Giuseppe G. A.</first><last>Celano</last></author>
      <author><first>Edoardo Maria</first><last>Ponti</last></author>
      <author><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Vylomova</last></author>
      <author><first>Ryan</first><last>Cotterell</last></author>
      <author><first>Isabelle</first><last>Augenstein</last></author>
      <pages>1–11</pages>
      <abstract>Typological knowledge bases (KBs) such as WALS (Dryer and Haspelmath, 2013) contain information about linguistic properties of the world’s languages. They have been shown to be useful for downstream applications, including cross-lingual transfer learning and linguistic probing. A major drawback hampering broader adoption of typological KBs is that they are sparsely populated, in the sense that most languages only have annotations for some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a>, and skewed, in that few <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a> have wide coverage. As typological features often correlate with one another, it is possible to predict them and thus automatically populate typological KBs, which is also the focus of this shared task. Overall, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> attracted 8 submissions from 5 teams, out of which the most successful <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> make use of such feature correlations. However, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Error_detection_and_correction">error analysis</a> reveals that even the strongest submitted systems struggle with predicting feature values for languages where few features are known.</abstract>
      <url hash="9c3cd0dd">2020.sigtyp-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sigtyp-1.1</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939790" />
      <bibkey>bjerva-etal-2020-sigtyp</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Predicting Typological Features in WALS using Language Embeddings and Conditional Probabilities : FAL Submission to the SIGTYP 2020 Shared Task<fixed-case>WALS</fixed-case> using Language Embeddings and Conditional Probabilities: <fixed-case>ÚFAL</fixed-case> Submission to the <fixed-case>SIGTYP</fixed-case> 2020 Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Martin</first><last>Vastl</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Zeman</last></author>
      <author><first>Rudolf</first><last>Rosa</last></author>
      <pages>29–35</pages>
      <abstract>We present our submission to the SIGTYP 2020 Shared Task on the prediction of typological features. We submit a constrained system, predicting typological features only based on the WALS database. We investigate two approaches. The simpler of the two is a system based on estimating correlation of feature values within languages by computing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conditional_probability">conditional probabilities</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mutual_information">mutual information</a>. The second approach is to train a neural predictor operating on precomputed language embeddings based on WALS features. Our submitted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> combines the two approaches based on their self-estimated confidence scores. We reach the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of 70.7 % on the test data and rank first in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">shared task</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="d2a6dd06">2020.sigtyp-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sigtyp-1.4</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939792" />
      <bibkey>vastl-etal-2020-predicting</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ufal/ST2020" additional="false">ufal/ST2020</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>NUIG : Multitasking Self-attention based approach to SigTyp 2020 Shared Task<fixed-case>NUIG</fixed-case>: Multitasking Self-attention based approach to <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>ig<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>yp 2020 Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Chinmay</first><last>Choudhary</last></author>
      <pages>43–50</pages>
      <abstract>The paper describes the Multitasking Self-attention based approach to constrained sub-task within Sigtyp 2020 Shared task. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> is simple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network">neural network based architecture</a> inspired by Transformers (CITATION) model. The model uses <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_multitasking">Multitasking</a> to compute values of all WALS features for a given input language simultaneously. Results show that our approach performs at par with the baseline approaches, even though our proposed approach requires only phylogenetic and geographical attributes namely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Longitude">Longitude</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latitude">Latitude</a>, Genus-index, Family-index and Country-index and do not use any of the known WALS features of the respective input language, to compute its missing WALS features.<i>Multitasking Self-attention based approach</i> to constrained sub-task within Sigtyp 2020 Shared task. Our model is simple neural network based architecture inspired by Transformers (CITATION) model. The model uses Multitasking to compute values of all WALS features for a given input language simultaneously.

Results show that our approach performs at par with the baseline approaches, even though our proposed approach requires only phylogenetic and geographical attributes namely <i>Longitude</i>, <i>Latitude</i>, <i>Genus-index</i>, <i>Family-index</i> and <i>Country-index</i> and do not use any of the known WALS features of the respective input language, to compute its missing WALS features.</abstract>
      <url hash="d823ce62">2020.sigtyp-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sigtyp-1.6</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939794" />
      <bibkey>choudhary-2020-nuig</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>