<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nlpmc">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-06-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Medical Conversations</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Parminder</first><last>Bhatia</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Steven</first><last>Lin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Rashmi</first><last>Gangadharaiah</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Byron</first><last>Wallace</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Izhak</first><last>Shafran</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Chaitanya</first><last>Shivade</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nan</first><last>Du</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mona</first><last>Diab</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <url hash="915e7714">2020.nlpmc-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="6f84e28c">2020.nlpmc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlpmc-2020-natural</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Methods for Extracting Information from Messages from Primary Care Providers to Specialists</title>
      <author><first>Xiyu</first><last>Ding</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Barnett</last></author>
      <author><first>Ateev</first><last>Mehrotra</last></author>
      <author><first>Timothy</first><last>Miller</last></author>
      <pages>1–6</pages>
      <abstract>Electronic consult (eConsult) systems allow specialists more flexibility to respond to referrals more efficiently, thereby increasing access in under-resourced healthcare settings like safety net systems. Understanding the usage patterns of eConsult system is an important part of improving specialist efficiency. In this work, we develop and apply classifiers to a dataset of eConsult questions from primary care providers to specialists, classifying the messages for how they were triaged by the specialist office, and the underlying type of clinical question posed by the primary care provider. We show that pre-trained transformer models are strong baselines, with improving performance from domain-specific training and shared representations.</abstract>
      <url hash="187aa064">2020.nlpmc-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpmc-1.1</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929890" />
      <bibkey>ding-etal-2020-methods</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Towards Understanding ASR Error Correction for Medical Conversations<fixed-case>ASR</fixed-case> Error Correction for Medical Conversations</title>
      <author><first>Anirudh</first><last>Mani</last></author>
      <author><first>Shruti</first><last>Palaskar</last></author>
      <author><first>Sandeep</first><last>Konam</last></author>
      <pages>7–11</pages>
      <abstract>Domain Adaptation for Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) error correction via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a> is a useful technique for improving out-of-domain outputs of pre-trained ASR systems to obtain optimal results for specific in-domain tasks. We use this technique on our dataset of Doctor-Patient conversations using two off-the-shelf ASR systems : Google ASR (commercial) and the ASPIRE model (open-source). We train a Sequence-to-Sequence Machine Translation model and evaluate it on seven specific UMLS Semantic types, including Pharmacological Substance, Sign or Symptom, and Diagnostic Procedure to name a few. Lastly, we breakdown, analyze and discuss the 7 % overall improvement in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_error_rate">word error rate</a> in view of each Semantic type.</abstract>
      <url hash="276bfafc">2020.nlpmc-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpmc-1.2</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929893" />
      <bibkey>mani-etal-2020-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>On the Utility of Audiovisual Dialog Technologies and Signal Analytics for Real-time Remote Monitoring of Depression Biomarkers</title>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Neumann</last></author>
      <author><first>Oliver</first><last>Roessler</last></author>
      <author><first>David</first><last>Suendermann-Oeft</last></author>
      <author><first>Vikram</first><last>Ramanarayanan</last></author>
      <pages>47–52</pages>
      <abstract>We investigate the utility of audiovisual dialog systems combined with speech and video analytics for real-time remote monitoring of depression at scale in uncontrolled environment settings. We collected audiovisual conversational data from participants who interacted with a cloud-based multimodal dialog system, and automatically extracted a large set of speech and vision metrics based on the rich existing literature of laboratory studies. We report on the efficacy of various audio and video metrics in differentiating people with mild, moderate and severe depression, and discuss the implications of these results for the deployment of such technologies in real-world neurological diagnosis and monitoring applications.</abstract>
      <url hash="6486a7ab">2020.nlpmc-1.7</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpmc-1.7</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929892" />
      <bibkey>neumann-etal-2020-utility</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>