<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.wildre">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the WILDRE5– 5th Workshop on Indian Language Data: Resources and Evaluation</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Girish Nath</first><last>Jha</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kalika</first><last>Bali</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sobha</first><last>L.</last></editor>
      <editor><first>S. S.</first><last>Agrawal</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Atul Kr.</first><last>Ojha</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-67-2</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ce03e7a8">2020.wildre-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>wildre-2020-wildre5</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Handling Noun-Noun Coreference in Tamil<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>amil</title>
      <author><first>Vijay</first><last>Sundar Ram</last></author>
      <author><first>Sobha</first><last>Lalitha Devi</last></author>
      <pages>20–24</pages>
      <abstract>Natural language understanding by automatic tools is the vital requirement for document processing tools. To achieve it, automatic system has to understand the coherence in the text. Co-reference chains bring coherence to the text. The commonly occurring reference markers which bring cohesiveness are Pronominal, Reflexives, Reciprocals, Distributives, One-anaphors, Nounnoun reference. Here in this paper, we deal with noun-noun reference in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>. We present the methodology to resolve these noun-noun anaphors and also present the challenges in handling the noun-noun anaphoric relations in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="91362146">2020.wildre-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>sundar-ram-lalitha-devi-2020-handling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Determination of Idiomatic Sentences in Paragraphs Using Statement Classification and Generalization of Grammar Rules</title>
      <author><first>Naziya</first><last>Shaikh</last></author>
      <pages>45–50</pages>
      <abstract>The translation systems are often not able to determine the presence of an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idiom_(language_structure)">idiom</a> in a given paragraph. Due to this many systems tend to return the word-for-word translation of such statements leading to loss in the flavor of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idiom_(language_structure)">idioms</a> in the paragraph. This paper suggests a novel approach to efficiently determine probability of any statement in a given English paragraph to be an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idiom">idiom</a>. This approach combines the rule-based generalization of idioms in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English language</a> and classification of statements based on the context to determine the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idiom_(language_structure)">idioms</a> in the sentence. The context based classification method can be used further for determination of idioms in regional Indian languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marathi_language">Marathi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Konkani_language">Konkani</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a> as the difference in the semantic context of the proverb as compared to the context in a paragraph is also evident in these other languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="fa36bd95">2020.wildre-1.9</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>shaikh-2020-determination</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>A Deeper Study on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(computer_vision)">Features</a> for Named Entity Recognition</title>
      <author><first>Malarkodi</first><last>C S</last></author>
      <author><first>Sobha</first><last>Lalitha Devi</last></author>
      <pages>66–72</pages>
      <abstract>This paper deals with the various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a> used for the identification of named entities. The performance of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning system</a> heavily depends on the feature selection criteria. The intention to trace the essential features required for the development of named entity system across languages motivated us to conduct this study. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">linguistic analysis</a> was done to find out the part of speech patterns surrounding the context of named entities and from the observation linguistic oriented features are identified for both Indian and European languages. The Indian languages belongs to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian language family</a> such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indo-Aryan_languages">Indo-Aryan language family</a> such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Punjabi_language">Punjabi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bengali_language">Bengali</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marathi_language">Marathi</a>, European languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_language">Spanish</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_language">Dutch</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hungarian_language">Hungarian</a> are used in this work. The machine learning technique CRFs was used for the system development. The experiments were conducted using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">linguistic features</a> and the results obtained for each languages are comparable with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_of_the_art">state-of-art systems</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="601c2e27">2020.wildre-1.12</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>c-s-lalitha-devi-2020-deeper</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>