<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.rail">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the first workshop on Resources for African Indigenous Languages</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Rooweither</first><last>Mabuya</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Phathutshedzo</first><last>Ramukhadi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mmasibidi</first><last>Setaka</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Valencia</first><last>Wagner</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Menno</first><last>van Zaanen</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-60-3</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="22832a2e">2020.rail-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>rail-2020-resources</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Endangered African Languages Featured in a Digital Collection : The Case of the Khomani San, Hugh Brody Collection<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>frican Languages Featured in a Digital Collection: The Case of the ǂ<fixed-case>K</fixed-case>homani <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>an, <fixed-case>H</fixed-case>ugh <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>rody <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ollection</title>
      <author><first>Kerry</first><last>Jones</last></author>
      <author><first>Sanjin</first><last>Muftic</last></author>
      <pages>1–8</pages>
      <abstract>The Khomani San, Hugh Brody Collection features the voices and history of indigenous hunter gatherer descendants in three endangered languages namely, N|uu, Kora and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Khoekhoe_language">Khoekhoe</a> as well as a regional dialect of Afrikaans. A large component of this collection is audio-visual (legacy media) recordings of interviews conducted with members of the community by Hugh Brody and his colleagues between 1997 and 2012, referring as far back as the 1800s. The Digital Library Services team at the University of Cape Town aim to showcase the collection digitally on the UCT-wide Digital Collections platform, Ibali which runs on Omeka-S. In this paper we highlight the importance of such a collection in the context of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Africa">South Africa</a>, and the ethical steps that were taken to ensure the respect of the Khomani San as their stories get uploaded onto a repository and become accessible to all. We will also feature some of the completed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collection_(publishing)">collection</a> on Ibali and guide the reader through the organisation of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collection_(publishing)">collection</a> on the Omeka-S backend. Finally, we will outline our development process, from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digitization">digitisation</a> to repository publishing as well as present some of the challenges in data clean-up, the curation of legacy media, multi-lingual support, and site organisation.</abstract>
      <url hash="ae8363d0">2020.rail-1.1</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>jones-muftic-2020-endangered</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Complex Setswana Parts of Speech Tagging</title>
      <author><first>Gabofetswe</first><last>Malema</last></author>
      <author><first>Boago</first><last>Okgetheng</last></author>
      <author><first>Bopaki</first><last>Tebalo</last></author>
      <author><first>Moffat</first><last>Motlhanka</last></author>
      <author><first>Goaletsa</first><last>Rammidi</last></author>
      <pages>21–24</pages>
      <abstract>Setswana language is one of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bantu_languages">Bantu languages</a> written disjunctively. Some of its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Part_of_speech">parts of speech</a> such as qualificatives and some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adverb">adverbs</a> are made up of multiple words. That is, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Part_of_speech">part of speech</a> is made up of a group of words. The disjunctive style of writing poses a challenge when a sentence is tokenized or when <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tag_(metadata)">tagging</a>. A few studies have been done on identification of multi-word parts of speech. In this study we go further to tokenize complex parts of speech which are formed by extending basic forms of multi-word parts of speech. The parts of speech are extended by recursively concatenating more parts of speech to a basic form of parts of speech. We developed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_prescription">rules</a> for building complex relative parts of speech. A morphological analyzer and Python NLTK are used to tag individual words and basic forms of multi-word parts of speech. Developed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rule_of_inference">rules</a> are then used to identify complex parts of speech. Results from a 300 sentence text files give a performance of 74 %. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tagger">tagger</a> fails when it encounters expansion rules not implemented and when <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tag_(metadata)">tagging</a> by the morphological analyzer is incorrect.</abstract>
      <url hash="f3682e0a">2020.rail-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <revision id="1" href="2020.rail-1.4v1" hash="805ae97f" />
      <revision id="2" href="2020.rail-1.4v2" hash="f3682e0a" date="2020-07-08">Correction in references section</revision>
      <bibkey>malema-etal-2020-complex</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Comparing Neural Network Parsers for a Less-resourced and Morphologically-rich Language : Amharic Dependency Parser<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>mharic Dependency Parser</title>
      <author><first>Binyam Ephrem</first><last>Seyoum</last></author>
      <author><first>Yusuke</first><last>Miyao</last></author>
      <author><first>Baye Yimam</first><last>Mekonnen</last></author>
      <pages>25–30</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we compare four state-of-the-art neural network dependency parsers for the Semitic language Amharic. As <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amharic">Amharic</a> is a morphologically-rich and less-resourced language, the out-of-vocabulary (OOV) problem will be higher when we develop data-driven models. This fact limits researchers to develop <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network">neural network parsers</a> because the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network">neural network</a> requires large quantities of data to train a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a>. We empirically evaluate neural network parsers when a small Amharic treebank is used for training. Based on our experiment, we obtain an 83.79 LAS score using the UDPipe system. Better <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> is achieved when the neural parsing system uses external resources like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embedding</a>. Using such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_(computer_science)">resources</a>, the LAS score for UDPipe improves to 85.26. Our experiment shows that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network">neural networks</a> can learn dependency relations better from limited data while segmentation and POS tagging require much data.</abstract>
      <url hash="2b143545">2020.rail-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>seyoum-etal-2020-comparing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Mobilizing Metadata : Open Data Kit (ODK) for Language Resource Development in East Africa<fixed-case>ODK</fixed-case>) for Language Resource Development in <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>ast <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>frica</title>
      <author><first>Richard</first><last>Griscom</last></author>
      <pages>31–35</pages>
      <abstract>Linguistic fieldworkers collect and archive metadata as part of the language resources (LRs) that they create, but they often work in resource-constrained environments that prevent them from using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer">computers</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_entry_clerk">data entry</a>. In such situations, linguists must complete time-consuming and error-prone digitization tasks that limit the quantity and quality of the resources and metadata that they produce (Thieberger &amp; Berez 2012 ; Margetts &amp; Margetts 2012). This paper describes a method for entering <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata">linguistic metadata</a> into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_device">mobile devices</a> using the Open Data Kit (ODK) platform, a suite of open source tools designed for mobile data collection.</abstract>
      <url hash="b7e900fa">2020.rail-1.6</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>griscom-2020-mobilizing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>A Computational Grammar of Ga<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>a</title>
      <author><first>Lars</first><last>Hellan</last></author>
      <pages>36–44</pages>
      <abstract>The paper describes aspects of an HPSG style computational grammar of the West African language Ga (a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kwa_languages">Kwa language</a> spoken in the Accra area of Ghana). As a Volta Basin Kwa language, Ga features many types of multiverb expressions and other particular constructional patterns in the verbal and nominal domain. The paper highlights theoretical and formal features of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammar">grammar</a> motivated by these phenomena, some of them possibly innovative to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_grammar">formal framework</a>. As a so-called deep grammar of the language, it hosts a rich lexical structure, and we describe ways in which the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammar">grammar</a> builds on previously available lexical resources. We outline an environment of current resources in which the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammar">grammar</a> is part, and lines of research and development in which it and its environment can be used.</abstract>
      <url hash="06389910">2020.rail-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>hellan-2020-computational</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>