<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.udw">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on Universal Dependencies (UDW 2020)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Marie-Catherine</first><last>de Marneffe</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Miryam</first><last>de Lhoneux</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Joakim</first><last>Nivre</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sebastian</first><last>Schuster</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="6d1f74e6">2020.udw-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>udw-2020-universal</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Verification, Reproduction and Replication of NLP Experiments : a Case Study on Parsing Universal Dependencies<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Experiments: a Case Study on Parsing <fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependencies</title>
      <author><first>Çağrı</first><last>Çöltekin</last></author>
      <pages>46–56</pages>
      <abstract>As in any field of inquiry that depends on experiments, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verifiability">verifiability</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Experiment">experimental studies</a> is important in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">computational linguistics</a>. Despite increased attention to verification of empirical results, the practices in the field are unclear. Furthermore, we argue, certain traditions and practices that are seemingly useful for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verificationism">verification</a> may in fact be counterproductive. We demonstrate this through a set of multi-lingual experiments on parsing Universal Dependencies treebanks. In particular, we show that emphasis on exact replication leads to practices (some of which are now well established) that hide the variation in experimental results, effectively hindering verifiability with a false sense of certainty. The purpose of the present paper is to highlight the magnitude of the issues resulting from these common practices with the hope of instigating further discussion. Once we, as a community, are convinced about the importance of the problems, the solutions are rather obvious, although not necessarily easy to implement.</abstract>
      <url hash="60b6e037">2020.udw-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>coltekin-2020-verification</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Land_mine">LFG</a> To <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urban_exploration">UD</a> : A Combined Approach<fixed-case>LFG</fixed-case> To <fixed-case>UD</fixed-case>: A Combined Approach</title>
      <author><first>Cheikh M. Bamba</first><last>Dione</last></author>
      <pages>57–66</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports on a systematic approach for deriving Universal Dependencies from LFG structures. The conversion starts with a step-wise transformation of the c-structure, combining part-of-speech (POS) information and the embedding path to determine the true head of dependency structures. The paper discusses several issues faced by existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithms</a> when applied on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolof_language">Wolof</a> and presents the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy">strategies</a> used to account for these issues. An experimental evaluation indicated that our approach was able to generate the correct output in more than 90 % of the cases, leading to a substantial improvement in conversion accuracy compared to the previous models.</abstract>
      <url hash="84d19d0f">2020.udw-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>dione-2020-lfg</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Configurable Dependency Tree Extraction from CCG Derivations<fixed-case>CCG</fixed-case> Derivations</title>
      <author><first>Kilian</first><last>Evang</last></author>
      <pages>87–93</pages>
      <abstract>We revisit the problem of extracting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependency_grammar">dependency structures</a> from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependency_grammar">derivation structures</a> of Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG). Previous approaches are often restricted to a narrow subset of CCG or support only one flavor of dependency tree. Our approach is more general and easily configurable, so that multiple styles of dependency tree can be obtained. In an initial case study, we show promising results for converting English, German, Italian, and Dutch CCG derivations from the Parallel Meaning Bank into (unlabeled) UD-style dependency trees.</abstract>
      <url hash="952e71bd">2020.udw-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>evang-2020-configurable</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>First Steps towards Universal Dependencies for Laz<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependencies for <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>az</title>
      <author><first>Utku</first><last>Türk</last></author>
      <author><first>Kaan</first><last>Bayar</last></author>
      <author><first>Ayşegül Dilara</first><last>Özercan</last></author>
      <author><first>Görkem Yiğit</first><last>Öztürk</last></author>
      <author><first>Şaziye Betül</first><last>Özateş</last></author>
      <pages>189–194</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laz_language">Laz language</a>, which is also the first Universal Dependencies Treebank for a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_the_Caucasus">South Caucasian language</a>. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> aims to create a syntactically and morphologically annotated resource for further research. We also aim to document an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">endangered language</a> in a systematic fashion within an inherently cross-linguistic framework : the Universal Dependencies Project (UD). As of now, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> consists of 576 sentences and 2,306 tokens annotated in light with the UD guidelines. We evaluated the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> on the dependency parsing task using a pretrained multilingual parsing model, and the results are comparable with other low-resourced treebanks with no <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training set</a>. We aim to expand our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> in the near future to include 1,500 sentences. The bigger goal for our project is to create a set of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebanks</a> for minority languages in Anatolia.</abstract>
      <url hash="f2b6354f">2020.udw-1.21</url>
      <bibkey>turk-etal-2020-first</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Dependency annotation of noun incorporation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polysynthetic_language">polysynthetic languages</a></title>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Tyers</last></author>
      <author><first>Karina</first><last>Mishchenkova</last></author>
      <pages>195–204</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes an approach to annotating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incorporation_(linguistics)">noun incorporation</a> in Universal Dependencies. It motivates the need to annotate this particular morphosyntactic phenomenon and justifies it with respect to frequency of the construction. A case study is presented in which the proposed annotation scheme is applied to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chukchi_language">Chukchi</a>, a language that exhibits <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incorporation_(linguistics)">noun incorporation</a>. We compare argument encoding in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chukchi_language">Chukchi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_language">Russian</a> and find that while in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and Russian discourse elements are primarily tracked through noun phrases and pronouns, in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chukchi_language">Chukchi</a> they are tracked through agreement marking and incorporation, with a lesser role for noun phrases.</abstract>
      <url hash="7494e366">2020.udw-1.22</url>
      <revision id="1" href="2020.udw-1.22v1" hash="8261a1c9" />
      <revision id="2" href="2020.udw-1.22v2" hash="7494e366" date="2020-12-11">Corrected author affiliations</revision>
      <bibkey>tyers-mishchenkova-2020-dependency</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>Universal Dependency Treebank for Xibe<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependency Treebank for <fixed-case>X</fixed-case>ibe</title>
      <author><first>He</first><last>Zhou</last></author>
      <author><first>Juyeon</first><last>Chung</last></author>
      <author><first>Sandra</first><last>Kübler</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Tyers</last></author>
      <pages>205–215</pages>
      <abstract>We present our work of constructing the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xibe">Xibe language</a> following the Universal Dependencies (UD) annotation scheme. Xibe is a low-resourced and severely endangered Tungusic language spoken by the Xibe minority living in the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region of China. We collected 810 sentences so far, including 544 sentences from a grammar book on written Xibe and 266 sentences from Cabcal News. We annotated those sentences manually from scratch. In this paper, we report the procedure of building this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> and analyze several important annotation issues of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a>. Finally, we propose our plans for future work.</abstract>
      <url hash="a358086c">2020.udw-1.23</url>
      <bibkey>zhou-etal-2020-universal</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>