<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.isa">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>16th Joint ACL - ISO Workshop on Interoperable Semantic Annotation PROCEEDINGS</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Harry</first><last>Bunt</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-48-1</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="06144088">2020.isa-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>isa-2020-joint</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Annotation-based Semantics</title>
      <author><first>Kiyong</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <pages>36–48</pages>
      <abstract>This paper proposes a semantics ABS for the model-theoretic interpretation of annotation structures. It provides a language ABSr, that represents semantic forms in a (possibly -free) type-theoretic first-order logic. For semantic compositionality, the representation language introduces two operators   and   with subtypes for the conjunctive or distributive composition of semantic forms. ABS also introduces a small set of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Predicate_(mathematical_logic)">logical predicates</a> to represent semantic forms in a simplified format. The use of ABSr is illustrated with some annotation structures that conform to ISO 24617 standards on semantic annotation such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISO-TimeML">ISO-TimeML</a> and ISO-Space.<i>semantic forms</i> in a (possibly <tex-math>\lambda</tex-math>-free) type-theoretic first-order logic. For semantic compositionality, the representation language introduces two operators <tex-math>\oplus</tex-math> and <tex-math>\oslash</tex-math> with subtypes for the conjunctive or distributive composition of semantic forms. ABS also introduces a small set of logical predicates to represent semantic forms in a simplified format. The use of ABSr is illustrated with some annotation structures that conform to ISO 24617 standards on semantic annotation such as ISO-TimeML and ISO-Space.</abstract>
      <url hash="6488ef9e">2020.isa-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>lee-2020-annotation</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>