<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.stoc">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings for the First International Workshop on Social Threats in Online Conversations: Understanding and Management</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Archna</first><last>Bhatia</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Samira</first><last>Shaikh</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-39-9</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="eafb0485">2020.stoc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>stoc-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>A Privacy Preserving Data Publishing Middleware for Unstructured, Textual Social Media Data</title>
      <author><first>Prasadi</first><last>Abeywardana</last></author>
      <author><first>Uthayasanker</first><last>Thayasivam</last></author>
      <pages>21–28</pages>
      <abstract>Privacy is going to be an integral part of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_science">data science and analytics</a> in the coming years. The next hype of data experimentation is going to be heavily dependent on privacy preserving techniques mainly as it’s going to be a legal responsibility rather than a mere social responsibility. Privacy preservation becomes more challenging specially in the context of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unstructured_data">unstructured data</a>. Social networks have become predominantly popular over the past couple of decades and they are creating a huge data lake at a high velocity. Social media profiles contain a wealth of personal and sensitive information, creating enormous opportunities for third parties to analyze them with different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithms</a>, draw conclusions and use in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disinformation">disinformation campaigns</a> and micro targeting based dark advertising. This study provides a mitigation mechanism for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disinformation">disinformation campaigns</a> that are done based on the insights extracted from personal / sensitive data analysis. Specifically, this research is aimed at building a privacy preserving data publishing middleware for unstructured social media data without compromising the true analytical value of those <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a>. A novel way is proposed to apply traditional structured privacy preserving techniques on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unstructured_data">unstructured data</a>. Creating a comprehensive twitter corpus annotated with privacy attributes is another objective of this research, especially because the research community is lacking one.</abstract>
      <url hash="8082d154">2020.stoc-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>abeywardana-thayasivam-2020-privacy</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Information Space Dashboard</title>
      <author><first>Theresa</first><last>Krumbiegel</last></author>
      <author><first>Albert</first><last>Pritzkau</last></author>
      <author><first>Hans-Christian</first><last>Schmitz</last></author>
      <pages>29–34</pages>
      <abstract>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_space">information space</a>, where information is generated, stored, exchanged and discussed, is not idyllic but a space where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disinformation">campaigns of disinformation</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Destabilization">destabilization</a> are conducted. Such campaigns are subsumed under the terms <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hybrid_warfare">hybrid warfare</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_warfare">information warfare</a> (Woolley and Howard, 2017). In order to enable awareness of them, we propose an information state dashboard comprising various components / apps for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_collection">data collection</a>, analysis and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_visualization">visualization</a>. The aim of the dashboard is to support an analyst in generating a common operational picture of the information space, link it with an operational picture of the physical space and, thus, contribute to overarching situational awareness. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dashboard">dashboard</a> is work in progress. However, a first prototype with components for exploiting elementary language statistics, keyword and metadata analysis, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_classification">text classification</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_theory">network analysis</a> has been implemented. Further components, in particular, for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Event_(computing)">event extraction</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> are under development. As a demonstration case, we briefly discuss the analysis of historical data regarding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_Chemnitz_protests">violent anti-migrant protests</a> and respective <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Counter-protest">counter-protests</a> that took place in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chemnitz">Chemnitz</a> in 2018.</abstract>
      <url hash="42387451">2020.stoc-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>krumbiegel-etal-2020-information</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>