<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.wac">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 12th Web as Corpus Workshop</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Adrien</first><last>Barbaresi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Felix</first><last>Bildhauer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Roland</first><last>Schäfer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Egon</first><last>Stemle</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-68-9</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="62332e65">2020.wac-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>wac-2020-web</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Current Challenges in Web Corpus Building</title>
      <author><first>Miloš</first><last>Jakubíček</last></author>
      <author><first>Vojtěch</first><last>Kovář</last></author>
      <author><first>Pavel</first><last>Rychlý</last></author>
      <author><first>Vit</first><last>Suchomel</last></author>
      <pages>1–4</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we discuss some of the current challenges in web corpus building that we faced in the recent years when expanding the corpora in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sketch_Engine">Sketch Engine</a>. The purpose of the paper is to provide an overview and raise discussion on possible solutions, rather than bringing ready solutions to the readers. For every issue we try to assess its severity and briefly discuss possible mitigation options.</abstract>
      <url hash="41af0837">2020.wac-1.1</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>jakubicek-etal-2020-current</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>The ELTE.DH Pilot Corpus   Creating a Handcrafted Gigaword Web Corpus with Metadata<fixed-case>ELTE</fixed-case>.<fixed-case>DH</fixed-case> Pilot Corpus – Creating a Handcrafted <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>igaword Web Corpus with Metadata</title>
      <author><first>Balázs</first><last>Indig</last></author>
      <author><first>Árpád</first><last>Knap</last></author>
      <author><first>Zsófia</first><last>Sárközi-Lindner</last></author>
      <author><first>Mária</first><last>Timári</last></author>
      <author><first>Gábor</first><last>Palkó</last></author>
      <pages>33–41</pages>
      <abstract>In this article, we present the method we used to create a middle-sized corpus using targeted web crawling. Our corpus contains news portal articles along with their metadata, that can be useful for diverse audiences, ranging from digital humanists to NLP users. The method presented in this paper applies rule-based components that allow the curation of the text and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata">metadata content</a>. The curated data can thereon serve as a reference for various tasks and measurements. We designed our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Workflow">workflow</a> to encourage modification and customisation. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concept</a> can also be applied to other genres of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portal_(architecture)">portals</a> by using the discovered <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattern">patterns</a> in the architecture of the portals. We found that for a systematic creation or extension of a similar corpus, our method provides superior <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> and ease of use compared to The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wayback_Machine">Wayback Machine</a>, while requiring minimal manpower and computational resources. Reproducing the corpus is possible if changes are introduced to the text-extraction process. The standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_Encoding_Initiative">TEI format</a> and Schema.org encoded metadata is used for the output format, but we stress that placing the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> in a digital repository system is recommended in order to be able to define semantic relations between the segments and to add rich annotation.</abstract>
      <url hash="1ac0dd2e">2020.wac-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>indig-etal-2020-elte</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>