<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.nlp4if">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on NLP for Internet Freedom: Censorship, Disinformation, and Propaganda</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Feldman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Giovanni</first><last>Da San Martino</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Chris</first><last>Leberknight</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Preslav</first><last>Nakov</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.nlp4if-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="604d9ccc">2021.nlp4if-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp4if-2021-nlp</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Identifying Automatically Generated Headlines using Transformers</title>
      <author><first>Antonis</first><last>Maronikolakis</last></author>
      <author><first>Hinrich</first><last>Schütze</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Stevenson</last></author>
      <pages>1–6</pages>
      <abstract>False information spread via the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet">internet</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> influences public opinion and user activity, while <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_model">generative models</a> enable fake content to be generated faster and more cheaply than had previously been possible. In the not so distant future, identifying fake content generated by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning models</a> will play a key role in protecting users from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misinformation">misinformation</a>. To this end, a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> containing human and computer-generated headlines was created and a user study indicated that humans were only able to identify the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake headlines</a> in 47.8 % of the cases. However, the most accurate automatic approach, transformers, achieved an overall accuracy of 85.7 %, indicating that content generated from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> can be filtered out accurately.</abstract>
      <url hash="76895ad7">2021.nlp4if-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4if-1.1</doi>
      <bibkey>maronikolakis-etal-2021-identifying</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Improving Cross-Domain Hate Speech Detection by Reducing the False Positive Rate</title>
      <author><first>Ilia</first><last>Markov</last></author>
      <author><first>Walter</first><last>Daelemans</last></author>
      <pages>17–22</pages>
      <abstract>Hate speech detection is an actively growing field of research with a variety of recently proposed approaches that allowed to push the state-of-the-art results. One of the challenges of such automated approaches   namely recent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning models</a>   is a risk of false positives (i.e., false accusations), which may lead to over-blocking or removal of harmless social media content in applications with little moderator intervention. We evaluate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning models</a> both under in-domain and cross-domain hate speech detection conditions, and introduce an SVM approach that allows to significantly improve the state-of-the-art results when combined with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning models</a> through a simple majority-voting ensemble. The improvement is mainly due to a reduction of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/False_positives_and_false_negatives">false positive rate</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="b454930c">2021.nlp4if-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4if-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>markov-daelemans-2021-improving</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hate-speech">Hate Speech</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/olid">OLID</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Leveraging Community and Author Context to Explain the Performance and Bias of Text-Based Deception Detection Models</title>
      <author><first>Galen</first><last>Weld</last></author>
      <author><first>Ellyn</first><last>Ayton</last></author>
      <author><first>Tim</first><last>Althoff</last></author>
      <author><first>Maria</first><last>Glenski</last></author>
      <pages>29–38</pages>
      <abstract>Deceptive news posts shared in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_community">online communities</a> can be detected with NLP models, and much recent research has focused on the development of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a>. In this work, we use characteristics of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_community">online communities</a> and authors   the context of how and where content is posted   to explain the performance of a neural network deception detection model and identify sub-populations who are disproportionately affected by model accuracy or failure. We examine who is posting the content, and where the content is posted to. We find that while author characteristics are better predictors of deceptive content than community characteristics, both characteristics are strongly correlated with model performance. Traditional performance metrics such as F1 score may fail to capture poor model performance on isolated sub-populations such as specific authors, and as such, more nuanced evaluation of deception detection models is critical.</abstract>
      <url hash="688ba3ac">2021.nlp4if-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4if-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>weld-etal-2021-leveraging</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>DamascusTeam at NLP4IF2021 : Fighting the Arabic COVID-19 Infodemic on Twitter Using AraBERT<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>amascus<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>eam at <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>IF</fixed-case>2021: Fighting the <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic <fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 Infodemic on <fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter Using <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>ra<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Ahmad</first><last>Hussein</last></author>
      <author><first>Nada</first><last>Ghneim</last></author>
      <author><first>Ammar</first><last>Joukhadar</last></author>
      <pages>93–98</pages>
      <abstract>The objective of this work was the introduction of an effective approach based on the AraBERT language model for fighting Tweets COVID-19 Infodemic. It was arranged in the form of a two-step pipeline, where the first step involved a series of pre-processing procedures to transform Twitter jargon, including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emojis</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoticon">emoticons</a>, into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plain_text">plain text</a>, and the second step exploited a version of AraBERT, which was pre-trained on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plain_text">plain text</a>, to fine-tune and classify the tweets with respect to their Label. The use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> pre-trained on plain texts rather than on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">tweets</a> was motivated by the necessity to address two critical issues shown by the scientific literature, namely (1) pre-trained language models are widely available in many languages, avoiding the time-consuming and resource-intensive model training directly on tweets from scratch, allowing to focus only on their fine-tuning ; (2) available plain text corpora are larger than tweet-only ones, allowing for better performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="3246b805">2021.nlp4if-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4if-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>hussein-etal-2021-damascusteam</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>NARNIA at NLP4IF-2021 : Identification of Misinformation in COVID-19 Tweets Using BERTweet<fixed-case>NARNIA</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>IF</fixed-case>-2021: Identification of Misinformation in <fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 Tweets Using <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>weet</title>
      <author><first>Ankit</first><last>Kumar</last></author>
      <author><first>Naman</first><last>Jhunjhunwala</last></author>
      <author><first>Raksha</first><last>Agarwal</last></author>
      <author><first>Niladri</first><last>Chatterjee</last></author>
      <pages>99–103</pages>
      <abstract>The spread of COVID-19 has been accompanied with widespread <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misinformation">misinformation</a> on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. In particular, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitterverse">Twitterverse</a> has seen a huge increase in dissemination of distorted facts and figures. The present work aims at identifying tweets regarding COVID-19 which contains harmful and false information. We have experimented with a number of Deep Learning-based models, including different word embeddings, such as Glove, ELMo, among others. BERTweet model achieved the best overall F1-score of 0.881 and secured the third rank on the above task.</abstract>
      <url hash="e434f5cf">2021.nlp4if-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4if-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>kumar-etal-2021-narnia</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>iCompass at NLP4IF-2021Fighting the COVID-19 Infodemic<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ompass at <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>IF</fixed-case>-2021–Fighting the <fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 Infodemic</title>
      <author><first>Wassim</first><last>Henia</last></author>
      <author><first>Oumayma</first><last>Rjab</last></author>
      <author><first>Hatem</first><last>Haddad</last></author>
      <author><first>Chayma</first><last>Fourati</last></author>
      <pages>115–118</pages>
      <abstract>This paper provides a detailed overview of the system and its outcomes, which were produced as part of the NLP4IF Shared Task on Fighting the COVID-19 Infodemic at NAACL 2021. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> is accomplished using a variety of techniques. We used state-of-the-art contextualized text representation models that were fine-tuned for the downstream task in hand. ARBERT, MARBERT, AraBERT, Arabic ALBERT and BERT-base-arabic were used. According to the results, BERT-base-arabic had the highest 0.784 F1 score on the test set.</abstract>
      <url hash="a774c93d">2021.nlp4if-1.17</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4if-1.17</doi>
      <bibkey>henia-etal-2021-icompass</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>