<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.dialdoc">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on Document-grounded Dialogue and Conversational Question Answering (DialDoc 2021)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Song</first><last>Feng</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Siva</first><last>Reddy</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Malihe</first><last>Alikhani</last></editor>
      <editor><first>He</first><last>He</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yangfeng</first><last>Ji</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mohit</first><last>Iyyer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Zhou</first><last>Yu</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="3e48dd78">2021.dialdoc-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="2ec0943c">2021.dialdoc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>dialdoc-2021-document</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Automatic Learning Assistant in Telugu<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>elugu</title>
      <author><first>Meghana</first><last>Bommadi</last></author>
      <author><first>Shreya</first><last>Terupally</last></author>
      <author><first>Radhika</first><last>Mamidi</last></author>
      <pages>29–37</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents a learning assistant that tests one’s knowledge and gives feedback that helps a person learn at a faster pace. A learning assistant (based on automated question generation) has extensive uses in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Education">education</a>, information websites, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-assessment">self-assessment</a>, FAQs, testing ML agents, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Research">research</a>, etc. Multiple researchers, and companies have worked on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_Assistance">Virtual Assistance</a>, but majorly in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>. We built our learning assistant for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu language</a> to help with teaching in the mother tongue, which is the most efficient way of learning. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is built primarily based on Question Generation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>. Many experiments were conducted on Question Generation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> in multiple ways. We have built the first hybrid machine learning and rule-based solution in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>, which proves efficient for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Short_story">short stories</a> or short passages in children’s books. Our work covers the fundamental question forms with question types : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adjective">adjective</a>, yes / no, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adverb">adverb</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verb">verb</a>, when, where, whose, quotative, and quantitative (how many / how much). We constructed rules for question generation using Part of Speech (POS) tags and Universal Dependency (UD) tags along with linguistic information of the surrounding relevant context of the word. We used keyword matching, multilingual sentence embedding to evaluate the answer. Our system is primarily built on question generation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>, and is also capable of evaluating the user’s answers to the generated questions.</abstract>
      <url hash="bd4bbb41">2021.dialdoc-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.dialdoc-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>bommadi-etal-2021-automatic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Combining Open Domain Question Answering with a Task-Oriented Dialog System</title>
      <author><first>Jan</first><last>Nehring</last></author>
      <author><first>Nils</first><last>Feldhus</last></author>
      <author><first>Harleen</first><last>Kaur</last></author>
      <author><first>Akhyar</first><last>Ahmed</last></author>
      <pages>38–45</pages>
      <abstract>We apply the modular dialog system framework to combine open-domain question answering with a task-oriented dialog system. This meta dialog system can answer questions from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia">Wikipedia</a> and at the same time act as a personal assistant. The aim of this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is to combine the strength of an open-domain question answering system with the conversational power of task-oriented dialog systems. After explaining the technical details of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>, we combined a new dataset out of standard datasets to evaluate the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>. We further introduce an evaluation method for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>. Using this method, we compare the performance of the non-modular system with the performance of the modular system and show that the modular dialog system framework is very suitable for this combination of conversational agents and that the performance of each agent decreases only marginally through the modular setting.</abstract>
      <url hash="b04297cd">2021.dialdoc-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.dialdoc-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>nehring-etal-2021-combining</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/clinc150">CLINC150</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/coqa">CoQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/squad">SQuAD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>CAiRE in DialDoc21 : Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialogue System<fixed-case>CA</fixed-case>i<fixed-case>RE</fixed-case> in <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ial<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>oc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialogue System</title>
      <author><first>Yan</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <author><first>Etsuko</first><last>Ishii</last></author>
      <author><first>Genta Indra</first><last>Winata</last></author>
      <author><first>Zhaojiang</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrea</first><last>Madotto</last></author>
      <author><first>Zihan</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Peng</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <author><first>Pascale</first><last>Fung</last></author>
      <pages>46–51</pages>
      <abstract>Information-seeking dialogue systems, including knowledge identification and response generation, aim to respond to users with fluent, coherent, and informative responses based on users’ needs, which. To tackle this challenge, we utilize data augmentation methods and several training techniques with the pre-trained language models to learn a general pattern of the task and thus achieve promising performance. In DialDoc21 competition, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> achieved 74.95 F1 score and 60.74 Exact Match score in subtask 1, and 37.72 SacreBLEU score in subtask 2. Empirical analysis is provided to explain the effectiveness of our approaches.</abstract>
      <url hash="17824f16">2021.dialdoc-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.dialdoc-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>xu-etal-2021-caire</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/HLTCHKUST/CAiRE_in_DialDoc21" additional="false">HLTCHKUST/CAiRE_in_DialDoc21</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/mrqa-2019">MRQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/searchqa">SearchQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/triviaqa">TriviaQA</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Team JARS : DialDoc Subtask 1-Improved Knowledge Identification with Supervised Out-of-Domain Pretraining<fixed-case>JARS</fixed-case>: <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ial<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>oc Subtask 1 - Improved Knowledge Identification with Supervised Out-of-Domain Pretraining</title>
      <author><first>Sopan</first><last>Khosla</last></author>
      <author><first>Justin</first><last>Lovelace</last></author>
      <author><first>Ritam</first><last>Dutt</last></author>
      <author><first>Adithya</first><last>Pratapa</last></author>
      <pages>103–108</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we discuss our submission for DialDoc subtask 1. The subtask requires systems to extract knowledge from FAQ-type documents vital to reply to a user’s query in a conversational setting. We experiment with pretraining a BERT-based question-answering model on different QA datasets from MRQA, as well as conversational QA datasets like CoQA and QuAC. Our results show that models pretrained on CoQA and QuAC perform better than their counterparts that are pretrained on MRQA datasets. Our results also indicate that adding more pretraining data does not necessarily result in improved performance. Our final model, which is an ensemble of AlBERT-XL pretrained on CoQA and QuAC independently, with the chosen answer having the highest average probability score, achieves an F1-Score of 70.9 % on the official test-set.</abstract>
      <url hash="10419e05">2021.dialdoc-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.dialdoc-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>khosla-etal-2021-team</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/coqa">CoQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/doc2dial-1">Doc2Dial</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hotpotqa">HotpotQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/mrqa-2019">MRQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/natural-questions">Natural Questions</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/newsqa">NewsQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/quac">QuAC</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/squad">SQuAD</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/triviaqa">TriviaQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/doc2dial">doc2dial</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>