<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.lantern">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-04-19">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Beyond Vision and LANguage: inTEgrating Real-world kNowledge (LANTERN)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Marius</first><last>Mosbach</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Michael A.</first><last>Hedderich</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sandro</first><last>Pezzelle</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Aditya</first><last>Mogadala</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dietrich</first><last>Klakow</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Marie-Francine</first><last>Moens</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Zeynep</first><last>Akata</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Kyiv, Ukraine</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ae3cbb95">2021.lantern-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>lantern-2021-beyond</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Visual Grounding Strategies for Text-Only Natural Language Processing</title>
      <author><first>Damien</first><last>Sileo</last></author>
      <pages>19–29</pages>
      <abstract>Visual grounding is a promising path toward more robust and accurate Natural Language Processing (NLP) models. Many multimodal extensions of BERT (e.g., VideoBERT, LXMERT, VL-BERT) allow a joint modeling of texts and images that lead to state-of-the-art results on multimodal tasks such as Visual Question Answering. Here, we leverage multimodal modeling for purely textual tasks (language modeling and classification) with the expectation that the multimodal pretraining provides a grounding that can improve text processing accuracy. We propose possible <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy_(game_theory)">strategies</a> in this respect. A first type of strategy, referred to as transferred grounding consists in applying multimodal models to text-only tasks using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Placeholder_name">placeholder</a> to replace image input. The second one, which we call associative grounding, harnesses <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image_retrieval">image retrieval</a> to match texts with related images during both pretraining and text-only downstream tasks. We draw further distinctions into both strategies and then compare them according to their impact on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language modeling</a> and commonsense-related downstream tasks, showing improvement over text-only baselines.<i>transferred grounding</i> consists in applying multimodal models to text-only tasks using a placeholder to replace image input. The second one, which we call <i>associative grounding</i>, harnesses image retrieval to match texts with related images during both pretraining and text-only downstream tasks. We draw further distinctions into both strategies and then compare them according to their impact on language modeling and commonsense-related downstream tasks, showing improvement over text-only baselines.</abstract>
      <url hash="a8765d1d">2021.lantern-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>sileo-2021-visual</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bookcorpus">BookCorpus</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/coco">COCO</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/imagenet">ImageNet</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/superglue">SuperGLUE</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>What Did This Castle Look like before? Exploring Referential Relations in Naturally Occurring Multimodal Texts</title>
      <author><first>Ronja</first><last>Utescher</last></author>
      <author><first>Sina</first><last>Zarrieß</last></author>
      <pages>53–60</pages>
      <abstract>Multi-modal texts are abundant and diverse in structure, yet Language &amp; Vision research of these naturally occurring texts has mostly focused on genres that are comparatively light on text, like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">tweets</a>. In this paper, we discuss the challenges and potential benefits of a L&amp;V framework that explicitly models referential relations, taking Wikipedia articles about buildings as an example. We briefly survey existing related tasks in L&amp;V and propose multi-modal information extraction as a general direction for future research.</abstract>
      <url hash="1666b58c">2021.lantern-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>utescher-zarriess-2021-castle</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>