<collection id="2017.jeptalnrecital">
  <volume id="long" ingest-date="2020-07-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes des 24&#232;me Conf&#233;rence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles. Volume 1 - Articles longs</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Iris</first><last>Eshkol-Taravella</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jean-Yves</first><last>Antoine</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Orl&#233;ans, France</address>
      <month>6</month>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ede7a90d">2017.jeptalnrecital-long.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2017-actes</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    </volume>
  <volume id="court" ingest-date="2020-07-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes des 24&#232;me Conf&#233;rence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles. Volume 2 - Articles courts</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Iris</first><last>Eshkol-Taravella</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jean-Yves</first><last>Antoine</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Orl&#233;ans, France</address>
      <month>6</month>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="64588f7b">2017.jeptalnrecital-court.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2017-actes-des</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Describing derivational polysemy with <fixed-case>XMG</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Marios</first><last>Andreou</last></author>
      <author><first>Simon</first><last>Petitjean</last></author>
      <pages>94&#8211;101</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we model and test the monosemy and polysemy approaches to derivational multiplicity of meaning, using Frame Semantics and XMG. In order to illustrate our claims and proposals, we use data from deverbal nominalizations with the suffix -al on verbs of change of possession (e.g. rental, disbursal). In our XMG implementation, we show that the underspecified meaning of affixes cannot always be reduced to a single unitary meaning and that the polysemy approach to multiplicity of meaning is more judicious compared to the monosemy approach. We also introduce constraints on the potential referents of derivatives. These constraints have the form of type constraints and specify which arguments in the frame of the verbal base are compatible with the referential argument of the derivative. The introduction of type constraints rules out certain readings because frame unification only succeeds if types are compatible.</abstract>
      <url hash="b996720c">2017.jeptalnrecital-court.12</url>
      <bibkey>andreou-petitjean-2017-describing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
  <volume id="recital" ingest-date="2020-07-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes des 24&#232;me Conf&#233;rence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles. 19es REncontres jeunes Chercheurs en Informatique pour le TAL (RECITAL 2017)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Iris</first><last>Eshkol-Taravella</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jean-Yves</first><last>Antoine</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Orl&#233;ans, France</address>
      <month>6</month>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="f4611ca2">2017.jeptalnrecital-recital.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2017-actes-des-24eme</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Machine Translation of Speech-Like Texts: Strategies for the Inclusion of Context</title>
      <author><first>Rachel</first><last>Bawden</last></author>
      <pages>1&#8211;14</pages>
      <abstract>Whilst the focus of Machine Translation (MT) has for a long time been the translation of planned, written texts, more and more research is being dedicated to translating speech-like texts (informal or spontaneous discourse or dialogue). To achieve high quality and natural translation of speechlike texts, the integration of context is needed, whether it is extra-linguistic (speaker identity, the interaction between speaker and interlocutor) or linguistic (coreference and stylistic phenomena linked to the spontaneous and informal nature of the texts). However, the integration of contextual information in MT systems remains limited in most current systems. In this paper, we present and critique three experiments for the integration of context into a MT system, each focusing on a different type of context and exploiting a different method: adaptation to speaker gender, cross-lingual pronoun prediction and the generation of tag questions from French into English.</abstract>
      <url hash="de8d432a">2017.jeptalnrecital-recital.1</url>
      <bibkey>bawden-2017-machine-translation</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Finding Missing Categories in Incomplete Utterances</title>
      <author><first>Mehdi</first><last>Mirzapour</last></author>
      <pages>149&#8211;160</pages>
      <abstract>Finding Missing Categories in Incomplete Utterances This paper introduces an efficient algorithm (O(n4 )) for finding a missing category in an incomplete utterance by using unification technique as when learning categorial grammars, and dynamic programming as in Cocke&#8211;Younger&#8211;Kasami algorithm. Using syntax/semantic interface of categorial grammar, this work can be used for deriving possible semantic readings of an incomplete utterance. The paper illustrates the problem with running examples.</abstract>
      <url hash="28c927d6">2017.jeptalnrecital-recital.12</url>
      <bibkey>mirzapour-2017-finding</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
  <volume id="demo" ingest-date="2020-07-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Actes des 24&#232;me Conf&#233;rence sur le Traitement Automatique des Langues Naturelles. Volume 3 - D&#233;monstrations</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Iris</first><last>Eshkol-Taravella</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jean-Yves</first><last>Antoine</last></editor>
      <publisher>ATALA</publisher>
      <address>Orl&#233;ans, France</address>
      <month>6</month>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ab5edebd">2017.jeptalnrecital-demo.0</url>
      <bibkey>jep-taln-recital-2017-actes-des-24eme-sur</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    </volume>
</collection>