<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2018.gwc">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-02-07">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 9th Global Wordnet Conference</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Piek</first><last>Vossen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Christiane</first><last>Fellbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>Global Wordnet Association</publisher>
      <address>Nanyang Technological University (NTU), Singapore</address>
      <month>January</month>
      <year>2018</year>
      <url hash="9e9cc8ba">2018.gwc-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="15c94917">2018.gwc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>gwc-2018-global</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>BanglaNet : Towards a WordNet for Bengali Language<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>angla<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et: Towards a <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et for <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>engali Language</title>
      <author><first>K.M. Tahsin Hassan</first><last>Rahit</last></author>
      <author><first>Khandaker Tabin</first><last>Hasan</last></author>
      <author><first>Md. Al-</first><last>Amin</last></author>
      <author><first>Zahiduddin</first><last>Ahmed</last></author>
      <pages>1–9</pages>
      <abstract>Despite being a popular language in the world, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bengali_language">Bengali language</a> lacks in having a good <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a>. This restricts us to do NLP related research work in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bengali_language">Bengali</a>. Most of the today’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnets</a> are developed by following expand approach. One of the key challenges of this approach is the cross-lingual word-sense disambiguation. In our research work, we make semantic relation between Bengali wordnet and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_WordNet">Princeton WordNet</a> based on well-established research work in other languages. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a> will derive relations between concepts as well. One of our key objectives is to provide a panel for lexicographers so that they can validate and contribute to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="67837898">2018.gwc-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>rahit-etal-2018-banglanet</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Towards Cross-checking <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> and SUMO Using Meronymy<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et and <fixed-case>SUMO</fixed-case> Using Meronymy</title>
      <author><first>Javier</first><last>Álvez</last></author>
      <author><first>German</first><last>Rigau</last></author>
      <pages>25–33</pages>
      <abstract>We describe the practical application of a black-box testing methodology for the validation of the knowledge encoded in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a>, SUMO and their mapping by using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automated_theorem_proving">automated theorem provers</a>. In this paper, weconcentrateonthepart-whole information provided by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> and create a large set of tests on the basis of few question patterns. From our preliminary evaluation results, we report on some of the detected inconsistencies.</abstract>
      <url hash="a32aa073">2018.gwc-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>alvez-rigau-2018-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Investigating English Affixes and their Productivity with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_WordNet">Princeton WordNet</a><fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish Affixes and their Productivity with <fixed-case>P</fixed-case>rinceton <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et</title>
      <author><first>Verginica</first><last>Mititelu</last></author>
      <pages>53–60</pages>
      <abstract>Such a rich language resource like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_WordNet">Princeton WordNet</a>, containing linguistic information of different types (semantic, lexical, syntactic, derivational, dialectal, etc.), is a thesaurus which is worth both being used in various language-enabled applications and being explored in order to study a language. In this paper we show how we used Princeton WordNet version 3.0 to study the English affixes. We extracted pairs of base-derived words and identified the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affix">affixes</a> by means of which the derived words were created from their bases. We distinguished among four types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphological_derivation">derivation</a> depending on the type of overlapping between the senses of the base word and those of the derived word that are linked by derivational relations in Princeton WordNet. We studied the behaviour of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affix">affixes</a> with respect to these derivation types. Drawing on these data, we inferred about their productivity.</abstract>
      <url hash="2b712ffd">2018.gwc-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>mititelu-2018-investigating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Mapping WordNet Concepts with CPA Ontology<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et Concepts with <fixed-case>CPA</fixed-case> Ontology</title>
      <author><first>Svetla</first><last>Koeva</last></author>
      <author><first>Cvetana</first><last>Dimitrova</last></author>
      <author><first>Valentina</first><last>Stefanova</last></author>
      <author><first>Dimitar</first><last>Hristov</last></author>
      <pages>69–76</pages>
      <abstract>The paper discusses the enrichment of WordNet data through merging of WordNet concepts and Corpus Pattern Analysis (CPA) semantic types. The 253 CPA semantic types are mapped to the respective WordNet concepts. As a result of mapping, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyponymy_and_hypernymy">hyponyms</a> of a synset to which a CPA semantic type is mapped inherit not only the respective WordNet semantic primitive but also the CPA semantic type.</abstract>
      <url hash="291226b5">2018.gwc-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>koeva-etal-2018-mapping</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Semantic Feature Structure Extraction From Documents Based on Extended Lexical Chains</title>
      <author><first>Terry</first><last>Ruas</last></author>
      <author><first>William</first><last>Grosky</last></author>
      <pages>87–96</pages>
      <abstract>The meaning of a sentence in a document is more easily determined if its constituent words exhibit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cohesion_(linguistics)">cohesion</a> with respect to their individual semantics. This paper explores the degree of cohesion among a document’s words using lexical chains as a semantic representation of its meaning. Using a combination of diverse types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_chain">lexical chains</a>, we develop a text document representation that can be used for semantic document retrieval. For our approach, we develop two kinds of lexical chains : (i) a multilevel flexible chain representation of the extracted semantic values, which is used to construct a fixed segmentation of these chains and constituent words in the text ; and (ii) a fixed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_chain">lexical chain</a> obtained directly from the initial semantic representation from a document. The extraction and processing of concepts is performed using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_database">lexical database</a>. The segmentation then uses these lexical chains to model the dispersion of concepts in the document. Representing each document as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dimension_(vector_space)">high-dimensional vector</a>, we use spherical k-means clustering to demonstrate that our approach performs better than previous techniques.</abstract>
      <url hash="efbee64e">2018.gwc-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>ruas-grosky-2018-semantic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Toward a Semantic Concordancer</title>
      <author><first>Adam</first><last>Pease</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrew</first><last>Cheung</last></author>
      <pages>97–104</pages>
      <abstract>Concordancers are an accepted and valuable part of the tool set of linguists and lexicographers. They allow the user to see the context of use of a word or phrase in a corpus. A large enough corpus, such as the Corpus Of Contemporary American English, provides the data needed to enumerate all common uses or meanings. One challenge is that there may be too many results for short search phrases or common words when only a specific context is desired. However, finding meaningful groupings of usage may be impractical if it entails enumerating long lists of possible values, such as city names. If a tool existed that could create some semantic abstractions, it would free the lexicographer from the need to resort to customized development of analysis software. To address this need, we have developed a Semantic Concordancer that uses dependency parsing and the Suggested Upper Merged Ontology (SUMO) to support linguistic analysis at a level of semantic abstraction above the original textual elements. We show how this facility can be employed to analyze the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_prepositions">English prepositions</a> by non-native speakers. We briefly introduce condordancers and then describe the corpora on which we applied this work. Next we provide a detailed description of the NLP pipeline followed by how this captures detailed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a>. We show how the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a> can be used to analyze errors in the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English prepositions</a> by non-native speakers of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>. Then we provide a description of a tool that allows users to build semantic search specifications from a set of English examples and how those results can be employed to build rules that translate sentences into logical forms.</abstract>
      <url hash="45acde09">2018.gwc-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>pease-cheung-2018-toward</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Using OpenWordnet-PT for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Question_answering">Question Answering</a> on Legal Domain<fixed-case>O</fixed-case>pen<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet-<fixed-case>PT</fixed-case> for Question Answering on Legal Domain</title>
      <author><first>Pedro</first><last>Delfino</last></author>
      <author><first>Bruno</first><last>Cuconato</last></author>
      <author><first>Guilherme</first><last>Paulino-Passos</last></author>
      <author><first>Gerson</first><last>Zaverucha</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexandre</first><last>Rademaker</last></author>
      <pages>105–112</pages>
      <abstract>In order to practice a legal profession in Brazil, law graduates must be approved in the OAB national unified bar exam. For their topic coverage and national reach, the OAB exams provide an excellent benchmark for the performance of legal information systems, as it provides objective metrics and are challenging even for humans, as only 20 % of its candidates are approved. After constructing a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">data set</a> on the exams and doing shallow experiments on it, we now employ the OpenWordnet-PT to verify whether using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_sense">word senses</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_relation">relations</a> we can improve previous results. We discuss the results, possible future ideas and the additions to the OpenWordnet-PT that we made.</abstract>
      <url hash="f4846440">2018.gwc-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>delfino-etal-2018-using</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Implementation of the Verb Model in plWordNet 4.0<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et 4.0</title>
      <author><first>Agnieszka</first><last>Dziob</last></author>
      <author><first>Maciej</first><last>Piasecki</last></author>
      <pages>113–122</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents an expansion of the verb model for plWordNet   the wordnet of Polish. A modified system of constitutive features (register, aspect and verb classes), synset and lexical relations is presented. A special attention is given to the proposed new relations and changes in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammatical_category">verb classification</a>. We discuss also the results of its verification by application to the description of a relatively large sample of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_verbs">Polish verbs</a>. The model introduces a new class of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_relation">relations</a>, namely non-constitutive synset relations that are shared among lexical units, but describe, not define <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synset">synsets</a>. The proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> is compared to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logical_consequence">entailment relations</a> in other wordnets, and the description of verbs based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Valency_(linguistics)">valency frames</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="86e782d7">2018.gwc-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>dziob-piasecki-2018-implementation</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Public Apologies in India-Semantics, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentimentality">Sentiment</a> and Emotion<fixed-case>I</fixed-case>ndia - Semantics, Sentiment and Emotion</title>
      <author><first>Sangeeta</first><last>Shukla</last></author>
      <author><first>Rajita</first><last>Shukla</last></author>
      <pages>123–135</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports a pilot study related to public apologies in India, with reference to certain <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Index_term">keywords</a> found in them. The study is of importance as the choice of lexical items holds importance which goes beyond the surface meaning of the words. The analysis of the lexical items has been done using interlinked digital lexical resources which, in future, can lend this study to computational tasks related to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opinion_mining">opinion mining</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_classification">document classification</a>. The study attempts an in-depth psycholinguistic analysis of whether the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apology_(act)">apology</a> conveys a sincerity of intent or is it a mere ritualistic exercise to control and repair damage.</abstract>
      <url hash="3d2e81e3">2018.gwc-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>shukla-shukla-2018-public</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Derivational Relations in Arabic WordNet<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et</title>
      <author><first>Mohamed Ali</first><last>Batita</last></author>
      <author><first>Mounir</first><last>Zrigui</last></author>
      <pages>136–144</pages>
      <abstract>When derivational relations deficiency exists in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">wordnet</a>, such as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic_WordNet">Arabic WordNet</a>, it makes it very difficult to exploit in the natural language processing community. Such deficiency is raised when many wordnets follow the same development path of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_WordNet">Princeton WordNet</a>. A rule-based approach for Arabic derivational relations is proposed in this paper to deal with this deficiency. The proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tactic_(method)">approach</a> is explained step by step. It involves the gathering of lexical entries that share the same <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Root_(linguistics)">root</a>, into a bag of words. Rules are then used to affect the appropriate derivational relations, i.e. to relate existing words in the AWN, involving part-of-speech switch. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Method_(computer_programming)">method</a> is implemented using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_(programming_language)">Java</a>. Manual verification by a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexicography">lexicographer</a> takes place to ensure good results. The described approach gave good results. It could be useful for other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphology_(linguistics)">morphologically complex languages</a> as well.</abstract>
      <url hash="e331ee56">2018.gwc-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>batita-zrigui-2018-derivational</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>The Company They Keep : Extracting Japanese Neologisms Using Language Patterns<fixed-case>J</fixed-case>apanese Neologisms Using Language Patterns</title>
      <author><first>James</first><last>Breen</last></author>
      <author><first>Timothy</first><last>Baldwin</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <pages>163–171</pages>
      <abstract>We describe an investigation into the identification and extraction of unrecorded potential lexical items in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese text</a> by detecting text passages containing selected language patterns typically associated with such items. We identified a set of suitable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattern">patterns</a>, then tested them with two large collections of text drawn from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web">WWW</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a>. Samples of the extracted items were evaluated, and it was demonstrated that the approach has considerable potential for identifying terms for later <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexicography">lexicographic analysis</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="cbf2108e">2018.gwc-1.19</url>
      <bibkey>breen-etal-2018-company</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Lexical-semantic resources : yet powerful resources for automatic personality classification</title>
      <author><first>Xuan-Son</first><last>Vu</last></author>
      <author><first>Lucie</first><last>Flekova</last></author>
      <author><first>Lili</first><last>Jiang</last></author>
      <author><first>Iryna</first><last>Gurevych</last></author>
      <pages>172–181</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we aim to reveal the impact of lexical-semantic resources, used in particular for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word-sense_disambiguation">word sense disambiguation</a> and sense-level semantic categorization, on automatic personality classification task. While <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Style_(sociolinguistics)">stylistic features</a> (e.g., part-of-speech counts) have been shown their power in this task, the impact of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a> beyond targeted word lists is relatively unexplored. We propose and extract three types of lexical-semantic features, which capture high-level concepts and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotions</a>, overcoming the lexical gap of word n-grams. Our experimental results are comparable to state-of-the-art methods, while no personality-specific resources are required.</abstract>
      <url hash="d41596fa">2018.gwc-1.20</url>
      <bibkey>vu-etal-2018-lexical</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Towards a principled approach to sense clustering   a case study of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a> and dictionary senses in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danish_language">Danish</a><fixed-case>D</fixed-case>anish</title>
      <author><first>Bolette</first><last>Pedersen</last></author>
      <author><first>Manex</first><last>Agirrezabal</last></author>
      <author><first>Sanni</first><last>Nimb</last></author>
      <author><first>Ida</first><last>Olsen</last></author>
      <author><first>Sussi</first><last>Olsen</last></author>
      <pages>182–189</pages>
      <abstract>Our aim is to develop principled methods for sense clustering which can make existing lexical resources practically useful in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a>   not too fine-grained to be operational and yet finegrained enough to be worth the trouble. Where traditional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dictionary">dictionaries</a> have a highly structured sense inventory typically describing the vocabulary by means of mainand subsenses, wordnets are generally fine-grained and unstructured. We present a series of clustering and annotation experiments with 10 of the most polysemous nouns in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danish_language">Danish</a>. We combine the structured information of a traditional Danish dictionary with the ontological types found in the Danish wordnet, DanNet. This constellation enables us to automatically cluster senses in a principled way and improve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inter-annotator_agreement">inter-annotator agreement</a> and wsd performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="f6658855">2018.gwc-1.21</url>
      <bibkey>pedersen-etal-2018-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>WordnetLoom   a Multilingual Wordnet Editing System Focused on Graph-based Presentation<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>oom – a Multilingual <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet Editing System Focused on Graph-based Presentation</title>
      <author><first>Tomasz</first><last>Naskręt</last></author>
      <author><first>Agnieszka</first><last>Dziob</last></author>
      <author><first>Maciej</first><last>Piasecki</last></author>
      <author><first>Chakaveh</first><last>Saedi</last></author>
      <author><first>António</first><last>Branco</last></author>
      <pages>190–199</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents a new re-built and expanded, version 2.0 of WordnetLoom   an open wordnet editor. It facilitates work on a multilingual system of wordnets, is based on efficient <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_architecture">software architecture</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thin_client">thin client</a>, and offers more flexibility in enriching wordnet representation. This new version is built on the experience collected during the use of the previous one for more than 10 years of plWordNet development. We discuss its extensions motivated by the collected experience. A special focus is given to the development of a variant for the needs of MultiWordnet of Portuguese, which is based on a very different wordnet development model.</abstract>
      <url hash="1ac23b8c">2018.gwc-1.22</url>
      <bibkey>naskret-etal-2018-wordnetloom</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Lexical Perspective on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">Wordnet</a> to Wordnet Mapping<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet to <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet Mapping</title>
      <author><first>Ewa</first><last>Rudnicka</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <author><first>Łukasz</first><last>Grabowski</last></author>
      <author><first>Maciej</first><last>Piasecki</last></author>
      <author><first>Tadeusz</first><last>Piotrowski</last></author>
      <pages>209–218</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents a feature-based model of equivalence targeted at (manual) sense linking between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_WordNet">Princeton WordNet</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PlWordNet">plWordNet</a>. The model incorporates insights from lexicographic and translation theories on bilingual equivalence and draws on the results of earlier synset-level mapping of nouns between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_WordNet">Princeton WordNet</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PlWordNet">plWordNet</a>. It takes into account all basic aspects of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">language</a> such as form, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meaning_(linguistics)">meaning</a> and function and supplements them with (parallel) corpus frequency and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transliteration">translatability</a>. Three types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equivalence_relation">equivalence</a> are distinguished, namely strong, regular and weak depending on the conformity with the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a>. The presented solutions are language-neutral and they can be easily applied to language pairs other than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_language">Polish</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>. Sense-level mapping is a more fine-grained mapping than the existing synset mappings and is thus of great potential to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation">human and machine translation</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="92ebe48f">2018.gwc-1.24</url>
      <bibkey>rudnicka-etal-2018-lexical</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>Wordnet-based Evaluation of Large Distributional Models for Polish<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet-based Evaluation of Large Distributional Models for <fixed-case>P</fixed-case>olish</title>
      <author><first>Maciej</first><last>Piasecki</last></author>
      <author><first>Gabriela</first><last>Czachor</last></author>
      <author><first>Arkadiusz</first><last>Janz</last></author>
      <author><first>Dominik</first><last>Kaszewski</last></author>
      <author><first>Paweł</first><last>Kędzia</last></author>
      <pages>229–238</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents construction of large scale test datasets for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embeddings</a> on the basis of a very large wordnet. They were next applied for evaluation of word embedding models and used to assess and compare the usefulness of different word embeddings extracted from a very large corpus of Polish. We analysed also and compared several publicly available <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> described in literature. In addition, several large word embeddings models built on the basis of a very large Polish corpus are presented.</abstract>
      <url hash="8e7189f3">2018.gwc-1.26</url>
      <bibkey>piasecki-etal-2018-wordnet</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Distant Supervision for Relation Extraction with Multi-sense Word Embedding</title>
      <author><first>Sangha</first><last>Nam</last></author>
      <author><first>Kijong</first><last>Han</last></author>
      <author><first>Eun-Kyung</first><last>Kim</last></author>
      <author><first>Key-Sun</first><last>Choi</last></author>
      <pages>239–244</pages>
      <abstract>Distant supervision can automatically generate labeled data between a large-scale corpus and a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_base">knowledge base</a> without utilizing human efforts. Therefore, many studies have used the distant supervision approach in relation extraction tasks. However, existing studies have a disadvantage in that they do not reflect the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homograph">homograph</a> in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embedding</a> used as an input of the relation extraction model. Thus, it can be seen that the relation extraction model learns without grasping the meaning of the word accurately. In this paper, we propose a relation extraction model with multi-sense word embedding. We learn multi-sense word embedding using a word sense disambiguation module. In addition, we use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network">convolutional neural network</a> and piecewise max pooling convolutional neural network relation extraction models that efficiently grasp key features in sentences. To evaluate the performance of the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a>, two additional methods of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embedding</a> were learned and compared. Accordingly, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> showed the highest performance among them.</abstract>
      <url hash="461fc3cb">2018.gwc-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>nam-etal-2018-distant</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="28">
      <title>Cross-Lingual and Supervised Learning Approach for Indonesian Word Sense Disambiguation Task<fixed-case>I</fixed-case>ndonesian Word Sense Disambiguation Task</title>
      <author><first>Rahmad</first><last>Mahendra</last></author>
      <author><first>Heninggar</first><last>Septiantri</last></author>
      <author><first>Haryo Akbarianto</first><last>Wibowo</last></author>
      <author><first>Ruli</first><last>Manurung</last></author>
      <author><first>Mirna</first><last>Adriani</last></author>
      <pages>245–250</pages>
      <abstract>Ambiguity is a problem we frequently face in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a>. Word Sense Disambiguation (WSD) is a task to determine the correct sense of an ambiguous word. However, research in WSD for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesian_language">Indonesian</a> is still rare to find. The availability of English-Indonesian parallel corpora and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> for both languages can be used as training data for WSD by applying Cross-Lingual WSD method. This training data is used as an input to build a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> using supervised machine learning algorithms. Our research also examines the use of Word Embedding features to build the WSD model.</abstract>
      <url hash="667fe9f1">2018.gwc-1.28</url>
      <bibkey>mahendra-etal-2018-cross</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="30">
      <title>Simple Embedding-Based Word Sense Disambiguation</title>
      <author><first>Dieke</first><last>Oele</last></author>
      <author><first>Gertjan</first><last>van Noord</last></author>
      <pages>259–265</pages>
      <abstract>We present a simple knowledge-based WSD method that uses word and sense embeddings to compute the similarity between the gloss of a sense and the context of the word. Our method is inspired by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lesk_algorithm">Lesk algorithm</a> as it exploits both the context of the words and the definitions of the senses. It only requires large unlabeled corpora and a sense inventory such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a>, and therefore does not rely on annotated data. We explore whether additional extensions to Lesk are compatible with our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Method_(computer_programming)">method</a>. The results of our experiments show that by lexically extending the amount of words in the gloss and context, although it works well for other implementations of Lesk, harms our method. Using a lexical selection method on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context_(language_use)">context words</a>, on the other hand, improves it. The combination of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> with lexical selection enables our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> to outperform state-of the art <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge-based_systems">knowledge-based systems</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="c19f0f0c">2018.gwc-1.30</url>
      <bibkey>oele-noord-2018-simple</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/word-sense-disambiguation-a-unified">Word Sense Disambiguation: a Unified Evaluation Framework and Empirical Comparison</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="31">
      <title>Semi-automatic WordNet Linking using Word Embeddings<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et Linking using Word Embeddings</title>
      <author><first>Kevin</first><last>Patel</last></author>
      <author><first>Diptesh</first><last>Kanojia</last></author>
      <author><first>Pushpak</first><last>Bhattacharyya</last></author>
      <pages>266–271</pages>
      <abstract>Wordnets are rich lexico-semantic resources. Linked wordnets are extensions of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnets</a>, which link similar concepts in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnets</a> of different languages. Such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_(computer_science)">resources</a> are extremely useful in many Natural Language Processing (NLP) applications, primarily those based on knowledge-based approaches. In such approaches, these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_resource">resources</a> are considered as gold standard / oracle. Thus, it is crucial that these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_(computer_science)">resources</a> hold correct information. Thereby, they are created by human experts. However, manual maintenance of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_(project_management)">resources</a> is a tedious and costly affair. Thus techniques that can aid the experts are desirable. In this paper, we propose an approach to link <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnets</a>. Given a synset of the source language, the approach returns a ranked list of potential candidate synsets in the target language from which the human expert can choose the correct one(s). Our technique is able to retrieve a winner synset in the top 10 ranked list for 60 % of all synsets and 70 % of noun synsets.</abstract>
      <url hash="ba85ab63">2018.gwc-1.31</url>
      <bibkey>patel-etal-2018-semi</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="32">
      <title>Multilingual Wordnet sense Ranking using nearest context<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet sense Ranking using nearest context</title>
      <author><first>E Umamaheswari</first><last>Vasanthakumar</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <pages>272–283</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we combine methods to estimate sense rankings from raw text with recent work on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embeddings</a> to provide sense ranking estimates for the entries in the Open Multilingual WordNet (OMW). The existing Word2Vec pre-trained models from Polygot2 are only built for single word entries, we, therefore, re-train them with multiword expressions from the wordnets, so that multiword expressions can also be ranked. Thus this trained <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> gives <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embedding">embeddings</a> for both single words and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interlingue">multiwords</a>. The resulting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexicon">lexicon</a> gives a WSD baseline for five languages. The results are evaluated for Semcor sense corpora for 5 languages using Word2Vec and Glove models. The Glove model achieves an average accuracy of 0.47 and Word2Vec achieves 0.31 for languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_language">Italian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesian_language">Indonesian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese</a>. The experimentation on OMW sense ranking proves that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rank_correlation">rank correlation</a> is generally similar to the human ranking. Hence <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributional_semantics">distributional semantics</a> can aid in Wordnet Sense Ranking.</abstract>
      <url hash="3ea89375">2018.gwc-1.32</url>
      <bibkey>vasanthakumar-bond-2018-multilingual</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="34">
      <title>An Iterative Approach for Unsupervised Most Frequent Sense Detection using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> and Word Embeddings<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et and Word Embeddings</title>
      <author><first>Kevin</first><last>Patel</last></author>
      <author><first>Pushpak</first><last>Bhattacharyya</last></author>
      <pages>293–297</pages>
      <abstract>Given a word, what is the most frequent sense in which it occurs in a given corpus? Most Frequent Sense (MFS) is a strong baseline for unsupervised word sense disambiguation. If we have large amounts of sense-annotated corpora, MFS can be trivially created. However, sense-annotated corpora are a rarity. In this paper, we propose a method which can compute MFS from raw corpora. Our approach iteratively exploits the semantic congruity among related words in corpus. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> performs better compared to another similar work.</abstract>
      <url hash="82a1e150">2018.gwc-1.34</url>
      <bibkey>patel-bhattacharyya-2018-iterative</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="35">
      <title>Automatic Identification of Basic-Level Categories</title>
      <author><first>Chad</first><last>Mills</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <author><first>Gina-Anne</first><last>Levow</last></author>
      <pages>298–305</pages>
      <abstract>Basic-level categories have been shown to be both psychologically significant and useful in a wide range of practical applications. We build a rule-based system to identify basic-level categories in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a>, achieving 77 % accuracy on a test set derived from prior psychological experiments. With additional annotations we found our system also has low precision, in part due to the existence of many categories that do not fit into the three classes (superordinate, basic-level, and subordinate) relied on in basic-level category research.</abstract>
      <url hash="8056cd88">2018.gwc-1.35</url>
      <bibkey>mills-etal-2018-automatic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="36">
      <title>African Wordnet : facilitating language learning in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_Africa">African languages</a><fixed-case>A</fixed-case>frican <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet: facilitating language learning in <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>frican languages</title>
      <author><first>Sonja</first><last>Bosch</last></author>
      <author><first>Marissa</first><last>Griesel</last></author>
      <pages>306–313</pages>
      <abstract>The development of the African Wordnet (AWN) has reached a stage of maturity where the first steps towards an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software">application</a> can be attempted. The AWN is based on the expand method, and to compensate for the general resource scarceness of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_Africa">African languages</a>, various development strategies were used. The aim of this paper is to investigate the usefulness of the current isiZulu Wordnet in an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software">application</a> such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_acquisition">language learning</a>. The advantage of incorporating the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a> of a language into a language learning system is that it provides learners with an integrated application to enhance their learning experience by means of the unique sense identification features of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnets</a>. In this paper it will be demonstrated by means of a variety of examples within the context of a basic free online course how the isiZulu Wordnet can offer the language learner improved decision support.</abstract>
      <url hash="0f476253">2018.gwc-1.36</url>
      <bibkey>bosch-griesel-2018-african</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="37">
      <title>Hindi Wordnet for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_pedagogy">Language Teaching</a> : Experiences and Lessons Learnt<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>indi <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet for Language Teaching: Experiences and Lessons Learnt</title>
      <author><first>Hanumant</first><last>Redkar</last></author>
      <author><first>Rajita</first><last>Shukla</last></author>
      <author><first>Sandhya</first><last>Singh</last></author>
      <author><first>Jaya</first><last>Saraswati</last></author>
      <author><first>Laxmi</first><last>Kashyap</last></author>
      <author><first>Diptesh</first><last>Kanojia</last></author>
      <author><first>Preethi</first><last>Jyothi</last></author>
      <author><first>Malhar</first><last>Kulkarni</last></author>
      <author><first>Pushpak</first><last>Bhattacharyya</last></author>
      <pages>314–323</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports the work related to making Hindi Wordnet1 available as a digital resource for language learning and teaching, and the experiences and lessons that were learnt during the process. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_(computing)">language data</a> of the Hindi Wordnet has been suitably modified and enhanced to make it into a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_acquisition">language learning aid</a>. This aid is based on modern pedagogical axioms and is aligned to the learning objectives of the syllabi of the school education in India. To make it into a comprehensive language tool, grammatical information has also been encoded, as far as these can be marked on the lexical items. The delivery of information is multi-layered, multi-sensory and is available across multiple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computing_platform">digital platforms</a>. The front end has been designed to offer an eye-catching user-friendly interface which is suitable for learners starting from age six onward. Preliminary testing of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tool</a> has been done and it has been modified as per the feedbacks that were received. Above all, the entire exercise has offered gainful insights into learning based on associative networks and how knowledge based on such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_network">networks</a> can be made available to modern learners.</abstract>
      <url hash="add72dd2">2018.gwc-1.37</url>
      <bibkey>redkar-etal-2018-hindi</bibkey>
    <title_ar>Wordnet الهندية لتدريس اللغة: الخبرات والدروس المستفادة</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Hindi Wordnet para ensino de idiomas: experiências e lições aprendidas</title_pt>
      <title_es>Wordnet en hindi para la enseñanza de idiomas: experiencias y lecciones aprendidas</title_es>
      <title_ja>言語教育のためのヒンディー語ワードネット：学習した経験と教訓</title_ja>
      <title_zh>印地语语教Wordnet:经训</title_zh>
      <title_hi>हिंदी Wordnet for Language Teaching: Experiences and Lessons Learned</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Wordnet Hiondúis do Mhúineadh Teangacha: Eispéiris agus Ceachtanna Foghlamtha</title_ga>
      <title_el>Χίντι για τη διδασκαλία γλωσσών: εμπειρίες και μαθήματα που μαθαίνονται</title_el>
      <title_hu>Hindi Wordnet nyelvtanításhoz: tapasztalatok és tanulságok</title_hu>
      <title_kk>Тіл оқыту үшін хинди Wordnet: Experience and Lesson Learned</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Hindi Wordnet kalbų mokymui: patirtis ir išmokta pamoka</title_lt>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_ml>ഭാഷ പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള ഹിന്ദ്രി വാര്‍ഡ്നെറ്റ്: പരിഭാഷകളും പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_it>Wordnet Hindi per l'insegnamento delle lingue: esperienze e lezioni apprese</title_it>
      <title_mt>Wordnet Indjan għat-Tagħlim tal-Lingwi: Esperjenzi u Tagħlim</title_mt>
      <title_mk>Хиндиски Wordnet за учење јазици: Дознати се искуства и лекции</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Wordnet Hindi untuk Guru Bahasa: Pengalaman dan Pelajaran Dibelajar</title_ms>
      <title_pl>Słowo hindi dla nauczania języka: doświadczenia i lekcje</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Cuvinte hindi pentru predarea limbilor străine: Experiențe și lecții învățate</title_ro>
      <title_mn>Хинди хэл багш суралцах үеийн Wordnet: туршилт болон суралцах</title_mn>
      <title_no>Hindi Wordnet for språk- læring: Experiences and Lessons Learn</title_no>
      <title_si>භාෂාව ඉගෙනීම සඳහා හින්දී Wordnet: පරීක්ෂණ සහ පාසල් ඉගෙනීම</title_si>
      <title_sv>Hindi Wordnet för språkundervisning: Erfarenheter och lärdomar</title_sv>
      <title_sr>Hindi Wordnet za učenje jezika: iskustva i učenje</title_sr>
      <title_so>Ereyga Hindi ee Waxbarashada luqada: Erayada iyo waxbarashada</title_so>
      <title_ta>மொழி கற்றுக்கான இந்திய வார்த்தை</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Hindi Wordnet for Language Teaching: Experiences and Lessons Learned</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Til o'rganish uchun Hindiston soʻzlari: Ersus va o'rganish</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Giáo dục tiếng Hindi: Kinh nghiệm và bài học</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Хинди думи за езиково обучение: преживявания и уроци</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Hindi Wordnet za učenje jezika: iskustva i učenje</title_hr>
      <title_da>Hindi Wordnet til sprogundervisning: erfaringer og lektioner lært</title_da>
      <title_nl>Hindi Wordnet voor Taalonderwijs: Ervaringen en Leren Leren</title_nl>
      <title_fa>Hindi Wordnet for Language Teaching: Experiences and Lessons Learned</title_fa>
      <title_de>Hindi Wordnet für den Sprachunterricht: Erfahrungen und Lektionen gelernt</title_de>
      <title_ko>인도어 Wordnet 언어 교육: 경험과 교훈</title_ko>
      <title_id>Hindi Wordnet untuk Guru Bahasa: Pengalaman dan Pelajaran Dibelajar</title_id>
      <title_sw>Mtandao wa Kihindi kwa ajili ya mafunzo ya lugha: Tatizo na kujifunza somo</title_sw>
      <title_af>Hindi Wordnet vir Taal Leer: Experiences and Lessons Learn</title_af>
      <title_sq>Hindi Wordnet for Language Teaching: Experiences and Lessons Learnt</title_sq>
      <title_tr>Dil öwrenmek üçin Hindistança sözler</title_tr>
      <title_am>የHindi ቃላት ለቋንቋ አስተማሪ: ምህረት እና ማስተማር</title_am>
      <title_bs>Hindi Wordnet za učenje jezika: iskustva i učenje</title_bs>
      <title_bn>Hindi Wordnet for Language Teaching: Experiences and Lessons Learnt</title_bn>
      <title_az>Dil 칬yr톛nm톛si 칲칞칲n Hindi Wordnet: Experience and Lessons Learn</title_az>
      <title_ca>Hindi Wordnet for Language Teaching: Experiences and Lessons Learnt</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Hindština Wordnet pro výuku jazyků: zkušenosti a lekce učené</title_cs>
      <title_et>Hindi Wordnet keeleõpetamiseks: kogemused ja õppetunnid</title_et>
      <title_fi>Hindi Wordnet kieltenopetukseen: Kokemuksia ja oppitunteja</title_fi>
      <title_hy>Հինդի Wordnet լեզվի ուսուցման համար. Փորձառություններ և սովորված դասեր</title_hy>
      <title_jv>Perintah Panjenengan kanggo Kejaring Language</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Hindi Wordnet za poučevanje jezikov: izkušnje in lekcije</title_sk>
      <title_he>Hindi Wordnet for Language Teaching: Experiences and Lessons Learnt</title_he>
      <title_bo>Hindi Wordnet for Language Teaching: Experience and Lesson Learn</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>توضح هذه الورقة العمل المتعلق بجعل Hindi Wordnet1 متاحة كمصدر رقمي لتعلم اللغة وتدريسها ، والخبرات والدروس التي تم تعلمها أثناء العملية. تم تعديل بيانات اللغة الخاصة بـ Hindi Wordnet وتحسينها بشكل مناسب لجعلها أداة مساعدة لتعلم اللغة. تعتمد هذه المساعدة على البديهيات التربوية الحديثة وتتوافق مع أهداف التعلم لمناهج التعليم المدرسي في الهند. لجعلها أداة لغوية شاملة ، تم أيضًا تشفير المعلومات النحوية ، بقدر ما يمكن تمييزها على العناصر المعجمية. تسليم المعلومات متعدد الطبقات ومتعدد الحواس ومتاح عبر منصات رقمية متعددة. تم تصميم الواجهة الأمامية لتقديم واجهة سهلة الاستخدام لافتة للنظر ومناسبة للمتعلمين بدءًا من سن السادسة فصاعدًا. تم إجراء اختبار أولي للأداة وتم تعديلها وفقًا للتعليقات التي تم تلقيها. قبل كل شيء ، قدم التمرين بأكمله رؤى مفيدة في التعلم القائم على الشبكات الترابطية وكيف يمكن إتاحة المعرفة القائمة على هذه الشبكات للمتعلمين المعاصرين.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Este documento informa sobre el trabajo relacionado con hacer que Wordnet1 en hindi esté disponible como un recurso digital para el aprendizaje y la enseñanza de idiomas, y las experiencias y lecciones que se aprendieron durante el proceso. Los datos lingüísticos de Hindi Wordnet se han modificado y mejorado adecuadamente para convertirlos en una ayuda para el aprendizaje de idiomas. Esta ayuda se basa en axiomas pedagógicos modernos y está alineada con los objetivos de aprendizaje de los programas de la educación escolar en la India. Para convertirla en una herramienta lingüística integral, también se ha codificado la información gramatical, en la medida en que se puede marcar en los elementos léxicos. La entrega de información es de varios niveles, multisensorial y está disponible en múltiples plataformas digitales. El front-end ha sido diseñado para ofrecer una interfaz llamativa y fácil de usar que es adecuada para estudiantes a partir de los seis años. Se han realizado pruebas preliminares de la herramienta y se ha modificado según los comentarios recibidos. Sobre todo, todo el ejercicio ha ofrecido perspectivas provechosas sobre el aprendizaje basado en redes asociativas y cómo el conocimiento basado en dichas redes puede ponerse a disposición de los estudiantes modernos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo relata o trabalho relacionado à disponibilização do Hindi Wordnet1 como recurso digital para aprendizagem e ensino de línguas, e as experiências e lições aprendidas durante o processo. Os dados de idioma do Hindi Wordnet foram modificados e aprimorados adequadamente para torná-lo um auxílio para o aprendizado de idiomas. Esse auxílio é baseado em axiomas pedagógicos modernos e está alinhado aos objetivos de aprendizagem dos programas de educação escolar na Índia. Para torná-lo uma ferramenta linguística abrangente, as informações gramaticais também foram codificadas, na medida em que podem ser marcadas nos itens lexicais. A entrega de informações é multicamada, multissensorial e está disponível em várias plataformas digitais. O front-end foi projetado para oferecer uma interface amigável e atraente, adequada para alunos a partir dos seis anos de idade. Os testes preliminares da ferramenta foram feitos e ela foi modificada conforme os feedbacks recebidos. Acima de tudo, todo o exercício ofereceu insights valiosos sobre a aprendizagem baseada em redes associativas e como o conhecimento baseado em tais redes pode ser disponibilizado aos alunos modernos.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、言語学習と教授のためのデジタルリソースとしてヒンディー語Wordnet 1を利用できるようにするための作業と、その過程で学んだ経験と教訓について報告する。 ヒンディー語Wordnetの言語データは、言語学習支援になるように適切に修正および強化されています。 この補助は、現代の教育理論に基づいており、インドの学校教育のシラビアの学習目標と一致しています。 包括的な言語ツールにするために、文法情報もエンコードされています。 情報の提供は多層的で、多感覚であり、複数のデジタルプラットフォームで利用できます。 フロントエンドは、6歳以降の学習者に適した、目を引くユーザーフレンドリーなインターフェースを提供するように設計されています。 ツールの予備テストが完了し、受け取ったフィードバックに従って変更されました。 とりわけ、演習全体は、連想ネットワークに基づいた学習と、そのようなネットワークに基づいた知識が現代の学習者にどのように利用可能になるかについての有益な洞察を提供している。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>本文告印地语Wordnet1为言学、教学之数,及此经训。 印地语Wordnet言数已损益,使为言学辅助工具。 此援基于现代教学公理,并与印度学校教育教学大纲的学习保持一样。 为具言具,语法息编码,可以记词汇目。 信息传多层次,多感官,且可跨数平台得之。 前端旨供引人注目用户好界面,宜从六岁始学者。 其初试已成,因所得反馈改之。 最要者,全习为基于联想网络之学,及所以资于今之学者,网络有益于见也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर हिंदी वर्डनेट 1 को भाषा सीखने और शिक्षण के लिए डिजिटल संसाधन के रूप में उपलब्ध कराने से संबंधित काम की रिपोर्ट करता है, और इस प्रक्रिया के दौरान सीखे गए अनुभवों और पाठों की रिपोर्ट करता है। हिंदी वर्डनेट के भाषा डेटा को उपयुक्त रूप से संशोधित किया गया है और इसे भाषा सीखने की सहायता में बनाने के लिए बढ़ाया गया है। यह सहायता आधुनिक शैक्षणिक स्वयंसिद्धों पर आधारित है और भारत में स्कूली शिक्षा के पाठ्यक्रम के सीखने के उद्देश्यों के लिए संरेखित है। इसे एक व्यापक भाषा उपकरण में बनाने के लिए, व्याकरणिक जानकारी को भी एन्कोडेड किया गया है, जहां तक इन्हें लेक्सिकल आइटम पर चिह्नित किया जा सकता है। जानकारी का वितरण बहु-स्तरित, बहु-संवेदी है और कई डिजिटल प्लेटफार्मों पर उपलब्ध है। फ्रंट एंड को एक आंख को पकड़ने वाले उपयोगकर्ता के अनुकूल इंटरफ़ेस प्रदान करने के लिए डिज़ाइन किया गया है जो छह साल की उम्र से शुरू होने वाले शिक्षार्थियों के लिए उपयुक्त है। उपकरण का प्रारंभिक परीक्षण किया जा चुका है और इसे प्राप्त फीडबैक के अनुसार संशोधित किया गया है। इन सबसे ऊपर, पूरे अभ्यास ने साहचर्य नेटवर्क के आधार पर सीखने में लाभकारी अंतर्दृष्टि की पेशकश की है और इस तरह के नेटवर्क के आधार पर ज्ञान को आधुनिक शिक्षार्थियों को कैसे उपलब्ध कराया जा सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Tuairiscíonn an páipéar seo an obair a bhaineann le Wordnet Hiondúis1 a chur ar fáil mar acmhainn dhigiteach d’fhoghlaim agus do theagasc teangacha, agus ar na heispéiris agus na ceachtanna a foghlaimíodh le linn an phróisis. Tá sonraí teanga an Wordnet Hiondúis modhnaithe agus feabhsaithe go hoiriúnach chun é a dhéanamh mar áis foghlama teanga. Tá an chabhair seo bunaithe ar aicsiomaí nua-aimseartha oideolaíocha agus tá sé ailínithe le cuspóirí foghlama na siollabas oideachais scoile san India. Chun gur uirlis chuimsitheach teanga í, tá faisnéis ghramadaí ionchódaithe freisin, chomh fada agus is féidir iad seo a mharcáil ar na míreanna foclóireachta. Tá seachadadh faisnéise ilshraitheach, ilchéadfach agus tá sé ar fáil thar ardáin dhigiteacha iolracha. Dearadh an foirceann tosaigh chun comhéadan a thaitníonn leis an tsúil le húsáid a thairiscint atá oiriúnach d’fhoghlaimeoirí atá ag tosú ó sé bliana d’aois ar aghaidh. Tá réamhthástáil déanta ar an uirlis agus athraíodh í de réir an aiseolais a fuarthas. Thar aon ní eile, thairg an cleachtadh ar fad léargas tairbheach ar an bhfoghlaim atá bunaithe ar líonraí comhthiomsaitheacha agus ar an gcaoi ar féidir eolas atá bunaithe ar líonraí dá leithéid a chur ar fáil d’fhoghlaimeoirí nua-aimseartha.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დოკუმენტის შესახებ ინდური სიტყვების შესახებ, როგორც დიზიტალური რესურსი ენის სწავლებისთვის და სწავლებისთვის და გამოცდილებისთვის, რომელიც პროცესის განმავლობაში სწ Hindi Wordnet-ის ენის მონაცემები მსგავსიდ შეცვლა და უფრო მეტადებული იყო ენის სწავლების დახმარებაში. ეს დახმარება მოდინარე მედიადოგიური აქსიომებზე დაბაზიან და ინდოეთში სკოლური განსწავლების სილაბის მისამართებელი მისამართებელია. თუმცა ეს ყველაფერი ენათის ხელსაწყოთა შესაძლებელია, გრამიკალური ინფორმაცია კოდირებულია, თუმცა ეს შესაძლებელია ლექსიკალური ელემენტებში. ინფორმაციის გადატვირთვა არის მრავალური, მრავალური სენსორია და მრავალური დიზიტალური პლატატურების განმავლობაში აქვს. შვიდი წლიდან დაწყებული სწავლებელებისთვის საჭირო ინტერფექტი, რომელიც საჭირო იყო შვიდი წლიდან. მოწყობილობის პირველი ტესტი მოქმედება და იყო შეცვლა, როგორც მიღებულიან წინახსნა. ყველაზე უფრო მეტად, ყველა განვიცემები იყო სწავლების შესახებ, როგორ აზიანციური ქსელების ბაზაზე და როგორ ასეთი ქსელების ბაზაზე მეცნიერება შეიძლება მოხილოთ მო</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία αναφέρει το έργο που σχετίζεται με τη διάθεση του Χίντι Wordnet1 ως ψηφιακού πόρου για την εκμάθηση και τη διδασκαλία γλωσσών, καθώς και τις εμπειρίες και τα μαθήματα που αποκτήθηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια της διαδικασίας. Τα γλωσσικά δεδομένα του Χίντι Wordnet έχουν τροποποιηθεί κατάλληλα και ενισχυθεί ώστε να γίνουν ένα βοήθημα εκμάθησης γλωσσών. Η βοήθεια αυτή βασίζεται σε σύγχρονα παιδαγωγικά αξιώματα και ευθυγραμμίζεται με τους μαθησιακούς στόχους της σχολικής εκπαίδευσης στην Ινδία. Για να γίνει ένα ολοκληρωμένο γλωσσικό εργαλείο, κωδικοποιήθηκαν και οι γραμματικές πληροφορίες, στο βαθμό που μπορούν να επισημανθούν στα λεξικά στοιχεία. Η παροχή πληροφοριών είναι πολυεπίπεδη, πολυαισθητηριακή και διατίθεται σε πολλαπλές ψηφιακές πλατφόρμες. Το μπροστινό άκρο έχει σχεδιαστεί για να προσφέρει μια ελκυστική φιλική προς το χρήστη διεπαφή η οποία είναι κατάλληλη για μαθητές που αρχίζουν από την ηλικία έξι ετών και μετά. Έχει γίνει προκαταρκτική δοκιμή του εργαλείου και έχει τροποποιηθεί σύμφωνα με τις ανατροφοδοτήσεις που ελήφθησαν. Πάνω απ 'όλα, ολόκληρη η άσκηση έχει προσφέρει κερδοσκοπικές γνώσεις για τη μάθηση που βασίζεται σε συσχετιστικά δίκτυα και πώς η γνώση που βασίζεται σε αυτά τα δίκτυα μπορεί να καταστεί διαθέσιμη στους σύγχρονους μαθητές.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo riporta il lavoro relativo alla messa a disposizione di Hindi Wordnet1 come risorsa digitale per l'apprendimento e l'insegnamento delle lingue, nonché le esperienze e le lezioni apprese durante il processo. I dati linguistici del Wordnet Hindi sono stati opportunamente modificati e migliorati per farne un aiuto per l'apprendimento delle lingue. Questo aiuto si basa su assiomi pedagogici moderni ed è allineato agli obiettivi di apprendimento dei programmi di istruzione scolastica in India. Per farne uno strumento linguistico completo, sono state codificate anche le informazioni grammaticali, nella misura in cui queste possono essere contrassegnate sugli elementi lessicali. La fornitura di informazioni è multistrato, multisensoriale ed è disponibile su più piattaforme digitali. Il front-end è stato progettato per offrire un'interfaccia user-friendly accattivante che è adatta per gli studenti a partire dai sei anni di età. Test preliminari dello strumento è stato fatto ed è stato modificato secondo i feedback ricevuti. Soprattutto, l'intero esercizio ha offerto spunti utili sull'apprendimento basato su reti associative e su come le conoscenze basate su tali reti possano essere messe a disposizione degli studenti moderni.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз Hindi Wordnet1 тілдерді оқыту мен оқыту үшін цифрлық ресурс ретінде жұмыс жұмысын жұмыс істейді, жұмыс кезінде оқылған тәжірибелер мен сабақтар ретінде. Hindi Wordnet тілінің деректері дұрыс өзгертілген және тіл оқыту көмегімен өзгертілген. Бұл көмек қазіргі педагогикалық асиемдеріне негізделген және Индиядағы мектепті білім беру мақсаттарына тең. Бұны толық тіл құралы болу үшін грамматикалық мәліметтер қолданылады, егер олар лексикалық нысандарда белгілене алады. Мәліметті бірнеше қабатты, көп сезімді жіберу және бірнеше цифрлық платформалардың арқылы қол жеткізеді. Алты жастан басталатын оқытушылар үшін көздерді қарау интерфейсін көрсету үшін құрылған. Құрылғының алдыңғы сынауы жасалған және ол қабылдаған қайталанулар ретінде өзгертілді. Барлық жұмыс істеу үшін қалай білім желіне негізделген оқытуға және қалай білім желіне негізделген оқытуға арналған түсініктер берді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_hu>A tanulmány a Hindi Wordnet1 digitális nyelvtanulási és oktatási forrásként való elérhetővé tételével kapcsolatos munkát, valamint a folyamat során elsajátított tapasztalatokat és leckéket mutatja be. A Hindi Wordnet nyelvi adatait megfelelően módosították és továbbfejlesztették, hogy nyelvtanulási segédeszközzé tegyék. Ez a segítségnyújtás modern pedagógiai axiómákon alapul, és összhangban van az indiai iskolai oktatás tanterveinek tanulási célkitűzéseivel. Annak érdekében, hogy átfogó nyelvi eszközzé váljon, nyelvtani információkat is kódoltak, amennyiben ezek a lexikai elemeken jelölhetők. Az információk továbbítása többrétegű, többszenzoros és több digitális platformon is elérhető. Az előlapot úgy tervezték, hogy figyelemfelkeltő, felhasználóbarát felületet kínáljon, amely hat éves kortól kezdődő tanulók számára alkalmas. A szerszám előzetes tesztelését elvégeztük, és a kapott visszajelzések alapján módosítottuk. Mindenekelőtt az egész gyakorlat nyereséges betekintést nyújtott az asszociatív hálózatokon alapuló tanulásba és arról, hogy az ilyen hálózatokon alapuló tudás hogyan lehet a modern tanulók számára elérhetővé tenni.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente pateikiamas darbas, susijęs su Hindi Wordnet1 prieinamumu kaip skaitmeninis kalbų mokymosi ir mokymo šaltinis, taip pat patirtis ir patirtis, įgyta proceso metu. The language data of the Hindi Wordnet has been suitably modified and enhanced to make it into a language learning aid.  Ši pagalba grindžiama šiuolaikinėmis pedagoginėmis ašiomis ir suderinama su mokyklinio švietimo stipendijų Indijoje mokymosi tikslais. Kad ji taptų visapusiška kalbų priemonė, taip pat buvo koduota gramatinė informacija, kiek ji gali būti pažymėta tekstiniuose straipsniuose. Informacijos teikimas yra daugiasluoksnis, daugiasluoksnis ir prieinamas įvairiose skaitmeninėse platformose. Priekinė sąsaja sukurta taip, kad būtų įdomi naudotojui palanki sąsaja, tinkama mokiniams nuo šešių metų amžiaus. Išankstinis priemonių bandymas buvo atliktas ir jis buvo pakeistas atsižvelgiant į gautus duomenis. Visų pirma, visa ši veikla suteikė naudingą žinią apie asociaciniais tinklais grindžiamą mokymąsi ir apie tai, kaip šiuolaikiniams besimokantiems asmenims gali būti prieinamos tokiomis žiniomis grindžiamos žinios.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Kertas ini melaporkan kerja berkaitan dengan membuat Hindi Wordnet1 tersedia sebagai sumber digital untuk belajar dan mengajar bahasa, dan pengalaman dan pelajaran yang telah belajar semasa proses. Data bahasa dari Hindi Wordnet telah diubahsuai dan diperbaiki dengan sesuai untuk membuatnya menjadi bantuan pembelajaran bahasa. Bantuan ini berdasarkan aksiom pedagogi modern dan disesuaikan dengan tujuan pembelajaran syllabi pendidikan sekolah di India. Untuk membuatnya menjadi alat bahasa yang meliputi, maklumat grammatik juga telah dikodekan, sejauh ini boleh ditandai pada item leksikal. Penghantaran maklumat berbilang lapisan, berbilang-sensori dan tersedia melalui platform digital berbilang. Bahagian depan telah dirancang untuk menawarkan antaramuka yang menyeronokkan pengguna yang sesuai untuk pelajar bermula dari umur enam tahun ke depan. Ujian awal alat telah dilakukan dan ia telah diubahsuai mengikut balas balik yang diterima. Terutama-utama, seluruh latihan telah menawarkan pandangan yang berguna dalam pembelajaran berdasarkan rangkaian asosiatif dan bagaimana pengetahuan berdasarkan rangkaian tersebut boleh dibuat tersedia untuk pelajar modern.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jirrapporta l-ħidma relatata mat-tqegħid għad-dispożizzjoni tal-Hindi Wordnet1 bħala riżorsa diġitali għat-tagħlim u t-tagħlim tal-lingwi, u l-esperjenzi u l-lezzjonijiet li ttieħdu matul il-proċess. Id-dejta tal-lingwa tal-Hindi Wordnet ġiet modifikata u mtejba kif xieraq biex issir għajnuna għat-tagħlim tal-lingwi. Din l-għajnuna hija bbażata fuq assiomi pedagoġiċi moderni u hija allinjata mal-għanijiet tat-tagħlim tas-sillabi tal-edukazzjoni skolastika fl-Indja. Biex issir għodda lingwistika komprensiva, l-informazzjoni grammatika ġiet ikkodifikata wkoll, safejn dawn jistgħu jiġu mmarkati fuq l-oġġetti lexiċi. It-twassil tal-informazzjoni huwa multisaff, multisensorju u huwa disponibbli minn pjattaformi diġitali multipli. It-tarf ta’ quddiem ġie ddisinjat biex joffri interfaċċja faċli għall-utent li taqbad l-għajnejn li hija adattata għal dawk li jitgħallmu li jibdew minn sitt snin ’il quddiem. Sar ittestjar preliminari tal-għodda u ġiet modifikata skont ir-reazzjonijiet li waslu. Fuq kollox, l-eżerċizzju kollu offra fehmiet profittabbli fit-tagħlim ibbażat fuq netwerks assoċjattivi u kif l-għarfien ibbażat fuq netwerks bħal dawn jista’ jkun disponibbli għal studenti moderni.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас Хинди Wordnet1-г хэлний суралцах, багш суралцах, болон үйл явцдаа сурсан туршлага, хичээл болон хичээл болгон тоон боловсруулах боломжтой ажлыг тайлбарладаг. Хинди Wordnet-ийн хэл өгөгдлийн мэдээлэл нь хэл суралцах тусламжтай болгон зөвхөн өөрчлөгдсөн бөгөөд нэмэгдүүлсэн. Энэ тусламжтай нь орчин үеийн педагогик тэнхлэг дээр суурь боловсролын суралцах зорилготой юм. Үүнийг бүрэн хэл хэрэгсэл болгохын тулд грамматикийн мэдээлэл мөн шинэчлэгдсэн. Мэдээлэл нийлүүлэх нь олон давхар, олон мэдрэмжтэй бөгөөд олон дижитал платформууд дээр ашиглагддаг. Эхний төгсгөл нь 6 настайгаас эхлээд сурагчид хэрэглэгчийн найзуудтай интерфейсийг сануулахын тулд зориулагдсан. Эхлээд хэрэгсэл шалгалт хийгдсэн бөгөөд хүлээж авсан хариултын хувьд өөрчлөгдсөн. Эхлээд бүх дасгал хөдөлгөөн нь холбоотой сүлжээнд суралцах болон орчин үеийн суралцагчид хэрхэн мэдлэг хэрхэн ашиглах боломжтой талаар олж авсан.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret rapporterer arbeidet relatert til å gjera Hindi Wordnet1 tilgjengeleg som ein digital ressurs for språk læring og læring, og opplevelsane og leksjonar som ble lært under prosessen. Språkdatane til Hindi Wordnet er rett endra og forbetra for å gjera det til eit språk læringshjelp. Dette hjelpet er basert på moderne pedagogiske aksiom og er tilpassa til læringsmålsettinga til syllabi i skoleeutdanninga i India. For å gjera det i eit komplett språkkverktøy, er det også koda grammatiske informasjon, så langt dei kan markerast på dei leksiske elementa. Informasjonen er tilgjengeleg med fleire lag, fleire sensorer og er tilgjengeleg over fleire digital plattformer. Framgangspunktet er utforma for å tilbya eit brukargrensesnitt som er passande for lærarar som startar frå seks år framover. Førehandsvising av verktøyet er fullført og er endra som per tilbakemeldingar som vert motteken. Overalt har heile øvinga tilbyt gjennomsikt på læring basert på asosiativ nettverk og korleis kunnskap basert på slike nettverk kan gjerast tilgjengeleg for moderne lærarar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_mk>Овој весник известува за работата поврзана со поставувањето на Хинди Ворднет1 на располагање како дигитален ресурс за учење и предавање јазици, како и за искуствата и лекциите кои беа научени за време на процесот. Јазичките податоци на Хинди Ворднет се соодветно модификувани и подобрени за да станат помош за учење јазици. Оваа помош се базира на модерните педагошки аксиоми и се прилагодува на целите за учење на силабите на училишното образование во Индија. За да се претвори во сеопфатна јазичка алатка, граматичките информации се, исто така, кодирани, во колку што можат да бидат обележани на лексичките предмети. Предавањето информации е мултислоевно, мултисензорно и е достапно преку повеќе дигитални платформи. Интерфејсот е дизајниран со цел да понуди интерфејс привлечен за корисниците кој е соодветен за учениците од шест години натаму. Прелиминарното тестирање на алатката е направено и е модификувано според реакциите кои беа применети. Пред сé, целата вежба нуди добитни информации за учењето базирано на асоцијативните мрежи и како знаењето базирано на вакви мрежи може да биде достапно за модерните ученици.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł przedstawia prace związane z udostępnianiem słowa hinduskiego jako cyfrowego źródła do nauki i nauczania języków oraz doświadczenia i lekcje, które zostały wyciągnięte w trakcie tego procesu. Dane językowe słowa hindi zostały odpowiednio zmodyfikowane i ulepszone, aby stać się pomocą do nauki języka. Pomoc ta opiera się na nowoczesnych aksjomach pedagogicznych i jest dostosowana do celów uczenia się programów edukacji szkolnej w Indiach. Aby stać się kompleksowym narzędziem językowym, zakodowano również informacje gramatyczne, o ile można je zaznaczyć na elementach leksykalnych. Dostarczanie informacji jest wielowarstwowe, wielozymysłowe i dostępne na wielu platformach cyfrowych. Front end został zaprojektowany tak, aby zapewnić przyciągający wzrok interfejs, który jest odpowiedni dla uczących się od sześciu lat. Wstępne testy narzędzia zostały przeprowadzone i zostały zmodyfikowane zgodnie z otrzymanymi informacjami zwrotnymi. Przede wszystkim całe ćwiczenie dało zarobkowy wgląd w naukę opartą na sieciach asocjacyjnych oraz w jaki sposób wiedza oparta na takich sieciach może być udostępniana współczesnym uczniom.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ ഹിന്ദി വോര്‍ഡെറ്റ്1 ഭാഷ പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനും പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്ന അനുഭവങ്ങള്‍ക്കും പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്ന അനുഭവങ്ങള്‍ ഹിന്ദി വാര്‍ഡ്നെറ്റിന്റെ ഭാഷ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ശരിയായി മാറ്റിയിരിക്കുന്നു. അതിനെ ഭാഷ പഠിക്കുന്ന സഹായിയാക്കാ This aid is based on modern pedagogical axioms and is aligned to the learning objectives of the syllabi of the school education in India.  അതിനെ ഒരു പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായ ഭാഷ ഉപകരണത്തിലേക്കാക്കാന്‍ ഗ്രാമാട്ടിക്കല്‍ വിവരങ്ങളും എക്കോഡിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. ഇതിന്റെ  വിവരങ്ങളുടെ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഒരുപാട് സംഘടിപ്പിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു, പല-സെന്റരിയാണ്. പല ഡിജിറ്റല്‍ പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോമുകള ആറു വയസ്സുമുതല്‍ തുടങ്ങുന്ന പഠിക്കുന്നവര്‍ക്ക് പ്രയോജനമായ ഒരു കണ്ണ് പിടിക്കുന്ന ഉപയോക്താവിന്റെ സുഹൃത്തുക്കളുട ഉപകരണത്തിന്റെ ആദ്യ പരീക്ഷണം നടത്തിയിരിക്കുന്നു. പിന്നീട് ലഭിച്ചിരിക്കുന്ന പ്രതികരണങ്ങള്‍ക്കുള്ള പ് എല്ലാവര്‍ക്കും മുഴുവന്‍ പരിശീലനത്തിനും ആധുനിക ശിഷ്ഠര്‍ക്ക് എങ്ങനെയാണ് പഠിക്കാന്‍ കഴിയുന്നതെന്നും പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിന് മുഴ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_so>Warqaddaas wuxuu wargelinayaa shaqada la xiriira ka dhigista in Xindi Wordnet1 uu u helo asal diimeed oo ah luqada barashada iyo waxbarashada, iyo khibrada iyo waxbarashada lagu bartay xiliga. Macluumaadka luqada ee erayga Hindi waxaa loo beddelay si loo hagaajiyo caawimaad barashada afka. Kaalmadaas waxay ku saleysan tahay iskuul-xirfadeedka modern, waxaana lagu hagaajiyaa waxyaabaha barashada iskuulka ee India. Si uu uga dhigo qalabka luuqada aasaasiga ah, waxaa sidoo kale lagu qoray macluumaadka grammadaha, sida lagu calaamadeeyo alaabta lexicada. Wixii macluumaad lagu soo diro waa mid kala duduwan oo kala duduwan, oo waxaa laga heli karaa tallaalo kala duduwan oo kala duduwan. Ugu horraysa waxaa loo qoray in la siiyo Interfac la-qabsado oo la isticmaalayo, taasoo u haboon waxbarashada ka bilaabata lix sano. Waxaa la sameeyay imtixaanka hore ee qalabka, waxaana loo beddeliyey jawaabayaasha la aqbalay. Dhammaan jimicsigu waxey waxyaabo faa'iido leh u fidisay waxbarasho ku saleysan shabakada ururka iyo sidoo kale aqoonta lagu saleynayo shabakadahan iyo sidoo kale loo heli karo waxbarashada asalka ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare prezintă lucrările legate de punerea la dispoziție a limbii hindi Wordnet1 ca resursă digitală pentru învățarea și predarea limbilor străine, precum și experiențele și lecțiile învățate în timpul procesului. Datele lingvistice ale limbii hindi Wordnet au fost modificate și îmbunătățite corespunzător pentru a le transforma într-un ajutor de învățare a limbilor străine. Acest ajutor se bazează pe axiome pedagogice moderne și este aliniat la obiectivele de învățare ale programelor de învățământ școlar din India. Pentru a-l transforma într-un instrument lingvistic cuprinzător, informațiile gramaticale au fost, de asemenea, codificate, în măsura în care acestea pot fi marcate pe elementele lexicale. Furnizarea informațiilor este multistratificată, multisenzorială și este disponibilă pe mai multe platforme digitale. Partea frontală a fost concepută pentru a oferi o interfață prietenoasă și ușor de utilizat care este potrivită pentru cursanții începând cu vârsta de șase ani în sus. Testarea preliminară a uneltei a fost efectuată și a fost modificată conform feedback-urilor primite. Mai presus de toate, întregul exercițiu a oferit perspective profitabile asupra învățării bazate pe rețele asociative și modul în care cunoștințele bazate pe astfel de rețele pot fi puse la dispoziția cursanților moderni.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>මේ පැත්තේ හින්දි වර්ඩනට් 1 විදියට භාෂාව ඉගෙන ගන්න, ඉගෙන ගන්න, ඉගෙන ගන්න, සහ පරීක්ෂණය සහ පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා දැනගත්ත හ හින්දී වර්ඩනෙට්ගේ භාෂාව දත්ත හොඳටම වෙනස් කරලා තියෙනවා ඒක භාෂාව ඉගෙන ගන්න උදව් වෙනුවෙන්. මේ උදව් අධ්‍යාන්‍ය පෙඩාගෝගික් අක්ෂියෝම් වලට ආධාරිත වෙනවා ඒ වගේම ඉන්දියාවේ ඉස්කෝලේ ඉස්කෝලේ ඉස්කෝ ඒක සම්පූර්ණ භාෂා උපකරණයක් වෙනුවෙන්, ගර්මාතික තොරතුරු කොඩ් කරලා තියෙනවා, මේක ලෙක්සිකාල් අයිතියක් වලින තොරතුරු පිළිගන්න බොහොම ස්ථානයක්, බොහොම සංවේදනයක් තියෙනවා ඒ වගේම ගොඩක් ඩිජිටල් ප්ලේට්පර ප්‍රධාන අන්තිමය සැලසුම් කරලා තියෙන්නේ ප්‍රයෝජකයෙන් ප්‍රයෝජකයෙක් අල්ලගන්න පුළුවන් අන්තිමත් අන්ත උපකරණයේ ප්‍රධාන පරීක්ෂණය කරලා තියෙන්නේ ඒක ප්‍රධාන පරීක්ෂණය විසින් වෙනස් කරලා තියෙන්නේ. ඔක්කොම උඩින්, මුළු ප්‍රයෝජනය ප්‍රයෝජනය ප්‍රයෝජනය කරලා තියෙනවා සම්බන්ධ ජාලයේ අධාරිත ජාලයේ අධාරිත ජාලය</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir prijavljuje rad povezan sa činjenicom indijskih Wordnet1 dostupnim kao digitalni resurs za učenje jezika i učenje, i iskustva i lekcije koje su naučile tokom procesa. Podaci o jeziku indijskog Wordnet a odgovaraju modificirani su i poboljšani kako bi ga učinili u pomoć za učenje jezika. Ova pomoć se temelji na modernom pedagogičkom aksiomu i usklađuje se sa ciljevima učenja silabija školskog obrazovanja u Indiji. Da bi to učinio sveobuhvatnim jezičkim alatom, gramatičke informacije su takođe kodirane, koliko se to može označiti na leksičkim predmetima. Dostava informacija je višeslojna, višesenzorna i dostupna na višestrukim digitalnim platformama. Prednji kraj je dizajniran kako bi ponudio prijateljski interfejs za korisnike koji je odgovarajući učenicima koji počinju od šest godina dalje. Preliminarno testiranje alata je obavljeno i modificirano je po odnosima koje su primile. Uglavnom, cijela vježba je ponudila dobar uvid u učenje na osnovu asocijativnih mreža i kako znanja na temelju takvih mreža mogu biti dostupna modernim učenicima.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தில் Hindi Wordnet1 மொழி கற்றுக்கு மற்றும் கற்றுக்கொள்ளும் போது பயிற்சிகள் மற்றும் பயிற்சிக்கப்பட்ட அனுபவம் மற்றும் ப Hindi Wordnet மொழி தரவு சரியாக மாற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் அதை மொழி கற்றல் உதவியாக மாற்ற முடிக்கப்பட்டது. இந்த உதவி தற்போதைய பள்ளி கல்வி கல்வி கல்வியின் கல்வி சில்லாபிக்கு அடிப்படையாக இருக்கிறது மற்றும் இந்தியாவில் உள்ள கல்வி கல இதை ஒரு மொழி கருவியாக ஆக்க, சிறந்த தகவலும் குறியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது, இது லெக்சிக்சியல் உருப்படிகள் மீது குறியிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. தகவல் வழங்குதல் பல- அடுக்கு, பல- உணர்வு மற்றும் பல இலக்கங்கள் முழுவதும் கிடைக்கும். முன் முடிவு வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது ஆறு வயதிலிருந்து மாணவர்களுக்கு பொருத்தமான கண் பிடிக்கும் பயனர் இடைமுகத்தை வழங்கு கருவியின் முன்னிருப்பு சோதனை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது மற்றும் பெற்றுள்ள பதில்கள் போன்ற மாற்றப்பட்டது. மேலும், இந்த பயிற்சி முழுவதும் சம்பந்தமான வலைப்பின்னல்களை அடிப்படையில் கற்றுக்கொள்ளும் பார்வையை அளித்துள்ளது மற்றும் இவ்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>This paper reports the work related to making Hindi Wordnet1 available as a digital resource for language learning and teaching, and the experiences and lessons that were learned during the process. ہندی ورڈنیٹ کی زبان ڈیٹا ٹھیک طور پر بدل دیا گیا ہے اور اس کو ایک زبان سکھانے کی مدد بنانے کے لئے بہتر کیا گیا ہے. یہ مدد مدینہ مدینہ پڈاگوژیکل آکسیوم پر بنیاد ہے اور انڈیا میں سکول سکونٹ کی تعلیم کے سیکھنے کے موارد پر متصل ہے. اسے ایک گھیری زبان کے ابزار میں بنانے کے لئے، گراماتیکی معلومات بھی اکنود کر دی گئی ہے، جب تک یہ لکسیکی ابزار پر نشان دی جاتی ہیں. معلومات کے تحویل ملی لائر، ملی سنسور ہے اور بہت سی ڈیجیٹل پلٹروم پر موجود ہے. فرینٹ انتظام کی طراحی کی گئی ہے کہ ایک آنکھ پکڑنے والی کارساز دوستی انٹرنیفس پیش کرے جو چھ سال سے آغاز ہونے والوں کے لئے مناسب ہے. ابزار کی پہلی امتحان کر دی گئی ہے اور اس کو جو ملی گئی فیڈبک کے مطابق بدل دیا گیا ہے۔ سب سے زیادہ، تمام آزمائش نے شریک نیٹورک پر بنیاد رکھی ہے اور کس طرح ایسی نیٹورک پر بنیاد علم آزمائش کرنے والوں کے لئے موجود ہو سکتا ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats redogör för arbetet med att göra Hindi Wordnet1 tillgänglig som en digital resurs för språkinlärning och språkundervisning samt de erfarenheter och lärdomar som har lärts under processen. Språkuppgifterna i hindi Wordnet har modifierats och förbättrats på lämpligt sätt för att göra det till ett hjälpmedel för språkinlärning. Detta stöd är baserat på moderna pedagogiska axiom och är anpassat till lärandemålen i läroplanen för skolutbildningen i Indien. För att göra det till ett heltäckande språkverktyg har även grammatisk information kodats, såvida dessa kan markeras på lexikala poster. Leveransen av information är flerskiktig, multisensorisk och finns tillgänglig på flera digitala plattformar. Framsidan har utformats för att erbjuda ett iögonfallande användarvänligt gränssnitt som är lämpligt för elever från sex års ålder och framåt. Preliminärt test av verktyget har gjorts och det har ändrats enligt de återkopplingar som inkommit. Framför allt har hela övningen gett givande insikter i lärande baserat på associativa nätverk och hur kunskap baserad på sådana nätverk kan göras tillgänglig för moderna elever.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_uz>Bu qogʻoz Hindi Wordnet1 tilni o'rganish, o'rganish va o'rganish uchun raqamli resource, va jarayonda o'rganilgan tajriba va o'rganishlarni anglatadi. Hindiston soʻzlarining tili maʼlumotlari juda muhimiy oʻzgartirildi va uni tilni o'rganish yordam qilish uchun oshirilgan edi. Bu yordam yangi maktab o'qituvchisi asosida yaratilgan va Hindiston maktab ta'limning maqsadlariga bir qanday ishlaydi. Ularni butun til asbob qilish uchun grammatik maʼlumoti kodlash mumkin, ammo ularning leksikal elementlarini belgilash mumkin. Name Name Asboblarni birinchi sinov qilindi va qabul qilingan javoblar sifatida oʻzgartirildi. Bu hammasidan hamma ishlaydi, buni bir xil tarmoq tarmoqlarida o'rganishga qo'llab ko'rinadi, va bu tarmoqning asosida qanday o'rganishni yangi o'quvchilarga qo'llash mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này báo cáo công việc làm của Hindi Wordrể làm tài nguyên kỹ thuật số cho việc học và giảng dạy ngôn ngữ, và những kinh nghiệm và bài học được học trong quá trình đó. Thông tin ngôn ngữ của Hindley Wordet đã được chỉnh sửa và cải tiến thích hợp để biến nó thành hỗ trợ học ngôn ngữ. Sự hỗ trợ này dựa trên các chuyên gia giáo dục hiện đại và phù hợp với các mục tiêu học vấn trong giáo trình giáo dục ở Ấn Độ. Để biến nó thành một công cụ ngôn ngữ toàn diện, các thông tin ngữ pháp cũng đã được mã hóa, nếu có thể đánh dấu trên các mục văn bản. Thông tin được cung cấp đa lớp, đa cảm xúc và có thể cung cấp trên nhiều bục số. Phần trước được thiết kế để cung cấp một giao diện thông thạo để bắt mắt, phù hợp với học viên từ độ tuổi sáu tới. Việc thử nghiệm sơ bộ của công cụ đã được thực hiện và nó đã được thay đổi theo nguồn cung cấp được nhận. Trên hết, to àn bộ bài tập đã cung cấp một nguồn hiểu biết tích cực về học dựa trên mạng xã hội và làm thế nào để những học viên hiện đại có thể cung cấp kiến thức dựa trên mạng lưới đó.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir izvještava rad povezan s činjenicom indijskih Wordnet1 dostupnim kao digitalni resurs za učenje jezika i učenje, te iskustva i lekcije koje su naučile tijekom procesa. Podaci o jeziku Hindskog Wordnet a odgovarajuće su modificirani i poboljšani kako bi ga učinili u pomoć učenja jezika. Ova pomoć je temeljena na modernom pedagogičkom aksiumu i prilagođena je ciljevima učenja silabija školskog obrazovanja u Indiji. Da bi to učinio sveobuhvatnim jezičkim alatom, gramatičke informacije su također kodirane, koliko se to može označiti na leksičkim predmetima. Dostava informacija je višeslojna, višesenzorna i dostupna na višestrukim digitalnim platformama. Prednji kraj je dizajniran kako bi ponudio pogledno prijateljski interfejs korisnika koji je odgovaran učenicima koji počinju od šest godina dalje. Preliminarno testiranje alata je obavljeno i modificirano je po odnosima koje su primile. Uglavnom, cijela vježba je ponudila dobitni uvid u učenje na temelju asocijacijskih mreža i kako znanja na temelju takvih mreža mogu biti dostupna modernim učenicima.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия представя работата, свързана с предоставянето на хинди Wordnet1 като дигитален ресурс за изучаване и преподаване на езици, както и опита и уроците, придобити по време на процеса. Езиковите данни на хинди думи са подходящо модифицирани и подобрени, за да се превърне в помощно средство за изучаване на езици. Тази помощ се основава на съвременни педагогически аксиоми и е съобразена с учебните цели на учебната програма на училищното образование в Индия. За да се превърне в изчерпателен езиков инструмент, е кодирана и граматическа информация, доколкото тя може да бъде отбелязана върху лексикалните елементи. Доставката на информация е многопластова, многосетивна и е достъпна в множество дигитални платформи. Предният край е проектиран да предлага привлекателен и удобен за потребителя интерфейс, който е подходящ за ученици от шестгодишна възраст нататък. Предварително тестване на инструмента е направено и той е променен според получените обратни данни. Преди всичко цялото упражнение предложи доходоносни прозрения за ученето въз основа на асоциативни мрежи и как знанията въз основа на такива мрежи могат да бъдат предоставени на съвременните учащи.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>In dit artikel wordt verslag uitgebracht over het werk met betrekking tot het beschikbaar maken van Hindi Wordnet1 als digitale bron voor het leren en onderwijzen van talen, en over de ervaringen en lessen die tijdens het proces zijn geleerd. De taalgegevens van het Hindi Wordnet zijn aangepast en verbeterd om het tot een hulpmiddel voor het leren van talen te maken. Deze hulp is gebaseerd op moderne pedagogische axioma's en is afgestemd op de leerdoelen van de syllabi van het schoolonderwijs in India. Om er een uitgebreid taalhulpmiddel van te maken, is ook grammaticale informatie gecodeerd, voor zover deze kan worden gemarkeerd op de lexicale items. De levering van informatie is meerlaags, multisensorisch en beschikbaar op meerdere digitale platforms. De front-end is ontworpen om een opvallende gebruikersvriendelijke interface te bieden die geschikt is voor leerlingen vanaf zes jaar. Voorlopig testen van de tool is gedaan en het is gewijzigd volgens de feedback die werd ontvangen. De hele oefening heeft vooral winstgevende inzichten opgeleverd in leren op basis van associatieve netwerken en hoe kennis op basis van dergelijke netwerken beschikbaar kan worden gesteld aan moderne leerkrachten.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel beskriver arbejdet i forbindelse med at gøre hindi Wordnet1 tilgængelig som en digital ressource til sproglæring og undervisning samt de erfaringer og erfaringer, der blev lært i løbet af processen. Sprogdataene i hindi Wordnet er blevet tilstrækkeligt modificeret og forbedret til at gøre det til et sproglæringshjælpemiddel. Denne hjælp er baseret på moderne pædagogiske aksiomer og er tilpasset læringsmålsætningerne for skoleundervisningen i Indien. For at gøre det til et omfattende sprogværktøj er grammatisk information også blevet kodet, for så vidt disse kan mærkes på de leksikologiske punkter. Leveringen af oplysninger er multi-lags, multi-sensorisk og er tilgængelig på tværs af flere digitale platforme. Den forreste ende er designet til at tilbyde en iøjnefaldende brugervenlig grænseflade, som er velegnet til elever fra seks år og frem. Indledende test af værktøjet er blevet udført, og det er blevet ændret efter de feedback, der blev modtaget. Frem for alt har hele øvelsen givet indsigt i læring baseret på associative netværk, og hvordan viden baseret på sådanne netværk kan stilles til rådighed for moderne elever.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag berichtet über die Arbeit im Zusammenhang mit der Bereitstellung von Hindi Wordnet1 als digitale Ressource für Sprachenlernen und -unterricht sowie über die Erfahrungen und Lektionen, die während des Prozesses gelernt wurden. Die Sprachdaten des Hindi Wordnet wurden entsprechend modifiziert und erweitert, um es zu einer Sprachlernhilfe zu machen. Diese Hilfe basiert auf modernen pädagogischen Axiomen und ist auf die Lernziele der Lehrpläne der Schulbildung in Indien ausgerichtet. Um es zu einem umfassenden Sprachwerkzeug zu machen, wurden auch grammatische Informationen kodiert, soweit diese auf den lexikalischen Elementen markiert werden können. Die Bereitstellung von Informationen ist vielschichtig, multisensorisch und über mehrere digitale Plattformen verfügbar. Das Frontend wurde entwickelt, um eine auffällige benutzerfreundliche Oberfläche zu bieten, die für Lernende ab sechs Jahren geeignet ist. Das Tool wurde vorab getestet und gemäß den erhaltenen Rückmeldungen modifiziert. Vor allem bot die gesamte Übung gewinnbringende Einblicke in das Lernen auf Basis assoziativer Netzwerke und wie Wissen auf Basis solcher Netzwerke modernen Lernenden zugänglich gemacht werden kann.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ گزارش می‌دهد که کار ارتباط با تبدیل کردن Wordnet1 هندی را به عنوان یک منبع دیجیتال برای یادگیری و آموزش زبان، و تجربه‌ها و درس‌هایی که در طول فرایند یاد گرفته بودند. داده‌های زبان هندی Wordnet به طور مناسب تغییر داده شده و به طور بالاتر تغییر داده شده است تا آن را به یک کمک یادگیری زبان تبدیل کند. این کمک بر اساس آکسیوم پدیاگوژی مدرن است و به هدف یادگیری سیلابی تحصیل مدرسه در هند متصل شده است. برای ساختن آن به وسیله زبان کلی، اطلاعات گرامیک همچنین رمز شده است، تا زمانی که این‌ها می‌توانند بر وسیله‌های زبان نشان داده شود. تحويل دادن اطلاعات با طبقه‌هاي متعدد، متعدد حسور است و در طريق چندتا platformهاي ديجيتال موجود است. پایان جلوی طراحی شده است برای پیشنهاد interface ی که از شش سالگی به بعد می‌رسد برای دانش آموزان مناسب است. آزمایش اولیه ابزار انجام شده و به عنوان پشتیبانی که دریافت شده تغییر داده شده است. بالاخره، کل تمرین به یادگیری بر روی شبکه های شریک و چگونه دانش بر روی این شبکه ها می تواند برای دانش آموزان مدرن در دسترس قرار دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini melaporkan pekerjaan yang berhubungan dengan membuat Hindi Wordnet1 tersedia sebagai sumber daya digital untuk belajar dan mengajar bahasa, dan pengalaman dan pelajaran yang telah dipelajari selama prosesnya. The language data of the Hindi Wordnet has been suitably modified and enhanced to make it into a language learning aid.  This aid is based on modern pedagogical axioms and is aligned to the learning objectives of the syllabi of the school education in India.  Untuk membuatnya menjadi alat bahasa komprensif, informasi grammatik juga telah dikodeksi, sejauh ini dapat ditandai pada item lexik. Pengiriman informasi adalah multi-lapisan, multi-sensor dan tersedia melalui berbagai platform digital. Bagian depan telah dirancang untuk menawarkan antaramuka yang menyenangkan pengguna yang cocok untuk para pelajar mulai dari usia enam tahun ke depan. Pengujian awal dari alat telah dilakukan dan telah diubah sesuai dengan balasan yang diterima. Terutama-utama, seluruh latihan telah menawarkan pandangan yang berguna dalam belajar berdasarkan jaringan asosiasi dan bagaimana pengetahuan berdasarkan jaringan tersebut dapat dibuat tersedia untuk para pelajar modern.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 인도어 Wordnet1을 언어 학습과 교육의 디지털 자원으로 하는 것과 이 과정에서 얻은 경험과 교훈을 보고한다.인디언 워드넷의 언어 데이터는 적당한 수정과 강화를 거쳐 언어 학습 보조 도구가 되었다.이 지원은 현대 교육학 원리를 바탕으로 인도 학교 교육 요강의 학습 목표와 일치한다.종합적인 언어 도구가 되기 위해 문법 정보도 어휘 항목에 표시될 수만 있다면 인코딩된다.정보의 전달은 다차원적이고 감각적이어서 여러 개의 디지털 플랫폼을 뛰어넘어 진행할 수 있다.전단 디자인은 사람들의 주목을 끄는 사용자 친선 인터페이스를 제공하여 6세 이상의 학습자에게 적용된다.이미 도구의 초보적인 테스트를 완성하였으며, 받은 피드백에 따라 수정하였다.가장 중요한 것은 전체 연습은 연상 네트워크를 바탕으로 하는 학습과 이런 네트워크를 바탕으로 하는 지식을 현대 학습자에게 어떻게 제공하는지에 유익한 견해를 제공했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Gazeti hili linaripoti kazi zinazohusiana na kufanya kazi ya Kihindi Wordnet1 kama rasilimali ya kidigitali kwa ajili ya kujifunza na kufundisha lugha, na uzoefu na masomo yaliyojifunza wakati wa mchakato huo. Takwimu za lugha za neno la Kihindi imebadilishwa na kuboreshwa ili kuifanya kuwa misaada ya kujifunza lugha. Msaada huu unategemea misaada ya kisasa na inaunganishwa na malengo ya elimu ya shule nchini India. To make it into a comprehensive language tool, grammatical information has also been encoded, as far as these can be marked on the lexical items.  The delivery of information is multi-layered, multi-sensory and is available across multiple digital platforms.  Mwisho wa mbele umetengenezwa kutoa sura ya mtumiaji anayetangalia macho yenye urafiki na ambayo inafaa kwa wanafunzi kuanzia kuanzia umri wa sita. Ujaribu wa awali wa zana hiyo umefanyika na imebadilishwa kwa mujibu wa majibu yaliyopokea. Zaidi ya yote, zoezi hili limetoa mitazamo yenye ufanisi katika kujifunza kwa kutumia mitandao ya ushirika na jinsi maarifa yanavyoweza kupatikana kwa wanafunzi wa kisasa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument raporton punën lidhur me bërjen e disponueshme të Hindi Wordnet1 si një burim dixhital për mësimin dhe mësimin e gjuhës dhe përvojat dhe mësimet që u mësuan gjatë procesit. Të dhënat e gjuhës së Hindi Wordnet janë modifikuar dhe përmirësuar në mënyrë të përshtatshme për t'i bërë a to në një ndihmë për mësimin e gjuhës. Kjo ndihmë bazohet në aksiomet pedagogjikë moderne dhe është e përputhur me objektivat e mësimit të sillabeve të arsimit shkollor në Indi. Për ta bërë atë në një mjet të përgjithshëm gjuhësh, informacioni grammatik është koduar gjithashtu, deri sa këto mund të shënohen në elementet lexike. The delivery of information is multi-layered, multi-sensory and is available across multiple digital platforms.  Faqja e përparme është dizajnuar për të ofruar një interfaqe miqësore me përdoruesit që është e përshtatshme për nxënësit që fillojnë nga mosha gjashtë vjeç e tutje. Testimi paraprak i mjetit është bërë dhe është modifikuar sipas reagimeve që janë marrë. Mbi të gjitha, e gjithë ushtrimi ka ofruar kuptime të fitueshme në mësimin bazuar në rrjetet shoqëruese dhe se si njohuritë bazuar në rrjete të tilla mund të bëhen në dispozicion për mësuesit modern ë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz Hindi Wordnet1 dilini öwrenmek we öwrenmek üçin digital çeşmeler bolmagyny we öwrenmek üçin bilinen tecrübeleri we sapaklary ulanýandygyny bildirýär. Hindi Wordnet'iň dil maglumaty gowy üýtgedilen we muny dil öwrenmegi kömegine üýtgetmek üçin bejerilip üýtgedildi. Bu kömek modern pedagogiýaly asymlara daýanýar we Hindistanyň mekdep biliniň syllabi ýasynyň amaçlaryna düzüldir. Onu bütin bir dil araçysyna görkezmek üçin gramatik maglumaty hem kodlandyryldy çünki bunlar lektik elementlerde işaretlenebilir. Maglumaty teslimatdyr birnäçe gatlakly, birnäçe sensorçy we birnäçe dijital platformlaryň içinde bar. Öňki soňky 6 ýaşyndan bäri öwrenmeklere üçin göz önüne göz önüne görýän interface teklip etmek üçin tasarlanýar. Esbap zolakynyň öňki synagy bitirildi we ol alan netijesi bilen üýtgedildi. Hemme zadyň üstünde, bütin egzam ortaklyk şebekelere daýanýan öwrenmeleri we şu şebekelere daýanýan bilim häzirki öwrenmelere mümkin edilebilir.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier rapporteer die werk wat verwante is om Hindi Wordnet1 te maak beskikbaar as 'n digitale hulpbron vir taal leer en leer, en die erfarings en leers wat onder die proses geleer is. Die taal data van die Hindi Wordnet is geskik gewysig en verbeter om dit in 'n taal leer hulp te maak. Hierdie hulp is gebaseer op moderne pedagogiese aksiome en is aligned to the learning objectives of the syllabi of the school education in India. Om dit in 'n kompleksief taal nutsprogram te maak, is grammatiese inligting ook gekodeer, sodat dit op die leksiese items kan merk word. Die verskaffing van inligting is multilaag, multisensoreer en is beskikbaar oor veelvuldige digitale platforme. Die voorkant einde is ontwerp om 'n oog-vangende gebruiker-vriendelike koppelvlak te bied wat geskik is vir lêers wat begin van ses ouderdom aan. Vorige toets van die hulpmiddel is gedoen en dit is verander as per die terugmelding wat ontvang is. Op alles het die hele oefening verskaf geweldige insig in die leer gebaseer op asosiasielike netwerke en hoe kennis gebaseer op sodanige netwerke kan beskikbaar word vir moderne leerners.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>ይህ ገጽ የኪንዲ Wordnet1 ስራ ለቋንቋ ትምህርት እና ትምህርት እና በፕሮጀክት ውስጥ የተማሩት ስህተትና ትምህርት የተገኘውን የዲጂተል resource እና ትምህርት ማድረግ የሚያስገኘውን ሥራ ያስታውቃል፡፡ የHindi ቃላት የቋንቋ ዳታዎች በቋንቋ ትምህርት እርዳታ ለማድረግ ተሻግሮአል፡፡ ይህ እርዳታ የአሁኑን የትምህርት ትምህርት ትምህርት ትምህርት ትምህርት ዕቅድ ላይ ነው፡፡ የቋንቋ ቋንቋ ጥናት ለማድረግ፣ የgrammatical መረጃ ደግሞ ሆኖአል፡፡ The delivery of information is multi-layered, multi-sensory and is available across multiple digital platforms.  የፊተኛውም ፍጻሜ ከስድስት ዓመት ጀምሮ ለተማሪዎቹ የሚጠቅመውን የዓይን-ተማሪ-ወዳጅ interface ለማሳየት ነው፡፡ የመጀመሪያ መፈትሄ የመስሪያው መፈተኛ ተደርጎአል እና እንደተቀበለው መልስ ተለውጦአል፡፡ ከሁሉም በላይ ጉዳዩ ሁሉም በአዲስ ተማሪዎች ላይ እንዴት እውቀት እንዲችል ይችላል በማድረግ ለመማር የሚያስፈልገውን ሀብታሞች አቀረበ፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt Hindi Wordnet1 dillərin öyrənməsi və öyrənməsi üçün dijital resursu olaraq, həmçinin öyrəndiyi təcrübələri və dərsələri ilə əlaqəsizlik edir. Hindi Wordnet dillərin verilənləri düzgün dəyişdirilmiş və onu dil öyrənməsi köməyinə çevirmək üçün daha yaxşı dəyişdirilmişdir. Bu kömək modern pedagojik axiomlarına dayanılır və Hindistandakı məktəb təhsilinin silabisinin öyrənməsi məqsədilə uyğunlaşdırılır. Onu bütün dil vasitəsinə çevirmək üçün, qrammatik məlumatlar də kodlanmışdır, laksici məlumatlar üzərində işarə edilənlərə qədər. Malümatın təbliğ edilməsi çoxlu, çoxlu sensor və çoxlu dijital platformların arasında faydalanır. Ön sonu altı yaşından sonra başlayan öyrənənənlərə uyğun bir istifadəçi dostu interfejsini təbliğ etmək üçün hazırlanmışdır. Bu vasitədən əvvəlki imtahana çəkildi və alınan feedback kimi dəyişdirildi. Həqiqətən, bütün təcrübə ortaq ağlara dayanan öyrənməyə və böyük ağlara dayanan bilgilər moderni öyrənənənlərə necə faydalanacaqlarını öyrəndi.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>এই কাগজটি জানাচ্ছে যে হিন্দি ওয়ার্ডনেট১ ভাষা শিক্ষা ও শিক্ষার জন্য ডিজিটাল সম্পদ হিসেবে পাওয়া যাচ্ছে, আর এই প্রক্রিয়ার সময় যে অভিজ The language data of the Hindi Wordnet has been suitably modified and enhanced to make it into a language learning aid.  এই সাহায্য আধুনিক শিক্ষাগত এক্সিওমের উপর ভিত্তিক এবং ভারতের স্কুল শিক্ষার্থীর শিক্ষার উদ্দেশ্যে একত্রিত হয়। এটিকে একটি সম্পূর্ণ ভাষার টুল হিসেবে পরিণত করার জন্য গ্রাম্যাটিক্যাল তথ্য এনকোড করা হয়েছে, যেহেতু লেক্সিক্যাল আইটেমগুলো তথ্য প্রদান করা হচ্ছে বহুসংখ্যা, বহুসংবেদনশীল এবং বেশ কয়েকটি ডিজিটাল প্ল্যাটফর্ম জুড়ে পাওয়া যায়। প্রাথমিক শেষের জন্য একটি চোখ-আচ্ছাদিত ব্যবহারকারী বন্ধুত্বপূর্ণ ইন্টারফেস প্রদান করার জন্য ডিজাইন করা হয়েছে যা ছয় বছর বয়স থ টুলের প্রাথমিক পরীক্ষা করা হয়েছে এবং প্রতিক্রিয়া প্রদান করা হয়েছে সেটি পরিবর্তন করা হয়েছে। সবচেয়ে বেশীর ভিত্তিতে এই পুরো অনুশীলন আধুনিক শিক্ষার্থীদের ক্ষেত্রে শিক্ষা প্রদান করেছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj novinar izvještava rad povezan s obzirom na to da Hindi Wordnet1 bude dostupan kao digitalni resurs za učenje jezika i učenje, te iskustva i lekcije koje su naučile tijekom procesa. Podaci o jeziku Hindskog Wordnet a odgovaraju modificirani su i poboljšani kako bi ga učinili u pomoć učenja jezika. Ova pomoć se temelji na modernom pedagogičkom aksiumu i usklađuje se sa ciljevima učenja silabija školskog obrazovanja u Indiji. Da bi to učinio sveobuhvatnim jezičkim alatom, gramatičke informacije su također kodirane, koliko se to može označiti na leksičkim predmetima. Dostava informacija je višeslojna, višesenzorna i dostupna na višestrukim digitalnim platformama. Prednji kraj je dizajniran kako bi ponudio pogledni interfejs koji je prikladan za učenike koji počinju od šest godina dalje. Preliminarno testiranje alata je obavljeno i modificirano je po odnosima koje su primile. Uglavnom, cijela vježba je ponudila dobitni uvid u učenje na temelju asocijacijskih mreža i kako znanja na temelju takvih mreža mogu biti dostupna modernim učenicima.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek popisuje práci týkající se zpřístupnění hindského slovíčka jako digitálního zdroje pro výuku a výuku jazyků a zkušenosti a lekce, které byly získány během procesu. Jazyková data Hindštiny Wordnetu byla vhodně upravena a vylepšena tak, aby se stala pomůckou pro výuku jazyků. Tato pomoc je založena na moderních pedagogických axiomech a je sladěna s učebními cíli osnov školního vzdělávání v Indii. Aby se z něj stal komplexní jazykový nástroj, byly také kódovány gramatické informace, pokud je lze označit na lexikálních položkách. Poskytování informací je vícevrstvé, vícesmyslové a je dostupné napříč několika digitálními platformami. Přední konec byl navržen tak, aby nabízel poutavé uživatelsky přívětivé rozhraní, které je vhodné pro studenty od šesti let dále. Bylo provedeno předběžné testování nástroje a byl upraven podle obdržených zpětných vazeb. Celé cvičení nabízí především výdělečné poznatky o učení založeném na asociativních sítích a o tom, jak mohou být znalosti založené na těchto sítích zpřístupněny moderním studentům.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>This paper reports the work related to making Hindi Wordnet1 available as a digital resource for language learning and teaching, and the experiences and lessons that were learnt during the process.  Les dades de llenguatge de la Hindi Wordnet s'han modificat i millorat de manera adequada per convertir-la en una ajuda d'aprenentatge de llenguatges. This aid is based on modern pedagogical axioms and is aligned to the learning objectives of the syllabi of the school education in India.  Per convertir-la en una eina de llenguatge completa, també s'ha codificat la informació gramàtica, fins que es poden marcar en els articles lèxics. The delivery of information is multi-layered, multi-sensory and is available across multiple digital platforms.  La frontera ha estat dissenyada per oferir una interfície aconseguible per a l'usuari que és adequada per als alumnes que comencen des de sis anys. S'ha fet un examen preliminar de l'eina i s'ha modificat segons els feedback que van rebre. Abans de tot, tot l'exercici ha oferit comprensions beneficioses sobre l'aprenentatge basat en xarxes associatives i com el coneixement basat en aquestes xarxes pot ser disponible als alumnes moderns.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas dokumendis kirjeldatakse hindi sõna kättesaadavaks tegemist keeleõppe ja -õpetamise digitaalse ressursina ning protsessi käigus saadud kogemusi ja õppetunde. Hindi keeleandmeid on sobivalt muudetud ja täiustatud, et muuta see keeleõppe abivahendiks. See abi põhineb kaasaegsetel pedagoogilistel aksioomidel ja on kooskõlas India koolihariduse õppekavade õppeeesmärkidega. Selleks, et muuta see terviklikuks keeletööriistaks, on kodeeritud ka grammatiline teave, kuivõrd neid saab märkida leksikaalsetele elementidele. Teabe edastamine on mitmekihiline, mitmekihiline ja saadaval mitmel digitaalsel platvormil. Esiosa on loodud pakkuma pilkupüüdvat kasutajasõbralikku liidest, mis sobib õppijatele alates kuuendast eluaastast. Tööriista esialgne testimine on tehtud ja seda on muudetud vastavalt saadud tagasisidele. Eelkõige on kogu harjutus pakkunud tulusat ülevaadet assotsiatsioonivõrgustikel põhinevast õppimisest ja sellest, kuidas sellistel võrgustikel põhinevad teadmised kaasaegsetele õppijatele kättesaadavaks teha.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa kerrotaan hindi-sana1:n käyttöönotosta digitaalisena resurssina kielten oppimiseen ja opettamiseen sekä prosessin aikana saaduista kokemuksista ja opetuksista. Hindi Wordnetin kielitietoja on muokattu ja parannettu sopivasti kieltenoppimisen apuvälineeksi. Tämä tuki perustuu nykyaikaisiin pedagogisiin aksioomiin ja on linjattu Intian kouluopetuksen opetussuunnitelmien oppimistavoitteisiin. Jotta siitä tulisi kattava kielityökalu, on myös koodattu kieliopillinen tieto, sikäli kuin ne voidaan merkitä sanastoon. Tiedonanto on monikerroksista, moniaistista ja sitä on saatavilla useilla digitaalisilla alustoilla. Etuosa on suunniteltu tarjoamaan katseenvangitseva käyttäjäystävällinen käyttöliittymä, joka sopii oppijoille kuusivuotiaasta lähtien. Työkalun alustava testaus on tehty ja sitä on muokattu saatujen palautteiden mukaisesti. Ennen kaikkea koko harjoitus on tarjonnut ansiokasta tietoa assosiatiivisiin verkostoihin pohjautuvasta oppimisesta ja siitä, miten näihin verkostoihin pohjautuva tieto voidaan tuoda nykyaikaisten oppijoiden saataville.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_hy>This paper reports the work related to making Hindi Wordnet1 available as a digital resource for language learning and teaching, and the experiences and lessons that were learnt during the process.  The language data of the Hindi Wordnet has been suitably modified and enhanced to make it into a language learning aid.  Այս օգնությունը հիմնված է ժամանակակից pedagoգիական աքսիոմների վրա և համապատասխանում է Հնդկաստանի դպրոցական կրթության ուսումնական նպատակներին: Որպեսզի այն դառնա ընդհանուր լեզվի գործիք, գրամատիկ ինֆորմացիան նաև կոդավորվել է, քանի որ դրանք կարող են նշանվել լեքսիկական տարրերի վրա: Տեղեկատվությունը բազմաշերտ, բազմազգայական է և հասանելի է բազմաթիվ թվային հարթակներում: The front end has been designed to offer an eye-catching user-friendly interface which is suitable for learners starting from age six onward.  Գործիքի նախարդական փորձարկումը կատարվել է և այն փոխվել է ըստ ստացած արձագանքների: Նախ և առաջ, ամբողջ գործընթացը օգտակար ընկալումներ է առաջարկել սովորելու համար, որը հիմնված է ասոցատիվ ցանցերի վրա, և ինչպես գիտելիքները, հիմնված նման ցանցերի վրա, կարող են հասանելի դարձնել ժամանակակից սովորողներին:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku so prikazane delo, povezano z zagotavljanjem dostopnosti hindijske besedi1 kot digitalnega vira za učenje in poučevanje jezikov, ter izkušnje in lekcije, pridobljene med procesom. Jezikovni podatki hindijske besede so bili ustrezno spremenjeni in izboljšani, da bi bili pripomočki za učenje jezikov. Ta pomoč temelji na sodobnih pedagoških aksiomih in je usklajena z učnimi cilji učnega načrta šolskega izobraževanja v Indiji. Za celovito jezikovno orodje so bile kodirane tudi slovnične informacije, kolikor jih je mogoče označiti na leksikalnih elementih. Dobava informacij je večplastna, večsenzorična in je na voljo na več digitalnih platformah. Sprednji del je zasnovan tako, da ponuja privlačen uporabniku prijazen vmesnik, ki je primeren za učence od šestih let naprej. Opravljeno je bilo predhodno testiranje orodja in je bilo spremenjeno glede na prejete povratne informacije. Predvsem je celotna vaja ponudila pridobljene vpoglede v učenje na podlagi asociativnih mrež in kako je znanje na podlagi teh mrež na voljo sodobnim učencem.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>העיתון הזה דווח על העבודה הקשורה להפעילה של הונדי וורדנט1 זמינה כמשאב דיגיטלי ללימוד ושפה ולמדה, והחוויות והשיעורים שנלמדו במהלך התהליך. נתוני השפה של הונדי וורדנט השתנו וממשתפרים בהתאם כדי להפוך אותו לסיוע ללמוד שפות. העזרה הזו מבוססת על אקסיומים pedagogic מודרניים ומתואמת למטרות הלימודים של סילבי החינוך בבית הספר בהודו. כדי להפוך אותו לתוך כלי שפה מכיל, מידע גרמטי גם היה מקודד, עד כמה אלה יכולים להיות מסמנים על פריטים הלקסיים. המשלוח של מידע הוא ממספר שכבות, ממספר חושים והוא זמין ברחבי מספר פלטפורמות דיגיטליות. הקצה הקדמי מעוצב כדי להציע ממשק ידידותי למשתמשים שמתאים ללמודים מתחילים בגיל שש ואילך. הבדיקה הקדמית של הכלי נעשה והיא הושנתה לפי התחזורים שקיבלו. מלבד הכל, כל התרגיל הציע תובנות מרוויחות ללמוד מבוססת על רשתות שותפות ואיך ידע מבוסס על רשתות כאלה יכול להיות זמין ללמודים מודרניים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>@ info An canza harshen da aka canza maganar Hinddi mai daidai kuma an ƙara shi dõmin ya zama mataimaki na karanta harshen. Wannan taimako ne a kan karatun axomi na yanzu kuma ana haɗa zuwa masu karatun da aka sanar da littãfin da ke cikin India. To, don ka sami shi zuwa wata zane na jumla cikin harshen, an kodi information grammatisk, kamar da za'a yi alama da su kan abubuwa na leksisi. Ana bãyar da shirin information yana da multi-layin, mai yawan-sensori kuma ana iya sami duk platformi masu yawa. An design ƙarshen gabani dõmin a nuna interfekt mai tsaro da idãnu, mai daidai wa masu lõkaci na fara ta tsohon shekara 6. An riga jarraba shirin ayuka da aka riga shi, kuma an canza shi kamar yadda aka motsa cewa masu motsa. Ga duk da yake, aikin wannan ya bãyar da gannai mai amfani zuwa a kan learning a kan zane-zane masu haɗi da zance a kan asansa da waɗancan garwaya masu yanzu.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Perintah iki bakal kelompok nggawe barang nggawe word net1 tentang kanggo ngilangno kelas digit kanggo ingkang alih lan ngregani, lan alam kuwi perintah lan lesalam kuwi wis kelas nèng Perintah kuwi. Awak dhèwèké kelangan kelangan nang Siti Word net iki adalah kanggo ngubah banjur nggawe ngubah lengkang bantuan. Banyak iki dadi sabanjur ning aksi pedanggé karo hal-sabanjur kanggo ngilanggar nggambar obaraning winih dhéwé ning acara dhéwé ning barang. Jejaring Laptop" and "Desktop FindOK First of the first testing of the tool is been rampung and it's been replaced as the first time by the information that was given. Lahke kabèh, akeh jênêmên minggu gawe lan ijêmên kuwi tindakan karo sistem sing asênêr kuwi tindakan tambah sing nyebutaké karo akèh netwisi iki bakal terus ngéwangi layar.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་བྱུང་བའི་རྩིས་ཐོག་ཏུ་Hindi Wordnet1 ཡི་སྒེར་གྱི་རྒྱབ་སྤྲོད་དང་། སྐད་རིགས་ཤེས་ཀྱི་ཆ་རྐྱེན་དང་། ལས་སྦྱོར་གྱི་pieredz་ དང་སྐད Hindi Wordnet ཡི་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་གི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་དེ་ལྟར་ཡར་བསྒྱུར་བཅོས་དང་འགྱུར་བྱས་ན་ཏེ། སྐད་རིགས་ཤེས་ཀྱི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་དང་། འདིས་རྒྱལ་ཁབ་འདི་ནི་moderག་གི་སློབ་ཆེན་གྱི་གནས་སྟངས་དང་ཕྱོགས་སྟེ་ རྒྱ་གར་གྱི་ཤེས་ཡོན་གྱི་དམིགས་ཡུལ་དང་མཐུན་སྒྲིག་ཡོད། སྐད་ཡིག་ལག་ཆ་ཞིག The delivery of information is multilayer, multi-sensory and is available across multiple digital platforms. མཐའ་མཇུག་ངོས་འཛིན་འདི་ལྟ་བུ་ཞིབ་ཡོད་པའི་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་མཐུད་སྣེ་འདྲ་བ་ཞིག་བྱིན་ཡོད། ལག་ཆས་ཀྱི་སྔོན་ལྟའི་བརྟག་ཞིབ་བྱེད་ཚར་བ། དེ་དག་ཐོབ་པའི་ངོས་ལབ་ཀྱི་རྗེས་སུ་ཞིབ་བཅུག་ཚར་བ Above all, the whole exercise has offered gainful insights into learning based on associative networks and how knowledge based on such networks can be made available to modern learners.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="41">
      <title>Enchancing the Collaborative Interlingual Index for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_humanities">Digital Humanities</a> : Cross-linguistic Analysis in the Domain of Theology</title>
      <author><first>Laura</first><last>Slaughter</last></author>
      <author><first>Wenjie</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis Morgado Da</first><last>Costa</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <pages>341–346</pages>
      <abstract>We aim to support <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_humanities">digital humanities</a> work related to the study of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religious_text">sacred texts</a>. To do this, we propose to build a cross-lingual wordnet within the do-main of theology. We target the Collaborative Interlingual Index (CILI) directly instead of each individual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a>. The paper presents background for this proposal : (1) an overview of concepts relevant to theology and (2) a summary of the domain-associated issues observed in the Princeton WordNet (PWN). We have found that definitions for concepts in this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_of_discourse">domain</a> can be too restrictive, inconsistent, and unclear. Necessary synsets are missing, with the PWN being skewed towards <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christianity">Christianity</a>. We argue that tackling problems in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain-specific_language">single domain</a> is a better method for improving CILI. By focusing on a single topic rather than a single language, this will result in the proper construction of definitions, romanization / translation of lemmas, and also improvements in use of / creation of a cross-lingual domain hierarchy.</abstract>
      <url hash="5c84f182">2018.gwc-1.41</url>
      <bibkey>slaughter-etal-2018-enchancing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="43">
      <title>Further expansion of the Croatian WordNet<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>roatian <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et</title>
      <author><first>Krešimir</first><last>Šojat</last></author>
      <author><first>Matea</first><last>Filko</last></author>
      <author><first>Antoni</first><last>Oliver</last></author>
      <pages>352–357</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper a semi-automatic procedure for the expansion of the Croatian Wordnet (CroWN) is presented. An English-Croatian dictionary was used in order to translate monosemous PWN 3.0 English variants. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">precision</a> values of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automation">automatic process</a> is low (about 30 %), but the results proved valuable for the enlargment of CroWN. After manual validation, 10,884 new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synchrony_and_diachrony">synset-variant pairs</a> were added to CroWN, achieving a total of 62,075 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synchrony_and_diachrony">synset-variant pairs</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="f0c21982">2018.gwc-1.43</url>
      <bibkey>sojat-etal-2018-expansion</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="48">
      <title>Sinitic Wordnet : Laying the Groundwork with Chinese Varieties Written in Traditional Characters<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet: Laying the Groundwork with <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese Varieties Written in Traditional Characters</title>
      <author><first>Chih-Yao</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Shu-Kai</first><last>Hsieh</last></author>
      <pages>384–387</pages>
      <abstract>The present work seeks to make the logographic nature of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_script">Chinese script</a> a relevant research ground in wordnet studies. While wordnets are not so much about words as about the concepts represented in words, synset formation inevitably involves the use of orthographic and/or phonetic representations to serve as headword for a given concept. For wordnets of Chinese languages, if their synsets are mapped with each other, the connection from logographic forms to lexicalized concepts can be explored backwards to, for instance, help trace the development of cognates in different varieties of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a>. The Sinitic Wordnet project is an attempt to construct such an integrated wordnet that aggregates three <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varieties_of_Chinese">Chinese varieties</a> that are widely spoken in Taiwan and all written in traditional Chinese characters.</abstract>
      <url hash="533fd25f">2018.gwc-1.48</url>
      <bibkey>lee-hsieh-2018-sinitic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="50">
      <title>Toward Constructing the National Cancer Institute Thesaurus Derived WordNet (ncitWN)<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et (ncit<fixed-case>WN</fixed-case>)</title>
      <author><first>Amanda</first><last>Hicks</last></author>
      <author><first>Selja</first><last>Seppälä</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <pages>394–400</pages>
      <abstract>We describe preliminary work in the creation of the first specialized vocabulary to be integrated into the Open Multilingual Wordnet (OMW). The NCIt Derived WordNet (ncitWN) is based on the National Cancer Institute Thesaurus (NCIt), a controlled biomedical terminology that includes formal class restrictions and English definitions developed by groups of clinicians and terminologists. The ncitWN is created by converting the NCIt to the WordNet Lexical Markup Framework and adding semantic types. We report the development of a prototype ncitWN and first steps towards integrating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_technology">it</a> into the OMW.</abstract>
      <url hash="e166e33e">2018.gwc-1.50</url>
      <bibkey>hicks-etal-2018-toward</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="51">
      <title>Towards a Crowd-Sourced WordNet for Colloquial English<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et for Colloquial <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish</title>
      <author><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <author><first>Ian</first><last>Wood</last></author>
      <author><first>Amanda</first><last>Hicks</last></author>
      <pages>401–406</pages>
      <abstract>Princeton WordNet is one of the most widely-used resources for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a>, but is updated only infrequently and can not keep up with the fast-changing usage of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English language</a> on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media platforms</a> such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a>. The Colloquial WordNet aims to provide an open platform whereby anyone can contribute, while still following the structure of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a>. Many crowd-sourced lexical resources often have significant quality issues, and as such care must be taken in the design of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_interface">interface</a> to ensure quality. In this paper, we present the development of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computing_platform">platform</a> that can be opened on the Web to any lexicographer who wishes to contribute to this resource and the lexicographic methodology applied by this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interface_(computing)">interface</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="89d89ebb">2018.gwc-1.51</url>
      <bibkey>mccrae-etal-2018-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="53">
      <title>SardaNet : a Linguistic Resource for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sardinian_language">Sardinian Language</a><fixed-case>S</fixed-case>arda<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et: a Linguistic Resource for <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>ardinian Language</title>
      <author><first>Manuela</first><last>Angioni</last></author>
      <author><first>Franco</first><last>Tuveri</last></author>
      <author><first>Maurizio</first><last>Virdis</last></author>
      <author><first>Laura Lucia</first><last>Lai</last></author>
      <author><first>Micol Elisa</first><last>Maltesi</last></author>
      <pages>412–419</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the process of building SardaNet, a linguistic resource for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sardinian_language">Sardinian language</a> including the different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variety_(linguistics)">linguistic varieties</a> in Sardinia. SardaNet aims at identifying the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantic relations</a> between Sardinian terms, by manually mapping existing WordNet entries to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sardinian_language">Sardinian word senses</a>. The work, still in progress, has been developed in collaboration with the University of Cagliari. After discussing some linguistic peculiarities, the paper presents the basic steps of the construction process, the method and the tools involved, the issues encountered during the development and the current version of SardaNet.</abstract>
      <url hash="01c9a3ee">2018.gwc-1.53</url>
      <bibkey>angioni-etal-2018-sardanet</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>