<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2018.iwslt">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2022-02-18">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 15th International Conference on Spoken Language Translation</booktitle>
      <publisher>International Conference on Spoken Language Translation</publisher>
      <address>Brussels</address>
      <month>October 29-30</month>
      <year>2018</year>
      <url hash="289091ee">2018.iwslt-1</url>
      <editor><first>Marco</first><last>Turchi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jan</first><last>Niehues</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Marcello</first><last>Frederico</last></editor>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="25b3ea73">2018.iwslt-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>iwslt-2018-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Unsupervised Parallel Sentence Extraction from Comparable Corpora</title>
      <author><first>Viktor</first><last>Hangya</last></author>
      <author><first>Fabienne</first><last>Braune</last></author>
      <author><first>Yuliya</first><last>Kalasouskaya</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexander</first><last>Fraser</last></author>
      <pages>7-13</pages>
      <abstract>Mining parallel sentences from comparable corpora is of great interest for many downstream tasks. In the BUCC 2017 shared task, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> performed well by training on gold standard parallel sentences. However, we often want to mine <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallelism_(grammar)">parallel sentences</a> without bilingual supervision. We present a simple approach relying on bilingual word embeddings trained in an unsupervised fashion. We incorporate orthographic similarity in order to handle words with similar surface forms. In addition, we propose a dynamic threshold method to decide if a candidate sentence-pair is parallel which eliminates the need to fine tune a static value for different datasets. Since we do not employ any language specific engineering our approach is highly generic. We show that our approach is effective, on three language-pairs, without the use of any bilingual signal which is important because parallel sentence mining is most useful in low resource scenarios.</abstract>
      <url hash="cb9f14e0">2018.iwslt-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>hangya-etal-2018-unsupervised</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bucc">BUCC</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Analyzing Knowledge Distillation in Neural Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Dakun</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Josep</first><last>Crego</last></author>
      <author><first>Jean</first><last>Senellart</last></author>
      <pages>23-30</pages>
      <abstract>Knowledge distillation has recently been successfully applied to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_machine_translation">neural machine translation</a>. It allows for building shrunk networks while the resulting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> retain most of the quality of the original <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a>. Despite the fact that many authors report on the benefits of knowledge distillation, few have discussed the actual reasons why it works, especially in the context of neural MT. In this paper, we conduct several experiments aimed at understanding why and how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distillation">distillation</a> impacts <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> on an English-German translation task. We show that translation complexity is actually reduced when building a distilled / synthesised bi-text when compared to the reference bi-text. We further remove noisy data from synthesised translations and merge filtered synthesised data together with original reference, thus achieving additional gains in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="99d49824">2018.iwslt-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>zhang-etal-2018-analyzing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Multi-Source Neural Machine Translation with Data Augmentation</title>
      <author><first>Yuta</first><last>Nishimura</last></author>
      <author><first>Katsuhito</first><last>Sudoh</last></author>
      <author><first>Graham</first><last>Neubig</last></author>
      <author><first>Satoshi</first><last>Nakamura</last></author>
      <pages>48-53</pages>
      <award>Best Student Paper</award>
      <abstract>Multi-source translation systems translate from multiple languages to a single target language. By using information from these multiple sources, these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> achieve large gains in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a>. To train these systems, it is necessary to have corpora with parallel text in multiple sources and the target language. However, these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpora</a> are rarely complete in practice due to the difficulty of providing human translations in all of the relevant languages. In this paper, we propose a data augmentation approach to fill such incomplete parts using multi-source neural machine translation (NMT). In our experiments, results varied over different language combinations but significant gains were observed when using a source language similar to the target language.</abstract>
      <url hash="9ab44f77">2018.iwslt-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>nishimura-etal-2018-multisource</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>The USTC-NEL Speech Translation system at IWSLT 2018<fixed-case>USTC</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>NEL</fixed-case> Speech Translation system at <fixed-case>IWSLT</fixed-case> 2018</title>
      <author><first>Dan</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Junhua</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Wu</first><last>Guo</last></author>
      <author><first>Shifu</first><last>Xiong</last></author>
      <author><first>Zhiqiang</first><last>Ma</last></author>
      <author><first>Rui</first><last>Song</last></author>
      <author><first>Chongliang</first><last>Wu</last></author>
      <author><first>Quan</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <pages>70-75</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the USTC-NEL (short for National Engineering Laboratory for Speech and Language Information Processing University of science and technology of china) system to the speech translation task of the IWSLT Evaluation 2018. The system is a conventional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pipeline_(computing)">pipeline system</a> which contains 3 modules : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">speech recognition</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_post-processing">post-processing</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>. We train a group of hybrid-HMM models for our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">speech recognition</a>, and for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a> we train transformer based neural machine translation models with speech recognition output style text as input. Experiments conducted on the IWSLT 2018 task indicate that, compared to baseline system from KIT, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> achieved 14.9 BLEU improvement.</abstract>
      <url hash="64a80ff2">2018.iwslt-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>liu-etal-2018-ustc</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>The ADAPT System Description for the IWSLT 2018 Basque to English Translation Task<fixed-case>ADAPT</fixed-case> System Description for the <fixed-case>IWSLT</fixed-case> 2018 <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>asque to <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish Translation Task</title>
      <author><first>Alberto</first><last>Poncelas</last></author>
      <author><first>Andy</first><last>Way</last></author>
      <author><first>Kepa</first><last>Sarasola</last></author>
      <pages>76-82</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we present the ADAPT system built for the Basque to English Low Resource MT Evaluation Campaign. Basque is a low-resourced, morphologically-rich language. This poses a challenge for Neural Machine Translation models which usually achieve better performance when trained with large sets of data. Accordingly, we used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synthetic_data">synthetic data</a> to improve the translation quality produced by a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> built using only authentic data. Our proposal uses back-translated data to : (a) create new sentences, so the system can be trained with more data ; and (b) translate sentences that are close to the test set, so the model can be fine-tuned to the document to be translated.</abstract>
      <url hash="42692a7e">2018.iwslt-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>poncelas-etal-2018-adapt</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wmt-2016">WMT 2016</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>وصف نظام التكيف لمهمة الترجمة الباسكية إلى الإنجليزية IWSLT 2018</title_ar>
      <title_pt>A descrição do sistema ADAPT para a tarefa de tradução de basco para inglês do IWSLT 2018</title_pt>
      <title_es>Descripción del sistema ADAPT para la tarea de traducción del euskera al inglés IWSLT 2018</title_es>
      <title_ja>IWSLT 2018バスク語から英語への翻訳タスクのADAPTシステム説明</title_ja>
      <title_ga>Cur síos ar an gCóras ADAPT do Thasc Aistriúcháin Bascais go Béarla IWSLT 2018</title_ga>
      <title_zh>IWSLT 2018 巴斯克语至英语翻译者 ADAPT 统言之</title_zh>
      <title_hi>IWSLT 2018 बास्क के लिए अंग्रेजी अनुवाद कार्य के लिए ADAPT सिस्टम विवरण</title_hi>
      <title_el>Η περιγραφή του συστήματος για το έργο της βασκικής σε αγγλική μετάφραση</title_el>
      <title_hu>Az ADAPT rendszer leírása az IWSLT 2018 baszk-angol fordítási feladathoz</title_hu>
      <title_ka>ADAPT სისტემის გამოსახულება IWSLT 2018 ბასკის ანგლისური განსახულების საქმე</title_ka>
      <title_it>Descrizione del sistema ADAPT per il compito di traduzione dal basco all'inglese IWSLT 2018</title_it>
      <title_kk>ADAPT жүйелік IWSLT 2018 баскша ағылшын аудару тапсырмасының сипаттамасы</title_kk>
      <title_mk>АДАПТ системски опис за IWSLT 2018 коски на англиски превод</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Huraian Sistem ADAPT untuk Tugas Terjemahan Bahasa ke Inggeris IWSLT 2018</title_ms>
      <title_lt>ADAPT sistemos aprašymas IWSLT 2018 Baskų ir anglų vertimo darbui</title_lt>
      <title_ml>IWSLT 2018 ബാസ്കിനുള്ള ADAPT സിസ്റ്റം വിവരണം ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് പരിഭാഷ ടാസ്കിലേക്കു്</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Id-Deskrizzjoni tas-Sistema ADAPT għall-IWSLT 2018 Kompitu ta’ Traduzzjoni Baska għall-Ingliż</title_mt>
      <title_no>ADAPT-systemskildring for IWSLT-2018 bask til engelsk omsetjingsverkt</title_no>
      <title_mn>ADAPT системийн тодорхойлолт нь IWSLT 2018 оны Баск-д Англи хэлний хөрөнгө оруулах</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Opis systemu ADAPT dla zadania tłumaczeniowego IWSLT 2018</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Descrierea sistemului ADAPT pentru sarcina de traducere din limba bască în engleză IWSLT 2018</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Описане АДАПТ Система за IWSLT 2018 Баски на английски транспортни задatak</title_sr>
      <title_si>The ADAPT System Description for the IWSLT 2018 Basque to English translation Job</title_si>
      <title_sv>Beskrivning av systemet ADAPT för IWSLT 2018 baskiska till engelska översättningsuppgifter</title_sv>
      <title_so>Description of the ADAPT system for the IWSLT 2018 Basque to Ingiriis Task Translation</title_so>
      <title_ta>IWSLT 2018 பாஸ்க் ஆங்கிலம் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு பணிக்கு ADAPT அமைப்பு விவரம்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>IWSLT 2018 کے لئے باسک انگلیسی ترجمہ ٹاکس کے لئے ADAPT سیسٹم کا سپرت</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Mô tả hệ thống ADAP cho Nhiệm vụ IWSLT 88 Dịch sang tiếng Anh</title_vi>
      <title_nl>De ADAPT systeembeschrijving voor de IWSLT 2018 Baskisch naar Engels vertaaltaak</title_nl>
      <title_da>ADAPT System Beskrivelse af IWSLT 2018 Baskisk til Engelsk Oversættelse Opgave</title_da>
      <title_hr>Opis ADAPT sustava za IWSLT 2018 Baskijski na engleski prevodni zadatak</title_hr>
      <title_id>Deskripsi Sistem ADAPT untuk Tugas Terjemahan Bahasa Inggris IWSLT 2018</title_id>
      <title_ko>IWSLT 2018 바스크 영어 번역 임무의 사용자 적응 시스템 설명</title_ko>
      <title_de>Die ADAPT Systembeschreibung für die IWSLT 2018 Baskisch to English Übersetzungsaufgabe</title_de>
      <title_tr>ADAPT sistemi Wasp</title_tr>
      <title_fa>Description of the ADAPT System for the IWSLT 2018 Basque to English Translation Task</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Maelezo ya Mfumo wa ADAPT kwa ajili ya IWSLT 2018 Basque kwa ajili ya Tafsiri ya Kiingereza</title_sw>
      <title_af>Die ADAPT Stelsel Beskrywing vir die IWSLT 2018 Basque na Engelske Vertaling Taak</title_af>
      <title_bg>Описание на системата АДАПТ за задачата за превод от баски на английски език 2018</title_bg>
      <title_sq>Description of the ADAPT System for the IWSLT 2018 Basque to English Translation Task</title_sq>
      <title_am>The ADAPT System Description for the IWSLT 2018 Basque to English translation Task</title_am>
      <title_az>IWSLT 2018 Basque il톛 캻ngiliz 칂eviri G칬z톛li 칲칞칲n ADAPT Sistemi T톛rc칲m톛</title_az>
      <title_bn>IWSLT ২০১৮ বাস্কের জন্য ADAPT সিস্টেমের বর্ণনা ইংরেজি অনুবাদ করার জন্য</title_bn>
      <title_hy>2018 թվականի բասկի դեպի անգլերեն թարգմանման գործի ADAPT համակարգի նկարագրությունը</title_hy>
      <title_bs>ADAPT sistemski opis za IWSLT 2018 Baskijski na engleski prevodni zadatak</title_bs>
      <title_ca>La descripció del sistema ADAPT per la tasca de traducció vasca a anglès IWSLT 2018</title_ca>
      <title_et>ADAPT süsteemi kirjeldus IWSLT 2018 baski-inglise tõlketöö jaoks</title_et>
      <title_fi>ADAPT-järjestelmän kuvaus IWSLT 2018 baskista englantiin -käännöstehtävään</title_fi>
      <title_cs>Popis systému ADAPT pro IWSLT 2018 Baskičtina do angličtiny Překlad úlohy</title_cs>
      <title_jv>tab-style</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Opis sistema ADAPT za prevajalsko nalogo IWSLT 2018 iz baskovščine v angleščino</title_sk>
      <title_he>Description of the ADAPT System for the IWSLT 2018 Basque to English Translation Task</title_he>
      <title_ha>Description for the IWSLT 2018 Basque to English translation job</title_ha>
      <title_bo>ADAPT མ་ལག་གི་འགྲེལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་IWSLT 2018 ས་ཡིག་གཟུགས་ལས་དབྱིན་ཡིག་སྐད་འགྲེལ་བཤད།</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم في هذا البحث نظام ADAPT المصمم لحملة تقييم مسرح ماجنت منخفضة الموارد من الباسك إلى الإنجليزية. لغة الباسك هي لغة منخفضة الموارد وغنية من الناحية الشكلية. يشكل هذا تحديًا لنماذج الترجمة الآلية العصبية التي عادةً ما تحقق أداءً أفضل عند تدريبها باستخدام مجموعات كبيرة من البيانات. وفقًا لذلك ، استخدمنا البيانات التركيبية لتحسين جودة الترجمة التي ينتجها نموذج تم إنشاؤه باستخدام بيانات أصلية فقط. يستخدم اقتراحنا البيانات المُعاد ترجمتها من أجل: (أ) إنشاء جمل جديدة ، بحيث يمكن تدريب النظام بمزيد من البيانات ؛ و (ب) ترجمة الجمل القريبة من مجموعة الاختبار ، بحيث يمكن ضبط النموذج بدقة على المستند المراد ترجمته.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>En este artículo presentamos el sistema ADAPT creado para la campaña de evaluación de MT de bajos recursos del euskera al inglés. El euskera es una lengua de pocos recursos y rica en morfología. Esto plantea un desafío para los modelos de traducción automática neuronal que, por lo general, logran un mejor rendimiento cuando se entrenan con grandes conjuntos de datos. En consecuencia, utilizamos datos sintéticos para mejorar la calidad de la traducción producida por un modelo creado solo con datos auténticos. Nuestra propuesta utiliza datos retrotraducidos para: (a) crear nuevas oraciones, para que el sistema pueda entrenarse con más datos; y (b) traducir oraciones que estén cerca del conjunto de pruebas, de modo que el modelo se pueda ajustar al documento que se va a traducir.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Neste artigo apresentamos o sistema ADAPT construído para a Campanha de Avaliação de MT de Baixo Recurso Basco para Inglês. O basco é uma língua de poucos recursos e morfologicamente rica. Isso representa um desafio para os modelos de tradução automática neural, que geralmente obtêm melhor desempenho quando treinados com grandes conjuntos de dados. Assim, usamos dados sintéticos para melhorar a qualidade da tradução produzida por um modelo construído usando apenas dados autênticos. Nossa proposta utiliza dados retrotraduzidos para: (a) criar novas sentenças, para que o sistema possa ser treinado com mais dados; e (b) traduzir sentenças próximas ao conjunto de teste, para que o modelo possa ser ajustado ao documento a ser traduzido.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、バスク語から英語への低資源MT評価キャンペーンのために構築された適応システムを紹介する。バスク語は低資源で形態豊富な言語である。これは、大規模なデータセットで訓練された場合に通常より優れたパフォーマンスを達成するニューラル・マシン・トランスレーション・モデルにとって課題となる。そこで、合成データを活用し、真正なデータのみを用いて構築されたモデルによって、翻訳品質を向上させました。当社の提案では、逆翻訳されたデータを使用して次のことを行います。(a)新しい文章を作成して、より多くのデータを使用してシステムをトレーニングできるようにします。(b)テストセットに近い文章を翻訳して、翻訳されるドキュメントにモデルを微調整できるようにします。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ga>Sa pháipéar seo cuirimid i láthair an córas ADAPT a tógadh don Fheachtas Measúnaithe MT ó Bhascach go Béarla. Is teanga íseal-acmhainní í an Bhascais, atá saibhir ó thaobh moirfeolaíochta de. Cruthaíonn sé seo dúshlán do mhúnlaí Néar-Aistriúcháin Meaisín a ghnóthaíonn feidhmíocht níos fearr de ghnáth nuair a chuirtear oiliúint orthu le tacair mhóra sonraí. Dá réir sin, d’úsáideamar sonraí sintéiseacha chun feabhas a chur ar cháilíocht an aistriúcháin a tháirgtear trí mhúnla a tógadh ag úsáid sonraí barántúla amháin. Úsáideann ár dtogra sonraí aisaistrithe chun: (a) abairtí nua a chruthú, ionas gur féidir an córas a oiliúint le tuilleadh sonraí; agus (b) abairtí atá gar don tacar trialach a aistriú, ionas gur féidir an tsamhail a mhionchoigeartú don doiciméad atá le haistriú.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_zh>于本文中,引为巴斯克语至英语低资源MT评估结构之ADAPT系统。 巴斯克语者,资也,形多言也。 为神经机器翻译挑战,以大集教之。 故我用合成数以崇真数所生译质。 臣等议用回译数:(a) 创新句,以统可以多数;(b) 创新句,以统可以多数;(b) 创新句;(c) 创新句;(d (b)译近试集之句,以模形微调其文档。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>इस पेपर में हम अंग्रेजी कम संसाधन एमटी मूल्यांकन अभियान के लिए बास्क के लिए निर्मित ADAPT प्रणाली प्रस्तुत करते हैं। बास्क एक कम संसाधन वाली, रूपात्मक रूप से समृद्ध भाषा है। यह न्यूरल मशीन ट्रांसलेशन मॉडल के लिए एक चुनौती है जो आमतौर पर डेटा के बड़े सेट के साथ प्रशिक्षित होने पर बेहतर प्रदर्शन प्राप्त करते हैं। तदनुसार, हमने केवल प्रामाणिक डेटा का उपयोग करके बनाए गए मॉडल द्वारा उत्पादित अनुवाद की गुणवत्ता में सुधार करने के लिए सिंथेटिक डेटा का उपयोग किया। हमारा प्रस्ताव बैक-अनूदित डेटा का उपयोग करता है: (ए) नए वाक्यों को बनाएं, ताकि सिस्टम को अधिक डेटा के साथ प्रशिक्षित किया जा सके; और (बी) उन वाक्यों का अनुवाद करें जो परीक्षण सेट के करीब हैं, इसलिए मॉडल को अनुवादित किए जाने वाले दस्तावेज़ के लिए ठीक किया जा सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დომენტში ჩვენ აჩვენებთ ADAPT სისტემა, რომელიც ბასკის გასაკეთებელად ინგლისური მინუს რესურსის MT გასაკეთებელი კამპანიაში. ბასკი არის ცოტა რესურსური, მორპოლოგიურად ბედნიერი ენაა. ეს აჩვენებს ნეიროლური მაქსინის გადაწყვეტილების მოდელებისთვის, რომლებიც საშუალოდ უკეთესი გამოყენება, როდესაც დიდი მონაცემებით გადაწყვეტილი მო ამიტომ, ჩვენ სინტეტიკური მონაცემები გამოყენეთ, რომ გაუქმნათ მოდელის გამოყენება მხოლოდ ავტონტიკური მონაცემებით. ჩვენი პროგრამები გამოყენება ახალი სიტყვების შექმნა, რადგან სისტემა უფრო მეტად მონაცემებით შეიძლება ახალი სიტყვების შექმნა; (b) ტესტის სეტის დაბრუნებული წარმოდგენების შემდეგ მოდელი შეიძლება გადაწყენოთ დოკუმენტის შემდეგ.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Ebben a tanulmányban bemutatjuk a baszk-angol alacsony erőforrású MT értékelési kampány ADAPT rendszerét. A baszk egy alacsony erőforrású, morfológiailag gazdag nyelv. Ez kihívást jelent a Neural Machine Translation modellek számára, amelyek általában jobb teljesítményt érnek el nagy adatkészletekkel történő kiképzés esetén. Ennek megfelelően szintetikus adatokat használtunk a kizárólag hiteles adatokat felhasználó modell által készített fordítási minőség javítására. Javaslatunk visszafordított adatokat használ a következőkre: (a) új mondatok létrehozására, így a rendszer több adattal képezhető; és (b) fordítson le olyan mondatokat, amelyek közel vannak a tesztkészlethez, így a modell finomhangolható a fordítandó dokumentumhoz.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Στην παρούσα εργασία παρουσιάζουμε το σύστημα που κατασκευάστηκε για την καμπάνια αξιολόγησης των βασκικών προς αγγλικών χαμηλών πόρων ΜΤ. Τα βασκικά είναι μια γλώσσα με χαμηλούς πόρους και μορφολογικά πλούσια. Αυτό αποτελεί πρόκληση για τα μοντέλα Νευρικής Μηχανικής Μετάφρασης τα οποία συνήθως επιτυγχάνουν καλύτερη απόδοση όταν εκπαιδεύονται με μεγάλα σύνολα δεδομένων. Ως εκ τούτου, χρησιμοποιήσαμε συνθετικά δεδομένα για να βελτιώσουμε την ποιότητα της μετάφρασης που παράγεται από ένα μοντέλο κατασκευασμένο μόνο με αυθεντικά δεδομένα. Η πρότασή μας χρησιμοποιεί μεταγραφικά δεδομένα για: (α) να δημιουργήσει νέες προτάσεις, ώστε το σύστημα να μπορεί να εκπαιδευτεί με περισσότερα δεδομένα. και β) μεταφράσουν προτάσεις που είναι κοντά στο σετ δοκιμών, έτσι ώστε το μοντέλο να μπορεί να προσαρμοστεί στο έγγραφο που θα μεταφραστεί.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente pristatome ADAPT sistemą, sukurtą baskų ir anglų žemųjų išteklių MT vertinimo kampanijai. Baskų kalba yra mažai išteklių turinti, morfologiškai turtinga kalba. Tai kelia iššūkį neurologinių mašinų vertimo modeliams, kurie paprastai pasiekia geresnius rezultatus rengiant didelius duomenų rinkinius. Todėl naudojame sintetinius duomenis, kad pagerintume vertimo kokybę, gautą naudojant model į, kuriame naudojami tik autentiški duomenys. Mūsų pasiūlyme naudojami grįžtamieji duomenys: a) sukurti naujus sakinius, kad sistema galėtų būti apmokoma daugiau duomenų; ir b) verti sakinius, kurie yra artimi bandymų rinkiniui, kad modelis galėtų b ūti tiksliai pritaikytas prie vertimo dokumento.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Во овој весник го претставуваме АДАПТ системот изграден за Баски до Англиска кампања за евалуација на МТ со ниски ресурси. Коски е нискоресурсен, морфолошки богат јазик. Ова претставува предизвик за моделите за превод на неврални машини кои обично постигнуваат подобра резултат кога се обучуваат со големи податоци. Според тоа, користевме синтетички податоци за подобрување на квалитетот на превод произведен од модел изграден користејќи само автентични податоци. Нашиот предлог користи преведени податоци за: (a) да создаде нови реченици, за системот да може да биде обучен со повеќе податоци; и (b) преведување реченици кои се блиски до тестот, за моделот да може да биде фино прилагоден на документот кој ќе биде преведен.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_it>In questo articolo presentiamo il sistema ADAPT costruito per la campagna di valutazione MT dal basco all'inglese Low Resource. Il basco è una lingua ricca di risorse e morfologicamente ricca. Ciò rappresenta una sfida per i modelli Neural Machine Translation, che di solito raggiungono prestazioni migliori se addestrati con grandi insiemi di dati. Di conseguenza, abbiamo utilizzato dati sintetici per migliorare la qualità della traduzione prodotta da un modello costruito utilizzando solo dati autentici. La nostra proposta utilizza i dati tradotti indietro per: (a) creare nuove frasi, in modo che il sistema possa essere addestrato con più dati; e (b) tradurre frasi vicine al set di test, in modo che il modello possa essere perfezionato al documento da tradurre.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағазда баск жүйесіне MT бағаттау кампаниясы үшін төменгі ресурстарды ағылшын тіліне құрылған ADAPT жүйесін таңдаймыз. Баск - көп ресурс, морфологиялық баяны тіл. Бұл нейрондық компьютерді аудару үлгілерінде көп деректерді оқыту үшін жақсы жұмыс істейтін үлгілер үшін мәселе береді. Сондықтан біз тек аутентификациялық деректерді қолдану үшін синтетикалық деректерді қолдандық. Біздің ұсынысымыз қайта аударылған деректерді: a) жаңа сөздерді құру үшін жүйеңіз көптеген деректермен оқылмай алады. және b) сынақтар жиынына жақын сөздерді аудару үшін үлгі құжатты аудару үшін дұрыс түзетуге болады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Dalam kertas ini kami perkenalkan sistem ADAPT yang dibina untuk Kampanye Evaluasi MT Sumber Terrendah Bahasa Bask ke Inggeris. Basque is a low-resourced, morphologically-rich language.  Ini menghasilkan cabaran untuk model Perjemahan Mesin Neural yang biasanya mencapai prestasi yang lebih baik bila dilatih dengan set data yang besar. Oleh sebab itu, kami menggunakan data sintetik untuk meningkatkan kualiti terjemahan yang dihasilkan oleh model yang dibina hanya menggunakan data yang sah. cadangan kami menggunakan data terjemahan semula untuk: (a) mencipta kalimat baru, supaya sistem boleh dilatih dengan lebih banyak data; and (b) translate sentences that are close to the test set, so the model can be fine-tuned to the document to be translated.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>F’dan id-dokument nippreżentaw is-sistema ADAPT mibnija għall-Kampanja ta’ Valutazzjoni MT Baska għal Ingliż b’Riżorsi Baxxi. Il-Bask huwa lingwa b’riżorsi baxxi u rikka morfoloġikament. Dan joħloq sfida għall-mudelli tat-Traduzzjoni tal-Magni Newrali li normalment jiksbu prestazzjoni a ħjar meta jitħarrġu b’settijiet kbar ta’ dejta. Għaldaqstant, użajna dejta sintetika biex ittejjeb il-kwalità tat-traduzzjoni prodotta minn mudell mibni bl-użu ta’ dejta awtentika biss. Our proposal uses back-translated data to: (a) create new sentences, so the system can be trained with more data;  and (b) translate sentences that are close to the test set, so the model can be fine-tuned to the document to be translated.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ ബാസ്കിന് വേണ്ടി ഉണ്ടാക്കിയ ADAPT സിസ്റ്റത്തെ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് വിഭവങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് കുറഞ്ഞ എംടി വിവരണ ബാസ്ക് ഒരു കുറഞ്ഞ വിഭവങ്ങളാണ്, മോര്‍ഫോളജിക്കല്‍ സമ്പന്നമായ ഭാഷ. This poses a challenge for Neural Machine Translation models which usually achieve better performance when trained with large sets of data.  അതുകൊണ്ട്, ഞങ്ങള്‍ സിന്തെറ്റിക്ക് ഡേറ്റായി ഉപയോഗിച്ച് ഒരു മോഡല്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയിരിക്കുന്ന പരിഭാഷക്കിന്റെ ഗ ഞങ്ങളുടെ പ്രൊദ്ദേശിപ്പ് പിന്നില്‍ പരിഭാഷ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു: (a) പുതിയ വാക്കുകള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കുക, അതുക (b) പരീക്ഷ സജ്ജീകരണത്തിന് അടുത്തുള്ള വാക്കുകള്‍ പരിശോധിക്കുക, അതുകൊണ്ട് രേഖയില്‍ പരിഭാഷപ്പെടുത്താന്‍ മോഡല</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаасан дээр бид Баск хэлний бага боловсролын MT оценки кампанийг бүтээсэн ADAPT системийг илтгэнэ. Баск бол бага эрчим хүчтэй, морфологийн баян хэл. Энэ нь мэдээллийн олон хэмжээний мэдээллээр суралцах үед илүү сайн үйл ажиллагааг гаргадаг мэдрэлийн машин хөгжүүлэх загварын сорилт юм. Тиймээс бид зөвхөн зөвхөн үнэн өгөгдлийг ашиглан бүтээсэн загварын хөгжүүлэх хэмжээсүүдийг сайжруулахын тулд синтетик өгөгдлийг ашигласан. Бидний санал буцаад орчуулсан өгөгдлийг (a) шинэ өгөгдлийг бий болгож, системийг олон өгөгдлийн дасгал суралцаж болно. (b) шалгалтын хэлбэрээс ойрхон өгүүлбэрийг орлуулж болно. Тиймээс загвар нь баримт орлуулах боломжтой болно.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>I denne papiret presenterer vi ADAPT-systemet bygd for baskisk til anglesk låg ressurs MT-evalueringskampanjen. Bask er ein låg ressursert, morfologisk rikt språk. Dette viser eit utfordring for neuralmaskineomsetjingsmodular som vanlegvis oppnår bedre utføringar når opplært med store datasett. I tillegg brukte vi syntetiske data for å forbetra omsetjingskvaliteten produsert av eit modell bygd med berre autentisk data. Vår forslag brukar tilbakeomsette data til: a) opprett nye setningar, slik at systemet kan trenast med fleire data. og b) oversetter setningar som er nær testsettet, slik at modellen kan setjast inn i dokumentet som skal oversettest.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>În această lucrare prezentăm sistemul ADAPT construit pentru campania de evaluare a MT din bască în engleză cu resurse reduse. Basca este o limbă bogată din punct de vedere morfologic cu resurse scăzute. Acest lucru reprezintă o provocare pentru modelele Neural Machine Translation, care, de obicei, obțin performanțe mai bune atunci când sunt instruite cu seturi mari de date. În consecință, am folosit date sintetice pentru a îmbunătăți calitatea traducerii produsă de un model construit doar cu date autentice. Propunerea noastră folosește date traduse înapoi pentru: (a) crearea de propoziții noi, astfel încât sistemul să poată fi instruit cu mai multe date; și (b) traduc propoziții care sunt aproape de setul de test, astfel încât modelul să poată fi reglat fin la documentul care urmează să fie tradus.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>W artykule przedstawiamy system ADAPT zbudowany dla baskijsko-angielskiej kampanii oceny niskich zasobów MT. Baskijski jest językiem o niskich zasobach, bogatym morfologicznie. Stanowi to wyzwanie dla modeli neuronowego tłumaczenia maszynowego, które zazwyczaj osiągają lepszą wydajność podczas treningu z dużymi zbiorami danych. W związku z tym wykorzystaliśmy dane syntetyczne do poprawy jakości tłumaczenia wytwarzanego przez model zbudowany wyłącznie z autentycznymi danymi. Nasza propozycja wykorzystuje dane przetłumaczone wstecznie do: (a) tworzenia nowych zdań, dzięki czemu system może być przeszkolony z większą ilością danych; i b) tłumaczyć zdania, które są blisko zestawu testowego, aby model mógł być dostosowany do dokumentu, który ma być tłumaczony.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>U ovom papiru predstavljamo sistem ADAPT izgrađen za baskijsku kampanju za procjenu MT za manje resurse na engleskom jeziku. Baskijski je nizak izvor, morfološki bogat jezik. To predstavlja izazov za modele neurološkog prevoda, koji obično postižu bolju izvršnost kada su obučeni velikim serijama podataka. Stoga smo koristili sintetičke podatke kako bi poboljšali kvalitet prevođenja izgrađenim modelom koji koristi samo autentične podatke. Naš prijedlog koristi prevedeni podaci na: a) stvoriti nove rečenice, tako da sistem može biti obučen sa više podataka; i b) prevedite rečenice koje su blizu seta testa, tako da se model može dobro uključiti dokumentu za prevedenje.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ පත්තරේ අපි ADAPT පද්ධතිය පෙන්වන්නේ බාස්ක් පද්ධතිය ඉංග්‍රීසියේ අඩු ප්‍රධාන MT විශ්ලේෂණ කම්පැන් බාස්ක් තමයි අඩුම ප්‍රධානයක්, මොර්ෆෝලෝජික විශාල භාෂාවක්. මේක ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා න්‍යූරල් මැෂින් වාර්ථාපනය මොඩේල්ස් එක්ක ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් හොඳ ප්‍රශ ඉතින්, අපි සින්ටෙටික් දත්ත භාවිතා කරනවා වාර්ථාව ප්‍රමාණයක් නිර්මාණය කරලා නිර්මාණය කරපු මදුල්ය අපේ ප්‍රයෝජනය පිටිපස්සේ පරිවර්තන දත්ත භාවිත කරනවා: a) අළුත් වචන සිද්ධා කරන්න, ඉතින් පද්ධතිය තව තො සහ (b) පරීක්ෂණ සෙට්ටුවට ලඟ ඉන්න ප්‍රවේශයක් පරීක්ෂණය කරන්න, ඉතින් මොඩේල් හරියට පරික්ෂණය කරන්න පුළුවන්</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Warqadan waxaan ku qornaa ADAPT-ka ee loo dhisay Basque-ka-Ingiriis Resource Low MT Evaluation Campaign. Basque waa luqad hoos-resourceed, morphologically-rich. Taasi waxay leedahay dhibaato u ah tusaalaha tarjumidda Neural machine, kaas oo inta badan gaadha bandhig ka wanaagsan marka lagu tababariyo koox badan oo macluumaad. Sidaas darteed, waxaynu isticmaalnay macluumaadka la-talinta si aan u hagno takhasada turjumaadda oo model ah oo lagu dhisay isticmaalka macluumaadka rasmi ah oo kaliya. Furriinkeennu wuxuu isticmaalaa macluumaadyo dib u turjuman: (a) u abuura erayo cusub, si aan nidaamka lagu baran karo macluumaad dheeraad ah; (b) turjuma erayada ku dhow saxda imtixaanka, sidaa darteed samoolka waxaa lagu turjumi karaa si loo turjumo.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>I denna uppsats presenterar vi ADAPT-systemet byggt för baskisk till engelsk lågresurs MT Evaluation Campaign. Baskiska är ett språk med låg resurs och morfologiskt rikt. Detta innebär en utmaning för Neural Machine Translation modeller som vanligtvis uppnår bättre prestanda när de tränas med stora datamängder. Därför använde vi syntetiska data för att förbättra översättningskvaliteten som producerats av en modell byggd med enbart autentiska data. Vårt förslag använder bakåtöversatta data för att: (a) skapa nya meningar, så att systemet kan utbildas med mer data; och (b) översätta meningar som ligger nära testuppsättningen, så att modellen kan finjusteras till det dokument som ska översättas.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தில் நாம் பாஸ்க் அமைப்பை காண்பிக்கிறோம் ஆங்கிலத்திற்கு குறைந்த மூலம் MT evaluation campaign. பாஸ்க் ஒரு குறைந்த வளர்ந்த மொழி. இது பெரிய தகவல்களுடன் பயிற்சி செய்யப்பட்ட போது நியூரல் இயந்திரம் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு மாதிரிகளுக்கு ஒரு சவால் ஆகும். ஆகையால், நாங்கள் ஒரு மாதிரி உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ள மொழிபெயர்ப்பு தரவை மேம்படுத்த பயன்படுத்தினோம் உண்மையான தகவலை மட் எங்கள் பரிந்துரையின் மீண்டும் மொழிபெயர்ப்பிடப்பட்ட தரவை பயன்படுத்துகிறது: (a) புதிய வாக்கியங்களை உருவாக்கு (b) சோதனை அமைப்புக்கு அருகிலுள்ள வாக்கியங்களை மொழிபெயர்த்து, மாதிரியின் மொழியை மொழிபெயர்க்க முடியும்.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>اس کاغذ میں ہم نے باسک کے لئے ساختہ ADAPT سیسٹم کو انگلیسی کے نیچے رسسوس MT Evaluation Campaign کے لئے پیش کیا ہے. باسک ایک کم رسسورٹ کی زبان ہے۔ یہ نئورل ماشین ترجمہ موڈل کے لئے ایک چال ڈالتا ہے جسے معمولاً بہترین عملکرد حاصل کرتا ہے جب بڑے ڈاکٹوں کے ساتھ تربیت کی جاتی ہے۔ اسی طرح ہم نے سینٹیسی ڈیٹا استعمال کیا ہے کہ ایک موڈل کے ذریعہ پیدا ہوا ترجمہ کیفیت کو بہتر کریں جو صرف حقیقت ڈیٹا کے مطابق بنایا گیا ہے. ہماری پیشنهاد واپس ترجمہ ڈیٹا کو استعمال کرتا ہے: اور (b) عبارت کو ترجمہ کریں جو آزمائش سٹ کے نزدیک ہیں، اس لئے مدل کو ترجمہ کرنا چاہیے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu hujjatda biz Basque uchun yaratilgan ADAPT tizimini ingliz Resource Low MT Taʼminlovchi Kampaniyaga present qilamiz. Baski juda kichkina murakkab, morfologik hosil tili. Name Shunday qilib, biz faqat haqiqiqiy maʼlumot yordamida tarjima sifatini bajarish uchun foydalanamiz. Бизнинг суҳбатимиз яна таркиб қилинган маълумотларни фойдаланади: (a) yangi so'zlar yaratish, shunday qilib, tizimning ko'proq maʼlumot bilan o'rganishi mumkin; (b) sinov moslamalariga yaqin so'zlarni tarjima qilish mumkin. Bu uchun model hujjatga tarjima qilishi mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Trong tờ giấy này chúng tôi giới thiệu hệ thống ADAP được xây dựng cho chiến dịch đánh giá Nguồn Tài nguyên thấp người Basque. Xứ Basque là một ngôn ngữ giàu có có, ít xoay xở. Điều này đặt ra một thách thức cho các mô hình lắp máy thần kinh (thần kinh) Dịch sang thường đạt hiệu suất tốt hơn khi được huấn luyện với các bộ dữ liệu lớn. Do đó, chúng tôi dùng dữ liệu tổng hợp để cải thiện chất lượng dịch sản xuất bởi một mẫu được xây dựng bằng chỉ những dữ liệu chính xác. Đề nghị của chúng tôi sử dụng các dữ liệu dịch ngược để: a) tạo ra các câu mới, để cho hệ thống có thể được đào tạo thêm thông tin; và (b) dịch các câu gần với b ộ thử, để mô hình có thể được chỉnh chính xác theo tài liệu cần dịch.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>U ovom papiru predstavljamo sistem ADAPT izgrađen za baskijsku kampanju za procjenu MT-a za manje resurse na engleskom jeziku. Baskijski je nizak izvor, morfološki bogat jezik. To predstavlja izazov za modele neurološkog prevoda strojeva koji obično postignu bolju učinku kada se obučavaju velikim skupinama podataka. Stoga smo koristili sintetičke podatke kako bi poboljšali kvalitet prevođenja iz model a izgrađenog samo autentičnim podacima. Naš prijedlog koristi natrag prevedeni podaci na: a) stvoriti nove rečenice, kako bi sustav mogao biti obučen s više podataka; i b) prevedite rečenice koje su blizu seta ispitivanja, tako da se model može ispravno uključiti dokumentu za prevedenje.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>В настоящата статия представяме системата АДАПТ, изградена за кампанията за оценка на МТ от баски до английски език с ниски ресурси. Баскът е език с ниски ресурси, морфологично богат. Това представлява предизвикателство за моделите на неврален машинен превод, които обикновено постигат по-добра производителност, когато се обучават с големи набори от данни. Съответно използвахме синтетични данни, за да подобрим качеството на превода, произведено от модел, изграден само с автентични данни. Нашето предложение използва обратно преведени данни за: (а) създаване на нови изречения, така че системата да може да бъде обучена с повече данни; и б) превежда изречения, които са близо до тестовия набор, така че моделът може да бъде фино настроен към документа, който ще бъде преведен.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>I denne artikel præsenterer vi ADAPT systemet bygget til baskisk til engelsk lav ressource MT evalueringskampagne. Baskisk er et lavt ressourcebesparende og morfologisk rigt sprog. Dette udgør en udfordring for Neural Machine Translation modeller, som normalt opnår bedre ydeevne, når de trænes med store datasæt. Derfor brugte vi syntetiske data til at forbedre oversættelseskvaliteten produceret af en model, der kun er bygget ud fra autentiske data. Vores forslag bruger back-translated data til at: (a) oprette nye sætninger, så systemet kan trænes med flere data; og (b) oversætte sætninger, der ligger tæt på testsættet, så modellen kan finjusteres til det dokument, der skal oversættes.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>In dit artikel presenteren we het ADAPT systeem gebouwd voor de Baskisch naar Engels Low Resource MT Evaluation Campaign. Baskisch is een taal met weinig middelen en morfologische rijkdom. Dit vormt een uitdaging voor Neural Machine Translation modellen die meestal betere prestaties behalen wanneer ze worden getraind met grote hoeveelheden gegevens. Daarom hebben we synthetische gegevens gebruikt om de vertaalkwaliteit van een model dat uitsluitend gebaseerd is op authentieke gegevens te verbeteren. Ons voorstel maakt gebruik van back-vertaalde data om: (a) nieuwe zinnen te creëren, zodat het systeem getraind kan worden met meer data; en (b) zinnen vertalen die dicht bij de testset liggen, zodat het model kan worden afgestemd op het te vertalen document.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Dalam kertas ini kami memperkenalkan sistem ADAPT yang dibangun untuk Kampanye Evaluasi MT Ressource Rendah Bahasa Baska ke Inggris. Basque is a low-resourced, morphologically-rich language.  Ini merupakan tantangan untuk model Translation Mesin Neural yang biasanya mencapai prestasi yang lebih baik ketika dilatih dengan set besar data. Oleh karena itu, kami menggunakan data sintetis untuk meningkatkan kualitas terjemahan yang diproduksi oleh model yang dibuat hanya menggunakan data autentik. Usaha kami menggunakan data terjemahan kembali untuk: (a) membuat kalimat baru, sehingga sistem dapat dilatih dengan lebih banyak data; dan (b) menerjemahkan kalimat yang dekat dengan set tes, sehingga model dapat disesuaikan dengan dokumen yang akan diterjemahkan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>In diesem Beitrag stellen wir das ADAPT-System vor, das für die baskisch-englisch Low Resource MT Evaluation Campaign entwickelt wurde. Baskisch ist eine Sprache mit geringen Ressourcen, die morphologisch reich ist. Dies stellt eine Herausforderung für Modelle der neuronalen maschinellen Übersetzung dar, die normalerweise bessere Leistung erzielen, wenn sie mit großen Datensätzen trainiert werden. Dementsprechend haben wir synthetische Daten verwendet, um die Übersetzungsqualität eines Modells zu verbessern, das ausschließlich authentische Daten verwendet. Unser Vorschlag verwendet rückübersetzte Daten, um: (a) neue Sätze zu erstellen, damit das System mit mehr Daten trainiert werden kann; und (b) Sätze übersetzen, die nahe am Testsatz liegen, damit das Modell auf das zu übersetzende Dokument abgestimmt werden kann.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 바스크 영어 저자원 기계 번역 평가 활동을 위한 자체 적응 시스템을 소개한다.바스케어는 자원이 부족하고 형태가 풍부한 언어이다.이것은 신경 기계 번역 모델에 도전을 제기했다. 빅데이터 집합을 사용하여 훈련을 할 때 이런 모델은 일반적으로 더욱 좋은 성능을 얻을 수 있다.따라서 우리는 합성 데이터를 사용하여 실제 데이터로만 구축된 모델로 이루어진 번역의 질을 향상시킨다.우리의 건의는 반역 데이터를 사용하는 것이다. (a) 새로운 문장을 만들면 시스템이 더 많은 데이터로 훈련할 수 있다.(b) 테스트 집합에 가까운 문장을 번역하면 모델은 번역할 문서에 따라 미세하게 조정할 수 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Katika karatasi hii tunaonyesha mfumo wa ADAPT ulioanzishwa kwa ajili ya Basque kwa ajili ya kampeni ya Uchunguzi wa Rasilimali Zisizo ya Kiingereza. Basque ni lugha yenye rasilimali duni, yenye utajiri wa kimaadili. Hii inaleta changamoto kwa mifano ya Tafsiri ya Mashine ya Njerumani ambayo mara nyingi hufanikiwa ufanisi mzuri unapofundishwa na makundi makubwa ya taarifa. Kwa hiyo, tulitumia taarifa za pamoja ili kuboresha ubora wa tafsiri uliotengenezwa na modeli iliyotengenezwa kwa kutumia taarifa za uhalisia tu. pendekezo letu linatumia taarifa zilizotafsiriwa kwa nyuma: (a) kutengeneza sentensi mpya, ili mfumo unaweza kufundishwa kwa takwimu zaidi; na kutafsiri maneno yanayokaribia seti ya jaribio, kwa hiyo mifano inaweza kutumika vizuri kwa waraka kutafsiriwa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>ما در این کاغذ سیستم ADAPT را برای کمپانی ارزیابی MT منابع کم انگلیسی ساخته می‌کنیم. باسک یک زبان کمتری از منابع است که به صورت مورفولوژیک ثروتمند است. این یک چالش برای مدلهای ترجمه ماشین عصبی قرار می دهد که معمولاً هنگامی که با مجموعه های بزرگ داده آموزش داده می شود، عملکرد بهتر را می رساند. به همین دلیل، ما از داده‌های سنتتی استفاده کردیم تا کیفیت ترجمه‌ای که توسط یک مدل ساخته شده با استفاده از داده‌های حقیقی بهتر شود. پیشنهاد ما از داده‌های عقب ترجمه به: a) جمله‌های جدید ایجاد می‌کند، پس سیستم می‌تواند با داده‌های بیشتری آموزش داده شود. و (b) جمله‌های نزدیک به مجموعه آزمایش ترجمه می‌کند، بنابراین مدل می‌تواند به سند ترجمه شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyzda biziň ADAPT sistemasyny beýik Ressource MT Taýýarlama kampanýasyna bask üçin guruldyrylýan. Baskça azajyk, morfologik bilen baý dildir. Bu näyral maşynyň terjime nusgasyny üçin kynçylyk bar. Bu nusgasy uly düzüm maglumatlar bilen öňünde has gowy hereket edip bilýär. Şol sebäpli, diňe hakyky maglumatlary ulanan bir nusga tarapyndan üretilen terjime kwalitesini geliştirmek üçin sintetik maglumatlary ulandyk Biziň teklibimiz arka terjime edilen maglumaty şuna ulanýar: we (b) testiň düzümlerine ýakyn sözlerni terjime edip, şonuň üçin modi terjime edilmeli senediň üstine hat edilsin.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Në këtë letër paraqesim sistemin ADAPT të ndërtuar për kampanjën Baske në Anglisht të vlerësimit të MT me burime të ulta. Basku është një gjuhë e pasur me burime të ulta dhe morfologjike. Kjo paraqet një sfidë për modelet e Translacionit të Makinës Neurale që zakonisht arrijnë performancë më të mirë kur trajnohen me grupe të mëdha të dhënash. Sipas kësaj, përdorëm të dhëna sintetike për të përmirësuar cilësinë e përkthimit prodhuar nga një model i ndërtuar duke përdorur vetëm të dhëna autentike. Propozimi ynë përdor të dhëna të përkthyera prapa për: (a) të krijojë fjalime të reja, kështu që sistemi mund të trajnohet me më shumë të dhëna; and (b) translate sentences that are close to the test set, so the model can be fine-tuned to the document to be translated.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Այս թղթի մեջ մենք ներկայացնում ենք ADAPT համակարգը, որը կառուցվել է Բասկի և Անգլերենի ցածր ռեսուրսների MT գնահատման քարոզարշավի համար: Բասկը ցածր ռեսուրսների, մորֆոլոգիապես հարուստ լեզու է: Սա մարտահրավեր է առաջացնում նյարդային մեքենայի թարգմանման մոդելների համար, որոնք սովորաբար ավելի լավ արդյունք են ստանում, երբ ուսուցանվում են մեծ տվյալների համակարգերով: Հետևաբար, մենք օգտագործեցինք սինթետիկ տվյալներ թարգմանության որակի բարելավման համար, որը ստեղծվել է մի մոդելի միջոցով, որը ստեղծվել է միայն իրական տվյալներ օգտագործելով: Մեր առաջարկությունը օգտագործում է վերադարձ թարգմանված տվյալներ՝ a) ստեղծելու նոր նախադասություններ, որպեսզի համակարգը կարողանա սովորել ավելի շատ տվյալներով: և (b) թարգմանել նախադասությունները, որոնք մոտ են փորձարկումների սահմանին, այնպես որ մոդելը կարելի է լավ համապատասխանել թարգմանելու փաստաթղթին:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>በዚህ ገጾች ውስጥ ለባስክ የደረገውን ADAPT ስርዓት ወደ ኢንግሊዝኛ ታናሽ የኢንጂልኛ ዕቃ MT አረጋጋጭ ዘመቻ እናቀርባለን፡፡ ባስክ የጎደለው፣ የሞሮፎሎጂ ባለጠጋ ቋንቋ ነው፡፡ ይህ የናውሬል መኪን ትርጉም ሞዴላዎችን የሚያሳውቅ ጥቃት ነው፡፡ ስለዚህም በአስረንጋዊ ዳታ ብቻ በመጠቀም በሞዴል የተዘጋጀውን ትርጉም ጥሩ ለማድረግ ተጠቃሚ ነበር፡፡ አዲስ ቃላት መፍጠር ይችላል፣ የስርዓት ዳታዎችን ለመጠቀም ይችላል፡፡ እና (b) ፈተናው ማዘጋጀት የሚቀርቡትን ቃላት ትርጉም፤ ሞዴል ለሰነዱ ለመትረጉም ይችላል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>In hierdie papier vertoon ons die ADAPT stelsel gebou vir die Baske na Engels Lae Hulpbron MT Evaluering Kampanie. Baske is 'n lae hulpbron, morfologiese ryk taal. Hierdie stel 'n uitdrukking vir Neural Masjien Vertaling Modelle wat gewoonlik beter uitdrukking bereik wanneer opgelei word met groot stelle data. Ons het dus sintetiese data gebruik om die vertalingskwaliteit te verbeter wat deur 'n model gebou word deur slegs outentiese data te gebruik. Ons voorstel gebruik terugvertaalde data na: (a) skep nuwe teikens, sodat die stelsel kan onderwerp word met meer data; en (b) vertaling setinge wat naby die toets stel is, sodat die model kan fyn-tuned wees na die dokument om vertaling te word.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_bn>এই কাগজটিতে আমরা বাস্কের জন্য বাস্কে নির্মিত এডিএপিটি সিস্টেম উপস্থাপন করছি ইংরেজি থেকে নিম্ন রিসোর্স এমটি ইন বাস্ক একটি কম সম্পদ, মর্ফোলজিক-সমৃদ্ধ ভাষা। এটি নিউরাল মেশিন অনুবাদ মডেলের জন্য একটি চ্যালেঞ্জ যা সাধারণত বিশাল তথ্যের প্রশিক্ষণ দিয়ে ভালো প্রদর্শন করে। তাই, আমরা সিন্টেটিক ডাটা ব্যবহার করেছি অনুবাদের মান উন্নত করার জন্য, যা একটি মডেল তৈরি করেছে তা শুধুমাত্র সত্যিকারী  আমাদের প্রস্তাব পুনরাবৃত্তির তথ্য ব্যবহার করে: (a) নতুন বাক্য তৈরি করুন, যাতে সিস্টেম আরো তথ্য দিয়ে প্রশিক্ষণ প এবং (b) টেস্ট সেটের কাছাকাছি কাছাকাছি বাক্য অনুবাদ করুন, যাতে এই নথিটি অনুবাদ করতে পারে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıtda baskı üçün İngilizə Aşağı Kaynağı MT Evaluasyon Kampağına inşa edilmiş ADAPT sistemini göstəririk. Basque düşük-düşük, morfolojik-zengin dildir. Bu, böyük məlumatlar ilə təhsil edildiyi zaman daha yaxşı performans edəcək Neural Machine Translation modellərinin çətinliklərini göstərir. Beləliklə, sadəcə həqiqi məlumatlar vasitəsilə inşa edilmiş modellərdən ürəklənmiş çeviri kalitetini yaxşılaşdırmaq üçün sintetik məlumatları kullandıq. Bizim teklifimiz geri çevirilmiş məlumatları istifadə edir: a) yeni cümlələr yarat, böylece sistemi daha çox məlumatla təhsil edilə bilər; və b) sınama quruluğuna yaxın olan cümlələri tərcümə edir, b öylece modeli tərcümə ediləcək dökümə tərcümə edilə bilər.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>En aquest article presentem el sistema ADAPT construït per a la Campania d'Evaluació de MT de baix recursos vasc a anglès. Basque is a low-resourced, morphologically-rich language.  Això representa un repte per als models de traducció de màquines neuronals que normalment aconsegueixen millor rendiment quan s'entrenen amb grans conjunts de dades. Per tant, vam utilitzar dades sintètiques per millorar la qualitat de traducció produïda per un model construït només fent servir dades autèntiques. La nostra proposta utilitza dades retrotraduïdes per a: a) crear frases noves, per tal que el sistema pugui ser entrenat amb més dades; i b) traduir frases que són properes del conjunt de proves, per tal que el model es pugui ajustar fins al document a traduir.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>V tomto článku představujeme systém ADAPT vytvořený pro baskicko-anglickou Low Resource MT Evaluation Campaign. Baskičtina je nízké zdroje, morfologicky bohatý jazyk. To představuje výzvu pro modely neuronového strojového překladu, které obvykle dosahují lepšího výkonu při tréninku s velkými množinami dat. Proto jsme použili syntetická data ke zlepšení kvality překladu vytvořeného modelem sestaveným pouze z autentických dat. Náš návrh využívá zpětně přeložená data k: (a) vytvoření nových vět, aby systém mohl být trénován s více dat; a b) překládat věty, které jsou blízko testovací sady, takže model může být jemně naladěn na dokument, který má být přeložen.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_bs>U ovom papiru predstavljamo sistem ADAPT izgrađen za baskijsku kampanju za procjenu MT-a za manje resurse. Bask je nisko sredstvo, morfološki bogat jezik. To predstavlja izazov za modele neurološkog prevoda strojeva koji obično postignu bolju učinku kada su obučeni velikim skupinama podataka. Stoga smo koristili sintetičke podatke kako bi poboljšali kvalitet prevođenja iz model a izgrađenog samo autentičnim podacima. Naš prijedlog koristi ponovno prevedeni podaci na: a) stvoriti nove rečenice, tako da sistem može biti obučen sa više podataka; i b) prevedite rečenice koje su blizu seta testa, tako da se model može dobro uključiti dokumentu prevedeno.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas töös tutvustame ADAPT süsteemi, mis on ehitatud baski-inglise madala ressursiga MT hindamise kampaania jaoks. Baski keel on madala ressursiga ja morfoloogiliselt rikas keel. See kujutab endast väljakutset neuromasintõlke mudelitele, mis tavaliselt saavutavad suuremate andmekogumitega koolitamisel parema jõudluse. Sellest tulenevalt kasutasime sünteetilisi andmeid tõlkekvaliteedi parandamiseks, mis on toodetud ainult autentsete andmete abil. Meie ettepanekus kasutatakse tagasitõlgitud andmeid, et: a) luua uusi lauseid, et süsteemi saaks koolitada rohkem andmeid; ja (b) tõlkida lauseid, mis on lähedal testikomplekti, nii et mudelit saab täpselt häälestada tõlgitava dokumendiga.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>T채ss채 artikkelissa esittelemme ADAPT-j채rjestelm채n, joka rakennettiin Baskimaan ja Englantiin Low Resource MT Evaluation Campaign -kampanjalle. Baski on v채h채resurssinen ja morfologisesti rikas kieli. T채m채 on haaste neurokonek채채nn철smalleille, jotka yleens채 saavuttavat paremman suorituskyvyn, kun niit채 koulutetaan suurilla tietojoukoilla. N채in ollen hy철dynsimme synteettist채 dataa parantaaksemme vain aitoa dataa hy철dynt채v채n mallin tuottamaa k채채nn철slaatua. Ehdotuksessamme k채ytet채채n taaksep채in k채채nnettyj채 tietoja: (a) luodaan uusia lauseita, jotta j채rjestelm채채 voidaan kouluttaa enemm채n tietoja; ja (b) k채채nt채채 lauseita, jotka ovat l채hell채 testijoukkoa, jotta malli voidaan hienos채채t채채 k채채nnett채v채채n asiakirjaan.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_he>בעיתון הזה אנו מציגים את מערכת ADAPT שנבנתה עבור קמפיין הערכה באנגלית למקורים נמוכים MT. בסקית היא שפה עשירה במקורים נמוכים ומורפולוגיים. זה יוצר אתגר עבור דוגמני התרגום של מכונות נוירות שבדרך כלל משיגים ביצועים טובים יותר כאשר מאומנים עם קבוצות גדולות של נתונים. לכן השתמשנו במידע סינטטי כדי לשפר את איכות התרגום שנוצרה על ידי דוגמא שנבנה בשימוש רק נתונים אמיתיים. הצעה שלנו משתמשת בנתונים מתרגמים אחורה כדי: a) ליצור משפטים חדשים, כך שהמערכת יכולה להיות מאומנת עם יותר נתונים; (b) לתרגם משפטים קרובים לסט הבדיקות, כך שהדוגמן יכול להתאים למסמך שיתרגום.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Ga wannan takardan da Muke iya gabatar da AADATT na'urar da aka gina wa Basque zuwa Ingiriya Low Resource MT Bayan Aiki. Basque is a low-resourced, morphologically-rich language.  Wannan yana da wata ƙudura wa misãlai masu Translate na Kijeri na Neural, wanda ko da ya ƙunsa da mafiya kyau a lokacin da aka sanar da shi da tsari masu yawa. Wancan, mun yi amfani da data na haɗi dõmin mu kyautata tsarin fassarar da wani motel wanda aka samar da shi, ana yi amfani da data masu inganci kawai. Dakatanmu yana amfani da data masu fassarwa da aka sake-fassarwa zuwa: (a) ka sami tsarin da za'a sanar da shi na ƙaranci; Kuma ka sarrafa kalmõmi waɗanda ke mafi kusantar da tsarin jarraba, dõmin an iya iya daidaita misalin kowandan takardar da za'a fassara.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku predstavljamo sistem ADAPT, zgrajen za akcijo ocenjevanja MT nizkih virov baskovsko-angleško. Baskovščina je jezik z nizkimi viri, morfološko bogat. To predstavlja izziv za modele nevralnega strojnega prevajanja, ki običajno dosegajo boljšo zmogljivost pri usposabljanju z velikimi nabori podatkov. V skladu s tem smo uporabili sintetične podatke za izboljšanje kakovosti prevodov, ki ga je izdelal model, zgrajen samo z avtentičnimi podatki. Naš predlog uporablja nazaj prevedene podatke za: (a) ustvarjanje novih stavkov, da se sistem lahko usposablja z več podatki; in (b) prevajajo stavke, ki so blizu preskusnega nabora, tako da je model mogoče natančno prilagoditi dokumentu, ki ga je treba prevesti.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Nang pepulan iki kita nggawe sistem DEPAT sing nggawe kanggo Kemerdekaan Basque kanggo Kemerdekaan MT Kemerdekaan Pasir Basque kuwi basa sing paling kelas, kuwi mangka-alah banget. Iki sampeyan akeh perbudhakan kanggo model penting Neral Masine Tulung dhéwé iso nggawe barang sing luwih dumadhi karo data sing gawe kudu ditulak bantuan. slot Isoporungu punika menehi kelas-terjamahan kanggo: :a) gawe barang-terjamahan karo data anyar, dadi sistem iso disenyong karo data yang terus-terjamahan; Tanggal</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>འོག་གི་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོས་རྒྱ་ནག་ཡིག་གི་ཚད་ལུས་པ་ཇུས་མཐུན་གྱི་རྒྱུ་མཚན་ལ་བཟོ་བཀོད་པ་ཡིན། བྷ་སིཀ་ནི་གཟུགས་རིས་འདི་ལྕགས་ཅན་མེད་པ་ཞིག་རེད། འདིས་Neural Machine་ཡིག་སྒྲུབ་ཀྱི་མ་དབྱིབས་ལ་གདོང་ལེན་དགོས་པ་ཞིག་ཡིན་པས་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་སྔར་སྒྲིག་ཡིག་ཆ་གསལ་གྲ འུ་ཅག་གིས་དབྱིབས་བདེ་རིགས་གནས་ཚུལ་གསལ་བཤད་བྱས་པ ང་ཚོའི་བསམ (b) བརྟག་ཞིབ་ཀྱི་སྒྲིག་འཛུགས་ཀྱི་སྒོ་རྒྱག་ཡོད་པའི་ཚིག་རྐང་འདིའི་ནང་ལྟ་བུ་འཇུག་བྱེད་དགོས།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>The MeMAD Submission to the IWSLT 2018 Speech Translation Task<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>e<fixed-case>MAD</fixed-case> Submission to the <fixed-case>IWSLT</fixed-case> 2018 Speech Translation Task</title>
      <author><first>Umut</first><last>Sulubacak</last></author>
      <author><first>Jörg</first><last>Tiedemann</last></author>
      <author><first>Aku</first><last>Rouhe</last></author>
      <author><first /><last>Stig-ArneGrönroos</last></author>
      <author><first>Mikko</first><last>Kurimo</last></author>
      <pages>89-94</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the MeMAD project entry to the IWSLT Speech Translation Shared Task, addressing the translation of English audio into German text. Between the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pipeline_(computing)">pipeline</a> and end-to-end model tracks, we participated only in the former, with three contrastive systems. We tried also the latter, but were not able to finish our end-to-end model in time. All of our systems start by transcribing the audio into text through an automatic speech recognition (ASR) model trained on the TED-LIUM English Speech Recognition Corpus (TED-LIUM). Afterwards, we feed the transcripts into English-German text-based neural machine translation (NMT) models. Our systems employ three different translation models trained on separate training sets compiled from the English-German part of the TED Speech Translation Corpus (TED-TRANS) and the OPENSUBTITLES2018 section of the OPUS collection. In this paper, we also describe the experiments leading up to our final <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermodynamic_system">systems</a>. Our experiments indicate that using OPENSUBTITLES2018 in training significantly improves <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation_(biology)">translation</a> performance. We also experimented with various preand postprocessing routines for the NMT module, but we did not have much success with these. Our best-scoring system attains a BLEU score of 16.45 on the test set for this year’s task.</abstract>
      <url hash="9b99e769">2018.iwslt-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>sulubacak-etal-2018-memad</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Samsung and University of Edinburgh’s System for the IWSLT 2018 Low Resource MT Task<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>amsung and <fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversity of <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>dinburgh’s System for the <fixed-case>IWSLT</fixed-case> 2018 Low Resource <fixed-case>MT</fixed-case> Task</title>
      <author><first>Philip</first><last>Williams</last></author>
      <author><first>Marcin</first><last>Chochowski</last></author>
      <author><first>Pawel</first><last>Przybysz</last></author>
      <author><first>Rico</first><last>Sennrich</last></author>
      <author><first>Barry</first><last>Haddow</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexandra</first><last>Birch</last></author>
      <pages>118-123</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the joint submission to the IWSLT 2018 Low Resource MT task by Samsung R&amp;D Institute, Poland, and the University of Edinburgh. We focused on supplementing the very limited in-domain Basque-English training data with out-of-domain data, with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synthetic_data">synthetic data</a>, and with data for other language pairs. We also experimented with a variety of model architectures and features, which included the development of extensions to the Nematus toolkit. Our submission was ultimately produced by a system combination in which we reranked translations from our strongest individual system using multiple weaker systems.</abstract>
      <url hash="6fe9958f">2018.iwslt-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>williems-etal-2018-samsung</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>The AFRL IWSLT 2018 Systems : What Worked, What Did n’t<fixed-case>AFRL</fixed-case> <fixed-case>IWSLT</fixed-case> 2018 Systems: What Worked, What Didn’t</title>
      <author><first>Brian</first><last>Ore</last></author>
      <author><first>Eric</first><last>Hansen</last></author>
      <author><first>Katherine</first><last>Young</last></author>
      <author><first>Grant</first><last>Erdmann</last></author>
      <author><first>Jeremy</first><last>Gwinnup</last></author>
      <pages>124-130</pages>
      <abstract>This report summarizes the Air Force Research Laboratory (AFRL) machine translation (MT) and automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems submitted to the spoken language translation (SLT) and low-resource MT tasks as part of the IWSLT18 evaluation campaign.</abstract>
      <url hash="b409fe59">2018.iwslt-1.18</url>
      <bibkey>afrl-etal-2018-ore</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>CUNI Basque-to-English Submission in IWSLT18<fixed-case>CUNI</fixed-case> <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>asque-to-<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish Submission in <fixed-case>IWSLT</fixed-case>18</title>
      <author><first>Tom</first><last>Kocmi</last></author>
      <author><first>Dušan</first><last>Variš</last></author>
      <author><first>Ondřej</first><last>Bojar</last></author>
      <pages>142-146</pages>
      <abstract>We present our submission to the IWSLT18 Low Resource task focused on the translation from Basque-to-English. Our submission is based on the current state-of-the-art self-attentive neural network architecture, Transformer. We further improve this strong <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(medicine)">baseline</a> by exploiting available <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monolingualism">monolingual data</a> using the back-translation technique. We also present further improvements gained by a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">transfer learning</a>, a technique that trains a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> using a high-resource language pair (Czech-English) and then fine-tunes the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> using the target low-resource language pair (Basque-English).</abstract>
      <url hash="742d6232">2018.iwslt-1.21</url>
      <bibkey>kocmi-etal-2018b-cuni</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>Data Selection with Feature Decay Algorithms Using an Approximated Target Side</title>
      <author><first>Alberto</first><last>Poncelas</last></author>
      <author><first>Gideon</first><last>Maillette de Buy Wenniger</last></author>
      <author><first>Andy</first><last>Way</last></author>
      <pages>173-180</pages>
      <abstract>Data selection techniques applied to neural machine translation (NMT) aim to increase the performance of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> by retrieving a subset of sentences for use as training data. One of the possible data selection techniques are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transduction_(machine_learning)">transductive learning methods</a>, which select the data based on the test set, i.e. the document to be translated. A limitation of these methods to date is that using the source-side test set does not by itself guarantee that sentences are selected with correct translations, or translations that are suitable given the test-set domain. Some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpora</a>, such as subtitle corpora, may contain parallel sentences with inaccurate translations caused by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internationalization_and_localization">localization</a> or length restrictions. In order to try to fix this problem, in this paper we propose to use an approximated target-side in addition to the source-side when selecting suitable sentence-pairs for training a model. This approximated target-side is built by pre-translating the source-side. In this work, we explore the performance of this general idea for one specific data selection approach called Feature Decay Algorithms (FDA). We train German-English NMT models on data selected by using the test set (source), the approximated target side, and a mixture of both. Our findings reveal that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> built using a combination of outputs of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Food_and_Drug_Administration">FDA</a> (using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_set">test set</a> and an approximated target side) perform better than those solely using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_set">test set</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="3b09452f">2018.iwslt-1.26</url>
      <bibkey>poncelas-etal-2018-data</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wmt-2015">WMT 2015</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Multi-paraphrase Augmentation to Leverage Neural Caption Translation</title>
      <author><first>Johanes</first><last>Effendi</last></author>
      <author><first>Sakriani</first><last>Sakti</last></author>
      <author><first>Katsuhito</first><last>Sudoh</last></author>
      <author><first>Satoshi</first><last>Nakamura</last></author>
      <pages>181-188</pages>
      <abstract>Paraphrasing has been proven to improve translation quality in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation (MT)</a> and has been widely studied alongside with the development of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_machine_translation">statistical MT (SMT)</a>. In this paper, we investigate and utilize neural paraphrasing to improve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation_(biology)">translation quality</a> in neural MT (NMT), which has not yet been much explored. Our first contribution is to propose a new way of creating a multi-paraphrase corpus through visual description. After that, we also proposed to construct neural paraphrase models which initiate expert models and utilize them to leverage NMT. Here, we diffuse the image information by using image-based paraphrasing without using the image itself. Our proposed image-based multi-paraphrase augmentation strategies showed improvement against a vanilla NMT baseline.</abstract>
      <url hash="f7f681b3">2018.iwslt-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>effendi-etal-2018-multi</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/coco">COCO</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>