<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2019.icon">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-10">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 16th International Conference on Natural Language Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Dipti Misra</first><last>Sharma</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pushpak</first><last>Bhattacharya</last></editor>
      <publisher>NLP Association of India</publisher>
      <address>International Institute of Information Technology, Hyderabad, India</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2019</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="8847b7d4">2019.icon-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>icon-2019-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>A Deep Ensemble Framework for Fake News Detection and Multi-Class Classification of Short Political Statements</title>
      <author><first>Arjun</first><last>Roy</last></author>
      <author><first>Kingshuk</first><last>Basak</last></author>
      <author><first>Asif</first><last>Ekbal</last></author>
      <author><first>Pushpak</first><last>Bhattacharyya</last></author>
      <pages>9–17</pages>
      <abstract>Fake news, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rumor">rumor</a>, incorrect information, and misinformation detection are nowadays crucial issues as these might have serious consequences for our social fabrics. Such information is increasing rapidly due to the availability of enormous web information sources including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media feeds</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blog">news blogs</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_newspaper">online newspapers</a> etc. In this paper, we develop various deep learning models for detecting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake news</a> and classifying them into the pre-defined fine-grained categories. At first, we develop individual models based on Convolutional Neural Network (CNN), and Bi-directional Long Short Term Memory (Bi-LSTM) networks. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_representation_and_reasoning">representations</a> obtained from these two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> are fed into a Multi-layer Perceptron Model (MLP) for the final <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a>. Our experiments on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benchmarking">benchmark dataset</a> show promising results with an overall <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of 44.87 %, which outperforms the current state of the arts.</abstract>
      <url hash="d3430c1c">2019.icon-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>roy-etal-2019-deep</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/liar">LIAR</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Introducing Aspects of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creativity">Creativity</a> in Automatic Poetry Generation</title>
      <author><first>Brendan</first><last>Bena</last></author>
      <author><first>Jugal</first><last>Kalita</last></author>
      <pages>26–35</pages>
      <abstract>Poetry Generation involves teaching systems to automatically generate text that resembles <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poetry">poetic work</a>. A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning system</a> can learn to generate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poetry">poetry</a> on its own by training on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus of poems</a> and modeling the particular style of language. In this paper, we propose taking an approach that fine-tunes GPT-2, a pre-trained language model, to our downstream task of poetry generation. We extend prior work on poetry generation by introducing creative elements. Specifically, we generate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poetry">poems</a> that express emotion and elicit the same in readers, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poetry">poems</a> that use the language of dreamscalled dream poetry. We are able to produce <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poetry">poems</a> that correctly elicit the emotions of sadness and joy 87.5 and 85 percent, respectively, of the time. We produce dreamlike poetry by training on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus of texts</a> that describe <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dream">dreams</a>. Poems from this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> are shown to capture elements of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dream_vision">dream poetry</a> with scores of no less than 3.2 on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Likert_scale">Likert scale</a>. We perform crowdsourced human-evaluation for all our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poetry">poems</a>. We also make use of the Coh-Metrix tool, outlining metrics we use to gauge the quality of text generated.</abstract>
      <url hash="2200f374">2019.icon-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>bena-kalita-2019-introducing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Incorporating Sub-Word Level Information in Language Invariant Neural Event Detection</title>
      <author><first>Suhan</first><last>Prabhu</last></author>
      <author><first>Pranav</first><last>Goel</last></author>
      <author><first>Alok</first><last>Debnath</last></author>
      <author><first>Manish</first><last>Shrivastava</last></author>
      <pages>36–44</pages>
      <abstract>Detection of TimeML events in text have traditionally been done on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpora</a> such as TimeBanks. However, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning methods</a> have not been applied to these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corpus_linguistics">corpora</a>, because these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> seldom contain more than 10,000 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Event_(probability_theory)">event mentions</a>. Traditional architectures revolve around highly feature engineered, language specific statistical models. In this paper, we present a Language Invariant Neural Event Detection (ALINED) architecture. ALINED uses an aggregation of both sub-word level features as well as lexical and structural information. This is achieved by combining convolution over character embeddings, with recurrent layers over contextual word embeddings. We find that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> extracts relevant <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> for event span identification without relying on language specific features. We compare the performance of our language invariant model to the current state-of-the-art in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_language">Spanish</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_language">Italian</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>. We outperform the F1-score of the state of the art in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> by 1.65 points. We achieve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Federation_of_the_Phonographic_Industry">F1-scores</a> of 84.96, 80.87 and 74.81 on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_language">Spanish</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_language">Italian</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a> respectively which is comparable to the current states of the art for these languages. We also introduce the automatic annotation of events in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a>, a low resource language, with an F1-Score of 77.13.</abstract>
      <url hash="dea3fc5f">2019.icon-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>prabhu-etal-2019-incorporating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Event Centric Entity Linking for Hindi News Articles : A Knowledge Graph Based Approach<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>indi News Articles: A Knowledge Graph Based Approach</title>
      <author><first>Pranav</first><last>Goel</last></author>
      <author><first>Suhan</first><last>Prabhu</last></author>
      <author><first>Alok</first><last>Debnath</last></author>
      <author><first>Manish</first><last>Shrivastava</last></author>
      <pages>45–55</pages>
      <abstract>We describe the development of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_graph">knowledge graph</a> from an event annotated corpus by presenting a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pipeline_(software)">pipeline</a> that identifies and extracts the relations between entities and events from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi news articles</a>. Due to the semantic implications of argument identification for events in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a>, we use a combined syntactic argument and semantic role identification methodology. To the best of our knowledge, no other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Architecture">architecture</a> exists for this purpose. The extracted combined role information is incorporated in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_graph">knowledge graph</a> that can be queried via subgraph extraction for basic questions. The architectures presented in this paper can be used for participant extraction and event-entity linking in most <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indo-Aryan_languages">Indo-Aryan languages</a>, due to similar syntactic and semantic properties of event arguments.</abstract>
      <url hash="fad8c55e">2019.icon-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>goel-etal-2019-event</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Non-native Accent Partitioning for Speakers of Indian Regional Languages<fixed-case>I</fixed-case>ndian Regional Languages</title>
      <author><first>Radha Krishna</first><last>Guntur</last></author>
      <author><first>Krishnan</first><last>Ramakrishnan</last></author>
      <author><first>Vinay Kumar</first><last>Mittal</last></author>
      <pages>65–74</pages>
      <abstract>Acoustic features extracted from the speech signal can help in identifying speaker related multiple information such as geographical origin, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regional_accents_of_English">regional accent</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nativity_of_Jesus">nativity</a>. In this paper, classification of native speakers of South Indian languages is carried out based upon the accent of their non-native language, i.e., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>. Four South Indian languages : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a> are examined. A database of English speech from the native speakers of these languages, along with the native language speech data was collected, from a non-overlapping set of speakers. Segment level acoustic features F0 and Mel-frequency cepstral coefficients (MFCCs) are used. Accent partitioning of non-native English speech data is carried out using multiple classifiers : k-nearest neighbour (KNN), <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_discriminant_analysis">linear discriminant analysis (LDA)</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Support_vector_machine">support vector machine (SVM)</a>, for validation and comparison of results. Classification accuracies of 86.6 % are observed using KNN, and 89.2 % or more than 90 % using SVM classifier. A study of acoustic feature F0 contour, related to L2 intonation, showed that native speakers of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada language</a> are quite distinct as compared to those of Tamil or Telugu languages. It is also observed that identification of Malayalam and Kannada speakers from their English speech accent is relatively easier than Telugu or Tamil speakers.</abstract>
      <url hash="fbe59409">2019.icon-1.8</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="65c25af3">2019.icon-1.8.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>guntur-etal-2019-non</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>A little perturbation makes a difference : Treebank augmentation by perturbation improves transfer parsing</title>
      <author><first>Ayan</first><last>Das</last></author>
      <author><first>Sudeshna</first><last>Sarkar</last></author>
      <pages>75–84</pages>
      <abstract>We present an approach for cross-lingual transfer of dependency parser so that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a> trained on a single source language can more effectively cater to diverse target languages. In this work, we show that the cross-lingual performance of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parsers</a> can be enhanced by over-generating the source language treebank. For this, the source language treebank is augmented with its perturbed version in which controlled perturbation is introduced in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parse_tree">parse trees</a> by stochastically reordering the positions of the dependents with respect to their heads while keeping the structure of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parse_tree">parse trees</a> unchanged. This enables the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a> to capture diverse syntactic patterns in addition to those that are found in the source language. The resulting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a> is found to more effectively parse target languages with different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax_(programming_languages)">syntactic structures</a>. With <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> as the source language, our system shows an average improvement of 6.7 % and 7.7 % in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_asynchronous_receiver-transmitter">UAS</a> and LAS over 29 target languages compared to the baseline single source parser trained using unperturbed source language treebank. This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an order-free parser algorithm.</abstract>
      <url hash="22d7c447">2019.icon-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>das-sarkar-2019-little</bibkey>
    <title_ar>القليل من الاضطراب يحدث فرقًا: زيادة Treebank عن طريق الاضطراب يحسن تحليل النقل</title_ar>
      <title_es>Una pequeña perturbación marca la diferencia: el aumento de Treebank por perturbación mejora el análisis de transferencias</title_es>
      <title_pt>Uma pequena perturbação faz a diferença: o aumento do Treebank por perturbação melhora a análise de transferência</title_pt>
      <title_ja>ちょっとした摂動が違いをもたらす：摂動によるツリーバンク増強は、転送構文解析を向上させる</title_ja>
      <title_hi>एक छोटी सी गड़बड़ी एक अंतर बनाता है: परेशानी द्वारा Treebank वृद्धि हस्तांतरण पार्सिंग में सुधार करता है</title_hi>
      <title_zh>一点扰动即有为:扰动增强树库可以改善传输解析</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Déanann beagán suaiteadh difríocht: feabhsaíonn méadú ar Bhruach na gCrann trí shuaitheadh an pharsáil aistrithe</title_ga>
      <title_el>Μια μικρή διαταραχή κάνει τη διαφορά: Η αύξηση της τράπεζας δέντρων με διαταραχή βελτιώνει την ανάλυση μεταφοράς</title_el>
      <title_hu>Egy kis perturbáció különbséget tesz: a fák perturbációval történő nagyobbítása javítja az átviteli elemzést</title_hu>
      <title_ka>ცოტა პერტურბაცია განსხვავებს: Treebank augmentation by perturbation improves transfer parsing</title_ka>
      <title_lt>Truputį perturbacija daro skirtumą: perturbacija padidina medžio banką gerina perdavimo analizę</title_lt>
      <title_it>Un po' di perturbazione fa la differenza: l'aumento del banco degli alberi da perturbazione migliora l'analisi del trasferimento</title_it>
      <title_kk>Кішкене белсендіру айырмашылығы: Treebank augmentation by turbation improves transfer parsing</title_kk>
      <title_mt>A little perturbation makes a difference: Treebank augmentation by perturbation improves transfer parsing</title_mt>
      <title_ml>കുറച്ച് കുഴപ്പമുണ്ടാക്കുന്നത് വ്യത്യാസം ഉണ്ടാക്കുന്നു: ട്രെബാങ്കിന്‍റെ കൂടുതല്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ മാറ</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Бага зэрэг эргэн тойронд өөрчлөгдөж байна: эргэн тойронд модны банкны нэмэлт нь</title_mn>
      <title_no>Ein liten perturbasjon gjer ein forskjell: Treebank augmentasjon ved perturbasjon forbedrar tolking av overføringar</title_no>
      <title_pl>Trochę zakłóceń robi różnicę: powiększenie banku drzewa poprzez zakłócenie poprawia parsowanie transferu</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Malo perturbacije čini razliku: povećanje Treebank-a perturbacijom poboljšava analizu prijenosa</title_sr>
      <title_ro>O mică perturbare face diferența: mărirea băncii copace prin perturbare îmbunătățește analiza transferului</title_ro>
      <title_si>පුංචි ප්‍රවේශනයක් වෙනස් කරනවා: ක්‍රීබැන්ක් විශාලනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය විශාලනය කරනවා</title_si>
      <title_sv>Lite störning gör skillnad: Treebank förstärkning genom störning förbättrar överföringstolkningen</title_sv>
      <title_so>Wax yar oo turjumista ah ayaa kala bedelaya: kordhinta Treebank waxey kordhisaa baarkiisa beddelka</title_so>
      <title_ta>ஒரு சிறிய மாறுபாடு வித்தியாசமாக்குகிறது: குழப்பமாக்குதல் மூலம் மாற்றுதல் பாசிங்கை மேம்படுத்துகிறது</title_ta>
      <title_ur>تھوڑی سی مصیبت فرق کرتی ہے: درخت بانک اضافہ کرتی ہے پرٹربیٹ کے ذریعہ ترنسیٹ پارسینگ کو اضافہ کرتی ہے</title_ur>
      <title_mk>Малку пертурбирање прави разлика: зголемувањето на дрвената банка со пертурбирање го подобрува пренесувањето</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Sedikit gangguan membuat perbezaan: peningkatan pokok dengan gangguan meningkatkan penghuraian pemindahan</title_ms>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Một chút phiền phức làm nên sự khác biệt: Tăng bậc cây cối do ô nhiễm cải tạo cải tiến phân tích.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Малко смущения прави разлика: увеличаването на дървесната банка чрез смущения подобрява трансферния анализ</title_bg>
      <title_da>Lidt forstyrrelse gør en forskel: Træbank forstørrelse ved forstyrrelse forbedrer overførsel parsing</title_da>
      <title_hr>Malo perturbacije čini razliku: povećanje Treebank-a perturbacijom poboljšava analizu prijenosa</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Een beetje verstoring maakt het verschil: Boombank augmentatie door verstoring verbetert transfer parsing</title_nl>
      <title_ko>약간의 소요가 발생하면 달라집니다: 소요 강화 트리 라이브러리를 통해 전송 분석을 개선할 수 있습니다</title_ko>
      <title_de>Ein wenig Störung macht den Unterschied: Baumbankvergrößerung durch Störung verbessert das Transferparsing</title_de>
      <title_id>A little perturbation makes a difference: Treebank augmentation by perturbation improves transfer parsing</title_id>
      <title_sw>Uvurugu mdogo unaleta tofauti: Kuongezeka kwa Treebank kwa mabadiliko yanaboresha mabadiliko ya usafirishaji</title_sw>
      <title_fa>یک تغییر کوچک تغییر می‌دهد: افزایش درخت بانک توسط تغییر تغییر تغییر تغییر</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Biraz turbasyon üýtgeşik edip getirir: perturbasyon bilen agaç küýtgeşigi terjime parsasyny geliştirir</title_tr>
      <title_hy>Մի փոքր անհանգստացողություն փոխում է. անհանգստացողության միջոցով ծառի աճը բարելավում է փոխանցման վերլուծությունը</title_hy>
      <title_am>A little perturbation makes a difference: Treebank augmentation by perturbation improves transfer parsing</title_am>
      <title_az>Biraz f톛rql톛ndirm톛k f톛rql톛ndirir:</title_az>
      <title_bn>সামান্য পার্টারেশন পার্সিং এর মাধ্যমে ট্রেবাঙ্ক বাড়িয়ে দিচ্ছে:</title_bn>
      <title_af>'n Klein perturbasie maak 'n verskil: Boom bank vergroot deur perturbasie verbeter oordrag verwerking</title_af>
      <title_cs>Malá porucha má rozdíl: Rozšíření stromové břehy pomocí poruchy zlepšuje analýzu přenosu</title_cs>
      <title_et>Väike häire teeb vahet: puupanga suurendamine häire abil parandab ülekande parsimist</title_et>
      <title_bs>Malo perturbacije čini razliku: povećanje Treebank-a perturbacijom poboljšava analiziranje prijenosa</title_bs>
      <title_fi>Pieni häiriö tekee eron: Treebank suurennus häiriöllä parantaa siirtojen jäsentämistä</title_fi>
      <title_ca>Una mica de perturbació fa una diferència: l'augment de la banca d'arbre per perturbació millora l'analisi de transfer ències</title_ca>
      <title_sq>Një shqetësim i vogël bën një ndryshim: rritja e bazës së pemëve nga shqetësimi përmirëson analizimin e transferit</title_sq>
      <title_jv>A little</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Malo motenj naredi razliko: povečanje drevesne banke z motnjo izboljšuje razčlenitev prenosa</title_sk>
      <title_ha>Ki ɗan turbatori na samar da rabo: Ƙaraɗar Treebank da perturbation na improve parse transfer</title_ha>
      <title_he>הפרעה קטנה משנה: גידול בין עצים על ידי הפרעה משפר את מחקר העברה</title_he>
      <title_bo>བརྒྱུད་འཕྲུལ་ཆེ་ཀྱི་ལས་ཀ་རྐྱེན་འདི་འདྲ་ཞིག་དང་།</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم طريقة لنقل عبر اللغات لمحلل التبعية بحيث يمكن للمحلل المدرب على لغة مصدر واحدة أن يلبي بشكل أكثر فاعلية اللغات المستهدفة المتنوعة. في هذا العمل ، نوضح أنه يمكن تحسين الأداء عبر اللغات للموزعين عن طريق الإفراط في إنشاء بنك شجرة اللغة المصدر. لهذا الغرض ، يتم تعزيز بنك شجرة اللغة المصدر بنسخته المضطربة التي يتم فيها إدخال الاضطراب الخاضع للرقابة في أشجار التحليل من خلال إعادة ترتيب مواقف المعالين بشكل عشوائي فيما يتعلق برؤوسهم مع الحفاظ على بنية أشجار التحليل دون تغيير. يمكّن هذا المحلل اللغوي من التقاط أنماط نحوية متنوعة بالإضافة إلى تلك الموجودة في اللغة المصدر. تم العثور على المحلل اللغوي الناتج لتحليل اللغات المستهدفة ذات الهياكل النحوية المختلفة بشكل أكثر فاعلية. مع اللغة الإنجليزية كلغة مصدر ، يُظهر نظامنا تحسنًا متوسطًا بنسبة 6.7٪ و 7.7٪ من حيث UAS و LAS أكثر من 29 لغة مستهدفة مقارنةً بالمحلل اللغوي الأساسي ذو المصدر الوحيد الذي تم تدريبه باستخدام بنك شجرة لغة المصدر غير المضطرب. ينتج عن هذا أيضًا تحسن كبير في محلل النقل الذي اقترحته (CITATION) والذي يتضمن خوارزمية محلل "بدون ترتيب".</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos un enfoque para la transferencia multilingüe del analizador de dependencias para que el analizador capacitado en un solo idioma de origen pueda atender de manera más efectiva a diversos idiomas de destino. En este trabajo, mostramos que el rendimiento multilingüe de los analizadores puede mejorarse mediante la sobregeneración del banco de árboles del idioma de origen. Para ello, el banco de árboles del lenguaje fuente se amplía con su versión perturbada en la que se introduce una perturbación controlada en los árboles de análisis sintáctico reordenando estocásticamente las posiciones de los dependientes con respecto a sus cabezas, manteniendo sin cambios la estructura de los árboles de análisis sintáctico. Esto permite que el analizador capture diversos patrones sintácticos además de los que se encuentran en el idioma de origen. Se ha descubierto que el analizador resultante analiza de manera más eficaz los idiomas de destino con diferentes estructuras sintácticas. Con el inglés como idioma de origen, nuestro sistema muestra una mejora promedio del 6,7% y el 7,7% en términos de UAS y LAS en 29 idiomas de destino en comparación con el analizador de una sola fuente de referencia entrenado con el banco de árboles del idioma de origen sin perturbaciones. Esto también da como resultado una mejora significativa con respecto al analizador de transferencia propuesto por (CITATION) que implica un algoritmo de análisis sintáctico «sin orden».</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos uma abordagem para transferência multilíngue do analisador de dependência para que o analisador treinado em um único idioma de origem possa atender com mais eficiência a diversos idiomas de destino. Neste trabalho, mostramos que o desempenho multilíngue dos analisadores sintáticos pode ser aprimorado pela supergeração do banco de árvores do idioma de origem. Para isso, o treebank da linguagem fonte é aumentado com sua versão perturbada na qual a perturbação controlada é introduzida nas árvores de análise reordenando estocasticamente as posições dos dependentes em relação às suas cabeças, mantendo a estrutura das árvores de análise inalterada. Isso permite que o analisador capture diversos padrões sintáticos além daqueles encontrados no idioma de origem. O analisador resultante é encontrado para analisar de forma mais eficaz as linguagens de destino com diferentes estruturas sintáticas. Com o inglês como idioma de origem, nosso sistema mostra uma melhoria média de 6,7% e 7,7% em termos de UAS e LAS em mais de 29 idiomas de destino em comparação com o analisador de origem única de linha de base treinado usando o banco de árvores de idioma de origem sem perturbações. Isso também resulta em uma melhoria significativa em relação ao analisador de transferência proposto por (CITATION) que envolve um algoritmo analisador “sem ordem”.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_hi>हम निर्भरता पार्सर के क्रॉस-लिंगुअल हस्तांतरण के लिए एक दृष्टिकोण प्रस्तुत करते हैं ताकि एकल स्रोत भाषा पर प्रशिक्षित पार्सर अधिक प्रभावी ढंग से विविध लक्ष्य भाषाओं को पूरा कर सके। इस काम में, हम दिखाते हैं कि पार्सर के क्रॉस-लिंगुअल प्रदर्शन को स्रोत भाषा ट्रीबैंक को अधिक उत्पन्न करके बढ़ाया जा सकता है। इसके लिए, स्रोत भाषा ट्रीबैंक को इसके परेशान संस्करण के साथ संवर्धित किया जाता है जिसमें पार्स पेड़ों की संरचना को अपरिवर्तित रखते हुए उनके सिर के संबंध में आश्रितों की स्थिति को फिर से व्यवस्थित करके पार्स के पेड़ों में नियंत्रित गड़बड़ी पेश की जाती है। यह पार्सर को स्रोत भाषा में पाए जाने वाले लोगों के अलावा विविध वाक्यात्मक पैटर्न को कैप्चर करने में सक्षम बनाता है। परिणामी पार्सर को विभिन्न वाक्यात्मक संरचनाओं के साथ लक्ष्य भाषाओं को अधिक प्रभावी ढंग से पार्स करने के लिए पाया जाता है। स्रोत भाषा के रूप में अंग्रेजी के साथ, हमारी प्रणाली यूएएस और एलएएस के संदर्भ में 6.7% और 7.7% का औसत सुधार दिखाती है, जो बेसलाइन एकल स्रोत पार्सर की तुलना में 29 लक्ष्य भाषाओं की तुलना में अनियंत्रित स्रोत भाषा ट्रीबैंक का उपयोग करके प्रशिक्षित की गई है। इसके परिणामस्वरूप (CITATION) द्वारा प्रस्तावित स्थानांतरण पार्सर पर भी महत्वपूर्ण सुधार होता है जिसमें "ऑर्डर-फ्री" पार्सर एल्गोरिथ्म शामिल होता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ja>単一のソース言語で訓練された構文解析器が多様なターゲット言語により効果的に対応できるように、依存関係構文解析器のクロスリンガル転送のためのアプローチを提示する。 この作業では、ソース言語ツリーバンクを過剰に生成することで、構文解析器のクロスリンガルパフォーマンスを向上させることができることを示します。 このため、ソース言語ツリーバンクは、構文解析木の構造を変えないままにしながら、依存関係者の頭部に対する位置を確率的に並べ替えることによって、構文解析木に制御された摂動が導入されるその摂動バージョンで拡張される。 これにより、構文解析器は、ソース言語に見られる構文パターンに加えて、多様な構文パターンを取り込むことができる。 結果として得られる構文解析器は、異なる構文構造を持つターゲット言語をより効果的に構文解析することが見出される。 英語をソース言語とすると、当社のシステムは、摂動されていないソース言語ツリーバンクを使用してトレーニングされたベースラインシングルソースパーサーと比較して、29のターゲット言語を超えるUASおよびLASの点で平均して6.7 ％および7.7 ％の改善を示します。 これはまた、「順序無し」構文解析器アルゴリズムを含む（引用）によって提案された転送構文解析器よりも大幅に改善される。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>吾言恃解析器之传输方法,以基单一源言之解析器可以迎合异端。 此等事,解析器跨语性,可以过生语言树库以益之。 由是源语树库因其扰版而强之,随机复序,依项相对,而持解析树之结构不变,引扰于解析树中受控。 此使解析器得诸语法式,及语言语法式也。 见生解析器可更效解析有异语法结构之语。 以英语为源言语,与用无扰动源言树库训练之基线单源解析器,吾等系于 29 种之 UAS 与 LAS 均升 6.7% 7.7%。 此亦(CITATION)言无序解析器算法之传输解析器显改也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid cur chuige i láthair maidir le haistriú tras-teanga parsálaí spleáchais ionas gur féidir leis an parsálaí atá oilte ar theanga foinse amháin freastal níos éifeachtaí ar sprioctheangacha éagsúla. Sa saothar seo, léirímid gur féidir feabhas a chur ar fheidhmíocht thrastheangach na bparsálaithe trí róghiniúint a dhéanamh ar chrainn na teanga foinse. Chuige seo, cuirtear leis an gcruach crann teanga foinse lena leagan suaite ina dtugtar suaite rialaithe isteach sna crainn pharsála trí shuíomhanna na gcleithiúnaithe a athordú go stocach i leith a gcinn agus struchtúr na gcrann parsála a choinneáil gan athrú. Ligeann sé seo don pharsálaí patrúin chomhréire ilghnéitheacha a ghabháil de bhreis orthu sin atá le fáil sa teanga fhoinseach. Faightear amach go ndéanann an parsálaí a bheidh mar thoradh air a pharsáil ar bhealach níos éifeachtaí sprioctheangacha le struchtúir chomhréire éagsúla. Agus an Béarla mar theanga foinseach againn, léiríonn ár gcóras feabhas 6.7% agus 7.7% ar an meán i dtéarmaí UAS agus LAS os cionn 29 sprioctheanga i gcomparáid leis an bparsálaí foinse aonair bonnlíne atá oilte ag baint úsáide as crann stór teanga foinse gan cur isteach. Mar thoradh air seo freisin tá feabhas suntasach ar an parsálaí aistrithe atá molta ag (CITATION) a bhaineann le algartam parsálaí “saor ó ordú”.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ მივიღებთ განსაცემებულობის პანსერერისთვის მრავალური ტრანსპერისთვის პროგრამა, რადგან პანსერისთვის, რომელიც ერთი მხოლოდ მხოლოდ ენაზე შეგვიძლია უფრო ამ სამუშაოში ჩვენ ჩვენ აჩვენებთ, რომ პარასერების მრავალენგური სამუშაო კონტაქტი შეიძლება უფრო მეტი წარმოიქმნათ სამუშაო ენის სამუშაო. ამისთვის, მისი პერტურბულ ვერსიით, რომელიც კონტროლურებული პერტურბულაციას პერტურბულაციაში ჩვენება პერტურბულაციას პერტურბულაციაში, რომელიც სტარქტიურად გადაწყენებულია პერტურბულაციას, სტარქტიურად ეს მოწყობილობის შესაძლებელია განსხვავებული სინტაქტიკური მონაცემების დამატებით, რომლებიც მიიღება მსოფლიო ენაში. შემდეგ პანელიზერი ძებნა სხვა სინტაქტიული სტრუქტურებით უფრო ეფექტიურად მინიშვნელოვანი ენების პანელიზაცია. ანგლისური ენაზე, ჩვენი სისტემა 6.7% და 7.7%-ის განმავლობაში, რომელიც UAS და LAS 29 მიზეზეზი ენაზე დამატებულია, რომელიც მხოლოდ ერთი მხოლოდ პანელიზატორი, რომელიც გამოყენებულია, რომელიც არ გა ეს შეიძლება ასევე გავამუშავება გადასრულებული გადასრულება გადასრულებული გადასრულება (CITATION) განსაზღვრებული გადასრულებაზე, რომელიც 'order-free' გადასრულებული' ალგორ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε μια προσέγγιση για τη διασυνοριακή μεταφορά του αναλυτή εξάρτησης έτσι ώστε ο αναλυτής εκπαιδευμένος σε μια γλώσσα προέλευσης να μπορεί να εξυπηρετήσει αποτελεσματικότερα διαφορετικές γλώσσες-στόχους. Σε αυτή την εργασία, δείχνουμε ότι η διαγώνια απόδοση των αναλύσεων μπορεί να ενισχυθεί με την υπερπαραγωγή της τράπεζας δέντρων της πηγής γλώσσας. Για το σκοπό αυτό, η βάση δέντρων της γλώσσας προέλευσης συμπληρώνεται με την διαταραγμένη εκδοχή της στην οποία εισάγεται ελεγχόμενη διαταραχή στα δένδρα αναλύοντας στοχαστικά τις θέσεις των εξαρτώμενων σε σχέση με τα κεφάλια τους διατηρώντας αμετάβλητη τη δομή των δέντρων. Αυτό επιτρέπει στον αναλυτή να συλλάβει διάφορα συντακτικά μοτίβα εκτός από αυτά που βρίσκονται στη γλώσσα προέλευσης. Ο αναλυτής που προκύπτει διαπιστώνεται ότι αναλύει πιο αποτελεσματικά τις γλώσσες-στόχους με διαφορετικές συντακτικές δομές. Με την αγγλική ως γλώσσα προέλευσης, το σύστημά μας δείχνει μια μέση βελτίωση 6.7% και 7.7% από την άποψη UAS και LAS σε σχέση με τις 29 γλώσσες-στόχους σε σύγκριση με τον αναλυτή ενιαίας πηγής που εκπαιδεύεται χρησιμοποιώντας μη διαταραγμένη βάση δέντρων γλώσσας πηγής. Αυτό οδηγεί επίσης σε σημαντική βελτίωση σε σχέση με τον αναλυτή μεταφοράς που προτείνεται από (που περιλαμβάνει έναν αλγόριθμο ανάλυσης χωρίς παραγγελία).</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Bemutatunk egy megközelítést a függőség-elemző többnyelvű átvitelére, hogy az egyetlen forrásnyelvre képzett elemző hatékonyabban tudja kielégíteni a különböző célnyelveket. Ebben a munkában megmutatjuk, hogy az elemzők többnyelvű teljesítménye javítható a forrásnyelv hármaságának túltermelésével. Ennek érdekében a forrásnyelvű fák torzított változatával kiegészülnek, amelyben a párzsfákban szabályozott perturbációt vezetnek be, sztochasztikusan átrendezve az eltartottak fejükhöz viszonyított pozícióját, miközben a párzsfák szerkezetét változatlanul tartják. Ez lehetővé teszi az elemző számára, hogy különböző szintaktikus mintákat rögzítsen a forrásnyelvben találhatókon kívül. A kapott elemző hatékonyabban elemezi a célnyelveket különböző szintaktikus struktúrákkal. Az angol nyelv mint forrásnyelv, rendszerünk átlagosan 6,7%-os, illetve 7,7%-os javulást mutat az UAS és LAS tekintetében 29 célnyelven, összehasonlítva a zavartalan forrásnyelvű treebank használatával képzett alapvető egyforráskódú elemzővel. Ez jelentős javulást eredményez a (CITATION) által javasolt transzfer elemzőhöz képest, amely egy "rendelésmentes" elemző algoritmust tartalmaz.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo un approccio per il trasferimento cross-lingual del parser di dipendenza in modo che il parser addestrato su una singola lingua di origine possa soddisfare più efficacemente diverse lingue di destinazione. In questo lavoro, mostriamo che le prestazioni cross-lingual dei parser possono essere migliorate generando troppo il treebank del linguaggio sorgente. Per questo, l'albero della lingua di origine viene ampliato con la sua versione perturbata in cui la perturbazione controllata viene introdotta negli alberi di parse riorganizzando stocasticamente le posizioni dei dipendenti rispetto alle loro teste mantenendo inalterata la struttura degli alberi di parse. Ciò consente al parser di catturare diversi modelli sintattici oltre a quelli che si trovano nella lingua di origine. Il parser risultante è trovato per analizzare più efficacemente le lingue di destinazione con diverse strutture sintattiche. Con l'inglese come lingua di origine, il nostro sistema mostra un miglioramento medio del 6,7% e del 7,7% in termini di UAS e LAS su 29 lingue di destinazione rispetto al parser di base single source addestrato utilizzando treebank della lingua di origine non perturbata. Questo comporta anche un miglioramento significativo rispetto al parser di trasferimento proposto da (CITATION) che prevede un algoritmo di parser 'order-free'.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Тәуелсіздік талдаушысының көп тілді аудару үшін тәуелсіздік аудару арқылы таңдаймыз, сондықтан бір көз тілде оқылған талдаушы көбірек тілдерге әртүрлі тілдерді кө Бұл жұмыс ішінде, талдаушылардың көптеген тілдердің көпшілігін көпшілік тілдерді құру үшін көптеген жұмыс істеуге болады. Бұл үшін көздегі тілдер бақылауы өзгертілген нұсқасынан көтеріледі. Бұл бақылау құрылғысын өзгертілмеген уақытта бақылау ағаштарында талдау ағаштарында сақталады. Бұл талдаушысы көзінің тілінде табылған синтактикалық үлгілерін қосымша, түрлі синтактикалық үлгілерді түсіруге мүмкіндік береді. Назардағы талдаушы басқа синтактикалық құрылғылармен мақсатты тілдерді оқу үшін табылды. Ағылшын тіліне көздегі тіл ретінде, жүйеміз 29 нақты тілден UAS және LAS тілдерінің орташа 6,7% және 7,7% дегенді көрсетеді. Бір негізгі көздегі талдау бағытты тіл бағыттамасынан салыстырылған бір бағытты талда Бұл сондай-ақ "order-free" талдаушы алгоритмі болады (CITATION) қолданылатын транспорттау талдаушының көбірек жақсартылығын өзгертеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Презентираме пристап за прекујазичен трансфер на анализатор на зависност за анализаторот обучен на еден извор јазик да може поефикасно да се погрижи за различните метни јазици. Во оваа работа, покажуваме дека прекујазичните резултати на анализаторите може да се подобрат преку генерирање на дрвото на изворниот јазик. За ова, групата на дрвјата на изворот јазик е зголемена со нејзината нервозна верзија во која се воведува контролирана пертурбирација во дрвјата на анализирање со стокастички реорганизација на позициите на зависниците во однос на нивните глави, додека структурата на дрвјата на анализирање не се менува. Ова овозможува анализаторот да сними различни синтактички шеми, покрај оние што се најдени во изворниот јазик. The resulting parser is found to more effectively parse target languages with different syntactic structures.  With English as the source language, our system shows an average improvement of 6.7% and 7.7% in terms of UAS and LAS over 29 target languages compared to the baseline single source parser trained using unperturbed source language treebank.  Ова, исто така, резултира со значително подобрување во однос на анализаторот на трансфер предложен од (CITATION) кој вклучува алгоритм на анализаторот „без наредба“.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>ആശ്രയിക്കുന്നതിന്റെ സ്ഥാനത്തിനുള്ള മാറ്റങ്ങള്‍ക്കുള്ള ക്രിസ്ലിങ്ഗല്‍ സ്വാധീനിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള ഒരു വഴിയാണ് ഞങ്ങള്‍ കൊ ഈ ജോലിയില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചു കൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു, പാര്‍സറുകളുടെ ക്രിസ്റ്റ് ലിങ്ക് പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ മുന്‍കൂട്ടുവാന്‍ സോ അതിന് വേണ്ടി, സ്രോതഭാഷ ട്രീബാങ്ക് അതിന്‍റെ കൂട്ടത്തില്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ കൂടുതലാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു. പാര്‍സ് വൃക്ഷങ്ങളുടെ സ്ഥാനം മാറ്റുമ്പോള്‍ പാര്‍സ് മരങ്ങളുടെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില ഉറവിട ഭാഷയില്‍ കണ്ടെത്തുന്നവയ്ക്ക് കൂടാതെ വ്യത്യസ്ത സിനിട്ടാക്റ്റിക് രീതികള്‍ പിടികൂടാന്‍ പ്രദര്‍ശി പരിഗണന ഭാഷകള്‍ വ്യത്യസ്ത സിനിട്ടാക്ടിക്കുറിച്ചുള്ള അടിസ്ഥാനങ്ങളുമായി കൂടുതല്‍ പാര്‍സ് ചെയ്യുന സ്രോതസ്സ് ഭാഷയായി ഇംഗ്ലീഷില്‍ ഞങ്ങളുടെ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ സാധാരണ മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്തിയിരിക്കുന്നു. യുഎസും ലാസും 29 ലക്ഷ്യഭാഷകളുമായി മെച്ചപ്പെടുത് ഇതിനും ഒരു 'ഓര്‍ഡര്‍- സ്വതന്ത്രമായ' പരാജയപ്രകാരം അല്‍ഗോരിതം ചേര്‍ത്തിരിക്കുന്ന Transfer Parser (CITATION) പ്രായശ്ചിത്തമായ മുന്നേറ്റ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>We present an approach for cross-lingual transfer of dependency parser so that the parser trained on a single source language can more effectively cater to diverse target languages.  F’dan ix-xogħol, naraw li l-prestazzjoni translingwistika tal-analizzaturi tista’ tittejjeb billi tiġi ġġenerata żżejjed il-bażi tas-siġar tal-lingwa tas-sors. Għal dan il-għan, il-bażi tas-siġar tal-lingwa tas-sors hija miżjuda bil-verżjoni perturbed tagħha li fiha tiġi introdotta perturbazzjoni kkontrollata fis-siġar tal-ipproċessar billi l-pożizzjonijiet tad-dipendenti jiġu rranġati mill-ġdid b’mod stokastiku fir-rigward tar-ras tagħhom filwaqt li l-istruttura tas-siġar tal-ipproċessar ma tinbidilx. Dan jippermetti li l-analizzatur jaqbad mudelli sintetiċi varji minbarra dawk li jinsabu fil-lingwa tas-sors. The resulting parser is found to more effectively parse target languages with different syntactic structures.  With English as the source language, our system shows an average improvement of 6.7% and 7.7% in terms of UAS and LAS over 29 target languages compared to the baseline single source parser trained using unperturbed source language treebank.  Dan jirriżulta wkoll f'titjib sinifikanti fuq il-analizzatur tat-trasferiment propost minn (CITATION) li jinvolvi algoritmu tal-analizzatur 'ħieles mill-ordni'.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_lt>Pateikiame tarpkalbinio priklausomybės analizatoriaus perdavimo metodą, kad vienoje šaltinio kalboje mokomas analizatorius galėtų veiksmingiau atsižvelgti į įvairias tikslines kalbas. Šiame darbe parodomi, kad analizatorių tarpkalbinį veiksmingumą galima pagerinti per daug sukuriant šaltinio kalbos medžio bazę. For this, the source language treebank is augmented with its perturbed version in which controlled perturbation is introduced in the parse trees by stochastically reordering the positions of the dependents with respect to their heads while keeping the structure of the parse trees unchanged.  Tai leidžia analizatoriui surinkti įvairius sintaksinius modelius, be tų, kurie randami šaltinio kalba. Nustatyta, kad atliktas analizatorius veiksmingiau analizuoja tikslines kalbas su skirtingomis sintaksinėmis struktūromis. Kadangi anglų kalba yra šaltinio kalba, mūsų sistema vidutiniškai pagerėjo 6,7 % ir 7,7 % UAS ir LAS atžvilgiu daugiau kaip 29 tikslinėmis kalbomis, palyginti su pradiniu vieno šaltinio analizatoriumi, parengtu naudojant neapdorotą šaltinio kalbos medžio bazę. This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an 'order-free' parser algorithm.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>We present an approach for cross-lingual transfer of dependency parser so that the parser trained on a single source language can more effectively cater to diverse target languages.  In this work, we show that the cross-lingual performance of the parsers can be enhanced by over-generating the source language treebank.  Untuk ini, pangkalan pepohonan bahasa sumber ditambah dengan versi terganggu di mana perturbasi kawalan diperkenalkan dalam pepohonan hurai-hurai dengan stokastik mengubah kedudukan dependen terhadap kepala mereka sementara struktur pepohonan hurai-hurai tidak berubah. Ini membenarkan penghurai untuk menangkap corak sintaktik berbeza selain daripada corak yang ditemui dalam bahasa sumber. The resulting parser is found to more effectively parse target languages with different syntactic structures.  Dengan bahasa Inggeris sebagai bahasa sumber, sistem kita menunjukkan peningkatan rata-rata 6.7% dan 7.7% dalam terma UAS dan LAS lebih dari 29 bahasa sasaran dibandingkan dengan penghurai sumber tunggal as as dilatih menggunakan pangkalan pohon bahasa sumber yang tidak diubah. This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an 'order-free' parser algorithm.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_pl>Przedstawiamy podejście do transferu zależności między językami, dzięki czemu parser przeszkolony na jednym języku źródłowym może skuteczniej obsługiwać różne języki docelowe. W niniejszej pracy pokazujemy, że wydajność parserów można zwiększyć poprzez nadmierne generowanie bazy drzew języka źródłowego. W tym celu baza drzew języka źródłowego jest rozszerzona o wersję zakłóconą, w której kontrolowana zakłócenie jest wprowadzana w drzewach parse poprzez stochastyczne zmiany pozycji zależnych w stosunku do ich głów przy jednoczesnym zachowaniu struktury drzew parse niezmienionej. Umożliwia to parser przechwytywanie różnych wzorców składni oprócz tych, które znajdują się w języku źródłowym. Wynikowy parser okazuje się, że skuteczniej parsuje języki docelowe z różnymi strukturami składni. Z angielskim jako językiem źródłowym nasz system wykazuje średnią poprawę 6,7% i 7,7% pod względem UAS i LAS w porównaniu do 29 języków docelowych w porównaniu z bazowym parserem pojedynczego źródła przeszkolonym przy użyciu niezakłóconej bazy języka źródłowego. Skutkuje to również znaczącą poprawę w stosunku do parsera transferu proponowanego przez (CITATION), który obejmuje algorytm parsera bez zamówienia.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Vă prezentăm o abordare pentru transferul interlingv al analizorului de dependență, astfel încât analizorul instruit pe o singură limbă sursă poate satisface mai eficient diverse limbi țintă. În această lucrare, arătăm că performanța cross-lingvistică a parserelor poate fi îmbunătățită prin supra-generarea brak-ului de limbă sursă. Pentru aceasta, limbajul sursă al copacilor este amplificat cu versiunea sa perturbată în care perturbarea controlată este introdusă în copacii de pătrunjeri prin reordonarea stocastică a pozițiilor dependenților în raport cu capetele lor, menținând structura pătrunjerilor neschimbată. Acest lucru permite parserului să capteze diverse modele sintactice în plus față de cele care se găsesc în limba sursă. Analizorul rezultat este găsit pentru a analiza mai eficient limbile țintă cu diferite structuri sintactice. Cu limba engleză ca limbă sursă, sistemul nostru arată o îmbunătățire medie de 6,7% și 7,7% în ceea ce privește UAS și LAS peste 29 de limbi țintă comparativ cu analizorul de bază unic sursă instruit folosind treebank-ul limbajului sursă neperturbat. Acest lucru duce, de asemenea, la o îmbunătățire semnificativă față de parserul de transfer propus de (CITATION) care implică un algoritm de parser "fără ordine".</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer ein tilnærming for cross-language transfer of dependency parser so that the parser trained on a single source language can more effectively cater to different target languages. I denne arbeida viser vi at den krysspråksfunksjonen av tolkaren kan forbetrast ved å laga overføringar av kjeldespråkstrykket. Dette er den kjeldespråkstrebanen auka med den perturberte versjonen der kontrollerte perturbasjon vert introdusert i tolkingstemmen ved å stokastisk reorderera posisjonen av avhengige med respekt til hodene, mens strukturen av tolkingstemmene er ikkje endra. Dette slår på at tolkaren skal henta ulike syntaksiske mønsterelement i tillegg til dei som finst i kjeldespråket. Det er funne å tolka målspråk meir effektivt med ulike syntaktiske strukturar. Med engelsk som kjeldespråket viser systemet vårt gjennomsnittlig forbetringa av 6,7 % og 7,7 % i uttrykk av UAS og LAS over 29 målspråk, samanlikna med baseline enkelt kjeldetolkar som treng med ugjennomsiktig kjeldespråk. Dette fører også til signifikante forbedringar over overføringslagstolkaren som foreslår av (CITATION) som involverer ein "rekkefølgje fri" tolkaralgoritme.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo pristup preko jezika prebacivanja ovisnosti analizatora kako bi analizator obučen na jednom izvornom jeziku mogao učinkovitiji prihvatiti različite ciljne jezike. U ovom poslu, pokazujemo da se međujezička izvedba parsera može poboljšati preko generacije izvornog jezika. Za to se izvorni jezik treeban povećava sa svojom perturbiranom verzijom u kojoj se kontrolirana perturbacija uvede u drveće za analizu stokastički reordinirajući pozicije ovisnika u pogledu glave dok drže strukturu drveća za analizu ne menja. To omogućava analizatoru da uhvati različite sintaktičke obrasce, dodatno onima koji su pronađeni na izvornom jeziku. Nalazi se rezultat analizatora da učinkovitije analizira ciljne jezike sa različitim sintaktičkim strukturama. S engleskim kao izvornom jezikom, naš sistem pokazuje prosjeèno poboljšanje od 6,7% i 7,7% u odnosu na UAS i LAS preko 29 ciljnih jezika u usporedbi sa početnim jedinim izvornim analizatorom koji je obučen sa nepromištenim jezikom. To je takođe rezultat značajnog poboljšanja nad analizatorom prijenosa predloženim (CITATION) koji uključuje algoritam "besplatnog" analizatora.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu soo bandhignaynaa qaab u wareejinta luuqadaha ku xiran ee ku xiran ku saabsan baaritaanka, si baaritaanka lagu baray luqada hal luqad oo aad u faa’iido ah oo luuqado kala duduwan. Shuqulkaas waxaynu muujinnaa in baarlamayaasha baarlamaha lagu sameeyo lagu kordhin karo qoraalka luqada ah oo aad u kordhin karto. Sababtaas darteed waxaa lagu kordhiyey warqada afka asalka ah treebank, kaas oo lagu maamulaa dhaqdhaqaaq, oo lagu soo daahiriyaa geedaha baarlamaanka, iyadoo lagu hagaajiyaa qaybaha ay kuwa ku xiran yihiin madaxooda, inta ay haystaan dhismaha geedaha baarlamaanka. Taas waxaa ku habboon kara baaritaanku inuu qabsado qaabab kala duduwan oo la xiriira kuwa lagu helay luqada asalka ah. The resulting parser is found to more effectively parse target languages with different syntactic structures.  With English as the source language, our system shows an average improvement of 6.7% and 7.7% in terms of UAS and LAS over 29 target languages compared to the baseline single source parser trained using unperturbed source language treebank.  Taas waxaa sidoo kale ka soo jeeda hagaajinta badbaadada la wareejiyo (CITATION) oo ku saabsan algorithm 'order-free' Parser algorithm.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>අපි භාෂාවක් විශේෂ විශේෂකයේ විශේෂතාවක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රවේශයක් තියෙන්නේ, ඉතින් එක මුළු භාෂාවට ප්‍රවේශ මේ වැඩේ අපි පෙන්වන්නේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් විශාල භාෂාව ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙන්න පුළුවන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් භා මේකෙන්, මුළු භාෂාව ට්‍රීබැන්ක් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂය කරලා තියෙන්නේ මුළු භාෂාව සංවිධානය කරලා තියෙන්නේ මුළු භාෂාව සංවිධානය කරලා ත මේක සක්‍රිය කරනවා විවිධ සංකේතික පෙට්ටර් එක්ක මුළු භාෂයේ හොයාගෙන ඉන්න අනුවෙන් විවිධ සංකේත ප්‍රතිචාර විශාලකය හොයාගත්තා වෙනස් සංකේතික සංවිධානය සඳහා ලක්ෂණ භාෂාව විශාලනය ඉංග්‍රීසි භාෂා වලින්, අපේ පද්ධතිය 6.7% සහ 7.7% වලින් ඉලක්ෂ භාෂා 29 වලින් UAS සහ LAS වලින් සාමාන්‍ය විශේෂණය පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන් විදි මේක තමයි 'ක්‍රමය-නිදහස්' පරීක්ෂක අල්ගෝරිතම් වලින් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න ප්‍රයෝජනය විශ්වාස කරනවා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_mn>Бид хэл олон хамааралтай хуваалцааны шилжүүлэх арга замыг тайлбарлаж байна. Тиймээс нэг эх үүсвэрийн хэл дээр сургалтын хуваалцагч нь олон зорилготой хэл дээр илүү үр дүнтэй холбоотой болно. Энэ ажил дээр бид судлаачидын олон хэлний үйл ажиллагааг эх үүсвэрийн хэлний загвар дээр нэмэгдүүлж чадна. Үүний тулд эх үүсвэрийн хэл дагуулын хөгжлийн хөгжлийн хувилбар нэмэгддэг. Энэ нь хуваалцааны модонд хуваалцах модод хамааралтай хүмүүсийн нөхцөлийг толгойгоо харьцуулж, хуваалцах модонуудын бүтэц өөрчлөгдсөн үед хуваалцах боломжтой болго Энэ нь ажиллагчид эх үүсвэрийн хэл дээр олон олон синтактикийн загваруудыг авах боломжтой болгодог. Үүний үр дүнтэй ажиллагч нь зориулагдсан хэлнүүдийг өөр шинжлэх ухааны бүтцийг илүү үр дүнтэй хуваалцах болно. Англи хэлний эх үүсвэрийн хэл болгон бидний систем UAS болон LAS 29 зорилготой хэлний хувьд дундаж 6.7% болон 7.7% дэвшилтэй харьцуулдаг. Газрын эх үүсвэрийн хуваагч нь анхны эх үүсвэрийн хуваагч хэлний сургалтыг ашиглаж сургалтын Энэ нь мөн "order-free" хуваарилагчийн алгоритмыг нэмэгдүүлэх (CITATION) санал болгон шилжүүлэх хуваарилагч дээр маш чухал сайжруулах боломжтой.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar ett tillvägagångssätt för korspråkig överföring av beroendetolkare så att tolkaren utbildad på ett enda källspråk mer effektivt kan tillgodose olika målspråk. I detta arbete visar vi att tolkningarnas tvärspråkliga prestanda kan förbättras genom att övergenerera källspråkets trädbank. För detta utökas källspråkets trädbank med dess störda version där kontrollerad störning introduceras i parsträden genom att stokastiskt omorganisera positionerna för de beroendes i förhållande till deras huvuden samtidigt som parsträdens struktur hålls oförändrad. Detta gör det möjligt för tolkaren att fånga olika syntaktiska mönster utöver de som finns i källspråket. Den resulterande tolkaren har visat sig mer effektivt tolka målspråk med olika syntaktiska strukturer. Med engelska som källspråk visar vårt system en genomsnittlig förbättring på 6,7% och 7,7% i termer av UAS och LAS över 29 målspråk jämfört med baslinjetolkningen av enstaka källkod utbildad med oprerterad källspråks treebank. Detta resulterar också i betydande förbättring jämfört med överföringsparsern föreslagen av (CITATION) som involverar en "orderfri" parseralgoritm.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>We present an approach for cross-lingual transfer of dependency parser so that the parser trained on a single source language can more effectively cater to diverse target languages.  இந்த வேலையில், நாம் காண்பிக்கிறோம் பார்சர்களின் குறியீட்டு மொழி மொழி ட்ரீபாங் மூலம் உருவாக்க முடியும். இதற்காக, மூல மொழி treebank அதிகப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பதிப்புடன் அதிகப்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, அதில் கட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட பச்சை மரங்களில் கட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, சார்ந்தவர்கள் தங்கள் தலைகளை மாற் This enables the parser to capture diverse syntactic patterns in addition to those that are found in the source language.  @ info: whatsthis மூல மொழி போன்ற ஆங்கிலத்தில், எங்கள் கணினியில் UAS மற்றும் LAS 29 இலக்க மொழிகளில் சராசரியான முன்னேற்றத்தை காட்டுகிறது மூல மொழியை பயிற்சி செய்யாத மூலம்  இதும் முன்னேற்றத்தை முன்னேற்றும் முன்னேற்றத்தை கொண்டு 'வரிசை- இலவச' பரிமாற்றி அல்கோரிட்டம் சேர்க்கிறது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم ایک مطابق زبان کے متوسط زبان کا انتقال پارچر کے لئے ایک طریقہ پیش کرتے ہیں تاکہ پارچر ایک سراسر زبان پر آموزش کی جاتی ہے اس طرح مختلف موجود زبانوں کے لئے زیادہ اثرات کے ساتھ استعمال کرسکتا ہے. ہم اس کام میں دکھاتے ہیں کہ پارس کے کثیر زبان کے عملکرد کو سورج زبان کی تربیب سے زیادہ پیدا کر کے زیادہ بڑھا سکتے ہیں۔ اس کے لیے، سورج زبان تریب بانک اس کی مختلف ورزی سے بڑھا جاتا ہے جس میں کنٹرول کی پرٹربی درختوں میں پارس کے درختوں میں پیش کیا جاتا ہے اس طرح مضبوط طور پر ان کے سروں کے معاملہ سے مسلط موقعیت کو دوبارہ تغییر دیتا ہے جب کہ پارس درختوں کی ساخت بدل نہیں جاتی۔ یہ پارچر کو مختلف سینٹاکتیک پٹرنے کے لئے اس کے علاوہ بھی ممکن ہے جو سورج زبان میں پائی جاتی ہے۔ نتیجہ پارچر کو مختلف سینٹاکٹیک ساختاروں کے ساتھ موجود زبانوں کو زیادہ اثبات کے ساتھ پارچس کرنے کے لئے پایا گیا ہے. انگلیسی کے ساتھ سورس زبان کے طور پر، ہماری سیسٹم 6.7% اور 7.7% کے متوسط عمدہ کو UAS اور LAS کے 29 موقع زبانوں پر مطابق بیس لین یوں سورس پارٹر کے مطابق جو غیر محسوب سورس زبان تریب کے مطابق تعلیم کی جاتی ہے۔ یہ بھی بہت اچھی تغییر پارسیٹر (CITATION) کے ذریعہ سے پیش کیا گیا ہے جو ایک 'order-free' پارسیٹر الگوریتم میں شامل ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi đưa ra một phương pháp chuyển giao ngôn ngữ khác nhau của phân tích phụ thuộc để vị cha xứ được đào tạo trên một ngôn ngữ độc mã có thể cung cấp hiệu quả cho các ngôn ngữ khác nhau. Trong công việc này, chúng tôi cho thấy khả năng ngôn ngữ khác nhau của các phân viên có thể tăng cường nhờ phát điện phát quá nhiều ngôn ngữ nguồn. Cho việc này, ngôn ngữ phát ngôn ngữ phổ biến sẽ được tăng thêm với phiên bản xáo trộn của nó, trong đó sẽ được phép gây rối ở các cây phân phân phân, bằng cách điều chỉnh lại các vị trí của người phụ thuộc về đầu của họ, trong khi cấu trúc của cây phân tách không thay đổi. Điều này cho phép phân tách các mô hình cú pháp khác nhau, cùng với các mô hình được tìm thấy trong ngôn ngữ nguồn. Kết quả phân tách ngôn ngữ đích với cấu trúc cú pháp khác nhau. Với tiếng Anh là ngôn ngữ nguồn, hệ thống của chúng tôi cho thấy một cải tiến trung bình của 6.7. và 7.7. Với dạng UAS và LAS trên 29 là ngôn ngữ tiêu điểm so với một phân tách nguyên mẫu được đào tạo bằng ngôn ngữ nguồn chưa sửa đổi. Điều này cũng dẫn đến một sự cải tiến đáng kể so với phân tích chuyển nhượng do lập trình được đề nghị bởi "Bộ phân tách lệnh".</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Biz tashqi tilni boshqa tillar tarjima qilish uchun qoʻllanmiz, shunday qilib, bitta manba tilda o'rganish imkoniyatini bir xil tilda o'rganish tilida qo'llaniladi. Bu ishda, biz parserlarning har xil tillar bajarishini ko'rsatishimiz mumkin, manba tilning tili treebank bilan bir necha ishlab chiqarishi mumkin. Bu uchun, manba tili treebank bir xil versiyasi bilan qo'shiladi. Bu parcha daraxtda turbatning boshqaruvchisi bo'ladi. Ularning boshqaruvchilari bilan boshqarishda qo'llanmalarning joylarini o'zgartirish mumkin. @ info @ info: status Ingliz tilida, bizning tizimimizning o'rtacha o'zgarishlar uchun UAS va LAS 29 dan ortiq so'zlar davomida o'zgarishga o'rganish mumkin, bizning o'rtacha o'zgarishni o'rganish mumkin. Bu yerda tarjima berilgan tarjima parametrlarining (CITATION) 'order- free' parameter algorithm' ga bogʻliq boʻlgan tarjima parametrlariga juda katta yaxshi bajaradi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме подход за междуезичен трансфер на анализатор на зависимост, така че анализаторът, обучен на един изходен език, да може по-ефективно да обслужва различни целеви езици. В тази работа показваме, че междуезичното представяне на анализаторите може да бъде подобрено чрез свръхгенериране на изходния език. За тази цел източният език се увеличава с неговата смущаваща версия, в която се въвежда контролирана смущаване в парсните дървета чрез стохастично пренареждане на позициите на зависимите по отношение на главите им, като същевременно се запазва структурата на парсните дървета непроменена. Това позволява на анализатора да улавя различни синтактични модели в допълнение към тези, които се намират в изходния език. Полученият анализатор е установен, че по-ефективно анализира целевите езици с различни синтактични структури. С английския език като изходен език, нашата система показва средно подобрение от 6,7% и 7,7% по отношение на UAS и LAS над 29 целеви езика в сравнение с базовия анализатор на единичен източник, обучен с използване на неспокоен изходен език трибанк. Това също води до значително подобрение в сравнение с трансферния анализатор, предложен от (CITATION), който включва алгоритъм "без поръчка" анализатор.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren een aanpak voor cross-lingual transfer van dependence parser, zodat de parser getraind op een enkele brontaal effectiever kan inspelen op diverse doeltalen. In dit werk laten we zien dat de cross-lingual performance van de parsers kan worden verbeterd door de boombank van de brontaal te overgenereren. Hiervoor wordt de boombank van de brontaal uitgebreid met zijn gestoorde versie waarin gecontroleerde verstoring in de parse bomen wordt geïntroduceerd door stochastisch de posities van de afhankelijke personen ten opzichte van hun hoofden te herschikken terwijl de structuur van de parse bomen ongewijzigd blijft. Dit stelt de parser in staat om verschillende syntactische patronen vast te leggen naast die die in de brontaal worden gevonden. De resulterende parser wordt gevonden om doeltalen effectiever te parsen met verschillende syntactische structuren. Met Engels als brontaal toont ons systeem een gemiddelde verbetering van 6.7% en 7.7% in termen van UAS en LAS ten opzichte van 29 doeltalen in vergelijking met de baseline single source parser die is getraind met behulp van onbestoorde brontaalboombank. Dit resulteert ook in een significante verbetering ten opzichte van de transfer parser voorgesteld door (CITATION) die een 'order-free' parser algoritme omvat.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Predstavljamo pristup preko jezika prebacivanja ovisnosti analizatora kako bi analizator obučen na jednom izvornom jeziku mogao učinkovitiji prihvatiti različite ciljne jezike. U ovom poslu pokazujemo da se međujezički učinkoviti parsera može poboljšati preko generacije izvornog jezika. Za to se izvorni jezik treeban povećava sa svojom perturbiranom verzijom u kojoj se kontrolirana perturbacija uvodi u analiziranje drvećem stokastički reordinirajući položaje ovisnika u pogledu glave dok drže strukturu drveća za analiziranje nepromijenjene. To omogućava analizatoru da uhvati različite sintaktičke obrasce osim onih koji su pronađeni na izvornom jeziku. Nalazi se rezultat analizatora da učinkovitije analizira ciljne jezike s različitim sintaktičkim strukturama. S engleskim kao izvornom jezikom, naš sustav pokazuje prosječan poboljšanje od 6,7% i 7,7% u smislu UAS-a i LAS-a preko 29 ciljnih jezika u usporedbi s početnom jedinstvenom izvornom analizatorom obučenim s nepromijenjenim jezikom. To također rezultira značajno poboljšanje nad analizatorom prijenosa predloženim (CITATION) koji uključuje algoritam "besplatnog" analizatora.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer en tilgang til tværsproget overførsel af afhængighedsfortolker, så fortolkeren trænet på et enkelt kildesprog mere effektivt kan imødekomme forskellige målsprog. I dette arbejde viser vi, at fortolkernes tværsprogede ydeevne kan forbedres ved at overgenerere kildesprogets treebank. Til dette forstærkes kildesprogets træbank med sin forstyrrede version, hvor kontrolleret forstyrrelse indføres i parsetræerne ved stokastisk omordning af de afhængige personers positioner i forhold til deres hoveder, samtidig med at parsetræernes struktur holdes uændret. Dette gør det muligt for fortolkeren at fange forskellige syntaktiske mønstre ud over dem, der findes i kildesproget. Den resulterende fortolker er fundet til mere effektivt at fortolke målsprog med forskellige syntaktiske strukturer. Med engelsk som kildesprog viser vores system en gennemsnitlig forbedring på 6,7% og 7,7% i form af UAS og LAS over 29 målsprog sammenlignet med basislinjen single source parser uddannet ved hjælp af uforstyrret kildesprog treebank. Dette resulterer også i en betydelig forbedring i forhold til overførsel parser foreslået af (CITATION), der involverer en 'ordre-fri' parser algoritme.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 해상기에 의존하는 다중 언어 이동 방법을 제시하여 단일 원시 언어에서 훈련된 해상기가 서로 다른 목표 언어에 더욱 효과적으로 적응할 수 있도록 했다.이 작업에서 우리는 과도한 원본 언어 트리 라이브러리 생성을 통해 해석기의 다중 언어 성능을 향상시킬 수 있음을 보여 주었다.이를 위해 원시 언어 트리 라이브러리는 교란 버전을 통해 확장되었고 해석 트리의 구조가 변하지 않는 상황에서 종속 트리의 머리 위치에 대한 무작위 재배열을 통해 해석 트리에 통제 교란을 도입했다.이로써 해석기는 원시 언어에 존재하는 문법 모델 이외의 각종 문법 모델을 포착할 수 있다.그 결과 생성된 해석기는 서로 다른 문법 구조를 가진 목표 언어를 더욱 효과적으로 해석할 수 있다는 것을 발견했다.영어를 원본언어로 하여 방해받지 않은 원본언어 트리 라이브러리 훈련을 사용하는 기선 단원해상도에 비해 우리 시스템은 29개 목표언어에서 UAS와 LAS가 평균 6.7%와 7.7% 높아졌다.이것 또한 (인용문)에서 제기한 전송 해상도에 대한 현저한 개선을 초래했다. 이 해상도는'무순서'해상도 알고리즘과 관련된다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>Wir stellen einen Ansatz für den sprachübergreifenden Transfer von Dependency Parser vor, damit der Parser, der auf einer einzigen Quellsprache trainiert ist, effektiver auf verschiedene Zielsprachen eingehen kann. In dieser Arbeit zeigen wir, dass die sprachübergreifende Leistung der Parser durch Übergenerierung der Quellsprachenbank verbessert werden kann. Dazu wird die Quellsprachenbank um ihre gestörte Version erweitert, in der kontrollierte Störung in die Parse-Bäume eingeführt wird, indem die Positionen der Abhängigkeiten in Bezug auf ihre Köpfe stochastisch neu geordnet werden, während die Struktur der Parse-Bäume unverändert bleibt. Dadurch kann der Parser zusätzlich zu den in der Ausgangssprache gefundenen syntaktischen Mustern auch verschiedene syntaktische Muster erfassen. Der resultierende Parser analysiert Zielsprachen mit unterschiedlichen syntaktischen Strukturen effektiver. Mit Englisch als Ausgangssprache zeigt unser System eine durchschnittliche Verbesserung von 6,7% und 7,7% in Bezug auf UAS und LAS gegenüber 29 Zielsprachen im Vergleich zu dem Baseline Single Source Parser, der mit ungestörter Quellsprachenbank trainiert wurde. Dies führt auch zu einer signifikanten Verbesserung gegenüber dem von (CITATION) vorgeschlagenen Transferparser, der einen "ordnungsfreien" Parser-Algorithmus beinhaltet.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_tr>Biz adat챌a diller baglanylyk tans챌ysyny흫 g철챌체rmesi 체챌in bir golla힊dyr첵arys 힊onu흫 체챌in t채ze bir 챌e힊me dilinde bilim tans챌ysyny흫 be첵leki maksady dillerini 첵erine 첵etirsin. Bu i힊de, parsad챌ylary흫 챌arpaky diller 체챌in 챌e힊me dilini흫 챌yky힊yny t채zeden d철redip gelip biljekdigini g철rke첵채ris. Bu 체챌in, 챌e힊me dil baglan챌y aga챌lary흫 strukturyny 체첵tgetme첵채n 챌yky힊 s체r체mi bilen 체첵tgedi. Bu 챌e힊me dilinde tapyl첵an 첵agda첵lary흫 체stine 챌e힊itli sintaktik d체zlerni yakalamagy m체mkin ed첵채r. Netij채n 챌철z체mler tapyl첵ar, be첵leki sintaktik d체z체mler bilen maksady흫 dillerini ahtarmak 체챌in daha t채sirli 챌철zmek 체챌in tapyldy. I흫lis챌e 챌e힊me dili bolup, sistemimiz 6.7% we 7.7% di첵ip UAS we LAS bilimi 29 maksady dilinde bilinen be첵ik 챌e힊me pa첵la힊챌ysy bilen tertiblenen be첵ik 챌e힊me pa첵la힊챌ysy bilen g철rkezil첵채r. Bu da 'order-free' t채ze bir tansi첵et챌i algoritmi bilen teklip eden transferi tansi첵et챌isi 체st체nde m철h체m geli힊meler bolar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Ons stel 'n toegang voor die kruistale oordrag van afhanklikheidspanseerder so dat die ontvanger wat op 'n enkele bron taal opgelei is, meer effektief kan kateer na verskeie doel tale. In hierdie werk, wys ons dat die kruistale prestasie van die verwerkers kan verbeter word deur die oorsaak van die bron taal treebank te genereer. Vir hierdie is die bron taal treebank vergroot met sy perturbeerde weergawe waarin die kontroleerde perturbasie in die verwerking bome ingevoer word deur stokasteel herordening van die posisies van die afhanklike met respek na hul koppe terwyl die struktuur van die verwerking bome onverander hou. Hierdie aktiveer die ontwerker om verskeie sintaktieke patrone in bygevoeg aan die wat in die bron taal gevind word. Die resulteerde ontleerder is gevind na meer effektief ontleed doel tale met verskillende sintaktieke strukture. Met Engels as die bron taal, vertoon ons stelsel 'n gemiddelde verbetering van 6.7% en 7.7% in terms van UAS en LAS oor 29 doel tale vergelyk met die basilyn enkel bron ontwerker wat opgelei word deur onverwerp bron taal treibank. Hierdie resultaat ook in betaling verbetering oor die oordrag-ontleerder wat deur (KITATION) voorgestel word wat 'n 'volgorde-vry' ontleerder algoritme insluit.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_fa>ما یک روش برای انتقال متفاوت زبان‌های متفاوت از متقاعد بستگی را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم تا متقاعد بر یک زبان منبع آموزش داده شود تا به زبان‌های متفاوت هدف بیشتری به کار برساند. در این کار، ما نشان می دهیم که عملکرد متفاوت زبان‌های متفاوت‌کننده‌ها می‌توانند با تولید زیادی از تولید درخت‌های زبان منبع بیشتر بشوند. برای این، ترکیب زبان منبع با نسخه‌ی متغییر خود افزایش می‌شود که در درخت‌های متغییر کنترل می‌شود با توجه به جایگاهی بستگی‌ها با نسبت به سرشان در حالی که ساختار درخت‌های متغییر را بدون تغییر نگه می‌دارد. این باعث می‌شود پالایشگر الگوهای سنتاکتیک مختلف را در اضافه به آن‌ها که در زبان منبع یافته‌اند بگیرد. ویرایشگر نتیجه یافت می‌شود که زبانهای هدف را با ساختارهای سنتاکتیک متفاوت بیشتر بررسی می‌کند. با انگلیسی به عنوان زبان منبع، سیستم ما با استفاده از ترکیب زبان منبع متوسط 6.7 درصد و 7.7 درصد به عنوان زبان UAS و LAS بیش از 29 زبان هدف را در مقایسه با متخصص یک منبع منبع بنیادی آموزش داده می‌شود. این همچنین به نتیجه توسط تقسیم انتقال (CITATION) پیشنهاد می‌کند که با یک الگوریتم تقسیم‌کننده «آزاد دستور» شامل می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Kami mempersembahkan pendekatan untuk transfer saling bahasa dari parser dependensi sehingga parser dilatih pada bahasa sumber tunggal dapat lebih efektif menjaga bahasa sasaran yang berbeda. Dalam pekerjaan ini, kami menunjukkan bahwa pertunjukan saling bahasa parser dapat diperbaiki dengan menghasilkan lebih dari generasi pangkalan pohon bahasa sumber. For this, the source language treebank is augmented with its perturbed version in which controlled perturbation is introduced in the parse trees by stochastically reordering the positions of the dependents with respect to their heads while keeping the structure of the parse trees unchanged.  This enables the parser to capture diverse syntactic patterns in addition to those that are found in the source language.  Penanalis hasilnya ditemukan untuk menghurai bahasa sasaran dengan struktur sintaksi yang berbeda dengan lebih efektif. With English as the source language, our system shows an average improvement of 6.7% and 7.7% in terms of UAS and LAS over 29 target languages compared to the baseline single source parser trained using unperturbed source language treebank.  This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an 'order-free' parser algorithm.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք ներկայացնում ենք մի մոտեցում կախվածության վերարտադրողի փոխլեզվով փոխանցելու համար, որպեսզի մեկ աղբյուր լեզվով վարժեցված վերարտադրողը ավելի արդյունավետ կարողանա օգտագործել բազմազան նպատակային լեզուներ: Այս աշխատանքի ընթացքում մենք ցույց ենք տալիս, որ վերլուծողների լեզվի փոխարեն կարելի է բարելավել վերարտադրելով աղբյուր լեզվի ծառի հիմքը: Այսպիսով, աղբյուր լեզվի ծառի արտադրյալը աճում է անհանգստացած տարբերակով, որտեղ վերահսկվող անհանգստացողությունը ներկայացվում է արտադրյալ ծառերի մեջ, աստոստատիկ վերադասավորելով կախված մարդկանց դիրքերը իրենց գլխավորների նկատմամբ, մինչդեռ արտադրյալների կառուց Սա հնարավորություն է տալիս վերլուծողին վերցնել բազմազան սինտակտիկ կաղապարներ, բացի այն կաղապարներից, որոնք գտնվում են աղբյուր լեզվով: Արդյունքում ստացված վերլուծումը ավելի արդյունավետ վերլուծում է նպատակային լեզուները տարբեր սինտակտիկ կառուցվածքներով: With English as the source language, our system shows an average improvement of 6.7% and 7.7% in terms of UAS and LAS over 29 target languages compared to the baseline single source parser trained using unperturbed source language treebank.  Սա նաև հանգեցնում է նշանակալի բարելավմանը (CITItion) կողմից առաջարկված վերաբերյալ վերաբերյալ վերաբերյալ, որը ներառում է "անհրաժեշտ" վերաբերյալ վերաբերյալ վերաբերյալ ալգորիթմ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>We present an approach for cross-lingual transfer of dependency parser so that the parser trained on a single source language can more effectively cater to diverse target languages.  In this work, we show that the cross-lingual performance of the parsers can be enhanced by over-generating the source language treebank.  ስለዚህም የቋንቋው ቋንቋ treebank የፓርላው ዛፎች መሠረት በተለወጠው ጊዜ የፓርላማ ዛፎች ሥርዓት በመቆጣጠር በተደጋጋሚ የደጋፊዎቹን ሥርዓት በራሳቸው ላይ በመስጠት በማድረግ አግኝቷል፡፡ ይህ ተሳታፊው በተለየ ቋንቋ ቋንቋ ውስጥ ካገኙት ሌላ ልዩ ዓይነት ተጨማሪን ለመያዝ ይችላል። የፍጥረቱ ምርጫዎች በተለየ ልዩ ልዩ ሲንታቲካዊ ግንኙነት ቋንቋዎችን ለመለጠፍ ተገኝቷል፡፡ የእንግሊዝኛ ቋንቋ እንደ ምንጭ ቋንቋ፣ ስርዓታችን የሀገር ቋንቋዎች እና የዩኤስና የLAS ቋንቋዎች 29 በመተካከል የተጠቃሚ የ6.7 በመቶ እና 7.7 በመቶ ያሳያል፡፡ ይህም ደግሞ የ'order-ነጻ' ተርጓሚው አጎሪትም በሚያሳየው የtransfer ተርጓሚው ተርጓሚው (CITATION) በተጠቃሚ ክፍተት ያሳርፋል።</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaweza kuweka mbinu ya usafirishaji wa lugha mbalimbali wa kutegemea kujitegemea ili mchambuzi aliyefundishwa kwa lugha moja inayoweza kuwa na ufanisi zaidi katika lugha mbalimbali za malengo. Katika kazi hii, tunaonyesha kwamba utendaji wa lugha mbalimbali wa mabunge unaweza kuongezeka kwa kuzalisha zaidi lugha ya lugha. Kwa hili, lugha ya asili ya lugha hiyo imeongezewa na toleo la utaratibu ambalo hudhibitiwa na ukatili unaanzishwa katika miti ya bunge kwa kuamuru upya nafasi za wategemea kwa kuheshimu vichwa vyao wakati wakiweka muundo wa miti ya bunge. Hii inawezesha mchambuzi kuchukua mitindo mbalimbali ya ushirikiano pamoja na wale waliopatikana kwa lugha ya msingi. Anachambua matokeo yanapatikana kutangaza lugha zinazolenga kwa ufanisi zaidi na miundombinu tofauti ya ushirikiano. Kwa lugha ya Kiingereza kama lugha ya vyanzo, mfumo wetu unaonyesha maendeleo ya wastani wa asilimia 6.7 na 7.7 kwa mujibu wa lugha za UAS na LAS zaidi ya 29 zenye lengo la lengo linalolinganisha na vyanzo pekee vya msingi vilivyofundishwa kwa kutumia lugha ya lugha isiyotarajiwa. This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an 'order-free' parser algorithm.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা ক্রিভাষায় নির্ভরশীল পরিবর্তনের জন্য একটি উপায় উপস্থাপন করি যাতে একটি সোর্স ভাষায় প্রশিক্ষণ প্রদান করা হয়েছে বিভিন্ন লক্ষ্য ভাষার জন এই কাজে আমরা দেখাচ্ছি যে পার্সারের ক্ষেত্রে ভাষাভাষার প্রদর্শনের ক্ষেত্রে সোর্স ভাষা ট্রিব্যাংকের বাড়িয়ে দিয়ে বাড় এর জন্য সূত্র ভাষা ত্রিবাঙ্ক তার পার্স বৃক্ষের নিয়ন্ত্রণ নিয়ন্ত্রণের সংস্করণে বাড়িয়ে দেয়া হয়েছে যেখানে পার্স গাছে নিয়ন্ত্রণ করা হয়েছে তাদের মাথার প্রতি নির্ভর করে নির এটি সূত্র ভাষায় যাদের পাওয়া যায় তাদের ছাড়াও বিভিন্ন সিন্ট্যাকটিক প্রান্ত গ্রহণ করার জন্য প্রস্তুতি প্রদর্ ফলাফলের প্রসার বিভিন্ন সিন্ট্যাক্টিক কাঠামোর মাধ্যমে লক্ষ্য ভাষাকে আরো কার্যকর করে পার্স করা যায়। With English as the source language, our system shows an average improvement of 6.7% and 7.7% in terms of UAS and LAS over 29 target languages compared to the baseline single source parser trained using unperturbed source language treebank.  This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an 'order-free' parser algorithm.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Biz müvəffəqiyyət ayırıcısının çox dilli tərəfdarlığı üçün bir yol göstəririk ki, tərəfdarlıq dilində təhsil edilən ayırıcının müxtəlif məqsəd dillərinə daha müvəffəqiyyətli tərəfdarlıq edə bilər. Bu işdə, biz parçacıların çox dilli performansının mənbə dillərinin çəkişməsi ilə daha çox təmizlənəcəyini göstəririk. Buna görə, mənbə dilinin çətinlikləri üzüntülmüş versiyonu ilə artırılır ki, ayırma ağaclarının yapısını dəyişiklik etmədiyi vaxt təvəkkül edənlərin yerini başlarına yönəltməklə stokastik olaraq ayırma ağaclarında daxil edilir. Bu, seçənçilərin mənbə dilində tapılanların yanında müxtəlif sintaktik örneklərini almasını qabilleştirir. Növbəti analizacı, müxtəlif sintaktik quruları ilə məqsəd dillərini daha etkili ayırmaq üçün tapılır. İngilizce dili mənbə dili olaraq, sistemimiz ortalama 6.7% və 7.7% ilə UAS və LAS ilə 29 məqsəd dillərinin üstündə 29 məqsəd dillərindən üstün olan tək mənbə ayırıcısı ilə müqayisədə təhsil edilməmiş mənbə dili tərəfindən təhsil edilən təhsil dili tərəfindən təhsil edil Bu da "order-free" ayırıcı algoritmi ilə təklif edilən təkrar ayırıcısının üstündə möhkəm təmizlənməsi olar.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo pristup preko jezika prebacivanja ovisnosti analizatora kako bi analizator obučen na jednom izvornom jeziku mogao učinkovitiji prihvatiti različite ciljne jezike. U ovom poslu, pokazujemo da se međujezički učinkoviti parsera može poboljšati preko generacije izvornog jezika. Za to se izvorni jezik treeban povećava sa svojom perturbiranom verzijom u kojoj se kontrolirana perturbacija uvede u analiziranje drvećem stokastički reordinirajući položaje ovisnika u pogledu njihovih glava dok drže strukturu drveća za analiziranje bez promjene. To omogućava analizatoru da uhvati različite sintaktičke obrasce osim onih koji su pronađeni na izvornom jeziku. Pronađen je rezultat analizatora da učinkovitije analizira ciljne jezike sa različitim sintaktičkim strukturama. S engleskim kao izvornom jezikom, naš sistem pokazuje prosječan poboljšanje od 6,7% i 7,7% u odnosu na UAS i LAS preko 29 ciljnih jezika u usporedbi s početnom jedinstvenom analizatorom izvora koji je trenirao s neodređenim jezikom. To također rezultira značajno poboljšanje nad analizatorom prijenosa predloženim (CITATION) koji uključuje algoritam "besplatnog" analizatora.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Tutvustame lähenemisviisi sõltuvuse parseri keeleüleseks ülekandmiseks, et ühe lähtekeelega koolitatud parser saaks efektiivsemalt teenindada erinevaid sihtkeeli. Käesolevas töös näitame, et parserite keeleülest jõudlust saab parandada lähtekeele puupanga üle genereerimisega. Selleks täiendatakse lähtekeele puupanka selle häirunud versiooniga, kus parsimispuude juurutatakse kontrollitud häire, korraldades stohastiliselt ülalpeetavate positsioone nende peade suhtes, hoides parsimispuude struktuuri muutumatuna. See võimaldab parser jäädvustada erinevaid süntaktilisi mustreid lisaks nendele, mis on leitud lähtekeeles. Saadud parser on leitud, et paremini parsib sihtkeeli erinevate süntaktiliste struktuuridega. Kui lähtekeeleks on inglise keel, näitab meie süsteem keskmiselt 6,7% ja 7,7% paranemist UAS ja LAS osas 29 sihtkeele võrreldes lähtekeelega, mida koolitati häirimata lähtekeele puupanka kasutades. See toob kaasa ka märkimisväärse paranemise võrreldes (CITATION) pakutud ülekandeparseriga, mis hõlmab tellimusvaba parseri algoritmi.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esitämme lähestymistavan riippuvuuden jäsentäjän monikieliseen siirtoon, jotta yhdellä lähdekielellä koulutettu jäsentäjä voi paremmin palvella erilaisia kohdekieliä. Tässä työssä osoitetaan, että jäsentäjien monikielistä suorituskykyä voidaan parantaa luomalla lähdekielen treebank yli. Tätä varten lähdekielen treebank on lisätty sen häiriintyneellä versiolla, jossa kontrolloitu häiriö otetaan käyttöön jäsennyspuissa järjestämällä stokastisesti riippuvaisten asennot heidän päihinsä nähden samalla kun jäsennyspuiden rakenne pysyy muuttumattomana. Tämä mahdollistaa jäsentäjän kaappaamaan erilaisia syntaktisia kuvioita niiden lisäksi, jotka löytyvät lähdekielestä. Tuloksena olevan jäsentäjän havaitaan jäsentävän tehokkaammin kohdekieliä eri syntaktisilla rakenteilla. Kun lähdekielenä on englanti, järjestelmämme näyttää keskimääräisen parannuksen 6,7% ja 7,7% AMK ja LAS verrattuna 29 kohdekieleen verrattuna yhden lähdekoodin jäsentäjään, joka on koulutettu häiriintymättömällä lähdekielellä. Tämä johtaa myös merkittävään parannukseen verrattuna (CITATION) ehdottamaan siirtoparseriin, joka sisältää "order-free" parserialgoritmin.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme přístup pro cross-jazyčný přenos závislostního parseru tak, aby parser trénovaný na jednom zdrojovém jazyce mohl efektivněji reagovat na různé cílové jazyky. V této práci ukazujeme, že výkon parserů může být zvýšen nadměrným generováním stromové banky zdrojového jazyka. Za tímto účelem je stromová banka zdrojového jazyka rozšířena o její narušenou verzi, v níž je do parse stromů zavedena řízená perturbace stochastickým uspořádáním pozic závislých vůči jejich hlavám při zachování struktury parse stromů nezměněné. To umožňuje parseru zachytit různé syntaktické vzory kromě těch, které se nacházejí ve zdrojovém jazyce. Výsledný parser je zjištěn, že efektivněji analyzuje cílové jazyky s různými syntaktickými strukturami. S angličtinou jako zdrojovým jazykem, náš systém ukazuje průměrné zlepšení 6,7% a 7,7% z hlediska UAS a LAS oproti 29 cílovým jazykům ve srovnání se základním single source parserem trénovaným pomocí nerušené zdrojové stromové banky. To také vede k výraznému zlepšení oproti přenosovému parseru navrženému (CITATION), který zahrnuje algoritmus parseru bez objednávek.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim një qasje për transferimin ndërgjuhësor të analizuesit të varësisë në mënyrë që analizuesi i trajnuar në një gjuhë të vetme burimi mund të kujdeset më efektivisht për gjuhët e ndryshme të objektivit. In this work, we show that the cross-lingual performance of the parsers can be enhanced by over-generating the source language treebank.  Për këtë, baza e drurit e gjuhës burimore shtohet me version in e saj të shqetësuar në të cilin shqetësimi i kontrolluar futet në pemët e analizimit duke riorganizuar stokastikisht pozicionet e të varurve në lidhje me kokat e tyre ndërsa mban strukturën e pemëve të analizimit të pandryshuara. This enables the parser to capture diverse syntactic patterns in addition to those that are found in the source language.  Analizatori rezultues gjendet për të analizuar më efektivisht gjuhët objektive me struktura të ndryshme sintaktike. Me anglishtin si gjuhën burimore, sistemi ynë tregon një përmirësim mesatar prej 6.7% dhe 7.7% në lidhje me UAS dhe LAS mbi 29 gjuhë objektive krahasuar me analizuesin bazë të burimit të vetëm të trajnuar duke përdorur bazën e gjuhës burimore të papërpunuar. This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an 'order-free' parser algorithm.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_ca>We present an approach for cross-lingual transfer of dependency parser so that the parser trained on a single source language can more effectively cater to diverse target languages.  In this work, we show that the cross-lingual performance of the parsers can be enhanced by over-generating the source language treebank.  For this, the source language treebank is augmented with its perturbed version in which controlled perturbation is introduced in the parse trees by stochastically reordering the positions of the dependents with respect to their heads while keeping the structure of the parse trees unchanged.  Això permet al analitzador capturar patrons sinàtics diversos a més dels que es troben en la llengua fontal. Es troba que l'analitzador resultant analitza de manera més efectiva les llengües alvo amb diferents estructures sinàctiques. With English as the source language, our system shows an average improvement of 6.7% and 7.7% in terms of UAS and LAS over 29 target languages compared to the baseline single source parser trained using unperturbed source language treebank.  Això també resulta en una millora significativa en relació amb l'analitzador de transfer ència proposat per (CITATION) que implica un algoritme d'analitzador "sense ordre".</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_he>אנו מציגים גישה לעברת תלויות בין שפתיים כדי שהמעבד המתאמן בשפה מקור אחת יוכל לטפל בצורה יעילה יותר בשפות מטרה מגוונות. בעבודה הזאת, אנו מראים שהביצועים הצלביים של המעבדים יכולים להשתפר על ידי מיוצר יותר מדי את עץ השפה המקורית. For this, the source language treebank is augmented with its perturbed version in which controlled perturbation is introduced in the parse trees by stochastically reordering the positions of the dependents with respect to their heads while keeping the structure of the parse trees unchanged.  זה מאפשר למחקר לתפוס דפוסים סינטקטיים מגוונים בנוסף לאלה שמוצאים בשפה המקורית. המחקר הנוצא נמצא כדי לאבד את שפות המטרה באופן יעיל יותר עם מבנים סינטקטיים שונים. עם אנגלית כשפת המקור, המערכת שלנו מראה שיפור ממוצע של 6.7% ו-7.7% במונחים של UAS ו-LAS מעל 29 שפות מטרה בהשוואה למחקר המקור היחיד הבסיסי מאומן באמצעות עץ שפת המקור ללא הפרעה. זה גם גורם לשיפור משמעותי על מעבד העברה המוצע על ידי (CITATION) שכולל אלגוריתם מעבד 'ללא סדר'.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo pristop za medjezični prenos razčlenjevalnika odvisnosti, tako da lahko razčlenjevalnik, usposobljen za en sam izvorni jezik, učinkoviteje poskrbi za različne ciljne jezike. V tem delu smo pokazali, da je mogoče večjezično učinkovitost razčlenjevalnikov izboljšati s prekomerno generiranjem treebanke izvornega jezika. V ta namen je treebanka izvornega jezika dopolnjena s svojo moteno različico, v kateri se nadzorovana motnja uvede v pariziranih drevesih s stohastičnim prerazporejanjem položajev vzdrževanih glede na njihove glave, hkrati pa ohranja strukturo pariziranih dreves nespremenjeno. To omogoča razčlenjevalcu, da zajame različne sintaktične vzorce poleg tistih, ki jih najdemo v izvornem jeziku. Ugotovljeno je, da nastali razčlenjevalnik učinkoviteje razčlenja ciljnih jezikov z različnimi sintaktičnimi strukturami. Z angleščino kot izvornim jezikom naš sistem kaže povprečno izboljšanje za 6,7% in 7,7% v smislu UAS in LAS v primerjavi z osnovnim razčlenjevalnikom enega vira, usposobljenim z uporabo brez motenj izvornega jezika treebank. To pomeni tudi znatno izboljšanje razčlenjevalnika prenosa, ki ga predlaga (CITATION), ki vključuje algoritem razčlenjevalnika brez naročil.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna gabatar da wata matsayi wa shige na ɗabi'ar-lugha na ɗabi'a-ɗabi'a, don a so Parser wanda aka sanar da shi a kan harshen ɗabi'a, ya iya ƙaranci masu tsari zuwa lugha masu ƙayyade. Daga wannan aikin, Munã nũna cewa, za'a ƙara fassarar-lingui na parser ko kuma za'a ƙara shi da sauri-zaɓen lugha. Daga wannan, ana ƙara harshen marubuci da version na perturbatar da ke iya tunkuɗe turbatar da shi a cikin itãcen parse, ana umurce masu shida matsayin da ke tsari ga kãwunansu, a lokacin da ke tsare matsayin itãcen parse. Wannan na yarda da parallori ya kãma wasu shiryoyi mãsu haɗuwa da kuma da waɗanda aka samu cikin harshen source. An gane parse lugha masu amfani da matsayi masu yin amfani da su da tsarin suntactic dabam-dabam. Da Ingiriya kamar harshen maganar farko, aikin mu na nuna mai ƙaranci wa sauri na kasa 6.7% da 7.7% cikin muhimman lugha na UAN da LoS da ke ƙaranci 29 masu jiyyada kuma aka samã shi da fasalin maganar salon ɗabi'a da aka sanar da shi na fassarar nau'in lugha da ba'a perturbuɗe ba. This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an 'order-free' parser algorithm.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་འདྲ་བརྗོད་ཀྱི་རྟེན་འབྲེལ་བའི་དབྱེ་འབྱེད་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་གཅིག་འཆར་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། འུ་ཅག་གི་ལཱ་སྟངས་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ཡིག་སྐད་རིགས་ཀྱི་ལས་འགན་འགྱུར་བ་ནི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་ཀྱི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་བསྐྱེད་ཚད་དང་། For this, the source language treebank is augmented with its perturbed version in which controlled perturbation is introduced in the parse trees by stochastically reordering the positions of the dependents with respect to their heads while keeping the structure of the parse trees unchanged. འདིས་དབྱིབས་ཞིབ་པ་ལ་རྒྱབ་སྐྱོར་ཡོད་པའི་དབྱེ་རིགས་སྣ་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་ཆ་རྣམ་པར་ལེན་ནུས་ཡོད་པ དབྱིབས་འབྱུང་བའི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་ནི་དམིགས་ཡུལ་གྱི་སྐད་རིགས་སྤྱོད་མི་འདྲ་བ་དང་མཉམ་དུ་ལས་སྦྱོར་བྱེད་ཐུབ་པ དབྱིན་ཡིག་གི་ཐོག་ཁུངས་སྐད་ཡིག་དང་གཅིག་པུ་ཡིན་ན། ང་ཚོའི་མ་ལག་གིས་འཇུག་རྟེན་འདིའི་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་ཚད་གཞི་ཤོག་བྱས་པའི་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་༢༠་དང་ལས་སྒྲི This also results in significant improvement over the transfer parser proposed by (CITATION) that involves an 'order-free' parser algorithm.</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé éntuk sistem kanggo nggawe luwih-luwih akeh pisan karo panelusuran kanggo sampeyan siji sing tukang mroleh kanggo nguasai perusahaan langkung sampeyan. Nang lan nggambar iki, kita ngomong bantuan kanggo bantayan tindang karo perusahaan bangsane bisa supoyo nggawe barang nggawe aturan bantayan bangsa. Saiki iki, perusahaan langkung tresnaning ing ing nggawe versi dadi aturan sing perusahaan karo perusahaan Digawe text Gandhis Inggris nganggo kelompok bangsa, sistem dhéwé iso nglanggar sapa kut luwih dumadhi 6.7% lan 7.7% sing ditambah menyang kalagayut ASS karo LAS liyo sing itlanjut liyo sing sampeyan bakal terus nggo oleh-oleh sing perusahaan winih Ngubah iki dadi akeh barêng langkung kanggo nyebah kanggo nggawe layar kanggo nyebah cara nggawe "order-free"</abstract_jv>
      </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Sanskrit Segmentation revisited<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>anskrit Segmentation revisited</title>
      <author><first>Sriram</first><last>Krishnan</last></author>
      <author><first>Amba</first><last>Kulkarni</last></author>
      <pages>105–114</pages>
      <abstract>Computationally analyzing Sanskrit texts requires proper segmentation in the initial stages. There have been various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tools</a> developed for Sanskrit text segmentation. Of these, Grard Huet’s Reader in the Sanskrit Heritage Engine analyzes the input text and segments it based on the word parameters-phases like iic, ifc, Pr, Subst, etc., and sandhi (or transition) that takes place at the end of a word with the initial part of the next word. And it enlists all the possible solutions differentiating them with the help of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phase_(matter)">phases</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phase_(matter)">phases</a> and their analyses have their use in the domain of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">sentential parsers</a>. In segmentation, though, they are not used beyond deciding whether the words formed with the phases are morphologically valid. This paper tries to modify the above segmenter by ignoring the phase details (except for a few cases), and also proposes a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Probability_function">probability function</a> to prioritize the list of solutions to bring up the most valid solutions at the top.</abstract>
      <url hash="b4688758">2019.icon-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>krishnan-kulkarni-2019-sanskrit</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Dataset for Aspect Detection on Mobile reviews in Hindi<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>indi</title>
      <author><first>Pruthwik</first><last>Mishra</last></author>
      <author><first>Ayush</first><last>Joshi</last></author>
      <author><first>Dipti</first><last>Sharma</last></author>
      <pages>130–134</pages>
      <abstract>In recent years <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opinion_mining">Opinion Mining</a> has become one of the very interesting fields of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_processing">Language Processing</a>. To extract the gist of a sentence in a shorter and efficient manner is what <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opinion_mining">opinion mining</a> provides. In this paper we focus on detecting aspects for a particular <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_(mathematical_analysis)">domain</a>. While relevant research work has been done in aspect detection in resource rich languages like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, we are trying to do the same in a relatively resource poor Hindi language. Here we present a corpus of mobile reviews which are labelled with carefully curated aspects. The motivation behind Aspect detection is to get information on a finer level about the data. In this paper we identify all aspects related to the gadget which are present on the reviews given online on various websites. We also propose <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(medicine)">baseline models</a> to detect <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammatical_aspect">aspects</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi text</a> after conducting various experiments.</abstract>
      <url hash="74a9e224">2019.icon-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>mishra-etal-2019-dataset</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>Towards Handling Verb Phrase Ellipsis in English-Hindi Machine Translation<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish-<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>indi Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Niyati</first><last>Bafna</last></author>
      <author><first>Dipti</first><last>Sharma</last></author>
      <pages>150–159</pages>
      <abstract>English-Hindi machine translation systems have difficulty interpreting verb phrase ellipsis (VPE) in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, and commit errors in translating sentences with VPE. We present a solution and theoretical backing for the treatment of English VPE, with the specific scope of enabling English-Hindi MT, based on an understanding of the syntactical phenomenon of verb-stranding verb phrase ellipsis in Hindi (VVPE). We implement a rule-based system to perform the following sub-tasks : 1) Verb ellipsis identification in the English source sentence, 2) Elided verb phrase head identification 3) Identification of verb segment which needs to be induced at the site of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ellipsis_(linguistics)">ellipsis</a> 4) Modify input sentence ; i.e. resolving <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verb–object–subject">VPE</a> and inducing the required <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verb–object–subject">verb segment</a>. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> obtains 94.83 percent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">precision</a> and 83.04 percent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a> on subtask (1), tested on 3900 sentences from the BNC corpus. This is competitive with state-of-the-art results. We measure <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of subtasks (2) and (3) together, and obtain a 91 percent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> on 200 sentences taken from the WSJ corpus. Finally, in order to indicate the relevance of ellipsis handling to MT, we carried out a manual analysis of the English-Hindi MT outputs of 100 sentences after passing it through our system. We set up a basic metric (1-5) for this evaluation, where 5 indicates drastic improvement, and obtained an average of 3.55. As far as we know, this is the first attempt to target ellipsis resolution in the context of improving English-Hindi machine translation.</abstract>
      <url hash="7965028d">2019.icon-1.18</url>
      <bibkey>bafna-sharma-2019-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Kunji : A Resource Management System for Higher Productivity in Computer Aided Translation Tools</title>
      <author><first>Priyank</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Manish</first><last>Shrivastava</last></author>
      <author><first>Dipti Misra</first><last>Sharma</last></author>
      <author><first>Rashid</first><last>Ahmad</last></author>
      <pages>184–192</pages>
      <abstract>Complex NLP applications, such as machine translation systems, utilize various kinds of resources namely lexical, multiword, domain dictionaries, maps and rules etc. Similarly, translators working on Computer Aided Translation workbenches, also require help from various kinds of resources-glossaries, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminology">terminologies</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concordance_(publishing)">concordances</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation_memory">translation memory</a> in the workbenches in order to increase their productivity. Additionally, translators have to look away from the workbenches for linguistic resources like Named Entities, Multiwords, lexical and lexeme dictionaries in order to get help, as the available resources like concordances, terminologies and glossaries are often not enough. In this paper we present <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kunji">Kunji</a>, a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_management_(computing)">resource management system</a> for translation workbenches and MT modules. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> can be easily integrated in translation workbenches and can also be used as a management tool for resources for MT systems. The described <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_management_(computing)">resource management system</a> has been integrated in a translation workbench Transzaar. We also study the impact of providing this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_management">resource management system</a> along with linguistic resources on the productivity of translators for English-Hindi language pair. When the linguistic resources like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexeme">lexeme</a>, NER and MWE dictionaries were made available to translators in addition to their regular translation memories, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concordance_(publishing)">concordances</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminology">terminologies</a>, their productivity increased by 15.61 %.</abstract>
      <url hash="a20f5438">2019.icon-1.22</url>
      <bibkey>gupta-etal-2019-kunji</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="25">
      <title>Unsung Challenges of Building and Deploying Language Technologies for Low Resource Language Communities</title>
      <author><first>Pratik</first><last>Joshi</last></author>
      <author><first>Christain</first><last>Barnes</last></author>
      <author><first>Sebastin</first><last>Santy</last></author>
      <author><first>Simran</first><last>Khanuja</last></author>
      <author><first>Sanket</first><last>Shah</last></author>
      <author><first>Anirudh</first><last>Srinivasan</last></author>
      <author><first>Satwik</first><last>Bhattamishra</last></author>
      <author><first>Sunayana</first><last>Sitaram</last></author>
      <author><first>Monojit</first><last>Choudhury</last></author>
      <author><first>Kalika</first><last>Bali</last></author>
      <pages>211–219</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we examine and analyze the challenges associated with developing and introducing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_technology">language technologies</a> to low-resource language communities. While doing so we bring to light the successes and failures of past work in this area, challenges being faced in doing so, and what have they achieved. Throughout this paper, we take a problem-facing approach and describe essential factors which the success of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technology">technologies</a> hinges upon. We present the various aspects in a manner which clarify and lay out the different tasks involved, which can aid organizations looking to make an impact in this area. We take the example of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gondi_language">Gondi</a>, an extremely-low resource Indian language, to reinforce and complement our discussion.</abstract>
      <url hash="ceb13465">2019.icon-1.25</url>
      <bibkey>joshi-etal-2019-unsung</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>DRCoVe : An Augmented Word Representation Approach using Distributional and Relational Context<fixed-case>DRC</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>V</fixed-case>e: An Augmented Word Representation Approach using Distributional and Relational Context</title>
      <author><first>Md. Aslam</first><last>Parwez</last></author>
      <author><first>Muhammad</first><last>Abulaish</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohd</first><last>Fazil</last></author>
      <pages>220–229</pages>
      <abstract>Word representation using the distributional information of words from a sizeable corpus is considered efficacious in many natural language processing and text mining applications. However, distributional representation of a word is unable to capture distant relational knowledge, representing the relational semantics. In this paper, we propose a novel word representation approach using distributional and relational contexts, DRCoVe, which augments the distributional representation of a word using the relational semantics extracted as syntactic and semantic association among entities from the underlying corpus. Unlike existing approaches that use external knowledge bases representing the relational semantics for enhanced word representation, DRCoVe uses typed dependencies (aka syntactic dependencies) to extract relational knowledge from the underlying corpus. The proposed approach is applied over a biomedical text corpus to learn <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_processor_(electronic_device)">word representation</a> and compared with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GloVe_(machine_learning)">GloVe</a>, which is one of the most popular word embedding approaches. The evaluation results on various benchmark datasets for word similarity and word categorization tasks demonstrate the effectiveness of DRCoVe over the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GloVe">GloVe</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="e9f8c9f8">2019.icon-1.26</url>
      <bibkey>parwez-etal-2019-drcove</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>A Deep Learning Approach for Automatic Detection of Fake News</title>
      <author><first>Tanik</first><last>Saikh</last></author>
      <author><first>Arkadipta</first><last>De</last></author>
      <author><first>Asif</first><last>Ekbal</last></author>
      <author><first>Pushpak</first><last>Bhattacharyya</last></author>
      <pages>230–238</pages>
      <abstract>Fake news detection is a very prominent and essential task in the field of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journalism">journalism</a>. This challenging <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Problem_solving">problem</a> is seen so far in the field of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Politics">politics</a>, but it could be even more challenging when it is to be determined in the multi-domain platform. In this paper, we propose two effective models based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning</a> for solving fake news detection problem in online news contents of multiple domains. We evaluate our techniques on the two recently released datasets, namely Fake News AMT and Celebrity for fake news detection. The proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> yield encouraging performance, outperforming the current hand-crafted feature engineering based state-of-the-art system with a significant margin of 3.08 % and 9.3 % by the two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a>, respectively. In order to exploit the datasets, available for the related tasks, we perform cross-domain analysis (model trained on FakeNews AMT and tested on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celebrity">Celebrity</a> and vice versa) to explore the applicability of our systems across the domains.</abstract>
      <url hash="166cb9aa">2019.icon-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>saikh-etal-2019-deep</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="28">
      <title>Samajh-Boojh : A Reading Comprehension system in Hindi<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>indi</title>
      <author><first>Shalaka</first><last>Vaidya</last></author>
      <author><first>Hiranmai</first><last>Sri Adibhatla</last></author>
      <author><first>Radhika</first><last>Mamidi</last></author>
      <pages>239–248</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents a novel approach designed to answer questions on a reading comprehension passage. It is an end-to-end system which first focuses on comprehending the given passage wherein it converts <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unstructured_data">unstructured passage</a> into a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structured_data">structured data</a> and later proceeds to answer the questions related to the passage using solely the aforementioned <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structured_data">structured data</a>. To the best of our knowledge, the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design">design</a> is first of its kind which accounts for entire process of comprehending the passage and then answering the questions associated with the passage. The comprehension stage converts the passage into a Discourse Collection that comprises of the relation shared amongst logical sentences in given passage along with the key characteristics of each sentence. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design">design</a> has its applications in academic domain, query comprehension in speech systems among others.</abstract>
      <url hash="c8c6e93b">2019.icon-1.28</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="2325c695">2019.icon-1.28.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>vaidya-etal-2019-samajh</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>