<collection id="2020.parlaclarin">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Second ParlaCLARIN Workshop</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Darja</first><last>Fi&#353;er</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Maria</first><last>Eskevich</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Franciska</first><last>de Jong</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-47-4</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9b50da83">2020.parlaclarin-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>parlaclarin-2020-parlaclarin</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Compiling <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>zech Parliamentary Stenographic Protocols into a Corpus</title>
      <author><first>Barbora</first><last>Hladka</last></author>
      <author><first>Maty&#225;&#353;</first><last>Kopp</last></author>
      <author><first>Pavel</first><last>Stra&#328;&#225;k</last></author>
      <pages>18&#8211;22</pages>
      <abstract>The Parliament of the Czech Republic consists of two chambers: the Chamber of Deputies (Lower House) and the Senate (Upper House). In our work, we focus on agenda and documents that relate to the Chamber of Deputies exclusively. We pay particular attention to stenographic protocols that record the Chamber of Deputies&#8217; meetings. Our overall goal is to (1) compile the protocols into a ParlaCLARIN TEI encoded corpus, (2) make this corpus accessible and searchable in the TEITOK web-based platform, (3) annotate the corpus using the modules available in TEITOK, e.g. detect and recognize named entities, and (4) highlight the annotations in TEITOK. In addition, we add two more goals that we consider innovative: (5) update the corpus every time a new stenographic protocol is published online by the Chambers of Deputies and (6) expose the annotations as the linked open data in order to improve the protocols&#8217; interoperability with other existing linked open data. This paper is devoted to the goals (1) and (5).</abstract>
      <url hash="c9a1f422">2020.parlaclarin-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>hladka-etal-2020-compiling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Who mentions whom? Recognizing political actors in proceedings</title>
      <author><first>Lennart</first><last>Kerkvliet</last></author>
      <author><first>Jaap</first><last>Kamps</last></author>
      <author><first>Maarten</first><last>Marx</last></author>
      <pages>35&#8211;39</pages>
      <abstract>We show that it is straightforward to train a state of the art named entity tagger (spaCy) to recognize political actors in Dutch parliamentary proceedings with high accuracy. The tagger was trained on 3.4K manually labeled examples, which were created in a modest 2.5 days work. This resource is made available on github. Besides proper nouns of persons and political parties, the tagger can recognize quite complex definite descriptions referring to cabinet ministers, ministries, and parliamentary committees. We also provide a demo search engine which employs the tagged entities in its SERP and result summaries.</abstract>
      <url hash="0d61d348">2020.parlaclarin-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>kerkvliet-etal-2020-mentions</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Querying a large annotated corpus of parliamentary debates</title>
      <author><first>Sascha</first><last>Diwersy</last></author>
      <author><first>Giancarlo</first><last>Luxardo</last></author>
      <pages>75&#8211;79</pages>
      <abstract>The TAPS corpus makes it possible to share a large volume of French parliamentary data. The TEI-compliant approach behind its design choices facilitates the publishing and the interoperability of data, but also the implementation of exploratory data analysis techniques in order to process institutional or political discourse. We demonstrate its application to the debates occurred in the context of a specific legislative process, which generated a strong opposition.</abstract>
      <url hash="553ad4c1">2020.parlaclarin-1.13</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>diwersy-luxardo-2020-querying</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>