<collection id="2020.aespen">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Workshop on Automated Extraction of Socio-political Events from News 2020</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ali</first><last>H&#252;rriyeto&#287;lu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Erdem</first><last>Y&#246;r&#252;k</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Vanni</first><last>Zavarella</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Hristo</first><last>Tanev</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-50-4</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="a9720b21">2020.aespen-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>aespen-2020-automated</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Automated Extraction of Socio-political Events from News (<fixed-case>AESPEN</fixed-case>): Workshop and Shared Task Report</title>
      <author><first>Ali</first><last>H&#252;rriyeto&#287;lu</last></author>
      <author><first>Vanni</first><last>Zavarella</last></author>
      <author><first>Hristo</first><last>Tanev</last></author>
      <author><first>Erdem</first><last>Y&#246;r&#252;k</last></author>
      <author><first>Ali</first><last>Safaya</last></author>
      <author><first>Osman</first><last>Mutlu</last></author>
      <pages>1&#8211;6</pages>
      <abstract>We describe our effort on automated extraction of socio-political events from news in the scope of a workshop and a shared task we organized at Language Resources and Evaluation Conference (LREC 2020). We believe the event extraction studies in computational linguistics and social and political sciences should further support each other in order to enable large scale socio-political event information collection across sources, countries, and languages. The event consists of regular research papers and a shared task, which is about event sentence coreference identification (ESCI), tracks. All submissions were reviewed by five members of the program committee. The workshop attracted research papers related to evaluation of machine learning methodologies, language resources, material conflict forecasting, and a shared task participation report in the scope of socio-political event information collection. It has shown us the volume and variety of both the data sources and event information collection approaches related to socio-political events and the need to fill the gap between automated text processing techniques and requirements of social and political sciences.</abstract>
      <url hash="c904d4b7">2020.aespen-1.1</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>hurriyetoglu-etal-2020-automated</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Text Categorization for Conflict Event Annotation</title>
      <author><first>Fredrik</first><last>Olsson</last></author>
      <author><first>Magnus</first><last>Sahlgren</last></author>
      <author><first>Fehmi</first><last>ben Abdesslem</last></author>
      <author><first>Ariel</first><last>Ekgren</last></author>
      <author><first>Kristine</first><last>Eck</last></author>
      <pages>19&#8211;25</pages>
      <abstract>We cast the problem of event annotation as one of text categorization, and compare state of the art text categorization techniques on event data produced within the Uppsala Conflict Data Program (UCDP). Annotating a single text involves assigning the labels pertaining to at least 17 distinct categorization tasks, e.g., who were the attacking organization, who was attacked, and where did the event take place. The text categorization techniques under scrutiny are a classical Bag-of-Words approach; character-based contextualized embeddings produced by ELMo; embeddings produced by the BERT base model, and a version of BERT base fine-tuned on UCDP data; and a pre-trained and fine-tuned classifier based on ULMFiT. The categorization tasks are very diverse in terms of the number of classes to predict as well as the skeweness of the distribution of classes. The categorization results exhibit a large variability across tasks, ranging from 30.3% to 99.8% F-score.</abstract>
      <url hash="dbb4eb54">2020.aespen-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>olsson-etal-2020-text</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Seeing the Forest and the Trees: Detection and Cross-Document Coreference Resolution of Militarized Interstate Disputes</title>
      <author><first>Benjamin</first><last>Radford</last></author>
      <pages>35&#8211;41</pages>
      <abstract>Previous efforts to automate the detection of social and political events in text have primarily focused on identifying events described within single sentences or documents. Within a corpus of documents, these automated systems are unable to link event references&#8212;recognize singular events across multiple sentences or documents. A separate literature in computational linguistics on event coreference resolution attempts to link known events to one another within (and across) documents. I provide a data set for evaluating methods to identify certain political events in text and to link related texts to one another based on shared events. The data set, Headlines of War, is built on the Militarized Interstate Disputes data set and offers headlines classified by dispute status and headline pairs labeled with coreference indicators. Additionally, I introduce a model capable of accomplishing both tasks. The multi-task convolutional neural network is shown to be capable of recognizing events and event coreferences given the headlines&#8217; texts and publication dates.</abstract>
      <url hash="4990922d">2020.aespen-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>radford-2020-seeing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Supervised Event Coding from Text Written in <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic: Introducing Hadath</title>
      <author><first>Javier</first><last>Osorio</last></author>
      <author><first>Alejandro</first><last>Reyes</last></author>
      <author><first>Alejandro</first><last>Beltr&#225;n</last></author>
      <author><first>Atal</first><last>Ahmadzai</last></author>
      <pages>49&#8211;56</pages>
      <abstract>This article introduces Hadath, a supervised protocol for coding event data from text written in Arabic. Hadath contributes to recent efforts in advancing multi-language event coding using computer-based solutions. In this application, we focus on extracting event data about the conflict in Afghanistan from 2008 to 2018 using Arabic information sources. The implementation relies first on a Machine Learning algorithm to classify news stories relevant to the Afghan conflict. Then, using Hadath, we implement the Natural Language Processing component for event coding from Arabic script. The output database contains daily geo-referenced information at the district level on who did what to whom, when and where in the Afghan conflict. The data helps to identify trends in the dynamics of violence, the provision of governance, and traditional conflict resolution in Afghanistan for different actors over time and across space.</abstract>
      <url hash="c5108ead">2020.aespen-1.9</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>osorio-etal-2020-supervised</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Protest Event Analysis: A Longitudinal Analysis for <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>reece</title>
      <author><first>Konstantina</first><last>Papanikolaou</last></author>
      <author><first>Haris</first><last>Papageorgiou</last></author>
      <pages>57&#8211;62</pages>
      <abstract>The advent of Big Data has shifted social science research towards computational methods. The volume of data that is nowadays available has brought a radical change in traditional approaches due to the cost and effort needed for processing. Knowledge extraction from heterogeneous and ample data is not an easy task to tackle. Thus, interdisciplinary approaches are necessary, combining experts of both social and computer science. This paper aims to present a work in the context of protest analysis, which falls into the scope of Computational Social Science. More specifically, the contribution of this work is to describe a Computational Social Science methodology for Event Analysis. The presented methodology is generic in the sense that it can be applied in every event typology and moreover, it is innovative and suitable for interdisciplinary tasks as it incorporates the human-in-the-loop. Additionally, a case study is presented concerning Protest Analysis in Greece over the last two decades. The conceptual foundation lies mainly upon claims analysis, and newspaper data were used in order to map, document and discuss protests in Greece in a longitudinal perspective.</abstract>
      <url hash="0673559d">2020.aespen-1.10</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>papanikolaou-papageorgiou-2020-protest</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>