<collection id="2020.globalex">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 2020 Globalex Workshop on Linked Lexicography</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ilan</first><last>Kernerman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Simon</first><last>Krek</last></editor>
      <editor><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jorge</first><last>Gracia</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sina</first><last>Ahmadi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Besim</first><last>Kabashi</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-46-7</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="0bd585a9">2020.globalex-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>globalex-2020-2020</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Modelling Frequency and Attestations for <fixed-case>O</fixed-case>nto<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ex-Lemon</title>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Chiarcos</last></author>
      <author><first>Maxim</first><last>Ionov</last></author>
      <author><first>Jesse</first><last>de Does</last></author>
      <author><first>Katrien</first><last>Depuydt</last></author>
      <author><first>Anas Fahad</first><last>Khan</last></author>
      <author><first>Sander</first><last>Stolk</last></author>
      <author><first>Thierry</first><last>Declerck</last></author>
      <author><first>John Philip</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <pages>1&#8211;9</pages>
      <abstract>The OntoLex vocabulary enjoys increasing popularity as a means of publishing lexical resources with RDF and as Linked Data. The recent publication of a new OntoLex module for lexicography, lexicog, reflects its increasing importance for digital lexicography. However, not all aspects of digital lexicography have been covered to the same extent. In particular, supplementary information drawn from corpora such as frequency information, links to attestations, and collocation data were considered to be beyond the scope of lexicog. Therefore, the OntoLex community has put forward the proposal for a novel module for frequency, attestation and corpus information (FrAC), that not only covers the requirements of digital lexicography, but also accommodates essential data structures for lexical information in natural language processing. This paper introduces the current state of the OntoLex-FrAC vocabulary, describes its structure, some selected use cases, elementary concepts and fundamental definitions, with a focus on frequency and attestations.</abstract>
      <url hash="3d238906">2020.globalex-1.1</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>chiarcos-etal-2020-modelling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Towards an Extension of the Linking of the Open <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>utch <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et with <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>utch Lexicographic Resources</title>
      <author><first>Thierry</first><last>Declerck</last></author>
      <pages>33&#8211;35</pages>
      <abstract>This extended abstract presents on-going work consisting in interlinking and merging the Open Dutch WordNet and generic lexicographic resources for Dutch, focusing for now on the Dutch and English versions of Wiktionary and using the Algemeen Nederlands Woordenboek as a quality checking instance. As the Open Dutch WordNet is already equipped with a relevant number of complex lexical units, we are aiming at expanding it and proposing a new representational framework for the encoding of the interlinked and integrated data. The longer term goal of the work is to investigate if and on how senses can be restricted to particular morphological variations of Dutch lexical entries, and how to represent this information in a Linguistic Linked Open Data compliant format.</abstract>
      <url hash="d7e39ea5">2020.globalex-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>declerck-2020-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Widening the Discussion on &#8220;False <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>riends&#8221; in Multilingual Wordnets</title>
      <author><first>Hugo</first><last>Gon&#231;alo Oliveira</last></author>
      <author><first>Ana</first><last>Lu&#237;s</last></author>
      <pages>36</pages>
      <abstract>There are wordnets in many languages, many aligned with Princeton WordNet, some of which in a (semi-)automatic process, but we rarely see actual discussions on the role of false friends in this process. Having in mind known issues related to such words in language translation, and further motivated by false friend-related issues on the alignment of a Portuguese wordnet with Princeton Wordnet, we aim to widen this discussion, while suggesting preliminary ideas of how wordnets could benefit from this kind of research.</abstract>
      <url hash="61ed0502">2020.globalex-1.6</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>goncalo-oliveira-luis-2020-widening</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Building Sense Representations in <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>anish by Combining Word Embeddings with Lexical Resources</title>
      <author><first>Ida</first><last>R&#248;rmann Olsen</last></author>
      <author><first>Bolette</first><last>Pedersen</last></author>
      <author><first>Asad</first><last>Sayeed</last></author>
      <pages>45&#8211;52</pages>
      <abstract>Our aim is to identify suitable sense representations for NLP in Danish. We investigate sense inventories that correlate with human interpretations of word meaning and ambiguity as typically described in dictionaries and wordnets and that are well reflected distributionally as expressed in word embeddings. To this end, we study a number of highly ambiguous Danish nouns and examine the effectiveness of sense representations constructed by combining vectors from a distributional model with the information from a wordnet. We establish representations based on centroids obtained from wordnet synests and example sentences as well as representations established via are tested in a word sense disambiguation task. We conclude that the more information extracted from the wordnet entries (example sentence, definition, semantic relations) the more successful the sense representation vector.</abstract>
      <url hash="1122a9b0">2020.globalex-1.8</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>rormann-olsen-etal-2020-building</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Chiarcos</last></author>
      <author><first>Niko</first><last>Schenk</last></author>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>F&#228;th</last></author>
      <pages>98&#8211;105</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our contribution to the Third Shared Task on Translation Inference across Dictionaries (TIAD-2020). We describe an approach on translation inference based on symbolic methods, the propagation of concepts over a graph of interconnected dictionaries: Given a mapping from source language words to lexical concepts (e.g., synsets) as a seed, we use bilingual dictionaries to extrapolate a mapping of pivot and target language words to these lexical concepts. Translation inference is then performed by looking up the lexical concept(s) of a source language word and returning the target language word(s) for which these lexical concepts have the respective highest score. We present two instantiations of this system: One using WordNet synsets as concepts, and one using lexical entries (translations) as concepts. With a threshold of 0, the latter configuration is the second among participant systems in terms of F1 score. We also describe additional evaluation experiments on Apertium data, a comparison with an earlier approach based on embedding projection, and an approach for constrained projection that outperforms the TIAD-2020 vanilla system by a large margin.</abstract>
      <url hash="e09d78d7">2020.globalex-1.16</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>chiarcos-etal-2020-translation</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>