<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.globalex">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 2020 Globalex Workshop on Linked Lexicography</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ilan</first><last>Kernerman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Simon</first><last>Krek</last></editor>
      <editor><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jorge</first><last>Gracia</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sina</first><last>Ahmadi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Besim</first><last>Kabashi</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-46-7</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="0bd585a9">2020.globalex-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>globalex-2020-2020</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Modelling Frequency and Attestations for OntoLex-Lemon<fixed-case>O</fixed-case>nto<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ex-Lemon</title>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Chiarcos</last></author>
      <author><first>Maxim</first><last>Ionov</last></author>
      <author><first>Jesse</first><last>de Does</last></author>
      <author><first>Katrien</first><last>Depuydt</last></author>
      <author><first>Anas Fahad</first><last>Khan</last></author>
      <author><first>Sander</first><last>Stolk</last></author>
      <author><first>Thierry</first><last>Declerck</last></author>
      <author><first>John Philip</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <pages>1–9</pages>
      <abstract>The OntoLex vocabulary enjoys increasing popularity as a means of publishing lexical resources with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_Description_Framework">RDF</a> and as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linked_data">Linked Data</a>. The recent publication of a new OntoLex module for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexicography">lexicography</a>, lexicog, reflects its increasing importance for digital lexicography. However, not all aspects of digital lexicography have been covered to the same extent. In particular, supplementary information drawn from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpora</a> such as frequency information, links to attestations, and collocation data were considered to be beyond the scope of lexicog. Therefore, the OntoLex community has put forward the proposal for a novel module for frequency, attestation and corpus information (FrAC), that not only covers the requirements of digital lexicography, but also accommodates essential data structures for lexical information in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a>. This paper introduces the current state of the OntoLex-FrAC vocabulary, describes its structure, some selected use cases, elementary concepts and fundamental definitions, with a focus on frequency and attestations.</abstract>
      <url hash="3d238906">2020.globalex-1.1</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>chiarcos-etal-2020-modelling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Towards an Extension of the Linking of the Open Dutch WordNet with Dutch Lexicographic Resources<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>utch <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et with <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>utch Lexicographic Resources</title>
      <author><first>Thierry</first><last>Declerck</last></author>
      <pages>33–35</pages>
      <abstract>This extended abstract presents on-going work consisting in interlinking and merging the Open Dutch WordNet and generic lexicographic resources for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_language">Dutch</a>, focusing for now on the Dutch and English versions of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wiktionary">Wiktionary</a> and using the Algemeen Nederlands Woordenboek as a quality checking instance. As the Open Dutch WordNet is already equipped with a relevant number of complex lexical units, we are aiming at expanding it and proposing a new representational framework for the encoding of the interlinked and integrated data. The longer term goal of the work is to investigate if and on how senses can be restricted to particular morphological variations of Dutch lexical entries, and how to represent this information in a Linguistic Linked Open Data compliant format.</abstract>
      <url hash="d7e39ea5">2020.globalex-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>declerck-2020-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Widening the Discussion on False Friends in Multilingual Wordnets<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>riends” in Multilingual Wordnets</title>
      <author><first>Hugo</first><last>Gonçalo Oliveira</last></author>
      <author><first>Ana</first><last>Luís</last></author>
      <pages>36</pages>
      <abstract>There are wordnets in many languages, many aligned with Princeton WordNet, some of which in a (semi-)automatic process, but we rarely see actual discussions on the role of false friends in this process. Having in mind known issues related to such words in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation">language translation</a>, and further motivated by false friend-related issues on the alignment of a Portuguese wordnet with Princeton Wordnet, we aim to widen this discussion, while suggesting preliminary ideas of how wordnets could benefit from this kind of research.</abstract>
      <url hash="61ed0502">2020.globalex-1.6</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>goncalo-oliveira-luis-2020-widening</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Building Sense Representations in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danish_language">Danish</a> by Combining Word Embeddings with Lexical Resources<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>anish by Combining Word Embeddings with Lexical Resources</title>
      <author><first>Ida</first><last>Rørmann Olsen</last></author>
      <author><first>Bolette</first><last>Pedersen</last></author>
      <author><first>Asad</first><last>Sayeed</last></author>
      <pages>45–52</pages>
      <abstract>Our aim is to identify suitable sense representations for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danish_language">Danish</a>. We investigate sense inventories that correlate with human interpretations of word meaning and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ambiguity">ambiguity</a> as typically described in dictionaries and wordnets and that are well reflected distributionally as expressed in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embeddings</a>. To this end, we study a number of highly ambiguous Danish nouns and examine the effectiveness of sense representations constructed by combining <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_space">vectors</a> from a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distribution_(mathematics)">distributional model</a> with the information from a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a>. We establish <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representation_(arts)">representations</a> based on centroids obtained from wordnet synests and example sentences as well as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representation_(arts)">representations</a> established via are tested in a word sense disambiguation task. We conclude that the more information extracted from the wordnet entries (example sentence, definition, semantic relations) the more successful the sense representation vector.</abstract>
      <url hash="1122a9b0">2020.globalex-1.8</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>rormann-olsen-etal-2020-building</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Chiarcos</last></author>
      <author><first>Niko</first><last>Schenk</last></author>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Fäth</last></author>
      <pages>98–105</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our contribution to the Third Shared Task on Translation Inference across Dictionaries (TIAD-2020). We describe an approach on translation inference based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_algebra">symbolic methods</a>, the propagation of concepts over a graph of interconnected dictionaries : Given a mapping from source language words to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_item">lexical concepts</a> (e.g., synsets) as a seed, we use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bilingual_dictionary">bilingual dictionaries</a> to extrapolate a mapping of pivot and target language words to these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_item">lexical concepts</a>. Translation inference is then performed by looking up the lexical concept(s) of a source language word and returning the target language word(s) for which these lexical concepts have the respective highest score. We present two instantiations of this system : One using WordNet synsets as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concepts</a>, and one using lexical entries (translations) as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concepts</a>. With a threshold of 0, the latter <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_configuration">configuration</a> is the second among participant systems in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F1_score">F1 score</a>. We also describe additional evaluation experiments on Apertium data, a comparison with an earlier approach based on embedding projection, and an approach for constrained projection that outperforms the TIAD-2020 vanilla system by a large margin.</abstract>
      <url hash="e09d78d7">2020.globalex-1.16</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>chiarcos-etal-2020-translation</bibkey>
    <title_ar>استدلال الترجمة عن طريق انتشار المفهوم</title_ar>
      <title_es>Inferencia de traducción por propagación de conceptos</title_es>
      <title_pt>Inferência de tradução por propagação de conceito</title_pt>
      <title_ja>概念伝播による翻訳推論</title_ja>
      <title_zh>因名译推理</title_zh>
      <title_hi>अवधारणा प्रसार द्वारा अनुवाद अनुमान</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Tátal Aistriúcháin trí Iomadú Coincheapa</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Comment</title_ka>
      <title_el>Μετάφραση συμπέρασμα κατά διάδοση εννοιών</title_el>
      <title_hu>Fordítás Inference koncepció szerint Propagation</title_hu>
      <title_it>Traduzione Inferenza per concetto Propagazione</title_it>
      <title_kk>Концепция пропагациясы бойынша аудармалардың қасиеттері</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Vertimo pagal koncepciją Inferencija</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Превод:</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title_ms>
      <title_ml>പരിഭാഷപ്പെടുത്തുന്നതിന്റെ പ്രഭാവം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Inferenza tat-Traduzzjoni bil-Propagazzjoni tal-Kunċett</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Компьютерийн шинжлэх ухаан</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Wniosek tłumaczenia poprzez propagację koncepcji</title_pl>
      <title_no>Omsetjingsference etter konseptpropagasjon</title_no>
      <title_ro>Traducere Inferență după concept Propagație</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Inferencija prevoda po proširenju koncepta</title_sr>
      <title_si>@ title: window</title_si>
      <title_so>Turjumista ku saabsan ogeysiiska</title_so>
      <title_sv>Översättning Inferens efter begrepp Propagation</title_sv>
      <title_ta>மொழிபெயர்ப்பு மொழிபெயர்ப்பு</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Tarjima qilish</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Dịch bởi hoà thuyết</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Преводови изводи по размножаване на концепцията</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Inferencija prevoda po proširenju koncepta</title_hr>
      <title_da>Oversættelse Inference efter begreb Propagation</title_da>
      <title_nl>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title_nl>
      <title_de>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title_de>
      <title_id>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title_id>
      <title_fa>تغییر ترجمه توسط تغییر نظریه</title_fa>
      <title_ko>개념 전파에 기초한 번역 추리</title_ko>
      <title_tr>Görniş Opşenler:</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Tafsiri na Utafiti</title_sw>
      <title_sq>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title_sq>
      <title_af>Vertaling Inferensie deur Konsensiepropagasie</title_af>
      <title_hy>Թարգմանական ինֆերանսը ըստ գաղափարի պրոգացիայի</title_hy>
      <title_bn>কনসেপ্টের বৈশিষ্ট্যাবলীর অনুবাদ</title_bn>
      <title_am>ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_az>T톛rc칲m톛 칐l칞칲s칲</title_az>
      <title_bs>Inferencija prevoda po propagaciji koncepta</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Překlad závěr podle šíření konceptů</title_cs>
      <title_et>Tõlke järeldus mõiste levitamise järgi</title_et>
      <title_fi>Käännösjohtopäätös käsitteen levittämisen mukaan</title_fi>
      <title_jv>undo-type</title_jv>
      <title_he>תורגם ע"י Qsubs מצוות</title_he>
      <title_sk>Sklep prevoda po razmnoževanju koncepta</title_sk>
      <title_ha>Translation Inference by Concept Propagation</title_ha>
      <title_bo>ཡིག་ཚོགས་ལ་བསམ་བྱ་ཚུལ་དང་འགྲེལ་བཤད་</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تصف هذه الورقة مساهمتنا في المهمة المشتركة الثالثة حول استدلال الترجمة عبر القواميس (TIAD-2020). نحن نصف نهجًا في استدلال الترجمة استنادًا إلى الأساليب الرمزية ، ونشر المفاهيم على رسم بياني للقواميس المترابطة: بالنظر إلى التعيين من كلمات لغة المصدر إلى المفاهيم المعجمية (على سبيل المثال ، synsets) كبذور ، نستخدم قواميس ثنائية اللغة لاستقراء رسم الخرائط من الكلمات اللغوية المحورية والهدف لهذه المفاهيم المعجمية. ثم يتم إجراء استدلال الترجمة من خلال البحث عن المفهوم (المفاهيم) المعجمية لكلمة لغة المصدر وإرجاع كلمة (كلمات) اللغة الهدف التي حصلت هذه المفاهيم المعجمية على أعلى درجة لها. نقدم نسختين من هذا النظام: أحدهما يستخدم مجموعات WordNet كمفاهيم ، والآخر يستخدم إدخالات معجمية (ترجمات) كمفاهيم. مع عتبة 0 ، يكون التكوين الأخير هو الثاني بين أنظمة المشاركين من حيث درجة F1. وصفنا أيضًا تجارب تقييم إضافية على بيانات Apertium ، ومقارنة مع نهج سابق يعتمد على تضمين الإسقاط ، ونهج الإسقاط المقيد الذي يتفوق على نظام الفانيليا TIAD-2020 بهامش كبير.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo describe nuestra contribución a la Tercera tarea compartida sobre la inferencia de la traducción en los diccionarios (TIAD-2020). Describimos un enfoque sobre la inferencia de la traducción basado en métodos simbólicos, la propagación de conceptos en un gráfico de diccionarios interconectados: Dado un mapeo de las palabras del idioma fuente a los conceptos léxicos (por ejemplo, synsets) como semilla, utilizamos diccionarios bilingües para extrapolar un mapeo de pivote y objetivo palabras del lenguaje a estos conceptos léxicos. La inferencia de la traducción se realiza buscando los conceptos léxicos de una palabra del idioma de origen y devolviendo la (s) palabra (s) del idioma de destino para los cuales estos conceptos léxicos tienen la puntuación más alta respectiva. Presentamos dos instancias de este sistema: una que usa synsets de WordNet como conceptos y otra que usa entradas léxicas (traducciones) como conceptos. Con un umbral de 0, esta última configuración es la segunda entre los sistemas participantes en términos de puntuación F1. También describimos experimentos de evaluación adicionales en datos de Apertium, una comparación con un enfoque anterior basado en la proyección incrustada y un enfoque para la proyección restringida que supera al sistema básico TIAD-2020 por un amplio margen.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo descreve nossa contribuição para a Terceira Tarefa Compartilhada sobre Inferência de Tradução entre Dicionários (TIAD-2020). Descrevemos uma abordagem de inferência de tradução baseada em métodos simbólicos, a propagação de conceitos em um gráfico de dicionários interconectados: Dado um mapeamento de palavras do idioma de origem para conceitos lexicais (por exemplo, synsets) como uma semente, usamos dicionários bilíngues para extrapolar um mapeamento de palavras pivô e da língua-alvo para esses conceitos lexicais. A inferência de tradução é então realizada procurando o(s) conceito(s) lexical(is) de uma palavra do idioma de origem e retornando a(s) palavra(s) do idioma de destino para os quais esses conceitos lexicais têm a respectiva pontuação mais alta. Apresentamos duas instanciações desse sistema: uma usando synsets WordNet como conceitos e outra usando entradas lexicais (traduções) como conceitos. Com um limite de 0, esta última configuração é a segunda entre os sistemas participantes em termos de pontuação F1. Também descrevemos experimentos de avaliação adicionais em dados Apertium, uma comparação com uma abordagem anterior baseada em projeção de incorporação e uma abordagem para projeção restrita que supera o sistema vanilla TIAD-2020 por uma grande margem.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>この論文では、辞書全体の翻訳推論に関する3番目の共有タスク（ TIAD -2020 ）への貢献について説明します。 私たちは、記号的方法に基づく翻訳推論のアプローチ、相互に接続された辞書のグラフ上での概念の伝播について説明します。ソース言語の単語から辞書の概念（例えば、シンセット）へのマッピングをシードとして考えると、私たちはバイリンガル辞書を使用して、ピボットとターゲット言語の単語のこれらの辞書の概念へのマッピングを推測します。 次いで、翻訳推論は、語源言語単語の語源的概念（複数可）を調べ、これらの語源的概念がそれぞれの最高スコアを有する対象言語単語（複数可）を返すことによって実行される。 このシステムの2つのインスタンスを提示します。1つは概念としてWordNetシンセットを使用し、もう1つは概念として辞書エントリ（翻訳）を使用します。 閾値が０である場合、後者の構成は、Ｆ１スコアに関して参加システムの中で２番目である。 また、Apertiumデータの追加の評価実験、埋め込み投影に基づく以前のアプローチとの比較、およびTIAD -2020バニラシステムを大幅に上回る制約付き投影のアプローチについても説明します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर शब्दकोशों (TIAD-2020) में अनुवाद अनुमान पर तीसरे साझा कार्य में हमारे योगदान का वर्णन करता है। हम प्रतीकात्मक तरीकों के आधार पर अनुवाद अनुमान पर एक दृष्टिकोण का वर्णन करते हैं, परस्पर शब्दकोशों के ग्राफ पर अवधारणाओं का प्रसार: एक बीज के रूप में लेक्सिकल अवधारणाओं (जैसे, synsets) के लिए स्रोत भाषा शब्दों से एक मानचित्रण को देखते हुए, हम द्विभाषी शब्दकोशों का उपयोग इन लेक्सिकल अवधारणाओं के लिए धुरी और लक्षित भाषा शब्दों के मानचित्रण को एक्सट्रपलेशन करने के लिए करते हैं। अनुवाद अनुमान तब एक स्रोत भाषा शब्द की लेक्सिकल अवधारणा (ओं) को देखकर और लक्ष्य भाषा शब्द (ओं) को वापस करके किया जाता है, जिसके लिए इन लेक्सिकल अवधारणाओं में संबंधित उच्चतम स्कोर होता है। हम इस प्रणाली के दो इंस्टेंटेशन प्रस्तुत करते हैं: एक अवधारणाओं के रूप में वर्डनेट सिंसेट का उपयोग करना, और एक अवधारणाओं के रूप में लेक्सिकल प्रविष्टियों (अनुवाद) का उपयोग करना। 0 की दहलीज के साथ, बाद का कॉन्फ़िगरेशन F1 स्कोर के मामले में प्रतिभागी प्रणालियों के बीच दूसरा है। हम एपर्टियम डेटा पर अतिरिक्त मूल्यांकन प्रयोगों का भी वर्णन करते हैं, एम्बेडिंग प्रोजेक्शन के आधार पर पहले के दृष्टिकोण के साथ तुलना करते हैं, और विवश प्रक्षेपण के लिए एक दृष्टिकोण जो टीआईएडी -2020 वेनिला सिस्टम को एक बड़े मार्जिन से बेहतर बनाता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>本文引我对跨词典译推理第三共享职(TIAD-2020)之献。 余述重译推理之法,其略曰:给定自源言单词至词汇名(如,synsets)映以为种,以双语词典推枢轴而言单词词汇其名。 已而求其言单词词汇反之词汇其最高分言单词以译推之。 二实:一以 WordNet 合集为名,一以词法条(译)为名。 阈值为 0 时,后一置 F1 分参与者统中第二。 又叙Apertium数之实验,较之早景,与一约束投影之法,其性大优于TIAD-2020。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Déanann an páipéar seo cur síos ar an méid a chuireamar leis an Tríú Tasc Comhroinnte ar Thástáil Aistriúcháin thar Fhoclóirí (TIAD-2020). Déanaimid cur síos ar chur chuige ar thátal aistriúcháin bunaithe ar mhodhanna siombalacha, ar iomadú coincheapa thar ghraf d’fhoclóirí idirnasctha: I bhfianaise mapála ó fhocail na teanga foinse go coincheapa foclóireachta (m.sh., synsets) mar shíol, úsáidimid foclóirí dátheangacha chun léarscáiliú a eachtarshuíomh. focail mhaighdeog agus sprioctheanga do na coincheapa foclóireachta seo. Déantar tátal aistriúcháin ansin trí bhreathnú a dhéanamh ar choincheap(í) foclóireachta focal teanga foinse agus ar ais ar an bhfocal/na focail sprioctheanga a bhfuil an scór is airde ag na coincheapa foclóireachta seo ina leith. Cuirimid dhá mheandarú den chóras seo i láthair: ceann amháin ag baint úsáide as synsets WordNet mar choincheapa, agus ceann ag baint úsáide as iontrálacha foclóireachta (aistrithe) mar choincheapa. Le tairseach de 0, is é an chumraíocht deiridh an dara ceann i measc na gcóras rannpháirtithe i dtéarmaí scór F1. Déanaimid cur síos freisin ar thurgnaimh mheastóireachta breise ar shonraí Apertium, comparáid le cur chuige níos luaithe bunaithe ar theilgean leabú, agus cur chuige maidir le teilgean srianta a sháraíonn córas fanaile TIAD-2020 le corrlach mór.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία περιγράφει τη συνεισφορά μας στην τρίτη κοινή εργασία για τη μετάφραση συμπερασμάτων σε λεξικά (ΤΙAD-2020). Περιγράφουμε μια προσέγγιση σχετικά με το συμπέρασμα μετάφρασης βασισμένη σε συμβολικές μεθόδους, τη διάδοση εννοιών σε ένα γράφημα διασυνδεδεμένων λεξικών: Με δεδομένη τη χαρτογράφηση από λέξεις της πηγής σε λεξικές έννοιες (π.χ. σύνσετ) ως σπόρο, χρησιμοποιούμε δίγλωσσα λεξικά για να εξάγουμε μια χαρτογράφηση λέξεων στροφής και γλώσσας στόχου σε αυτές τις λεξικές έννοιες. Στη συνέχεια, το συμπέρασμα της μετάφρασης πραγματοποιείται με αναζήτηση της λεξικής έννοιας μιας λέξης της πηγής γλώσσας και επιστροφή της λέξης της γλώσσας στόχου για την οποία αυτές οι λεξικές έννοιες έχουν την αντίστοιχη υψηλότερη βαθμολογία. Παρουσιάζουμε δύο στιγμιότυπα αυτού του συστήματος: μία που χρησιμοποιεί συνοπτικά σύνολα ως έννοιες και μία που χρησιμοποιεί λεξικές καταχωρήσεις (μεταφράσεις) ως έννοιες. Με κατώτατο όριο 0, η τελευταία διαμόρφωση είναι η δεύτερη μεταξύ των συμμετεχόντων συστημάτων όσον αφορά την βαθμολογία F1. Περιγράφουμε επίσης πρόσθετα πειράματα αξιολόγησης σε δεδομένα Apertium, μια σύγκριση με μια παλαιότερη προσέγγιση βασισμένη στην ενσωμάτωση της προβολής, και μια προσέγγιση για περιορισμένη προβολή που ξεπερνά το σύστημα βανίλιας κατά μεγάλο περιθώριο.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a tanulmány bemutatja hozzájárulásunkat a szótárak közötti fordítási inferenciával kapcsolatos harmadik megosztott feladathoz (TIAD-2020). A fordítási következtetés szimbolikus módszereken alapuló megközelítését írjuk le, a fogalmak terjesztését egy összekapcsolt szótárak grafikonján keresztül: A forrásnyelvi szavaktól a lexikai fogalmakig (pl. szintaszetekig) való térképezést vetve kétnyelvű szótárakat használunk arra, hogy extrapoláljuk a pivot- és célnyelvi szavakat ezekre a lexikai fogalmakra. A fordítási következtetést ezután a forrásnyelvi szó lexikai fogalmának (fogalmainak) megkeresésével végezzük el, és visszaadjuk azt a célnyelvi szót (szavakat), amelyre ezek a lexikai fogalmak rendelkeznek a legmagasabb pontszámmal. Ennek a rendszernek a két pillanatát mutatjuk be: az egyik a WordNet szinoniákat fogalmaként használja, a másik pedig a lexikális bejegyzéseket (fordításokat) fogalmaként. A 0 küszöbértékkel az utóbbi konfiguráció a második a résztvevő rendszerek között F1 pontszám tekintetében. További értékelési kísérleteket is bemutatunk Apertium adatokon, egy korábbi, beágyazási vetítésen alapuló megközelítéssel való összehasonlítást, valamint egy korlátozott vetítésen alapuló megközelítést, amely nagy mértékben felülmúlja a TIAD-2020 vanília rendszert.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ეს დოკუმენტი აღწერს ჩვენი დამატება სამუშაო დამატებული სამუშაო დავალებისთვის სამუშაო დავალების ინფერენციაზე (TIAD-2020). ჩვენ სიმბოლოგიური მეტებისთვის გადავიწყებთ შეცვლის ინფრენციის პროგრაცია, კონცეტების პროგრაცია კონცექტურების განმავლობაზე, საშუალებული სიტყვების განმავლობაზე: გამოყენებული სიტყვების სიტყვებისთვის ლექსიკალური კონცექტურებისთვის (მაგალითად სინქ შემდეგ გადაწყვეტილების ინფრენცია იქნება, რომელიც ამ ლექსიკალური კონცექტის სიტყვის ლექსიკალური კონცექტის შესახებ და მისაღების სიტყვის(ები) გადაწყვეტილებით, რომლებიც ამ ლე ჩვენ ამ სისტემის ორი ინტენტიციაცია ჩვენებთ: ერთი WordNet სინქექტის გამოყენება როგორც კონცექტის, და ერთი ლექსიკალური ინტენტიციების გამოყენება (გარგება) როგ 0-ის პირობით, შემდეგ კონფიგურაცია არის F1 წერტილის შესახებ მოთავსებული სისტემის მეორე. ჩვენ ასევე აღწერეთ აპერტიომის მონაცემების დამატებით ექსპერიმენტები, პროექციის დაბაზეული პროექციის დამატებით დამუშავებული პროექციის დამატებით და პროექციის დამატებით, რომელიც გავანალილი</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente apibūdinamas mūsų indėlis į trečiąją bendrą vertimo žodynais užduotį (TIAD-2020). Mes apibūdiname požiūrį į vertimo išvadas, grindžiamas simboliniais metodais, sąvokų sklaidą tarpusavyje sujungtų žodynų grafikoje: atsižvelgiant į žemėlapį nuo išorinių kalbų žodžių iki leksinių sąvokų (pvz., sintezių) kaip sėklos, mes naudojame dvikalbius žodynus, kad ekstrapoliuotume šių leksinių sąvokų sukimosi ir tikslinės kalbos žodžių žemėlapį. Tada vertimo išvada atliekama ieškant šaltinio kalbos žodžio lexinės s ąvokos (-ų) ir grąžinant tikslinės kalbos žodį (-us), kuriam (-iems) šios leksinės sąvokos turi atitinkamą didžiausią rezultatą. Mes pristatome dvi šios sistemos instancijas: viena naudoja WordNet sintezes kaip koncepcijas, o kita naudoja lexinius įrašus (vertimus) kaip koncepcijas. With a threshold of 0, the latter configuration is the second among participant systems in terms of F1 score.  Taip pat aprašome papildomus vertinimo eksperimentus, susijusius su apertio duomenimis, palyginimą su ankstesniu metodu, pagrįstu įterpimo prognozėmis, ir ribotos prognozės metodą, kuris labai viršija TIAD-2020 vanilių sistemą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo descrive il nostro contributo al terzo compito condiviso sull'inferenza della traduzione tra dizionari (TIAD-2020). Descriviamo un approccio sull'inferenza traduttiva basato su metodi simbolici, la propagazione dei concetti su un grafico di dizionari interconnessi: Data una mappatura dalle parole della lingua di origine ai concetti lessicali (ad esempio, i sinonimi) come seme, usiamo dizionari bilingui per estrapolare una mappatura delle parole pivot e della lingua di destinazione a questi concetti lessicali. L'inferenza della traduzione viene quindi eseguita cercando i concetti lessicali di una parola della lingua di origine e restituendo le parole della lingua di destinazione per le quali questi concetti lessicali hanno il punteggio più alto. Presentiamo due istanziazioni di questo sistema: una che utilizza i sinonimi WordNet come concetti, e una che utilizza le voci lessicali (traduzioni) come concetti. Con una soglia di 0, quest'ultima configurazione è la seconda tra i sistemi partecipanti in termini di punteggio F1. Descriviamo anche ulteriori esperimenti di valutazione sui dati Apertium, un confronto con un approccio precedente basato sulla proiezione embedding e un approccio per la proiezione vincolata che supera di gran lunga il sistema vanilla TIAD-2020.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз сөздіктердің ортақтастырылған тапсырмаға (TIAD-2020) үшінші ортақтастырылған тапсырмаға қатынасызды таңдайды. Біз символдық әдістеріне негізделген аудармалардың инференциясының арқылы, бірлескен сөздердің графикасында концепциялардың пропагациясын түсіндіреміз: көзінің тілден сөздерді лексикалық концепцияларға (мысалы, символдық концепцияларға сәйкестік) сәйкестігін (мысалы,  Аударманың көзі тілдің лексикалық концепциясын іздеп, мақсатты тілдің сөздерін қайтарып, осы лексикалық концепциялардың ең жоғары нәтижесін қайтаруға болады. Біз осы жүйеңіздің екі институцияларын келтіреміз: WordNet- тің қадамдастыруын концепциялар ретінде, бірінші лексикалық жазуларды (аудармаларды) концепциялар ретінде қолданады. 0- тың шегі болса, соңғы баптау - F1- нүкте қатысушылардың екіншісі. Біз сондай-ақ Apertium деректерінің қосымша оқу тәжірибелерін таңдаймыз, бұрынғы проекциясының негізінде салыстырылған тәжірибелерімен және TIAD-2020 vanilla жүйесіне үлкен шектеу арқылы шектелген проекциялардың</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Овој документ го опишува нашиот придонес за третата заедничка задача за превод на речниците (ТИАД-2020). Опишуваме пристап кон преведувачката инференција базиран на симболични методи, пропалирањето на концептите преку график на меѓуповрзани речници: Со оглед на мапирање од зборовите на изворниот јазик до лексикалните концепти (на пример синсети) како семе, користиме двојјазични речници за екстраполирање на мапирање на зборовите на вртен јазик и Преведувачката инференција потоа се извршува со пребарување на лексикалниот концепт(и) на зборот(и) на изворниот јазик и враќање на зборот(ите) на јазикот(и) на кој(и) овие лексикални концепти имаат највисок резултат. Презентираме две инстанции од овој систем: една користи WordNet синсети како концепти, а една користи лексикални записи (преводи) како концепти. Со праг од 0, последната конфигурација е втората меѓу системите на учесниците во поглед на оценката F1. Ние, исто така, опишуваме дополнителни експерименти за евалуација на податоците од Апертиум, споредба со претходниот пристап базиран на вклучување проекции, и пристап за ограничена проекција што го надминува ванилскиот систем ТИАД-2020 со голема маргина.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kertas ini menggambarkan kontribusi kita ke Tugas Terberkongsi ketiga tentang Inferensi Terjemahan di seluruh Kamus (TIAD-2020). Kami menggambarkan pendekatan pada kesimpulan terjemahan berdasarkan kaedah simbolik, penyebaran konsep melalui graf kamus yang saling terhubung: diberikan peta dari perkataan bahasa sumber ke konsep leksikal (cth., sinset) sebagai benih, kami menggunakan kamus dua bahasa untuk ekstrapolasi peta perkataan pivot dan bahasa sasaran kepada konsep leksikal ini. Kemudian kesimpulan terjemahan dilakukan dengan mencari konsep leksikal bagi perkataan bahasa sumber dan mengembalikan perkataan bahasa sasaran yang konsep leksikal ini mempunyai skor tertinggi. Kami perkenalkan dua kejadian sistem ini: Satu menggunakan sinset WordNet sebagai konsep, dan satu menggunakan masukan leksikal (terjemahan) sebagai konsep. Dengan ambang 0, konfigurasi terakhir adalah kedua diantara sistem peserta dalam terma skor F1. Kami juga menggambarkan eksperimen penilaian tambahan pada data Apertium, perbandingan dengan pendekatan yang lebih awal berdasarkan projeksi penyampaian, dan pendekatan untuk projeksi yang terhalang yang melebihi sistem vanila TIAD-2020 dengan margin besar.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ നിഘടക്ഷത്തിലെ മൂന്നാം പങ്കാളിയുള്ള പണിയിലേക്ക് ഞങ്ങളുടെ പങ്ക് വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു ചിഹ്നങ്ങളില്‍ അടിസ്ഥാനമായി പരിഭാഷപ്പെടുത്തിയിരിക്കുന്ന അഭിപ്രോഗ്രാപ്പ് ചെയ്യുന്നതിനെക്കുറിച്ച് ഞങ്ങള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്ന ഒരു ചിഹ്നങ്ങള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു: ഒരു സോര്‍സ്സ് ഭാഷയുടെ വാക്കുകള്‍ നോക്കുന്നതിനാല്‍ പരിഭാഷപ്പെടുത്തി ഈ ലെക്സിക്കല്‍ ആശയങ്ങള്‍ക്കുള്ള ഏറ്റവും ഉയര്‍ന്ന സ്കോര്‍ട്ടുകള്‍ ഉള്ള ലക്ഷ് ഈ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ രണ്ടു അവസ്ഥ നാം കാണിക്കുന്നു. ഒരാള്‍ വാര്‍ഡ്നെറ്റ് സിനിസ്റ്റുകള്‍ ആശയങ്ങളായി ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു. ഒരാള്‍ ലെക എഫ്‌1 സ്കോര്‍ട്ടില്‍ പങ്കാളികളുടെ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ രണ്ടാമത്തെ ക്രമീകരണം കൂട്ടുകാരുടെ ഇടയിലാണ്. അപ്പാര്‍ട്ടിയം ഡാറ്റായില്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ പരിശോധന പരീക്ഷണങ്ങള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു. പ്രോജക്ടിങ്ങ് പ്രോജക്ഷന്‍ അടിസ്ഥാനമായി അടിസ്ഥാനമാക്കുന്ന ഒരു മുന്‍പ് നീക്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jiddeskrivi l-kontribut tagħna għat-Tielet Kompitu Konġunt dwar l-Inferenza tat-Traduzzjoni bejn id-Dizzjonarji (TIAD-2020). Aħna niddeskrivu approċċ dwar l-inferenza tat-traduzzjoni bbażat fuq metodi simboliċi, il-propagazzjoni ta’ kunċetti fuq grafika ta’ dikjararji interkonnessi: Minħabba mapping minn kliem tal-lingwa tas-sors g ħal kunċetti lexiċi (e ż., sinsetts) bħala żerriegħa, a ħna nużaw dikjararji billingwi biex nisttrapolaw mapping ta’ kliem tal-lingwa pivot u fil-mira għal dawn il-kunċetti lexiċi. L-inferenza tat-traduzzjoni mbagħad titwettaq billi jitfittex il-kunċett(i) lexiku(i) ta’ kelma tal-lingwa tas-sors u tiġi rritornata l-kelma(i) tal-lingwa fil-mira li għaliha dawn il-kunċetti lexiċi għandhom l-ogħla punteġġ rispettiv. Aħna nippreżentaw żewġ istanzjazzjonijiet ta’ din is-sistema: wieħed juża s-sinsetti WordNet bħala kunċetti, u wieħed juża l-entrati lexiċi (traduzzjonijiet) bħala kunċetti. With a threshold of 0, the latter configuration is the second among participant systems in terms of F1 score.  Aħna niddeskrivu wkoll esperimenti addizzjonali ta' evalwazzjoni dwar id-dejta tal-Aperzju, paragun ma' approċċ preċedenti bbażat fuq projezzjoni inkorporata, u approċċ għal projezzjoni ristretta li taqbeż is-sistema tal-vanilla TIAD-2020 b'marġini kbir.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас хэвлэгдэх үеийн үеийн хэвлэгдэх (TIAD-2020) 3 дахь хуваалтын ажил дээр бидний нийлүүлэлтийг тайлбарладаг. Бид символын аргын үндсэн орчлолын инференцийн тухай ойлголт, харилцааны хоорондын холбоотой үгийг график дээр дэвшүүлэх арга загварыг тайлбарлаж байна: эх үүсвэрийн хэл үгийг лексикийн ойлголтын төлөө (жишээлбэл, синзет) гэх мэт зураг ашиглаж, бид хоёр хэл үгийг pivot болон target хэл үгийг эд Ингээд хөгжлийн инференцийг эх үүсвэрийн хэлний лексикийн тодорхойлолт(үүдийг) харж, зорилготой хэлний үг(үүдийг) буцааж, эдгээр лексикийн тодорхойлолтууд хамгийн өндөр тооны үзүүлэлт гаргадаг. Бид энэ системийн хоёр хугацааныг тайлбарлаж байна: WordNet-ийг ойлголт гэж ашиглаж байгаа нэг, нэг нь сөрөг хэлбэрүүдийг ойлголт гэж ашиглаж байгаа. 0-ын хэмжээтэй хоёр дахь загвар нь F1 оноо гэх мэт оролцогчдын системийн хоёр дахь дахь загвар юм. Мөн бид Апертиум өгөгдлийн дээр нэмэлт үнэлгээ туршилтыг тайлбарлаж байна. Өмнөх арга баримтын төсөөллийн тухай харьцуулж байна. Мөн TIAD-2020 оны ванилл системийг маш том завсарлагаар үржүүлэх шаардлагатай төсөөллийн тухай харьцуулсан.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir opisuje naš doprinos Trećem zajedničkom zadatku o infekciji prevoda u raznim rečenicima (TIAD-2020). Opišemo pristup inferenciji prevođenja na temelju simboličkih metoda, proširenje koncepta na grafiku međupovezanih rečenica: S obzirom na mapiranje iz izvornog jezika reči na leksičke koncepte (npr. sinsete) kao semen, koristimo dve jezičke rečenice kako bi ekstrapolirali mapiranje pivotova i ciljnih jezičkih reči na ove leksičke koncepte. Inferencija prevoda je onda provedena tražeći leksički koncept(s) izvornog jezika riječi i vratiti ciljnu jezičku reč(s) za koju ovi leksički koncepti imaju najviši rezultat. Predstavljamo dve instancije ovog sistema: jedan koristi WordNet sinkronizaciju kao koncept, a jedan koristi leksičke ulaze (prevode) kao koncept. Sa praškom od 0, poslednja konfiguracija je druga među sistemima učesnika u smislu rezultata F1. Također opisujemo dodatne eksperimente za procjenu podataka o Apertiumu, usporedbu sa ranijim pristupom baziranim na ugrađenju projekcije, i pristup ograničenim projekcijama koji nadmaže sistem vanile TIAD-2020 sa velikom marginom.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł opisuje nasz wkład w trzecie wspólne zadanie dotyczące wniosków tłumaczeń w słownikach (TIAD-2020). Opisujemy podejście do wnioskowania tłumaczeń oparte na metodach symbolicznych, propagowanie pojęć na wykresie wzajemnie powiązanych słowników: Biorąc pod uwagę mapowanie ze słów języka źródłowego do koncepcji leksykalnych (np. zestawów syntetycznych) jako ziarno, używamy dwujęzycznych słowników do ekstrapolowania mapowania słów pivot i docelowych do tych koncepcji leksykalnych. Wniosek tłumaczeniowy jest następnie wykonywany poprzez wyszukiwanie koncepcji leksykalnych słowa języka źródłowego i zwracanie słowa języka docelowego, dla których te koncepcje leksykalne mają odpowiednio najwyższy wynik. Przedstawiamy dwie instancje tego systemu: jedną używającą syntezów WordNet jako pojęć, a drugą używającą wpisów leksykalnych (tłumaczeń) jako pojęć. Z progiem 0, ta ostatnia konfiguracja jest drugą wśród systemów uczestniczących pod względem wyniku F1. Opisujemy również dodatkowe eksperymenty oceniające dane Apertium, porównanie z wcześniejszym podejściem opartym na projekcji osadzenia oraz podejście do projekcji ograniczonej, które znacznie przewyższa system waniliowy TIAD-2020.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare descrie contribuția noastră la cea de-a treia sarcină partajată privind inferența traducerii în dicționare (TIAD-2020). Descriem o abordare a inferenței traducerii bazată pe metode simbolice, propagarea conceptelor peste un grafic de dicționare interconectate: Dată fiind o mapare de la cuvinte din limba sursă la concepte lexicale (de exemplu, sinoteuri) ca o sămânță, folosim dicționare bilingve pentru a extrapola o mapare a cuvintelor pivot și limba țintă la aceste concepte lexicale. Concluzia traducerii este apoi efectuată prin căutarea conceptului (conceptelor) lexical al unui cuvânt din limba sursă și returnarea cuvântului (cuvintelor) din limba țintă pentru care aceste concepte lexicale au cel mai mare scor respectiv. Prezentăm două instanții ale acestui sistem: una folosind sintetiile WordNet ca concepte și una folosind intrări lexicale (traduceri) ca concepte. Cu un prag de 0, ultima configurație este a doua dintre sistemele participante în ceea ce privește scorul F1. De asemenea, descriem experimente suplimentare de evaluare a datelor Apertium, o comparație cu o abordare anterioară bazată pe proiecția încorporată și o abordare pentru proiecția constrânsă care depășește cu o marjă mare sistemul de vanilie TIAD-2020.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret beskriver vårt bidrag til den tredje delte oppgåva om omsetjingskonferensen over ordlister (TIAD-2020). Vi beskriver ein tilnærming på omsetjingsinformasjon basert på symbolske metoder, utviklinga av konseptar over eit graf av interconnected dictionaries: Given eit karting frå kjeldespråk ord til leksiske konseptar (f.eks. synsett) som frø, bruker vi bilinguelt ordbokstavar for å ekstrapolisera ein karting av pivot og målspråk ord til desse leksiske konseptane. Omsetjingsinformasjon vert derfor utført ved å sjå opp leksiske konsept( ar) til eit kjeldespråk ord og tilbakestilla målsspråk( ar) ordet( ar) som desse leksiske konseptane har den heile høgste poeng( ar). Vi presenterer to instansasjonar i dette systemet: Ein som brukar WordNet synkroniserer som konseptar, og ein brukar leksiske oppføringar (omsetjingar) som konseptar. Med ein terskel på 0 er den siste oppsettet den andre mellom deltakarsystemet med F1- poeng. Vi beskriver også ekstra evalueringseksperimenter på Apertium-data, samanlikning med ein tidlegare tilnærming basert på innbygging av projeksjon, og ein tilnærming for begrenset projeksjon som utfører vanylsystemet TIAD-2020 med stor margin.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_so>Warqaddan waxaa ku qoran noogu contributeynayo shaqada saddexaad ee lagu sharciyey Turjubaan Inference across dictionaries (TIAD-2020). Waxaynu tilmaamaynaa qaab ku saabsan cudurada turjumaadda ku saleysan qaabab calaamad ah, waraajinta fikrada ku saabsan sawirada ku saabsan luqada dhexe e e isku xiran: Sida uu karto sawir ka soo baxay hadallada afka sourceed ilaa fikrada leksikal (tusaale ahaan synsets) sida farcan ah, waxaan u isticmaalnaa luqadaha labada luqadood si a an u soo saarno karto sawirada afka ee pivot iyo waxyaabaha ku hagaajiya oo aan u jeedno fikradan lexic Waqtiga turjumaadda waxaa la sameeyaa marka la eego fikrada leksikarka ee afka nooca ah iyo in lagu soo celiyo hadalka luqada (s) ee loogu talagalay, kaas oo dhanka leksikalka ah ay haystaan darajada ugu sareeya. Waxaan soo bandhignaa laba xaaladood oo nidaamkan ah: Mid isticmaalaya WordNet si fikrada ah, mid isticmaalaya qoraalka leksikal (turjumaan) sida fikrada. Xiriir 0, xubinta dambe waa mid labaad oo ka mid ah nidaamka qayb-qaata oo ku qoran score F1. Sidoo kale waxaynu ku qornaa imtixaanka qiimeynta kale oo ku saabsan Apertium data, taas oo la barbardhigi karo qaab hore oo ku saleysan sameynta dhaqdhaqaalaha, iyo qaab lagu sameynayo qorshaha qasabka ah oo soo saara nidaamka TIAD-2020 oo baal ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats beskriver vårt bidrag till den tredje delade uppgiften om översättningsinferens över ordböcker (TIAD-2020). Vi beskriver ett förhållningssätt till översättningsdeferens baserat på symboliska metoder, spridning av begrepp över en graf av sammanlänkade ordböcker: Med en kartläggning från källspråksord till lexikala begrepp (t.ex. synsets) som ett frö använder vi tvåspråkiga ordböcker för att extrapolera en kartläggning av pivot- och målspråksord till dessa lexikala begrepp. Översättningsslutsatsen utförs sedan genom att leta upp det lexikala begreppet i ett källspråksord och returnera det/de målspråksord som dessa lexikala begrepp har högst poäng för. Vi presenterar två instantier av detta system: En använder WordNet-synuppsättningar som begrepp och en använder lexikala poster (översättningar) som begrepp. Med en tröskel på 0 är den senare konfigurationen den andra bland deltagarsystem när det gäller F1 poäng. Vi beskriver också ytterligare utvärderingsexperiment på Apertiumdata, en jämförelse med ett tidigare tillvägagångssätt baserat på inbäddningsprojektion, och ett tillvägagångssätt för tvångsprojektion som överträffar TIAD-2020 vaniljsystemet med stor marginal.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>(TIAD-2020) یہ کاغذ لکھنے والوں کے درمیان ترجمہ انفارنس کے بارے میں تیسرے شریک ٹاکس میں ہمارا حصہ بیان کرتا ہے۔ ہم سیمبلیک طریقوں پر بنیاد رکھتے ہیں ترجمہ ایفانس کے ذریعہ ایک طریقہ کا مطابق بیان کرتے ہیں، ایک گراف سے متصل ہوئے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے لکھنے والے سورج زبان کے لکھنے کے ذریعے لکھنے کے ذریعے اور ہدایت زبان کے لکھنے کے ذریعے لکھنے کے ذریعے عمل کئے جاتے ہیں جن کے لئے یہ لکھی نظریں بہترین اسکور ہیں. ہم اس سیسٹم کے دو انٹنسیٹ کو پیش کرتے ہیں: ایک WordNet کا استعمال کرتا ہے کہ تفصیل کے طور پر، اور ایک لکسیکل انٹریٹ (ترجمہ) کو تفصیل کے طور پر استعمال کرتا ہے۔ 0 کے دروازے کے ساتھ، آخری تنظیمات F1 اسکور کے مطابق دوسرا ہے. ہم نے آپرٹیوم ڈاٹیوم کے بارے میں اضافہ ارزیابی آزمائش کی آزمائش کا مطابق بیان کرتا ہے، ایک پہلے طریقہ کے مطابق پیدا کرنے پر بنیاد رکھا ہے، اور ایک طریقہ محدود ہونے کے لئے جو TIAD-2020 vanilla سیستم کو بڑی محدودیت سے زیادہ اضافہ کرتا ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_si>මේ පැත්තේ අපේ සම්බන්ධය විස්තර කරනවා තුන්වෙනි සම්බන්ධ කාර්යාලයට භාවිතය සම්බන්ධ විස්තර (TIAD-2020යි)  අපි ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා සිම්බලික විදිහට, ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශ @ info: tooltip අපි මේ පද්ධතියේ ස්ථානය දෙකක් පෙන්වන්නේ: WordNet විශ්වාසයෙන් පාවිච්චි වෙනුවෙන් පද්ධතියක් විදියට සහ ලෙක් 0 වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රමාණයක් තියෙන්නේ, අන්තිම ප්‍රමාණය F1 ප්‍රමාණයක් වලින් අංශිකයෙන් අංශිකයෙන් අ අපි අපර්ටියම් දත්තේ අතර අවශ්‍ය විශ්ලේෂණ පරීක්ෂණ පරීක්ෂණ ප්‍රයෝජනයක් වගේම විස්තර කරනවා, පළවෙනි ප්‍රයෝජනයක් සඳහා පරීක්ෂණය සඳහ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தில் மூன்றாம் பகிர்ந்த பணிக்கு எங்கள் பங்கு விவரிக்கிறது மொழிபெயர்ப்பு மாற்று அகராதிகள் முழுமையாக நாம் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு பாதிப்பு முறைமைகளை அடிப்படையில் மொழியிலிருந்து வரைபடத்தின் மீது விளக்கம் செய்யும் வழியை விவரிக்கிறது. மூல மொழிகளிலிருந்து ஒரு வரைபடம் வரைபடத்திலிருந்து லெக்சிக்சியல் கருத மூல மொழி வார்த்தையின் மொழியின் மொழியின் மொழிபெயர்ப்புகளை பார்த்து மொழியின் மொழிபெயர்ப்புகளை திருப்பினால் மொழிபெயர்ப்புகள் செ இந்த கணினியின் இரண்டு நிகழ்வுகளை நாம் காண்பிக்கிறோம்: ஒரு வார்ட்நெட்டின் ஒத்திசைவை உபயோகிக்கும் ஒரு கருத்துகளாக, மற் பூமியின் விளிம்புகளுடன், கடைசி வடிவமைப்பு F1 மதிப்புகளில் பங்கீட்டாளர் அமைப்புகளில் இரண்டாவது. நாம் கூடுதல் பரிசோதனைகளை குறிப்பிடுகிறோம் அப்போர்ட்ரியம் தரவின் மீது, முந்தைய செயல்பாடு திட்டத்தை அடிப்படையில் ஒப்பிடுகிறது, மற்றும் பெரிய முறையில</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Bu hujjat lugʻatlarning boshqa tarjima qilish (TIAD-2020) bilan uchinchi boʻlishilgan vazifaning qandaydigan qandaydir. Biz bir tarjima qilish usulida bog'liq lugʻatlarning grafikdagi fikrlarni tahrirlashni anglatamiz: Soul so'zlaridan tasvirlash (m. g. synsets) soni sifatida, biz ikkita lugʻatlarga foydalanamiz, pivot va lugʻatdagi so'zlarni chizish uchun bu leksikal g'oyatga qarang. Keyin tarjima qilish natijasida manba tilning eng yuqori cheksiz conceptlarini ko'rib turadi va bu cheksiz g'oyalarning eng yuqori darajaga oʻtish soʻzni qaytadi. We present two instantiations of this system: One using WordNet synsets as concepts, and one using lexical entries (translations) as concepts.  0 chegarasi bilan ikkinchi moslama F1 scori bilan bogʻliq tizimdan ikkinchi. Biz Apertium maʼlumotdagi qoʻshimcha qiymatni tahmil qilamiz, bir oldingi qanday tajriba tajriba qilishga qaramaymiz, diqqat loyihasi asosida, va katta margin bilan TIAD-2020 vanillar tizimni bajarishga qaror qiladigan qiymatni ko'rsatuvchimiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này mô tả sự đóng góp của chúng ta cho Nhiệm vụ chia sẻ về dịch ngữ qua Dictionary (TIAD-2020). Chúng tôi mô tả một phương pháp ám ảnh dịch dựa trên các phương pháp tượng trưng, sự truyền bá của các khái niệm trên một đồ thị của các từ ngữ nối nhau: Dựa vào một bản đồ từ ngôn ngữ nguồn đến các khái niệm ngôn ngữ văn học (v.d., các từ điển) như một hạt giống, chúng tôi sử dụng các từ điển hai thứ hai để tính phân loại các từ pivot và ngôn ngữ đích cho các khái niệm ngôn ngữ đó. Liên kết dịch được thực hiện bằng cách tìm hiểu các khái niệm ngôn ngữ từ điển của một từ ngôn ngữ nguồn và trả lại các từ ngôn ngữ đích mà các từ ngữ này có tỉ lệ cao nhất. Chúng tôi hiện ra hai sự phân tích của hệ thống này: Một dùng cấu trúc WordNet làm khái niệm, và một dùng mục văn (dịch) làm khái niệm. Với ngưỡng 0, cấu hình sau là thứ hai trong hệ thống tham gia với điểm F1. Chúng tôi cũng mô tả các thí nghiệm đánh giá bổ sung trên dữ liệu khỉ Apartium, một so sánh với một phương pháp trước dựa trên sự nhúng dự đoán, và một phương pháp hình phạt hạn chế được thực hiện bởi hệ thống vani TID-2020 với một khoảng cách rất lớn.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия описва нашия принос към третата споделена задача по превеждането в речниците (ТИАД-2020). Описваме подход към изводите на превода, базиран на символични методи, разпространението на понятия върху графика на взаимосвързани речници: Като се има предвид картирането от думи на изходния език към лексикалните понятия (например синсети) като семе, използваме двуезични речници, за да екстраполираме картирането на ключови и целеви езикови думи към тези лексикални понятия. Изводът за превод се извършва чрез търсене на лексикалната концепция(и) на изходната дума и връщане на целевата дума(и), за която тези лексикални понятия имат съответния най-висок резултат. Представяме две инстанции на тази система: едната използва синтези като понятия и другата използва лексикални записи (преводи) като понятия. С праг от 0, последната конфигурация е втората сред системите участници по отношение на резултат от Формула 1. Също така описваме допълнителни експерименти за оценка на данни от апертиум, сравнение с по-ранен подход, базиран на вградена проекция, и подход за ограничена проекция, който надминава ваниловата система ТИАД-2020 с голям марж.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel beschrijft onze bijdrage aan de derde gedeelde taak over vertaalinferentie tussen woordenboeken (TIAD-2020). We beschrijven een benadering van vertaalinferentie gebaseerd op symbolische methoden, de verspreiding van concepten over een grafiek van onderling verbonden woordenboeken: Gezien een toewijzing van brontaalwoorden naar lexicale concepten (bijvoorbeeld synsets) als zaad, gebruiken we tweetalige woordenboeken om een toewijzing van pivot- en doeltaalwoorden naar deze lexicale concepten te extrapoleren. Vertalingsinterferentie wordt dan uitgevoerd door het lexicale concept(en) van een brontaalwoord op te zoeken en het doeltaalwoord(en) te retourneren waarvoor deze lexicale concepten de respectievelijk hoogste score hebben. We presenteren twee instanties van dit systeem: een met WordNet synsets als concepten, en een met lexicale vermeldingen (vertalingen) als concepten. Met een drempel van 0 is de laatste configuratie de tweede onder deelnemersystemen wat betreft F1 score. We beschrijven ook aanvullende evaluatieexperimenten op Apertium data, een vergelijking met een eerdere benadering gebaseerd op embedding projectie, en een benadering voor beperkte projectie die het TIAD-2020 vanille systeem met een grote marge overtreft.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Dette dokument beskriver vores bidrag til den tredje delte opgave om oversættelsesference på tværs af ordbøger (TIAD-2020). Vi beskriver en tilgang til oversættelsesundersøgelse baseret på symbolske metoder, udbredelsen af begreber over en graf af sammenhængende ordbøger: Givet en kortlægning fra kildesprogsord til leksikalske begreber (f.eks. synsets) som et frø, bruger vi tosprogede ordbøger til at ekstrapolere en kortlægning af pivot- og målsprogsord til disse leksikalske begreber. Oversættelsesundersøgelse udføres derefter ved at slå det/de leksikalske begreb op for et kildesprogsord og returnere det/de målsprogsord, som disse leksikalske begreber har den respektive højeste score for. Vi præsenterer to instantier af dette system: En bruger WordNet synsets som begreber, og en bruger leksikalske poster (oversættelser) som begreber. Med en tærskel på 0 er sidstnævnte konfiguration den anden blandt deltagersystemer med hensyn til F1 score. Vi beskriver også yderligere evalueringseksperimenter på Apertium data, en sammenligning med en tidligere tilgang baseret på integrering projektion, og en tilgang til begrænset projektion, der med stor margin overgår TIAD-2020 vaniljesystemet.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir opisuje naš doprinos Trećem zajedničkom zadatku o infekciji prevoda u svim riječima (TIAD-2020). Opišemo pristup infekciji prevoda na temelju simboličkih metoda, proširenje koncepta na grafiku međupovezanih riječi: S obzirom na mapiranje iz izvornog jezika riječi na leksičke koncepte (npr. sinsete) kao semen, koristimo dvije jezičke riječi kako bi ekstrapolirali mapiranje pivotova i ciljnih jezičkih riječi na te leksičke koncepte. Zatim se infekcija prevoda provodi gledanjem leksičkog koncepta riječi izvornog jezika i vraćanjem ciljne jezičke riječi(e) za koje ovi leksički koncepti imaju najviši rezultat. Predstavljamo dvije instancije ovog sustava: jedan koristi WordNet sinkronizaciju kao koncept, a jedan koristi leksičke ulaze (prevode) kao koncept. Sa praškom od 0, posljednja konfiguracija je druga među sustavima učesnika u smislu rezultata F1. Također opisujemo dodatne eksperimente za procjenu podataka o Apertiumu, usporedbu s ranijim pristupom na osnovu ugrađenja projekcije i pristup ograničenim projekcijama koji iznosi sustav vanile TIAD-2020 velikom marginom.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag beschreibt unseren Beitrag zur dritten gemeinsamen Aufgabe zur Translation Inference across Dictionaries (TIAD-2020). Wir beschreiben einen Ansatz zur Translation Inference basierend auf symbolischen Methoden, die Verbreitung von Konzepten über einen Graphen miteinander verbundener Wörterbücher: Angesichts einer Zuordnung von quellsprachlichen Wörtern zu lexikalischen Konzepten (z.B. Synsets) als Seed verwenden wir zweisprachige Wörterbücher, um eine Zuordnung von Pivot- und Zielsprachenwörtern auf diese lexikalischen Konzepte zu extrapolieren. Die Translation Inference wird dann durchgeführt, indem die lexikalischen Konzepte eines Ausgangssprachenwortes gesucht und die Zielsprachenworte zurückgegeben werden, für die diese lexikalischen Konzepte die jeweils höchste Punktzahl aufweisen. Wir stellen zwei Instanzen dieses Systems vor: Eine, die WordNet-Synsets als Konzepte verwendet, und eine, die lexikalische Einträge (Übersetzungen) als Konzepte verwendet. Mit einem Schwellenwert von 0 ist letztere Konfiguration die zweite unter den Teilnehmersystemen in Bezug auf F1-Score. Wir beschreiben auch zusätzliche Evaluationsexperimente mit Apertium-Daten, einen Vergleich mit einem früheren Ansatz basierend auf Einbettungsprojektion und einen Ansatz für eingeschränkte Projektion, der das TIAD-2020 Vanille-System um einen großen Teil übertrifft.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini menjelaskan kontribusi kita ke Tugas Tertiga Berkongsi tentang Translation Inference across Dictionaries (TIAD-2020). Kami menggambarkan pendekatan pada inferensi terjemahan berdasarkan metode simbolik, propagasi konsep melalui grafik kamus terhubung: Mengingat peta dari kata bahasa sumber ke konsep lexik (contohnya, sinset) sebagai benih, kami menggunakan kamus dua bahasa untuk ekstrapolasi peta dari kata pivot dan kata bahasa sasaran ke konsep lexik ini. Kesimpulan terjemahan kemudian dilakukan dengan mencari konsep-konsep lexik dari kata bahasa sumber dan mengembalikan kata-kata bahasa sasaran yang konsep-konsep lexik ini memiliki skor tertinggi. We present two instantiations of this system: One using WordNet synsets as concepts, and one using lexical entries (translations) as concepts.  Dengan batas 0, konfigurasi terakhir adalah kedua di antara sistem peserta dalam terma skor F1. Kami juga menjelaskan eksperimen evaluasi tambahan pada data Apertium, perbandingan dengan pendekatan sebelumnya berdasarkan proyeksi penyampaian, dan pendekatan untuk proyeksi terbatas yang melebihi sistem vanila TIAD-2020 dengan margin besar.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 세 번째 크로스 사전 번역 추리 공유 임무(TIAD-2020)에 대한 우리의 공헌을 묘사한다.우리는 기호 방법을 바탕으로 하는 번역 추리 방법, 즉 개념이 서로 관련된 사전도에서 전파되는 것을 묘사했다. 주어진 언어의 단어에서 어휘 개념(예를 들어 문법집)에 대한 비추는 것을 씨앗으로 하고 우리는 이중 언어 사전을 이용하여 추축과 목표 언어의 단어가 이런 어휘 개념에 비추는 것을 추정한다.그리고 원시 언어 단어의 어휘 개념을 찾아 이 어휘 개념들이 가장 높은 점수를 받은 목표 언어 단어를 되돌려 번역 추리를 한다.우리는 이 시스템의 두 가지 실례를 제시했다. 하나는 워드넷 문법집을 개념으로 하고, 다른 하나는 어휘 항목 (번역) 을 개념으로 한다.F1 성적에서 다음 구성의 한도값은 0으로 참여자 시스템에서 2위를 차지했다.우리는 또한 광맹 데이터에 대한 추가 평가 실험, 초기에 끼워 넣은 투영을 바탕으로 하는 방법과 비교, TIAD-2020 바닐라 시스템보다 어느 정도 우수한 구속 투영 방법을 묘사했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ توصیف دسترسی ما به کار سوم مشترک در مورد تغییرات ترجمه در سراسر گفتگوها (TIAD-2020) توصیف می‌کند. ما روش ترجمه‌ای را بر اساس روش‌های سیم‌بولیک توصیف می‌کنیم، گسترش مفهوم‌ها بر اساس یک گراف از لغوی‌های متصل: با توجه به نقشه‌بندی از کلمات منبع به عنوان مفهوم‌های زبان‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گونه‌گو سپس آلودگی ترجمه با نگاه کردن مفهوم(ها) زبان منبع و بازگرداندن کلمه(ها) زبان(ها) را که این مفهوم‌های زبان‌شناسی بالاترین امتیاز دارند انجام می‌شود. ما دو مرحله از این سیستم را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم: یکی از استفاده از WordNet به عنوان تفسیر، و یکی از ورودهای زبانی (ترجمه) به عنوان تفسیر استفاده می‌کند. با یک سطح 0، پیکربندی آخرین دوم بین سیستم‌های شرکتگر به عنوان امتیاز F1 است. ما همچنین آزمایشات ارزیابی اضافی در داده‌های آپرتیوم را توصیف می‌کنیم، مقایسه با یک روش پیشینه بر اساس پیکربندی، و یک روش برای پروژه‌های محدودیت که سیستم وینیل TIAD-2020 را با یک مرز بزرگ بالاتر می‌کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Gazeti hili linaelezea mchango wetu wa Tatu wa Kushirikiana na Tatu kuhusu Kungiliwa na Tafsiri katika Dictionari (TIAD-2020). Tunaelezea mbinu za kutokana na maambukizi ya kutafsiri kwa msingi wa njia za alama, kutangaza dhana juu ya picha ya lugha zinazohusiana na lugha: Kutokana na ramani kutoka kwenye maneno ya asili ya lugha hadi dhana za lexico (kwa mfano, synseti) kama seed, tunatumia dictionari wa lugha mbili ili kutengeneza ramani ya maneno ya pivot na malengo ya lugha kwa dhana hizi za lexico. Ugonjwa wa utafsiri unafanyika kwa kuangalia dhana(s) za kisaikolojia ya neno la lugha na kurejesha neno(s) la lugha inayolenga lengo ambalo dhana hizi za lexico zina heshima kubwa. Tunaweza kutoa matukio mawili ya mfumo huu: Mmoja kwa kutumia mtandao wa WordNet huunga mkono kama dhana, na moja kwa kutumia maandishi ya lexico (tafsiri) kama dhana. Kwa kutumia alama ya 0, configuration ya pili ni ya pili kati ya mfumo wa washiriki kwa ajili ya score za F1. Tunaweza pia kuelezea majaribio mengine ya uchimbaji wa taarifa za Apertium, ukilinganishwa na mbinu za awali zinazotokana na mradi wa kutengeneza, na mbinu za miradi inayolazimika kufanya mfumo wa upotovu wa TIAD-2020 kwa kiwango kikubwa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz sözlükleriň arasynda terjime etmek üçin üçünji paýlaşan zadymyzy (TIAD-2020) bardyr. Biz simbolik metodlara daýan ýan terjime çykyşynyň bir golaýyny, olaryň jümeleri golaýlaşyk tekizlikleriň grafynda g örkezilýän ýagdaýyny tassyýaryp görýäris: Mens dilinden golaý sözlerinden leksiýaly düşünjümlere (meseläpli, synset) taryha görä, biz pivot we maksady dil sözleriniň mapperini bu leksiýa düşünjümlere golaýlaşyk Şimdi terjime edilen hat larynyň bir çeşme diliniň(ler) s özlerini gözlemek we şu mekdebe sözleriniň(ler) sözleriniň iň yükselen sanlarynda gaýd etmek üçin bellenilýär. Biz bu sistemiň iki görnüşleri görkeýäris: WordNet'i düşünjüňe görkezýän birisi, we birisi leksiýal girişi (terjime) düşünjüňe görkezýän. 0-iň süýtgesi bilen, soňky düzümler F1 अंश (अंश) bilen iştirakçi sistemalaryň ikinjisi bolar. Biz hem Apertium maglumaty üzerinde esasy deňlemek deneylerini tassykladyrys. Iňki tassyklama ýagdaýynda daýan edilen öňki tassyklama ýagdaýynda we TIAD-2020 vanilla sistemini büyük gabdalyk bilen üstüne çykýan ýagdaýynda.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument përshkruan kontributin tonë në Detyrën e Tretë të Përbashkët mbi Inferencën e Përkthimit nëpërmjet fjalorëve (TIAD-2020). Ne përshkruajmë një qasje mbi përfundimin e përkthimit bazuar në metodat simbolike, përhapjen e koncepteve mbi një grafik të fjalorëve të ndërlidhur: Duke pasur parasysh një hartim nga fjalët e gjuhës origjinale deri në konceptet lexike (për shembull sinset) si një farë, ne përdorim fjalorët dy-gjuhës për të ekstrapoliuar një hartim të fjalëve të gjuhës së drejtuar dhe të fjalëve të drejtueshme në këto koncepte lexike. Përfundimi i përkthimit bëhet pastaj duke kërkuar konceptin(t) lexik(ë) të një fjale gjuhë burimi dhe duke kthyer fjalën(t) e gjuhës objektive për të cilën këto koncepte lexike kanë rezultatin më të lartë respektivisht. Ne paraqesim dy instanca të këtij sistemi: një duke përdorur sintezat WordNet si koncepte, dhe një duke përdorur entrata lexike (përkthime) si koncepte. With a threshold of 0, the latter configuration is the second among participant systems in terms of F1 score.  Ne përshkruajmë gjithashtu eksperimente shtesë vlerësimi mbi të dhënat e Apertiumit, një krahasim me një qasje më të hershme bazuar në përfshirjen e projektave dhe një qasje për projektave të kufizuara që tejkalon sistemin e vanilës TIAD-2020 me një margin të madh.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>ይህ ፕሮግራም በሦስተኛው የተካፈሉት ስራችን በአካላት አካባቢዎች ላይ መግለጫ (TIAD-2020) ይናገራል፡፡ የአፍሪካ ቋንቋ ቃላት ከቋንቋ ቃላት ወደ ሌክሲካዊ ቃላት (ለምሳሌ Synsets) በመጠቀም፣ የሁለት ቋንቋዎች መዝገብ እናስቀምጣለን፡፡ ትርጓሜ በኋላም የደረጃ ቋንቋ ቃላትን በመመለስ እና የደረጃ ቋንቋ ቃላትን (s) በመመለስ ይደረጋል፡፡ ይህንን ስርዓት ሁለት ሁኔታ ያሳየናል፤ አንዱ የWordNet ሲናሴቶችን እንደሚጠቀም አንዱም የልኬክሲካዊ ግንኙነቶችን (ትርጓሜዎችን) እንደሚጠቀም ነው፡፡ የ0 መድረክ፣ የመጨረሻይቱ ምርጫዎች F1 score በመስመር ውስጥ ሁለተኛ ነው፡፡ በአፍሪትዮም ዳታዎች ላይ የተጨማሪን የአፍሪትዮን ድምፅ እናሳውቃለን፤ በተቀድሞው ፕሮጀክት ላይ የተደረገውን እና የTIAD-2020 የንዋናውን ስርዓት በሚያሳየው ግንኙነት እና ትልቅ ስርዓት ላይ የተደረገውን ግንኙነት እናሳውቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier beskrywe ons bydraai tot die Trede Gedeelde Opdrag op Vertaling Inferensie oor woordeboeke (TIAD-2020). Ons beskryf 'n toegang op vertaling inferensie gebaseer op simboliese metodes, die propagasie van koncepte oor 'n graf van interkonnekteerde woordeboeke: Gien 'n kaart van bron taal woorde na leksiese konsepte (bv. sinstel) as 'n saad, gebruik ons twee tale woordeboeke om 'n kaart van pivot en doel taal woorde te ekstrapolieer na hierdie leksiese konsepte. Vertaling inferensie is dan uitgevoer deur die leksiese konsepte( s) van 'n bron taal woord te soek en die doel taal woord( s) terugkeer waarvoor hierdie leksiese konsepte die respektief hoogste telling het. Ons stel twee instansies van hierdie stelsel voor: een wat WordNet gebruik, sinkroniseer as konsepte, en een wat leksiese inskrywings (vertalings) gebruik as konsepte. Met 'n drukklok van 0, die laaste opstelling is die tweede onder deelnaders stelsels in terms van F1 telling. Ons beskrywe ook addisionele evalueringseksperimente op Apertium data, 'n vergelyking met 'n vroeër toegang gebaseer op inbêer projeksie en 'n toegang vir beheinde projeksie wat die TIAD-2020 vanilla stelsel deur 'n groot grens uitvoer.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Այս հոդվածը նկարագրում է մեր ներդրումը բառարանների միջև թարգմանվող ներդրումների երրորդ հանձնարարության վրա (TIAD 2020). Մենք նկարագրում ենք թարգմանման եզրակացության մոտեցումը, որը հիմնված է սիմվոլիկ մեթոդների վրա, գաղափարների տարածումը փոխկապակցված բառարանների գրաֆիկի վրա: Հաշվի առնելով քարտեզագրությունը աղբյուր լեզվի բառերից մինչև լեքսիկական գաղափարներ (օրինակ սինսետները) որպես սերմ, մենք օգտագործում ենք երկլեզու բառարաններ Translation inference is then performed by looking up the lexical concept(s) of a source language word and returning the target language word(s) for which these lexical concepts have the respective highest score.  Մենք ներկայացնում ենք այս համակարգի երկու անգամ. մեկը WordNet-ի սինսետները օգտագործում է որպես գաղափարներ, իսկ մյուսը՝ լեքսիկական գրքերը (թարգմանությունները) որպես գաղափարներ: Երկրորդ կառուցվածքն է մասնակիցների համակարգերի երկրորդը F1 գնահատման առումով: Մենք նաև նկարագրում ենք ավելին գնահատման փորձեր Ապերցիումի տվյալների վրա, համեմատություն նախկին մոտեցումների հետ, որը հիմնված է պրոեկցիայի ներառման վրա, և սահմանափակ պրոեկցիայի մոտեցում, որը շատ ավելի մեծ արժեքով է արտադրում TIAD 2020 վանիլա</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt Sözlüklərin Üçüncü Bölünən Tərcümə Bölünməsi barəsindəki Tərcümə Bölünməsini (TIAD-2020) yazır. Biz simbolik yollarına dayanan tərcüm infeksiyonu, bağlantılı sözlərin grafından nəzərlərin propagasyonunu təsdiqləyirik: mənbə dilindən leksik sözlərinə xəritə vermək üçün, bu leksik nəzərlərinə pivot və məqsəd dillərin xəritəsini əlavə etmək üçün iki dil sözlərini istifadə edirik. Tərcümə infeksiyonu mənbə dilinin leksik nəzəriyyətini gözləyir və bu leksik nəzəriyyətlərinin ən yüksək nöqtəsinə sahib olduğu məqsəd dillərin s özünü geri qaytarar. Biz bu sistemin iki başlanğıcını göstəririk: WordNet sinkronizasisini konsept kimi istifadə edən birisi, bir də leksik girişi (tercümələri) konsept kimi istifadə edir. 0-nın sütunu ilə, son qurğulama F1 nöqtəsi ilə iştirakçi sistemlərinin ikinci dəfəsidir. Biz də Apertium verilənlərinin əlavə değerlendirmə təcrübələrini, əvvəlki təcrübələrini inkişaf etməyə dayanan bir metodların və TIAD-2020 vanilla sistemini böyük bir tərəfdən üstün edəcək müəyyən edilmiş projeksiyonun metodlarını təsbit edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটি আমাদের তৃতীয় শেয়ার করা কাজের অবদান ব্যাখ্যা করেছে সারা ভাষায় অনুবাদ প্রবেশের ব্যাপারে (TIAD-2020)। আমরা ভিত্তিক পদ্ধতির উপর ভিত্তিক ভাবে অনুবাদের অসংস্থার ব্যাপারে একটি উপায় বর্ণনা করি: সূত্র ভাষা থেকে লেক্সিক্সিক্যাল ধারণা থেকে মানচিত্র (যেমন সিনেট) বৃষ্টি হিসেবে আমরা দুই ভাষার অভিভাবক ব্যবহার করি প সোর্স ভাষার শব্দের দিকে লেক্সিকাল ধারণা (গুলো) দেখে অনুবাদ করা হয় এবং টার্গেট ভাষার শব্দ ফিরিয়ে দেয়ার মাধ্যমে এই লেক্সিকাল ধারণাগুলো সর্ব আমরা এই সিস্টেমের দুই উদ্দেশ্য উপস্থাপন করছি: একটি ওয়ার্ডনেট সিনেটকে ধারণা হিসেবে ব্যবহার করে এবং একটি লেক্সিক্যাল এন্ট্রিস (অনুবাদ শেষ কনফিগারেশন F1 স্কোরের মাধ্যমে অংশগ্রহণকারী সিস্টেমের মধ্যে দ্বিতীয়। আমরা এপার্টিয়াম তথ্যের উপর আরো মূল্য পরীক্ষার পরীক্ষা বর্ণনা করি, প্রকল্পের উপর ভিত্তিতে একটি প্রাথমিক উপায় এবং বিশাল মার্গিন দ্বারা টিআইএড-২০২০০ ভ্যানিল্যালা</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir opisuje naš doprinos Trećem zajedničkom zadatku o infekciji prevoda u raznim dijelovima (TIAD-2020). Opišemo pristup infekciji prevoda baziran na simboličkim metodama, proširenje koncepta preko grafika međupovezanih riječi: S obzirom na mapiranje iz riječi izvornog jezika na leksičke koncepte (npr. sinteze) kao semen, koristimo dvojezičke riječi kako bi ekstrapolirali mapiranje pivotova i ciljnih jezičkih riječi na ove leksičke koncepte. Inferencija prevoda se onda provodi tražeći leksički koncept riječi izvornog jezika i vratiti ciljnu jezičku riječ(e) za koju ovi leksički koncept imaju najviši rezultat. Predstavljamo dvije instancije ovog sistema: jedan korištenje WordNet sinkronizacije kao koncept, a jedan korištenje leksičkih ulaza (prevoda) kao koncept. Sa praškom od 0, poslednja konfiguracija je druga među sustavima učesnika u smislu rezultata F1. Također opisujemo dodatne eksperimente za procjenu podataka o Apertiumu, usporedbu sa ranijim pristupom baziranim na ugrađenju projekcije, i pristup ograničenim projekcijama koji nadmaže sistem vanile TIAD-2020 sa velikom marginom.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest paper descriu la nostra contribució a la Tercera tasca compartida sobre la transferència de traducció entre diccionaris (TIAD-2020). Descrevem un enfocament sobre la inferència de traducció basat en mètodes simbòlics, la propagació de conceptes sobre un gràfic de diccionaris interconnectats: Dant un mapatge des de les paraules del llenguatge de fonts fins als conceptes lexics (per exemple, sinsets) com a semilla, utilitzem diccionaris bilingües per extrapolar un mapatge de paraules del llenguatge pivot i del llenguatge alvo a aquests conceptes lexics. La inferència de traducció s'efectua buscant el concepte(s) lèxic(s) d'una paraula de llenguatge de font i retornant la(s) paraula(s) del llenguatge d'alvo per la qual aquests conceptes lèxics tenen la puntuació més alta respectiva. Presentam dues instancies d'aquest sistema: Una utilitzant WordNet sinsets com conceptes, i una utilitzant entrades lècsiques (traduccions) com conceptes. Amb un umbre de 0, aquesta última configuració és la segona entre els sistemes participants en termes de puntuació F1. També descrivim experiments adicionals d'evaluació sobre les dades d'Apertium, una comparació amb un enfocament anterior basat en incorporar projeccions, i un enfocament per projeccions restringides que supera el sistema de vanilla TIAD-2020 en gran marge.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek popisuje náš příspěvek k třetímu sdílenému úkolu o překladatelské inferenci napříč slovníky (TIAD-2020). Popisujeme přístup k překladové inferenci založený na symbolických metodách, šíření pojmů na grafu propojených slovníků: Vzhledem k mapování slov zdrojového jazyka k lexikálním pojmům (např. synsetům) jako semenu, používáme dvojjazyčné slovníky k extrapolaci mapování slov pivot a cílového jazyka na tyto lexikální pojmy. Překladová inference se pak provádí vyhledáním lexikálních konceptů slova zdrojového jazyka a vrácením slova v cílovém jazyce, pro které mají tyto lexikální koncepty příslušně nejvyšší skóre. Představujeme dvě instancie tohoto systému: jednu používající WordNet synsety jako koncepty a druhou používající lexikální položky (překlady) jako koncepty. S prahem 0 je druhá konfigurace mezi účastníky systémů z hlediska F1 skóre druhá. Dále popisujeme další hodnotící experimenty na Apertiových datech, srovnání se starším přístupem založeným na embeddingové projekci a přístup pro omezenou projekci, který výrazně předčí vanilkový systém TIAD-2020.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas dokumendis kirjeldatakse meie panust kolmandasse ühisesse ülesandesse tõlke järelduste kohta sõnaraamatutes (TIAD-2020). Kirjeldame sümboolsetel meetoditel põhinevat lähenemisviisi tõlke järeldusele, kontseptsioonide levitamisele omavahel seotud sõnaraamatute graafikul: Lähtekeelsetest sõnadest leksikaalsetele mõistetele (nt sünkroonidele) kui seemne, kasutame kahekeelseid sõnaraamatuid, et ekstrapoleerida pöörde- ja sihtkeelsete sõnade kaardistamine nendele leksikaalsetele mõistetele. Seejärel tehakse tõlke järeldus, otsides üles lähtekeelse sõna leksikaalsed kontseptsioonid ja tagastades sihtkeelsed sõnad, mille jaoks need leksikaalsed kontseptsioonid on vastavalt kõrgeima skoori saanud. Esitleme selle süsteemi kaks instantiatsiooni: üks kasutab WordNeti sündmustena kontseptsioonidena ja teine kasutab leksikalkirjeid (tõlkeid) kontseptsioonidena. Künnisega 0 on viimane konfiguratsioon F1 skoori poolest teine osalejate süsteemide seas. Samuti kirjeldame täiendavaid hindamiskatseid Apertiumi andmetega, võrdlust varasema lähenemisviisiga, mis põhineb manustamisprojektsioonil, ja piiratud prognoosi lähenemisviisi, mis ületab TIAD-2020 vaniljesüsteemi suure marginaali.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa kuvataan osuuttamme käännösten tulkintaa eri sanakirjoissa koskevaan kolmanteen yhteiseen tehtävään (TIAD-2020). Kuvaamme symbolisiin menetelmiin perustuvaa käännöksen päättelyä, käsitteiden leviämistä toisiinsa kytkeytyvien sanakirjojen graafilla: Lähtökielen sanoista lexikaalisiin käsitteisiin (esim. synsetit) kartoitetaan siemenenä kaksikielisiä sanakirjoja ekstrapoloidaksemme pivot- ja kohdekielen sanojen kartoituksen näihin lexikaalisiin käsitteisiin. Käännöksen päättely suoritetaan etsimällä lähdekielen sanan lexikaalisia käsitteitä ja palauttamalla kohdekielen sana(t), jolle näillä lexikaalisilla käsitteillä on korkein pistemäärä. Esitämme kaksi instantiaatiota tästä järjestelmästä: toisessa käytetään WordNet-synsetejä käsitteinä ja toisessa käytetään sanastomerkintöjä (käännöksiä) käsitteinä. Kun kynnysarvo on 0, jälkimmäinen kokoonpano on toinen osallistujajärjestelmistä F1-pisteiden osalta. Kuvailemme myös Apertium-aineiston lisäarviointikokeiluja, vertailua aikaisempaan upotusprojektioon perustuvaan lähestymistapaan sekä rajoitetun projektion lähestymistapaa, joka ylittää TIAD-2020 vaniljajärjestelmän suurella marginaalilla.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_he>העיתון הזה מתאר את התרומה שלנו למשימה השלישית המשותפת על פרסומת התרגום בין המילונים (TIAD-2020). אנחנו מתארים גישה על תוצאות התרגום מבוססת על שיטות סימפוליות, ההפיצה של הרעיונות מעל גרף של מילונים מקושרים: בהתחשב במפה ממילות שפת מקור למחשבות לקסיקליות (למשל סינסטים) כזרע, אנו משתמשים במילונים שתיים לשונות כדי להוציא מפה של מילים פיוט ושפת המטרה למחשבות הלקסיקליים הללו. המסקנה של התרגום מתבצעת על ידי חיפוש על הרעיון(ים) הלקסי של מילת שפת מקור ושוב את המילה(ים) של שפת המטרה אנחנו מציגים שני תקופות של המערכת הזאת: אחת משתמשת בסינסטים WordNet כמחשבות, ואחת משתמשת בכתבות לקסיות (תרגומות) כמחשבות. עם גבול של 0, הגדרה האחרונה היא השנייה בין מערכות משתתפות במונחים של נקודת F1. We also describe additional evaluation experiments on Apertium data, a comparison with an earlier approach based on embedding projection, and an approach for constrained projection that outperforms the TIAD-2020 vanilla system by a large margin.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Perintah iki dadi tanggal nggawe Ndoleh kanggo Kemerdekaan tanggal 3 Awak dhéwé énglemi pancening nggunaké tarjamahan karo perangkat simbolbar, nggawe geranggunaké conectasi karo kelakoran nggawe barang kelakon Terjamahan Awak dhéwé éntuk durung kelas karo sistem iki: Siji alam nggambar word net seneng nggawe barang kelas, lan saben nggambar kelas nggo nggambar luwih (terjamahan) nganggep sistem. Metweke granang 0, sampek langgar sampek ing sekondiki ning acara sistem sing perusahaan liyo F1 Awakdhéwé éntuk pisan pancening nggawe Perintah dodekan karo Apertium data, nggawe geraraning mèh karo diangkat sing sabanjuré nggawe gerarané perusahaan winih nggawe gerarané kaya nggawe gerarané perusahaan kanggo ngilanggar nggawe sistem TIED-2020 durung langgar banjuré.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་ང་ཚོའི་གོ་སྐབས་འདི་ཕན་ཚེར་བརྗོད་ཆེན་པོ་དང་མཉམ་སྦྲེལ་བའི་བྱ་ཚིག་ལ་འགྲེལ་བཤད་ནི། (TIAD-2020) ང་ཚོས་མཚོན་རྟགས་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་སྔོན་ལྗོངས་དང་སྦྲེལ་བའི་འཇུག་སྣོད་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་གཏོང་གི་ཐོག་ཁྲམ། Translation inference is then performed by looking up the lexical concept(s) of a source language and returning the target language(s) for which these lexical concepts have the highest score. It is the same as in English. We present two instantiations of this system: One using WordNet synsets as concepts, and one using lexical entries (translations) as concepts. 0 ཡི་གྲངས་ཚད་དང་མཐའ་མ་དུ། རྗེས་མའི་སྒྲིག་སྟངས་འདི་F1 རིམ་པ་ལྟར་ཞུགས་སྤྱོད་པའི་མ་ལག་གི་གཉིས་པ་རེད། ང་ཚོས་Apertium ཡིག་ཆ་གསལ་གྱིས་བཟུང་བའི་གཟུགས་བརྙན་ལས་གཞན་ཞིག་བྲིས་བ་ཡིན་ན། དེ་ལྟ་བུའི་གཟུགས་བརྙན་ཞིག</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_sk>Ta prispevek opisuje naš prispevek k tretji skupni nalogi o sklepanju prevodov v slovarjih (TIAD-2020). Opisujemo pristop k sklepanju prevodov, ki temelji na simboličnih metodah, razmnoževanju konceptov prek grafa medsebojno povezanih slovarjev: Glede na preslikavo od besed izvornega jezika do leksikalnih konceptov (npr. sinetičnih) kot seme, uporabljamo dvojezične slovarje, da ekstrapoliramo preslikavo pivotnih in ciljnih jezikovnih besed na te leksikalne koncepte. Prevajalski sklep se nato izvede z iskanjem leksikalnih konceptov besede izvornega jezika in vračanjem besed ciljnega jezika, za katere imajo ti leksikalni koncepti ustrezno najvišjo oceno. Predstavljamo dve instanciaciji tega sistema: ena uporablja WordNet sinete kot koncepte in ena uporablja leksikalne vnose (prevode) kot koncepte. S pragom 0 je slednja konfiguracija druga med sodelujočimi sistemi glede na rezultat F1. Opisujemo tudi dodatne evalvacijske poskuse na podatkih Apertium, primerjavo s prejšnjim pristopom, ki temelji na vdelani projekciji, in pristop za omejeno projekcijo, ki za veliko maržo presega vanilijev sistem TIAD-2020.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>@ action: inmenu Tuna bayyana wani hanyo a kan fassarar kasar fassarci, a kan hanyoyin ayukan ayuka da aka yi bayani ga wani grafi na haɗi da dictionaries: Gida wani ramani daga harshen kwance zuwa kalmõmin littafi (misali, syntsettu) zuwa zura, za'a yi amfani da dictionary biyu dõmin ya ƙãra wani kartoni na magana na pivot da za'a yi amfani da wannan littafin leksisi. Tsarin tarjima da kuma a sami shi da ya dũba zato(na'urar) wa maganar harshe na kwance kuma ya kõma maganar harshe(s) da za'a yi amfani da shi. Tuna ƙayyade sau biyu na'urar wannan na'ura: ɗayan ta yi amfani da wordNet na samu'i kamar zato, da ɗayan ta yi amfani da shiryoyin ayuka na leksisi (fassarar) kamar zato. @ action: inmenu Tuna bayyana misãlai masu ƙari ga evaluation kan data na Afartium, samfani da wani hanyor farko a kan shirin da aka samar da shi, da kuma wata matsayi ga haramtar da aka lazimta ta ta sami tsarin TIAD-2020 da wani margin mai girma.</abstract_ha>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>