<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.onion">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of LREC2020 Workshop "People in language, vision and the mind" (ONION2020)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Patrizia</first><last>Paggio</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Albert</first><last>Gatt</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Roman</first><last>Klinger</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-70-2</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="d9186cde">2020.onion-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>onion-2020-lrec2020</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Analysis of Body Behaviours in Human-Human and Human-Robot Interactions</title>
      <author><first>Taiga</first><last>Mori</last></author>
      <author><first>Kristiina</first><last>Jokinen</last></author>
      <author><first>Yasuharu</first><last>Den</last></author>
      <pages>7–14</pages>
      <abstract>We conducted preliminary comparison of human-robot (HR) interaction with human-human (HH) interaction conducted in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese</a>. As the result, body gestures increased in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_factors_and_ergonomics">HR</a>, while hand and head gestures decreased in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_factors_and_ergonomics">HR</a>. Concerning <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_gestures">hand gesture</a>, they were composed of more diverse and complex forms, trajectories and functions in HH than in HR. Moreover, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English speakers</a> produced 6 times more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_gestures">hand gestures</a> than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese speakers</a> in HH. Regarding head gesture, even though there was no difference in the frequency of head gestures between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English speakers</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese speakers</a> in HH, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese speakers</a> produced slightly more nodding during the robot’s speaking than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English speakers</a> in HR. Furthermore, positions of nod were different depending on the language. Concerning <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gesture">body gesture</a>, participants produced <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gesture">body gestures</a> mostly to regulate appropriate distance with the robot in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_resources">HR</a>. Additionally, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English speakers</a> produced slightly more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_gestures">body gestures</a> than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese speakers</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="29b6f4db">2020.onion-1.2</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>mori-etal-2020-analysis</bibkey>
    <title_ar>تحليل سلوكيات الجسم في التفاعلات بين الإنسان والإنسان والروبوت</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Análise de Comportamentos Corporais em Interações Humano-Humano e Humano-Robô</title_pt>
      <title_es>Análisis de los comportamientos corporales en las interacciones humano-humano y humano-robot</title_es>
      <title_ja>ヒト-ヒトおよびヒト-ロボット相互作用における体の行動の分析</title_ja>
      <title_zh>人与人机交互中身体行为分</title_zh>
      <title_hi>मानव-मानव और मानव-रोबोट इंटरैक्शन में शारीरिक व्यवहार का विश्लेषण</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Anailís ar Iompar Coirp in Idirghníomhaíochtaí Daonna-Duine agus Daonna-Róbait</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ადამიანის-ადამიანის და ადამიანის-პრობოტის ინტერქექციების კონფიგურაციის ანალიზაცია</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Testviselkedés elemzése ember-ember és ember-robot interakciókban</title_hu>
      <title_el>Ανάλυση Συμπεριφερειών Σώματος σε Αλληλεπιδράσεις Άνθρωπου-Ανθρώπου και Άνθρωπου-Ρομπότ</title_el>
      <title_it>Analisi dei comportamenti corporei nelle interazioni uomo-uomo e uomo-robot</title_it>
      <title_lt>Kūno elgesio analizė žmogaus-žmogaus ir žmogaus-robotų sąveikose</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Analysis of Body Behaviours in Human-Human and Human-Robot Interactions</title_mk>
      <title_kk>Адам-адам және адам-робот интерфейстерінде дене қасиеттерін анализ</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Analisi perilaku badan dalam Interaksi Manusia-Manusia dan Manusia-Robot</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Analiżi tal-Imġiba tal-Korp fl-Interazzjonijiet Uman-Bniedem u Uman-Robot</title_mt>
      <title_ml>മനുഷ്യനും മനുഷ്യര്‍ റോബോട്ട് ഇന്റര്‍ക്ഷനുകളില്‍ ശവ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങളുടെ വിശ്വാസം</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Хүн-Хүн-Хүн-Хүн-Роботын харилцааны биеийн үйл ажиллагааны шинжилгээ</title_mn>
      <title_no>Analysering av kroppførsel i menneske-menneske og menneske-robot-interaksjonar</title_no>
      <title_pl>Analiza zachowań ciała w interakcjach człowiek-człowiek i człowiek-robot</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Analiza comportamentelor corporale în interacțiunile om-om și om-robot</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Analiza ponašanja tijela u interakciji ljudskih i ljudskih i robota</title_sr>
      <title_si>මිනිස්-මිනිස් සහ මිනිස්-රොබෝට් සම්බන්ධ විශ්ලේෂණය</title_si>
      <title_so>Analyse of Body behaviours in Human and Human-Robot Interactions</title_so>
      <title_sv>Analys av kroppsbeteenden i människa-människa och människa-robot interaktioner</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>انسان-انسان اور انسان-روبوٹ انٹراکس میں جسم کے رفتار کا تحلیل</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Phân tích hành vi cơ thể trong tương tác con người và người máy</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Анализ на поведението на тялото при взаимодействията човек-човек и човек-робот</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Analiza ponašanja tijela u interakciji ljudskih i ljudskih i ljudskih robota</title_hr>
      <title_da>Analyse af kropsadfærd i menneske-menneske og menneske-robot interaktioner</title_da>
      <title_nl>Analyse van lichaamsgedrag in mens-mens en mens-robot interacties</title_nl>
      <title_de>Analyse des Körperverhaltens in Mensch-Mensch- und Mensch-Roboter-Interaktionen</title_de>
      <title_ko>인체와 로봇의 상호작용 중의 신체 행위 분석</title_ko>
      <title_id>Analisi perilaku tubuh dalam interaksi manusia-manusia dan manusia-robot</title_id>
      <title_fa>تحلیل رفتارهای بدن در تعامل انسان-انسان و انسان-ربات</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Anachambua tabia za mwili katika mikataba ya binadamu na binadamu</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Beden davranışynyň çözümlemesi</title_tr>
      <title_af>Analiseer van Liggingsgedrag in Mens-Mens en Mens-Robot Interaksies</title_af>
      <title_sq>Analiza e sjelljeve të trupit në ndërveprimet njerëzore-njerëzore dhe njerëzore-robotë</title_sq>
      <title_am>የሰው እና የሰው-Robot Interaction</title_am>
      <title_bn>মানব মানব এবং মানব-রোবট ইন্টারনেটের বিশ্লেষণ</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Մարդու-մարդկային և մարդկային-ռոբոտի ինտերակցիաների մարմնի վարքագծի վերլուծությունը</title_hy>
      <title_az>İnsan-İnsan və İnsan-Robot Interaksiyonlarında Beden Davranışlarının analizi</title_az>
      <title_bs>Analiza ponašanja tijela u interakciji ljudskih i ljudskih i ljudskih robota</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Anàlisi del comportament corporal en les interaccions entre humans i humans i robots</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Analýza tělesného chování v interakcích člověk-člověk a člověk-robot</title_cs>
      <title_et>Kehakäitumise analüüs inimese-inimese ja inimese-roboti koostoimes</title_et>
      <title_fi>Kehon käyttäytymisen analyysi ihmisen ja ihmisen ja robotin vuorovaikutuksessa</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Tanalé ning Body Effects ning Human-Human-Jobot interaksi</title_jv>
      <title_ha>Ana Analyza of Board Opposites in Man and Man-Robot interaction</title_ha>
      <title_he>ניתוח התנהגות הגוף באינטראקציות אנושית-אנושית-רובוטית</title_he>
      <title_sk>Analiza telesnega vedenja v interakcijah človek-človek in človek-robot</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Human-Human-Robot Interactions ནང་གི་སྒེར་གྱི་འགྲོ་སྟངས་ཀྱི་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་བྱེད་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>أجرينا مقارنة أولية للتفاعل بين الإنسان الآلي (HR) والتفاعل بين الإنسان والإنسان (HH) باللغتين الإنجليزية واليابانية. ونتيجة لذلك ، زادت إيماءات الجسم في معدل ضربات القلب ، بينما انخفضت إيماءات اليد والرأس في معدل ضربات القلب. فيما يتعلق بإيماءات اليد ، فقد كانت تتألف من أشكال ومسارات ووظائف أكثر تنوعًا وتعقيدًا في HH منها في الموارد البشرية. علاوة على ذلك ، أنتج المتحدثون باللغة الإنجليزية 6 مرات إيماءات يدوية أكثر من المتحدثين اليابانيين في HH. فيما يتعلق بإيماءات الرأس ، على الرغم من عدم وجود اختلاف في تواتر إيماءات الرأس بين المتحدثين باللغة الإنجليزية والمتحدثين اليابانيين في HH ، أنتج المتحدثون اليابانيون إيماءات أكثر قليلاً أثناء تحدث الروبوت عن المتحدثين باللغة الإنجليزية في الموارد البشرية. علاوة على ذلك ، كانت مواقف الإيماءة مختلفة حسب اللغة. فيما يتعلق بإيماءات الجسد ، أنتج المشاركون إيماءات جسدية في الغالب لتنظيم المسافة المناسبة مع الروبوت في الموارد البشرية. بالإضافة إلى ذلك ، أنتج المتحدثون باللغة الإنجليزية إيماءات جسدية أكثر قليلاً من المتحدثين اليابانيين.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Se realizó una comparación preliminar de la interacción humano-robot (HR) con la interacción humano-humano (HH) realizada en inglés y en japonés. Como resultado, los gestos corporales aumentaron en la FC, mientras que los gestos de manos y cabeza disminuyeron en la FC. En cuanto a los gestos con las manos, se componían de formas, trayectorias y funciones más diversas y complejas en HH que en HR. Además, los angloparlantes produjeron 6 veces más gestos con las manos que los japoneses en HH. En cuanto a los gestos con la cabeza, aunque no hubo diferencia en la frecuencia de los gestos con la cabeza entre los angloparlantes y los hablantes de japonés en HH, los hablantes de japonés produjeron un poco más de asentimiento durante la conversación del robot que los angloparlantes en HR Además, las posiciones de asentimiento eran diferentes según el idioma. En cuanto a los gestos corporales, los participantes produjeron gestos corporales principalmente para regular la distancia adecuada con el robot en HR. Además, los angloparlantes produjeron un poco más de gestos corporales que los japoneses.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Realizamos uma comparação preliminar da interação humano-robô (HR) com a interação humano-humano (HH) realizada em inglês e em japonês. Como resultado, os gestos corporais aumentaram na FC, enquanto os gestos de mão e cabeça diminuíram na FC. Quanto aos gestos com as mãos, eles eram compostos de formas, trajetórias e funções mais diversas e complexas em HH do que em HR. Além disso, os falantes de inglês produziram 6 vezes mais gestos com as mãos do que os falantes de japonês em HH. Em relação ao gesto de cabeça, embora não tenha havido diferença na frequência de gestos de cabeça entre falantes de inglês e falantes de japonês em HH, falantes de japonês produziram um pouco mais de aceno de cabeça durante a fala do robô do que falantes de inglês em HR. Além disso, as posições de aceno foram diferentes dependendo do idioma. Em relação ao gesto corporal, os participantes produziram gestos corporais principalmente para regular a distância adequada com o robô na FC. Além disso, os falantes de inglês produziram um pouco mais de gestos corporais do que os falantes de japonês.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>英語と日本語で実施したヒト-ロボット（ HR ）相互作用とヒト-ヒト（ HH ）相互作用の予備比較を実施した。その結果、体のジェスチャーはHRで増加し、手と頭のジェスチャーはHRで減少しました。手のジェスチャーに関しては、HHではHRよりも多様で複雑な形態、軌道、機能で構成されていました。さらに、英語話者はHHでは日本語話者の6倍の手のジェスチャーを生成しました。頭のジェスチャーについては、HHでは英語話者と日本語話者の間で頭のジェスチャーの頻度に差はなかったものの、日本語話者はロボットの話す間に、HRでは英語話者よりも少しうなずくことが多かった。さらに、頷く位置は言語によって異なっていた。身体のジェスチャーに関しては、参加者は主に人事部門のロボットとの適切な距離を調整するために身体のジェスチャーを作成しました。さらに、英語話者は日本語話者よりもわずかに身体のジェスチャーを作成しました。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>以英语与日语对人机(HR)交与人(HH)相较也。 故身势加于心率,而手头减于心率,其于HH,多样化于HR,迹成于功。 此外,HH之中,言英语者手势倍日语6。 头势者,虽在HH中,英语使用者与日语使用者头手势频率无异,然日语使用者在机器人言之间,较HR中英语使用者更多点头。 此外点头位因语而异。 夫身之姿势,参与者生之大体,所以调HR中机器人之适也,又言英语者较日语者之生体势略多。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हमने अंग्रेजी और जापानी में आयोजित मानव-मानव (एचएच) इंटरैक्शन के साथ मानव-रोबोट (एचआर) इंटरैक्शन की प्रारंभिक तुलना की। नतीजतन, एचआर में शरीर के इशारों में वृद्धि हुई, जबकि एचआर में हाथ और सिर के इशारों में कमी आई। हाथ के इशारे के बारे में, वे एचआर की तुलना में एचएच में अधिक विविध और जटिल रूपों, प्रक्षेपवक्रों और कार्यों से बने थे। इसके अलावा, अंग्रेजी बोलने वालों ने एचएच में जापानी वक्ताओं की तुलना में 6 गुना अधिक हाथ के इशारों का उत्पादन किया। सिर के इशारे के बारे में, भले ही एचएच में अंग्रेजी बोलने वालों और जापानी वक्ताओं के बीच सिर के इशारों की आवृत्ति में कोई अंतर नहीं था, जापानी वक्ताओं ने एचआर में अंग्रेजी बोलने वालों की तुलना में रोबोट के बोलने के दौरान थोड़ा अधिक सिर हिलाया। इसके अलावा, भाषा के आधार पर नोड की स्थिति अलग-अलग थी। शरीर के इशारे के बारे में, प्रतिभागियों ने ज्यादातर मानव संसाधन में रोबोट के साथ उचित दूरी को विनियमित करने के लिए शरीर के इशारों का उत्पादन किया। इसके अतिरिक्त, अंग्रेजी बोलने वालों ने जापानी वक्ताओं की तुलना में थोड़ा अधिक शरीर के इशारों का उत्पादन किया।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Rinneamar réamhchomparáid idir idirghníomhaíocht daonna-robot (AD) le hidirghníomhaíocht daonna-daonna (HH) a rinneadh i mBéarla agus i Seapáinis. Mar thoradh air sin, mhéadaigh gothaí coirp san AD, agus laghdaigh gothaí láimhe agus cinn san AD. Maidir le gothaí láimhe, bhí foirmeacha, conairí agus feidhmeanna níos éagsúla agus níos casta i HH ná mar a bhí siad in AD. Ina theannta sin, rinne cainteoirí Béarla 6 huaire níos mó gothaí láimhe ná cainteoirí Seapánacha in HH. Maidir le gothaí cinn, cé nach raibh aon difríocht idir minicíocht na ngeotaí cloiginn idir cainteoirí Béarla agus cainteoirí Seapánacha in HH, tháirg cainteoirí Seapánacha beagán níos mó nodaireachta le linn labhairt an róbait ná mar a bhí cainteoirí Béarla in AD. Ina theannta sin, bhí suíomhanna nodaireachta difriúil ag brath ar an teanga. Maidir le gothaí coirp, tháirg rannpháirtithe gothaí coirp den chuid is mó chun achar cuí a rialú leis an róbat in Acmhainní Daonna. Ina theannta sin, rinne cainteoirí Béarla beagán níos mó gothaí coirp ná cainteoirí Seapánacha.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Előzetes összehasonlítást végeztünk az ember-robot (HR) interakciónak az ember-ember (HH) interakcióval angol és japán nyelven. Ennek eredményeképpen a testmozdulatok emelkedtek a HR-ben, míg a kéz- és fejmozdulatok csökkentek a HR-ben. A kézmozdulatokat illetően sokszínűbb és összetettebb formákból, pályákból és funkciókból álltak, mint a HR-ben. Továbbá az angolul beszélők 6-szor több kézmozdulatot készítettek, mint a japán beszélők HH-ban. Ami a fejmozdulatokat illeti, annak ellenére, hogy a fejmozdulatok gyakoriságában nem volt különbség az angol és japán beszélők között a HH-ban, a japán beszélők valamivel több bólintást okoztak a robot beszélése során, mint az angol beszélők a HR-ben. Továbbá a bólintás helyzete a nyelvtől függően eltérő volt. Ami a testmozdulatokat illeti, a résztvevők testmozdulatokat készítettek elsősorban a robot HR-ben való megfelelő távolságának szabályozására. Ezenkívül az angol beszélők kissé több testmozdulatot produkáltak, mint a japán beszélők.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Πραγματοποιήσαμε προκαταρκτική σύγκριση της αλληλεπίδρασης ανθρώπου-ρομπότ (HR) με αλληλεπίδραση ανθρώπου-ανθρώπου (HH) στα αγγλικά και στα ιαπωνικά. Ως αποτέλεσμα, οι χειρονομίες του σώματος αυξήθηκαν στο HR, ενώ οι χειρονομίες χεριού και κεφαλιού μειώθηκαν στο HR. Όσον αφορά τη χειρονομία των χεριών, αποτελούνταν από πιο ποικίλες και σύνθετες μορφές, τροχιές και λειτουργίες στην ΗΕ από ό,τι στην ΗΕ. Επιπλέον, οι αγγλόφωνοι παρήγαγαν 6-φορές περισσότερες χειρονομίες από ό,τι οι ιαπωνικοί ομιλητές στην ΗH. Όσον αφορά τη χειρονομία κεφαλής, παρόλο που δεν υπήρχε διαφορά στη συχνότητα των χειρονομίων κεφαλής μεταξύ των αγγλικόφωνων και των ιαπωνόφωνων ομιλητών στο ΗH, οι ιαπωνόφωνοι έκαναν ελαφρώς μεγαλύτερο νεύμα κατά τη διάρκεια της ομιλίας του ρομπότ από ό,τι οι αγγλικόφωνοι στο HR. Επιπλέον, οι θέσεις του νεύματος ήταν διαφορετικές ανάλογα με τη γλώσσα. Όσον αφορά τη χειρονομία σώματος, οι συμμετέχοντες παρήγαγαν χειρονομίες σώματος κυρίως για να ρυθμίσουν την κατάλληλη απόσταση με το ρομπότ στο HR. Επιπλέον, οι αγγλικοί ομιλητές παρήγαγαν ελαφρώς περισσότερες χειρονομίες σώματος από τους ιαπωνικούς ομιλητές.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ ადამიანის-პრობოტის (HR) ინტერნექციაციის (HH) ინტერნექციაციას, რომელიც ადამიანის-ადამიანის (HH) ინტერნექციაციას ინგლისურად და იაპონურად გა როგორც შედეგი, სხეულის გესტები HR-ში გაზრდა, როგორც ხელი და გესტები HR-ში გაზრდა. პირველი გესტურის შესახებ, ისინი უფრო განსხვავებული და კომპლექციური ფორმებით, ტრაექტორიები და ფუნქციები HH-ში ვიდრე HR-ში. დამატებით, ანგლისური მუშაობელი 6-ჯერ უფრო მეტი ხელის გესტი, ვიდრე იაპონური მუშაობელი HH-ში. თუმცა პრობოტის საუკეთესო საუკეთესო გესექტის განსხვავება არ იყო ინგლისური საუკეთესო საუკეთესო საუკეთესო საუკეთესო საუკეთესო საუკეთესო გესექტის განსხვავებაში დამატებით, კონდის პოზაციები განსხვავებული იყო ენაზე. სხვა გესტის გესტის შესახებ სხვა გესტის გესტის შემდეგ სხვა გესტის განმავლობა, რომელსაც პრობოტის განმავლობა HR-ში. დამატებით, ანგლისური საუკეთესები უფრო მეტი ცხოვრების გესტი, ვიდრე იაპონური საუკეთესები.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Abbiamo condotto un confronto preliminare dell'interazione uomo-robot (HR) con l'interazione uomo-umano (HH) condotto in inglese e in giapponese. Di conseguenza, i gesti del corpo sono aumentati nell'HR, mentre i gesti della mano e della testa sono diminuiti nell'HR. Per quanto riguarda il gesto della mano, erano composti da forme, traiettorie e funzioni più diverse e complesse in HH che in HR. Inoltre, gli anglofoni hanno prodotto 6 volte più gesti delle mani rispetto ai giapponesi in HH. Per quanto riguarda il gesto della testa, anche se non c'era differenza nella frequenza dei gesti della testa tra gli anglofoni e quelli giapponesi in HH, i giapponesi hanno prodotto un po' più cenni durante la conversazione del robot rispetto agli anglofoni in HR. Inoltre, le posizioni di cenno erano diverse a seconda della lingua. Per quanto riguarda il gesto del corpo, i partecipanti hanno prodotto gesti del corpo principalmente per regolare la distanza appropriata con il robot in HR. Inoltre, gli anglofoni producevano un po' più gesti corporei rispetto ai giapponesi.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Біз адам- роботтар (HR) адам- адам- адам- адам (HH) интернетациясы ағылшын және япон тілінде істеген интернетациясын алдындағы салыстырып жүрдік. Нәтижесінде, дене жұмыс HR-де көтерілген, қол мен бас жұмыс HR-де көтерілген. Қол жүйесі туралы, Олар HH-де HR-ден артық және комплекс пішімдер, траекториялар және функциялардан құрылды. Сонымен қатар, ағылшын сөйлейткілері HH-де жапон сөйлейткілерінен 6 рет көп көп жұмыс істеді. Бастапқы жұмыс туралы, HH адресінде ағылшын сөйлейтіншілер мен жапон сөйлейтіншілердің арасындағы айырмашылық болмаса да, япон сөйлейтіншілері Роботтың сөйлейтінің ағылшын сөйлейтіншілерден артық көп жазылған. Сонымен қатар, ноd орналасуы тіліне тәуелді. Қатысушылар денесінің жұмысы туралы, HR-де роботтың қашықтығын баптау үшін денесінің жұмысын жасады. Сонымен қатар ағылшын сөйлейткілері жапон сөйлейткілерінен бірнеше дене жеңіліктерін жасады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Išankstinį žmogaus ir robot ų (HR) sąveikos su žmogaus ir žmogaus (HH) sąveika palyginimą atlikome anglų ir japonų kalbomis. Dėl to HR padidėjo kūno gestai, o HR sumažėjo rankų ir galvos gestai. Kalbant apie rankinius gestus, jie buvo sudaryti iš įvairiausių ir sudėtingesnių formų, trajektorijų ir funkcijų HH srityje nei HR. Be to, anglų kalbėtojai gavo 6 kartus daugiau rankų gestų nei japonų kalbėtojai HH. Kalbant apie galvos gestą, nors anglų kalbėtojų ir japonų kalbėtojų galvos gestų dažnis HH nesiskyrė, japonų kalbėtojai roboto kalbos metu šiek tiek labiau nodavo nei anglų kalbėtojų HR. Be to, mazgų padėtis buvo skirtinga priklausomai nuo kalbos. Concerning body gesture, participants produced body gestures mostly to regulate appropriate distance with the robot in HR.  Be to, anglų kalbėtojai padarė šiek tiek daugiau kūno gestų nei japonų kalbėtojai.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Kami melakukan perbandingan awal antara interaksi manusia-robot (HR) dengan interaksi manusia-manusia (HH) dilakukan dalam bahasa Inggeris dan Jepun. Sebagai hasilnya, gerakan badan meningkat dalam HR, sementara gerakan tangan dan kepala berkurang dalam HR. Mengenai gerakan tangan, mereka terdiri dari bentuk yang lebih berbeza dan kompleks, trajektori dan fungsi dalam HH daripada HR. Selain itu, pembicara Inggeris menghasilkan 6 kali lebih banyak gerakan tangan daripada pembicara Jepun dalam HH. Mengenai gerakan kepala, walaupun tidak ada perbezaan dalam frekuensi gerakan kepala antara pembicara Inggeris dan pembicara Jepun dalam HH, pembicara Jepun menghasilkan sedikit lebih nodding semasa berbicara robot daripada pembicara Inggeris dalam HR. Lagipun, kedudukan nod berbeza bergantung pada bahasa. Mengenai gerak tubuh, peserta menghasilkan gerak tubuh kebanyakan untuk mengatur jarak yang sesuai dengan robot dalam HR. Additionally, English speakers produced slightly more body gestures than Japanese speakers.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Правивме прелиминарна споредба на интеракција човек-робот (ХР) со интеракција човек-човек (ХХ) спроведена на англиски и јапонски. Како резултат на тоа, телесните гести се зголемија во ХР, додека рачните и главните гести се намалија во ХР. Во врска со рачниот гест, тие беа составени од поразлични и комплексни форми, траектории и функции во ХХ отколку во ХХ. Покрај тоа, англиските говорници произведоа 6 пати поголеми рачни гести од јапонските говорници во ХХ. Што се однесува до гестот на главата, иако не постоеше разлика во фреквенцијата на гестот на главата помеѓу англиските и јапонските на ХХ, јапонските на ХХ произведуваа малку поголем клик за време на говорот на роботот отколку англиските на ХХ. Покрај тоа, позициите на јазикот беа различни во зависност од јазикот. Во врска со гестот на телото, учесниците произведуваа гестови на телото претежно за да регулираат соодветна дистанца со роботот во ХР. Additionally, English speakers produced slightly more body gestures than Japanese speakers.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>ഞങ്ങള്‍ ആദ്യമായി മനുഷ്യന്‍ റോബോട്ടിന്‍റെ (HR) തമ്മിലുള്ള ബന്ധപ്പെടുത്തിയിരുന്നു ഇംഗ്ലീഷിലും ജപ്പാനീസിലും നടത്തിയ മനുഷ് അതിന്റെ ഫലമായി ഹെര്‍ആരില്‍ ശരീരത്തിന്റെ ഗ്രേഡുകള്‍ വര്‍ദ്ധിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. ഹെഡും തലയുടെ ഗ്രേസ്റ്റുകളും HR-ല ഹാന്‍ഡ് ഗെസ്റ്റേഷനെക്കുറിച്ച്, അതിനെ കൂടുതല്‍ വ്യത്യസ്തമായ, കൂടുതല്‍ സങ്കീര്‍ണ്ണമായ രൂപത്തില്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയിരുന്നു,  അതുകൊണ്ടും, ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നവര്‍ ഹെഹ്ഹിലെ ജപ്പാനീസ് സംസാരികളെക്കാള്‍ 6 പ്രാവശ്യം കൈയ് ഹെയ്ഹിലെ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് സംസാരികള്‍ക്കും ജപ്പാനീസ് സംസാരികള്‍ക്കും തമ്മിലുള്ള തലസംസാരത്തിന്‍റെ വ്യത്യസ്തമായിരുന്നില്ലെങ്കിലും ജാപ്പനീസ് സ്പീക്കര്‍ക കൂടാതെ, നോഡിന്റെ സ്ഥാനങ്ങള്‍ ഭാഷയെ ആശ്രയിച്ചിരുന്നു. ശരീരത്തെക്കുറിച്ച് പങ്കാളികള്‍ ശരീരത്തിന്‍റെ ഗെസ്റ്റുകള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയിരിക്കുന്നു. ഹെര്‍ആരിലെ റോബോട്ടിന്‍റെ  കൂടാതെ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് സ്പീക്ടര്‍ ജപ്പാനീസ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നവരെക്കാള്‍ ശരീരത്തെക്കാള്‍ കുറച്ച് മാത്ര</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Vi oppførte første sammenlikning av menneskelrobot-interaksjon med menneskelmenneskelig (HH) interaksjon gjennomført på engelsk og japansk. I resultatet har kroppegestar økt i HR, mens håndgestar og hovudgestar ned i HR. I håndgestøren ble dei lagde av meir forskjellige og komplekse formar, trajektoriar og funksjonar i HH enn i HR. I tillegg lagde engelske taler 6 ganger meir håndstillingar enn japanske taler i HH. I tillegg til hovudgesturen, selv om det ikkje var noe forskjellig i frekvensen av hovudgesturen mellom engelske sprøykarar og japanske sprøykarar i HH, produserte Japanske sprøykarar litt meir noding under roboten snakker enn engelske sprøykarar i HR. I tillegg var posisjonar på nod ulike avhengig av språket. I høve til kroppegestøren, har deltakarane laga kroppegestørar for å regulere tilpassande avstanden med roboten i HR. I tillegg, engelske talerar produserte litt meir kroppe-gestar enn japanske talerar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_mt>Sar paragun preliminari ta’ interazzjoni bejn il-bniedem u r-robot (HR) ma’ interazzjoni bejn il-bniedem u l-bniedem (HH) imwettqa bl-Ingliż u bil-Ġappuniż. Bħala riżultat, il-ġesti tal-ġisem żdiedu fir-RGħ, filwaqt li l-ġesti tal-idejn u tar-ras naqsu fir-RGħ. Fir-rigward tal-ġesti tal-idejn, dawn kienu magħmula minn forom, trajettorji u funzjonijiet aktar diversifikati u kumplessi fl-HH milli fir-RGħ. Barra minn hekk, il-kelliema Ingliżi pproduċew 6 darbiet aktar ġesti bl-idejn mill-kelliema Ġappuniżi fl-HH. Fir-rigward tal-ġest tar-ras, minkejja li ma kien hemm l-ebda differenza fil-frekwenza tal-ġesti tar-ras bejn il-kelliema Ingliżi u l-kelliema Ġappuniżi fl-HH, il-kelliema Ġappuniżi pproduċew ftit aktar nodding matul il-kelliema tar-robot milli l-kelliema Ingliżi fir-HR. Barra minn hekk, il-pożizzjonijiet tan-nodi kienu differenti skont il-lingwa. Fir-rigward tal-ġesti tal-ġisem, il-parteċipanti pproduċew ġesti tal-ġisem l-aktar biex jirregolaw id-distanza xierqa mar-robot fir-RGħ. Barra minn hekk, il-kelliema Ingliżi pproduċew ftit aktar ġesti tal-ġisem mill-kelliema Ġappuniżi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Przeprowadziliśmy wstępne porównanie interakcji człowiek-robot (HR) z interakcją człowiek-człowiek (HH) w języku angielskim i japońskim. W rezultacie gesty ciała zwiększyły się w HR, podczas gdy gesty dłoni i głowy zmniejszyły się w HR. Jeśli chodzi o gesty ręki, składały się one z bardziej zróżnicowanych i złożonych form, trajektorii i funkcji w HH niż w HR. Ponadto angielscy użytkownicy produkowali 6-krotnie więcej gestów dłoni niż japońscy użytkownicy w HH. Jeśli chodzi o gest głowy, mimo że nie było różnicy w częstotliwości gestów głowy między angielskimi a japońskimi mówiącymi w HH, japońscy użytkownicy produkowali nieco więcej kiwania głową podczas mówienia robota niż angielscy w HR. Ponadto pozycje kiwania były różne w zależności od języka. Jeśli chodzi o gesty ciała, uczestnicy wykonywali gesty ciała głównie w celu regulowania odpowiedniej odległości z robotem w HR. Dodatkowo, angielscy użytkownicy produkowali nieco więcej gestów ciała niż japońscy.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Am efectuat o comparație preliminară a interacțiunii om-robot (HR) cu interacțiunea om-om (HH) efectuată în limba engleză și japoneză. Ca urmare, gesturile corpului au crescut în HR, în timp ce gesturile mâinilor și capului au scăzut în HR. În ceea ce privește gestul mâinii, acestea au fost compuse din forme, traiectorii și funcții mai diverse și mai complexe în HH decât în HR. Mai mult decât atât, vorbitorii de engleză au produs de 6 ori mai multe gesturi de mână decât vorbitorii de japoneză în HH. În ceea ce privește gestul capului, deși nu a existat nicio diferență în frecvența gesturilor capului între vorbitorii de engleză și vorbitorii de japoneză în HH, vorbitorii de japoneză au produs un pic mai mult din cap în timpul vorbirii robotului decât vorbitorii de engleză în HR. Mai mult decât atât, pozițiile de cap au fost diferite în funcție de limbă. În ceea ce privește gesturile corporale, participanții au produs gesturi corporale în principal pentru a regla distanța corespunzătoare cu robotul în HR. În plus, vorbitorii de engleză au produs puțin mai multe gesturi corporale decât vorbitorii de japoneză.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mn>Бид хүн-робот (HR) хүн-хүн-хүн (HH) англи болон япон хэлний харилцааныг эхлээд харьцуулсан. Үүний үр дүнд биеийн хөдөлгөөн HR-д нэмэгдсэн ба гар, толгой хөдөлгөөн HR-д бага байлаа. Гар хөдөлгөөний тухай тэд HH-д HR-ээс илүү олон төрлийн, төвөгтэй хэлбэрээс бүрдсэн. Үүнээс гадна Англи хэлэгчид ХХ-ын Япон хэлэгчдээс 6 дахин илүү гар хөдөлгөөн бүтээсэн. ХХ-д Англи хэлэгчид болон Япон хэлэгчид хоорондын толгой хөдөлгөөний тухай өөрчлөлт байхгүй ч, Япон хэлэгчид Роботын хэлэгчид Англи хэлэгчдээс илүү бага зэрэг дуугарч байлаа. Үүнээс гадна хэл дээр хамааралтай өөр нөхцөл байдал байсан. Биеийн хөдөлгөөний тухай оролцогчдын оролцогчдын хөдөлгөөн ихэнхдээ ДР-ын роботын зайг зөвхөн зөвхөн хөдөлгөөнтэй бүтээсэн. Мөн Англи хэлэгчид Япон хэлэгчдээс бага зэрэг биеийн хөдөлгөөн бий болгосон.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sr>Provodili smo preliminarnu usporedbu interakcije ljudskih robota (HR) sa interakcijom ljudskih i ljudskih (HH) provedenom na engleskom i japanskom jeziku. Kao rezultat toga, gesti tijela su povećani u HR, dok su ruke i gesti glave smanjene u HR. Što se tiče gesta ruke, sastavljeni su od raznih i kompleksnih oblika, trajektorija i funkcija u HH nego u HR. Osim toga, engleski govornici su proizveli 6 puta više gesta od japanskih govornika u HH. Što se tiče glavnog gesta, iako nije bilo razlike u frekvenciji glavnih gesta između engleskih govornika i japanskih govornika u HH, japanski govornici su proizveli malo više klimanja tokom govora robota nego engleskih govornika u HR. Osim toga, pozicije klinka su različite ovisno o jeziku. Što se tiče gesta tijela, učesnici su proizveli geste tijela uglavnom da reguliraju odgovarajuću udaljenost sa robotom u HR. Osim toga, engleski govornici su proizveli malo više gesta tijela nego japanski govornici.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අපි මිනිස්සු රොබෝට් (HR) සම්බන්ධයෙන් මිනිස්-මිනිස් (HH) සම්බන්ධයෙන් ඉංග්‍රීසි වලින් ජාපානිස් වලින් කර ඉතින්, HR වලට ශරීරය හැසිරීම් වැඩියි, අත සහ ඔළු හැසිරීම් HR වලට අඩු වෙලා තියෙනවා. අත්තර සැකසුම් ගැන, ඔවුන් HR වලට වඩා විවිදියට සහ සංවිධානය සහ සංවිධානය සඳහා සංවිධානය කරලා තියෙනවා. තවත් ඉංග්‍රීසි ස්පීකර් හයක් වැඩි අත්තර ක්‍රියාත්මක වඩා ජාපාන් ස්පීකර් වල HH වලින්. ඔළුවන්ගේ හැස්සීම් ගැන, HH වල ඉංග්‍රීසි ස්පීකර් සහ ජාපාන් ස්පීකර් වලින් ප්‍රමාණයක් නෑ නමුත් ජාපාන් ස්පීකර් වලින් රොබෝට් කතා කරප තවත්, nod ස්ථානය වෙනස් වුනා භාෂාව අවශ්‍යයෙන්. සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන් ශරීරය ගැන, සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන් ශරීරය ගැන සිද්ධ වෙනුවෙන් සිද්ධ වෙනුවෙන් විශ තවත් ඉංග්‍රීසි ස්පීකර්ට ජාපාන් ස්පීකර්ට වඩා ටිකක් වැඩි ශරීරයක් නිර්මාණය කරනවා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Vi genomförde preliminär jämförelse av människa-robot (HR) interaktion med människa-människa (HH) interaktion utförd på engelska och japanska. Till följd av detta ökade kroppsgesterna i HR, medan hand- och huvudgesterna minskade i HR. När det gäller handgester bestod de av mer mångsidiga och komplexa former, banor och funktioner i HH än i HR. Dessutom producerade engelsktalande 6 gånger fler handgester än japansktalare i HH. När det gäller huvudgester, även om det inte fanns någon skillnad i frekvensen av huvudgester mellan engelsktalande och japansktalande i HH, producerade japansktalande något mer nickande under robotens tal än engelsktalande i HR. Dessutom var positionerna för nickning olika beroende på språk. När det gäller kroppsgester producerade deltagarna kroppsgester främst för att reglera lämpligt avstånd med roboten i HR. Dessutom producerade engelsktalande något fler kroppsgester än japansktalare.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>ہم نے انسان-انسان-انسان-انسان (HH) کے مصاحبات کے مطابق انسان-روبوت (HR) کی پہلی مقایسہ کی۔ اس کے نتیجہ میں جسم کی حرکتیں HR میں زیادہ ہوتی ہیں اور ہاتھ اور سر کی حرکتیں HR میں کم ہوتی ہیں ہاتھ کی جستجو کے بارے میں وہ HR سے زیادہ مختلف اور پیچیدہ فرموں سے بنائے گئے۔ اور اس کے علاوہ، انگلیسی زبان کرنے والوں نے HH میں جاپانی زبان کرنے والوں سے 6 برابر زیادہ ہاتھ جستجو پیدا کیا۔ سر جسم کے بارے میں، اگرچہ HH میں انگلیسی صحبت کرنے والوں اور جاپانی صحبت کرنے والوں کے درمیان سر جسم کے فرکانس میں کوئی فرکانس نہیں تھا، جاپانی صحبت کرنے والوں نے HR میں روبوت کی بات میں بہت کم زیادہ ناڈینگ بنایا تھا۔ اور اس کے بعد نود کی موقعیت زبان پر متفاوت تھی۔ جسم کی جستجو کے بارے میں، مشرکین نے جسم کی جستجو اکثریت سے HR میں روبوت کے ساتھ مناسب دور کی تنظیم کرنے کے لئے پیدا کیا ہے. اور اضافہ، انگلیسی زبانداروں نے جاپانی زبانداروں سے بہت کم زیادہ جسم کی جسم پیدا کی۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_so>We conducted preliminary comparison of human-robot (HR) interaction with human-human (HH) interaction conducted in English and in Japanese.  Sababtaas darteed waxaa kordhay qalabka jidhka ee HR, iyadoo gacanta iyo madaxu ay ku yaraatay HR. Gacanta waxaa laga sameeyaa noocyo kala duduwan oo adag oo kala duduwan, wadooyin iyo shaqooyin HH ka mid ah HR. Sidoo kale luuqadaha ingiriisiga ah waxay sameeyeen lix jeer oo ka badan qofka ku hadla dadka Japoniya ee HH. Kuwii ku saabsan hadalka madaxa, xataa in kastoo aan kala duwanayn hadalka madaxa ee afka Ingiriiska iyo dadka Jabaneeska ah ee HH ku hadla, hadalka Jabaneesiinta ayaa ka shaqeeya hadalka afka ingiriiska ee robotiga ee HR. Intaas waxaa dheer, meeshooyinka nod waxay ku xiran jireen luqada. Kuwii ku saabsan qalabka jidhka, kuwa ka qeybqaaday ayaa soo saaray qalabka jidhka sida badan in lagu maamulo safar ku haboon karo roboteen ee HR. Sidoo kale luuqadaha ingiriisiga ku hadlayaasha ayaa soo saaray wax ka badan jidhka kuwa ku hadla Jabanees.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>நாங்கள் முதல் ஒப்பிட்டு மனித மனித ஒப்பீடுகளை மொழில் ஆங்கிலத்திலும் ஜப்பானிய மொழியிலும் செயல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. முடிவுக்காக, HR-ல் உடல் குறிப்புகள் அதிகரித்து, HR-ல் கையும் தலைப்பும் குறைப்புகளும் குறைகிறது. கையின் செயல்பாடுகள் பற்றி, அவர்கள் மிகவும் பல்வேறு மற்றும் சிக்கலான வடிவங்கள், தடங்குகள் மற்றும் செயல்பாடுகள் HR-ல் விட மேலும், ஆங்கிலத்தில் பேசுபவர்கள் HH-ல் ஜப்பானிய பேச்சாளர்களை விட 6 முறை கைகள் உருவாக்கினார்கள். தலைப்பு குறிப்புகள் பற்றி எனினும் HH இல் ஆங்கிலத்தில் பேசுபவர்களுக்கும் ஜப்பானிகளுக்கும் இடையே தலைப்பு குறிப்புகளின் வேறுபாடுகள் இல்லை எனினும் HR ல் ஆ மேலும், நோடின் நிலைகள் மொழியை சார்ந்து மாறுபட்டது. உடல் குறிப்பு பற்றி, பங்கீட்டாளர்கள் பெரும்பாலாக உடல் குறிப்புகளை உருவாக்கி HR ல் ரோபோட்டுடன் பொருத்தமான தூ மேலும், ஆங்கிலத்தில் பேசுபவர்கள் ஜப்பானிய பேசுபவர்களை விட சிறிது உடல் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi đã tiến hành so sánh sơ bộ về giao tiếp giữa người-robot (HR) và người-con (HHM) với giao tiếp thực hiện bằng tiếng Anh và tiếng Nhật. Kết quả là, cử chỉ cơ thể tăng lên ở HR, còn tay và đầu cử chỉ giảm xuống ở HR. Đối với hành động bằng tay, chúng bao gồm các dạng, quỹ đạo và chức năng khác nhau hơn ở HHM so với HR. Hơn nữa, những người nói tiếng Anh sản xuất gấp sáu lần cử chỉ tay so với người Nhật ở HHM. Về chủ nghĩa cử chỉ, mặc dù không có s ự khác biệt về tần số cử chỉ giữa người Anh và người Nhật ở HHM, những người nói tiếng Nhật xuất hiện hơi lớn tiếng gật đầu hơn những người nói tiếng Anh ở HR. Hơn nữa, vị trí gật đầu khác nhau tùy theo ngôn ngữ. Về hành động cơ thể, những người tham gia sản xuất hành động thể xác chủ yếu để điều chỉnh khoảng cách thích hợp với robot tại HR. Những người nói tiếng Anh còn tạo ra những cử chỉ cơ thể hơn người Nhật.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Biz ingliz tilida va Yaponchaga ishlatadigan inson (HH) shaxsiyati bilan birinchi muammolar bilan boshqarishni bajardik. Va natijada, huddi HR'da o'zgarishlarni ko'paydi, agar qo'l va boshqa sarlavhasi HR'da kamaytadi. Gap gestur haqida ular HR'da ko'proq turli va murakkab shakllar, sakkizlar va funksiyatlarni o'zgartirdi. Keyin ingliz tillari HH tilidagi Japoniya gapiruvchidan 6 marta ko'proq qo'llangan qo'lbolarni yaratadi. Regarding head gesture, even though there was no difference in the frequency of head gestures between English speakers and Japanese speakers in HH, Japanese speakers produced slightly more nodding during the robot's speaking than English speakers in HR.  Ko'rsatilgan, nod'ning joylari tilga bir xil bo'lgan edi. Tashqi gestur haqida qiziqaruvchilar HR'ning robot bilan mos keladigan masofadan boshqarish uchun body gesturlarini yaratadi. Ko'pchilik, ingliz tili tillari Yapon tillarga ko'proq jidh gesturlarini yaratadi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Направихме предварително сравнение на взаимодействието човек-робот (ЧР) с взаимодействието човек-човек (ХХ), проведено на английски и японски език. В резултат на това жестовете на тялото се увеличават в сърдечния ритъм, а жестовете на ръцете и главата намаляват в сърдечния ритъм. Що се отнася до жестовете на ръцете, те са съставени от по-разнообразни и сложни форми, траектории и функции в ХХ, отколкото в ХР. Освен това англоговорящите произвеждат 6 пъти повече жестове с ръце от японските в ХХ. Що се отнася до жестовете на главата, въпреки че няма разлика в честотата на жестовете на главата между англоговорящите и японските говорещи в ХХ, японските говорещи произвеждат малко повече кимане по време на говоренето на робота, отколкото англоговорящите в ЧР. Освен това позициите на кимване са различни в зависимост от езика. Що се отнася до телесните жестове, участниците произвеждат телесни жестове най-вече за регулиране на подходящото разстояние с робота в ЧР. Освен това англоговорящите създадоха малко повече телесни жестове от японските.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We hebben voorlopige vergelijking uitgevoerd van mens-robot (HR) interactie met mens-mens (HH) interactie uitgevoerd in het Engels en in het Japans. Hierdoor namen lichaamsbewegingen toe in HR, terwijl hand- en hoofdbewegingen afnamen in HR. Met betrekking tot handgebaren bestonden ze uit meer uiteenlopende en complexe vormen, trajecten en functies in HH dan in HR. Bovendien produceerden Engelstaligen zes keer meer handgebaren dan Japanners in HH. Wat betreft hoofdgebaren, hoewel er geen verschil was in de frequentie van hoofdgebaren tussen Engelstaligen en Japanners in HH, produceerden Japanse sprekers iets meer knikken tijdens het spreken van de robot dan Engelstaligen in HR. Bovendien waren de posities van knikken verschillend afhankelijk van de taal. Wat lichaamsgebaren betreft, produceerden deelnemers lichaamsgebaren meestal om de juiste afstand met de robot in HR te regelen. Daarnaast produceerden Engelstaligen iets meer lichaamsgebaren dan Japanners.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Vi foretog en foreløbig sammenligning af menneske-robot (HR) interaktion med menneske-menneske (HH) interaktion udført på engelsk og japansk. Som følge heraf øgede kropsbevægelser i HR, mens hånd- og hovedbevægelser faldt i HR. Hvad angår håndbevægelser, var de sammensat af mere forskelligartede og komplekse former, baner og funktioner i HH end i HR. Desuden producerede engelsktalende 6 gange flere håndbevægelser end japansktalende i HH. Med hensyn til hovedbevægelser, selv om der ikke var nogen forskel i hyppigheden af hovedbevægelser mellem engelsktalende og japansktalende i HH, producerede japansktalende lidt mere nikkende under robottens tale end engelsktalende i HR. Desuden var positionerne for nikken forskellige afhængigt af sproget. Med hensyn til kropsbevægelser producerede deltagerne kropsbevægelser mest for at regulere passende afstand med robotten i HR. Derudover producerede engelsktalende lidt flere kropsbevægelser end japansktalende.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Provodili smo preliminarnu usporedbu interakcije ljudskih robota (HR) s interakcijom ljudskih i ljudskih (HH) provedenom na engleskom i japanskom jeziku. Kao rezultat toga, gesti tijela su povećani u HR, dok su ruke i gesti glave smanjene u HR. Što se tiče gesta ruke, sastavljene su od raznih i složenih oblika, trajektorija i funkcija u HH nego u HR. Osim toga, engleski govornici su proizveli 6 puta više gesta ruke od japanskih govornika u HH. Što se tiče glavnog gesta, iako nije bilo razlike u frekvenciji glavnih gesta između engleskih govornika i japanskih govornika u HH-u, japanski govornici su proizveli malo više klimanja tijekom govora robota nego engleskih govornika u HR-u. Osim toga, pozicije klinka su različite ovisno o jeziku. Što se tiče gesta tijela, učesnici su proizveli geste tijela uglavnom kako bi regulirali odgovarajuću udaljenost s robotom u HR. Osim toga, engleski govornici su proizveli malo više tjelesnih gesta od japanskih govornika.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Wir haben einen vorläufigen Vergleich der Mensch-Roboter (HR) Interaktion mit Mensch-Mensch (HH) Interaktion auf Englisch und Japanisch durchgeführt. Infolgedessen nahmen Körpergesten in der HR zu, während Hand- und Kopfgesten in der HR abnahmen. Hinsichtlich der Handgeste bestanden sie in HH aus vielfältigeren und komplexeren Formen, Trajektorien und Funktionen als in der HR. Darüber hinaus produzierten englische Sprecher 6-mal mehr Handgesten als japanische Sprecher in HH. In Bezug auf die Kopfgeste gab es zwar keinen Unterschied in der Häufigkeit der Kopfgesten zwischen englischen und japanischen Sprechern in HH, japanische Sprecher erzeugten während des Sprechens des Roboters etwas mehr Nicken als englische Sprecher in HR. Außerdem waren die Nickpositionen je nach Sprache unterschiedlich. In Bezug auf Körpergesten produzierten die Teilnehmer Körpergesten meist, um den entsprechenden Abstand mit dem Roboter in der HR zu regulieren. Darüber hinaus produzierten englische Sprecher etwas mehr Körpergesten als japanische Sprecher.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kami melakukan perbandingan awal dari interaksi manusia-robot (HR) dengan interaksi manusia-manusia (HH) dilakukan dalam bahasa Inggris dan Jepang. Sebagai hasilnya, gerakan tubuh meningkat dalam HR, sementara gerakan tangan dan kepala berkurang dalam HR. Mengenai gerakan tangan, mereka terdiri dari bentuk yang lebih berbeda dan kompleks, trajektori dan fungsi di HH daripada HR. Selain itu, pembicara Inggris menghasilkan 6 kali lebih banyak gerakan tangan daripada pembicara Jepang di HH. Mengenai gerakan kepala, meskipun tidak ada perbedaan dalam frekuensi gerakan kepala antara pembicara Inggris dan pembicara Jepang di HH, pembicara Jepang menghasilkan sedikit lebih nodding selama berbicara robot daripada pembicara Inggris di HR. Selain itu, posisi nod berbeda bergantung pada bahasa. Mengenai gerak tubuh, peserta menghasilkan gerak tubuh kebanyakan untuk mengatur jarak yang sesuai dengan robot di HR. Selain itu, pembicara Inggris menghasilkan sedikit lebih banyak gerakan tubuh daripada pembicara Jepang.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>ما پیشینیان مقایسه‌ای از ارتباط با ارتباط انسان و انسان (HH) با انگلیسی و ژاپنی انجام دادیم. در نتیجه، حرکت بدن در HR افزایش یافت، در حالی که دست و سر در HR افزایش یافت. راجع به حرکت دست، آنها از شکل های مختلف و پیچیده تر، مسیر و عملکرد در HH از HR ساخته شده‌اند. علاوه بر این، سخنرانی انگلیسی شش برابر حرکت های دست بیشتری از سخنرانی ژاپنی در HH تولید کردند. در مورد حرکت سر، حتی اگرچه فرکانس حرکت سر بین زبان انگلیسی و زبان‌گویی ژاپنی در HH وجود نداشت، زبان‌گویی ژاپنی در زمان صحبت روبات کمی بیشتر از زبان‌گویی انگلیسی در HR تولید کردند. علاوه بر این، موقعیت‌های نود بر اساس زبان متفاوت بودند. در مورد جستجو بدن، شرکتگران بیشتر جستجو بدن را تولید کردند تا فاصله مناسب با روبات در HR کنترل کنند. به اضافه، سخنرانی انگلیسی به اندازه‌ای از سخنرانی ژاپنی جسد بیشتری تولید کردند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Ons het vooraf vergelyking van mens-robot (HR) interaksie met mens-mens-interaksie (HH) wat in Engels en in Japanse gedoen is. As die resultaat, liggaamsgesture het in HR vergroot, terwyl hand en kopgesture in HR verklein het. Aangaande hand gestuur is hulle gemaak van meer verskillende en komplekse vorms, trajektories en funksies in HH as in HR. Ook het Engelske sprekkers 6 maal meer hand gestuur geproduseer as Japanse sprekkers in HH. Aangaande kopgestuur, selfs al was daar geen verskil in die frekwensie van kopgestuur tussen Engelske sprekkers en Japanse sprekkers in HH nie, Japanse sprekkers het 'n bietjie meer noding geproduseer gedurende die robot se praat as Engelse sprekkers in HR. Verder was posisies van nod anders afhanklik van die taal. Aangaande liggaamsgestuur het deelnaders liggaamsgestuur geproduseerd meeste om geskikte afstand te reg met die robot in HR. In addition, English speakers produced slightly more body gestures than Japanese speakers.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sw>We conducted preliminary comparison of human-robot (HR) interaction with human-human (HH) interaction conducted in English and in Japanese.  Matokeo yake, matukio ya mwili yaliongezeka katika HR, wakati matukio ya mkono na kichwa yalipungua huko HR. Kuhusu matukio ya mkono, yalitengenezwa na aina mbalimbali na tatizo, mabadiliko na kazi za HH kuliko katika HR. Zaidi ya hayo, wazungumzaji wa Kiingereza walitengeneza viungo vya mkono mara 6 zaidi ya wazungumzaji wa Kijapani huko HH. Kuhusu tukio la kichwa, ingawa hakuna tofauti katika vigezo vya kichwa kati ya wazungumzaji wa Kiingereza na Wajapani wa HH, hotuba za Kijapani walitengeneza habari kidogo wakati wa hotuba ya roboti kuliko wazungumzaji wa Kiingereza nchini HR. Zaidi ya hayo, nafasi za nod zilikuwa tofauti kulitegemea lugha. Kuhusu gesi za mwili, washiriki walitengeneza gesi za mwili kwa kiasi kikubwa kudhibiti umbali sahihi na roboti huko HR. Zaidi ya hayo, hotuba za Kiingereza walitengeneza viungo vya mwili zaidi ya wazungumzaji wa Kijapani.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Biz adam-robot(HR) ynsan-ynsan(HH) bilen Iňlisçe we japonça tutuşan etkileşimi ilkinji gezek görä çykdy. Soňunda beden gesteleri HR'de artýar, el we kell gesteleri hR'de azalýar. Eli çekişi bilen görä, HH'de HR'den köp şeklinde dürli we karmaşık şekllerden oluşuldy. Iňlisçe gürleşýänler HH'de Japon dilinde gürleşýänlerden 6 gezek gowy hereket edipdi. Kaç çekmesi barada, HH'de Iňlis dilinde gürleşýänler we japonça dilinde gürleşýänler arasynda birnäçe daşlyk ýok bolsa-da, japonça gürleşýänler robotyň gürleşýän wagtynda HR'de Iňlis dilinde gürleşýänlerden has daşlyk diýipdir. Munuň üçin (nod) ýerleri dile görä birnäçe-birnäçe görýärdi. Beden gesteleri barada, iştirakçiler beden hareketlerden köplenç derejesi üçin robot bilen ýerli uzaklary düzenlemek üçin janly hereket etdiler. Iňlis dilinde gürleşýänler Japonça gürleşýänlerden biraz köp beden hareket edipdi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>We conducted preliminary comparison of human-robot (HR) interaction with human-human (HH) interaction conducted in English and in Japanese.  Si rezultat, gjesturat e trupit u rritën në HR, ndërsa gjesturat e dorës dhe kokës u ulën në HR. Në lidhje me gjesturën e dorës, ato ishin përbërë nga forma më të ndryshme dhe komplekse, trajektori dhe funksione në HH sesa në HR. Përveç kësaj, fletësit angleze prodhuan 6 herë më shumë gjeste dore se fletësit japonezë në HH. Në lidhje me gjesturën e kokës, edhe pse nuk kishte dallim në frekuencën e gjesturave të kokës midis fletësve angleze dhe fletësve japonezë në HH, fletësve japonezë prodhuan pak më tepër nodding gjatë foljes s ë robotit se fletësve angleze në HR. Përveç kësaj, pozicionet e nodit ishin të ndryshme në varësi të gjuhës. Në lidhje me gjesturën e trupit, pjesëmarrësit prodhuan gjesturat e trupit kryesisht për të rregulluar distancën e duhur me robot in në HR. Përveç kësaj, fletësit angleze prodhuan pak më shumë gjeste trupi se fletësit japonezë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք կատարեցինք մարդկային-ռոբոտի (ՀՀՀ) փոխազդեցության նախաձեռնական համեմատությունը մարդկային-մարդկային (ՀՀ) փոխազդեցության հետ, որը կատարվում էր անգլերենով և ճապոներենով: Արդյունքում, մարմնի շարժումները բարձրացան ՀՀ-ում, մինչդեռ ձեռքերի և գլխի շարժումները նվազեցին ՀՀ-ում: Ինչ վերաբերում է ձեռքի ժեստերին, դրանք կազմված էին ավելի բազմազան և բարդ ձևերից, ուղիներից և ֆունկցիաներից ՀՀ-ում, քան ՀՀՀ-ում: Ավելին, անգլերեն խոսնակները 6 անգամ ավելի շատ ձեռքերի շարժումներ արտադրեցին քան ճապոնացիները ՀՀ-ում: Ինչ վերաբերում է գլխավոր ժեստերին, չնայած որ անգլերեն և ճապոներեն ժեստերի հաճախականության տարբերություն չկար գլխավոր ժեստերի հաճախականության մեջ ՀՀ-ում, ճապոներեն ժեստերն արտադրեցին մի քիչ ավելին գլխավոր գլխավոր ժեստերը ռոբո Ավելին, կետի դիրքերը տարբերվում էին, կախված լեզվից: Ինչ վերաբերում է մարմնի ժեստերին, մասնակիցները ստեղծեցին մարմնի ժեստեր հիմնականում, որպեսզի կարգավորեն համապատասխան հեռավորությունը ՀԱ-ի ռոբոտի հետ: Ավելին, անգլերեն խոսնակները մի քիչ ավելի շատ մարմնի շարժումներ արտադրեցին քան ճապոնացիները:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>We conducted preliminary comparison of human-robot (HR) interaction with human-human (HH) interaction conducted in English and in Japanese.  ስለዚህም አካል አካባቢ እጃዎችና ራሳቸው በHR ውስጥ ሲጎድሉ አካል ይጨመር ነበር፡፡ ስለ እጁ ግንኙነት፣ ከHR ይልቅ በተለየ እና በተጨማሪው ፎርማዎች፣ የግንኙነት እና ፍቃድ የተሰለፉ ናቸው፡፡ ደግሞም እንግሊዘኛ ቃላት ከጃፓንኛ ንግግሮችን ይልቅ 6 እጥፍ እጃቸውን አቀረቡ፡፡ በአንግሊዝኛ እና በጃፓን ንግግር እና በጃፓን እና በአፍሪካዊ ቋንቋዎች መካከል የራስ ቁጥጥር ምንም ልዩነት ባይኖር፣ የጃፓን ንግግር አዋቂዎች በሮቦት ንግግር ውስጥ ከኢንግሊዝኛ ቋንቋዎች የበለጠ በይነግሪክ ቋንቋዎች ላይ ትንሽ አነስተዋል፡፡ ከዚህም በላይ በቋንቋው ላይ የኖድ ስፍራዎች የተለየ ናቸው፡፡ በሥጋው ግንኙነት ላይ ተጋሪዎቹ በአካባቢው አካል ግንኙነት ከሮቦት ጋር በመጠቀም አካባቢ ግንኙነት አቀረቡ፡፡ በተጨማሪም እንግሊዘኛ ንግግሊዘኞች ከጃፓን ንግግሮች የበለጠ የሥጋውን ግንኙነት አቀረቡ፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>ইংরেজি এবং জাপানী ভাষায় অনুষ্ঠিত মানুষ (এইচএইচএইচএইচএইচএইচ) মানুষের (এইচএইচএইচএইচএইচ) মানুষের সাথে মানব-রোবটের তুলনার প্রথম ফলাফলের ফলে এইচআর এর মাথায় শরীরের গুলি বৃদ্ধি হয়েছে, যখন হাত এবং মাথায় হাত কমে গেছে। হাতের গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ঘটনার ব্যাপারে তারা এইচএইচআর-এর চেয়ে বেশী বিভিন্ন এবং কমপ্লিক ফর্ম, ট্রাক্টরি এবং ফাংশনের সংগঠিত এছাড়াও ইংরেজী ভাষাকারীরা এইচএইচ-এর জাপানী ভাষাকারীদের চেয়ে ৬ বার হাতের প্রতিযোগিতা প্রকাশ কর Regarding head gesture, even though there was no difference in the frequency of head gestures between English speakers and Japanese speakers in HH, Japanese speakers produced slightly more nodding during the robot's speaking than English speakers in HR.  এছাড়াও, নোডের অবস্থান ভিন্ন ভাষার উপর নির্ভর করে। অংশগ্রহণকারীরা এইচআর-এর রোবটের সাথে যথাযথ দূরত্ব নিয়ন্ত্রণের জন্য দেহের জেগুট তৈরি করেছেন। এছাড়াও ইংরেজী ভাষাকারীরা জাপানি ভাষাকারীদের চেয়ে কিছুটা বেশী শরীরের প্রতীক তৈরি করেছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 영어와 일본어로 진행된 인간과 기계의 상호작용에 대해 초보적인 비교를 진행하였다.이에 따라 HR에서는 신체 자세가 증가하는 반면 HR에서는 손과 머리 자세가 줄어든다.제스처의 경우 HH그룹이 HR그룹보다 제스처 형태, 궤적과 기능이 다양하고 복잡하다.이 밖에 HH에서는 영어를 하는 사람의 손짓이 일본어를 하는 사람의 6배에 이른다.머리 자세와 관련해서는 HH에서 영어를 하는 사람과 일본어를 하는 사람 사이에 머리 자세의 빈도가 차이가 없지만, HR에서 일본어를 하는 사람은 로봇이 영어를 하는 사람보다 조금 더 고개를 끄덕인다.그리고 고개를 끄덕이는 위치는 언어에 따라 다르다.신체 자세의 경우 참가자가 신체 자세를 취하는 것은 주로 HR에서 로봇과의 적절한 거리를 조절하기 위해서다.또 영어를 하는 사람이 일본어를 하는 사람보다 몸짓을 조금 더 많이 한다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_bs>Provodili smo preliminarnu usporedbu interakcije ljudskih robota (HR) sa interakcijom ljudskih i ljudskih (HH) provedenom na engleskom i japanskom jeziku. Kao rezultat toga, gesti tijela su povećani u HR, dok su ruke i gesti glave smanjene u HR. Što se tiče gesta ruke, sastavljeni su od raznih i kompleksnih oblika, trajektorija i funkcija u HH nego u HR. Osim toga, engleski govornici su proizveli šest puta više gesta od japanskih govornika u HH. Što se tiče glavnog gesta, iako nije bilo razlike u frekvenciji glavnih gesta između engleskih govornika i japanskih govornika u HH, japanski govornici su proizveli malo više klimanja tokom govora robota nego engleskih govornika u HR. Osim toga, pozicije klinka su različite ovisno o jeziku. Što se tiče gesta tijela, učesnici su proizveli geste tijela uglavnom kako bi regulirali odgovarajuću udaljenost sa robotom u HR. Osim toga, engleski govornici su proizveli malo više gesta tijela nego japanski govornici.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_az>ńįnsan-insan (HH) il…ô ńįngilizce v…ô Japonca iŇül…ôdil…ôn insan-robot (HR) m√ľxt…ôlif …ôlaq…ôl…ôrini ilk d…ôf…ô saldńĪq. Sonu√ßta, b…ôd…ôniyy…ôt h…ôr…ôk…ôtl…ôri HR-d…ô artńĪrdńĪ, …ôl v…ô baŇü h…ôr…ôk…ôtl…ôri HR-d…ô azaldńĪ. ∆Źl gesti haqqńĪnda, HH'd…ô HR'd…ôn daha √ßox m√ľxt…ôlif v…ô kompleks formlardan olub. ∆Źksin…ô, ńįngilizci danńĪŇüanlar HH'd…ô Japon danńĪŇüanlarńĪndan 6 kat daha √ßox istifad…ô etdil…ôr. BaŇü gesti bar…ôsind…ô, HH-d…ô ńįngilizce danńĪŇüanlarńĪ v…ô Japon danńĪŇüanlarńĪ arasńĪnda baŇü gestl…ôrinin s ńĪfńĪrlńĪńüńĪ olmasa da, Japon danńĪŇüanlarńĪ robot danńĪŇüdńĪńüńĪ zaman HR-d…ô ńįngilizce danńĪŇüanlarńĪndan daha √ßox danńĪŇümaq yaratdńĪlar. Daha sonra, n√∂d m…ôqamlarńĪ dilin…ô bańülńĪ idi. V√ľcud gesti bar…ôsind…ô, iŇütirak√ßil…ôr HR robotu il…ô uyńüun m…ôsaf…ôni d√ľz…ôltm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn v√ľcud gesti yaratdńĪlar. ∆Źksin…ô, ńįngiliz…ô danńĪŇüanlarńĪ Japonca danńĪŇüanlardan daha √ßox v√ľcud gesti yaratdńĪlar.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_cs>Provedli jsme předběžné srovnání interakce člověk-robot (HR) s interakcí člověk-člověk (HH) v angličtině a japonštině. V důsledku toho se v HR zvyšovala gesta těla, zatímco gesta ruky a hlavy snižovaly. Pokud jde o ruční gesto, byly složeny z rozmanitějších a složitějších forem, trajektorií a funkcí v HH než v HR. Angličtí mluvčí navíc produkovali 6-krát více gest rukou než japonští mluvčí v HH. Pokud jde o geste hlavy, i když nebyl žádný rozdíl v frekvenci gest hlavy mezi anglicky mluvícími a japonsky mluvícími v HH, japonští mluvčí produkovali během mluvení robota o něco více kývání než anglicky mluvící v HR. Kromě toho se pozice kývání lišily v závislosti na jazyce. Co se týče tělesných gest, účastníci vytvářeli tělesná gesta převážně pro regulaci odpovídající vzdálenosti s robotem v HR. Navíc angličtina mluvčí produkovali o něco více gest těla než japonští mluvčí.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Eelnevalt võrdlesime inimese-roboti (HR) interaktsiooni inimese-inimese (HH) interaktsiooniga inglise ja jaapani keeles. Selle tulemusena suurenesid keha žestid pulsis, käe- ja peažestid vähenesid pulsis. Käe žesti osas koosnesid need HH-s mitmekesisematest ja keerukamatest vormidest, trajektooridest ja funktsioonidest kui HR-s. Lisaks tootsid inglise keelt kõnelevad kuus korda rohkem käsi žeste kui jaapani keelt kõnelevad HH. Kuigi peažestide sageduses ei olnud erinevust inglise keelt ja jaapani keelt HH-s kõnelevate vahel, siis jaapani keelt kõnelevad tootsid roboti kõnelemise ajal veidi rohkem noogutamist kui inglise keelt HR-s. Lisaks olid noogutamise asendid sõltuvalt keelest erinevad. Kehažestide osas tootsid osalejad kehažestid peamiselt selleks, et reguleerida robotiga HR-s sobivat kaugust. Lisaks tootsid inglise keelt kõnelevad veidi rohkem kehažeste kui jaapani keelt kõnelevad.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Suoritimme alustavan vertailun ihmisen ja robotin (HR) vuorovaikutuksesta ihmisen ja ihmisen (HH) vuorovaikutukseen englanniksi ja japaniksi. Tämän seurauksena kehon eleet lisääntyivät sykkeessä ja käsi- ja pääeleet vähenivät sykkeessä. Käsieleen osalta ne koostuivat monimuotoisemmista ja monimutkaisemmista muodoista, trajektoreista ja toiminnoista HH:ssä kuin HR:ssä. Lisäksi englantilaiset tuottivat kuusi kertaa enemmän käsieleitä kuin japanilaiset HH:ssa. Pääeleiden taajuudessa ei ollut eroa englanninkielisten ja japanilaisten välillä HH:ssa, mutta japanilaiset tuottivat robotin puheen aikana hieman enemmän nyökkäystä kuin englanninkieliset HR:ssä. Lisäksi nyökkäyksen asennot vaihtelivat kielestä riippuen. Kehoelen osalta osallistujat valmistivat kehoeleitä lähinnä säätelemään sopivaa etäisyyttä robotin kanssa HR:ssä. Lisäksi englantilaiset tuottivat hieman enemmän kehoeleitä kuin japanilaiset.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>Vam fer una comparació preliminar de l'interacció humano-robot (HR) amb l'interacció humano-humana (HH) en anglès i japonès. Com a resultat, els gestos corporals van augmentar en RH, mentre els gestos de mà i cap van disminuir en RH. En relació amb el gest manual, estaven composts de formes, trajectòries i funcions més diverses i complexes en HH que en HR. A més, els anglesos van produir 6 vegades més gestos de mà que els japonesos en HH. En relació amb el gest del cap, encara que no hi havia diferència en la freqüència de gests del cap entre parlants anglesos i japonesos en HH, els parlants japonesos van produir una mica més nodding durant la conversa del robot que els anglesos en HR. Furthermore, positions of nod were different depending on the language.  En relació al gest corporal, els participants van produir gests corporals principalment per regular la distància apropiada amb el robot en RH. A més, els anglesos van produir una mica més gestos corporals que els japonesos.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé éntuk perusahaan tanggal wigatasahan karo perusahaan-bot anyar (HR) iso nggambar barang-uwong karo nggambar uwong-uwong. Yo wis ditambah, sampeyan gesture dipun HR, durung manut lan kelas kuwi wis ambas barang HR. Manyak gesture sampeyan, wong iki sak ngawasipun luwih karo perusahaan karo pakek, trajector karo funksi lagi HH karo HR Nambah, basa Inggris barang manung suxtang kelas telu maning tuwih manung apapangin HH. Ngacah nggambar kelas gest, tho saben ora ono cah dumadhi kapan pangan ingkang dipuluhay lan basa japanya iki ning HH, basa sing japanya luwih apik dhéwé ngerasakno sing katêpakan karo bot sing bisa ngomong ingkang HR. politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Ngubah Jagad-Jagad Manyak-mangkat, basa Inggris barang daftar puteh padha uga sawasar luwih basa japoni.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Izvedli smo predhodno primerjavo interakcije človek-robot (HR) z interakcijo človek-človek (HH) v angleščini in japonščini. Posledično so se kretnje telesa povečale v srčnem utripu, kretnje roke in glave pa se zmanjšale v srčnem utripu. Kar zadeva geste z rokami, so bile sestavljene iz bolj raznolikih in kompleksnih oblik, poti in funkcij v HH kot v HR. Poleg tega so angleški govorci naredili šestkrat več rok kot japonski govorci v HH. Čeprav pogostost glavnih gest med angleškimi in japonskimi govorniki v HH ni bila razlike v pogostosti glavnih gest, so japonski govorniki med govorjenjem robota povzročili nekoliko več kimanja kot angleški govorniki v HR. Poleg tega so bili položaji kimanja različni glede na jezik. V zvezi s telesnimi gestami so udeleženci izdelali telesne geste predvsem za uravnavanje ustrezne razdalje z robotom v HR. Poleg tega so angleški govorci ustvarili nekoliko več telesnih gest kot japonski govorci.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>ביצענו השוואה מראשית של אינטראקציה אנושית-רובוט (HR) עם אינטראקציה אנושית-אנושית (HH) ביצעה באנגלית וביפנית. כתוצאה מכך, מחוות הגוף גדלו ב HR, בעוד מחוות יד וראש נפלו ב HR. בנוגע למחווות יד, הם היו מורכבים בצורות, מסלולים ופעולות מורכבות יותר בהם מאשר בHR. חוץ מזה, מדברים אנגליים יצרו 6 פעמים יותר מחווות יד מאשר מדברים יפנים ב HH. בנוגע למחאות הראשית, למרות שלא היה שום הבדל בתדר המחאות הראשיות בין רופאים אנגליים לרופאים יפניים ב HH, רופאים יפניים יצרו קצת יותר ניקוד בזמן הרובוט מדבר מאשר רופאים אנגליים ב HR. חוץ מזה, עמדות הנקודה היו שונות בהתאם לשפה. Concerning body gesture, participants produced body gestures mostly to regulate appropriate distance with the robot in HR.  Additionally, English speakers produced slightly more body gestures than Japanese speakers.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>We conducted preliminary comparison of human-robot (HR) interaction with human-human (HH) interaction conducted in English and in Japanese.  Na ƙara, gestures za'a ƙara cikin HR, da kuma haske na hannu da kichin na ƙara cikin HR. Amma ga gestuta hannuwan, aka samo su daga wasu former masu dabam da masu adadi, hanyoyi da functionin da ke cikin HH ko da kuma a cikin HR. Da haka, masu maganar Ingiriya sun zaɓi sauti sau 6 sau tallar hannuwansu da ke cikin HH. Ga gaskiyar huge, kuma kõ dã ba ta kasance wani s ãɓãni ba a cikin marafan saurãre na huɗunsa a tsakanin saukarar Ingiriya da mazaɓa-jama'a cikin HH, sai saurãre-japane suka samu da abu kaɗan da saurare a lokacin da za'a faɗi na Ingiriya da HR. Da haka, filinaikin nod na dabam-daba'a, sun yi daidai a kan harshen. Aka kan gesture na jikin, mãsu shirin bayani suka sami gesture na jikin, mafi yawansa, dõmin ya yi adadi ga hanya masu daidai da matofon cikin HR. Da haka, masu saurãren Ingiriya sun sami sauti da abu kaɗan daga saurãren Jabaniya.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་མིའི་རྩོམ་པ་དང་མཉམ་ཐག་ནས་གནད་དོན་འགྱུར་བའི་སྔོན་གྱི་མཉམ་དུ་བྲིས་པ་ཡིན། མཐོང་སྐྱེས་པའི་གནས་ཚུལ་གྱི་མཐུན་འགྱུར་བ་ནི་HR ཞིག་ཏུ་ཡར་རྒྱས་པ་དང་ལག་དང་གནོད་པའི་ཚད་HR ཞིག ལག་པ་དང་མཐུན་སྣེ་ཚོགས་འདི་HR ནང་ལས་ཕལ་ཆེན་སྣེ་འདྲ་ཞིག་ལས་བཟོ་འདུག འོན་ཀྱང་། དབྱིན་ཡིག་གི་སྐད་པ་ཚོས་HH ནང་ཡོད་པའི་སྐད་ཆ་ཉེ་ཧོང་གི་དཀྲོག་གཏོང་ལས་༦་རིང་ མགོ་ཡི་སྐོར་ལ་བསམ་བྱས་ཡོད་ནའང་། དབྱིན་ཡིག་གི་སྐད་རྒྱ་ནག་དང་ཉེ་ཧོང་གི་སྐད་ཀྱི་རྒྱ་ནག་ནང་དུ་ཡོད་པ་རྒྱ་ནག་ནང་དུ་ཉེ་ཧོང་གི་སྐད་ཀྱི་རྐད་ཀྱི་ནང་ ད་དུང་། མིང་གི་གནས་ཡུལ་ནི་སྐད་རིགས་དང་གཅིག་པ་མཚུངས་ཡིན། མཉམ་ལས་ཀྱི་སྒེར་གྱི་གནས་སྟངས་དང་མཐུན་སྣེ་ཚོགས་ནི་དབུལ་གྱི་ལས་འགུལ་མཐུན་གྱི་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་བཟོ་བ་ཡིན། ད་དུང་། དབྱིན་ཡིག་གི་སྐད་ཆ་རྒྱ་ནག་གི་མིང་རྣམས་ལས་ཀར་འགྱུར་བའི་འགྱུར་བ་སྐྱེས་བ་རེད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Improving <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">Sentiment Analysis</a> with Biofeedback Data</title>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Schlör</last></author>
      <author><first>Albin</first><last>Zehe</last></author>
      <author><first>Konstantin</first><last>Kobs</last></author>
      <author><first>Blerta</first><last>Veseli</last></author>
      <author><first>Franziska</first><last>Westermeier</last></author>
      <author><first>Larissa</first><last>Brübach</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Roth</last></author>
      <author><first>Marc Erich</first><last>Latoschik</last></author>
      <author><first>Andreas</first><last>Hotho</last></author>
      <pages>28–33</pages>
      <abstract>Humans frequently are able to read and interpret emotions of others by directly taking verbal and non-verbal signals in human-to-human communication into account or to infer or even experience <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotions</a> from mediated stories. For <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer">computers</a>, however, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_recognition">emotion recognition</a> is a complex problem : Thoughts and feelings are the roots of many <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior">behavioural responses</a> and they are deeply entangled with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neurophysiology">neurophysiological changes</a> within humans. As such, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotions</a> are very subjective, often are expressed in a subtle manner, and are highly depending on context. For example, machine learning approaches for text-based sentiment analysis often rely on incorporating sentiment lexicons or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> to capture the contextual meaning. This paper explores if and how we further can enhance <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biofeedback">biofeedback</a> of humans which are experiencing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotions</a> while reading texts. Specifically, we record the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heart_rate">heart rate</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_oscillation">brain waves</a> of readers that are presented with short texts which have been annotated with the emotions they induce. We use these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physiology">physiological signals</a> to improve the performance of a lexicon-based sentiment classifier. We find that the combination of several <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biosignal">biosignals</a> can improve the ability of a text-based classifier to detect the presence of a sentiment in a text on a per-sentence level.</abstract>
      <url hash="1b303c6b">2020.onion-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>schlor-etal-2020-improving</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>