<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.crac">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Computational Models of Reference, Anaphora and Coreference</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Maciej</first><last>Ogrodniczuk</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Vincent</first><last>Ng</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yulia</first><last>Grishina</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sameer</first><last>Pradhan</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="50191fb4">2020.crac-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>crac-2020-models</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>It’s absolutely divine ! Can fine-grained sentiment analysis benefit from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a>?</title>
      <author><first>Orphee</first><last>De Clercq</last></author>
      <author><first>Veronique</first><last>Hoste</last></author>
      <pages>11–21</pages>
      <abstract>While it has been claimed that anaphora or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a> plays an important role in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opinion_mining">opinion mining</a>, it is not clear to what extent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a> actually boosts performance, if at all. In this paper, we investigate the potential added value of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a> for the aspect-based sentiment analysis of restaurant reviews in two languages, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_language">Dutch</a>. We focus on the task of aspect category classification and investigate whether including coreference information prior to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Categorization">classification</a> to resolve implicit aspect mentions is beneficial. Because <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a> is not a solved task in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a>, we rely on both automatically-derived and gold-standard coreference relations, allowing us to investigate the true upper bound. By training a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> on a combination of lexical and semantic features, we show that resolving the coreferential relations prior to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a> is beneficial in a joint optimization setup. However, this is only the case when relying on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gold_standard">gold-standard relations</a> and the result is more outspoken for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> than for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_language">Dutch</a>. When validating the optimal models, however, we found that only the Dutch pipeline is able to achieve a satisfying performance on a held-out test set and does so regardless of whether coreference information was included.</abstract>
      <url hash="01a14f14">2020.crac-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>de-clercq-hoste-2020-absolutely</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Anaphoric Zero Pronoun Identification : A Multilingual Approach</title>
      <author><first>Abdulrahman</first><last>Aloraini</last></author>
      <author><first>Massimo</first><last>Poesio</last></author>
      <pages>22–32</pages>
      <abstract>Pro-drop languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic">Arabic</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_language">Italian</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese</a> allow morphologically null but referential arguments in certain syntactic positions, called anaphoric zero-pronouns. Much NLP work on anaphoric zero-pronouns (AZP) is based on gold mentions, but models for their identification are a fundamental prerequisite for their resolution in real-life applications. Such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Identity_(social_science)">identification</a> requires <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complex_system">complex language understanding</a> and knowledge of real-world entities. Transfer learning models, such as BERT, have recently shown to learn surface, syntactic, and semantic information, which can be very useful in recognizing AZPs. We propose a BERT-based multilingual model for AZP identification from predicted zero pronoun positions, and evaluate it on the Arabic and Chinese portions of OntoNotes 5.0. As far as we know, this is the first neural network model of AZP identification for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic">Arabic</a> ; and our approach outperforms the stateof-the-art for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a>. Experiment results suggest that BERT implicitly encode information about AZPs through their surrounding context.</abstract>
      <url hash="3b9e3990">2020.crac-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>aloraini-poesio-2020-anaphoric</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Predicting Coreference in Abstract Meaning Representations<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>bstract <fixed-case>M</fixed-case>eaning <fixed-case>R</fixed-case>epresentations</title>
      <author><first>Tatiana</first><last>Anikina</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexander</first><last>Koller</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Roth</last></author>
      <pages>33–38</pages>
      <abstract>This work addresses <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a> in Abstract Meaning Representation (AMR) graphs, a popular formalism for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_parsing">semantic parsing</a>. We evaluate several current coreference resolution techniques on a recently published AMR coreference corpus, establishing baselines for future work. We also demonstrate that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a> can improve the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of a state-of-the-art <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_parser">semantic parser</a> on this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="d61d8939">2020.crac-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>anikina-etal-2020-predicting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>TwiConv : A Coreference-annotated Corpus of Twitter Conversations<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>wi<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>onv: A Coreference-annotated Corpus of <fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter Conversations</title>
      <author><first>Berfin</first><last>Aktaş</last></author>
      <author><first>Annalena</first><last>Kohnert</last></author>
      <pages>47–54</pages>
      <abstract>This article introduces TwiConv, an English coreference-annotated corpus of microblog conversations from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a>. We describe the corpus compilation process and the annotation scheme, and release the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> publicly, along with this paper. We manually annotated nominal coreference in 1756 tweets arranged in 185 conversation threads. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation</a> achieves satisfactory <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation agreement</a> results. We also present a new method for mapping the tweet contents with distributed stand-off annotations, which can easily be adapted to different annotation tasks.</abstract>
      <url hash="ef43979d">2020.crac-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>aktas-kohnert-2020-twiconv</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/berfingit/twiconv" additional="false">berfingit/twiconv</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Reference to Discourse Topics : Introducing Global Shell Nouns</title>
      <author><first>Fabian</first><last>Simonjetz</last></author>
      <pages>68–78</pages>
      <abstract>Shell nouns (SNs) are abstract nouns like fact, issue, and decision, which are capable of refer- ring to non-nominal antecedents, much like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anaphora_(linguistics)">anaphoric pronouns</a>. As an extension of classical anaphora resolution, the automatic detection of SNs alongside their respective antecedents has received a growing research interest in recent years but proved to be a challenging task. This paper critically examines the assumption prevalent in previous research that SNs are typically accompanied by a specific antecedent, arguing that SNs like issue and decision are frequently used to refer, not to specific antecedents, but to global discourse topics, in which case they are out of reach of previously proposed resolution strategies that are tailored to SNs with explicit antecedents. The contribution of this work is three-fold. First, the notion of global SNs is defined ; second, their qualitative and quantitative impact on previous SN research is investigated ; and third, implications for previous and future approaches to SN resolution are discussed.</abstract>
      <url hash="22cdfbab">2020.crac-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>simonjetz-2020-reference</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Partially-supervised Mention Detection</title>
      <author><first>Lesly</first><last>Miculicich</last></author>
      <author><first>James</first><last>Henderson</last></author>
      <pages>91–98</pages>
      <abstract>Learning to detect entity mentions without using syntactic information can be useful for integration and joint optimization with other tasks. However, it is common to have partially annotated data for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Problem_solving">problem</a>. Here, we investigate two approaches to deal with partial annotation of mentions : weighted loss and soft-target classification. We also propose two neural mention detection approaches : a sequence tagging, and an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brute-force_search">exhaustive search</a>. We evaluate our methods with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a> as a downstream task, using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multitask_learning">multitask learning</a>. The results show that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F1_score">F1 score</a> improve for all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="bd071624">2020.crac-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>miculicich-henderson-2020-partially</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Enhanced Labelling in Active Learning for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">Coreference Resolution</a></title>
      <author><first>Vebjørn</first><last>Espeland</last></author>
      <author><first>Beatrice</first><last>Alex</last></author>
      <author><first>Benjamin</first><last>Bach</last></author>
      <pages>111–121</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we describe our attempt to increase the amount of information that can be retrieved through active learning sessions compared to previous approaches. We optimise the annotator’s labelling process using active learning in the context of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference_resolution">coreference resolution</a>. Using simulated active learning experiments, we suggest three adjustments to ensure the labelling time is spent as efficiently as possible. All three adjustments provide more information to the machine learner than the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline</a>, though a large impact on the F1 score over time is not observed. Compared to previous <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a>, we report a marginal F1 improvement on the final coreference models trained using for two out of the three approaches tested when applied to the English OntoNotes 2012 Coreference Resolution data. Our best-performing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> achieves 58.01 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-number">F1</a>, an increase of 0.93 F1 over the baseline model.</abstract>
      <url hash="1549d32f">2020.crac-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>espeland-etal-2020-enhanced</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/conll-2012-1">CoNLL-2012</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Reference in Team Communication for Robot-Assisted Disaster Response : An Initial Analysis</title>
      <author><first>Natalia</first><last>Skachkova</last></author>
      <author><first>Ivana</first><last>Kruijff-Korbayova</last></author>
      <pages>122–132</pages>
      <abstract>We analyze reference phenomena in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> of robot-assisted disaster response team communication. The annotation scheme we designed for this purpose distinguishes different types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legal_person">entities</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role">roles</a>, reference units and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_relation">relations</a>. We focus particularly on mission-relevant objects, locations and actors and also annotate a rich set of reference links, including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Co-reference">co-reference</a> and various other kinds of relations. We explain the categories used in our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation</a>, present their distribution in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> and discuss challenging cases.</abstract>
      <url hash="de0424db">2020.crac-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>skachkova-kruijff-korbayova-2020-reference</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Resolving Pronouns in Twitter Streams : Context can Help !<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter Streams: Context can Help!</title>
      <author><first>Anietie</first><last>Andy</last></author>
      <author><first>Chris</first><last>Callison-Burch</last></author>
      <author><first>Derry Tanti</first><last>Wijaya</last></author>
      <pages>133–138</pages>
      <abstract>Many people live-tweet televised events like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_presidential_debates">Presidential debates</a> and popular TV-shows and discuss people or characters in the event. Naturally, many tweets make pronominal reference to these people / characters. We propose an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a> for resolving <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_pronoun">personal pronouns</a> that make reference to people involved in an event, in tweet streams collected during the event.</abstract>
      <url hash="099e87b5">2020.crac-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>andy-etal-2020-resolving</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Coreference Strategies in English-German Translation<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish-<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>erman Translation</title>
      <author><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Lapshinova-Koltunski</last></author>
      <author><first>Marie-Pauline</first><last>Krielke</last></author>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Hardmeier</last></author>
      <pages>139–153</pages>
      <abstract>We present a study focusing on variation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference">coreferential devices</a> in English original <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TED_(conference)">TED talks</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News">news texts</a> and their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German translations</a>. Using exploratory techniques we contemplate a diverse set of coreference devices as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a> which we assume indicate language-specific and register-based variation as well as potential translation strategies. Our findings reflect differences on both dimensions with stronger variation along the lines of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Register_(sociolinguistics)">register</a> than between languages. By exposing interactions between text type and cross-linguistic variation, they can also inform multilingual NLP applications, especially <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="c9f60242">2020.crac-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>lapshinova-koltunski-etal-2020-coreference</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/parcorfull">ParCorFull</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>استراتيجيات Coreference في الترجمة الإنجليزية الألمانية</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Estratégias de correferência na tradução inglês-alemão</title_pt>
      <title_fr>Stratégies de coréférence en traduction anglais-allemand</title_fr>
      <title_es>Estrategias de correferencia en la traducción inglés-alemán</title_es>
      <title_ja>英独翻訳におけるコアレファレンス戦略</title_ja>
      <title_zh>英德译中协同推理策</title_zh>
      <title_ru>Основные стратегии в переводе с английского на немецкий</title_ru>
      <title_hi>अंग्रेजी-जर्मन अनुवाद में Coreference रणनीतियाँ</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Straitéisí Croílár san Aistriúchán Béarla-Gearmáinis</title_ga>
      <title_el>Στρατηγικές συνεργασίας στην αγγλική-γερμανική μετάφραση</title_el>
      <title_ka>ინგლისური- გერმანური თავსუფალისთვის სტრატეგია</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Koreference stratégiák angol-német fordításban</title_hu>
      <title_it>Strategie di Coreference nella traduzione inglese-tedesca</title_it>
      <title_kk>Ағылшын- неміс аудармасында қасиеттер стратегиясы</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Стратегии на коференција на англиско-германски превод</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Coreference Strategies in English-German translation</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Strategi Coreference dalam Terjemahan Inggeris-Jerman</title_ms>
      <title_ml>കോര്‍ഫെന്‍സ് സ്ട്രേറ്റേജികള്‍ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ്- ജര്‍മ്മന്‍ പരിഭാഷ</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Coreference Strategies in English-German Translation</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Англи-Германы хөрөнгө оруулалт</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Strategia współpracy w tłumaczeniu angielsko-niemieckim</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Strategii Coreference în traducerea engleză-germană</title_ro>
      <title_no>Koreferencestrategier i engelsk- tysk oversettelse</title_no>
      <title_si>ඉංග්‍රීසිය- ජර්මන් භාවිතයේ ප්‍රධාන සංදේශය</title_si>
      <title_sr>Strategije korisnosti na engleskom-nemačkom prevodu</title_sr>
      <title_so>Coreference Strategies ku qoran Ingiriis-German Translation</title_so>
      <title_sv>Coreference-strategier i engelsk-tysk översättning</title_sv>
      <title_ta>ஆங்கிலம்- ஜெர்மன் மொழிபெயர்ப்பில் கோர்பென்ஸ் ஸ்ட்ரேட்ஜிகள்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>انگلیسی-جرمن ترجمہ میں سرپرست استراتژی</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Coreference Strategies in English-German Translation</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Phiên bản dịch tiếng Anh-Đức</title_vi>
      <title_hr>Strategije korisnosti na engleskom-njemačkom prevodu</title_hr>
      <title_da>Coreference Strategier i engelsk-tysk oversættelse</title_da>
      <title_nl>Coreference strategieën in Engels-Duits vertaling</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Стратегии за кореференция на английски-немски превод</title_bg>
      <title_de>Coreferenz Strategien in Englisch-Deutsch Übersetzung</title_de>
      <title_fa>استراتژی‌های پیشنهاد در ترجمه‌های انگلیسی-آلمانی</title_fa>
      <title_ko>공지 전략</title_ko>
      <title_tr>Iňlisçe-Almança terjimelerinde gözleňlikler</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Miradi ya Coreference kwa Tafsiri ya Kiingereza na Kijerumani</title_sw>
      <title_af>Koreferensiestrategies in Engels- Duitse Vertaling</title_af>
      <title_am>Coreference Strategies in English-German translation</title_am>
      <title_az>캻ngilizce-Almanl캼q terc칲m톛sind톛 Koreferens Strateji</title_az>
      <title_bn>কোরেফেন্স স্ট্যাটেজি ইংরেজী জার্মান অনুবাদের ভাষায়</title_bn>
      <title_id>Coreference Strategies in English-German Translation</title_id>
      <title_bs>Strategije korisnosti na engleskom-njemačkom prevodu</title_bs>
      <title_sq>Strategjitë e Koreferencës në Traktlim anglo-gjerman</title_sq>
      <title_cs>Strategie spolupráce v anglicko-německém překladu</title_cs>
      <title_hy>Անգլերեն-գերմաներեն թարգմանության համակարգչային ռազմավարությունները</title_hy>
      <title_et>Coreference strateegiad inglise-saksa tõlke keeles</title_et>
      <title_fi>Coreference Strategies in English-German Translation</title_fi>
      <title_ca>Estratègies de coreferència en traducció anglo-alemanya</title_ca>
      <title_jv>Kowé Kareferasi Sitèran kanggo Terjamahan Inggris-German</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Strategije Coreference v angleško-nemškem prevodu</title_sk>
      <title_he>Strategies Coreference בתרגום אנגלי-גרמני</title_he>
      <title_bo>དབྱིན་ཡིག་དང་སྐད་ཡིག་གི་སྐད་བསྒྱུར་བའི་ཐབས་ལམ་གཙོ་རིམ།</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم دراسة تركز على تنوع الأجهزة المرجعية في محادثات TED الإنجليزية الأصلية والنصوص الإخبارية وترجماتها الألمانية. باستخدام التقنيات الاستكشافية ، نفكر في مجموعة متنوعة من أجهزة المرجع كميزات نفترض أنها تشير إلى تباين خاص بلغة معينة وقائم على التسجيل بالإضافة إلى استراتيجيات الترجمة المحتملة. تعكس النتائج التي توصلنا إليها الاختلافات في كلا البعدين مع تباين أقوى على طول خطوط التسجيل أكثر من الاختلافات بين اللغات. من خلال الكشف عن التفاعلات بين نوع النص والتنوع عبر اللغات ، يمكنهم أيضًا إعلام تطبيقات البرمجة اللغوية العصبية متعددة اللغات ، وخاصة الترجمة الآلية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos um estudo com foco na variação de dispositivos correferenciais em palestras TED originais em inglês e textos de notícias e suas traduções em alemão. Usando técnicas exploratórias, contemplamos um conjunto diversificado de dispositivos de correferência como características que supomos indicar variações específicas da linguagem e baseadas em registros, bem como potenciais estratégias de tradução. Nossos achados refletem diferenças em ambas as dimensões com variação mais forte ao longo das linhas de registro do que entre as línguas. Ao expor as interações entre o tipo de texto e a variação linguística cruzada, eles também podem informar aplicativos de PNL multilíngues, especialmente a tradução automática.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos un estudio que se centra en la variación de los dispositivos correferenciales en las charlas TED originales en inglés y en los textos de noticias y sus traducciones al alemán. Mediante el uso de técnicas exploratorias, contemplamos un conjunto diverso de dispositivos de correferencia como características que suponemos que indican variaciones específicas del idioma y basadas en el registro, así como posibles estrategias de traducción. Nuestros hallazgos reflejan diferencias en ambas dimensiones con una mayor variación a lo largo de las líneas de registro que entre idiomas. Al exponer las interacciones entre el tipo de texto y la variación interlingüística, también pueden informar a las aplicaciones multilingües de PNL, especialmente la traducción automática.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>Nous présentons une étude axée sur la variation des dispositifs coréférentiels dans les conférences TED originales en anglais et les textes d'actualités et leurs traductions en allemand. À l'aide de techniques exploratoires, nous envisageons un ensemble diversifié de dispositifs de coréférence en tant que caractéristiques qui, selon nous, indiquent des variations spécifiques à la langue et basées sur des registres, ainsi que des stratégies de traduction potentielles. Nos résultats reflètent des différences dans les deux dimensions, avec une plus grande variation le long des lignes de registre qu'entre les langues. En exposant les interactions entre le type de texte et les variations interlinguistiques, ils peuvent également éclairer les applications multilingues de TAL, en particulier la traduction automatique.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>英語オリジナルのTEDトークやニューステキストとそのドイツ語訳におけるコアレンシャルデバイスのバリエーションに焦点を当てた研究を発表します。探索的手法を使用して、私たちは、言語固有のバリエーションとレジスタベースのバリエーション、および潜在的な翻訳戦略を示す特徴として、多様な一連のコアレファレンスデバイスを考慮します。私たちの調査結果は、両方の次元の違いを反映しており、言語間よりもレジスタの線に沿った強力なばらつきを示しています。テキストタイプとクロス言語的バリエーションとの間の相互作用を公開することによって、彼らはまた、多言語NLPアプリケーション、特に機械翻訳に情報を提供することができます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>臣等敷奏一端,英语始TED演和新闻文本及德语译中coreferential设备之变。 用探索性术者,以众协同引备为我假设,此特定言语寄存器之变,潜译之策也。 臣等见两维度之异,比言语之异,寄存器思路更强。 以公文跨语之交,为多言NLP应用程序给信息,尤为机器翻译。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>Мы представляем исследование, посвященное вариациям ключевых устройств в оригинальных выступлениях и новостных текстах TED на английском языке и их переводах на немецкий язык. Используя поисковые методы, мы рассматриваем разнообразный набор базовых устройств как признаки, которые, как мы предполагаем, указывают на языковые и регистровые вариации, а также потенциальные стратегии перевода. Наши выводы отражают различия по обоим измерениям с более сильными вариациями вдоль линий регистра, чем между языками. Выставляя взаимодействие между типом текста и кросс-лингвистической вариацией, они также могут информировать многоязычные приложения NLP, особенно машинный перевод.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_hi>हम अंग्रेजी मूल टेड वार्ता और समाचार ग्रंथों और उनके जर्मन अनुवादों में सह-क्षेत्रीय उपकरणों की भिन्नता पर ध्यान केंद्रित करते हुए एक अध्ययन प्रस्तुत करते हैं। अन्वेषक तकनीकों का उपयोग करके हम विशेषताओं के रूप में सह-संदर्भित उपकरणों के एक विविध सेट पर विचार करते हैं जो हम मानते हैं कि भाषा-विशिष्ट और रजिस्टर-आधारित भिन्नता के साथ-साथ संभावित अनुवाद रणनीतियों का संकेत मिलता है। हमारे निष्कर्ष भाषाओं के बीच की तुलना में रजिस्टर की तर्ज पर मजबूत भिन्नता के साथ दोनों आयामों पर अंतर को दर्शाते हैं। पाठ प्रकार और क्रॉस-भाषाई भिन्नता के बीच बातचीत को उजागर करके, वे बहुभाषी एनएलपी अनुप्रयोगों, विशेष रूप से मशीन अनुवाद को भी सूचित कर सकते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid i láthair staidéar a dhíríonn ar éagsúlacht na ngléasanna croí-thorthaí i mbunchainteanna Béarla TED agus téacsanna nuachta agus a n-aistriúcháin Gearmáinise. Agus úsáid á baint againn as teicníochtaí taiscéalaíochta déanaimid machnamh ar thacar ilghnéitheach de ghléasanna croí-chomhdhála mar ghnéithe a measaimid a léiríonn éagsúlacht teanga-shonrach agus bunaithe ar an gclár chomh maith le straitéisí aistriúcháin féideartha. Léiríonn ár dtorthaí na difríochtaí ar an dá thoise le héagsúlacht níos láidre de réir an chomhra ná mar a bhí idir teangacha. Trí idirghníomhaíochtaí a nochtadh idir cineál téacs agus éagsúlacht thrasteangach, is féidir leo feidhmchláir ilteangacha NLP a chur ar an eolas freisin, go háirithe aistriúchán meaisín.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Egy tanulmányt mutatunk be, amely az angol eredeti TED előadásokban és hírszövegekben és azok német fordításaiban a korreferenciális eszközök változatosságára összpontosít. Feltáró technikák alkalmazásával különböző coreferencia eszközök sorát tekintjük meg olyan funkcióként, amelyek feltételezésünk szerint nyelvspecifikus és regiszter alapú változásokat, valamint lehetséges fordítási stratégiákat jeleznek. Megállapításaink mindkét dimenzió különbségeit tükrözik, a nyelvek közötti nyilvántartási vonalak mentén nagyobb eltéréssel. A szövegtípus és a nyelvközi változatok közötti interakciók feltárásával többnyelvű NLP alkalmazásokat is tájékoztathatnak, különösen a gépi fordítást.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε μια μελέτη που επικεντρώνεται στην παραλλαγή των συνδεόμενων συσκευών σε πρωτότυπες ομιλίες και κείμενα ειδήσεων στα αγγλικά και τις γερμανικές μεταφράσεις τους. Χρησιμοποιώντας διερευνητικές τεχνικές εξετάζουμε ένα ποικίλο σύνολο συσκευών συγχορήγησης ως χαρακτηριστικά τα οποία υποθέτουμε ότι υποδεικνύουν γλωσσικές και μητρώες παραλλαγές καθώς και πιθανές μεταφραστικές στρατηγικές. Τα ευρήματά μας αντικατοπτρίζουν διαφορές και στις δύο διαστάσεις με μεγαλύτερη διακύμανση κατά μήκος των γραμμών του μητρώου από ό,τι μεταξύ των γλωσσών. Με την έκθεση αλληλεπιδράσεων μεταξύ του τύπου κειμένου και της γλωσσικής παραλλαγής, μπορούν επίσης να ενημερώσουν τις πολυγλωσσικές εφαρμογές και ιδιαίτερα τη μηχανική μετάφραση.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ აჩვენებთ სწავლა, რომელიც ინგლისური TED საუბარებში და ინფორმაციის ტექსტი და მათი გერმანური ტრანქციების განსხვავებაზე დავყენებთ. გამოყენებული ტექნექციების გამოყენება ჩვენ განსხვავებული მოწყობილობის სხვადასხვა სხვადასხვა მოწყობილობების შესახებ, რომლებიც ჩვენ ვფიქრობთ, რომ ენის სპექტიფიკური და რეგისტრისტ ჩვენი მონაცემები განსხვავებს ორივე განზომილებების განსხვავებაში, რომელიც უფრო ძლიერი განსხვავება რეგისტრის ხაზების განსხვავებაში, ვიდრე ენების ტექსტის ტიპის და კრესილენგურისტიკის განრავლების შესახებ, ისინი შეუძლიათ მრავალენგური NLP პროგრამების ინფორმაცია, განსაკუთრებით მაქსინური განაცვლა.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo uno studio incentrato sulla variazione dei dispositivi coreferenziali in inglese originale TED talks e testi di notizie e le loro traduzioni in tedesco. Utilizzando tecniche esplorative contempliamo una serie diversificata di dispositivi di coreferenza come caratteristiche che presumiamo indichino variazioni specifiche per la lingua e basate sul registro, nonché potenziali strategie di traduzione. I nostri risultati riflettono differenze su entrambe le dimensioni con variazioni più forti lungo le linee di registro che tra le lingue. Esponendo le interazioni tra tipo di testo e variazione cross-linguistica, possono anche informare le applicazioni di PNL multilingue, in particolare la traduzione automatica.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Біз ағылшын тіліндегі TED сөйлемелері мен жаңалық мәтіндері және олардың неміс аудармаларының түрлендірілігін зерттеуді таңдаймыз. Ескерту техникаларын қолдану үшін біз тілдердің ерекше және регистрациялық түрлендіру стратегияларына және потенциалдық аудару стратегияларына арналған түрлендіру құрылғыларының түрлендірілген қасиеттері Біздің табуларымыз тілдер арасындағы жолдар арасындағы күш айырмашылығымен екі өлшемдерде айырмашылығын көрсетеді. Мәтін түрі мен көп тілді айнымалылықтар арасындағы әріптерді көрсету арқылы олар бірнеше тілді NLP қолданбаларын, осылай-ақ машинаны аударуға болады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Mes pristatome tyrimą, kuriame daugiausia dėmesio skiriama koreferencinių prietaisų įvairovei anglų kalbų originaluose TED kalbose ir naujienų tekstuose bei jų vokiečių vertimuose. Naudodami tiriamuosius metodus, manome, kad įvairių koreferencinių prietaisų rinkinys yra savybės, kurios, kaip manome, rodo kalbos ir registro skirtumus bei galimas vertimo strategijas. Mūsų išvados atspindi abiejų matmenų skirtumus, kurie labiau skiriasi pagal registrą nei tarp kalbų. Išskleidžiant teksto tipo ir tarpkalbinių kintamųjų sąveiką, jos taip pat gali informuoti daugiakalbes NLP programas, ypač vertimą mašinomis.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Презентираме студија која се фокусира на варијацијата на кореференцијалните уреди во англиските оригинални TED разговори и вести и нивните германски преведувања. Користејќи експлоаторни техники, размислуваме за различни уреди за кореференција како карактеристики кои претпоставуваме дека покажуваат јазик-специфична и регистарска варијација, како и потенцијални стратегии за превод. Нашите откритија ги одразуваат разликите на двете димензии со посилна варијација по линиите на регистарот отколку помеѓу јазиците. Со изложување на интеракциите помеѓу текстовиот тип и прекујазичната варијација, тие, исто така, можат да информираат и мултијазички НЛП апликации, особено машински превод.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami memperkenalkan sebuah kajian yang fokus pada variasi peranti coreferential dalam perbincangan TED asal bahasa Inggeris dan teks berita dan terjemahan Jerman mereka. Dengan menggunakan teknik esploratori kami mempertimbangkan set berbeza peranti persamaan sebagai ciri-ciri yang kami anggap menunjukkan variasi bahasa-spesifik dan berdasarkan daftar serta strategi terjemahan potensi. Kesemuan kita mencerminkan perbezaan pada kedua-dua dimensi dengan variasi yang lebih kuat sepanjang garis register daripada antara bahasa. Dengan mengekspos interaksi antara jenis teks dan variasi saling bahasa, mereka juga boleh maklumkan aplikasi NLP berbilang bahasa, terutama terjemahan mesin.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mn>Бид Англи хэлний эхний TED-ийн яриа, мэдээллийн текст, герман хэлбэрийн төхөөрөмжүүдийг төвлөрүүлсэн судалгааг үзүүлсэн. Судалгааны техникуудыг ашиглан бид олон төрлийн зэрэгцээний төхөөрөмжүүдийг хэлний тодорхой, регистрийн үндсэн өөрчлөлт болон потенциал орчуулах стратеги гэж үздэг. Бидний ололтууд хэлний хоорондоос илүү хүчтэй өөрчлөлтийг харуулдаг. Текст төрлийн болон гишүүн хэлний өөрчлөлтийн хоорондын харилцааны харилцааныг илэрхийлж, тэд мөн олон хэлний NLP хэрэглэмжүүдийг, ялангуяа машин орчуулах боломжтой болно.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ml>ഇംഗ്ലീഷിലെ ആദ്യമായ ടെഡി സംസാരം, വാര്‍ത്തകാര്‍ത്തകള്‍, ജര്‍മ്മന്‍ ഭാഷകങ്ങള്‍ എന്നിവയുടെ മാറ്റങ്ങളില്‍ നാം ഒരു പഠിപ്പ പരിശോധന സാങ്കേതികവിദ്യ ഉപകരണങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ച് നമ്മള്‍ വ്യത്യസ്തമായ ഒരു കോര്‍ഫെന്‍സ് ഉപകരണങ്ങളെക്കുറിച്ച് ചിന്തിക്കുന്നു. ഭാഷ- പ്രത്യേക വിഭ Our findings reflect differences on both dimensions with stronger variation along the lines of register than between languages.  ടെക്സ്റ്റ് ടൈപ്പിന്റെയും ക്രിസ്റ്റിഗ്ലിസ്റ്റിക്ക് മാറ്റങ്ങള്‍ക്കുമിടയിലുള്ള ഇടപാടുകള്‍ വെളിപ്പെടുത്തുന</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nippreżentaw studju li jiffoka fuq il-varjazzjoni tal-apparat koreferenti fit-taħditiet oriġinali tal-Ingliż tat-TED u t-testi tal-a ħbarijiet u t-traduzzjonijiet Ġermaniżi tagħhom. Bl-użu ta’ tekniki esploratorji qed nikkunsidraw sett diversifikat ta’ apparati ta’ koreferenza bħala karatteristiċi li tassumi li jindikaw varjazzjoni speċifika għal-lingwa u bbażata fuq ir-reġistru kif ukoll strateġiji potenzjali ta’ traduzzjoni. Is-sejbiet tagħna jirriflettu d-differenzi fiż-żewġ dimensjonijiet b’varjazzjoni aktar b’saħħitha fuq il-linji tar-reġistru milli bejn il-lingwi. Billi jesponu interazzjonijiet bejn it-tip ta’ test u varjazzjoni translingwistika, jistgħu jinfurmaw ukoll applikazzjonijiet NLP multilingwi, speċjalment it-traduzzjoni bil-magna.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer ein studie som fokuserer på variasjonar av koreferensielle einingar i engelsk originale TED-snakk og nyhetstekstar og tysk oversettelsar. I bruk av utforskingstekningar ser vi på eit forskjellig set av koreferansjeeiningar som funksjonar som vi antar å indisera variasjonar med språk spesifisert og registrert basert på registrering, og potensielle omsetjingsstrategiar. Finningane våre gjeld forskjeller på begge dimensjonar med sterkere variasjonar langs registreringane enn mellom språk. Ved å eksponera interaksjonar mellom teksttypen og cross-linguistic variasjonar kan dei også informere fleirspråk NLP-program, spesielt maskinsomsetjing.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Prezentujemy opracowanie skupiające się na odmianie urządzeń współdzielnych w angielskich oryginalnych wykładach TED i tekstach wiadomości oraz ich tłumaczeniach niemieckich. Za pomocą technik eksploracyjnych rozważamy zróżnicowany zestaw urządzeń współreferencyjnych jako cechy, które zakładamy, wskazują na specyficzne dla języka i rejestru zmiany oraz potencjalne strategie tłumaczenia. Nasze ustalenia odzwierciedlają różnice w obu wymiarach z większą różnicą wzdłuż linii rejestru niż między językami. Ujawniając interakcje między typem tekstu a między różnymi językami, mogą one również informować wielojęzyczne aplikacje NLP, zwłaszcza tłumaczenia maszynowe.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo studiju fokusiranu na varijaciju koreferencijalnih uređaja na engleskom originalnom TED pregovorima i vestima i njihovim njemačkim prevodima. Koristeći istraživačke tehnike, razmišljamo o različitim setima dobrodošlih uređaja kao karakteristike koje pretpostavljamo ukazuju na različite varijacije jezika specifične i registrirane, kao i potencijalne strategije prevoda. Naši nalazi odražavaju razlike na obje dimenzije sa jačim varijacijom duž linija registracije nego između jezika. Izložavajući interakcije između tipa teksta i međujezičke varijacije, oni mogu takođe obavijestiti multijezičke aplikacije NLP, posebno prevod mašine.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ro>Prezentăm un studiu axat pe variația dispozitivelor corefențiale în discuțiile TED originale și textele de știri în limba engleză și traducerile lor în limba germană. Folosind tehnici de explorare, contemplăm un set divers de dispozitive de corefență ca caracteristici pe care presupunem că indică variațiile specifice limbii și bazate pe registre, precum și potențiale strategii de traducere. Constatările noastre reflectă diferențe la ambele dimensiuni, cu variații mai puternice de-a lungul liniilor de registru decât între limbi. Expunând interacțiunile dintre tipul de text și variațiile interlingvistice, acestea pot informa, de asemenea, aplicațiile PNL multilingve, în special traducerea automată.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>We present a study focusing on variation of coreferential devices in English original TED talks and news texts and their German translations.  Isticmaalka qalabka baaritaanka waxaynu ka fiirsanaynaa qalabo kala duduwan oo ah qalabka caafimaadka, kaas oo aynu ka malaynaynaa inay muuqato bedelka luqada ee gaarka ah iyo qoraalka iyo qoraalka turjumidda. Faahritaankeenu waxay ka muuqataa kala duwan labada dhinac oo ay ku kala duwan yihiin iskumarka diiwaangelinta inta ay kala duwan yihiin luuqadaha. Sidoo kale waxay sidoo kale ogeysiin karaan codsiga NLP luuqadaha kala duduwan, khusuusan tarjumaadda machine.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>අපි ඉංග්‍රීසියේ ප්‍රධාන කතාවක් සහ වාර්තාවක් සඳහා අධ්‍යානයක් පෙන්වන්නේ ඉංග්‍රීසියාවේ අධ්‍යානය පරීක්ෂණ විද්‍යාව භාවිතා කරන්න අපි හිතන්නේ විවිදිහට කෝරෙෆරෙන්ස් උපකරණ සෙට් විවිදිහට සඳහා භාෂාව විශේෂ සහ ලැයිස්ත අපේ හොයාගන්නේ භාෂාවට වඩා වඩා බලයි වෙනස් තියෙන වෙනස් දෙන්නම් පරික්ෂා කරනවා. පාළ වර්ගය සහ විශාල භාෂාවික වෙනස් අතර සම්බන්ධ විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියා කරන්න පුළුවන් ඔවුන්ට වඩා භාෂාව</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar en studie med fokus på variation av coreferenzial devices i engelska original TED talks och nyhetstexter samt deras tyska översättningar. Med hjälp av utforskande tekniker överväger vi en mängd olika coreferenceenheter som funktioner som vi antar indikerar språkspecifik och registerbaserad variation samt potentiella översättningsstrategier. Våra resultat återspeglar skillnader på båda dimensionerna med större variation längs registerlinjerna än mellan språk. Genom att avslöja interaktioner mellan texttyp och tvärspråklig variation kan de också informera flerspråkiga NLP-applikationer, särskilt maskinöversättning.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாங்கள் ஒரு ஆராய்ச்சி கொண்டிருக்கிறோம் ஆங்கிலத்தில் மாறுபாடுகளின் மூல TED பேச்சுகள் மற்றும் செய்தி உரைகள் மற்ற தேடும் தொழில்நுட்பங்களை பயன்படுத்தி நாம் பல்வேறு குறிப்பிட்ட சாதனங்களை குணங்களாக கருதுகிறோம். இதை நாம் கருதுகிறோம் மொழி- குறிப்பிட்ட Our findings reflect differences on both dimensions with stronger variation along the lines of register than between languages.  உரை வகையில் மற்றும் மொழி மாறுபாடுகளுக்கிடையே இடையேயுள்ள இடைவெளிப்படுத்தல் மூலம் அவர்கள் பல மொழி NLP பயன்பாடுகள், குறிப்ப</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم ایک مطالعہ پیش کرتے ہیں جو انگلیسی کی اصلی TED کلمات اور خبروں کے پیغام اور ان کے جرمانی ترجمہ پر تغییرات کی تغییرات کی تغییرات پر تمرکز کرتا ہے۔ تحقیق تکنیک کے مطابق ہم نے ایک مختلف مجموعہ کے مطابق مختلف مطابق مطابق مطابق طریقوں کے طور پر نظر رکھا ہے جن کو ہم سمجھتے ہیں کہ زبان کے مطابق اور رسیسٹر کی بنیادی تغییر اور امکانات ترجمہ استراتژیات کی ہمارے پیدا کرنے والے دونوں اندازوں میں مختلف ہیں جو زبانوں کے درمیان سے زیادہ طاقتور مختلف ہیں ٹیکسٹ کیپ اور کرس-زبان کی تغییرات کے درمیان تغییرات کے ذریعہ سے وہ بہت سی زبان کی NLP کاربرد بھی بتائیں گے، مخصوصاً ماشین ترجمہ کے ذریعہ۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>We present a study focusing on variation of coreferential devices in English original TED talks and news texts and their German translations.  Biz bir necha xizmatlardan foydalanuvchi texnologiyadan foydalanib, biz o'ylaymiz, har xil tarjima imkoniyatlarini va oddiy tarjima qilish strategiyasini ko'rsatumiz. Bizning natijalarimiz ikkita darajada o'zgarishlarni o'zgartiradi va o'zlar orasidagi bo'ylab ko'proq o'zgarishlar bilan ko'rinadi. Name</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi giới thiệu một nghiên cứu tập trung vào sự biến đổi của các thiết bị giám sát trong những buổi thảo luận bằng tin ở Anh Quốc và bản dịch Đức. Sử dụng các kỹ thuật thăm dò, chúng tôi xem xét một loạt các thiết bị khả năng hạn chế khác nhau như các tính năng mà chúng tôi giả sử chỉ ra các biến đổi ngôn ngữ cụ thể và quy trình. Những nghiên cứu của chúng tôi phản ánh sự khác nhau về cả hai chiều, với những thay đổi mạnh hơn theo dòng đăng ký hơn là giữa các ngôn ngữ. Bằng cách phơi bày sự tương tác giữa kiểu văn bản và biến đổi ngôn ngữ khác nhau, họ cũng có thể cung cấp ngôn ngữ đa dạng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме проучване, фокусирано върху вариацията на кореференциалните устройства в английските оригинални TED беседи и новинарски текстове и техните немски преводи. Използвайки изследователски техники, ние разглеждаме разнообразен набор от устройства за кореференция като характеристики, които предполагаме, че показват специфични за езика и регистъра вариации, както и потенциални стратегии за превод. Нашите констатации отразяват различията и в двете измерения с по-голяма вариация по линията на регистъра, отколкото между езиците. Чрез разкриване на взаимодействията между типа на текста и междулингвистичните вариации те могат да информират и многоезичните приложения за НЛП, особено машинния превод.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer en undersøgelse med fokus på variation af coreferencial devices i engelske originale TED foredrag og nyhedstekster og deres tyske oversættelser. Ved hjælp af eksperimenterende teknikker overvejer vi en bred vifte af coreference enheder som funktioner, som vi antager indikerer sprogspecifikke og registerbaserede variationer samt potentielle oversættelsesstrategier. Vores resultater afspejler forskelle på begge dimensioner med stærkere variation langs registerlinjerne end mellem sprogene. Ved at afsløre interaktioner mellem teksttype og tværsproget variation kan de også informere flersprogede NLP-applikationer, især maskinoversættelse.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren een studie gericht op variatie van coreferentiële apparaten in Engelse originele TED talks en nieuwsteksten en hun Duitse vertalingen. Met behulp van verkennende technieken beschouwen we een verscheidenheid aan coreferentieapparaten als kenmerken die we aannemen dat ze taalspecifieke en registergebaseerde variatie en potentiële vertaalstrategieën aangeven. Onze bevindingen weerspiegelen verschillen op beide dimensies met sterkere variatie langs registerlijnen dan tussen talen. Door interacties tussen teksttype en cross-linguïstische variatie bloot te leggen, kunnen ze ook meertalige NLP-toepassingen informeren, met name machinevertaling.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 영어의 원래 TED 강연과 뉴스 텍스트, 그리고 독일어 번역 중의 손가락질 수단의 변화에 중점을 두고 연구를 제기했다.탐색적 기술을 이용하여 우리는 일련의 서로 다른 공지 수단을 구상했다. 우리가 가설한 특징으로서 이러한 특징은 언어가 특정하고 어역을 바탕으로 하는 변이와 잠재적인 번역 전략을 나타냈다.우리의 발견은 두 차원의 차이를 반영하고 언어 영역에서의 차이가 언어 간의 차이보다 더 크다.텍스트 유형과 다중 언어 변이 사이의 상호작용을 제시함으로써 다중 언어 NLP 응용 프로그램, 특히 기계 번역에 정보를 제공할 수 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>Wir stellen eine Studie vor, die sich mit der Variation von Coreferenzial Devices in englischen Original TED Talks und Nachrichtentexten sowie deren deutschen Übersetzungen befasst. Mit explorativen Techniken betrachten wir eine Vielzahl von Coreferenz-Geräten als Merkmale, von denen wir annehmen, dass sie sprachspezifische und registerbasierte Variationen sowie mögliche Übersetzungsstrategien anzeigen. Unsere Ergebnisse spiegeln Unterschiede in beiden Dimensionen wider, mit stärkeren Variationen entlang der Registerlinien als zwischen den Sprachen. Durch die Aufdeckung von Interaktionen zwischen Texttyp und sprachübergreifender Variation können sie auch mehrsprachige NLP-Anwendungen, insbesondere maschinelle Übersetzungen, unterstützen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>We present a study focusing on variation of coreferential devices in English original TED talks and news texts and their German translations.  Menggunakan teknik eksplorasi kami mempertimbangkan set berbagai perangkat koreferensi sebagai fitur yang kami asumsikan menunjukkan variasi spesifik bahasa dan berdasarkan register serta strategi terjemahan potensial. Penemuan kita mencerminkan perbedaan pada kedua dimensi dengan variasi yang lebih kuat sepanjang garis register daripada antara bahasa. Dengan mengekspos interaksi antara tipe teks dan variasi saling bahasa, mereka juga dapat memberitahu aplikasi NLP berbagai bahasa, terutama terjemahan mesin.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_tr>Biz iňlis dilinde TED-iňlisçe gürrüňler, täzelikler we olaryň nemesçe terjimelerinde näçe ajaýyp janlaşyklaryna üns berýäris. exploratory tekniklerden ullanýan, çykyş düzümlerni üýtgeşmeleri we bellenen terjime stratejiklerini görkez diýip pikir edýäris. Çaplamalarymyz dilleriň arasynda çykyşlyklar bilen düýbünden has güýçli üýtgeşmeler. Metin hili we cross-linguistic çeşitleri arasynda faýllary açarak, olar köp dilli NLP uygulamalaryny, özellikle maşynyň terjimesini biljek bolýarlar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Tunajaribu utafiti unaohusisha mabadiliko ya vifaa vya msingi katika mazungumzo ya asili ya TED na ujumbe wa habari na tafsiri zao za Kijerumani. Kwa kutumia mbinu za uchunguzi tunafikiria aina mbalimbali za vifaa vya mafanikio kama vipengele ambavyo tunadhani inaonyesha mabadiliko ya lugha maalum na yenye usajili pamoja na mikakati ya tafsiri. Matokeo yetu yanaonyesha tofauti katika vipande viwili vikiwa na tofauti kubwa zaidi katika mistari ya uandikishaji kuliko kati ya lugha. Kwa kuonyesha mahusiano kati ya aina ya maandishi na mabadiliko ya lugha mbalimbali, wanaweza pia kutoa taarifa zana za lugha mbalimbali, hususani tafsiri ya mashine.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>ما یک مطالعه را نشان می دهیم که روی تغییرات دستگاه‌های مربوط به انگلیسی در صحبت اصلی TED و متن‌های خبری و ترجمه‌های آلمانی آنها تمرکز می‌کند. با استفاده از تکنیک‌های تحقیق، یک مجموعه از دستگاه‌های مختلف تحقیق را به عنوان ویژگی‌هایی که ما تصور می‌کنیم تغییرات متفاوت‌های زبان و بنیاد ثبت‌کننده و استراتژی‌های ترجمه پتانسیل را نشان می‌دهیم. پیدا کردن ما تفاوت در هر دوی بعدی با تفاوت قوی تر در خطوط ثبت از بین زبانها نشان می دهند. با توجه به تعاملات بین نوع متن و تغییرات متفاوتی زبان، آنها می توانند همچنین کاربردهای NLP متعددی را اطلاع دهند، مخصوصاً ترجمه ماشین.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_am>በንግግሊዝኛ አዋቂው የቴድ ንግግር እና የዜና ጽሑፎች እና የጀርመን ትርጓሜዎቻቸውን በመለወጥ ላይ የሚቆጣውን ትምህርት እናደርጋለን፡፡ የቋንቋ-specific እና የመዝገብ ቃላት እና የቻይነት ትርጉም strategie እናሳውቃለን፡፡ ፍጥረታችን ከቋንቋዎች መካከል ይልቅ የበረታች ልዩነትን በሁለቱ ልዩነት ላይ ይለያያል፡፡ የጽሑፍ ዓይነት እና የቋንቋ ቋንቋ መለያየት መካከል ግንኙነት በመግለጥ፣ በተለይም መሳሳይ ትርጉም በቋንቋዎች የNLP ፕሮግራሞች እንዲያስታውቁ ይችላሉ።</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>Ons stel 'n studie wat fokus op veranderinge van koreferensiele toestelle in Engels oorspronklike TED praat en nuustekste en hulle Duitse vertalings. Deur te gebruik ondersoek-teknike, ondersoek ons 'n verskeie stel van koreferensie-toestelle as funksies wat ons aanvaar om taal-spesifieke en registrasie-gebaseerde variasie te wys en potensieele vertaling-strategies te wys. Ons vindings reflekteer verskille op beide dimensies met sterker variasie langs die lyne van registrasie as tussen tale. Deur interaksies tussen teks tipe en kruislingwisiese veranderinge te eksponer, kan hulle ook multitaalse NLP-toepassings, veral masjien vertaling inlig.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hr>Predstavljamo studiju usredotočenu na varijaciju koreferencijalnih uređaja na engleskom originalnom TED pregovorima i tekstima novina i njihovim njemačkim prevodima. Koristeći istraživačke tehnike razmišljamo o različitim skupinama uređaja za pristojnost kao karakteristike koje pretpostavljamo ukazuju na različite varijacije jezika specifične i registrirane, kao i potencijalne strategije prevoda. Naši nalazi odražavaju razlike na obje dimenzije sa jačim varijacijom duž linija registracije nego između jezika. Izložavajući interakcije između tipa teksta i cross-linguisticke varijacije, mogu također obavijestiti multijezičke primjene NLP, posebno prevod stroja.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_az>Biz ńįngilis dilind…ô m…ônb…ôzi TED danńĪŇümalarńĪ, x…ôb…ôr m…ôtnl…ôrini v…ô AlmancńĪlarńĪ t…ôrc√ľm…ôl…ôrind…ô m√ľxt…ôlif m…ôlumatlarńĪnńĪ t…ôŇükil edirik. AraŇütńĪrma teknikl…ôrind…ôn istifad…ô edirik ki, dil m√ľ…ôyy…ôn edilmiŇü, register-based d…ôyiŇüiklikl…ôri v…ô potensial terc√ľm…ô stratejil…ôrini g√∂st…ôrdik. Bizim tapńĪlarńĪmńĪz dill…ôrin arasńĪndan daha q√ľvv…ôtli d…ôyiŇüiklikl…ôri il…ô h…ôr iki √∂l√ß√ľd…ô f…ôrql…ôndirir. M…ôtn t√ľr√ľ v…ô √ßox dil d…ôyiŇüiklikl…ôri arasńĪndakńĪ m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôŇükil g√∂st…ôrm…ôkl…ô, √ßoxlu dil NLP uyńüulamalarńĪnńĪ da bildir…ô bil…ôrl…ôr, √∂zl…ôrin…ô d…ô maŇüńĪn √ßevirimi.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা একটি গবেষণা উপস্থাপন করেছি ইংরেজি প্রকৃত টেডি কথা এবং সংবাদ লেখা এবং তাদের জার্মান অনুবাদের বিভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন বিভিন্ন ধরনের কোরেফারেন্স ডিভাইস হিসেবে আমরা বিভিন্ন ধরনের প্রযুক্তি ব্যবহার করি যা আমরা ধারণা করি ভাষার নির্দিষ্ট ভিত্তিক ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন আমাদের আবিস্কার ভাষার মধ্যে ভাষার চেয়ে শক্তিশালী পার্থক্যের সাথে প্রতিফলিত হয়েছে। টেক্সট টাইপ এবং ক্রস-ভাষার ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন প্রকাশের মাধ্যমে তারা বহুভাষায় এনএলপি অ্যাপ্লিকেশন সম্পর্কে জ</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo studiju usredotočenu na varijaciju koreferencijalnih uređaja na engleskom originalnom TED pregovorima i tekstima novina i njihovim njemačkim prevodima. Koristeći istraživačke tehnike, razmišljamo o različitim setu dobrodošlih uređaja kao karakteristike koje pretpostavljamo ukazuju na različite varijacije jezika specifične i registrirane, kao i potencijalne strategije prevoda. Naši nalazi odražavaju razlike na obje dimenzije sa jačim varijacijom duž linija registracije nego između jezika. Izložavajući interakcije između tipa teksta i cross-linguisticke varijacije, oni mogu također obavijestiti multijezičke aplikacije NLP, posebno prevod stroja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme studii zaměřené na variaci koreferenčních zařízení v anglických originálních TED přednáškách a zpravodajských textech a jejich německých překladech. Pomocí průzkumných technik uvažujeme o různorodé sadě koreferenčních zařízení jako o funkcích, které předpokládáme, že indikují jazykovou a registrovanou variaci a potenciální překladové strategie. Naše zjištění odrážejí rozdíly v obou dimenzích s větší variací podle linií registru než mezi jazyky. Odhalením interakcí mezi textovým typem a mezijazykovou variací mohou také informovat vícejazyčné aplikace NLP, zejména strojový překlad.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Tutvustame uuringut, mis keskendub inglise keelsete TED-kõnede ja uudistekirjade ning nende saksakeelsete tõlkete erinevustele. Uurivate tehnikate abil kaalume erinevaid koreferentsiseadmeid kui omadusi, mis eeldame, et viitavad keelele ja registripõhisele variatsioonile ning võimalikele tõlkestrateegiatele. Meie tulemused kajastavad erinevusi mõlemas mõõtmes, kus registri jooksul varieerub rohkem kui keelte vahel. Avastades teksti tüübi ja keeleülese variatsiooni vastastikuse mõju, saavad nad teavitada ka mitmekeelseid uue tööprogrammi rakendusi, eriti masintõlke.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esitämme tutkimuksen, jossa keskitytään englanninkielisten alkuperäisten TED-puheiden ja uutistekstien sekä niiden saksankielisten käännösten väliseen vaihteluun. Tutkimusmenetelmien avulla tarkastelemme erilaisia koreferenssilaitteita ominaisuuksina, joiden oletetaan osoittavan kielikohtaista ja rekisteripohjaista vaihtelua sekä mahdollisia käännösstrategioita. Tuloksemme heijastavat eroja molemmissa ulottuvuuksissa, ja rekisterissä on enemmän vaihtelua kuin kielissä. Ne voivat myös hyödyntää monikielisiä NLP-sovelluksia, erityisesti konekääntämistä, paljastamalla tekstityypin ja monikielisen vaihtelun vuorovaikutukset.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>Presentam un estudi centrat en la variació dels dispositius coreferents en les xerrades originals angleses TED i els textos de notícies i les seves traduccions alemanes. Utilitzant tècniques exploratories, considerem un conjunt divers de dispositius de referència com característiques que suposem indicar variacions específices per llenguatge i per registre, així com estratègies de traducció potencials. Els nostres descobriments reflecteixen diferències en ambdues dimensions amb una variació més forta a la línia del registre que entre les llengües. Expondant interaccions entre el tipus de text i la variació translingüística, també poden informar aplicacions NLP multilingües, especialment traducció automàtica.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim një studim që përqëndrohet në variacionin e pajisjeve koreferenciale në bisedimet origjinale angleze të TED dhe tekstet e lajmeve dhe përkthimet e tyre gjermane. Duke përdorur teknika eksploruese ne konsiderojmë një sërë të ndryshme paisjesh koreference si karakteristika të cilat supozojmë që tregojnë variacion specifik gjuhës dhe bazuar në regjistër si dhe strategji të mundshme përkthimi. Our findings reflect differences on both dimensions with stronger variation along the lines of register than between languages.  Duke ekspozuar ndërveprimet midis tipit të tekstit dhe variacionit ndër-gjuhësor, ato mund të informojnë gjithashtu aplikimet shumëgjuhëse NLP, veçanërisht përkthimin e makinave.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք ներկայացնում ենք մի ուսումնասիրություն, որը կենտրոնացնում է անգլերենի սկզբնական TED ելույթների, նորությունների տեքստների և նրանց գերմանացի թարգմանությունների բազմազանության վրա: Օգտագործելով ուսումնասիրության մեթոդներ, մենք դիտարկում ենք բազմազան համեմատական սարքեր որպես առանձնահատկություններ, որոնք ենթադրում ենք, ցույց են տալիս լեզվի կոնկրետ և ռեստորանների հիմնված տարբերությունները, ինչպես նաև պոտենցի Մեր հայտնաբերությունները արտացոլում են երկու չափումների տարբերությունները, որոնք ավելի ուժեղ տարբերություններ են կազմում լեզուների միջև: Տեքստի տեսակի և լեզվաբանական տարբերակների միջև փոխազդեցություններ բացահայտելով, նրանք կարող են նաև տեղեկացնել բազլեզու ՆԼՊ ծրագրեր, հատկապես մեքենային թարգմանություն:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé éntuk karo perusahaan sing nggambar dengané perangkat-perusahaan anyar tentang kanggo nggawe tarjamahan karo texti alam lan pitik-alam kuwi alam kuwi. Packages string" in "context_BAR_stringWrap Ngawe ngilanggar gerakan seneng perusahaan anyar tentang karo akeh lan karo pak-pakan langgar, iki iso nggawe aplikasi NLP uga tindang, supoyo akeh tarjamahan karo sistem.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo študijo, ki se osredotoča na variacijo koreferencialnih naprav v angleških izvirnih TED govorih in novinarskih besedilih ter njihovih nemških prevodih. Z raziskovalnimi tehnikami razmišljamo o raznolikem naboru koreferenčnih naprav kot značilnosti, za katere domnevamo, da kažejo na jezikovno specifično in registrsko spreminjanje ter potencialne strategije prevajanja. Naše ugotovitve odražajo razlike v obeh dimenzijah z močnejšimi razlikami v registrskih smereh kot med jeziki. Z razkrivanjem interakcij med vrsto besedila in medjezikovnimi različicami lahko uporabljajo tudi večjezične aplikacije NLP, zlasti strojno prevajanje.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna halatar da wani littafi wanda ke muhalli da variant na kayan aiki na daban-nau'i cikin Ingiriya masu maganar TeD da littafan lãbãri da fassararsu na jeruman. Yi amfani da masu motsi masu amfani da shiryoyin ayuka ko-nau'i, ko kuma misãlai masu fassarar da shirin ayuka ko da misalin mu na zato, za'a nũna canza variance-cikin-harshe-ƙayyade da aka rubũta shi da zane-fassarar masu yiwuwa. MataimakinMu sunã yin sãɓãni a kan duffai biyu da variant mai tsanani sunan rubũtarwa ko kuwa tsakanin harshe. Ga su bayyana interaction between nau'in text and variant-nau'in-linguistic, sai su iya sanar da shiryoyin ayuka na NLP masu yawa da hususan fassarar maɓalli.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו מציגים מחקר שמתמקד על שינוי של מכשירים משמעותיים בשיחות TED המקוריות באנגלית וטקסטים חדשות והתרגומות הגרמניות שלהם. באמצעות טכניקות חקירה אנו מתחשבים על קבוצה מיוחדת של מכשירי התאמה כתכונות שאנחנו מניחים שמצביעים על שונות ספציפיות לשפה ובסמכות רשומות, כמו גם אסטרטגיות תורגם פוטנציאליות. הממצאים שלנו משקפים הבדלים בשני המימדים עם שונות חזקות יותר לאורך קווי הרשום מאשר בין שפות. על ידי חשיפה של אינטראקציות בין סוג טקסט לבין השינויים הצלביים, הם יכולים גם להודיע ליישומים רבים של NLP, במיוחד התרגום מכונת.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་དབྱིན་ཡིག་གཟུགས་འགྱུར་བའི་སྒེར་གྱི་ནང་དུ་གཏོང་འཕྲིན་དང་བརྡ་ཚིག་དང་ཁོང་ཚོའི་སྐད་ཡིག Using exploratory techniques we contemplate a diverse set of coreference devices as features which we assume indicate language-specific and register-based variation as well as potential translation strategies. ང་ཚོའི་རྩ་འབྲས་ཐེངས་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ཆེ་ཆུང་དང་སྐད་རིགས་དབར་གྱི་འབྲི་བ་དང་ཁྱད་པར ཡིག་གི་དབྱེ་བ་དང་སྐད་རིགས་ལ་བསྟུན་ནས་དབྱེ་སྟངས་འདྲ་བ་དང་བསྟུན་ནས་དབྱེ་བ་མང་པོ་ཞིག་གི་NLP་ཉེར་སྤྱོད་དང་ཁྱད་</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>