<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nlposs">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of Second Workshop for NLP Open Source Software (NLP-OSS)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Eunjeong L.</first><last>Park</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Masato</first><last>Hagiwara</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dmitrijs</first><last>Milajevs</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nelson F.</first><last>Liu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Geeticka</first><last>Chauhan</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Liling</first><last>Tan</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ba8bcc58">2020.nlposs-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlposs-2020-nlp</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>End-to-end NLP Pipelines in Rust<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Pipelines in Rust</title>
      <author><first>Guillaume</first><last>Becquin</last></author>
      <pages>20–25</pages>
      <abstract>The recent progress in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a> research has been supported by the development of a rich open source ecosystem in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)">Python</a>. Libraries allowing NLP practitioners but also non-specialists to leverage state-of-the-art models have been instrumental in the democratization of this technology. The maturity of the open-source NLP ecosystem however varies between languages. This work proposes a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software">open-source library</a> aimed at bringing state-of-the-art <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rust_(programming_language)">Rust</a>. Rust is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systems_programming">systems programming language</a> for which the foundations required to build machine learning applications are available but still lacks ready-to-use, end-to-end NLP libraries. The proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_(computing)">library</a>, rust-bert, implements modern language models and ready-to-use pipelines (for example <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation">translation</a> or summarization). This allows further development by the Rust community from both NLP experts and non-specialists. It is hoped that this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_(computing)">library</a> will accelerate the development of the NLP ecosystem in Rust. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_(computing)">library</a> is under active development and available at https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract>
      <url hash="ab1aeb36">2020.nlposs-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlposs-1.4</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939741" />
      <bibkey>becquin-2020-end</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert" additional="false">guillaume-be/rust-bert</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/squad">SQuAD</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/sst">SST</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>خطوط أنابيب البرمجة اللغوية العصبية من طرف إلى طرف في الصدأ</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Pipelines de PNL de ponta a ponta em Rust</title_pt>
      <title_es>Canalizaciones de PNL de extremo a extremo en R</title_es>
      <title_ja>錆びたエンドツーエンドのNLPパイプライン</title_ja>
      <title_zh>Rust 中端至端 NLP 管道</title_zh>
      <title_hi>जंग में एंड-टू-एंड एनएलपी पाइपलाइनें</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Píblínte NLP ceann go ceann i meirge</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Végtől végig terjedő NLP csővezetékek rozsdában</title_hu>
      <title_el>Ολόκληροι αγωγοί σε σκουριά</title_el>
      <title_it>Tubi PNL end-to-end in ruggine</title_it>
      <title_kk>Аяқтау- аяқтау NLP пипелиндері</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Nuo galo į galą NLP vamzdynai Rust</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Крај до крај на NLP цевките во Раст</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Saluran NLP akhir-akhir dalam Rust</title_ms>
      <title_ml>റൂസ്റ്റിലെ NLP പൈപ്പെലിനുകള്‍ അവസാനിക്കുക</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Pipelines NLP f’Rust minn tmiem sa tmiem</title_mt>
      <title_mn>НЛП-ын төгсгөлд дуусахад</title_mn>
      <title_no>Slutt til slutt NLP- piksler i rust</title_no>
      <title_pl>Kompleksowe rurociągi NLP w rdzy</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Kraj do kraja NLP Pipeline u Rustu</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Conducte PNL end-to-end în rugină</title_ro>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>NLP Pipelines in Rust</title_so>
      <title_sv>Slut-till-slut NLP-rörledningar i rost</title_sv>
      <title_ur>روس میں NLP پیپیپیلین</title_ur>
      <title_ta>Comment</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Đường ống chính ở Rust</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Нефтопроводи от край до край в Ръст</title_bg>
      <title_da>End-to-end NLP-rørledninger i rust</title_da>
      <title_nl>End-to-end NLP pijpleidingen in roest</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Kraj do kraja NLP pipeline u Rustu</title_hr>
      <title_de>End-to-End NLP Pipelines in Rost</title_de>
      <title_fa>پایان پایان NLP Pipelines in Rust</title_fa>
      <title_ko>끝에서 끝까지 NLP 파이프 녹 슬기</title_ko>
      <title_id>Pipeline NLP dari akhir ke akhir dalam Rust</title_id>
      <title_sw>Makosa ya NLP ya mwisho nchini Rust</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Rust çe NLP Pipelini iň soňunda</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Pipelines NLP në Rust nga fundi në fund</title_sq>
      <title_af>End- to- end NLP Pipelines in Rust</title_af>
      <title_am>undo-type</title_am>
      <title_hy>Վերջ-վերջ ՆԼՊ խողովակաշարերը Ռաստում</title_hy>
      <title_az>Rust'da NLP Pipelini son-to-end</title_az>
      <title_bn>রুস্টের NLP পাইপেলাইন শেষ- থেকে শেষ</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Kraj do kraja NLP Pipeline u Rustu</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Pipelines NLP de final a final a Rust</title_ca>
      <title_cs>End-to-end NLP trubky v rezi</title_cs>
      <title_et>NLP-torustikud Rustis</title_et>
      <title_fi>Rustin NLP-putkistot</title_fi>
      <title_jv>End-to-end NLP Pipiline in Rust</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_he>צינורות NLP בסוף עד הסוף ברסט</title_he>
      <title_sk>Cevovodi iz konca do konca NLP v Rust</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Rust ནང་དུ་མཐའ་མཇུག་བསྡུ་ཡོད་པའི་NLP འོག་སྣོད</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تم دعم التقدم الأخير في أبحاث معالجة اللغة الطبيعية من خلال تطوير نظام بيئي غني مفتوح المصدر في Python. المكتبات التي تسمح لممارسي البرمجة اللغوية العصبية ولكن أيضًا غير المتخصصين بالاستفادة من أحدث النماذج كانت مفيدة في إضفاء الطابع الديمقراطي على هذه التكنولوجيا. ومع ذلك ، فإن نضج النظام البيئي مفتوح المصدر للغة البرمجة اللغوية العصبية يختلف بين اللغات. يقترح هذا العمل مكتبة جديدة مفتوحة المصدر تهدف إلى جلب أحدث تقنيات البرمجة اللغوية العصبية إلى Rust. Rust هي لغة برمجة أنظمة تتوفر لها الأسس المطلوبة لبناء تطبيقات التعلم الآلي ولكنها لا تزال تفتقر إلى مكتبات البرمجة اللغوية العصبية الجاهزة للاستخدام والشاملة. تقوم المكتبة المقترحة ، Rust-bert ، بتنفيذ نماذج لغوية حديثة وخطوط أنابيب جاهزة للاستخدام (على سبيل المثال الترجمة أو التلخيص). هذا يسمح بمزيد من التطوير من قبل مجتمع Rust من كل من خبراء البرمجة اللغوية العصبية وغير المتخصصين. من المأمول أن تعمل هذه المكتبة على تسريع تطوير النظام البيئي لمعالجة اللغة الطبيعية في Rust. المكتبة قيد التطوير النشط ومتاحة على https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>El progreso reciente en la investigación del procesamiento del lenguaje natural se ha visto respaldado por el desarrollo de un rico ecosistema de código abierto en Python. Las bibliotecas que permiten a los profesionales de la PNL, pero también a los no especialistas, aprovechar los modelos más avanzados han sido fundamentales en la democratización de esta tecnología. Sin embargo, la madurez del ecosistema de PNL de código abierto varía según el idioma. Este trabajo propone una nueva biblioteca de código abierto destinada a llevar PNL de última generación a Rust. Rust es un lenguaje de programación de sistemas para el que están disponibles los fundamentos necesarios para crear aplicaciones de aprendizaje automático, pero aún carece de bibliotecas de PNL completas y listas para usar. La biblioteca propuesta, rust-bert, implementa modelos de lenguaje modernos y canales listos para usar (por ejemplo, traducción o resumen). Esto permite un mayor desarrollo por parte de la comunidad de Rust tanto por parte de expertos como no especialistas en PNL. Se espera que esta biblioteca acelere el desarrollo del ecosistema de PNL en Rust. La biblioteca se encuentra en desarrollo activo y está disponible en https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>O progresso recente na pesquisa de processamento de linguagem natural foi apoiado pelo desenvolvimento de um rico ecossistema de código aberto em Python. Bibliotecas que permitem que praticantes de PNL, mas também não especialistas, alavanquem modelos de última geração têm sido fundamentais para a democratização dessa tecnologia. A maturidade do ecossistema de PNL de código aberto, no entanto, varia entre os idiomas. Este trabalho propõe uma nova biblioteca de código aberto destinada a trazer o estado da arte da PNL para Rust. Rust é uma linguagem de programação de sistemas para a qual as bases necessárias para criar aplicativos de aprendizado de máquina estão disponíveis, mas ainda carece de bibliotecas NLP de ponta a ponta prontas para uso. A biblioteca proposta, rust-bert, implementa modelos de linguagem modernos e pipelines prontos para uso (por exemplo, tradução ou resumo). Isso permite um maior desenvolvimento pela comunidade Rust de especialistas e não especialistas em PNL. Espera-se que esta biblioteca acelere o desenvolvimento do ecossistema de PNL em Rust. A biblioteca está em desenvolvimento ativo e disponível em https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>自然言語処理研究の最近の進歩は、Pythonの豊富なオープンソースエコシステムの開発によってサポートされています。 NLPの実践者だけでなく、非専門家が最先端のモデルを活用できるようにする図書館は、この技術の民主化に役立ってきた。 しかし、オープンソースのNLPエコシステムの成熟度は言語によって異なります。 この作品は、最先端のNLPをRustに持ち込むことを目的とした新しいオープンソースのライブラリを提案している。 Rustは、機械学習アプリケーションを構築するために必要な基盤が利用可能ですが、すぐに使用できるエンドツーエンドのNLPライブラリが不足しているシステムプログラミング言語です。 提案されているライブラリであるRust - Bertは、近代的な言語モデルとすぐに使用できるパイプライン（翻訳や要約など）を実装しています。 これにより、NLPの専門家と非専門家の両方からのRustコミュニティによるさらなる開発が可能になります。 このライブラリが、RustにおけるNLPエコシステムの開発を加速することを期待しています。 ライブラリは積極的に開発されており、https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bertから入手できます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रसंस्करण अनुसंधान में हाल की प्रगति को पायथन में एक समृद्ध खुले स्रोत पारिस्थितिकी तंत्र के विकास द्वारा समर्थित किया गया है। एनएलपी चिकित्सकों को अनुमति देने वाले पुस्तकालयों, लेकिन गैर-विशेषज्ञों को अत्याधुनिक मॉडल का लाभ उठाने की अनुमति देने वाले पुस्तकालयों ने इस तकनीक के लोकतंत्रीकरण में महत्वपूर्ण भूमिका निभाई है। ओपन-सोर्स एनएलपी पारिस्थितिकी तंत्र की परिपक्वता हालांकि भाषाओं के बीच भिन्न होती है। यह काम एक नए ओपन-सोर्स लाइब्रेरी का प्रस्ताव करता है जिसका उद्देश्य राज्य के अत्याधुनिक एनएलपी को जंग में लाना है। जंग एक सिस्टम प्रोग्रामिंग भाषा है जिसके लिए मशीन लर्निंग एप्लिकेशन बनाने के लिए आवश्यक नींव उपलब्ध हैं, लेकिन फिर भी रेडी-टू-यूज, एंड-टू-एंड एनएलपी पुस्तकालयों का अभाव है। प्रस्तावित पुस्तकालय, जंग-बर्ट, आधुनिक भाषा मॉडल और उपयोग के लिए तैयार पाइपलाइनों (उदाहरण के लिए अनुवाद या सारांश) को लागू करता है। यह एनएलपी विशेषज्ञों और गैर-विशेषज्ञों दोनों से जंग समुदाय द्वारा आगे के विकास की अनुमति देता है। यह आशा की जाती है कि यह पुस्तकालय जंग में एनएलपी पारिस्थितिकी तंत्र के विकास में तेजी लाएगा। पुस्तकालय सक्रिय विकास के तहत है और https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert पर उपलब्ध है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>自然语言治最新进展得Python富开源生态系统之助也。 图书馆许NLP从业者、非专业之士先进,此术之民主化用也。 然开源NLP生态系统之成熟度以言而异。 建一新开源库,引入最先进NLPRust。 Rust 为统编程语言,其构机器学应用程序所须可用,而犹阙成端 NLP 库。 议库 rust-bert 成今世语言模形及管道(如译若摘要)。 此 Rust 社区益发于 NLP 家及非专家。 愿此库速 Rust 中 NLP 生态系统之渐也。 该库正在积极开发中,可在 https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Tá an dul chun cinn le déanaí i dtaighde próiseála teanga nádúrtha tacaithe ag forbairt éiceachóras foinse oscailte saibhir i Python. Bhí leabharlanna a ligeann do chleachtóirí NLP ach freisin do dhaoine nach speisialtóirí iad chun samhlacha úrscothacha a ghiaráil, lárnach i ndaonlathú na teicneolaíochta seo. Ní hionann aibíocht an éiceachóras foinse oscailte NLP, áfach, idir teangacha. Molann an obair seo leabharlann foinse oscailte nua a bheidh dírithe ar NLP den scoth a thabhairt go Rust. Is teanga ríomhchláraithe córais é Rust a bhfuil na bunsraitheanna a theastaíonn chun feidhmchláir mheaisínfhoghlama a thógáil ar fáil di ach níl leabharlanna NLP réidh le húsáid inti fós. Cuireann an leabharlann atá beartaithe, rust-bert, samhlacha nua-aimseartha teanga agus píblínte réidh le húsáid i bhfeidhm (aistriúchán nó achoimriú mar shampla). Ligeann sé seo do phobal Rust tuilleadh forbartha a dhéanamh ó shaineolaithe NLP agus ó neamhspeisialtóirí. Táthar ag súil go gcuirfidh an leabharlann seo dlús le forbairt éiceachóras NLP i Rust. Tá an leabharlann á forbairt go gníomhach agus ar fáil ag https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>A természetes nyelvfeldolgozási kutatások közelmúltbeli előrehaladását a Python gazdag nyílt forráskódú ökoszisztémájának fejlesztése támogatta. Azok a könyvtárak, amelyek lehetővé teszik az NLP-gyakorlók, de nem szakemberek számára, hogy kihasználják a legkorszerűbb modelleket, kulcsfontosságúak voltak ennek a technológiának demokratizálásában. A nyílt forráskódú NLP ökoszisztéma érettsége azonban nyelvenként eltérő. Ez a munka egy új, nyílt forráskódú könyvtárat javasol, amelynek célja, hogy a legkorszerűbb NLP-t hozza Rustba. A Rust egy olyan rendszerprogramozási nyelv, amelyhez rendelkezésre állnak a gépi tanulási alkalmazások kiépítéséhez szükséges alapok, de még mindig hiányzik a használatra kész, végpontos NLP könyvtárak. A javasolt könyvtár, a rust-bert, modern nyelvi modelleket és használatra kész csővezetékeket valósít meg (például fordítás vagy összefoglalás). Ez lehetővé teszi a Rust közösség további fejlesztését mind az NLP szakértői, mind a nem szakemberek részéről. Reméljük, hogy ez a könyvtár felgyorsítja az NLP ökoszisztéma fejlődését Rustban. A könyvtár aktív fejlesztés alatt áll és elérhető a https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>I recenti progressi nella ricerca sull'elaborazione del linguaggio naturale sono stati sostenuti dallo sviluppo di un ricco ecosistema open source in Python. Le biblioteche che consentono ai professionisti del PNL ma anche ai non specialisti di sfruttare modelli all'avanguardia sono state strumentali nella democratizzazione di questa tecnologia. La maturità dell'ecosistema PNL open source varia tuttavia da una lingua all'altra. Questo lavoro propone una nuova libreria open source volta a portare NLP all'avanguardia a Rust. Rust è un linguaggio di programmazione dei sistemi per il quale sono disponibili le basi necessarie per costruire applicazioni di apprendimento automatico, ma manca ancora di librerie NLP end-to-end pronte all'uso. La libreria proposta, rust-bert, implementa modelli linguistici moderni e pipeline pronte all'uso (ad esempio traduzione o sintesi). Ciò consente un ulteriore sviluppo da parte della comunità Rust sia da parte di esperti NLP che non specialisti. Si spera che questa libreria accelererà lo sviluppo dell'ecosistema NLP in Rust. La biblioteca è in fase di sviluppo attivo e disponibile presso https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ka>პირადი ენის პროცესი პროგრესი პირველი პროგრესი პირველი პირველი პირველი პირველი პირველი პირველი პირველი პირველი პირველი ეკოსტემის განვითარება პირ ლიბური, რომლებიც NLP პრაქტიკონტებების შესაძლებლობა, მაგრამ არ-სპეციალური მოდელეების შესაძლებლობა, ამ ტექნოლოგიის დემოკრატიზაციაში ინსტრუმენტულია. განხორციელი NLP ეკოსისტემის წარმოდგენება მაგრამ ენების შორის განსხვავებულია. ეს სამუშაო ახალი გახსნილი წიგნალის ლიბერიკა, საზოგადომის მიხედვით, რომ NLP-ის სამუშაო პროსტის გადატანა. Rust არის სისტემის პროგრამების ენაა, რომლის გამოსახულება მაქსინური სწავლების პროგრამების გამოსახულება, მაგრამ არ არის დჲრე გამოყენება, end-to-end NLP ლიბრიკაში. პროსტი-ბერტი, მინდომენტური ენის მოდელები და გამოყენებელი რუპლინეები (მაგალითად, გადაწყვეტილება ან გადაწყვეტილება). ეს უფრო მეტი განვითარებას პასტის საზოგადოებაში NLP ექსპერტისგან და არ-სპეციალური განვითარებაში. იმედია, რომ ეს ლიბოლობურია დაწყვირდება NLP ეკოსისტემის განვითარებას Rust-ში. ბიბლიოტერია აქტიური განვითარება და ხელსახურება https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_kk>Табиғи тілдерді өңдеу зерттеулерінің жаңа бағдарламасы Python- да ашық көзінің экосистемін жасау арқылы қолданылады. Осы технологияны демократизациялау үшін библиотекалар NLP практиктеріне мүмкіндік береді, бірақ оның арнаулы емес специалисторларына қолдану үлгілерін қолдануға мүмкіндік береді. Ашық көздегі NLP экосистемінің өтеу күні тілдер арасында айырылады. Бұл жұмыс жаңа ашық көзі жинақтарын NLP күйін Rust-ге келтіру үшін ұсынады. Rust - машина оқыту қолданбаларын құру үшін керек негізделген жүйелік бағдарламалау тілі, бірақ әлі NLP жиындарын қолдану үшін дайын жоқ. Келтірілген кітапхана, rust-bert, қазіргі тіл үлгілерін және қолдану үшін дайын қолдану үшін қолданылады (мысалы, аудару не тұжырымдамасы). Бұл NLP эксперттерінің және специалистіктерінің бірнеше жасау мүмкіндігі болады. Бұл кітапхана NLP экосистемін Rust-де жұмыс істейді. Медиатека белсенді жасау және бар https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Naujausią pažangą gamtinių kalbų apdorojimo moksliniuose tyrimuose rėmė turtingos atvirojo šaltinio ekosistemos kūrimas Pythone. Bibliotekos, leidžiančios NLP specialistams, bet ir ne specialistams naudotis naujausiais modeliais, padėjo demokratizuoti šią technologiją. Tačiau atvirojo šaltinio NLP ekosistemos brandumas skirtingose kalbose skiriasi. Šiame darbe siūloma sukurti naują atviro kodo biblioteką, kuria Rust būtų pristatytas naujausias NLP. Rust yra sistemų programavimo kalba, kurios pagrindai, reikalingi mašinų mokymosi programų kūrimui, yra prieinami, tačiau vis dar trūksta parengtų naudoti, galutinių NLP bibliotekų. Siūloma biblioteka, rust-bert, įgyvendina šiuolaikinius kalbų modelius ir parengtus naudoti vamzdynus (pvz., vertimą arba santrauką). This allows further development by the Rust community from both NLP experts and non-specialists.  Tikimasi, kad ši biblioteka paspartins NLP ekosistemos plėtrą Ruste. Biblioteka aktyviai plėtojama ir pateikiama https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Неодамнешниот напредок во истражувањето за природното обработување јазик е поддржан од развојот на богат отворен екосистем во Python. Библиотеките кои им овозможуваат на практичарите на НЛП, но и на неспецијалистите, да влијаат на најсовремените модели, беа инструментални во демократизацијата на оваа технологија. Созрелоста на отворениот екосистем НЛП сепак се разликува меѓу јазиците. Оваа работа предложува нова библиотека со отворен извор со цел донесување на најсовремената НЛП во Раст. Раст е системски јазик за програмирање за кој се достапни фондациите потребни за изградба на апликации за машинско учење, но сé уште недостасуваат библиотеки од крај до крај подготвени за употреба. Предложената библиотека, rust-bert, имплементира модерни јазички модели и подготвени за употреба гасоводи (на пример превод или резултат). Ова овозможува понатамошен развој од страна на заедницата Раст од експерти на НЛП и не-специјалисти. Се надева дека оваа библиотека ќе го забрза развојот на екосистемот НЛП во Раст. The library is under active development and available at  https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>The recent progress in natural language processing research has been supported by the development of a rich open source ecosystem in Python.  Pustakawan yang membolehkan pelatih NLP tetapi juga non-specialists untuk mengambil alih model-state-of-the-art telah menjadi instrumental dalam demokratisasi teknologi ini. Maturiti ekosistem NLP sumber terbuka bagaimanapun berbeza antara bahasa. This work proposes a new open-source library aimed at bringing state-of-the-art NLP to Rust.  Rust adalah bahasa pemrograman sistem yang mana asas yang diperlukan untuk membina aplikasi pembelajaran mesin tersedia tetapi masih kekurangan perpustakaan NLP yang bersedia untuk digunakan. Pustaka yang direncanakan, rust-bert, melaksanakan model bahasa modern dan baris paip sedia-untuk-guna (contohnya terjemahan atau ringkasan). Ini membolehkan pembangunan lanjut oleh komuniti Rust dari ahli NLP dan bukan-ahli. Diharap perpustakaan ini akan mempercepat pembangunan ekosistem NLP di Rust. Pustaka berada di bawah pembangunan aktif dan tersedia di https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_el>Η πρόσφατη πρόοδος στην έρευνα επεξεργασίας φυσικής γλώσσας υποστηρίζεται από την ανάπτυξη ενός πλούσιου οικοσυστήματος ανοικτού κώδικα στην Python. Βιβλιοθήκες που επιτρέπουν σε επαγγελματίες αλλά και σε μη ειδικούς να αξιοποιήσουν μοντέλα τελευταίας τεχνολογίας έχουν καθοριστεί για τον εκδημοκρατισμό αυτής της τεχνολογίας. Ωστόσο, η ωριμότητα του οικοσυστήματος ανοικτού κώδικα διαφέρει μεταξύ των γλωσσών. Το έργο αυτό προτείνει μια νέα βιβλιοθήκη ανοιχτού κώδικα με στόχο την εισαγωγή της τελευταίας τεχνολογίας ΝΛΠ στο Rust. Η σκουριά είναι μια γλώσσα προγραμματισμού συστημάτων για την οποία τα θεμέλια που απαιτούνται για την κατασκευή εφαρμογών μηχανικής μάθησης είναι διαθέσιμα, αλλά εξακολουθούν να λείπουν έτοιμες προς χρήση, ολοκληρωμένες βιβλιοθήκες. Η προτεινόμενη βιβλιοθήκη, υλοποιεί σύγχρονα γλωσσικά μοντέλα και έτοιμους προς χρήση αγωγούς (για παράδειγμα μετάφραση ή σύνοψη). Αυτό επιτρέπει την περαιτέρω ανάπτυξη από την κοινότητα τόσο από ειδικούς όσο και από μη ειδικούς. Ελπίζουμε ότι αυτή η βιβλιοθήκη θα επιταχύνει την ανάπτυξη του οικοσυστήματος στο Ραστ. Η βιβλιοθήκη βρίσκεται υπό ενεργή ανάπτυξη και διατίθεται στη διεύθυνση: https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ml>സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷയുടെ പ്രക്രിയഭാഷയുടെ പരിശോധനത്തിലുള്ള ഏറ്റവും അടുത്ത പുരോഗങ്ങള്‍ പൈത്തോനിലെ ഒരു സമ്പന്നതയുള്ള സ NLP പരിശീലന്മാരെ അനുവദിക്കുന്ന ലൈബ്രറികള്‍ ഈ സാങ്കേതികവിദ്യയുടെ ജനാധിപത്യത്തില്‍ പ്രത്യേകിച്ചിരിക്കുന്ന സ്റ്റേറ്റ് ഓഫ @ info: status ഈ ജോലി ഒരു പുതിയ തുറന്ന സോര്‍സ് ലൈബ്രറി പ്രായശ്ചിത്തം ചെയ്യുന്നു. അതിനുള്ള ലക്ഷ്യം NLP-ന്റെ സ്റ്റേറ റുസ്റ്റ് ഒരു സിസ്റ്റം പ്രോഗ്രാമിംഗ് ഭാഷയാണ്. മെഷീന്‍ പഠിക്കുന്ന പ്രയോഗങ്ങള്‍ പണിയേണ്ട അടിസ്ഥാനങ്ങള്‍ പ്രൊദ്ദേശിച്ച ലൈബ്രറി, റസ്റ്റ്- ബെര്‍ട്ട്, ആധുനിക ഭാഷ മോഡലുകള്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നു, പൈപ്പെലിനുകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്ക നിങ്ങളുടെ രണ്ടു പ്രത്യേക വിശേഷികളില്‍ നിന്നും റസ്റ്റ് സമൂഹത്തിന്റെ വികസിപ്പിന് ഇത് കൂടുതല്‍ വികസിപ ഈ ലൈബ്രറി റൂസ്റ്റിലെ NLP സെക്സിസ്റ്റം വേഗത്തിലേക്ക് പെടുത്തുമെന്ന് പ്രതീക്ഷിക്കുന്നു. The library is under active development and available at  https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-progress reċenti fir-riċerka dwar l-ipproċessar tal-lingwi naturali ġie appoġġjat mill-iżvilupp ta’ ekosistema rikka ta’ sors miftuħ f’Python. Il-libreriji li jippermettu lill-prattikanti tal-NLP iżda wkoll lil dawk li mhumiex speċjalisti biex jinfurzaw il-mudelli l-aktar avvanzati kienu strumentali fid-demokratizzazzjoni ta’ din it-teknoloġija. Madankollu, il-maturità tal-ekosistema open-source NLP tvarja bejn il-lingwi. This work proposes a new open-source library aimed at bringing state-of-the-art NLP to Rust.  Rust huwa lingwa ta’ programmar tas-sistemi li għaliha l-fondazzjonijiet meħtieġa għall-bini ta’ applikazzjonijiet għat-tagħlim tal-magni huma disponibbli iżda għad m’għandhomx libreriji NLP lesti għall-użu minn tarf sa tarf. Il-librerija proposta, rust-bert, timplimenta mudelli moderni tal-lingwa u pipelines lesti għall-użu (pereżempju traduzzjoni jew sommarju). Dan jippermetti aktar żvilupp mill-komunità Rust kemm minn esperti tal-NLP kif ukoll minn mhux speċjalisti. Huwa ttamat li din il-librerija taċċellera l-iżvilupp tal-ekosistema NLP f’Rust. The library is under active development and available at  https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Байгалийн хэл үйлдвэрлэлийн судалгааны сүүлийн хөгжлийн хөгжлийг Питонд баян нээлттэй эх үүсвэрийн экосистемийн хөгжлийн тусламжтай болсон. НЛП сурагчид болон мэргэжилтэн биш мэргэжилтнүүд энэ технологийн ардчилсан загварыг ашиглах боломжтой номын сан. НЛП экосистемийн нээлттэй эх үүсвэрийн өсөлт хэлний хоорондоо өөрчлөгддөг. Энэ ажлын шинэ нээлттэй эх үүсвэрийн номын санал болгож, NLP-ын улс төрийг Руст руу оруулах зорилготой. Rust бол машины суралцах програмчлал бүтээх шаардлагатай системийн програмчлалын хэл юм. Гэхдээ NLP номын санг ашиглах бэлэн, төгсгөлд зогсохгүй. Өнөөдөр санал өгсөн номын сан, rust-bert, орчин үеийн хэл загварууд болон хоолойн шугам ашиглах бэлэн байдаг (жишээлбэл, орчин үеийн орчин үеийн хэл загваруудыг дамжуулдаг). Энэ нь Руст нийгэмд NLP мэргэжилтэн болон мэргэжилтэн бус хүмүүсээс илүү хөгжүүлэх боломжтой. Энэ номын санд НLP экосистемийн хөгжлийг Rust-д хурдан хөгжүүлэх гэж найдаж байна. Номын номын санг идэвхтэй хөгжлийн доор https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Progresul recent în cercetarea de procesare a limbajului natural a fost susținut de dezvoltarea unui ecosistem open source bogat în Python. Bibliotecile care permit practicienilor PNL, dar și non-specialiștilor să valorifice modele de ultimă generație au fost esențiale în democratizarea acestei tehnologii. Cu toate acestea, maturitatea ecosistemului PNL cu sursă deschisă variază între limbi. Această lucrare propune o nouă bibliotecă open-source menită să aducă PNL de ultimă generație în Rust. Rust este un limbaj de programare a sistemelor pentru care sunt disponibile fundațiile necesare pentru a construi aplicații de învățare automată, dar încă lipsește biblioteci NLP gata de utilizare, end-to-end. Biblioteca propusă, rust-bert, implementează modele lingvistice moderne și conducte gata de utilizare (de exemplu traducere sau rezumare). Acest lucru permite dezvoltarea ulterioară a comunității Rust atât din partea experților PNL, cât și din partea non-specialiștilor. Se speră că această bibliotecă va accelera dezvoltarea ecosistemului PNL în Rust. Biblioteca este în curs de dezvoltare activă și disponibilă la https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_no>Den siste framdringen i naturspråkshandteringsforskningen er støtta av utviklinga av ein ryg åpen kjeldeekosystem i Python. Bibliotekkar som tillater NLP-praktiseringar, men også ikkje-spesialistar for å levera tilstand-av-kunstmodeller har vært nyttig i demokratisering av denne teknologien. Ferdigheiten til open-source NLP-ekosystem varierer likevel mellom språk. Dette arbeidet foreslår eit nytt open-source bibliotek med mål for å henta NLP-tilstanden til kunsten til Rust. Rust er eit programmeringspråk for systemet som fundamentane krevst for å bygge maskinelæringsprogram er tilgjengelege, men ennå manglar klar til bruk, end- to- end NLP- bibliotek. Førehandsvis biblioteket, rust-bert, implementerer moderne språk- modeller og klar for å bruka røyr- linjer (for eksempel omsetjing eller samansering). Dette tillater framtidige utvikling av Rust-fellesskapet frå både NLP-ekspertar og ikkje-spesialistar. Det er håpent at denne biblioteket vil akselerera utviklinga av NLP-ekosystem i Rust. Biblioteken er under aktiv utvikling og tilgjengeleg på https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_so>Waxbarashada baaritaanka afka dabiicadda ah waxaa lagu caawiyey horumarinta nolosha furan ee Python. Maktabaduhu waxay leeyihiin qalabka ku saabsan demokrasiyada teknolojiyadan. Dhaqaalaha kooxda dhaqaalaha ee furan ee NLP waa kala duwan yihiin luuqadaha. Shaqadan wuxuu soo jeedaa maktabadda cusub ee furan oo loogu talagalay in uu Rust u keeno dowladda-da-da-art NLP. Rust waa luqad barnaamijka ah oo ay aasaasadu u baahan yihiin in la dhiso codsiga waxbarashada machineka, laakiin weli ma baahna maktabadaha u diyaarinta isticmaalka, dhamaadka ugu dambaysta NLP. Maktabadda la soo jeeday, rust-bert, wuxuu sameeyaa tusaale ahaan noocyada luuqada modern iyo mid u diyaar ah isticmaalka pipelines (tusaale ahaan turjumista ama summarinta). Tan waxaa dheeraad ah horumarinta bulshada Rust ee ka soo baxa khabiiriyiinta NLP iyo khabiiriyiinta aan aheyn. Waxaa rajaynayaa in maktabaddu uu horumarinayo nidaamka NLP ee Rust. Maktabaduhu wuxuu ku jiraa horumarinta waxqabad ah, waxaana laga helaa https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>පායිතන් වල ස්වාභාවික භාෂාව පරීක්ෂණයේ අලුත් ප්‍රධානයක් පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා ප්‍රති ලායිබ්‍රේරියන් NLP ප්‍රේක්ෂකයන්ට අවශ්‍ය කරන්න පුළුවන් නමුත් විශේෂකයෙන් නොවිශේෂකයන්ට මේ තාක්ෂණයේ ප්‍රධානිකරණය සඳ නිර්මාණය ප්‍රවෘත්තිය NLP ජීවිත පද්ධතියේ විවෘත වෙනස් කරනවා නමුත් භාෂාවල් අතර. මේ වැඩේ අළුත් විවෘත ප්‍රවෘත පුළුවන් ලොක්කොරියාවක් සැලසුම් කරනවා අධ්‍යයයට NLP කිරීමට. @ info ප්‍රයෝජනය පුද්ගලය, රුස්ට්-බර්ට්, අධ්‍යම භාෂාව මොඩේල් සහ පායිප්ලින් භාවිත කරන්න සූදානම් වෙනවා (උ මේකෙන් රුස්ට් සමාජිකයෙන් විශේෂ කරනවා NLP විශේෂකයෝ සහ විශේෂකයෝ නෙමෙයි. ඒක බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනවා මේ ලොක්කොරියා රුස්ට් වල NLP ජීවිත පද්ධතියේ විකාශය වේගය කරන්න. Name https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sr>Nedavni napredak istraživanja prirodnog jezika podržavao je razvoj bogatog ekosistema otvorenog izvora u Pythonu. Biblioteke koje dozvoljavaju praktičnicima NLP-a, ali takođe ne-specijalistima da utiču na modele države umjetnosti su bile instrumentalne u demokratizaciji ove tehnologije. Izrađenost otvorenog izvora ekosistema NLP međutim se razlikuje između jezika. Ovaj rad predlaže novu biblioteku otvorenog izvora koja je ciljana da dovede državni NLP u Rust. Rust je jezik programiranja sistema za koje su temelji potrebni za izgradnju aplikacija za učenje mašina dostupni, ali još uvek nedostaju knjižnice NLP-a spremne za upotrebu. Predložena biblioteka, rust-bert, implementira moderne jezičke modele i spremne za upotrebu cijevi (na primjer prevod ili sažetak). To omogućava daljnji razvoj Rust zajednice od eksperta NLP-a i ne-specijalista. Nadam se da će ova biblioteka ubrzati razvoj ekosistema NLP u Rustu. Biblioteka je pod aktivnim razvojom i dostupnim u https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_pl>Ostatnie postępy w badaniach nad przetwarzaniem języka naturalnego zostały wspierane przez rozwój bogatego ekosystemu open source w Pythonie. Biblioteki umożliwiające praktykom NLP, ale także niespecjalistom wykorzystanie najnowocześniejszych modeli miały kluczowe znaczenie w demokratyzacji tej technologii. Dojrzałość ekosystemu NLP open-source różni się jednak w poszczególnych językach. Niniejsza praca proponuje nową bibliotekę open source, której celem jest wprowadzenie do Rust najnowocześniejszego NLP. Rust jest językiem programowania systemów, dla którego dostępne są podstawy niezbędne do budowy aplikacji uczenia maszynowego, ale nadal brakuje gotowych do użycia, kompleksowych bibliotek NLP. Proponowana biblioteka, rust-bert, wdraża nowoczesne modele językowe i gotowe do użycia rurociągi (np. tłumaczenie lub podsumowanie). Pozwala to na dalszy rozwój społeczności Rust zarówno przez ekspertów NLP, jak i niespecjalistów. Liczy się, że biblioteka ta przyspieszy rozwój ekosystemu NLP w Rust. Biblioteka jest w trakcie aktywnego rozwoju i dostępna na stronie internetowej https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sv>De senaste framstegen inom forskning om naturlig språkbehandling har stötts av utvecklingen av ett rikt ekosystem med öppen källkod i Python. Bibliotek som tillåter NLP-utövare men även icke-specialister att utnyttja state-of-the-art modeller har varit avgörande för demokratiseringen av denna teknik. Mognaden hos det öppna NLP-ekosystemet varierar dock mellan olika språk. Detta arbete föreslår ett nytt bibliotek med öppen källkod som syftar till att föra toppmodern NLP till Rust. Rust är ett systemprogrammeringsspråk för vilket grunderna för att bygga maskininlärningsapplikationer finns tillgängliga men fortfarande saknar färdiga, end-to-end NLP-bibliotek. Det föreslagna biblioteket rust-bert implementerar moderna språkmodeller och färdiga pipelines (till exempel översättning eller sammanfattning). Detta möjliggör vidareutveckling av Rust gemenskapen från både NLP experter och icke-specialister. Förhoppningen är att detta bibliotek kommer att påskynda utvecklingen av NLP-ekosystemet i Rust. Biblioteket är under aktiv utveckling och finns tillgängligt på https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இயல்பான மொழி செயல்படுத்தும் ஆராய்ச்சியில் சமீபத்தின் முன்னேற்றம் பைதானில் ஒரு பழைய மூல மூலத்தின் மூல மூ NLP பயிற்சிகளை அனுமதிக்கும் நூலகங்களும் ஆனால் சிறப்பு அறிவிப்பவர்களும் இந்த தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் தொழில்நுட்பமா @ info: whatsthis @ info Rust is a system programming language for which foundations are required to build machine learning applications available but still does not need to use ready- to- end- to- end NLP libraries. பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட நூலகத்தை, rust- bert, நடத்தும் மொழி மாதிரிகளை இயக்குகிறது மற்றும் பயன்படுத்த துணுக்குகளை தயாராக பயன்படுத்த இது NLP விஷயங்கள் மற்றும் விசேஷிப்பாளர்கள் இருந்தும் ருஸ்ட் சமூகத்தார் மேலும் உருவாக்கும் அனுமதிக்க இந்த நூலகத்தை ரூஸ்டில் NLP சூழல் அமைப்பின் உருவாக்கத்தை விரைவாக்கும் என்று நம்புகிறேன். The library is under active development and available at  https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>پیتان میں ایک مالک اوپن سورس اکوسیسٹم کی توسعہ سے اچھی پیشرفت پیدا کی گئی ہے۔ لیبراریاں جنہوں نے NLP پھیلانے والوں کو اجازت دی ہے لیکن اس تکنولوژی کی دموکراتیزی میں بھی غیر مخصوص کرنے والوں کو اجازت دی ہے۔ اپنا اوپن سورس ایکسیسٹم کی پھوٹی لیکن زبانوں کے درمیان متفاوت ہے۔ یہ کام ایک نوی اوپن سورس لئبری کی پیشنهاد کرتا ہے جس کا مطابق یہ ہے کہ ایٹ آرت NLP کو روسٹ کی طرف لے آئیں۔ روس ایک سیسٹم پروگرامینگ زبان ہے جس کے لئے ماشین کی تعلیم کے لئے ضرورت کی بنیادیں موجود ہیں لیکن اب بھی NLP لئبریوں کے لئے تیار نہیں ہیں۔ پیشنهاد کی لائیبروری، روسٹ-برٹ، مدرن زبان مدلکوں اور پیپ لائین کے استعمال کرنے کے لئے تیار ہے (مثال ترجمہ یا ترجمہ کے لئے). یہ روسٹ کمونٹی کے ذریعہ سے زیادہ تغییرات اجازت دیتا ہے NLP متخصص اور غیر متخصص لوگوں سے۔ اس کی امید ہے کہ یہ لائیبری روس میں NLP اکوسیسٹم کی توسعہ تیزی کرے گی۔ لائیبروری فعال توسعہ کے اندر ہے اور اس میں موجود ہے https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Maktablar NLP ishga tushiruvchilarga ruxsat beradi, ammo bu texnologiya demokrasiyasiga ishlab chiqarish imkoniyatlarni ham ishlatmaydi. @ info: whatsthis Bu ishni Rust'ga joʻnatish uchun yangi ochiq manbasi kutubxonasini yaratadi. Rust - dasturlarni oʻrganish uchun dasturlarni yaratish kerak boʻlgan tizim tili, ammo uni ishlatish uchun tayyorlash uchun tayyorlar mavjud emas. Taʼminlovchi kutubxonasi, rust- bert, yangi tillar modellarini ishga tushirish va ishlatish uchun tayyorlar (masalan tarjima yoki hisoblash). Bu NLP ekspert va dohqonchalar bilan Rust jamiyatlaridan foydalanishga ruxsat beradi. Bu kutubxona Rustdagi NLP muhit tizimini tezlashtiradi deb umid qiladi. Maktab aktiv taʼminlovchi va mavjud emas https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Sự tiến bộ gần đây trong nghiên cứu xử lý ngôn ngữ tự nhiên được ủng hộ bởi sự phát triển một hệ sinh thái nguồn mở dồi dào ở Python. Thư viện cho những người hành nghề ở lập trường, nhưng cũng không phải chuyên gia điều khiển các mô hình hiện đại, đã góp phần vào sự phát triển kỹ thuật này. Sự trưởng thành của hệ sinh thái độc lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập lập. Công trình này đề nghị một thư viện mở nguồn mới nhằm mục đích đưa trụ sở đỉnh cao nhất Rust. Rust là một ngôn ngữ lập trình hệ thống mà chúng ta cần thiết để xây dựng các ứng dụng học máy nhưng vẫn chưa có sẵn sàng để sử dụng, tận cùng tại thư viện NLP. Thư viện dự kiến, sét bert, thực hiện những mô hình ngôn ngữ hiện đại và ống dẫn sẵn sàng sử dụng (v. d. dịch hay tóm tắt). Điều này cho phép cộng đồng Rust tiếp tục phát triển từ chuyên gia sục sạo và không chuyên gia. Hy vọng thư viện này sẽ đẩy nhanh việc phát triển hệ sinh thái NLP ở Rust. Thư viện đang phát triển và có mặt tại https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>De recente vooruitgang in onderzoek naar natuurlijke taalverwerking werd ondersteund door de ontwikkeling van een rijk open source ecosysteem in Python. Bibliotheken waarmee NLP-beoefenaars maar ook niet-specialisten gebruik kunnen maken van state-of-the-art modellen, hebben een belangrijke rol gespeeld in de democratisering van deze technologie. De volwassenheid van het open-source NLP ecosysteem verschilt echter per taal. Dit werk stelt een nieuwe open-source bibliotheek voor om state-of-the-art NLP naar Rust te brengen. Rust is een systeemprogrammeertaal waarvoor de fundamenten die nodig zijn om machine learning applicaties te bouwen beschikbaar zijn, maar nog steeds ontbreekt het aan kant-en-klare, end-to-end NLP bibliotheken. De voorgestelde bibliotheek, roest-bert, implementeert moderne taalmodellen en kant-en-klare pipelines (bijvoorbeeld vertaling of samenvatting). Dit maakt verdere ontwikkeling door de Rust community mogelijk van zowel NLP experts als niet-specialisten. Hopelijk zal deze bibliotheek de ontwikkeling van het NLP ecosysteem in Rust versnellen. De bibliotheek is in actieve ontwikkeling en beschikbaar op: https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Неотдавнашният напредък в изследванията за обработка на естествени езици е подкрепен от развитието на богата екосистема с отворен код в Питон. Библиотеките, които позволяват на практикуващите НЛП, но и на неспециалистите да използват най-съвременните модели, са от решаващо значение за демократизацията на тази технология. Зрелостта на екосистемата на НЛП с отворен код обаче варира между езиците. Тази работа предлага нова библиотека с отворен код, насочена към внедряване на най-съвременните НЛО в Ръст. Ръст е системен програмен език, за който са налице основите, необходими за изграждане на приложения за машинно обучение, но все още липсват готови за използване библиотеки от край до край. Предложената библиотека, Руст-берт, внедрява съвременни езикови модели и готови за употреба тръбопроводи (например превод или обобщаване). Това позволява по-нататъшно развитие от страна на общността както от експерти на НЛП, така и от неспециалисти. Надяваме се тази библиотека да ускори развитието на екосистемата на НЛП в Ръст. Библиотеката е в процес на активно развитие и е достъпна на адрес: https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Nedavni napredak u istraživanju obrade prirodnog jezika podržan je razvojom bogatog otvorenog izvornog ekosistema u Pythonu. Biblioteke koje omogućavaju praktičarima NLP-a, ali također ne-specijalistima da utjecaju na modele države umjetnosti, bile su instrumentalne u demokratizaciji ove tehnologije. Zrađenost otvorenog izvora ekosistema NLP međutim se razlikuje između jezika. Ovaj rad predlaže novu knjižnicu otvorenog izvora u cilju donošenja države umjetnosti NLP Rustu. Rust je jezik programiranja sustava za kojeg su temelji potrebni za izgradnju programa za učenje strojeva dostupni, ali još uvijek nedostaju knjižnice NLP-a spremne za upotrebu, kraj do kraja. Predložena biblioteka, rust-bert, provede moderne jezičke modele i spremne za upotrebu cijevi (na primjer prevod ili sažetak). To omogućava daljnji razvoj Rust zajednice od stručnjaka NLP-a i ne-specijalista. Nadam se da će ova biblioteka ubrzati razvoj ekosistema NLP-a u Rustu. Biblioteka je pod aktivnim razvojom i dostupnim u https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>De seneste fremskridt inden for naturlig sprogbehandling forskning er blevet understøttet af udviklingen af et rigt open source økosystem i Python. Biblioteker, der giver NLP-udøvere, men også ikke-specialister mulighed for at udnytte state-of-the-art modeller, har været afgørende for demokratiseringen af denne teknologi. Modenheden i det åbne kildekode-NLP-økosystem varierer imidlertid fra sprog til sprog. Dette værk foreslår et nyt open source bibliotek, der tager sigte på at bringe state-of-the-art NLP til Rust. Rust er et programmeringssprog for systemer, hvor grundlaget for at bygge maskinlæringsapplikationer er tilgængeligt, men stadig mangler klar til brug, end-to-end NLP biblioteker. Det foreslåede bibliotek, rust-bert, implementerer moderne sprogmodeller og klar til brug pipelines (for eksempel oversættelse eller opsummering). Dette muliggør yderligere udvikling af Rust-fællesskabet fra både NLP-eksperter og ikke-specialister. Det håbes, at dette bibliotek vil fremskynde udviklingen af NLP økosystemet i Rust. Biblioteket er under aktiv udvikling og tilgængeligt på https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Die jüngsten Fortschritte in der Forschung zur Verarbeitung natürlicher Sprache wurden durch die Entwicklung eines reichen Open-Source-Ökosystems in Python unterstützt. Bibliotheken, die es NLP-Praktikern aber auch Nicht-Spezialisten ermöglichen, modernste Modelle zu nutzen, haben maßgeblich zur Demokratisierung dieser Technologie beigetragen. Die Reife des Open-Source-NLP-Ökosystems variiert jedoch zwischen den Sprachen. Diese Arbeit schlägt eine neue Open-Source-Bibliothek vor, die den neuesten Stand der Technik NLP nach Rust bringen soll. Rust ist eine Systemprogrammiersprache, für die die Grundlagen für den Aufbau von Machine Learning-Anwendungen vorhanden sind, jedoch noch keine gebrauchsfertigen End-to-End-NLP-Bibliotheken vorhanden sind. Die vorgeschlagene Bibliothek, rust-bert, implementiert moderne Sprachmodelle und gebrauchsfertige Pipelines (z.B. Übersetzung oder Zusammenfassung). Dies ermöglicht die Weiterentwicklung der Rust-Community sowohl von NLP-Experten als auch von Nicht-Spezialisten. Es wird gehofft, dass diese Bibliothek die Entwicklung des NLP-Ökosystems in Rust beschleunigen wird. Die Bibliothek befindet sich in aktiver Entwicklung und steht zur Verfügung unter https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kemajuan baru-baru ini dalam penelitian proses bahasa alam telah didukung oleh pengembangan ekosistem sumber terbuka kaya di Python. Perpustakaan yang memungkinkan praktek NLP tetapi juga non-spesialis untuk mengambil alih model state-of-the-art telah menjadi instrumental dalam demokratisasi teknologi ini. Kedewasan ekosistem NLP sumber terbuka bagaimanapun berbeda antara bahasa. Pekerjaan ini mengusulkan perpustakaan open-source baru yang bertujuan untuk membawa NLP state-of-the-art ke Rust. Rust adalah bahasa pemrograman sistem yang dibutuhkan oleh dasar untuk membangun aplikasi pembelajaran mesin tersedia tapi masih kekurangan perpustakaan NLP yang siap untuk digunakan. The proposed library, rust-bert, implements modern language models and ready-to-use pipelines (for example translation or summarization).  Ini memungkinkan perkembangan lanjut oleh komunitas Rust dari pakar NLP dan non-spesialis. Diharap perpustakaan ini akan mempercepat pengembangan ekosistem NLP di Rust. Perpustakaan berada di bawah pembangunan aktif dan tersedia di https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>پیشرفت اخیر در تحقیقات پردازش زبان طبیعی توسط توسعه یک منبع منبع باز در پایتون پشتیبانی شده است. کتابخانه‌ها که اجازه می‌دهند تمرین‌کنندگان NLP، ولی غیر متخصص‌کنندگان که مدل‌های هنری را تحت تأثیر قرار دهند، در دموکراتیک این تکنولوژی ابزار بودند. هرچند بزرگسالی اقلیسیستم NLP منبع باز بین زبانها متفاوت می‌شود. این کار یک کتابخانه‌ی منبع باز جدید را پیشنهاد می‌کند که هدف می‌گیرد که NLP ایالت هنر را به راست بیاورد. Rust یک زبان برنامه‌ریزی سیستم است که برای ساختن کاربردهای یادگیری ماشین نیاز دارد ولی هنوز کتابخانه‌های NLP آماده برای استفاده، پایان به پایان ندارد. کتابخانه پیشنهاد، rust-bert، مدل زبان مدرن و خطوط لوله آماده استفاده می‌کند (برای مثال ترجمه یا جمع کردن). این اجازه می دهد که توسط جامعه روست از متخصص NLP و غیر متخصص بیشتری توسعه کند. امیدواره است که این کتابخانه توسعه اکوسیستم NLP در روست سرعت دهد. کتابخانه تحت توسعه فعال و موجود است https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>파이톤의 풍부한 소스 생태계 개발은 자연 언어 처리 연구의 최신 진전을 지원했다.도서관은 NLP 종사자를 허용하지만, 비전문가가 최첨단 모델을 활용할 수 있도록 하는 것도 이 기술의 민주화에 중요한 역할을 한다.그러나 오픈소스 NLP 생태계의 성숙도는 언어에 따라 다르다.이 작업은 최첨단 NLP를 녹슬게 하기 위한 새로운 오픈소스 라이브러리를 제시했다.Rust는 시스템 프로그래밍 언어로 기계 학습 응용 프로그램을 구축하는 데 필요한 기초를 가지고 있지만, 여전히 기존의 끝에서 끝까지의 NLP 라이브러리가 부족하다.의안 중의 쿠루스트bert는 현대 언어 모델과 기존의 파이프라인(예를 들어 번역이나 요약)을 실현했다.이로써 Rust 커뮤니티는 NLP 전문가와 비전문가로부터 한층 더 발전할 수 있다.이 도서관이 중국 NLP 생태계의 발전을 가속화할 것으로 기대한다.이 도서관은 지금 적극적으로 개발 중이며,https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Maendeleo ya hivi karibuni katika utafiti wa utafiti wa lugha za asili imeungwa mkono na maendeleo ya mfumo mzuri wa asili nchini Python. Maktaba yanayoweza kuwaruhusu wataalam wa NLP lakini pia wale wasio na utaalam wa kutumia mifano ya sanaa zimekuwa vifaa katika demokrasia ya teknolojia hii. Uzalisho wa mfumo wa uchumi wa NLP unaopenda hata hivyo unatofautiana na lugha. Kazi hii inapendekeza maktaba mpya ya vyanzo huru yenye lengo la kuleta hali ya sanaa ya NLP kwenda Rust. Rust ni lugha ya mifumo ya programu ambayo msingi unahitaji kujenga zana za kujifunza mashine zinapatikana lakini bado hauna vifaa vya kutumia tayari, maktaba za mwisho wa NLP. Maktaba yaliyopendekezwa, matumizi ya lugha ya asili, inatekeleza mifano ya lugha za kisasa na pipesi zilizoandaa kutumika (kwa mfano utafsiri au muhtasari). Hii inaruhusu maendeleo zaidi na jamii ya Urusi kutoka kwa wataalam wa NLP na wataalam wasio na utaalam. Ni matumaini kwamba maktaba hii itaongezea maendeleo ya mfumo wa mazingira wa NLP nchini Rust. Maktaba ina maendeleo ya haraka na inapatikana katika https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Do첵al dil i힊le첵채n ara힊tyrmalary흫 i흫 so흫ky 철흫ki pytony흫 ba첵 a 챌yk 챌e힊me ekosistema tarapyndan d철redildi. K체t체phaneler NLP praktikantlaryna rugsat ber첵채rler 첵철ne bu teknoloji흫 demokrati첵asynda 철r채n m철h체m modalaryny etm채ge rugsat ber첵채rler. A챌yk 챌e힊me bolan NLP ekosistemini흫 철s체mligi diller arasynda 체첵tge힊ir. Bu i힊e NLP'i흫 durumyny Rusa getirmek 체챌in t채ze a 챌yk-kaynakly kitaphanay teklip edip bil첵채r. Rust ma힊yny 철wrenmek 체챌in gerekli temel programlemek dilidir. Emma bu sistemlerde NLP kitaplaryny bejermek 체챌in ta첵첵ar, ullanmak 체챌in bir nusgasy 첵ok. Taryh edilen kitaphanada, rust-bert, modern dil nusgalaryny we pipelini ullanmak 체챌in ta첵첵ar (철r채n terjime 첵a-da hulajla힊dyrma) implemente첵채r. Bu Rus jemgy첵etini흫 NLP uzmanlaryny흫 we spesialistleri흫 hem 철zlerini흫 첵철ne 첵철ne geli힊mesine m체mkin ed첵채r. Bu kitaphanada NLP ekosistema'y흫 geli힊mesini Rust'da tizle힊tirir di첵ip umyt ed첵채r. Kitaphanada janla힊dyr we 첵erle힊첵채n kitaphanada https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Die onlangse vordering in natuurlike taal verwerking ondersoek is ondersteun deur die ontwikkeling van 'n ryk open bron ekostelsel in Python. Biblioteeke wat NLP-praktiseerders toelaat, maar ook nie-spesialiseerdes om staat-van-kuns-modele te verwys, is instrumentaal in die demokrasiering van hierdie teknologie. Die vervuldigheid van die open-bron NLP ekostelsel verander tog tussen tale. Hierdie werk voorstel 'n nuwe open-bron biblioteek wat bedoel is om state-of-the-art NLP na Rust te bring. Rust is 'n stelselprogramming taal waarvoor die fondasie benodig is om masjien leer programme te bou is beskikbaar maar nog steeds is gereed om te gebruik, end-to-end NLP biblioteeke nie. Die voorgestelde biblioteek, rust-bert, implementeer moderne taal modele en gereed-om pipelyne te gebruik (byvoorbeeld vertaling of opsomming). Hierdie laat verdere ontwikkeling deur die Rust gemeenskap van NLP-eksperte en nie-spesialiste toe. Dit is hoop dat hierdie biblioteek die ontwikkeling van die NLP ekostelsel in Rust sal versneller. Die biblioteek is onder aktiewe ontwikkeling en beskikbaar by https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Përparimi i fundit në kërkimin e procesimit natyror të gjuhës është mbështetur nga zhvillimi i një ekosistemi të pasur burimi të hapur në Python. Bibliotekat që lejojnë praktikantët e NLP-së por gjithashtu jo-specialistët të përdorin modele më të larta kanë qenë instrumentale në demokratizimin e kësaj teknologji. Maturita e ekosistemit NLP me burim të hapur megjithatë ndryshon midis gjuhëve. Ky punë propozon një bibliotekë të re me burim të hapur që ka për qëllim sjelljen e NLP-së së ardhshme në Rust. Rust është një gjuhë programimi i sistemeve për të cilën themelet e kërkuara për të ndërtuar aplikacione mësimi i makinave janë në dispozicion por ende i mungon bibliotekat e NLP të gatshme për përdorim. Biblioteka e propozuar, rust-bert, zbaton modele moderne gjuhësh dhe tubacione të gatshme për përdorim (për shembull përkthimi apo përmbledhje). Kjo lejon zhvillimin e mëtejshëm nga komuniteti Rust si nga ekspertët e NLP-së, ashtu edhe nga jo-specialistët. Shpresohet se kjo bibliotekë do të përshpejtojë zhvillimin e ekosistemit NLP në Rust. Biblioteka është në zhvillim aktiv dhe në dispozicion në https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>የቀድሞው የፍጥረት ቋንቋ ተሟጋቾች በPython ባለጠጋ የተከፈተ የኩነቶች የኢኮኖስቲም አካባቢ በመፍጠር የተረዳ ነው፡፡ የመልከቦች መሪኮች የNLP ባለሥታተኞችን ግን የዓላማ-የ-አርእስት ዓይነቶች የግንኙነት እና አካባቢዎች የዚህ ቴክኖጂ ግንኙነት ግንኙነት በመግለጽ መሣሪያዎች ናቸው፡፡ የክፈት ክፍተት የNLP ኢኮኖሚ ውጤት በቋንቋዎች መካከል ተለየ። ይህ ሥራ አዲስ የክፈት-ምንጭ መዝገብ ቤትሪክ አዲስ የNLP-ሀገርን ወደ ሩስ ለማምጣት ያሳልፋል፡፡ Rust - የኮምፒዩተር ፕሮግራም ቋንቋ ነው፡፡ በተዘጋጀው መዝገብ ቤትሪክ፣ rust-bert፣ የአዲስ ቋንቋ ሞዴላዎችን እና የተዘጋጀ ፕሊፕላንዶች (ለምሳሌ ትርጉም ወይም ማጠቃለያ) ይህም የሩስ ማኅበረሰብ ከNLP ባለምህርት እና ያልተሟጋቾች ጋር ደግሞ መግለጫ ይችላል፡፡ ይህ መዝገብ መዝገብ በሩስ የNLP ኢኮኖስቲም መግለጫ እንዲያጋልጥ ተስፋ ያደርጋል፡፡ መዝገብ ቤትሪክ በሠርቷል እና በተገኘ https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>The recent progress in natural language processing research has been supported by the development of a rich open source ecosystem in Python.  Գրադարանները, որոնք թույլ են տալիս ՆԼՊ-ի մասնագետներին, բայց նաև ոչ մասնագետներին օգտագործել նորագույն մոդելները, շատ կարևոր են այս տեխնոլոգիայի դեմոկրատիզացիայի մեջ: Բաց աղբյուր ՆԼՊ էկոհամակարգի հասունությունը, այնուամենայնիվ, տարբերվում է լեզուների միջև: Այս աշխատանքը առաջարկում է նոր բաց կոդֆորմային գրադարան, որի նպատակով է Ռասթին նորագույն ՆԼՊ-ը բերել: Ռասթը համակարգչային ծրագրավորման լեզու է, որի համար հասանելի են հիմնադրամները, որոնք անհրաժեշտ են մեքենային ուսումնասիրության ծրագրերի կառուցման համար, բայց դեռևս պակասում են օգտագործելու պատրաստ, վերջ-վերջ ՆԼՊ Առաջարկված գրադարան, Rust-Bert, իրականացնում է ժամանակակից լեզվի մոդելներ և օգտագործելու պատրաստ խողովակաշարեր (օրինակ թարգմանություն կամ համառոտագրություն): Սա հնարավորություն է տալիս Ռասթ համայնքի զարգացումը երկուսից՝ ՆԼՊ-ի մասնագետներից և ոչ մասնագետներից: Հուսով է, որ այս գրադարան արագացնելու է Ռասթի ՆԼՊ էկոհամակարգի զարգացումը: Գրադարանը ակտիվ զարգացման ընթացքում է և հասանելի է https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Təbiətli dil işləmə araştırmalarında son tədbir Python'da çox a çıq mənbə ekosisteminin gelişməsi ilə dəstəklənir. Kütüphanələr NLP praksiyalarına izin verirlər, lakin bu teknolojinin demokratizasyonunda həm də xəstəlikləri olmayan modellərin istifadə etməsini mümkün edirlər. Açıq-kaynaklı NLP ekosisteminin ölçülüyü dillərin arasında fərqli olaraq. Bu işin yeni a çıq-kaynak kitabxanasını Rust-a gətirmək məqsədilə təklif edir. Rust maşın öyrənmək proqramlarını inşa etmək üçün ehtiyacı olan sistemlərin programlama dilidir, amma hələ də NLP kitablarını istifadə etmək üçün hazırlanmaq üçün hazırlanmır. Məsələn kitaphanesi, rust-bert, modern dil modellərini və pipelines (məsələn çeviriş ya da summarizasyon üçün hazırlanmaq üçün hazırlanır). Bu, Rust toplumunun NLP ekspertlərindən və spesialistlərindən daha böyük tədbirləşməsinə imkan verir. Bu kitabxanın Rust'da NLP ekosisteminin gelişməsini tezləşdirəcəyini ümid edir. Kitabxanın fəaliyyətli təhsil edilməsi və faydalanır. https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>প্রাকৃতিক ভাষা প্রক্রিয়ার গবেষণায় সাম্প্রতিক অগ্রগতি পাইথনের একটি সমৃদ্ধ উন্মুক্ত উৎস অর্থনৈতিক ব্যবস্থা উন এই প্রযুক্তির গণতান্ত্রিকভাবে এনএলপি প্রশিক্ষকদের অনুমতি দেয়া লাইব্রেরীগুলো কিন্তু বিশেষজ্ঞ বিশেষজ্ঞেরা এই প্রযুক্তির গ খোলা সোর্স এনএলপি ইকোসিস্টেমের ফলাফল ভাষার মধ্যে বিভিন্ন। এই কাজ একটি নতুন উন্মুক্ত সোর্স লাইব্রেরী প্রস্তাব করেছে যার উদ্দেশ্য হচ্ছে রাষ্ট্র-অফ-আর্ট-আর্ট এনএলপি রুস রুস্ট একটি সিস্টেম প্রোগ্রামিং ভাষা, যার জন্য মেশিন শিক্ষা প্রাপ্ত অ্যাপ্লিকেশন নির্মাণের জন্য ভিত্তিক ভাষা প্রয়োজন কিন্তু এখন প্রস্তাবিত লাইব্রেরি, রুস-বার্ট, আধুনিক ভাষার মডেল এবং পাইপেলাইন ব্যবহারের জন্য প্রস্তুত (উদাহরণস্বরূপ অনুবাদ অথবা সার্ এনএলপি বিশেষজ্ঞ এবং বিশেষজ্ঞ উভয়ের কাছ থেকে রুস্ট সম্প্রদায় আরো উন্নয়নের সুযোগ দেয়। আশা করা হচ্ছে এই লাইব্রেরীটি রুস্টের এনএলপি ইকোসিস্টেমের উন্নয়ন ত্বরান্বিত করবে। লাইব্রেরীটি সক্রিয় উন্নয়ন এবং প্রাপ্ত https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Nedavni napredak istraživanja prirodnog jezika podržan je razvojom bogatog ekosistema otvorenog izvora u Pythonu. Biblioteke koje dozvoljavaju praktičarima NLP-a, ali također ne-specijalistima da utjecaju na modele države umjetnosti, bile su instrumentalne u demokratizaciji ove tehnologije. Zazrelo ekosistema otvorenog izvora NLP međutim se razlikuje između jezika. Ovaj rad predlaže novu biblioteku otvorenog izvora koja je ciljana dovesti državni NLP u Rust. Rust je jezik programiranja sustava za koje su temelji potrebni za izgradnju aplikacija za učenje mašina dostupni, ali još uvijek nedostaju knjižnice NLP-a spremne za upotrebu. Predložena biblioteka, rust-bert, implementira moderne jezičke modele i spremne za upotrebu cijevi (na primjer prevod ili sažetak). To omogućava daljnji razvoj Rust zajednice od stručnjaka NLP-a i ne-specijalista. Nadam se da će ova biblioteka ubrzati razvoj ekosistema NLP u Rustu. Biblioteka je pod aktivnim razvojom i dostupnim u https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>El progrès recent en la recerca sobre el processament de llenguatges naturals ha estat sostenit pel desenvolupament d'un ecosistema de codi obert ric a Python. Libraries allowing NLP practitioners but also non-specialists to leverage state-of-the-art models have been instrumental in the democratization of this technology.  Tot i així, la maturitat del ecosistema NLP de codi obert varieix entre llengües. Aquesta obra propon una nova biblioteca de codi obert destinada a portar NLP d'última generació a Rust. Rust és un llenguatge de programació de sistemes per al qual les fonacions requerides per construir aplicacions d'aprenentatge màquinari estan disponibles però encara falten biblioteques de NLP preparates d'ús. La biblioteca proposada, rust-bert, implementa models moderns de llenguatge i pipelines pràctics d'ús (per exemple traducció o resum). Això permet més desenvolupament de la comunitat Rust, tant d'experts del NLP com de no especialistes. Esperem que aquesta biblioteca acceleri el desenvolupament de l'ecosistema NLP a Rust. La biblioteca està en desenvolupament actiu i està disponible a https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Nedávný pokrok ve výzkumu zpracování přirozeného jazyka byl podpořen rozvojem bohatého open source ekosystému v Pythonu. Knihovny umožňující pracovníkům NLP, ale také nespecialistům využívat nejmodernější modely, byly klíčové pro demokratizaci této technologie. Zralost open-source NLP ekosystému se však liší v jednotlivých jazycích. Tato práce navrhuje novou open-source knihovnu, jejímž cílem je přinést do Rustu nejmodernější NLP. Rust je systémový programovací jazyk, pro který jsou k dispozici základy potřebné pro vytváření aplikací strojového učení, ale stále chybí připravené, end-to-end knihovny NLP. Navrhovaná knihovna rost-bert implementuje moderní jazykové modely a připravené pipelines (např. překlad nebo shrnutí). To umožňuje další rozvoj komunity Rust od odborníků NLP i od nespecialistů. Doufáme, že tato knihovna urychlí rozvoj ekosystému NLP v Rustu. Knihovna je v aktivním rozvoji a je k dispozici na adrese: https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Hiljutisi edusamme looduskeele töötlemise uuringutes on toetanud rikkaliku avatud lähtekoodiga ökosüsteemi arendamine Pythonis. Raamatukogud, mis võimaldavad NLP praktikutel, kuid ka mittespetsialistidel kasutada kaasaegseid mudeleid, on olnud olulised selle tehnoloogia demokratiseerimisel. Avatud lähtekoodiga uue tööprogrammi ökosüsteemi küpsus on keelte lõikes siiski erinev. Käesolev töö pakub välja uue avatud lähtekoodiga raamatukogu, mille eesmärk on tuua Rusti kaasaegne NLP. Rust on süsteemide programmeerimiskeel, mille jaoks masinõppe rakenduste ehitamiseks vajalikud alused on kättesaadavad, kuid siiski puuduvad kasutusvalmis, otsast otsani NLP teegid. Pakutud raamatukogu, rust-bert, rakendab kaasaegseid keelemudeleid ja kasutusvalmis torujuhtmeid (nt tõlkimine või kokkuvõte). See võimaldab Rusti kogukonnal edasist arengut nii NLP ekspertidelt kui ka mittespetsialistidelt. Loodetakse, et see raamatukogu kiirendab Rusti NLP ökosüsteemi arengut. Raamatukogu on aktiivsel arendamisel ja kättesaadav aadressil https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Luonnonkielen käsittelytutkimuksen viimeaikaista kehitystä on tukenut runsaan avoimen lähdekoodin ekosysteemin kehittäminen Pythoniin. Kirjastot, joiden avulla NLP:n ammattilaiset mutta myös ei-asiantuntijat voivat hyödyntää viimeisimpiä malleja, ovat olleet keskeisessä asemassa tämän teknologian demokratisoinnissa. Avoimen lähdekoodin NLP-ekosysteemin kypsyys vaihtelee kuitenkin eri kielillä. Tässä työssä ehdotetaan uutta avoimen lähdekoodin kirjastoa, jonka tavoitteena on tuoda Rustiin uusinta NLP:tä. Rust on järjestelmäohjelmointikieli, jolle koneoppimissovellusten rakentamiseen tarvittavat perusteet ovat saatavilla, mutta silti puuttuu valmiita, end-to-end NLP kirjastoja. Ehdotettu kirjasto, rust-bert, toteuttaa nykyaikaisia kielimalleja ja käyttövalmiita putkistoja (esimerkiksi käännös tai yhteenveto). Tämä mahdollistaa Rust-yhteisön jatkokehityksen sekä NLP:n asiantuntijoilta että ei-asiantuntijoilta. Kirjaston toivotaan nopeuttavan Rustin NLP-ekosysteemin kehitystä. Kirjastoa kehitetään aktiivisesti ja se on saatavilla osoitteessa https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ha>@ info: status Libraries na yarda da masu amfani da NLP, amma kuma ba masu masu ƙayyade da mazaɓa-mazaɓa-masu-sanawa sun kasance masu ƙaranci a cikin Democratization of this technical. Tsarin aikin da aka buɗe na shirin ayuka na NLP, ko kuma yana da sãɓãni a tsakanin harshe. Wannan aikin yana ƙayyade wata littãfi na buɗe-source don ya yi amfani da ta zo da state-of-the-art NLP zuwa Rust. Rust yana wata harshen shiryoyin ayuka na'ura da kwamfyuta, wanda aka buƙata asalin da za'a ƙiƙira shiryoyin ayukan ayuka masu amfani da kwamfyutan tebur, kuma amma ba'a ƙara ba da littafan-da za'a yi amfani da shi, zuwa-ƙari na NLP. Maktabar da aka buƙata, rust-bert, yana amfani da misãlai na harshen yanzu da shirin da aka yi amfani da pibelines (misali, fassarar ko ƙararinsa). Wannan yana yarda da ƙarami na Rust daga duk masu fitarwa na NLP da masu hushi. Ina fãtan wannan littafi zai yi gaggãwa da kwamfyutan tebur na NaLP da Rust. The library is under active development and available at  https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>התקדמות האחרונה במחקר עיבוד שפת טבעית תומכה על ידי התפתחות של אקולוגית מקור פתוח עשירה בפיטון. ספריות שמאפשרות למאמנים של NLP אבל גם לא מומחים להשתמש בדוגמנים מצוינים היו משמעותיים בדמוקרטיזציה של הטכנולוגיה הזאת. הבגרות של אקולוגית NLP מקור פתוח שונה בכל מקרה בין שפות. העבודה הזו מציעה ספרייה חדשה במקור פתוח שמתכוונת להביא NLP מצוין לארסט. ראסט היא שפת תוכנת מערכות שבה היסודות הנדרשות לבנות אפשרויות לימוד מכונות זמינות, אך עדיין חסרות ספריות NLP מוכנות להשתמש. הספרייה המוצעת, רוסט-ברט, מפעילה דוגמנים לשפה מודרניים וצינורות מוכנים להשתמש (למשל תרגום או סאמריזציה). זה מאפשר התפתחות נוספות על ידי קהילת ראסט גם ממומחים NLP וגם לא מומחים. מקווה שהספרייה הזו תאיץ את התפתחות של האקו-מערכת NLP בראסט. הספרייה נמצאת תחת פיתוח פעיל והיא זמינה ב https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>FindOK Library Perintah kapan kelas nLP Open-source saiki dipun Wurlu iki supoya ngewehke kelompok sing gawe nggawe tarjamahan kanggo ngira stad-of-the-arts NLP kanggo Rust. Rust kuwi sistem sing lengkang program sing dibutungan kanggo nggawe aplikasi sistem cilana sing bisa nêmên, kuwi mau durung ono wektu nggawe sistem sing bisa-bisa uga, end-to-end LP puk dolanan. Laptop" and "Desktop Iki supoyo perusahaan kanggo nglanggar kanggo kowé komunitas Rust nang angkang dipolehasan NLP karo nek Gak-perusahaan Punika dipolehasé karo akeh stiftar kuwi nggawe Ngubah ekosistem NLP ning Rust. Pibloteka iku ning akeh pengguna-akeh lan akeh dumadhi https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Nedavni napredek v raziskavah obdelave naravnega jezika je podprl razvoj bogatega odprtokodnega ekosistema v Pythonu. Knjižnice, ki omogočajo izvajalcem NLP, pa tudi nespecialistom, da izkoristijo najsodobnejše modele, so bile ključnega pomena pri demokratizaciji te tehnologije. Zrelost odprtokodnega ekosistema NLP pa se med jeziki razlikuje. V tem delu je predlagana nova odprtokodna knjižnica, katere cilj je v Rust prinesti najsodobnejšo NLP. Rust je sistemski programski jezik, za katerega so na voljo temelji, potrebni za gradnjo aplikacij strojnega učenja, vendar še vedno nimajo pripravljenih knjižnic NLP od konca do konca. Predlagana knjižnica rust-bert uvaja sodobne jezikovne modele in pripravljene cevovode (npr. prevod ali povzetek). To omogoča nadaljnji razvoj skupnosti Rust s strani strokovnjakov NLP in nespecialistov. Upamo, da bo ta knjižnica pospešila razvoj ekosistema NLP v Rustu. Knjižnica je v aktivnem razvoju in je na voljo na spletni strani https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>སྤྱིར་བཏང་ནུས་ཀྱི་སྐད་རིགས་ལས དཔེ་དབུས་གཞུང་གིས་NLP སྟོན་མཁན་གྱི་སྤྱོད་མཁན་དང་ཁྱད་ཆོས་མེད་པའི་དབུགས་གཟུགས་རིས་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་སྤྱོད་ཆགས་པ་ཡིན་པས། ཁ་ཕྱེས་ཐོག་མའི་ཁུངས་ལུགས་པའི་NLP སྒྲིག་འགོད་གྱི་ཆེ་རྐྱེན་ཚད་སྐད་རིགས་དབར་སྦྲེལ་མཐུད་ཡོད། This work proposes a new open-source library aimed at bringing state-of-the-art NLP to Rust. Rust is a system programming language for which the foundations required to build machine learning applications are available but still lacks ready-to-use, end-to-end NLP libraries. The proposed library, rust-bert, implements modern language models and ready-to-use pipelines (for example translation or summarization). འདིས་NLP གླེང་སྡོམ་དང་མི་ཁྱད་པ་གཉིས་ལས་རྒྱལ་ཁབ་ཀྱི་ཚོགས་སྡེ་མང་པོ་ཞིག་གིས་ རྒྱ་ནག་གི་དྲ་རྒྱའི་ནང་དུ་NLP་འཛམ་གླིང་གི་ཡར་རྒྱས་འགྲོ་བཞིན་དགོས་པ་རེད། མཛུབ་སྤྱོད་དང་སྤྱོད་ཆོས་དུས་ལ་ཡར་སྐྱེལ་དང་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་ཡོད་པ https://github.com/guillaume-be/rust-bert.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Open Korean Corpora : A Practical Report<fixed-case>K</fixed-case>orean Corpora: A Practical Report</title>
      <author><first>Won Ik</first><last>Cho</last></author>
      <author><first>Sangwhan</first><last>Moon</last></author>
      <author><first>Youngsook</first><last>Song</last></author>
      <pages>85–93</pages>
      <abstract>Korean is often referred to as a low-resource language in the research community. While this claim is partially true, it is also because the availability of resources is inadequately advertised and curated. This work curates and reviews a list of Korean corpora, first describing institution-level resource development, then further iterate through a list of current open datasets for different types of tasks. We then propose a direction on how open-source dataset construction and releases should be done for less-resourced languages to promote research.</abstract>
      <url hash="6aeea4aa">2020.nlposs-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlposs-1.12</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939751" />
      <bibkey>cho-etal-2020-open</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/clovacall">ClovaCall</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/natural-questions">Natural Questions</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>PySBD : Pragmatic Sentence Boundary Disambiguation<fixed-case>P</fixed-case>y<fixed-case>SBD</fixed-case>: Pragmatic Sentence Boundary Disambiguation</title>
      <author><first>Nipun</first><last>Sadvilkar</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Neumann</last></author>
      <pages>110–114</pages>
      <abstract>We present a rule-based sentence boundary disambiguation Python package that works out-of-the-box for 22 languages. We aim to provide a realistic segmenter which can provide <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_(linguistics)">logical sentences</a> even when the format and domain of the input text is unknown. In our work, we adapt the Golden Rules Set (a language specific set of sentence boundary exemplars) originally implemented as a ruby gem pragmatic segmenter which we ported to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)">Python</a> with additional improvements and functionality. PySBD passes 97.92 % of the Golden Rule Set examplars for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, an improvement of 25 % over the next best open source Python tool.</abstract>
      <url hash="a8f7aca7">2020.nlposs-1.15</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="629e1b58">2020.nlposs-1.15.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlposs-1.15</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939754" />
      <bibkey>sadvilkar-neumann-2020-pysbd</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/nipunsadvilkar/pySBD" additional="false">nipunsadvilkar/pySBD</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/genia">GENIA</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>SacreROUGE : An Open-Source Library for Using and Developing Summarization Evaluation Metrics<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>acre<fixed-case>ROUGE</fixed-case>: An Open-Source Library for Using and Developing Summarization Evaluation Metrics</title>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Deutsch</last></author>
      <author><first>Dan</first><last>Roth</last></author>
      <pages>120–125</pages>
      <abstract>We present SacreROUGE, an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software">open-source library</a> for using and developing summarization evaluation metrics. SacreROUGE removes many obstacles that researchers face when using or developing metrics : (1) The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_(computing)">library</a> provides Python wrappers around the official implementations of existing evaluation metrics so they share a common, easy-to-use interface ; (2) it provides functionality to evaluate how well any metric implemented in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_(computing)">library</a> correlates to human-annotated judgments, so no additional code needs to be written for a new evaluation metric ; and (3) it includes scripts for loading datasets that contain human judgments so they can easily be used for evaluation. This work describes the design of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_(computing)">library</a>, including the core Metric interface, the command-line API for evaluating summarization models and metrics, and the scripts to load and reformat publicly available datasets. The development of SacreROUGE is ongoing and open to contributions from the community.</abstract>
      <url hash="2c4f247d">2020.nlposs-1.17</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="16198289">2020.nlposs-1.17.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.pdf</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlposs-1.17</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939755" />
      <bibkey>deutsch-roth-2020-sacrerouge</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/danieldeutsch/sacrerouge" additional="false">danieldeutsch/sacrerouge</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>