<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.alta">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-02-07">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the The 18th Annual Workshop of the Australasian Language Technology Association</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Maria</first><last>Kim</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Daniel</first><last>Beck</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Meladel</first><last>Mistica</last></editor>
      <publisher>Australasian Language Technology Association</publisher>
      <address>Virtual Workshop</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <url hash="5ebe2288">2020.alta-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="c94ee8a9">2020.alta-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>alta-2020-australasian</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Feature-Based Forensic Text Comparison Using a Poisson Model for Likelihood Ratio Estimation<fixed-case>P</fixed-case>oisson Model for Likelihood Ratio Estimation</title>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Carne</last></author>
      <author><first>Shunichi</first><last>Ishihara</last></author>
      <pages>32–42</pages>
      <abstract>Score- and feature-based methods are the two main ones for estimating a forensic likelihood ratio (LR) quantifying the strength of evidence. In this forensic text comparison (FTC) study, a score-based method using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosine_distance">Cosine distance</a> is compared with a feature-based method built on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poisson_kernel">Poisson model</a> with texts collected from 2,157 authors. Distance measures (e.g. Burrows’s Delta, Cosine distance) are a standard tool in authorship attribution studies. Thus, the implementation of a score-based method using a distance measure is naturally the first step for estimating LRs for textual evidence. However, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Textual_data">textual data</a> often violates the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">statistical assumptions</a> underlying <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">distance-based models</a>. Furthermore, such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> only assess the similarity, not the typicality, of the objects (i.e. documents) under comparison. A Poisson model is theoretically more appropriate than distance-based measures for authorship attribution, but it has never been tested with linguistic text evidence within the LR framework. The log-LR cost (Cllr) was used to assess the performance of the two methods. This study demonstrates that : (1) the feature-based method outperforms the score-based method by a Cllr value of ca. 0.09 under the best-performing settings and ; (2) the performance of the feature-based method can be further improved by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_selection">feature selection</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="beca8450">2020.alta-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>carne-ishihara-2020-feature</bibkey>
    <title_ar>مقارنة النص الجنائي القائم على الميزة باستخدام نموذج بواسون لتقدير نسبة الاحتمالية</title_ar>
      <title_es>Comparación de textos forenses basados en características mediante un modelo de Poisson para la estimación de la razón de probabilidad</title_es>
      <title_pt>Comparação de texto forense com base em recursos usando um modelo de Poisson para estimativa de razão de verossimilhança</title_pt>
      <title_ja>尤度比推定のためのポアソンモデルを使用した特徴ベースのフォレンジックテキストの比較</title_ja>
      <title_zh>取证文本,用泊松模形似然比量</title_zh>
      <title_hi>सुविधा-आधारित फोरेंसिक पाठ तुलना संभावना अनुपात अनुमान के लिए एक Poisson मॉडल का उपयोग कर</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Comparáid Téacs Fóiréinseach Gné-Bhunaithe ag Úsáid Samhail Poisson le haghaidh Meastachán Cóimheasa Dóchúlachta</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ფუნქციის ფორენსიკური ტექსტის შემდგომარება შესაძლებელია Poisson მოდელის გამოყენება</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Funkcióalapú törvényszéki szövegösszehasonlítás Poisson modell használatával a valószínűségi arány becsléséhez</title_hu>
      <title_el>Σύγκριση εγκληματολογικού κειμένου βάσει χαρακτηριστικών χρησιμοποιώντας ένα μοντέλο για την εκτίμηση της αναλογίας πιθανότητας</title_el>
      <title_kk>Қасиеттерді негіздеген мәтін салыстыру ықтималдық қасиеттердің Poisson үлгісін қолданып</title_kk>
      <title_it>Confronto del testo forense basato sulle caratteristiche utilizzando un modello Poisson per la stima del rapporto di probabilità</title_it>
      <title_lt>Atitikties pagrindu pagrįstas teisminis teksto palyginimas naudojant nuodų modelį tikėtino santykio įvertinimui</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Користејќи отровен модел за проценка на стапката на веројатност</title_mk>
      <title_mn>Хэрэглээний үндсэн судалгааны текст харьцуулалт</title_mn>
      <title_ml>ഒരു പോയിസോണ്‍ മോഡല്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള പ്രിയേറ്റ് റേഷന്‍ എസ്റ്റിമേഷന്‍റെ അടിസ്ഥാനമായ ഫെന്‍സിക് വാചകം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Tqabbil tat-test forensiku bbażat fuq il-karatteristiċi bl-użu ta’ Mudell ta’ Poisson għall-Istima tal-Proporzjon ta’ Probabbiltà</title_mt>
      <title_no>Samanlikning med forgensk tekst med funksjonsbasert bruk av eit Poisson-modell for sannsynleg forhold</title_no>
      <title_pl>Porównanie tekstów sądowych oparte na funkcjach przy użyciu modelu Poissona do oszacowania współczynnika prawdopodobieństwa</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Compararea textelor criminalistice bazate pe caracteristici utilizând un model Poisson pentru estimarea ratei de probabilitate</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Uspoređenje forenzičkog teksta na osnovu karakteristike korištenje modela Poisson za procjenu proporcija Likelihood</title_sr>
      <title_si>විශේෂතාවක් අධිරූපය පාළුවක් සම්බන්ධතාවක් ප්‍රයෝජනය ප්‍රයෝජනය ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Isticmaalka Poisson Model for Sikkerho Ratio Estimation</title_so>
      <title_sv>Funktionsbaserad kriminalteknisk textjämförelse med hjälp av en Poisson-modell för uppskattning av sannolikhetsförhållande</title_sv>
      <title_ms>Feature-Based Forensic Text Comparison Using a Poisson Model for Likelihood Ratio Estimation</title_ms>
      <title_ta>விகிதமான விகிதம்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Feature-Based Forensic Text Comparison Using a Poisson Model for Likelihood Ratio Estimation</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Comment</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Đối tượng nhãn hiệu quả dựa trên Sử dụng mô hình độc tính cho khả năng đánh giá tỉ lệ</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Функционално базирано съдебно-медицинско сравнение на текста с използване на модел на Поасон за оценка на съотношението на вероятността</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Functiegebaseerde forensische tekstvergelijking met behulp van een Poisson-model voor schatting van de waarschijnlijkheidsratio</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Uspoređenje forenzičkog teksta na osnovu karakteristike Koristeći model Poisson za procjenu procjene proporcije Likelihood</title_hr>
      <title_da>Funktionsbaseret retsmedicinsk tekstsammenligning ved hjælp af en Poisson-model til estimering af sandsynlighedsforhold</title_da>
      <title_de>Funktionsbasierter forensischer Textvergleich unter Verwendung eines Poisson-Modells zur Sch瓣tzung des Wahrscheinlichkeitsverh瓣ltnisses</title_de>
      <title_id>Perbandingan Teks Forensik Berdasarkan Feature Menggunakan Model Poison untuk Perkiraan Nisbah Kemungkinan</title_id>
      <title_ko>파송 모델을 바탕으로 추정된 특징에 기초한 법의학 텍스트 비교</title_ko>
      <title_fa>Щ…ЩӮШ§ЫҢШіЩҮвҖҢШіШ§ШІЫҢ Щ…ШӘЩҶ ЩӮШ§ЩҶЩҲЩҶЫҢ ШЁШұ ЩҫШ§ЫҢЩҮ ЩҲЫҢЪҳЩҮ Ш§ШіШӘЩҒШ§ШҜЩҮ Ш§ШІ Щ…ШҜЩ„ Poisson ШЁШұШ§ЫҢ Ш§ШұШІЫҢШ§ШЁЫҢ ЩҶШіШЁШӘ Likelihood</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Kulinganishwa na maandishi ya Kifaransa kwa kutumia Modeli ya Poisson kwa ajili ya Hesabu ya Kupunguzwa</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Feature-Based Forensic Text Comparison Using a Poisson Model for Likelihood Ratio Estimation</title_tr>
      <title_af>Feature- Based Forensic Text Vergelyking Gebruik ' n Poisson Model vir Likelihood Verhouding</title_af>
      <title_sq>Krahasimi i tekstit forensik bazuar në funksionet duke përdorur një model helmi për vlerësimin e raportit të mundësisë</title_sq>
      <title_am>የፊደል ቅርጽ ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_hy>Օգտագործելով թունավոր մոդել հավանականության հարաբերության գնահատման համար</title_hy>
      <title_az>Likelihood qiyməti üçün Poisson Modelini istifadə edərək Fərqli Metin Qərqləşdirməsi</title_az>
      <title_bn>বৈশিষ্ট্য-ভিত্তিক ফরেসিক লেখার তুলনা</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Comparació de text forensic basada en característiques utilitzant un model de Poisson per estimar la proporció de probabilitat</title_ca>
      <title_et>Funktsioonipõhine kohtuekspertiisi teksti võrdlus Poissoni mudeli abil tõenäosuse suhte hindamiseks</title_et>
      <title_cs>Forenzní porovnání textů založené na funkcích pomocí Poissonova modelu pro odhad pravděpodobnosti</title_cs>
      <title_bs>Uspoređenje forenzičkog teksta na osnovu karakteristike koristeći model Poisson za procjenu procjene proporcije Likelihood</title_bs>
      <title_fi>Ominaisuuksiin perustuva rikostekninen tekstivertailu Poisson-mallin avulla todennäköisyyssuhteen arvioimiseksi</title_fi>
      <title_jv>&lt;control&gt;&lt;shift&gt;U</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Primerjava forenzičnega besedila na podlagi funkcij z uporabo Poissonovega modela za oceno razmerja verjetnosti</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>Feature-Based Forensic Text Comparison Using a Poisson Model for Likelihood Ratio Estimation</title_bo>
      <title_he>שיוון טקסט משפטי מבוסס על תכונות באמצעות מודל רעל להערכת יחסי סבירות</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>الطرق القائمة على النقاط والميزات هما الطريقتان الرئيسيتان لتقدير نسبة احتمالية الطب الشرعي (LR) التي تحدد قوة الأدلة. في دراسة مقارنة النص الجنائي (FTC) ، تتم مقارنة طريقة قائمة على النقاط باستخدام مسافة جيب التمام مع طريقة قائمة على الميزات مبنية على نموذج بواسون مع نصوص تم جمعها من 2157 مؤلفًا. مقاييس المسافة (مثل دلتا بوروز ، مسافة جيب التمام) هي أداة قياسية في دراسات إسناد التأليف. وبالتالي ، فإن تنفيذ طريقة قائمة على النقاط باستخدام مقياس المسافة هو بطبيعة الحال الخطوة الأولى لتقدير LRs للأدلة النصية. ومع ذلك ، غالبًا ما تنتهك البيانات النصية الافتراضات الإحصائية الكامنة وراء النماذج القائمة على المسافة. علاوة على ذلك ، فإن هذه النماذج تقيم فقط التشابه ، وليس النموذجية ، للكائنات (أي المستندات) قيد المقارنة. يعد نموذج بواسون أكثر ملاءمة من الناحية النظرية من المقاييس القائمة على المسافة لإسناد التأليف ، ولكن لم يتم اختباره أبدًا باستخدام دليل النص اللغوي في إطار LR. تم استخدام تكلفة log-LR (Cllr) لتقييم أداء الطريقتين. توضح هذه الدراسة أن: (1) الطريقة القائمة على الميزة تتفوق على الطريقة القائمة على النقاط بواسطة قيمة Cllr كاليفورنيا. 0.09 تحت أفضل الإعدادات أداء و ؛ (2) يمكن تحسين أداء الطريقة القائمة على الميزة بشكل أكبر عن طريق اختيار الميزة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Os métodos baseados em pontuação e recursos são os dois principais para estimar uma razão de probabilidade forense (LR) que quantifica a força da evidência. Neste estudo de comparação de texto forense (FTC), um método baseado em pontuação usando a distância cosseno é comparado com um método baseado em recursos construído em um modelo de Poisson com textos coletados de 2.157 autores. Medidas de distância (por exemplo, Delta de Burrows, distância de cosseno) são uma ferramenta padrão em estudos de atribuição de autoria. Assim, a implementação de um método baseado em pontuação usando uma medida de distância é naturalmente o primeiro passo para estimar LRs para evidências textuais. No entanto, os dados textuais geralmente violam as suposições estatísticas subjacentes aos modelos baseados em distância. Além disso, esses modelos avaliam apenas a semelhança, não a tipicidade, dos objetos (ou seja, documentos) em comparação. Um modelo de Poisson é teoricamente mais apropriado do que medidas baseadas em distância para atribuição de autoria, mas nunca foi testado com evidências linguísticas de texto dentro da estrutura de LR. O custo log-LR (Cllr) foi utilizado para avaliar o desempenho dos dois métodos. Este estudo demonstra que: (1) o método baseado em características supera o método baseado em pontuação por um valor Cllr de ca. 0,09 nas configurações de melhor desempenho e; (2) o desempenho do método baseado em recursos pode ser melhorado ainda mais pela seleção de recursos.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Los métodos basados en puntuaciones y características son los dos métodos principales para estimar un cociente de probabilidad forense (LR) que cuantifica la solidez de la evidencia. En este estudio de comparación de textos forenses (FTC), se compara un método basado en puntuaciones que utiliza la distancia del coseno con un método basado en características construido en un modelo de Poisson con textos recopilados de 2.157 autores. Las medidas de distancia (por ejemplo, Delta de Burrows, distancia del coseno) son una herramienta estándar en los estudios de atribución de autoría. Por lo tanto, la implementación de un método basado en puntajes utilizando una medida de distancia es, naturalmente, el primer paso para estimar los LR para la evidencia textual. Sin embargo, los datos textuales a menudo violan los supuestos estadísticos que subyacen a los modelos basados en la distancia. Además, estos modelos solo evalúan la similitud, no la tipicidad, de los objetos (es decir, documentos) que se comparan. Un modelo de Poisson es teóricamente más apropiado que las medidas basadas en la distancia para la atribución de autoría, pero nunca se ha probado con evidencia de texto lingüístico dentro del marco de LR. Se utilizó el costo log-LR (Cllr) para evaluar el rendimiento de los dos métodos. Este estudio demuestra que: (1) el método basado en características supera al método basado en puntuaciones en un valor de Cllr de aproximadamente 0,09 en la configuración de mejor rendimiento y; (2) el rendimiento del método basado en características se puede mejorar aún más mediante la selección de características.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_zh>盖分数特征之法,量化度强度似然比(LR)之二要也。 于此证本较(FTC),用余弦相去分数,与泊松模形较之,当模有从2,157名作者所收也。 距(如 Burrows 三角洲、余弦)者,人归因论之具也。 故用距量成分数之法,自是度文本之LR首也。 然文本数常违,所据之数假设。 凡此诸质(文档)之相似性,非典型性也。 以理言之,泊松形势宜于去就,未尝试以语言文本于LR框架内也。 log-LR 成本 (Cllr) 以质二术之性。 本论曰:(1)至善置下,优于分数,Cllr值约为0.09而并行。 (2)者,所以为进一步提高也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>स्कोर- और फीचर-आधारित तरीके सबूत की ताकत को मापने वाले फोरेंसिक संभावना अनुपात (एलआर) का अनुमान लगाने के लिए दो मुख्य हैं। इस फोरेंसिक पाठ तुलना (एफटीसी) अध्ययन में, कोसाइन दूरी का उपयोग करके एक स्कोर-आधारित विधि की तुलना 2,157 लेखकों से एकत्र किए गए ग्रंथों के साथ पॉइसन मॉडल पर निर्मित एक सुविधा-आधारित विधि के साथ की जाती है। दूरी के उपाय (जैसे Burrows डेल्टा, कोसाइन दूरी) लेखकीय विशेषता अध्ययन में एक मानक उपकरण हैं। इस प्रकार, दूरी के उपाय का उपयोग करके एक स्कोर-आधारित विधि का कार्यान्वयन स्वाभाविक रूप से पाठ्य साक्ष्य के लिए एलआर का अनुमान लगाने के लिए पहला कदम है। हालांकि, पाठ्य डेटा अक्सर दूरी-आधारित मॉडल के अंतर्निहित सांख्यिकीय मान्यताओं का उल्लंघन करता है। इसके अलावा, इस तरह के मॉडल केवल समानता का आकलन करते हैं, न कि तुलना के तहत वस्तुओं (यानी दस्तावेजों) की विशिष्टता। एक पॉइसन मॉडल सैद्धांतिक रूप से लेखकत्व एट्रिब्यूशन के लिए दूरी-आधारित उपायों की तुलना में अधिक उपयुक्त है, लेकिन इसे एलआर फ्रेमवर्क के भीतर भाषाई पाठ साक्ष्य के साथ कभी भी परीक्षण नहीं किया गया है। लॉग-LR लागत (Cllr) का उपयोग दो विधियों के प्रदर्शन का आकलन करने के लिए किया गया था। यह अध्ययन दर्शाता है कि: (1) सुविधा-आधारित विधि सबसे अच्छा प्रदर्शन सेटिंग्स के तहत ca. 0.09 के Cllr मान द्वारा स्कोर-आधारित विधि outperforms और; (2) सुविधा-आधारित विधि के प्रदर्शन को सुविधा चयन द्वारा और बेहतर बनाया जा सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ja>スコアと特徴に基づく方法は、証拠の強さを定量化するための法医学的尤度比（ LR ）を推定するための2つの主な方法です。 このフォレンジックテキスト比較（ ＦＴＣ ）研究では、コサイン距離を使用したスコアベースの方法を、２ ， １ ５ ７人の著者から収集されたテキストを有するポアソンモデル上に構築された特徴ベースの方法と比較する。 距離の測定（例えば、バローズのデルタ、コサインの距離）は、著者帰属研究における標準的なツールです。 したがって、距離測定を使用するスコアベースの方法の実施は、当然ながら、テキスト証拠のためのＬＲを推定するための第１のステップである。 しかし、テキストデータは、距離ベースのモデルの基礎となる統計的仮定にしばしば違反する。 さらに、そのようなモデルは、比較対象のオブジェクト（すなわち、文書）の典型性ではなく、類似性を評価するだけである。 ポアソンモデルは、著者の帰属に関する距離ベースの尺度よりも理論的に適切であるが、LRフレームワーク内の言語的テキスト証拠でテストされたことはない。 Ｌｏｇ － ＬＲコスト（ Ｃｌｌｒ ）を使用して、２つの方法の性能を評価した。 本研究では、(1)特徴ベースの方法は、最高性能の設定下でCllr値が0.09程度でスコアベースの方法よりも優れていること、(2)特徴ベースの方法のパフォーマンスは、特徴の選択によってさらに向上させることができることを実証している。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ga>Is iad modhanna atá bunaithe ar scór agus gné an dá phríomh-mhodh chun cóimheas dóchúlachta fóiréinseach (CD) a mheas agus neart na fianaise á chainníochtú. Sa staidéar seo ar chomparáid téacs fhóiréinseach (FTC), déantar modh scórbhunaithe a úsáideann an fad Cosine a chur i gcomparáid le modh gné-bhunaithe a tógadh ar mhúnla Poisson le téacsanna a bailíodh ó 2,157 údar. Uirlis chaighdeánach is ea ciantomhais (m.sh. Burrows's Delta, Cosine distance) i staidéir ar leithdháileachán údair. Mar sin, is é cur i bhfeidhm modh scór-bhunaithe ag úsáid ciantomhais an chéad chéim go nádúrtha chun L-anna a mheas le haghaidh fianaise téacsúil. Mar sin féin, is minic a sháraíonn sonraí téacsúla na boinn tuisceana staidrimh is bun leis na samhlacha cianbhunaithe. Ina theannta sin, ní dhéanann samhlacha den sórt sin ach measúnú ar chosúlacht, ní ar thipiciúlacht, na n-oibiachtaí (i.e. doiciméid) faoi chomparáid. Tá samhail Poisson níos oiriúnaí go teoiriciúil ná bearta cianbhunaithe do shannadh údair, ach níor tástáladh riamh le fianaise téacs teangeolaíoch laistigh den chreat LR. Baineadh úsáid as an gcostas log-LR (Clr) chun feidhmíocht an dá mhodh a mheas. Léiríonn an staidéar seo: (1) go n-éiríonn níos fearr leis an modh gné-bhunaithe ná an modh scórbhunaithe ag luach Cmhl. 0.09 faoi na socruithe is fearr feidhmíochta agus; (2) is féidir feidhmíocht an mhodha gné-bhunaithe a fheabhsú tuilleadh trí roghnú gnéithe.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Οι μέθοδοι που βασίζονται στο σκορ και στα χαρακτηριστικά είναι οι δύο κύριες για την εκτίμηση ενός λόγου εγκληματολογικής πιθανότητας (LR) που ποσοτικοποιεί τη δύναμη των αποδεικτικών στοιχείων. Σε αυτή τη μελέτη της εγκληματολογικής σύγκρισης κειμένου (FTC) συγκρίνεται μια μέθοδος βασισμένη στην βαθμολογία που χρησιμοποιεί την απόσταση Cosine με μια μέθοδο βασισμένη σε χαρακτηριστικά βασισμένη σε ένα μοντέλο Poisson με κείμενα που συλλέγονται από συγγραφείς 2,157. Τα μέτρα απόστασης (π.χ. Δέλτα του Μπάροους, απόσταση Cosine) είναι ένα τυπικό εργαλείο στις μελέτες αποδόσεων συγγραφέων. Έτσι, η εφαρμογή μιας μεθόδου βάσει βαθμολογίας που χρησιμοποιεί μέτρο απόστασης είναι φυσικά το πρώτο βήμα για την εκτίμηση των LR για στοιχεία κειμένου. Ωστόσο, τα δεδομένα κειμένου συχνά παραβιάζουν τις στατιστικές παραδοχές που βασίζονται στα μοντέλα απόστασης. Επιπλέον, τα μοντέλα αυτά αξιολογούν μόνο την ομοιότητα και όχι την τυπικότητα των υπό σύγκριση αντικειμένων (δηλ. εγγράφων). Ένα μοντέλο Poisson είναι θεωρητικά πιο κατάλληλο από τα μέτρα που βασίζονται σε απόσταση για την απόδοση της συγγραφής, αλλά δεν έχει δοκιμαστεί ποτέ με γλωσσικά στοιχεία κειμένου στο πλαίσιο LR. Το κόστος log-LR (Clr) χρησιμοποιήθηκε για την αξιολόγηση της απόδοσης των δύο μεθόδων. Η μελέτη αυτή αποδεικνύει ότι: (1) η μέθοδος βάσει χαρακτηριστικών ξεπερνά τη μέθοδο βάσει βαθμολογίας κατά τιμή Clr περίπου 0.09 κάτω από τις ρυθμίσεις βέλτιστης απόδοσης και (2) η απόδοση της μεθόδου βάσει χαρακτηριστικών μπορεί να βελτιωθεί περαιτέρω με την επιλογή χαρακτηριστικών.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A pontszám- és funkcióalapú módszerek a két fő módszer a bizonyítékok erejét számszerűsítő törvényszéki valószínűségi arány (LR) becslésére. Ebben a törvényszéki szövegösszehasonlító (FTC) tanulmányban egy koszin távolságot alkalmazó pontszám alapú módszert hasonlítunk össze egy Poisson modellre épülő funkció alapú módszerrel, amelyet 2 157 szerzőtől gyűjtöttek össze. A távolságmérések (pl. Burrows Delta, Cosine távolság) a szerzői hozzárendelési tanulmányok standard eszközei. Így a távolságmérést alkalmazó pontszámon alapuló módszer alkalmazása természetesen az LR-k szöveges bizonyítékok számára történő becslésének első lépése. A szöveges adatok azonban gyakran sértik a távolságalapú modellek alapjául szolgáló statisztikai feltételezéseket. Ezen túlmenően az ilyen modellek csak az összehasonlított tárgyak (azaz dokumentumok) hasonlóságát értékelik, nem pedig tipikusasságát. A Poisson modell elméletileg megfelelőbb, mint a távolságon alapuló mérések a szerzői hozzárendelésre, de soha nem tesztelték nyelvi szövegbizonyítékokkal az LR keretein belül. A log-LR költséget (Cllr) a két módszer teljesítményének felmérésére használták. Ez a tanulmány kimutatja, hogy: (1) a funkcióalapú módszer a legjobb teljesítményű beállítások mellett körülbelül 0,09 Cllr értékkel felülmúlja a pontszámon alapuló módszert, és; (2) a funkcióalapú módszer teljesítménye tovább javítható a funkciók kiválasztásával.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>პროგრამეტრების და ფუნქციების განსაზღვრებული მეტოვები არის ორი მნიშვნელოვანი განსაზღვრებისთვის ფუნქციური შესაძლებლობა (LR) განსაზღვრებისთვის კვანტიფიკაცია. ამ ფორენსიკური ტექსტის შემდგომარებაში (FTC) სწავლაში, კოსინური განტოლების გამოყენება კოსინური განტოლების შემდგომარება, პოსინური მოდელზე შექმნილი პოსინური მოდელზე, რომელიც 2 157 ავტორებ Distance measures (e.g. Burrows's Delta, Cosine distance) are a standard tool in authorship attribution studies. ამიტომ, განტოლებების გამოყენება პირველი კონფიგურაცია, რომელიც ტექსტულ კოდენტულების გამოყენება, არის პირველი კონფიგურაცია. თუმცა, ტექსტური მონაცემები ზოგიერთად გაუკეთებს სტატისტიკური წარმოდგენები, რომლებიც განსხვავებული მოდელების ბაზედ. დამატებით, ასეთი მოდელები მხოლოდ განსაკუთრებულია განსაკუთრებულობას, არა ტიპიოგიურობას, პროგრამეტრების (მაგალითად დოკუმენტების) შემდეგ. Poisson მოდელი ტეორეტიკურად უფრო სწორესია, ვიდრე განსხვავებული მიზემები, მაგრამ ეს არასდროს ლანგური ტექსტის კოდენტის გამოცდილებით LR ფრამეტრის შიგნით. log-LR პროცემები (Cllr) გამოყენებულია ორი მეტის გამოყენება. ამ სწავლების გამოჩვენება, რომ: (1) ფუნქციების გარეშე პროცემის გარეშე უფრო მეტი, რომელიც უფრო უფრო უფრო უფრო უფრო უფრო უფრო უფრო უფრო უფრო უფრო უფ (2) ფუნქციების განსაზღვრებული მეტის კონქციენტი შეიძლება უფრო უფრო მეტად გააკეთება ფუნქციების არჩევით.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>I metodi basati su punteggi e caratteristiche sono i due principali per stimare un rapporto di probabilità forense (LR) che quantifica la forza delle prove. In questo studio forense text comparation (FTC), un metodo basato su punteggi che utilizza la distanza cosina è confrontato con un metodo basato su funzionalità costruito su un modello Poisson con testi raccolti da 2.157 autori. Le misure della distanza (ad esempio Delta di Burrows, distanza cosina) sono uno strumento standard negli studi sull'attribuzione dell'autore. Pertanto, l'implementazione di un metodo basato su punteggi utilizzando una misura della distanza è naturalmente il primo passo per stimare le LR per prove testuali. Tuttavia, i dati testuali spesso violano le ipotesi statistiche alla base dei modelli basati sulla distanza. Inoltre, tali modelli valutano solo la somiglianza, non la tipicità, degli oggetti (cioè documenti) oggetto di confronto. Un modello Poisson è teoricamente più appropriato delle misure basate sulla distanza per l'attribuzione dell'autore, ma non è mai stato testato con prove linguistiche testuali all'interno del framework LR. Il costo log-LR (Cllr) è stato utilizzato per valutare le prestazioni dei due metodi. Questo studio dimostra che: (1) il metodo basato sulle funzionalità supera il metodo basato sul punteggio di un valore Cllr di circa 0,09 nelle impostazioni più performanti e; (2) le prestazioni del metodo basato sulle caratteristiche possono essere ulteriormente migliorate selezionando le caratteristiche.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Нәтижелер мен мүмкіндіктерді негіздеген әдістер - мәліметтердің күшін есептеу үшін бұл екі негізгі әдістер. Бұл мәтін салыстыру (FTC) зерттеулерінде, 2 157 автордан жинақталған мәтіндермен Poisson үлгісіне негізделген мүмкіндік тәсілімен салыстырылады. Қашықтық өлшемдері (мысалы, Бурролдың Delta, Косинус қашықтығы) авториторлық қасиеттердің зерттеулерінің стандартты құралы. Сондықтан, аспан негіздеген әдісін қашықтық өлшемі қолданатын LRs мәтіндіктерінің оқу үшін бірінші қадамы. Бірақ мәтіндік деректері көбінесе, қашықтығынан негізделген қашықтық үлгілерді бақылайды. Қосымша, бұл үлгілер тек салыстырылған нысандардың (мысалы, құжаттардың) ұқсастығын анықтайды. Poisson моделі авториторлық қасиеттері үшін қашықтық қасиеттерден теоретикалық түрде қолданылады, бірақ ол LR қоршауындағы лингвистикалық мәтін құқықтарымен тексерілмеген. Журнал- LR бағасы (Cllr) екі әдістерді оқу үшін қолданылды. Бұл зерттеу дегенді көрсетеді: (1) мүмкіндіктердің негіздеген әдісі, нақты Cllr мәнінен, ca. 0. 09 деген ең жақсы орнатылған параметрлердің арқылы, және; (2) Қасиеттерді негіздеген әдісінің әрекетін таңдау арқылы қосымша жақсартуға болады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Методите базирани на оценки и карактеристики се двата главни за проценка на форензичкиот размер на веројатности (LR) кој ја квантификува силата на доказите. Во оваа форензичка споредба на текстот (FTC) студија, методот базиран на оценки со користење на косинската дистанца се споредува со методот базиран на карактеристики изграден на Poisson модел со тексти собрани од 2.157 автори. Distance measures (e.g. Burrows's Delta, Cosine distance) are a standard tool in authorship attribution studies.  Thus, the implementation of a score-based method using a distance measure is naturally the first step for estimating LRs for textual evidence.  Сепак, текстуалните податоци честопати ги прекршуваат статистичките претпоставки на кои се базирани моделите на далечина. Покрај тоа, ваквите модели ја проценуваат само сличноста, а не типичноста, на објектите (т.е. документите) во споредба. Поисонскиот модел е теоретски посоодветен од мерките базирани на далечина за атрибутирање на авторството, но никогаш не е тестиран со јазички докази за текст во рамките на ЛР. Лог-ЛР цената (Cllr) беше употребена за проценка на успехот на двата методи. Оваа студија покажува дека: (1) методот базиран на карактеристики го надминува методот базиран на оценки со Cllr вредност од околу 0,09 под најдобрите поставувања и; (2) успехот на методот базиран на карактеристики може понатаму да се подобри со изборот на карактеристики.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Rezultatais ir savybėmis pagrįsti metodai yra du pagrindiniai metodai, kuriais apskaičiuojamas teisminės tikimybės santykis (LR), nustatantis įrodymų stiprumą kiekybiškai. In this forensic text comparison (FTC) study, a score-based method using the Cosine distance is compared with a feature-based method built on a Poisson model with texts collected from 2,157 authors.  Atstumo priemonės (pvz., Burrows Delta, Kozino atstumas) yra standartinė autorių priskyrimo tyrimų priemonė. Taigi rezultatais pagrįsto metodo taikymas naudojant atstumo matavimą yra, žinoma, pirmasis žingsnis vertinant tekstinius įrodymus esančias LR vertes. Tačiau tekstiniai duomenys dažnai pažeidžia statistines prielaidas, kuriomis grindžiami nuotoliniais modeliais. Be to, tokie modeliai vertina tik palyginamų objektų (t. y. dokumentų) panašumą, o ne tipiškumą. Poisson model is teoriškai yra tinkamesnis už nuotolines priemones, skirtas autorių teisių suteikimui, tačiau jis niekada nebuvo išbandytas su kalbiniais teksto įrodymais LR sistemoje. Dviejų metodų veiksmingumui įvertinti buvo naudojamos log-LR sąnaudos (Cllr). Šis tyrimas rodo, kad: (1) pagal savybes grindžiamas metodas rezultatais grindžiamą metodą viršija maždaug 0,09 Cllr vertės pagal geriausius rezultatus nustatymus ir; (2) savybėmis grindžiamo metodo veiksmingumą galima toliau gerinti atrankos būdais būdu.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Kaedah berdasarkan skor dan ciri-ciri adalah dua kaedah utama untuk menghargai nisbah kemungkinan forensik (LR) menghargai kekuatan bukti. Dalam kajian perbandingan teks forensik ini (FTC), kaedah berdasarkan skor menggunakan jarak Cosine dibandingkan dengan kaedah berdasarkan ciri yang dibina pada model Poisson dengan teks dikumpulkan dari 2,157 penulis. Ukuran jarak (contohnya Delta Burrows, jarak Cosine) adalah alat piawai dalam kajian atribut penulis. Oleh itu, pelaksanaan kaedah berdasarkan skor menggunakan ukuran jarak adalah langkah pertama untuk menghargai LR untuk bukti teks. Namun, data teks sering melanggar asumsi statistik berdasarkan model jarak. Selain itu, model tersebut hanya menilai kesamaan, bukan kebiasaan, objek (iaitu dokumen) yang dibandingkan. Model Poisson secara teori lebih sesuai daripada tindakan berdasarkan jarak untuk atribut penulis, tetapi ia tidak pernah diuji dengan bukti teks bahasa dalam kerangka LR. Kost log-LR (Cllr) digunakan untuk menilai prestasi dua kaedah. kajian ini menunjukkan bahawa: (1) kaedah berdasarkan fitur melampaui kaedah berdasarkan skor dengan nilai Cllr ca. 0.09 dibawah tetapan yang paling berkesan dan; (2) prestasi kaedah berdasarkan fitur boleh diperbaiki lebih lanjut dengan pemilihan fitur.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>സ്കോര്‍- വിശേഷതകള്‍ അടിസ്ഥാനമാക്കിയ രണ്ട് പ്രധാന രീതികളാണ് തെളിവുകളുടെ ശക്തി നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കുന്നത് ഫോറന്‍സിക് സാധ്യതയ ഈ ഫോര്‍ണെന്‍സിക് ടെക്സ്റ്റ് പഠനത്തിന് തുല്യമാക്കുന്നതില്‍, കോസിന്‍ ദൂരം ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന ഒരു സ്കോര്‍ അടിസ്ഥാനമായ രീതിയില്‍ 2,157 രചയിതാക്കളില്‍ നിന്ന ദൂരെയുള്ള പ്രയോഗങ്ങള്‍ (ഉദാഹരണത്തിനായി ബുര്‍റോസിന്‍റെ ഡെല്‍ട്ട, കോസിന്‍റെ ദൂരം) അധികാരം പഠനത്തില്‍ ഒരു സാധാരണ ഉപകരണ അതുകൊണ്ട്, ഒരു ദൂര അളവിലൂടെ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന സ്കോര്‍ അടിസ്ഥാനമായ രീതിയുടെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനം സ്വാഭാവികമായി എല്‍ആര്‍സിനെ ടെക്സ് എന്നാലും, ടെക്സ്ചുളില്‍ ഡേറ്റാകള്‍ പലപ്പോഴും ദൂരത്തിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തുള്ള മോഡലുകളിലുള്ള സ്ഥിതികതയുട അതിനുശേഷം, ഇത്തരം മോഡലുകള്‍ തുല്യമാക്കിയിരിക്കുന്ന വസ്തുക്കളുടെ സാധാരണയത്തെക്കുറിച്ച് മാത്രമല്ല, തുല്യമായ വസ്തുക് ഒരു പോയിസ്സണ്‍ മോഡല്‍ സാധാരണ അധികാരത്തിനുള്ള അധികാരത്തിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തെക്കാള്‍ അധികാരികമായ മെച്ചറിയാന്‍ അധികാരം അധികാരം  ഈ രണ്ട് രീതികളുടെ പ്രദര്‍ശനം നിരീക്ഷിക്കുന്നതിനായി ലോഗ്-LR വില ഉപയോഗിച്ചു. This study demonstrates that: (1) the feature-based method outperforms the score-based method by a Cllr value of ca. 0.09 under the best-performing settings and;  (2) വിശേഷത്തിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനമായ രീതിയുടെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനം കൂടുതല്‍ മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്താന്‍ സാധിക്കും.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-metodi bbażati fuq il-punti u l-karatteristiċi huma ż-żewġ metodi ewlenin għall-istima ta’ proporzjon forensiku ta’ probabbiltà (LR) li jikkwantifika s-saħħa tal-evidenza. In this forensic text comparison (FTC) study, a score-based method using the Cosine distance is compared with a feature-based method built on a Poisson model with texts collected from 2,157 authors.  Il-miżuri tad-distanza (e ż. id-Delta ta’ Burrows, id-distanza ta’ Cosine) huma g ħodda standard fl-istudji dwar l-attribuzzjoni tal-awtur. Għalhekk, l-implimentazzjoni ta’ metodu bbażat fuq il-punteġġi bl-użu ta’ miżura tad-distanza naturalment hija l-ewwel pass għall-istima tal-LRs għal evidenza testwali. Madankollu, id-dejta testwali spiss tikser is-suppożizzjonijiet statistiċi sottostanti għal mudelli bbażati fuq id-distanza. Barra minn hekk, mudelli bħal dawn jivvalutaw biss is-similarità, mhux it-tipiċità, tal-oġġetti (jiġifieri dokumenti) li qed jitqabblu. Mudell Poisson huwa teoretikament aktar xieraq minn miżuri bbażati fuq id-distanza għall-attribuzzjoni tal-awtur, iżda qatt ma ġie ttestjat b’evidenza tat-test lingwistiku fil-qafas tal-LR. L-ispiża log-LR (Cllr) intużat biex tiġi vvalutata l-prestazzjoni taż-żewġ metodi. Dan l-istudju juri li: (1) il-metodu bbażat fuq il-karatteristiċi jaqbeż il-metodu bbażat fuq il-punteġġi b’valur Cllr ta’ madwar 0.09 taħt l-a ħjar konfigurazzjonijiet u; (2) il-prestazzjoni tal-metodu bbażat fuq il-karatteristiċi tista’ titjieb aktar permezz tal-għażla tal-karatteristiċi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Нээлт болон харилцааны үндсэн арга нь судалгааны магадлалын харьцаа (LR) тооцоолох хоёр гол арга юм. Энэ арга хэмжээний текст харьцуулах (FTC) судалгаанд Косины зай ашиглах тооны үндсэн арга нь Poisson загварын загвар дээр 2 157 зохиолчдын цуглуулагдсан текстэй харьцуулагддаг. Хязгаарлын хэмжээсүүд (жишээ нь Бурроудын Дельта, Косины зай) нь авторын харилцааны судалгаанд стандарт хэрэгсэл юм. Тэгэхээр тооны үндсэн арга хэрэглэх нь зай хэмжээг ашиглан ЛР-г текст баримтуудын талаар тооцох анхны алхам юм. Гэвч текст өгөгдлийн мэдээллийг ихэвчлэн зайн суурилсан загварын үндсэн статистикийн тодорхойлолтуудыг буруутгадаг. Мөн ийм загварууд зөвхөн харьцуулахад харьцуулсан объектуудын төстэй адилхан байдал биш. Poisson загвар нь зөвхөн зөвхөн зай суурилсан хэмжээсүүдээс илүү зөвхөн зөвхөн зөвхөн илүү зөвхөн байдаг. Гэхдээ энэ нь хэзээ ч LR хэмжээсүүдийн дотор хэлний текст баримтуудтай шалгалтан Лог-ЛР зардал (Cllr) нь хоёр аргаар ажиллахын тулд хэрэглэгдсэн. Энэ судалгаанд: (1) тооны үндсэн арга нь тооны үндсэн арга нь ca.0.09-ийн Cllr утгыг хамгийн сайн ажиллах боломжтой байдлын доор гаргадаг. (2) Хэрэглэгчийн үндсэн аргын үйл ажиллагааг өөрчлөлтийн сонголтоор илүү сайжруулж болно.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Poeng- og funksjonsbaserte metodane er dei to hovudmetodane for å estimere eit forholdet på forensisk sannsynlighet (LR) som kvantifiserer forsiktigheten. I denne forensiske tekstsammenlikninga (FTC) studien er eit poengbasert metode med kosinus- avstanden samanlikna med ein funksjonsbasert metode bygd på eit Poisson- modell med tekstar samla frå 2 157 utviklarar. Avstandsverktøya (f.eks. Delta av Burrows, Cosinus-avstanden) er eit standard verktøy i autoriseringsstudiar. Dette er det første steget for å estimere LR-ar for tekst-beviser for å implementera eit metode basert på poeng. Men tekstdata ofte violerer statistiske assumpsjonane under avstandsbaserte modeller. I tillegg kan desse modelane berre vurdere ulikheten, ikkje typiskheten, av objektane (dvs. dokument) under sammenlikning. Eit Poisson-modell er teoretisk meir rett enn avstandsbaserte tiltak for autoriseringsattribusjon, men det har aldri testert med språkstekstevident i LR-rammeverket. Logg- LR- kostnaden (Cllr) vart brukt for å vurdere utviklinga av to metodar. Denne studien viser at: (1) funksjonsbasert metoden utfører poengsbasert metoden ved ein Cllr- verdi av ca. 0. 09 under dei beste utføringsinnstillingane og (2) Utviklinga av metoden som er basert på funksjonar kan forbetrast meir ved å velja funksjonar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Metody oparte na wynikach i funkcjach to dwie główne metody oszacowania współczynnika prawdopodobieństwa kryminalistycznego (LR) kwantyfikujące siłę dowodów. W tym badaniu kryminalistycznego porównywania tekstów (FTC) porównano metodę opartą na wynikach wykorzystującą odległość kosynową z metodą opartą na funkcjach zbudowaną na modelu Poissona z tekstami zebranymi od autorów 2,157. Miary odległości (np. Delta Burrowsa, odległość kosynowa) są standardowym narzędziem w badaniach atrybucji autorskiej. Zatem wdrożenie metody opartej na wynikach wykorzystującej miarę odległości jest oczywiście pierwszym krokiem do szacowania LR dla dowodów tekstowych. Jednak dane tekstowe często naruszają założenia statystyczne leżące u podstaw modeli opartych na odległości. Ponadto takie modele oceniają jedynie podobieństwo, a nie typowość porównywanych obiektów (tj. dokumentów). Model Poissona jest teoretycznie bardziej odpowiedni niż miary oparte na odległości dla atrybucji autorstwa, ale nigdy nie był testowany z językowymi dowodami tekstowymi w ramach LR. Do oceny skuteczności obu metod wykorzystano koszt log-LR (Clr). Badanie to wykazuje, że: (1) metoda oparta na funkcjach przewyższa metodę opartą na wynikach o wartość Cllr około 0.09 w ustawieniach o najlepsze wyniki oraz; (2) wydajność metody opartej na funkcjach może być jeszcze bardziej poprawiona poprzez wybór funkcji.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Metodele bazate pe scor și caracteristici sunt cele două metode principale pentru estimarea unui raport de probabilitate criminalistică (LR) care cuantifică puterea dovezilor. În acest studiu de comparare a textelor criminalistice (FTC), o metodă bazată pe scoruri utilizând distanța cosină este comparată cu o metodă bazată pe caracteristici construită pe un model Poisson cu texte colectate de la 2 157 de autori. Măsurătorile distanței (de exemplu Delta Burrows, distanța cosină) sunt un instrument standard în studiile de atribuire a autorului. Astfel, implementarea unei metode bazate pe scoruri utilizând o măsură a distanței este, firește, primul pas pentru estimarea LR pentru dovezi textuale. Cu toate acestea, datele textuale încalcă adesea ipotezele statistice care stau la baza modelelor bazate pe distanță. În plus, astfel de modele evaluează doar similitudinea, nu tipicarea obiectelor (și anume documentele) în comparație. Un model Poisson este teoretic mai adecvat decât măsurile bazate pe distanță pentru atribuirea autorului, dar nu a fost niciodată testat cu dovezi lingvistice de text în cadrul LR. Costul log-LR (Cllr) a fost utilizat pentru a evalua performanța celor două metode. Acest studiu demonstrează că: (1) metoda bazată pe caracteristici depășește metoda bazată pe scor cu o valoare Cllr de aproximativ 0,09 în setările cele mai performante și; (2) performanța metodei bazate pe caracteristici poate fi îmbunătățită în continuare prin selectarea caracteristicilor.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Shaqooyin ku saleysan qiimeynta qiimeynta qiimeynta qiimeynta qalabka (LR) waa qiyaastii xoogga caddayn. Waxbarashadan qoraalka qalbiyada ee isbarbardhiga (FTC), waa qaab lagu soo bandhigay koosin-bannaantiisa, waxaa la barbaranayaa qaab ku saleysan qaab ah oo lagu dhisay model Poisson ah oo qoraalo laga soo ururiyey 2,157 oo qoraal ah. Measurada degaanka (tusaale. Burrows Delta, fog Cosin) waa qalabka caadi ah oo lagu qorayo waxbarashada rasmiga ah. Sidaa darteed in lagu sameeyo qaab koox ah oo lagu isticmaalayo qiyaasta fog waa qiyaastii ugu horraysa ee lagu qiimeeyo LRs oo lagu qiimeeyo caddeynta qoraalka. Si kastaba ha ahaatee macluumaadka qoraalka ah waxey inta badan burburiyaan malaha statisticada oo ku hoos yaala samooyinka fog. Waxaa kale oo lagu qiimeeyaa tusaalooyinkaas oo kaliya isku mid ahaanshaha e e alaabta (tusaale ahaan dukumentiyada). Tusaale Poisson ayaa si dhab ah ugu habboon qoraalka aad u fog ee warqada rasmiga ah, laakiin marna looma tijaabin caddeynta qoraalka luuqada ee LR gudaheeda. The log-LR cost (Cllr) was used to assess the performance of the two methods.  Waxbarashadan waxey muujiyaan in: (1) qaababka ku saleysan uu soo saaraa qaababka lagu qiimeeyo qiimaha Cllr oo qiyaas 0.09 ka hoosaysa habka ugu fiican ee lagu sameeyo iyo; (2) Muujinta qaababka tayada lagu saleeyo waxaa lagu sii kordhin karaa doorashada tayada.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>Metode na osnovu poena i funkcija su dve glavne za procjenu odnosa forenzičke verovatnosti (LR) kvantificiranja snage dokaza. U ovom forenzičkom ispitivanju o usporedbi teksta (FTC), metoda bazirana na rezultatima koristeći kosinsku udaljenost se uspoređuje sa metodom baziranom na funkcijama izgrađenom na model Poisson sa tekstima skupljenim od 2.157 autora. Mjere udaljenosti (npr. Delta Burrows's, kosinska udaljenost) su standardni alat u ispitivanjima privlačenja autoriteta. Tako je provedba metode bazirane na rezultatima koristeći mjeru udaljenosti prirodno prvi korak za procjenu LR-a za tekstualne dokaze. Međutim, tekstualni podaci često krše statističke pretpostavke na temelju modela na daljini. Osim toga, takvi modeli procjenjuju samo sličnost, ne tipičnost objekata (tj. dokumenti) u usporedbi. Model Poisson je teoretički prikladniji od mjera na temelju udaljenosti za privlačenje autoriteta, ali nikada nije testiran jezičkim tekstskim dokazima u okviru LR-a. Koštanje log-LR (Cllr) je korišćeno za procjenu provedbe dva metoda. Ova studija pokazuje da: (1) metoda osnovana na funkcijama iznosi metodu na osnovu rezultata Cllr vrijednošću ca. 0,09 pod najboljim nastavama i; (2) učinkovitost metode baziranog na funkcijama može se bolje poboljšati izrazom funkcija.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Score- och funktionsbaserade metoder är de två huvudsakliga metoderna för att uppskatta ett forensic probability ratio (LR) som kvantifierar styrkan av evidens. I denna forensiska textjämförelse (FTC) studie jämförs en poängbaserad metod med Cosinskt avstånd med en funktionsbaserad metod baserad på en Poissonmodell med texter insamlade från 2 157 författare. Distansmätning (t.ex. Burrows Delta, Cosine distance) är ett standardverktyg i författarskapsattributionsstudier. Därför är implementeringen av en poängbaserad metod med hjälp av ett avståndsmått naturligtvis det första steget för att uppskatta LR för textbevis. Textdata bryter dock ofta mot de statistiska antaganden som ligger till grund för distansbaserade modeller. Dessutom bedöms endast likheten mellan föremålen (dvs. dokumenten) i jämförelse, inte typligheten. En Poissonmodell är teoretiskt lämpligare än distansbaserade mått för författarskapsattribution, men den har aldrig testats med språklig textevidens inom LR-ramen. Kostnaden för log-LR (Cllr) användes för att bedöma resultaten av de två metoderna. Denna studie visar att: (1) den funktionsbaserade metoden överträffar den poängbaserade metoden med ett Cllr-värde på ca 0,09 under de bäst presterande inställningarna och; (2) Den funktionsbaserade metodens prestanda kan förbättras ytterligare genom val av funktioner.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>ප්‍රමාණය සහ විශේෂතාවක් අධාරිත විද්‍යාවය තමයි ප්‍රමාණය දෙකක් සාක්ෂික ශක්තිය (LR) විශ්වාස කරන්න. මේ ප්‍රධාන පණිවිඩය සම්බන්ධ (FTC) පරීක්ෂණයේදී, කෝසින් දුරට භාවිත කරන්න ප්‍රධාන පරීක්ෂණයක් ප්‍රධාන විධානයක් පොයිසෝන් මඩ දුරස්ථ විශේෂය (උදාහරණයෙන් Burrow's Delta, Cosine දුරස්ථ විශේෂය) ප්‍රමාණිත උපකරණයක් තමයි අධාර්යය අභ්‍යාස ඉතින්, අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක අංක නමුත්, පාළුවන් දත්ත සාමාන්‍යයෙන් සංඛ්‍යාත්මක විශ්වාස කරනවා දුරස්ථානය අධාරිත මොඩේල ඉතින්, මේ මොඩේල්ස් වගේ සාමාන්‍යතාවක් විතරයි, සාමාන්‍යතාවක් නෙවෙයි, සාමාන්‍යතාවක් විතරයි (ඉතින්, ලිපින Poisson නිර්මාණය තර්ගයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂය log-LR ක්‍රියාත්මක (Cllr) භාවිත කරලා තියෙන්නේ විද්‍යාත්මක දෙකක් ගැන ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන්න. මේ පරීක්ෂණය පෙන්වන්නේ: (1) ප්‍රශ්නයක් අධාරිත විධානය ස්කෝර් අධාරිත විධානයක් ca. 0. 09 විශ්වාස කරන්න හොඳ සැකසුම්  (2) විශේෂතාවක් අධාරිත විධානයේ විශේෂතාවක් තෝරාගන්න පුළුවන්.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>மதிப்பெண்கள் மற்றும் குணங்கள் அடிப்படையில் உள்ள இரண்டு முக்கிய முறைகள் தெளிவான அதிகாரத்தை மதிப்பிட வேண்டும். இந்த பென்சிக் உரையை ஒப்பீடு படிப்பு (FTC) முறைமையில், கோசைன் தூரத்தை பயன்படுத்தி ஒரு போயிஸான் மாதிரியில் அமைக்கப்பட்ட முறையில் 2,157 ஆசிரியரில் இரு தூரத்தின் அளவுகள் (உ. ம். பர்ரோஸ் டெல்டா, கோசைன் தூரம்) ஆசிரியர்களின் பங்கீட்டு படிப்பாடுகளில் ஒரு இயல்பான கருவி ஒரு தூரத்தின் அளவை பயன்படுத்தி ஒரு மதிப்பெண் அடிப்படையான முறைமையை செயல்படுத்துதல் முதல் படியாகும் நெடுக்கல் தெளிவான ஆதாரங் ஆனால், நெடுக்கல் தகவல் பெரும்பாலாகவே தூரத்தில் அடிப்படையில் உள்ள புள்ளிவிவரமான எண்ணங்களை மீறுகிறது. அதற்கு மேலும், இவ்வாறு மாதிரிகள் ஒப்பிடும் பொருட்களின் இயல்பானத்தை மட்டும் மதிப்பிடுகிறார்கள். A Poisson model is theoretically more appropriate than distance-based measures for authorship attribution, but it has never been tested with linguistic text evidence within the LR framework.  The log- LR cost (Cllr) was used to assess the performance of the two methods. இந்த ஆராய்ச்சி காண்பிக்கிறது: (1) குணங்கள் அடிப்படையாகும் முறைமையில் சிறந்த செயல்படுத்தும் அமைப்புகளில் க்ளாலர் மதிப்பை கொண்டு ம (2) குணங்களின் சார்ந்த முறைமையின் செயல்பாடு குணங்கள் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பால் மேலும் மேம்படுத்தலாம்.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>Score- and feature-based methods are the two main ones for estimating a forensic likelihood ratio (LR) which quantifies the strength of evidence. اس فورنسیک متن مقایسہ (FTC) کی مطالعہ میں کوسین فاصلہ کے مطالعہ سے ایک اسکور بنیاد متن کے مطالعہ سے ایک فائدہ بنیاد متن سے مقایسہ کیا جاتا ہے جو 2,157 لکھنے والوں سے جمع کئے گئے ہیں. فاصلہ اندازے (جیسے بروئز کے دلتا، کوسین فاصلہ) authorship attribution تحقیقات میں ایک استاندارد تولید ہیں. اسی طرح، ایک اسکور بنیادی طریقہ کی عملومات ایک دور اندازہ کے مطابق لر کا پہلا قدم ہے جو ٹکسٹیل مدارک کے لئے لر کا مطابق کرنا ہے. لیکن، ٹیکسٹل ڈیٹا اکثر سیاسٹیسٹی فرضیوں کو دور کی بنیادی موڈل کے نیچے بغاوت کرتا ہے. اور اس کے علاوہ یہ مدل صرف مقایسہ کے مطابق برابری کا ارزش کر رہے ہیں، بغیر عادت کے، موجود (یعنی سند) کے موجود ہیں۔ Poisson model is theoretically more appropriate than distance-based measures for authorship attribute, but it has never been tested with linguistic text evidence within the LR framework. لاگ-لار کے قیمت (Cllr) دو روش کے کامیابی کا ارزش کرنے کے لئے استعمال کیا گیا تھا. یہ مطالعہ دکھاتا ہے کہ: (1) فائدہ بنیادی طریقہ کا سیلر کی مطالعہ سے سیلر کے ذریعہ سے زیادہ استعمال کرتا ہے اور (2) فرصت پر بنیادی طریقہ کی عملکرد اضافہ کر سکتی ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Điểm đánh giá và dựa vào tính năng là hai phương pháp chính để ước lượng tỷ lệ xác suất theo pháp y (LR) định lượng sức mạnh bằng chứng. Trong cuộc so sánh văn bản pháp y (FTC) này, một phương pháp dựa vào điểm số dùng cự ly Cosin được so sánh với một phương pháp dựa trên tính năng được xây dựng trên một mô hình Poison với các văn bản thu thập từ tác giả 2,157. Khoảng cách xa (ví dụ, thung lũng Burrows, đường dài Cosine) là một công cụ tiêu chuẩn trong các nghiên cứu quyền tác quyền. Do đó, việc áp dụng một phương pháp dựa trên điểm dựa vào khoảng cách là bước đầu tiên cho việc ước lượng DSN để tìm bằng chứng kết cấu. Tuy nhiên, dữ liệu cấu trúc đã vi phạm các giả thiết thống kê dựa trên mô-đun-xa. Hơn nữa, các mô hình này chỉ đánh giá sự giống nhau, không phải tính phong đi ển, của các vật thể (tức là tài liệu) so sánh. Một mô hình độc dược trên lý thuyết phù hợp hơn phương pháp dựa trên khoảng cách để phân tích tác quyền, nhưng nó chưa bao giờ được kiểm tra bằng chứng văn bản ngôn ngữ trong phạm vi LR. The log-LR giá trị (ClR) được dùng để đánh giá kết quả của hai phương pháp. Nghiên cứu này chứng minh rằng: 1) phương pháp dựa trên tính năng đạt kết quả với phương pháp dựa trên điểm bằng một giá trị CIR của ca. 0.09 dưới thiết lập có trình độ kinh ngạc tốt nhất và (2) Khả năng hiệu quả của phương pháp dựa vào tính năng có thể được cải thiện thêm nhờ chọn đặc trưng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Foiz va imkoniyatlarning asosiy usullari hujjatning imkoniyatini aniqlash uchun ikki asosiy usullar. Ushbu Fransuzcha matn o'qituvchi (FTC) o'qituvchida, Cosinning orasidagi qismi asosida qoʻllangan usuli Poisson modelida yaratilgan, 2,157 mualliflargan matnlarni olib tashlash mumkin. Distance measures (e.g. Burrows Delta, Cosine distance) are a standard vosita. Shunday qilib, masofadagi holatni ishlatish imkoniyatini asl qilish asosiy usulini asosiy qilish asosiy matn huquqlarni qiymatlashning asosiy birinchi darajasi. Lekin, texnologiya maʼlumotlari ko'pincha uzoq modellarida statistik g'oyalarini bajaradi. Koʻrsatgich, bu modellar faqat bir xil narsalarni qiymatish mumkin, oddiy narsalarning (m'anaviy hujjatlari) qo'llaniladi. Name Ikki usullar bajarishni qiymatga (Cllr) foydalanadi. Bu ta'qituvni koʻrsatish mumkin: (1) imkoniyatlar asosida qiymatni ca. 0. 09ning eng yaxshi bajarish moslamalaridan foydalanish mumkin. (2) Xossalari asosida bajarish imkoniyatlarini bajarish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Методите, базирани на скори и характеристики, са двата основни метода за оценка на коефициента на съдебно-медицинска вероятност (ЛР), който количествено определя силата на доказателствата. В това съдебно изследване за сравнение на текстовете (ФТС) се сравнява скоробазиран метод, използващ косинусовото разстояние, с функционален метод, изграден по модел на Поасон с текстове, събрани от 2 157 автора. Мерките за дистанция (например делта на Бъроуз, косинусово разстояние) са стандартен инструмент в проучванията за приписване на авторски права. По този начин прилагането на метод, основан на резултат, с помощта на измерване на разстоянието, естествено е първата стъпка за оценяване на ЛР за текстови доказателства. Текстовите данни обаче често нарушават статистическите допускания, базирани на моделите на разстояние. Освен това тези модели оценяват само сходството, а не типичността на обектите (т.е. документите) в сравнение. Моделът на Поасон теоретично е по-подходящ от мерките, базирани на разстояние, за приписване на авторство, но никога не е бил тестван с лингвистични текстови доказателства в рамките на ЛР. За оценка на ефективността на двата метода беше използвана log-LR разходът (Cllr). Това проучване показва, че: (1) методът, основан на характеристиките, превъзхожда метода, основан на резултат, с стойност от приблизително 0,09 при най-добрите условия и; (2) ефективността на метода, основан на характеристиките, може да бъде допълнително подобрена чрез избор на характеристиките.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Score- en feature-based methoden zijn de twee belangrijkste methoden voor het schatten van een forensic waarschijnlijkheidsratio (LR) die de sterkte van bewijsmateriaal kwantificeert. In deze forensische tekstvergelijkingsstudie (FTC) wordt een score-gebaseerde methode met de Cosine afstand vergeleken met een feature-based methode gebaseerd op een Poisson model met teksten verzameld van 2,157 auteurs. Afstandsmetingen (bijvoorbeeld Burrows Delta, Cosine afstand) zijn een standaard hulpmiddel in auteurship attribution studies. Daarom is de implementatie van een score-gebaseerde methode met behulp van een afstandsmeting natuurlijk de eerste stap voor het schatten van LR's voor tekstueel bewijs. Textuele gegevens schenden echter vaak de statistische aannames die ten grondslag liggen aan afstandsmodellen. Bovendien beoordelen dergelijke modellen alleen de gelijkenis, niet de typaliteit, van de objecten (d.w.z. documenten) die worden vergeleken. Een Poisson model is theoretisch geschikter dan afstandsgebaseerde metingen voor auteurschapsattributie, maar het is nooit getest met linguïstisch tekstbewijs binnen het LR framework. De log-LR kosten (Clr) werden gebruikt om de prestaties van de twee methoden te beoordelen. Deze studie toont aan dat: (1) de feature-based methode de score-based methode overtreft met een Clr waarde van ca. 0.09 onder de best presterende instellingen en; (2) de prestaties van de op features gebaseerde methode kunnen verder worden verbeterd door featureselectie.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Score- og funktionsbaserede metoder er de to vigtigste til estimering af en retsmedicinsk sandsynlighedsgrad (LR), der kvantificerer styrken af evidens. I denne retsmedicinske tekstsammenligning (FTC) undersøgelse sammenlignes en scorebaseret metode ved hjælp af Cosine distance med en funktionsbaseret metode bygget på en Poisson model med tekster indsamlet fra 2.157 forfattere. Afstandsmålinger (f.eks. Burrows Delta, Cosine distance) er et standardværktøj i forfatterskabstilskrivningsstudier. Derfor er implementeringen af en scorebaseret metode ved hjælp af en afstandsmåling naturligvis det første skridt til at estimere LR'er til tekstdokumentation. Tekstdata overtræder dog ofte de statistiske antagelser, der ligger til grund for afstandsbaserede modeller. Desuden vurderer sådanne modeller kun ligheden mellem objekterne (dvs. dokumenterne) og ikke karakteristikaen. En Poisson model er teoretisk mere hensigtsmæssig end distance-baserede målinger for forfatterskabstilskrivning, men den er aldrig blevet testet med sproglig tekst evidens inden for LR rammerne. Log-LR omkostningerne (Cllr) blev anvendt til at vurdere resultaterne af de to metoder. Denne undersøgelse viser, at: (1) den funktionsbaserede metode overgår den scorebaserede metode med en Cllr-værdi på ca. 0,09 under de bedst ydende indstillinger og (2) Den funktionsbaserede metodes ydeevne kan forbedres yderligere ved udvælgelse af funktioner.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Metade temeljene na rezultatima i funkcijama su dvije glavne za procjenu odnosa forenzičke vjerojatnosti (LR) kvantificiranja snage dokaza. U ovom forenzičkom ispitivanju o usporedbi teksta (FTC), metoda temeljena na rezultatima koristeći udaljenost kosina se uspoređuje s metodom temeljenom na funkcijama izgrađenom na model Poisson sa tekstima skupljenim od 2.157 autora. Mjere udaljenosti (npr. Delta Burrows's, kosinska udaljenost) su standardni alat u ispitivanjima pribave autoriteta. Stoga, provedba metode temeljene na rezultatima koristeći mjeru udaljenosti prirodno je prvi korak za procjenu LR-a za tekstualne dokaze. Međutim, tekstualni podaci često krše statističke pretpostavke na temelju modela na temelju udaljenosti. Osim toga, takvi modeli procjenjuju samo sličnost objekata (tj. dokumenti) u usporedbi. Model Poisson teoretički je prikladniji od mjera temeljene na daljini za privlačenje autoriteta, ali nikada nije testiran jezičkim tekstskim dokazima u okviru LR-a. Troškovi log-LR (Cllr) su korišteni za procjenu učinkovitosti dvije metode. Ova ispitivanja pokazuje da: (1) metoda temeljena na funkcijama iznosi metodu temeljenu na rezultatu Cllr vrijednošću oko 0,09 pod najboljim nastavama i; (2) učinkovitost metode temeljene na funkcijama može se dodatno poboljšati izrazom funkcija.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Score- und feature-basierte Methoden sind die beiden wichtigsten Methoden zur Schätzung eines forensischen Likelihood Ratio (LR), das die Beweisstärke quantifiziert. In dieser forensischen Textvergleichsstudie (FTC) wird eine score-basierte Methode mit der Cosine-Distanz mit einer feature-basierten Methode verglichen, die auf einem Poisson-Modell mit Texten von 2,157-Autoren basiert. Entfernungsmessungen (z.B. Burrows Delta, Cosine Entfernung) sind ein Standardwerkzeug in Autorschaftszuschreibungsstudien. Somit ist die Implementierung einer score-basierten Methode unter Verwendung eines Distanzmaßes natürlich der erste Schritt zur Schätzung von LRs für textuelle Evidenz. Textdaten verletzen jedoch häufig die statistischen Annahmen, die distanzbasierten Modellen zugrunde liegen. Darüber hinaus beurteilen solche Modelle nur die Ähnlichkeit und nicht die Typizität der zu vergleichenden Objekte (d.h. Dokumente). Ein Poisson-Modell ist theoretisch besser geeignet als distanzbasierte Maßnahmen zur Autorenschaftszuweisung, wurde jedoch nie mit linguistischen Textnachweisen im LR-Rahmen getestet. Die log-LR Kosten (Clr) wurden verwendet, um die Leistung der beiden Methoden zu bewerten. Diese Studie zeigt, dass: (1) die feature-basierte Methode die score-basierte Methode um einen Cllr-Wert von ca. 0.09 unter den leistungsstärksten Einstellungen übertrifft und (2) Die Leistung der feature-basierten Methode kann durch Feature-Auswahl weiter verbessert werden.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>점수와 특징을 바탕으로 하는 방법은 법의학 유사비(LR)를 추정하는 두 가지 주요 방법으로 LR은 증거의 강도를 계량화하는 데 쓰인다.이 법의학 텍스트 비교(FTC) 연구에서는 저자 2천157명의 텍스트를 수집한 여현거리의 점수 기반 방법과 파송 모델 기반의 특징 기반 방법을 비교했다.거리 측정(예: Burrows의 Delta, 여현 거리)은 저자의 원인 연구의 표준 도구입니다.따라서 거리 메트릭을 사용하여 분수에 기반한 메트릭을 구현하는 것이 텍스트 증거 LRs를 추산하는 첫 번째 단계입니다.그러나 텍스트 데이터는 거리 기반 모델의 통계적 가설을 위반하는 경우가 많다.그 밖에 이런 모델은 비교 대상(즉 파일)의 유사성만 평가하고 비전형성만 평가한다.파슨 모형은 이론적으로 거리를 바탕으로 한 저자의 귀속 측정보다 적합하지만 LR 프레임워크에서 언어 텍스트 증거로 테스트를 한 적이 없다.로그 LR 비용(Cllr)은 두 가지 방법의 성능을 평가하는 데 사용됩니다.본 연구에 의하면 (1) 성능이 가장 좋은 설정과 조건에서 특징을 바탕으로 하는 방법의 Cllr값은 약 0.09로 분수를 바탕으로 하는 방법보다 우수하다.(2) 특징 선택을 통해 특징에 기반한 방법의 성능을 더욱 향상시킬 수 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_id>Metode berdasarkan skor dan fitur adalah dua metode utama untuk memperkirakan proporsi kemungkinan forensik (LR) mengurangi kekuatan bukti. Dalam penelitian perbandingan teks forensik ini (FTC), metode berdasarkan skor menggunakan jarak Cosine dibandingkan dengan metode berdasarkan fitur dibangun pada model Poisson dengan teks yang dikumpulkan dari 2.157 penulis. Ukuran jarak (contohnya Delta Burrows, jarak Cosine) adalah alat standar dalam studi atribut otoritas. Jadi, implementasi metode berdasarkan skor menggunakan ukuran jarak adalah langkah pertama untuk memperkirakan LR untuk bukti teks. Namun, data tekstual sering melanggar asumsi statistik berdasarkan model jarak. Selain itu, model tersebut hanya menilai kesamaan, bukan kebiasaan, objek (i.e. dokumen) yang dibandingkan. Sebuah model Poisson secara teori lebih sesuai daripada tindakan berdasarkan jarak untuk atribut pengarang, tetapi belum pernah diuji dengan bukti teks bahasa dalam rangka LR. Biaya log-LR (Cllr) digunakan untuk menilai prestasi dua metode. This study demonstrates that: (1) the feature-based method outperforms the score-based method by a Cllr value of ca. 0.09 under the best-performing settings and;  (2) prestasi dari metode berdasarkan fitur dapat diperbaiki lebih lanjut dengan seleksi fitur.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Utawala wa tuzo na utofauti ni njia mbili kuu kwa kadiria kiwango cha uwezekano wa kitabibu (LR) kinachopima nguvu ya ushahidi. Katika utafiti huu wa maandishi ya Kifaransa ukilinganisha (FTC), mbinu yenye msingi wa msingi kwa kutumia umbali wa Cosine inalinganishwa na mwelekeo ulioanzishwa kwenye muundo wa Poisson na maandishi yaliyokusanywa kutoka kwa waandishi 2,157. Distance measures (e.g. Burrows's Delta, Cosine distance) are a standard tool in authorship attribution studies.  Kwa hiyo, utekelezaji wa mbinu inayotegemea msingi kwa kutumia hatua ya umbali ni hatua ya kwanza ya kutathmini Rs kwa ushahidi wa msingi. Hata hivyo, takwimu za msingi mara nyingi huvunja dhana za takwimu zinazotokana na mifano ya mbali. Zaidi ya hayo, mifano hii inatambulia sawa, sio kawaida, ya vitu (yaani nyaraka) chini ya ulinganisho. Mradi wa Poisson kwa nadharia ni muhimu zaidi ya hatua za mbali kwa ajili ya kuchangia uwazi, lakini haijawahi kuchunguzwa kwa ushahidi wa maandishi ya lugha ndani ya mfumo wa LR. gharama za LR (Cllr) zilitumika kutathmini utendaji wa njia mbili. Utafiti huu unaonyesha kuwa: (1) njia inayotumiwa na utaratibu unaonyesha njia inayotumiwa na msingi wa kipindi cha Cllr cha takribani 0.09 chini ya mazingira mazuri na; (2) Utendaji wa mbinu inayohusiana na utaratibu unaweza kuboreshwa zaidi na uchaguzi wa tabia.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>روش‌های مربوط به امتیاز و ویژه‌ها دو اصلی برای ارزیابی نسبت احتمال پیشینیانی (LR) قدرت شواهد است. در این مطالعه متن پیشینیانی (FTC) یک روش بر اساس امتیاز با استفاده از فاصله کوسین با روش بر اساس یک مدل Poisson ساخته شده با متن جمع شده از ۲.157 نویسندگان مقایسه می‌شود. اندازه‌های فاصله (به عنوان دلتا، فاصله کوسین) یک ابزار استاندارد در مطالعه‌های تحصیلات اختیار است. بنابراین، عملیات یک روش بر اساس امتیاز با استفاده از اندازه فاصله طبیعی اولین قدم برای ارزیابی LR برای مدرک متن است. با این حال، داده های متن اغلب فرضیه های آماری را بر اساس مدل های متوسط فاصله شکسته می کند. علاوه بر این، چنین مدلها تنها شبیه‌ای را ارزیابی می‌کند، نه عادی، از شیوه‌ها (یعنی سند‌ها) در مقایسه. یک مدل Poisson نظریه‌ای از اندازه‌های بسیار فاصله‌تر از اندازه‌های مستقیم برای تعریف اختیار است، ولی هرگز با مدرک متن زبان‌شناسی در چهارچوب LR آزمایش نشده است. هزینه‌ی log-LR (Cllr) برای ارزیابی عملکرد دو روش استفاده شد. این مطالعه نشان می‌دهد: (۱) روش پایه‌های ویژه‌ای با ارزش Cllr از ca. 0. 09 زیر تنظیمات بهترین انجام‌دهنده‌ها و; (۲) عملکرد روش بر اساس ویژه‌ها می‌تواند با انتخاب ویژه‌ها بیشتر بهتر شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Telling- en funksie- gebaseerde metodes is die twee hoofde metodes vir die estimatie van 'n voorskynlikheid verhouding (LR) wat die krag van bevestig quantifiseer. In hierdie voorskynlike teks vergelyking (FTC) studie word 'n telling-gebaseerde metode gebruik van die Cosinus afstand vergelyk met 'n funksie-gebaseerde metode gebou op 'n Poisson model met teks versamel van 2,157 outeurs. Afstand-maatskappe (bv. Burrows s e Delta, Cosinus afstand) is 'n standaard nutsprogram in autorisasie-attribution studies. Daarom is die implementasie van 'n telling-gebaseerde metode gebruik van 'n afstand-maat natuurlik die eerste stap vir die estimatie van LR vir tekstuele bevestigheid. Maar, tekstuele data het dikwels die statistiese aanvaardes ondersteun afstand-gebaseerde modele gevolg. Verder, sodanige modele asserteer slegs die gelykenis nie, nie die tipies, van die objekte (bv. dokumente) onder vergelyking. 'n Poisson model is teorieese meer geskikte as afstand-gebaseerde maatjies vir outoriteit-toestelling, maar dit is nooit getest met lingwisiese teks bevestigheid binne die LR raamwerk nie. Die log- LR koste (Cllr) was gebruik om die prestasie van die twee metodes te asseer. Hierdie studie wys dat: (1) die funksie-gebaseerde metode uitvoer die punt-gebaseerde metode deur 'n Cllr waarde van ca. 0. 09 onder die beste-uitvoerde instellings en; (2) die prestasie van die funksie-gebaseerde metode kan verder verbeter word deur funksie-keuse.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Rakamlar we özellikler tabanlı yöntemleri, kanıtlaryň gücünü ölçürmek üçin iki sanal wajypdyr. Bu forensik metin karşılaştyryşynda (FTC) öwrenmesinde, Kosin aralygy ullanýan takmynan tabanly yöntemi 2,157 awtorlardan ýygnan metinler bilen guruldy. Meselelik ölçüleri (mysal. Demir Delta, Kosin uzakyny) awtomatik taýýarlama öwrenmelerinde standart araçlar. Şol sebäpli, अंदर tabanly bir yöntem üýtgetmek üçin uzak ölçüsi ullanýan ilkinji adım görnüşdürmek textual kanıtlar üçin LRlary hasaplamak üçin. Ýöne metin maglumaty köplenç uzaklaşdyran nusgalaryň statistiki pikirlerini bozmaýar. Munuň daýallary diňe daňlap görkezilişinde zadyň täsirini takyklaýar, diňe daňlap däl. Poisson nusgasy, awtomatik taýýarlanmagy üçin uzaklaşdyran ölçümlerden teoriýaly gowydyr, ýöne ol LR çerçevesinde hiç haçan lingwistiki tekst kanlag bilen barlanmaýar. Log-LR buýruky (Cllr) iki ýol eserini takmynmak üçin ullanýardy Bu araşdyrma şuny görkezýär: (1) özellikler tabanly taryh metodumyň ca'yň Cllr deňi bilen tertiblendirip bilýär. 0.09 iň gowy işlenýän düzümlerniň altynda we; (2) özellikler tabanly yöntemiň eserini özellikler saýlamak bilen gowulaşdyrylyp biler.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>የነጥብ እና የፊደል ሥርዓት ማስረጃዎችን የሚያስተካክል የፍሪካ ምናልባት ክፍል (LR) የሚቆጠር ሁለት ዋነቶች ናቸው፡፡ በዚህ የፊንስ ጽሑፍ ትምህርት (FTC) ትምህርት፣ የኮሲን ርዝመት የተደረገው የቆሮስ ሥርዓት ከ2,157 ጸሐፊዎች የተሰበሰቡ ጽሑፎች የተደረገውን የፖisson ሞዴል ላይ የተመሳሳይ ሥርዓት ይተካከላል፡፡ Distance measures (e.g. Burrows's Delta, Cosine distance) are a standard tool in authorship attribution studies.  ስለዚህም፣ የራቀ መስኮት በመጠቀም የscore-based ሥርዓት የኢንተርኔት ማስረጃ እንዲቆጠር የመጀመሪያ ደረጃ ነው፡፡ ነገር ግን የጽሑፍ ዳታዎች ብዙ ጊዜ የሩቅ ሥርዓት ምሳሌዎችን ያሳፈርሳሉ፡፡ ከዚህም በላይ፣ እንደነዚህ ዓይነቶች ብጤቱን ብቻ ይመልሳሉ፣ ጥያቄ አይደለም፣ አካባቢዎች (ምናልባት ሰነዶች) በሚያሳየው ነው፡፡ Poisson ሞዴል የራቀ ሥርዓት መብትን ለመፍጠር የሚሻል ነው፣ ነገር ግን በቋንቋዊ ጽሑፍ ማስረጃ ውስጥ በLR ፍሬም ውስጥ ከቶ አልተፈተናም፡፡ የlog-LR ዋጋው (Cllr) የሁለቱን ዓይነት ጥያቄውን ለማስተዋል ተጠቃሚ ነበር። ይሄ ትምህርት:(1) የፊደል-based ሥርዓት በክሎሎር ግምገማዎች በኩል 0.09 በተሻለ አካል እና በክፍለ ጠቃሚ ማሳየት የቆሮስ አካላት እንዲያሳየው ነው፡፡ (2) የፊደል ሠሌዳው አካባቢ ማድረግ በፊደል ምርጫው ይሻላል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Գորտերի և հատկանիշների հիմնականությամբ հիմնված մեթոդները երկու հիմնական մեթոդն են, որոնք օգնում են գնահատել ապացույցների ուժը: Այս ֆորանսիկ տեքստի համեմատության (ՖԹԿ) ուսումնասիրության ընթացքում կոզինոսի հեռավորությունը օգտագործող գնահատականների հիմնված մեթոդը համեմատում է պոյսոնի մոդելի վրա կառուցված հատկանիշների հիմնված մեթոդի հետ, որը հավաքվում է 2,157 Հեռավորության չափումները (օրինակ Բուրոուսի Դելտան, Կոզինային հեռավորությունը) ստեղծվում են ավտորիայի պատասխանատվության ուսումնասիրություններում ստանդարտ գործիք: Այսպիսով, գնահատականներով հիմնված մեթոդի կիրառումը հեռավորության չափով օգտագործելով բնականաբար առաջին քայլն է, որպեսզի հաշվարկենք տեքստային ապացույցների LR-ները: Այնուամենայնիվ, տեքստային տվյալները հաճախ խախտում են հեռավորության վրա հիմնված վիճակագրական ենթադրությունները: Ավելին, այսպիսի մոդելները գնահատում են միայն համեմատության մեջ եղած օբյեկտների (այսինքն՝ փաստաթղթերի) նմանությունը, ոչ թե բնորոշությունը: Փոյսոնի մոդելը տեսականորեն ավելի հարմար է, քան հեռավորության հիմնված չափումները հեղինակության պատասխանատվության համար, բայց այն երբեք չի փորձարկվել լեզվաբանական տեքստի ապացույցներով LR-ում: Լոգ-ԼՌ արժեքը (CILr) օգտագործվել է երկու մեթոդների արդյունավետության գնահատման համար: Այս ուսումնասիրությունը ցույց է տալիս, որ: (1) հատկանիշներով հիմնված մեթոդը գերազանցում է գնահատականով հիմնված մեթոդը մոտ 0.9-ի CILr արժեքի միջոցով լավագույն արդյունավետության ընթացքում, և (2) հատկանիշներով հիմնված մեթոդի արդյունավետությունը կարող է շարունակել բարելավվել հատկանիշների ընտրության միջոցով:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_sq>Metodat bazuar në pikë dhe karakteristika janë dy metodat kryesore për vlerësimin e një raporti të mundësisë forenzike (LR) për kuantifikimin e forcës së provave. In this forensic text comparison (FTC) study, a score-based method using the Cosine distance is compared with a feature-based method built on a Poisson model with texts collected from 2,157 authors.  Masat e distancës (për shembull Delta e Burrows, distanca Kozin) janë një mjet standard në studimet e atribucionit të autoritetit. Kështu, zbatimi i një metode bazuar në rezultate duke përdorur një masë distance është natyrisht hapi i parë për vlerësimin e LR për prova tekstuale. Megjithatë, të dhënat tekstuale shpesh shkelin supozimet statistike bazuar në modelet e distancës. Përveç kësaj, modelet e tilla vlerësojnë vetëm ngjashmërinë, jo tipicitetin, e objekteve (pra dokumenteve) në krahasim. Një model Poisson është teorikisht më i përshtatshëm se masa bazuar në distancë për atribucionin e autorisë, por nuk është testuar kurrë me prova teksti gjuhësore brenda kuadrit LR. Kostoja log-LR (Cllr) u përdorë për të vlerësuar performancën e të dy metodave. Ky studim demonstron se: (1) metoda e bazuar në funksione e kalon metodën e bazuar në rezultate me një vlerë Cllr prej rreth 0.09 nën rregullimet më të mira dhe; (2) performanca e metodës bazuar në karakteristika mund të përmirësohet më tej nga zgjedhja e karakteristikave.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bn>পরিমাণ এবং বৈশিষ্ট্য ভিত্তিক পদ্ধতি হচ্ছে প্রমাণের শক্তি পরিমাণে ফরেন্সিক সম্ভাবনার হার (এলআর) হিসেবে দুই প্রধান উপায়। এই ফরেন্সিক টেক্সটের তুলনায় (এফটিসি) গবেষণায়, কোসিন দূরত্ব ব্যবহার করে একটি স্কোর ভিত্তিক পদ্ধতির তুলনায় একটি পইসন মডেলে তৈরি করা এক বৈশিষ্ট্যের মাধ্যমে ত বার্রোসের ডেল্টা, কোসিনের দূরত্ব) নির্দিষ্ট ব্যবস্থা (যেমন বার্রোসের দিল্টা) অনুমোদনের বিতরণ গবেষণায় একটি স্থান Thus, the implementation of a score-based method using a distance measure is naturally the first step for estimating LRs for textual evidence.  তবে টেক্সুয়াল ডাটা প্রায়শই দূরত্ব ভিত্তিক মডেলের ভিত্তিক পরিসংখ্যান ধারণা লঙ্ঘন করে। এছাড়াও, এই মডেলগুলো শুধুমাত্র একই ধরনের মূল্যের মূল্য দেয়া হচ্ছে, তার তুলনায় বস্তুর (যেমন ডকুমেন্ট) নয়। কিন্তু এলআর ফ্রেমের ভিত্তিক টেক্সট প্রমাণের মাধ্যমে এটি ভাষায় পরীক্ষা করা হয়নি। এই দুই পদ্ধতির প্রদর্শনের মূল্য মূল্যের জন্য লগ-LR খরচ (ক্লিআর) ব্যবহার করা হয়েছে। এই গবেষণা প্রদর্শন করে যে: (১) বৈশিষ্ট্য ভিত্তিক পদ্ধতি স্কোর ভিত্তিক পদ্ধতির মান প্রকাশ করে যা ক্লালারের মান প্রায় ০. ০৯ এর সেরা প্রদর্শন (2) বৈশিষ্ট্যের ভিত্তিক পদ্ধতির প্রদর্শনের বৈশিষ্ট্য নির্বাচনের মাধ্যমে আরো উন্নত হতে পারে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Metode osnovane na rezultatima i funkcijama su dvije glavne za procjenu odnosa forenzičke vjerojatnosti (LR) kvantificiranja snage dokaza. U ovom forenzičkom ispitivanju o usporedbi teksta (FTC), metoda bazirana na rezultatima koristeći udaljenost kosina se uspoređuje sa metodom baziranom na funkcijama izgrađenom na model Poisson sa tekstima skupljenim od 2.157 autora. Mjere udaljenosti (npr. Delta Burrows's, kosinska udaljenost) su standardni alat u ispitivanjima privlačenja autoriteta. Stoga, provedba metode na osnovu rezultata koristeći mjeru udaljenosti prirodno je prvi korak za procjenu LR-a za tekstualne dokaze. Međutim, tekstualni podaci često krše statističke pretpostavke na temelju modela na daljini. Osim toga, takvi modeli procjenjuju samo sličnost, ne tipičnost objekata (tj. dokumenti) u usporedbi. Model Poisson teoretički je prikladniji od mjera na temelju udaljenosti za privlačenje autoriteta, ali nikada nije testiran jezičkim tekstskim dokazima u okviru LR-a. Koštanje log-LR (Cllr) je korišćeno za procjenu učinka dva metoda. Ova ispitivanja pokazuje da: (1) metoda bazirana na funkcijama iznosi metodu baziranu na rezultatima Cllr vrijednošću ca. 0,09 pod najboljim nastavama i; (2) učinkovitost metode temeljene na funkcijama može se bolje poboljšati izrazom funkcija.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Score- and feature-based methods are the two main ones for estimating a forensic likelihood ratio (LR) quantifying the strength of evidence.  En aquest estudi de comparació forense del text (FTC), un mètode basat en puntuacions que utilitza la distància Cosine es compara amb un mètode basat en característiques construït en un model Poisson amb textos recollits de 2.157 autors. Les mesures de distància (per exemple, el Delta de Burrows, la distància cosina) s ón una e in a normal en estudis d'atribució d'autorització. Així doncs, la implementació d'un mètode basat en puntuacions utilitzant una mesura de distància és, naturalment, el primer pas per estimar les RL per a l'evidència textual. Tanmateix, les dades textuals sovint violan les suposicions estadístiques subjacents a models basats en distància. A més, aquests models només valoren la similitud, no la típicitat, dels objectes (és a dir, els documents) en comparació. Un model Poisson és teòricament més apropiat que les mesures basades en distància per l'atribució d'autorització, però mai no s'ha provat amb proves lingüístices de text dins l'estructura del LR. El cost log-LR (Cllr) va ser utilitzat per avaluar el rendiment dels dos mètodes. Aquest estudi demostra que: (1) el mètode basat en característiques supera el mètode basat en puntuacions amb un valor Cllr d'aproximadament 0,09 sota les opcions de millor rendiment i; (2) el rendiment del mètode basat en les característiques pot millorar més a través de la selecció de característiques.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_az>Nöqtələr və fərqli metodlar, dəlillərin gücünü ölçüyən forensik mümkünlüyü (LR) hesablamaq üçün iki ana metodlardır. Bu forensik mətn karşılaşdırması (FTC) təhsilində, kosinun uzaqlaşımını istifadə edən score-based metod 2.157 yazıcılardan toplanmış mətnlərlə Poisson modeli üzərində inşa edilmiş xüsusiyyətli metodlarla qarşılaşdırılır. Uzaqlıq ölçüləri (bəz. Burrows's Delta, Kosin uzaqlaşığı) authorship attribution çalışmalarında standart bir vasitədir. Beləliklə, uzaq ölçüsünü istifadə edən score-based metodun ilk adım, təbiətli dəlillər üçün LR hesablaması üçün ilk adımdır. Lakin, textual verilər çox çox uzaq-tabanlı modellərin altındakı statistik zənnələrini pozur. Daha sonra, bu modellər yalnız müqayisədə olanların bənzərini, bənzərini, bənzərini (bənzərini, bənzərini, bənzərini) müqayisədə təmin edirlər. Poisson modeli təsdiqlənmək üçün uzaq-tabanlı ölçülərdən daha münasibdir, amma LR çerçivesində dilli metin dəlilləri ilə imtahana edilməmişdir. log-LR maliyyəti (Cllr) iki metodların performansını müəyyən etmək üçün istifadə edildi. Bu təcrübə göstərir ki: (1) xüsusiyyətli metod, ca.0.09'nin ən yaxşı təcrübələrinin altında Cllr qiyməti ilə müəyyən edilən metodların üstünü artırar və; (2) Xüsusiyyətli metodların təhsil seçimi ilə daha yaxşılaşdırılabilir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_fi>Piste- ja ominaisuusperusteiset menetelmät ovat kaksi tärkeintä, joilla arvioidaan rikosteknistä todennäköisyyssuhdetta (LR), joka kvantifioi todisteiden vahvuuden. Tässä rikosteknisessä tekstivertailututkimuksessa (FTC) verrataan pistepohjaista menetelmää, jossa käytetään cosiinietäisyyttä, Poissonin malliin perustuvaan ominaisuuspohjaiseen menetelmään, jossa on kerätty tekstejä 2 157 tekijältä. Etäisyysmittarit (esim. Burrowsin delta, kosiinietäisyys) ovat vakiotyökalu tekijän attribution tutkimuksissa. Näin ollen pisteperusteisen menetelmän käyttöönotto etäisyysmittarilla on luonnollisesti ensimmäinen askel arvioitaessa tekstinäyttöä. Tekstitiedot rikkovat kuitenkin usein etäisyyteen perustuvien mallien taustalla olevia tilastollisia oletuksia. Lisäksi tällaisissa malleissa arvioidaan ainoastaan vertailtavien kohteiden (eli asiakirjojen) samankaltaisuutta eikä niiden tyypillisyyttä. Poissonin malli on teoreettisesti tarkoituksenmukaisempi kuin etäisyyspohjaiset tekijät, mutta sitä ei ole koskaan testattu kielellisillä tekstitodisteilla LR:n puitteissa. Näiden kahden menetelmän suorituskyvyn arvioinnissa käytettiin log-LR-kustannusta (Cllr). Tämä tutkimus osoittaa, että: (1) ominaisuuspohjainen menetelmä ylittää pistepohjaisen menetelmän Cllr-arvolla noin 0,09 parhaiten suoriutuvissa asetuksissa ja (2) ominaisuuspohjaisen menetelmän suorituskykyä voidaan parantaa entisestään ominaisuusvalinnalla.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_cs>Metody založené na skóre a funkcích jsou dvě hlavní metody pro odhad forenzní pravděpodobnosti (LR) kvantifikující sílu důkazů. V této studie forenzního porovnávání textů (FTC) je porovnána metoda založená na skóre využívající Cosinovou vzdálenost s metodou založenou na funkcích postavenou na Poissonově modelu s texty shromážděnými od 2,157 autorů. Měření vzdálenosti (např. Burrowsova delta, cosinová vzdálenost) jsou standardním nástrojem ve studiích atribuce autorství. Implementace metody založené na skóre využívající měření vzdálenosti je tedy samozřejmě prvním krokem pro odhad LR pro textové důkazy. Textová data však často porušují statistické předpoklady založené na vzdálenosti modelů. Dále tyto modely posuzují pouze podobnost, nikoli typickost, objektů (tj. dokumentů), které jsou srovnávány. Poissonový model je teoreticky vhodnější než měřítka založená na vzdálenosti pro atribuci autorství, ale nikdy nebyl testován s jazykovými textovými důkazy v rámci LR. Pro posouzení výkonnosti obou metod byly použity náklady log-LR (Cllr). Tato studie prokázala, že: (1) metoda založená na funkcích překonává metodu založenou na skóre o hodnotu Cllr cca 0.09 při nejlepších nastaveních a; (2) výkon metody založené na funkcích lze dále zlepšit výběrem funkcí.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Skoori- ja funktsioonipõhised meetodid on kaks peamist meetodit kohtuekspertiisi tõenäosuse suhte (LR) hindamiseks tõendite tugevuse kvantifitseerimiseks. Selles kohtuekspertiisilises tekstivõrdluses (FTC) võrreldakse skooripõhist meetodit koosinuse kauguse kasutamisel Poissoni mudelil põhineva funktsioonipõhise meetodiga, mille tekstid on kogutud 157 autorilt. Kauguse mõõtmised (nt Burrows'i delta, koosinuse kaugus) on standardne vahend autorsuse omistamise uuringutes. Seega on punktipõhise meetodi rakendamine kauguse mõõtmise abil loomulikult esimene samm tekstiliste tõendite hindamisel. Ent tekstiandmed rikuvad sageli kauguspõhiste mudelite aluseks olevaid statistilisi eeldusi. Lisaks hindavad sellised mudelid ainult võrdlusaluste objektide (st dokumentide) sarnasust, mitte tüüpilisust. Poissoni mudel on teoreetiliselt sobivam kui kaugpõhised meetmed autoriõiguse omistamiseks, kuid seda ei ole kunagi LR raamistikus keeleliste tekstitõenditega testitud. Mõlema meetodi tulemuslikkuse hindamiseks kasutati logi-LR kulu (Cllr). Käesolev uuring näitab, et: (1) funktsioonipõhine meetod ületab skooripõhist meetodit Cllr-väärtusega ligikaudu 0,09 parimate tulemuste korral ja (2) funktsioonipõhise meetodi tulemuslikkust saab veelgi parandada funktsioonide valimisega.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>Punika- lan kelengatan-pernik dipunangé kuwi wis dipunangé awak dhéwé kuwi nggawe barang langkung sampeyan (LR) nggawe nggawe barang nggawe In this underensic text conversion Distance Dayen, nggawe esuk-esuk sistem sing basa gambar n' aku gambar kelangan langgar sampek dadi soalé kanggo nggawe LRs kanggo ngilanggar nggambar textual. politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Dugangane Point The log-LR value (Cllr) was used to assess the output of the second method. Mbangu (2) Atongsane kang caret-basa perangkat diangkat luwih dumadhi kanggo ngubah caret nggawe.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>השיטות המבוססות על נקודות ותכונות הן שתי השיטות העיקריות להערכה יחסי סבירות פלילי (LR) בכמות את כוח הראיות. במחקר הזה על שיוואי טקסט פלילי (FTC), שיטה מבוססת על נקודות בשימוש במרחק קוזין שווה לשיטה מבוססת על תכונות בנויה על מודל פויסון עם טקסטים שנאספו מ-2,157 סופרים. מדדים מרחק (למשל דלתא של בורוס, מרחק קוזין) הם כלי סטנדרטי במחקרי ההתאמות של הסופרים. ככה, ההפעלה של שיטה מבוססת על נקודות בשימוש במדידת מרחק היא באופן טבעי הצעד הראשון להערכה LR לראיות טקסטיות. בכל אופן, נתונים טקסטיים לעתים קרובות מפרים את ההנחות הסטטיסטיות שביסוד מודלים מבוססים במרחק. בנוסף, דוגמנים כאלה מעריכים רק את הדמיון, לא את הדמיוניות, של האובייקטים (כלומר מסמכים) תחת השוואה. דוגמנית פויסון מתאימה באופן תיאורטי יותר מאמצעים מבוססים מרחק לתיאור הסופריות, אבל היא מעולם לא נבחנה עם ראיות טקסט שפתיים בתוך המסגרת LR. עלות לוג-LR (Cllr) השתמשו כדי להעריך ביצועים של שתי השיטות. מחקר זה מראה כי: (1) השיטה המבוססת על תכונות מובילה את השיטה המבוססת על נקודות על ידי ערך Cllr של ca. 0.09 תחת ההגדרות הכי טובות (2) ביצוע השיטה המבוססת על תכונות יכול להשתפר עוד על ידי בחירת תכונות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>@ label cikin wannan littãfin kafarin da aka daidaita (FTC), an daidaita wata hanyor da aka yi amfani da durowa na Cosin, a sami da wani shirin da aka gina a kan wani misalin Poisson da littattafai wanda aka tattara daga 2,157 marubuci. Shiryoyin Distance (misali, durowa na Burrows, Cosin) sunan daidaita kayar rubutu cikin karatun masu rubutu. Thus, the implementation of a score-based method using a distance measure is naturally the first step for estimating LRs for textual evidence.  A lokacin da data masu matsayi ko da yawa za su ƙẽtare zato masu fassarar da ke cikin misãlai mai nĩsa. Furan haka, misãlai masu ƙaddara kawai da daidaita, kuma ba da halin, abun (misali takardar) da ke samu'a. Wata motsi na Poisson yana da amfani da yin takanci a kanana tsawo wa fassarar mutane, kuma ba a jarraba shi ba da takardar littafan linguistic cikin firam na LR. An yi amfani da nau'in log-LR (Cllr) don a ƙayyade gyaran shiryoyin biyu. Wannan littafin ya nuna cewa: (1) metoden a kan salon da aka ƙayyade shi yana ƙara hanyon a kure da kimar Cllr na ca.0.09 kuma a ƙari mafi kyaun fasahan da; (2) Ana iya ƙara gyare game da zaɓen shirin tayari.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Metodi, ki temeljijo na ocenah in značilnostih, sta glavni metodi za ocenjevanje forenzičnega razmerja verjetnosti (LR), ki količinsko opredeljuje moč dokazov. V tej forenzični primerjavi besedil (FTC) primerjamo metodo na osnovi rezultatov, ki uporablja kozinusovo razdaljo, z metodo na osnovi funkcij, zgrajeno na Poissonovem modelu z besedili, zbranimi od 2.157 avtorjev. Meritve razdalje (npr. Burrowsova delta, kozinusna razdalja) so standardno orodje v študijah pripisovanja avtorstva. Tako je izvajanje metode, ki temelji na rezultatih z uporabo merila razdalje, seveda prvi korak za oceno LR za besedilne dokaze. Vendar besedilni podatki pogosto kršijo statistične predpostavke, ki temeljijo na modelih na razdalji. Poleg tega takšni modeli ocenjujejo le podobnost in ne tipičnost predmetov (tj. dokumentov) v primerjavi. Poissonov model je teoretično primernejši od meril na podlagi razdalje za pripisovanje avtorstva, vendar nikoli ni bil testiran z jezikovnimi besedilnimi dokazi znotraj LR okvira. Za oceno učinkovitosti obeh metod so bili uporabljeni stroški log-LR (Cllr). Ta študija kaže, da: (1) metoda, ki temelji na značilnostih, presega metodo, temelječo na rezultatih, z vrednostjo Cllr približno 0,09 v najboljših nastavitvah in (2) učinkovitost metode, ki temelji na značilnostih, se lahko dodatno izboljša z izbiro značilnosti.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>Score- and feature-based methods are the two main ones for estimating a forensic likelihood ratio (LR) quantifying the strength of evidence. In this forensic text comparison (FTC) study, a score-based method using the Cosine distance is compared with a feature-based method built on a Poisson model with texts collected from 2,157 authors. ཐག་རིང་ཚད་ (དཔེར་ན། Burrows's Delta དང་། Cosine distance) ནི་དབང་རྩལ་གནས་སྟངས་དང་མཐུན་གྱི་ལག་ཆ་ཨིན། དེར་བརྟེན། དབྱངས་ཚད་ལྟར་རིམ་པ་སྤྱོད་པའི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་གཞི་བྱས་པ་དེ་རང་བཞིན་གྱིས་དང་པོ་རིམ་གྱི་གྲལ་རིམ་དང་པོ་རེད། ཡིན་ནའང་། ཡི་གེའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག་ཆ་རྒྱུན་ལྟར་སྐོར་གྱི་ཚད་རྩལ་བ་གཞི་བརྟེན་པའི་མིག་དཔེ་གཏོང་བ་དང་། དཔེ་དབྱིབས་འདི་དག་གི་མིག་དཔེ་དབར་གཅིག་པུ་མཐུན་རིམ་པ་ལས་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་དངོས་པོ་ཚོ་མིན་པར། A Poisson model is theoretically more appropriate than distance-based measures for authorship attribution, but it has never been tested with linguistic text evidence within the LR framework. དྲན་སྒྲིག་གི་དངུལ་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་དོན་དག (Cllr)འདི་ཐབས་ལམ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་མཐའ་སྟོན་པར་བེད་སྤྱོད་ཡོད། This study demonstrates that: (1) the feature-based method outperforms the score-based method by a Cllr value of ca. 0.09 under the best-performing settings and; and (2) the performance of the feature-based method can be further improved by feature selection.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Modelling Verbal Morphology in Nen<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>en</title>
      <author><first>Saliha</first><last>Muradoglu</last></author>
      <author><first>Nicholas</first><last>Evans</last></author>
      <author><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Vylomova</last></author>
      <pages>43–53</pages>
      <abstract>Nen verbal morphology is particularly complex ; a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transitive_verb">transitive verb</a> can take up to 1,740 unique forms. The combined effect of having a large <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Combinatorics">combinatoric space</a> and a low-resource setting amplifies the need for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP tools</a>. Nen morphology utilises distributed exponence-a non-trivial means of mapping form to meaning. In this paper, we attempt to model Nen verbal morphology using state-of-the-art <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning models</a> for morphological reinflection. We explore and categorise the types of errors these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> generate. Our results show sensitivity to training data composition ; different distributions of verb type yield different accuracies (patterning with E-complexity). We also demonstrate the types of patterns that can be inferred from the training data, through the case study of sycretism.</abstract>
      <url hash="ff3d2866">2020.alta-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>muradoglu-etal-2020-modelling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Pandemic Literature Search : Finding Information on COVID-19<fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19</title>
      <author><first>Vincent</first><last>Nguyen</last></author>
      <author><first>Maciek</first><last>Rybinski</last></author>
      <author><first>Sarvnaz</first><last>Karimi</last></author>
      <author><first>Zhenchang</first><last>Xing</last></author>
      <pages>92–97</pages>
      <abstract>Finding information related to a pandemic of a novel disease raises new challenges for information seeking and retrieval, as the new information becomes available gradually. We investigate how to better <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranking_(information_retrieval)">rank information</a> for pandemic information retrieval. We experiment with different ranking algorithms and propose a novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/End-to-end_principle">end-to-end method</a> for neural retrieval, and demonstrate its effectiveness on the TREC COVID search. This work could lead to a search system that aids scientists, clinicians, policymakers and others in finding reliable answers from the scientific literature.</abstract>
      <url hash="2ca9a550">2020.alta-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>nguyen-etal-2020-pandemic</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/cord-19">CORD-19</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ms-marco">MS MARCO</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Information Extraction from Legal Documents : A Study in the Context of Common Law Court Judgements</title>
      <author><first>Meladel</first><last>Mistica</last></author>
      <author><first>Geordie Z.</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Hui</first><last>Chia</last></author>
      <author><first>Kabir Manandhar</first><last>Shrestha</last></author>
      <author><first>Rohit Kumar</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Saket</first><last>Khandelwal</last></author>
      <author><first>Jeannie</first><last>Paterson</last></author>
      <author><first>Timothy</first><last>Baldwin</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Beck</last></author>
      <pages>98–103</pages>
      <abstract>‘Common Law’ judicial systems follow the doctrine of precedent, which means the legal principles articulated in court judgements are binding in subsequent cases in lower courts. For this reason, lawyers must search prior judgements for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legal_doctrine">legal principles</a> that are relevant to their case. The difficulty for those within the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legal_profession">legal profession</a> is that the information that they are looking for may be contained within a few paragraphs or sentences, but those few paragraphs may be buried within a hundred-page document. In this study, we create a schema based on the relevant information that legal professionals seek within judgements and perform text classification based on it, with the aim of not only assisting lawyers in researching cases, but eventually enabling large-scale analysis of legal judgements to find trends in court outcomes over time.</abstract>
      <url hash="e1d80d6f">2020.alta-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>mistica-etal-2020-information</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Overview of the 2020 ALTA Shared Task : Assess Human Behaviour<fixed-case>ALTA</fixed-case> Shared Task: Assess Human Behaviour</title>
      <author><first>Diego</first><last>Mollá</last></author>
      <pages>127–130</pages>
      <abstract>The 2020 ALTA shared task is the 11th in stance of a series of shared tasks organised by ALTA since 2010. The task is to classify texts posted in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> according to human judgements expressed in them. The data used for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> is a subset of SemEval 2018 AIT DISC, which has been annotated by domain experts for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a>. In this paper we introduce the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a>, describe the data and present the results of participating systems.</abstract>
      <url hash="5ea36a9e">2020.alta-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>molla-2020-overview</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>