<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.bucc">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 13th Workshop on Building and Using Comparable Corpora</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Reinhard</first><last>Rapp</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pierre</first><last>Zweigenbaum</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Serge</first><last>Sharoff</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-42-9</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="a7cecf05">2020.bucc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>bucc-2020-building</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Constructing a Bilingual Corpus of Parallel Tweets</title>
      <author><first>Hamdy</first><last>Mubarak</last></author>
      <author><first>Sabit</first><last>Hassan</last></author>
      <author><first>Ahmed</first><last>Abdelali</last></author>
      <pages>14–21</pages>
      <abstract>In a bid to reach a larger and more diverse audience, Twitter users often post parallel tweetstweets that contain the same content but are written in different languages. Parallel tweets can be an important resource for developing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation (MT) systems</a> among other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing (NLP) tasks</a>. In this paper, we introduce a generic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> for collecting parallel tweets. Using this method, we collect a bilingual corpus of English-Arabic parallel tweets and a list of Twitter accounts who post English-Arabictweets regularly. Since our method is generic, it can also be used for collecting parallel tweets that cover less-resourced languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serbian_language">Serbian</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urdu">Urdu</a>. Additionally, we annotate a subset of Twitter accounts with their countries of origin and topic of interest, which provides insights about the population who post parallel tweets. This latter information can also be useful for author profiling tasks.</abstract>
      <url hash="b3ac5e2f">2020.bucc-1.3</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>mubarak-etal-2020-constructing</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bilingual-corpus-of-arabic-english-parallel">Bilingual Corpus of Arabic-English Parallel Tweets</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Automatic Creation of Correspondence Table of Meaning Tags from Two Dictionaries in One Language Using Bilingual Word Embedding</title>
      <author><first>Teruo</first><last>Hirabayashi</last></author>
      <author><first>Kanako</first><last>Komiya</last></author>
      <author><first>Masayuki</first><last>Asahara</last></author>
      <author><first>Hiroyuki</first><last>Shinnou</last></author>
      <pages>22–28</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we show how to use bilingual word embeddings (BWE) to automatically create a corresponding table of meaning tags from two dictionaries in one language and examine the effectiveness of the method. To do this, we had a problem : the meaning tags do not always correspond one-to-one because the granularities of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_sense">word senses</a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concepts</a> are different from each other. Therefore, we regarded the concept tag that corresponds to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_sense">word sense</a> the most as the correct concept tag corresponding the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_sense">word sense</a>. We used two BWE methods, a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_map">linear transformation matrix</a> and VecMap. We evaluated the most frequent sense (MFS) method and the corpus concatenation method for comparison. The accuracies of the proposed methods were higher than the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of the random baseline but lower than those of the MFS and corpus concatenation methods. However, because our method utilized the embedding vectors of the word senses, the relations of the sense tags corresponding to concept tags could be examined by mapping the sense embeddings to the vector space of the concept tags. Also, our methods could be performed when we have only concept or word sense embeddings whereas the MFS method requires a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_corpus">parallel corpus</a> and the corpus concatenation method needs two tagged corpora.</abstract>
      <url hash="3b5027b0">2020.bucc-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>hirabayashi-etal-2020-automatic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Benchmarking Multidomain English-Indonesian Machine Translation<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish-<fixed-case>I</fixed-case>ndonesian Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Tri Wahyu</first><last>Guntara</last></author>
      <author><first>Alham Fikri</first><last>Aji</last></author>
      <author><first>Radityo Eko</first><last>Prasojo</last></author>
      <pages>35–43</pages>
      <abstract>In the context of Machine Translation (MT) from-and-to English, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesian_language">Bahasa Indonesia</a> has been considered a low-resource language, and therefore applying Neural Machine Translation (NMT) which typically requires large training dataset proves to be problematic. In this paper, we show otherwise by collecting large, publicly-available datasets from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web">Web</a>, which we split into several domains : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News">news</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religion">religion</a>, general, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversation">conversation</a>, to train and benchmark some variants of transformer-based NMT models across the domains. We show using BLEU that our models perform well across them, outperform the baseline Statistical Machine Translation (SMT) models, and perform comparably with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Translate">Google Translate</a>. Our datasets (with the standard split for training, validation, and testing), code, and models are available on<url>https://github.com/gunnxx/indonesian-mt-data</url>
      </abstract>
      <url hash="7513e58c">2020.bucc-1.6</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>guntara-etal-2020-benchmarking</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/gunnxx/indonesian-mt-data" additional="false">gunnxx/indonesian-mt-data</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Reducing the Search Space for Parallel Sentences in Comparable Corpora</title>
      <author><first>Rémi</first><last>Cardon</last></author>
      <author><first>Natalia</first><last>Grabar</last></author>
      <pages>44–48</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes and evaluates simple techniques for reducing the research space for parallel sentences in monolingual comparable corpora. Initially, when searching for parallel sentences between two comparable documents, all the possible sentence pairs between the documents have to be considered, which introduces a great degree of imbalance between parallel pairs and non-parallel pairs. This is a problem because even with a high performing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a>, a lot of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noise">noise</a> will be present in the extracted results, thus introducing a need for an extensive and costly manual check phase. We work on a manually annotated subset obtained from a French comparable corpus and show how we can drastically reduce the number of sentence pairs that have to be fed to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> so that the results can be manually handled.</abstract>
      <url hash="fe2455e4">2020.bucc-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>cardon-grabar-2020-reducing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>TALN / LS2N Participation at the BUCC Shared Task : Bilingual Dictionary Induction from Comparable Corpora<fixed-case>TALN</fixed-case>/<fixed-case>LS</fixed-case>2<fixed-case>N</fixed-case> Participation at the <fixed-case>BUCC</fixed-case> Shared Task: Bilingual Dictionary Induction from Comparable Corpora</title>
      <author><first>Martin</first><last>Laville</last></author>
      <author><first>Amir</first><last>Hazem</last></author>
      <author><first>Emmanuel</first><last>Morin</last></author>
      <pages>56–60</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the TALN / LS2N system participation at the Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC) shared task. We first introduce three strategies : (i) a word embedding approach based on fastText embeddings ; (ii) a concatenation approach using both character Skip-Gram and character CBOW models, and finally (iii) a cognates matching approach based on an exact match string similarity. Then, we present the applied <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy_(game_theory)">strategy</a> for the shared task which consists in the combination of the embeddings concatenation and the cognates matching approaches. The covered languages are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_language">Russian</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_language">Spanish</a>. Overall, our system mixing embeddings concatenation and perfect cognates matching obtained the best results while compared to individual strategies, except for English-Russian and Russian-English language pairs for which the concatenation approach was preferred.</abstract>
      <url hash="c0189300">2020.bucc-1.9</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>laville-etal-2020-taln</bibkey>
    <title_ar>مشاركة TALN / LS2N في مهمة BUCC المشتركة: استقراء قاموس ثنائي اللغة من Corpora المقارنة</title_ar>
      <title_es>Participación de TALN/LS2N en la tarea compartida de BUCC: inducción de diccionarios bilingües de corpus comparables</title_es>
      <title_pt>TALN/LS2N Participação na Tarefa Compartilhada BUCC: Indução de Dicionário Bilíngue de Corpora Comparáveis</title_pt>
      <title_zh>TALN/LS2N 预 BUCC 共同任务:比语料库双语词典归</title_zh>
      <title_ja>BUCC共有タスクへのTALN/LS 2 Nの参加：比較可能なコーポラルからのバイリンガル辞書紹介</title_ja>
      <title_hi>BUCC साझा कार्य में TALN / LS2N भागीदारी: तुलनीय कॉर्पोरेट से द्विभाषी शब्दकोश प्रेरण</title_hi>
      <title_ga>TALN/LS2N Rannpháirtíocht i dTasc Comhroinnte BUCC: Ionduchtú Foclóir Dhátheangach ón gCorparáid Inchomparáide</title_ga>
      <title_ka>TALN/LS2N მოწყობილობა BUCC საზოგადომი დავალებაში: შემდგომარებული კორპორადან მეორე სიტყვანის ინდექცია</title_ka>
      <title_el>Συμμετοχή στην Κοινή Εργασία: Δίγλωσση επαγωγή λεξικού από συγκρίσιμο σώμα</title_el>
      <title_hu>TALN/LS2N Részvétel a BUCC Közös Feladatban: Kétnyelvű szótár indukció az összehasonlítható Corpora-tól</title_hu>
      <title_mk>Учеството на TALN/LS2N на заедничката задача на BUCC: Дивјазична индукција на речникот од Comparable Corpora</title_mk>
      <title_it>TALN/LS2N Partecipazione al BUCC Shared Task: Dizionario bilingue Induzione da Corpora Comparabile</title_it>
      <title_lt>TALN/LS2N Dalyvavimas bendroje BUCC užduotyje: palyginamosios korporacijos dvikalbis žodynas</title_lt>
      <title_kk>TALN/LS2N BUCC ортақтастырылған тапсырманың қатынасы: Сәйкестірілген Корпорадан екі сөздік индукциясы</title_kk>
      <title_ms>TALN/LS2N Pesertaan dalam Tugas Berkongsi BUCC: Penginduksi Kamus Bilingual dari Korpora Berbanding</title_ms>
      <title_ml>TALN/LS2N BUCC പങ്കാളിയുള്ള ജോലിയില്‍ പങ്കാളി</title_ml>
      <title_mt>TALN/LS2N Parteċipazzjoni fil-Ħidma Kondiviża tal-BUCC: Induzzjoni Bilingwali tad-Dikjarnarju minn Korpora Komparabbli</title_mt>
      <title_mn>TALN/LS2N BUCC хуваалцаагүй ажлын хувьд оролцоо: Comparable Corpora-ын хоёр дүгнэлт өгүүлбэр</title_mn>
      <title_no>TALN/LS2N deltakar på BUCC delt oppgåve: Bilinguell ordbokinduksjon frå kompatibelt korpora</title_no>
      <title_pl>TALN/LS2N Udział w BUCC Shared Task: Indukcja dwujęzycznego słownika z porównywalnego korpusu</title_pl>
      <title_ro>TALN/LS2N Participarea la sarcina comună BUCC: Inducția dicționarului bilingv de la Corpora Comparabilă</title_ro>
      <title_sr>TALN/LS2N učestvovanje u zajedničkom zadatku BUCC: Bilingualna indikacija rečnika iz usporedne korpore</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>TALN/LS2N Participation at the BUCC Shared Task: Bilingual Dictionary Induction from Comparable Corpora</title_so>
      <title_sv>TALN/LS2N Deltagande i BUCC Delad Uppgift: Tvåspråkig ordbok Induktion från jämförbara Corpora</title_sv>
      <title_ta>TALN/LS2N BUCC பகிர்ந்த பணியில் பங்கீடு</title_ta>
      <title_ur>TALN/LS2N مشارکت بوسی شریک ٹاکس میں: مشارکت کورپور سے دوئینگ ڈیکلینگ انڈاکٹ</title_ur>
      <title_uz>@ info: status</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Công việc chia sẻ BUCC: sự nghiệp sản xuất thuyết quán bar từ Tập đoàn đối chiếu.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Участие в съвместната задача на БУК: двуезична индукция на речника от сравним корпор</title_bg>
      <title_da>TALN/LS2N Deltagelse i BUCC Fælles Opgave: Tosproget ordbog Induktion fra sammenlignelig Corpora</title_da>
      <title_nl>TALN/LS2N Deelname aan de BUCC Shared Task: Tweetalige woordenboek Inductie uit Vergelijkbaar Corpora</title_nl>
      <title_hr>TALN/LS2N učestvovanje u zajedničkom zadatku BUCC-a: dvostruka indukcija riječnika iz usporedne korpore</title_hr>
      <title_de>TALN/LS2N Teilnahme am BUCC Shared Task: zweisprachige Wörterbuchinduktion aus vergleichbarem Korpora</title_de>
      <title_ko>TALN/LS2NBUCC 공유 작업 참여: 비교 가능한 언어 자료 라이브러리에서 이중 언어 사전 귀납</title_ko>
      <title_fa>شرکت TALN/LS2N در وظیفه مشترک BUCC: فشار دوگانه‌ای از شرکت قابل مقایسه</title_fa>
      <title_id>TALN/LS2N Participation at the BUCC Shared Task: Bilingual Dictionary Induction from Comparable Corpora</title_id>
      <title_sw>TALN/LS2N ushiriki katika kazi ya BUCC ilishirikishwa: Ujenzi wa Kidikteta wa lugha kutoka Corpora inayofanana</title_sw>
      <title_sq>TALN/LS2N Pjesëmarrja në detyrën e përbashkët të BUCC: Induktimi dygjuhësor nga korpora e krahasueshme</title_sq>
      <title_tr>TALN/LS2N BUCC Paylaşım Görevinde Hizmet: Bilingual Sözlük Induction from Comparable Corpora</title_tr>
      <title_af>TALN/LS2N Deelnadering by die BUCC Gedeelde Opdrag: Bilinguele Woordeboek Induksie van Vergelykbare Korpora</title_af>
      <title_am>TALN/LS2N ተጋሪዎች BUCC Shared Task: Bilingual Dictionary Induction from Comparable Corpora</title_am>
      <title_az>BUCC paylaşılan işdə TALN/LS2N Bölüm: Compatibile Corpora'dan İkinci Sözlük Induksyonu</title_az>
      <title_hy>ՏԱLN-ի և LS2N-ի մասնակցությունը ԲուԿԿ-ի ընդհանուր հանձնարարում' Երկլեզու բառարանի ինդուկցիան համեմատական Կորպորայից</title_hy>
      <title_bn>TALN/LS2N বিউসিসি শেয়ার কর্মসূচিতে অংশগ্রহণ: তুলনা কর্পোরা থেকে বিলিঙ্গুলি অভিভাবক নির্দেশনা</title_bn>
      <title_bs>TALN/LS2N učestvovanje u zajedničkom zadatku BUCC: dvostruka indukcija dizajnera iz usporedne korpore</title_bs>
      <title_ca>TALN/LS2N Participation at the BUCC Shared Task: Bilingual Dictionary Induction from Comparable Corpora</title_ca>
      <title_cs>TALN/LS2N Účast na BUCC Shared Task: dvojjazyčná indukce slovníku ze srovnatelného korpusu</title_cs>
      <title_et>TALN/LS2N osalemine BUCC jagatud ülesandel: kahekeelse sõnaraamatu induktsioon võrreldavatest korpustest</title_et>
      <title_fi>TALN/LS2N Osallistuminen BUCC:n yhteiseen tehtävään: Kaksikielinen sanakirja Induktio vertailukelpoisesta corporasta</title_fi>
      <title_jv>MALN</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Sodelovanje TALN/LS2N na skupni nalogi BUCC: dvojezični slovar Indukcija iz primerljivih korpusov</title_sk>
      <title_ha>TALN/LS2N</title_ha>
      <title_he>TALN/LS2N משתתף במשימה המשותפת של BUCC: מילון משולש משותף</title_he>
      <title_bo>TALN/LS2N Participation at the BUCC Shared Task: Bilingual Dictionary Induction from Comparable Corpora</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تصف هذه الورقة مشاركة نظام TALN / LS2N في المهمة المشتركة للبناء واستخدام Corpora (BUCC). نقدم أولاً ثلاث استراتيجيات: (1) نهج تضمين كلمة يعتمد على تضمين النص السريع ؛ (2) نهج التسلسل باستخدام كل من نماذج Skip-Gram والحرف CBOW ، وأخيرًا (3) نهج المطابقة المتشابه على أساس تشابه سلسلة المطابقة التامة. بعد ذلك ، نقدم الإستراتيجية المطبقة للمهمة المشتركة والتي تتكون من مزيج من تسلسل حفلات الزفاف وأساليب المطابقة المتشابهة. اللغات المشمولة هي الفرنسية والإنجليزية والألمانية والروسية والإسبانية. بشكل عام ، حصل نظامنا الذي يخلط تسلسل حفلات الزفاف والمطابقة المتشابهة المثالية على أفضل النتائج مقارنة بالاستراتيجيات الفردية ، باستثناء أزواج اللغتين الإنجليزية والروسية والإنجليزية التي كان نهج التسلسل مفضلًا لها.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo descreve a participação do sistema TALN/LS2N na tarefa compartilhada Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Primeiramente, apresentamos três estratégias: (i) uma abordagem de incorporação de palavras baseada em incorporação de fastText; (ii) uma abordagem de concatenação usando os modelos Skip-Gram de caracteres e CBOW de caracteres e, finalmente (iii) uma abordagem de correspondência de cognatos baseada em uma similaridade de cadeia de correspondência exata. Em seguida, apresentamos a estratégia aplicada para a tarefa compartilhada que consiste na combinação das abordagens de concatenação de embeddings e correspondência de cognatos. Os idiomas abrangidos são francês, inglês, alemão, russo e espanhol. No geral, nosso sistema de combinação de concatenação de embeddings e correspondência perfeita de cognatos obteve os melhores resultados em comparação com estratégias individuais, exceto para pares de idiomas inglês-russo e russo-inglês para os quais a abordagem de concatenação foi preferida.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Este documento describe la participación del sistema TALN/LS2N en la tarea compartida Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Primero introducimos tres estrategias: (i) un enfoque de incrustación de palabras basado en incrustaciones de FastText; (ii) un enfoque de concatenación que utiliza modelos de salto-grama de caracteres y CBOW de caracteres, y finalmente (iii) un enfoque de coincidencia afín basado en una similitud de cadenas de caracteres de coincidencia exacta. A continuación, presentamos la estrategia aplicada para la tarea compartida que consiste en la combinación de los enfoques de concatenación de incrustaciones y emparejamiento afín. Los idiomas cubiertos son el francés, el inglés, el alemán, el ruso y el español. En general, nuestro sistema que mezcla la concatenación de incrustaciones y el emparejamiento perfecto de cognados obtuvo los mejores resultados en comparación con las estrategias individuales, excepto para los pares de idiomas inglés-ruso y ruso-inglés para los que se prefirió el enfoque de concatenación.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>この論文では、比較可能なコーラ（ BUCC ）共有タスクの構築と使用におけるTALN/LS 2 Nシステムの参加について説明します。まず、(i)高速テキスト埋め込みに基づく単語埋め込みアプローチ、(ii)文字スキップ-グラムモデルと文字CBOWモデルの両方を使用する連結アプローチ、そして最後に(iii)完全に一致する文字列の類似性に基づくコグネイトマッチングアプローチの3つの戦略を紹介します。次に、埋め込み連結とコグネイトマッチングアプローチの組み合わせで構成される共有タスクの適用された戦略を提示します。対象言語はフランス語、英語、ドイツ語、ロシア語、スペイン語です。全体的に、組み込みの連結と完璧なコグネイトマッチングのシステムは、連結アプローチが好ましい英語-ロシア語とロシア語-英語のペアを除いて、個々の戦略と比較して最高の結果を得ました。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>本文述 TALN/LS2N 统参构用,较语料库 (BUCC) 共事。 首言三策:(i)基于fastText嵌之词; (ii)用字符Skip-Gram与字符CBOW模形之法,最后(iii)基于精匹字符串相似性同源匹配之法。 然后共事之策,嵌联同源之组。 涵盖言法语,英语,德语,俄语西班牙语。 总体而言,比之单策,系统混嵌完同源匹配最佳,非首选联之英语 - 俄语与俄语 - 英语语对。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर TALN/LS2N सिस्टम भागीदारी का वर्णन करता है जो बिल्डिंग और यूजिंग कॉम्पेयरेबल कॉर्पोरेट (BUCC) साझा कार्य में है। हम पहले तीन रणनीतियों का परिचय देते हैं: (i) फास्टटेक्स्ट एम्बेडिंग के आधार पर एक शब्द एम्बेडिंग दृष्टिकोण; (ii) चरित्र स्किप-ग्राम और चरित्र सीबीओडब्ल्यू मॉडल दोनों का उपयोग करके एक संयोजन दृष्टिकोण, और अंत में (iii) एक सटीक मिलान स्ट्रिंग समानता के आधार पर एक कॉग्नेट्स मिलान दृष्टिकोण। फिर, हम साझा कार्य के लिए लागू रणनीति प्रस्तुत करते हैं जिसमें एम्बेडिंग संयोजन और कॉग्नेट्स मिलान दृष्टिकोण के संयोजन के संयोजन में शामिल होते हैं। कवर की गई भाषाएं फ्रेंच, अंग्रेजी, जर्मन, रूसी और स्पेनिश हैं। कुल मिलाकर, हमारे सिस्टम मिश्रण embeddings concatenation और सही cognates मिलान अंग्रेजी-रूसी और रूसी-अंग्रेजी भाषा जोड़े को छोड़कर, व्यक्तिगत रणनीतियों की तुलना में सबसे अच्छा परिणाम प्राप्त किया, जिसके लिए concatenation दृष्टिकोण पसंद किया गया था।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Déanann an páipéar seo cur síos ar rannpháirtíocht an chórais TALN/LS2N sa tasc comhroinnte um Thógáil agus Úsáid Corpora Inchomparáide (BUCC). Ar dtús tugaimid trí straitéis isteach: (i) cur chuige um leabú focal bunaithe ar leabaithe mearthéacs; (ii) cur chuige comhtháite ag baint úsáide as samhlacha carachtar Skip-Gram agus carachtar CBOW, agus ar deireadh (iii) cur chuige comhchuibhithe gaolmhar bunaithe ar chosúlacht teaghrán meaitseála beacht. Ansin, cuirimid i láthair an straitéis fheidhmeach don tasc comhroinnte atá comhdhéanta de chomhghaolú an leabaithe agus na cuir chuige meaitseála gaolmhaire. Is iad na teangacha clúdaithe Fraincis, Béarla, Gearmáinis, Rúisis agus Spáinnis. Tríd is tríd, fuair ár gcóras meascadh leabaithe comhchatánaithe agus meaitseáil ghaolmhar foirfe na torthaí is fearr agus iad i gcomparáid le straitéisí aonair, ach amháin i gcás péirí Béarla-Rúisis agus Rúisis-Béarla arbh fhearr an cur chuige comhcheangail ina leith.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία περιγράφει τη συμμετοχή του συστήματος στο κοινό έργο οικοδόμησης και χρήσης συγκρίσιμων σωμάτων (BUCC). Πρώτα εισάγουμε τρεις στρατηγικές: (i) μια προσέγγιση ενσωμάτωσης λέξεων βασισμένη σε ενσωμάτωση γρήγορου κειμένου. (ii) μια προσέγγιση συσχέτισης χρησιμοποιώντας και τα μοντέλα Skip-Gram και CBOW χαρακτήρων, και τέλος (iii) μια προσέγγιση αντιστοίχισης βασισμένη σε μια ακριβή ομοιότητα συμβολοσειρών αντιστοίχισης. Στη συνέχεια, παρουσιάζουμε την εφαρμοζόμενη στρατηγική για την κοινή εργασία η οποία συνίσταται στον συνδυασμό των συνδέσεων ενσωμάτωσης και των προσεγγίσεων αντιστοίχισης αντιστοίχισης. Οι καλυπτόμενες γλώσσες είναι γαλλικά, αγγλικά, γερμανικά, ρωσικά και ισπανικά. Συνολικά, το σύστημά μας που αναμιγνύει τη συμπλήρωση ενσωμάτωσης και την τέλεια αντιστοίχιση κονιών απέκτησε τα καλύτερα αποτελέσματα ενώ συγκρίνεται με μεμονωμένες στρατηγικές, εκτός από τα ζεύγη αγγλικής-ρωσικής και ρωσικής-αγγλικής γλώσσας για τα οποία προτιμήθηκε η προσέγγιση συμπλήρωσης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დოკუმენტი აღწერს TALN/LS2N სისტემის დამატებით დამატებით და გამოყენებას შემდგომარებული კორპორა (BUCC) დამატებით. ჩვენ პირველად სამი სტრატიგური გადავიყენებთ: i) სიტყვების გადაყენება, რომელიც FastText დაყენებულია; ii) კონფინციო პროგრამა, რომელიც გამოყენებულია სიმბოლოები Skip-Gram და სიმბოლოები CBOW მოდელების გამოყენება, და ბოლოს iii) კონფინციო კონფინციო, რომელიც კონფინციო შემდეგ ჩვენ ჩვენ გავაჩვენოთ მომხმარებული სტრატიგია საერთო დავალებისთვის, რომელიც კონფიგურაციის კონფიგურაციის კონფიგურაციის კონფიგურაციაში შექმნა და კ საკუთარი ენები არის ფრანგური, ანგლისური, გერმანური, პოსონური და სპანელი. ჩვენი სისტემის შემთხვევაში შემთხვევაში კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური კონფიგური შემთხვევაში მიიღეთ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A tanulmány bemutatja a TALN/LS2N rendszer részvételét a Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC) megosztott feladatban. Először három stratégiát vezetünk be: (i) egy szóbeágyazási megközelítés, amely a fastText beágyazásokon alapul; (ii) összekapcsolási megközelítés mind a Skip-Gram, mind a karakter CBOW modelleket használva, és végül (iii) egy pontos egyezési karakterlánc hasonlóságon alapuló megközelítés. Ezután bemutatjuk a megosztott feladatra vonatkozó alkalmazott stratégiát, amely a beágyazások összekapcsolódásából és a kognációs megközelítések kombinációjából áll. A lefedett nyelvek a francia, angol, német, orosz és spanyol. Összességében az egyéni stratégiákhoz képest a legjobb eredményeket értük el rendszerkeverő beágyazások összekapcsolásával és tökéletes kognátok összehasonlításával, kivéve az angol-orosz és orosz-angol nyelvpárokat, amelyeknél előnyben részesítettük az összekapcsolási megközelítést.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo descrive la partecipazione del sistema TALN/LS2N al compito condiviso Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Per prima cosa introduciamo tre strategie: (i) un approccio word embedding basato su fastText embeddings; (ii) un approccio di concatenazione utilizzando entrambi i modelli di carattere Skip-Gram e CBOW, e infine (iii) un approccio di corrispondenza cognitivo basato su una somiglianza esatta delle stringhe di corrispondenza. Quindi, presentiamo la strategia applicata per il compito condiviso che consiste nella combinazione delle concatenazioni di incorporazione e degli approcci di matching cognitivi. Le lingue coperte sono francese, inglese, tedesco, russo e spagnolo. Nel complesso, il nostro sistema di miscelazione di incorporazioni concatenate e perfect cognate matching ha ottenuto i migliori risultati rispetto alle singole strategie, ad eccezione delle coppie di lingue inglese-russo e russo-inglese per le quali è stato preferito l'approccio concatenazione.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente aprašomas TALN/LS2N sistemos dalyvavimas bendroje pastatų ir palyginamos korporacijos (BUCC) užduotyje. Pirmiausia įvedame tris strategijas: i) žodži ų įterpimo metodą, pagrįstą greitText įterpimu; ii) sutrumpinimo metodas naudojant tiek Skip-Gram, tiek CBOW modelius ir galiausiai iii) sutrumpinimo metodas, pagrįstas tiksliu atitikties juostos panašumu. Tuomet pristatysime taikytą bendros užduoties strategiją, kurią sudaro įdėjimo sutapimo ir kognatų derinimo metodai. Apibrėžiamos prancūzų, anglų, vokiečių, rusų ir ispanų kalbos. Apskritai, mūsų sistema, kuria derinami įdėjiniai ir tobulai suderinami pažįstamieji gaminiai, pasiekė geriausius rezultatus lyginant su atskiromis strategijomis, išskyrus anglų-rusų ir rusų-anglų kalbų poras, kurioms labiausiai buvo taikomas suvienodinimo metodas.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз TALN/LS2N жүйесінің құрылғындағы және Сәйкестік Корпора (BUCC) ортақ тапсырмасын қолдану және қолдану үшін қатынасын анықтайды. Біз біріншіден үш стратегия келтірдік: ii) таңбалар мен CBOW үлгілерін қолданып сәйкестік тәртібі, соңында (iii) сәйкестік жолдың ұқсастығына негізделген сәйкестік тәртібін белгілейді. Содан кейін біз ортақ тапсырма үшін қолданылатын стратегияны таңдаймыз. Бұл ендірілген тапсырмалардың біріктірілімі мен сәйкес келесімдерді біріктіреді. Мұндай тілдер француз, ағылшын, неміс, руссия және испан тілдері. Жалпы, біздің жүйеміздің сәйкестігіміз сәйкестіктеріміз бір стратегиялармен салыстырып, ағылшын-русс және русс-ағылшын тілдер тілдерінің екісінің жалпы нәтижелерін түсіндіреді. Бұл</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>This paper describes the TALN/LS2N system participation at the Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC) shared task.  Kami pertama-tama memperkenalkan tiga strategi: (i) pendekatan penyembedding perkataan berdasarkan penyembedding teks pantas; (ii) pendekatan penyesalan menggunakan kedua-dua aksara Skip-Gram dan model CBOW aksara, dan akhirnya (iii) pendekatan yang sepadan berdasarkan persamaan rentetan yang tepat. Kemudian, kita memperkenalkan strategi yang dilaksanakan untuk tugas berkongsi yang terdiri dalam kombinasi penyesalan penyembedding dan pendekatan yang sepadan. Bahasa tertutup adalah Perancis, Inggeris, Jerman, Rusia dan Sepanyol. Secara keseluruhan, sistem kita mencampurkan penyelesaian penyelesaian penyelesaian dan penyelesaian penyelesaian sempurna mendapat hasil terbaik semasa dibandingkan dengan strategi individu, kecuali pasangan bahasa Inggeris-bahasa Inggeris-bahasa Inggeris-bahasa Inggeris-bahasa Inggeris yang mana pendekatan penyelesaian lebih suka.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jiddeskrivi l-parteċipazzjoni tas-sistema TALN/LS2N fil-kompitu kondiviż tal-Bini u l-Użu ta’ Korpora Komparabbli (BUCC). L-ewwel jintroduċu tliet strateġiji: (i) approċċ ta' inkorporazzjoni tal-kliem ibbażat fuq inkorporazzjoni rapida tat-Test; (ii) approċċ ta’ konċentrazzjoni bl-użu kemm ta’ mudelli ta’ Skip-Gram kif ukoll ta’ CBOW tal-karattru, u fl-a ħħar mill-aħħar (iii) approċċ ta’ konċentrazzjoni bbażat fuq similarità eżatta ta’ strings ta’ qbil. Imbagħad, nippreżentaw l-istrateġija applikata għall-kompitu kondiviż li tikkonsisti fil-kombinazzjoni tal-konċentrazzjoni tal-inkorporazzjonijiet u l-approċċi ta’ tqabbil tal-konġenati. Il-lingwi koperti huma Franċiż, Ingliż, Ġermaniż, Russu u Spanjol. B’mod ġenerali, is-sistema tagħna li tħallat il-konċentrazzjoni tal-inkorporazzjonijiet u l-konġenati perfetti li jaqblu kisbet l-aħjar riżultati filwaqt li tqabblu mal-istrateġiji individwali, ħlief għall-pari tal-lingwa Ingliża-Ingliża, Ingliża-Ingliża u Ingliża-Ingliża li għalihom kien ippreferut l-approċċ tal-kon</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ TALN/LS2N സിസ്റ്റം പങ്കുചേര്‍ത്ത പണിയില്‍ പങ്കുചേര്‍ക്കുന്നതും ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതും പങ്കുചേര്‍ക്കുന്ന പണി ആദ്യം നമ്മള്‍ മൂന്നു ട്രാക്ടിക്യൂട്ടീജിനെ പരിചയപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു: (i) സ്ഥാനത്തിന്‍റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്ത് വാ (ii) അക്ഷരരൂപത്തില്‍ സ്കിപ്പ്- ഗ്രാമും സിബിയോവ് മോഡലുകളും ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന ഒരു സങ്കീര്‍ണ്ണമായ നടപടിയും, അവസാനം (ഐ) ഒരു കോഗ്നേറ്റുകള്‍ ശരിയായ പ്ര പിന്നെ നമ്മള്‍ പങ്കുചേര്‍ക്കുന്ന ജോലിക്കുള്ള പ്രയോഗിച്ച പ്രയോഗിച്ചുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്ന പ്രയോഗിക്കുന്ന ഒരു പ്രയോഗി മൂടിയ ഭാഷകള്‍ ഫ്രഞ്ച്, ഇംഗ്ലീഷ്, ജര്‍മ്മന്‍, റഷ്യന്‍, സ്പാനിഷ് എന്നിവരാണ്. എല്ലായിടത്തും നമ്മുടെ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ സംവിധാനങ്ങള്‍ കൂട്ടിചേര്‍ക്കുന്നതും പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായ കോഗ്നേറ്റുകളും കൂട്ടിചേര്‍ക്കുന്നതും നല്ല ഫലങ്ങള്‍ ലഭിച്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mk>Овој весник го опишува учеството на системот TALN/LS2N во заедничката задача за изградба и употреба на споредлива корпора (BUCC). Прво воведуваме три стратегии: (i) пристап на вградување на зборови базиран на брзи вградувања на текст; (ii) a concatenation approach using both character Skip-Gram and character CBOW models, and finally (iii) a cognates matching approach based on an exact match string similarity.  Потоа, ја претставуваме аплицираната стратегија за заедничката задача која се состои од комбинацијата на концентрација на вградувањата и способните пристапи на когнатите. Покриените јазици се француски, англиски, германски, руски и шпански. Вкупно, нашиот систем мешање на вградените концентрации и совршените концентрации доби најдобри резултати во споредба со индивидуалните стратегии, освен парови на англиско-руско и руско-англиско јазик за кои беше префериран концентрациониот пристап.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас нь TALN/LS2N системийн барилга болон Comparable Corpora (BUCC) хуваалцааны ажлыг ашиглаж байгааг тайлбарладаг. Бид эхлээд гурван стратегийг танилцуулж байна: ii) харьцаа Skip-Gram болон харьцаа CBOW загваруудыг ашиглаж байдаг тодорхойлолтын арга баримтууд. Эцэст нь iii) тодорхойлолтын арга баримтуудыг тодорхойлдог стринг тодорхойлолтой байдаг. Дараа нь бид хуваалцах үйл ажиллагаанд хэрэглэгдсэн стратегийг тайлбарлаж өгдөг. Энэ нь холбогдолтын нэгтгэл, холбогдолтой ойлголтын нэгтгэл юм. Холбоотой хэл бол Француз, Англи, Герман, Орос, Испан. Ихэнх тохиолдолд бидний систем холбогдолтой холбогдолтой холбогдолтой, төгс мэдлэгтэй холбогдолтой холбогдолтой болсон. Гэхдээ хэн нэгэн стратегийг харьцуулахад хамгийн сайн үр дүнг олсон. Англи-Орос, Орос-Англ</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret beskriver deltakaren av TALN/LS2N-systemet på bygging og bruk kompatibelt korpora (BUCC) delt oppgåve. Vi introduserer først tre strategiar: i) eit ord innebæringstilnærming basert på fastText-innbæringar. ii) ein samsvar-tilnærming med både teikn Hopp-Gram og teikn CBOW-modeller, og til slutt (iii) kjenner ein tilnærming basert på eit nøyaktig samsvar med teikn. Så presenterer vi den tilgjengelege strategien for den delte oppgåva som inneheld i kombinasjonen av samsvar med innbøkingar og kjenner tilgjengelege tilnærmingar. Den dekke språka er fransk, engelsk, tysk, russisk og spansk. Overalt, våre systemmeldingar innebygger sammenlikning og perfekt kognisjon som passar, fikk dei beste resultatene sammenlignet med individuelle strategier, unntatt for engelsk- russisk og russisk- engelsk parer som sammenlikninga er foretrukket for.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł opisuje uczestnictwo systemu TALN/LS2N w zadaniu wspólnym Budowanie i Używanie Porównywalnych Korpusów (BUCC). Najpierw przedstawiamy trzy strategie: (i) podejście do osadzenia słów oparte na osadzeniach fastText; (ii) podejście do łączenia z wykorzystaniem zarówno modeli CBOW znaków Skip-Gram, jak i CBOW znaków, a na koniec (iii) podejście do dopasowania oparte na podobieństwie ciągu dokładnego dopasowania. Następnie przedstawiamy zastosowaną strategię dla wspólnego zadania, która polega na połączeniu łączeń osadzeń i podejść kojarzonych dopasowujących. Objęte językami są francuski, angielski, niemiecki, rosyjski i hiszpański. Ogólnie rzecz biorąc, nasz system mieszania łączeń osadzeń i perfekcyjnego dopasowania poznań uzyskał najlepsze rezultaty w porównaniu do indywidualnych strategii, z wyjątkiem par językowych angielsko-rosyjsko i rosyjsko-angielsko, dla których preferowano podejście łączenia.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare descrie participarea sistemului TALN/LS2N la sarcina comună Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Introducem mai întâi trei strategii: (i) o abordare de încorporare a cuvintelor bazată pe încorporarea fastText; (ii) o abordare de concatenare care utilizează atât modelele de tip Skip-Gram, cât și modelele CBOW de tip caracter și, în cele din urmă (iii) o abordare de potrivire cunoaște bazată pe o similitudine exactă a șirului de potrivire. Apoi, prezentăm strategia aplicată pentru sarcina partajată care constă în combinația concatenării încorporărilor și abordărilor de potrivire a cunoașterii. Limbile acoperite sunt franceza, engleza, germana, rusa si spaniola. În general, sistemul nostru de amestecare a încorporărilor concatenate și potrivirea perfectă a cunoștințelor a obținut cele mai bune rezultate în comparație cu strategiile individuale, cu excepția perechilor de limbi engleză-rusă și rusă-engleză pentru care a fost preferată abordarea concatenării.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir opisuje sudjelovanje TALN/LS2N sistema u zgradi i korištenju komparabilne korpore (BUCC) zajedničkog zadatka. Prvo predstavljamo tri strategije: i) reč uključujući pristup na osnovu fastText ugrađenja; ii) pristup usklađivanja koristeći i modele karaktera Skip-Gram i karakter CBOW, i konačno (iii) kogniraju odgovarajući pristup na temelju tačne sličnosti string. Onda predstavljamo prijavljenu strategiju za zajednički zadatak koji se sastoji u kombinaciji sastavljanja sastavka i kognije odgovarajućih pristupa. Pokriveni jezici su francuski, engleski, nemački, ruski i španjolski. U svemu, naš sistem miješanje integracije i savršene kognite odgovarajuće dobio je najbolji rezultat u usporedbi sa individualnim strategijama, osim parova engleskog-ruskog i ruskog-engleskog jezika za koje je predložen pristup samoporavnosti.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalkan waxaa lagu qoraa qayb ka qeybqaadashada nidaamka TALN/LS2N ee Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Marka ugu horeysa waxaynu soo bandhignaynaa saddex strategiyo: (i) hadal ku habboon oo ku saleysan Text embeddings; (ii) qaab ku habboon isku mid ah oo ku isticmaalaya qoraalka Skip-Gram iyo qoraalka CBOW, ugu danbayna (iii) xiliga ku habboon isku mid ah xadhig saxda ah. Markaas waxaynu soo bandhignaa qorshaha la xiriiray shaqada la wadaajiyey oo ku jirta wadajirka xubnaha iyo qalabka la isku daro. Luqadaha qarsoon waa Faraansiis, Ingiriis, Jarmal, Ruush iyo Isbanish. Inta oo dhan, nidaamkayaga isku xiran kooxaha iyo kooxaha kaamilka ah ayaa helay resultiyada ugu wanaagsan marka la barbardhigo qoraalada gaarka ah, labada luuqada Ingiriis-Ruush iyo Ingiriis-Ingiriis-ka mooyaane, kuwaas oo ay u dooratay dhaqdhaqaaqdhaqaaq.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>මේ පැත්තේ TALN/LS2N පද්ධතිය බිල්ඩිම් එක්ක සහ සම්පූර්ණ කෝර්පෝරාව (BUCC) භාවිත කරන්න පුළුවන් විස්තර කරන්න මුලින්ම අපි ප්‍රධානය තුනක් ප්‍රදේශ කරන්න: (i) FastText Embdings විසින් අධාරිත වචනයක්; (II) අක්ෂර ස්කිප්-ග්‍රෑම් සහ අක්ෂර CBOW මෝඩල් දෙන්නම් භාවිතා සම්පූර්ණ විදිහට සම්පූර්ණ විදිහට සම්පූර්ණ විදිහට ඊට පස්සේ, අපි සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන් සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන් සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන් සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන් සහ සම්බන්ධ වෙනු කපුරු භාෂාවල් තමයි ෆ්‍රෑන්ස්, ඉංග්‍රීසි, ජර්මන්, රුසියාන්, ස්පැනිස්. සම්පූර්ණයෙන්, අපේ පද්ධතිය මික්ස් එක්ක සම්පූර්ණයෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් පිළිගත්ත</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats beskriver TALN/LS2N-systemdeltagandet vid den delade uppgiften Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Vi introducerar först tre strategier: (i) en word embedding approach baserad på fastText embeddings; (ii) ett sammanlänkat tillvägagångssätt med både tecken Skip-Gram och tecken CBOW modeller, och slutligen (iii) ett kognitivt matchande tillvägagångssätt baserat på en exakt matchsträngslikhet. Därefter presenterar vi den tillämpade strategin för den delade uppgiften som består i kombinationen av inbäddningar sammankoppling och kogates matchning tillvägagångssätt. De språk som omfattas är franska, engelska, tyska, ryska och spanska. Sammantaget uppnådde vårt system som blandar inbäddningar och perfekt kognitionsmatchning de bästa resultaten jämfört med enskilda strategier, förutom för engelsk-ryska och rysk-engelska språkpar för vilka sammanläggningsmetoden var att föredra.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த தாள் TALN/LS2N அமைப்பு பகிர்ந்த பணியை உருவாக்குதல் மற்றும் ஒப்பிடும் கோர்போரா (BUCC) பயன்படுத்தும் பகிர்ந்து செயலி முதலில் மூன்று திட்டங்களை குறிப்பிடுகிறோம்: (i) வார்த்தையான உரை நுழைவுகளை அடிப்படையில் உள்ளிடும் சொ (ii) a concatenation approach using both character Skip-Gram and character CBOW models, and finally (iii) a cognates matching approach based on an exact match string similarity.  பிறகு, நாம் பகிர்ந்த பணிக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட துறையீட்டை காண்பிக்கிறோம். அது உள்ளீடுகளை கூட்டும் மற்றும் குறியீடுகள் பொர மூடப்பட்ட மொழிகள் பிரெஞ்சு, ஆங்கிலம், ஜெர்மன், ருஷ்யன் மற்றும் ஸ்பானிஷ். மொத்தமாக, எங்கள் அமைப்பு உள்ளீடுகளை கலக்கும் மற்றும் முழுமையான குறியீடுகள் பொருத்தினால் சிறந்த முடிவுகள் பெற்றுவிட்டது, தனிப்பட்ட விளைவுகளை</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>This paper describes the TALN/LS2N system participation in the Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC) shared task. ہم پہلے تین استراتژی پیش کریں گے: i) ایک لکھی مضبوط تقریبا ہے جو fastText embeddings پر بنیاد ہے۔ (ii) ایک متقابل طریقہ ہے کہ دو شخصوں کو Skip-Gram اور Character CBOW موڈل کے مطابق، اور آخر میں (iii) ایک مطابق متقابل طریقہ پر مطابق مطابق استرینگ برابری کی بنیاد رکھتا ہے. پھر ہم مشترک کام کے لئے تقویت کی استراتژی پیش کرتے ہیں جو انبودینگ کی ملکیت میں ہے اور مطابق مطابق مطابق مطابق مطابق مطابق مطابق مطابق مطابق مطابق ہے محفوظ زبانیں فرانسوی، انگلیسی، جرمن، روسی اور اسپانیایی ہیں۔ سب سے، ہماری سیستم مہینڈنگ کی مہینڈنگ کی مہینڈنگ اور کامل معلومات کی مہینڈنگ کے ساتھ بہترین نتیجے حاصل کیے گئے، مگر انگلیسی-روسی اور روسی-انگلیسی زبان جوڑوں کے علاوہ جن کے لئے مہمانت کا طریقہ پسند کیا گیا ہے</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu hujjat buyruqni Buyruq va Buyruq Korpora (BUCC) bilan ishlatadigan TALN/LS2N tizimning qismini anglatadi. Birinchi so'zni uchta strategiya beramiz:(i) Soat Text embeddingi asosida yaratilgan so'z ichki bir so'z (ii) Koʻpaytirish usuli Skip- Gram va belgi CBOW modellari yordamida foydalanish va oxirida (iii) toʻgʻri mos keladigan usul bilan mos keladigan kognatlar. Keyin biz bir necha vazifa uchun qo'llangan strategiyani ko'rib chiqaramiz. Bu tashkilotlarni birlashtirish va kognatlarni birlashtirish usullari bilan birlashtirish mumkin. Bu tillar Fransuz, Ingliz, Olmoncha, Ruscha va Ispancha tili. Overall, our system mixing embeddings concatenation and perfect cognates matching obtained the best results while compared to individual strategies, except for English-Russian and Russian-English language pairs for which the concatenation approach was preferred.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này mô tả sự tham gia hệ thống TALN/LS2N tại tòa nhà và sử dụng một công việc chia sẻ của Corpus (BUCC). Đầu tiên chúng ta sẽ đưa ra ba chiến lược: i) một phương pháp lắp chữ dựa trên sự nhúng nhanh. Một phương pháp hợp tác dùng cả hình mẫu Skip-Gram và kí tự CBOW, và cuối cùng, III, một phương pháp khớp răng dựa trên một nét giống nhau chính xác. Sau đó, chúng tôi đưa ra chiến lược được áp dụng cho việc chia sẻ, gồm sự kết hợp của sự kết hợp giữa các cuộc họp và các phương pháp phù hợp. Những ngôn ngữ được đề cập là Pháp, Anh, Đức, Nga và Tây Ban Nha. Nói chung, sự hoà trộn hệ thống của chúng tôi thành lập và những bánh răng hoàn hảo đạt được kết quả tốt nhất so với các chiến lược cá nhân, ngoại trừ các cặp ngôn ngữ Anh-Nga và Nga-Anh mà cách tiếp cận hợp tác là thích hợp nhất.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия описва участието на системата в споделената задача Изграждане и използване на сравним корпор (БУК). Първо въвеждаме три стратегии: (i) подход за вграждане на думи, базиран на вграждания по бърз текст; ii) подход на конкатенация, използващ както моделите Skip-Gram, така и моделите CBOW, и накрая iii) подход на съвпадение на знаците въз основа на сходство на низовете с точно съвпадение. След това представяме приложената стратегия за споделената задача, която се състои в комбинацията на вградените конатенации и познатите подходи за съвпадение. Обхванатите езици са френски, английски, немски, руски и испански. Като цяло, нашата система за смесване на вграждания конкатенация и перфектно съвпадение на конгати постигна най-добри резултати в сравнение с индивидуалните стратегии, с изключение на английски-руските и руски-английски езикови двойки, за които беше предпочитан подход на конкатенация.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel beskriver TALN/LS2N-systemets deltagelse i Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC) delte opgave. Vi introducerer først tre strategier: (i) en word embedding tilgang baseret på fastText embeddings; (ii) en sammenkoblingsmetode ved hjælp af både tegn Skip-Gram og tegn CBOW modeller, og endelig (iii) en kognitiv matching metode baseret på en nøjagtig match streng lighed. Derefter præsenterer vi den anvendte strategi for den fælles opgave, som består i kombinationen af indlejringer sammenkobling og cognates matchende tilgange. De dækkede sprog er fransk, engelsk, tysk, russisk og spansk. Samlet set opnåede vores system blanding af indlejringer sammenkobling og perfekt cognates matching de bedste resultater sammenlignet med individuelle strategier, undtagen for engelsk-russisk og russisk-engelsk sprogpar, hvor sammenkobling tilgang var foretrukket.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel beschrijft de TALN/LS2N systeemparticipatie bij de gezamenlijke taak Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). We introduceren eerst drie strategieën: (i) een woord embedding aanpak gebaseerd op fastText embedding; (ii) een aaneenschakelingsbenadering waarbij gebruik wordt gemaakt van zowel tekens Skip-Gram als teken CBOW modellen, en ten slotte (iii) een cognate matching benadering gebaseerd op een exacte overeenkomst string gelijkenis. Vervolgens presenteren we de toegepaste strategie voor de gedeelde taak die bestaat uit de combinatie van de embeddings aaneenschakeling en de cognates matching benaderingen. De behandelde talen zijn Frans, Engels, Duits, Russisch en Spaans. Over het algemeen behaalde ons systeem het beste resultaat in vergelijking met individuele strategieën, behalve voor Engels-Russisch en Russisch-Engels taalparen waarvoor de aaneenschakeling de voorkeur had.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir opisuje sudjelovanje sustava TALN/LS2N u zgradi i korištenju komparabilne korpore (BUCC) zajedničkog zadatka. Prvo predstavljamo tri strategije: i) riječ uključujući pristup na osnovu fastText ugrađenja; ii) pristup usklađivanja koristeći i modele karaktera Skip-Gram i karakter CBOW, i konačno iii) kogniraju odgovarajući pristup na temelju točne sličnosti string. Onda predstavljamo prijavljenu strategiju za zajednički zadatak koji se sastoji u kombinaciji sastavljanja integracija i kognije odgovarajućih pristupa. Pokriveni jezici su francuski, engleski, nemački, ruski i španjolski. Nakon svega, naš sustav miješanja integracije i savršene kognite odgovarajuće dobio je najbolje rezultate u usporedbi s individualnim strategijama, osim parova engleskog-ruskog i ruskog-engleskog jezika za koje je preferiran pristup concatenacije.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag beschreibt die TALN/LS2N Systembeteiligung an der gemeinsamen Aufgabe Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Zunächst stellen wir drei Strategien vor: (i) einen Worteinbettungsansatz basierend auf fastText Einbettungen; (ii) ein Verkettungsansatz, der sowohl Zeichen Skip-Gram als auch Zeichen CBOW Modelle verwendet, und schließlich (iii) ein kognitiver Matching Ansatz basierend auf einer exakten Übereinstimmung String Ähnlichkeit. Anschließend stellen wir die angewandte Strategie für die gemeinsame Aufgabe vor, die in der Kombination der Einbettungsverkettung und der kognitiven Matching-Ansätze besteht. Die behandelten Sprachen sind Französisch, Englisch, Deutsch, Russisch und Spanisch. Insgesamt erzielte unser System die besten Ergebnisse im Vergleich zu einzelnen Strategien, mit Ausnahme von Englisch-Russisch und Russisch-Englisch Sprachpaaren, für die der Verkettungsansatz bevorzugt wurde.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini menggambarkan participasi sistem TALN/LS2N di tugas berbagi Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Pertama kita memperkenalkan tiga strategi: (i) pendekatan penyembedding kata berdasarkan penyembedding FastText; (ii) pendekatan konatenasi menggunakan kedua karakter Skip-Gram dan karakter model CBOW, dan akhirnya (iii) sebuah pendekatan yang cocok berdasarkan persamaan string persis. Kemudian, kami mempersembahkan strategi yang diterapkan untuk tugas yang sama yang terdiri dalam kombinasi dari penyesalan embedding dan pendekatan yang cocok. Bahasa tertutup adalah bahasa Perancis, Inggris, Jerman, Rusia dan Spanyol. Secara keseluruhan, sistem kami mencampur pembangunan konatenasi dan kognat sempurna yang cocok mendapat hasil terbaik sementara dibandingkan dengan strategi individu, kecuali pasangan bahasa Inggris-Rusia dan Rusia-Inggris yang mana pendekatan konatenasi lebih memilih.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ مشارکت سیستم TALN/LS2N در ساختمان و استفاده از کار مشترک کوپرا (BUCC) را توصیف می‌کند. ما اول سه استراتژی را معرفی می کنیم: (i) یک دستور وارد کردن کلمه بر اساس وارد کردن FastText; (ii) یک روش هماهنگی با استفاده از مدل های قالب Skip-Gram و karakter CBOW، و بالاخره (iii) یک روش هماهنگی را بر اساس یک شباهت string دقیق مشابه می‌کند. سپس، ما استراتژی کاربرد برای کار مشترک را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که در ترکیب ترکیب پیوند‌ها و ترکیب‌های پیوند‌های مشترک است. زبان‌های مخفی فرانسوی، انگلیسی، آلمانی، روسی و اسپانیایی هستند. در کل، سیستم ما که پیوند پیوند پیوند پیوند پیوند پیوند و شناخت کامل پیدا می‌کند، بهترین نتیجه‌ها را در مقایسه با استراتژی‌های فردی دریافت می‌کنند، به جز جفت زبان انگلیسی-روسی و روسی-انگلیسی که برای آن دستور پیوند</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 TALN/LS2N 시스템이 빌딩에서 참여하는 상황을 묘사하고 비교 가능한 자료 라이브러리(BUCC)를 사용하여 임무를 공유한다.우리는 먼저 세 가지 전략을 소개했다. (i) 빠른 텍스트 삽입을 바탕으로 하는 단어 삽입 방법.(ii) 문자를 사용하여Gram과 문자 CBOW 모델의 연결 방법을 건너뛰고 (iii)는 정확한 일치 문자열의 유사성을 바탕으로 동원된 일치 방법을 사용합니다.그 다음에 우리는 공유 임무의 응용 전략을 제시했는데 이 전략은 삽입된 연결과 동원 일치 방법의 조합을 포함한다.포함된 언어는 프랑스어, 영어, 독일어, 러시아어, 스페인어이다.전반적으로 개체 전략에 비해 우리는 연결과 완벽한 동원이 일치하는 시스템을 혼합하여 가장 좋은 결과를 얻었지만 영어-러시아어와 러시아어-영어 언어는 제외하고 연결 방법에 더 치우쳤다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Gazeti hili linaelezea ushiriki wa mfumo wa TALN/LS2N katika jengo na kutumia kampuni inayofanana (BUCC). Kwanza tunaanzisha mbinu tatu: (i) neno linalozungumzia kwa kutumia matokeo ya haraka; (ii) mbinu za ushirikiano kwa kutumia mbinu za mhusika Skip-Gram na maambukizi ya CBOW, na hatimaye (iii) mbinu zinazofanana na mbinu zinazolinganisha kutokana na mfumo unaofanana sahihi. Kisha, tunaweka mkakati uliotumika kwa kazi hiyo inayohusiana na kuunganisha mabango na mikakati yanayofanana na mbinu zinazofanana. Lugha zilizoandikwa ni Kifaransa, Kiingereza, Kijerumani, Urusi na Kihispania. Kwa ujumla, mfumo wetu unaohusisha mipango ya kuunganisha pamoja na mipango kamili yanayofanana ilipata matokeo bora wakati ukilinganishwa na mikakati binafsi, isipokuwa na wenzetu wa lugha ya Kiingereza na Kiingereza ambazo mbinu hizo zilipenda.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument përshkruan pjesëmarrjen e sistemit TALN/LS2N në detyrën e përbashkët të ndërtimit dhe përdorimit të Korporave të Bashkueshme (BUCC). Ne fillimisht futim tre strategji: (i) një qasje me fjalë përfshirje bazuar në përfshirje të shpejtë Teksti; (ii) një qasje bashkëkalimi duke përdorur si modelet Skip-Gram dhe CBOW të karakterit dhe më në fund (iii) një qasje bashkëkalimi bazuar në një ngjashmëri ekzakte të rreshtit të përputhjes. Pastaj, ne paraqesim strategjinë e aplikuar për detyrën e përbashkët e cila përbëhet në kombinimin e ndërtesave të ndërtesave dhe afrimeve të përshtatshme të njohur. The covered languages are French, English, German, Russian and Spanish.  Në përgjithësi, sistemi ynë përzier ndërtesat e ndërtesave dhe njohjet perfekte që përshtaten fitoi rezultatet më të mira ndërsa krahasoheshin me strategjitë individuale, me përjashtim të çifteve të gjuhës angleze-ruse dhe ruse-angleze për të cilat është preferuar metoda e ndërtesës.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz TALN/LS2N sistemiň bina we Maýyklyklaýyn Köpüri (BUCC) tarapynda bölýän işi barlaýar. Ilkinji gezek üç strategiýany tanyşdyrýarys: (ii) Kerçek Skip-Gram we Karakter CBOW nusgalaryny ulanan bir samlap metody, we iň soňunda (iii) bir eşleşen metody täze bir kategoriň meňzeşligine daýan ýar. Sonra, biz uygulanan işi paylaşdyrmak üçin bir strategiýany çykýarys. Bu sistemi birleştirmek üçin bir birleşme we tanyş golaýlarynda bar. Gürrülen diller Fransuzça, iňlisçe, Almança, Rusça we İspanyolça. Iňlis-Rus we Rus-iňlis dilinden başga bir hereket isleýän çykyşlarymyz üçin has gowy netijesi gazandy.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier beskrywe die TALN/LS2N stelsel deel by die bou en gebruik Vergelykbare Korpora (BUCC) gedeelde taak. Ons introduseer eerste drie strategies: (i) ân woord inbêring toegang gebaseer op fastText inbêring; (ii) ân samelewing toegang gebruik beide karakter Skip-Gram en karakter CBOW-modelles, en eindelik (iii) ân konnekteer ooreenstemmende toegang gebaseer op ân presies ooreenstemmende string gelykenis. Toe voorsien ons die aanwende strategie vir die gedeelde taak wat bestaan in die kombinasie van die inbêdings samelewing en die konnekteer ooreenstemmende toegange. Die bedek tale is Frans, Engels, Duits, Russies en Spaanse. Oorsaaklik, ons stelsel gemeng inbêdings samelewing en perfekte konnekteers wat ooreenstem het, het die beste resultate ontvang terwyl vergelyk het met individuele strategies, behalwe vir Engels-Russiese en Russiese-Engelse taal pare waarvan die samelewing toegang verkies was.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>ይህ ገጽ TALN/LS2N ስርዓት ተግባር በማንበብ እና በተቃራኒ ኮርፖራ (BUCC) በተካፈሉት ስራ ላይ ይናገራል፡፡ መጀመሪያ ሦስት ተቃውሞ እናስጠጋለን:(i) የጾም ጽሑፍ አካባቢዎች በመሠረት የሚደረገው ቃላት አቅራቢያ ነው:: (ii) የፊደል ቅርጽ-ግራም እና የCBOW ዓይነትን በመጠቀም እና በመጨረሻው (iii) የክፍለ ሥርዓት በሚያስተካክሉ ሥርዓት በመሠረት ላይ የሚተካክሉ ቀለም ከዚህም በኋላ በተካፈሉት ስራ ላይ የተጠቃሚ strategieን እናስቀራለን፡፡ የተከፈቱት ቋንቋዎች ፈረንሳይ፣ እንግሊዘኛ፣ ጀርመን፣ ራሽና ስፓኒሽ ናቸው። በጠቅላላ፣ የኢንጂልኛ-ሮሽኛ እና የንግግሊኛ ቋንቋ ተቃውሞ ካልተካክሉ የተሻለ ፍሬዎችን አግኝቷል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Այս հոդվածը նկարագրում է ԹԱԼN-ի և LS2N համակարգի մասնակցությունը կառուցվածքի և համեմատական կորպորայի (ԲՈԿԿ) ընդհանուր խնդրի վրա: Առաջին հերթին մենք ներկայացնում ենք երեք ռազմավարություն. i) բառ ներգրավող մոտեցում, հիմնված արագ տեքստի ներգրավման վրա: (ii) a concatenation approach using both character Skip-Gram and character CBOW models, and finally (iii) a cognates matching approach based on an exact match string similarity.  Այնուհետև մենք ներկայացնում ենք ընդհանուր խնդրի համար կիրառված ռազմավարությունը, որը կազմված է ներդրման համեմատության և ճանաչում համապատասխանող մոտեցումների համադրման մեջ: Գործված լեզուները ֆրանսերեն, անգլերեն, գերմաներեն, ռուսերեն և իսպաներեն են: Ամբողջ ընդհանուր առմամբ, մեր համակարգը խառնելով ներդրումների համեմատությունը և կատարյալ ճանաչողական համեմատությունը ստացավ լավագույն արդյունքները համեմատելով անհատական ռազմավարությունների հետ, բացի անգլերեն-ռուս և ռուս-անգլերեն զույգերի, որոնց</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটি বিল্ডিং এবং তুলনা কর্পোরা (বিউসিসি) শেয়ার কর্মসূচিতে টাএলএন/এলএস২এন সিস্টেম অংশগ্রহণের ব্যাখ্যা করছে। আমরা প্রথমে তিনটি কৌশল পরিচয় করিয়ে দিচ্ছি: (i) ফোস্ট ট টেক্সট বিভিন্ন ভিত্তিক ভিত্তিতে একটি শব্দের বিভিন্ (ii) ক্যারেক্টার স্কিপ- গ্রাম এবং চরিত্র সিবিওউড মডেল ব্যবহার করে একটি একত্রিত পদ্ধতি ব্যবহার করে এবং শেষ পর্যন্ত (আই) সঠিক ম্যাচ স্ট্রীনের একই ধরন তারপর আমরা শেয়ার কর্মসূচীর জন্য প্রযোজ্য কৌশল উপস্থাপন করেছি যা বিভিন্ন বিভিন্ন সংগঠন এবং কোক্নেটগুলোর সাথে মিলিত উপায়ের স ভাষাগুলো ফ্রেঞ্চ, ইংরেজি, জার্মান, রুশ এবং স্প্যানিশ। সাধারণত, আমাদের সিস্টেম মিশ্রিত প্রতিষ্ঠানগুলোর সাথে মিশ্রিত এবং পুরোপুরি কোক্নেটের মিশ্রিত ফলাফল পেয়েছে যখন ব্যক্তিগত কৌশলের তুলনায়, ইংর</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir opisuje sudjelovanje sustava TALN/LS2N u zgradi i korištenju komparabilne korpore (BUCC) zajedničkog zadatka. Prvo predstavljamo tri strategije: i) reč uključujući pristup na osnovu fastText ugrađenja; ii) pristup usklađivanja koristeći i modele karaktera Skip-Gram i karakter CBOW, i konačno iii) kogniraju odgovarajući pristup na temelju točne sličnosti string. Onda predstavljamo prijavljenu strategiju za zajednički zadatak koji se sastoji u kombinaciji sastavljanja integracije i kognije odgovarajućih pristupa. Pokriveni jezici su francuski, engleski, nemački, ruski i španjolski. Nakon svega, naš sistem koji miješa integraciju i savršene kognitete koji odgovaraju dobio je najbolji rezultat u usporedbi s individualnim strategijama, osim parova engleskog-ruskog i ruskog-engleskog jezika, za koje je preferiran pristup concatenacije.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_az>Bu kańüńĪt binada TALN/LS2N sisteminin paylaŇüńĪlmasńĪnńĪ v…ô Compatibile Corpora (BUCC) iŇül…ôm…ôsini t…ôsdiq edir. Biz ilk d…ôf…ô √ľ√ß strateji t…ôŇükil edirik: ii) h…ôr c√ľz…ô Skip-Gram v…ô karakter CBOW modell…ôrini istifad…ô ed…ôr…ôk m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôrzi v…ô nihay…ôt (iii) m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôrzi il…ô m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôrzi kimilińüini tanńĪyńĪr. Sonra, biz paylaŇüńĪlan iŇü √ľ√ß√ľn istifad…ô edil…ôn strateji g√∂st…ôririk ki, birl…ôŇüdirilmiŇü birl…ôŇüdirilm…ôl…ôr v…ô yaxńĪnlńĪqlarńĪn birl…ôŇüdirilm…ôsind…ôdir. √Ėzl…ônmiŇü dill…ôr FransńĪz, ńįngilizce, Alman, Rus v…ô ńįspanyoldadńĪr. ∆Źlb…ôtt…ô, sistemimiz birl…ôŇüdirilmiŇü birl…ôŇüdirilm…ôk v…ô m√ľk…ômm…ôl tanńĪyńĪŇülar, birl…ôŇüdirilm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn ńįngilizce-Rus v…ô Rus-ńįngilizce dill…ôrin √ßiftl…ôri istisna olmaqla, indir stratejil…ôr…ô qarŇüńĪlaŇüdńĪńüńĪ …ôn yaxŇüńĪ sonu√ßlarńĪ aldńĪ.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest paper descriu la participació del sistema TALN/LS2N en la tasca compartida Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Primer introduïm tres estratègies: i) un enfocament d'incorporació de paraules basat en incorporacions de text ràpid; ii) un enfocament de concatenació utilitzant tant els models Skip-Gram com CBOW de caràcter, i finalment iii) un enfocament de concatenació basat en una similitud exact a de cadena de concatenació. Llavors presentem l'estratègia aplicada per a la tasca compartida que consisteix en combinar la concatenació d'incorporacions i els enfocaments equivalents. Les llengües cobertes són francès, anglès, alemany, russo i espanyol. En general, el nostre sistema combinant concatenació d'incorporacions i cognats perfectes que coincideixen va obtenir els millors resultats mentre comparats amb estratègies individuals, excepte els parells de llenguatge anglès-russo i russo-anglès per als quals preferia l'enfocament de concatenació.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek popisuje účast systému TALN/LS2N na sdíleném úkolu Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC). Nejprve představujeme tři strategie: (i) přístup k vložení slov založený na vložení fastText; (ii) řetězovací přístup používající jak znakové modely Skip-Gram, tak znakové CBOW modely, a nakonec (iii) kognitivní přístup založený na přesné shodě řetězců podobnosti. Následně představujeme aplikovanou strategii pro sdílený úkol, která spočívá v kombinaci řetězců vložení a přístupů odpovídajících přístupům. Zahrnutými jazyky jsou francouzština, angličtina, němčina, ruština a španělština. Celkově, náš systém míchání embeddedů řetězení a perfektní shodování koňátů dosáhl nejlepších výsledků v porovnání s jednotlivými strategiemi, s výjimkou anglicko-ruských a rusko-anglických jazykových párů, u nichž byl preferován řetězení přístup.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas artiklis kirjeldatakse TALN/LS2N süsteemi osalemist võrreldavate korpuste ehitamise ja kasutamise (BUCC) jagatud ülesandes. Esiteks tutvustame kolme strateegiat: i) sõna manustamise lähenemisviis, mis põhineb fastText manustamisel; ii) konkatenatsiooni meetod, milles kasutatakse nii märkide Skip-Gram kui ka märkide CBOW mudeleid, ning lõpuks iii) kognitiivse sobitamise meetod, mis põhineb täpsel vastel stringide sarnasusel. Seejärel tutvustame rakendatud strateegiat jagatud ülesande jaoks, mis koosneb manustamise konkatenatsiooni ja kogniatide sobitamise lähenemisviiside kombinatsioonist. Kaetud keeled on prantsuse, inglise, saksa, vene ja hispaania keel. Kokkuvõttes saavutasid meie süsteemi segamise põimimiste konkatenatsioon ja täiuslik kongaatide sobitamine parimad tulemused võrreldes individuaalsete strateegiatega, välja arvatud inglise-vene ja vene-inglise keele paarid, mille puhul eelistati konkatenatsiooni lähenemist.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa kuvataan TALN/LS2N-järjestelmän osallistumista jaettuun Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC) -tehtävään. Esittelemme ensin kolme strategiaa: (i) sanan upottamiseen perustuva lähestymistapa, joka perustuu fastText upotuksiin; (ii) yhdistävä lähestymistapa käyttäen sekä merkkien Skip-Gram- että merkkien CBOW-malleja, ja lopuksi (iii) kognites matching lähestymistapa perustuu tarkan match merkkijonon samankaltaisuuteen. Tämän jälkeen esittelemme jaetun tehtävän sovelletun strategian, joka koostuu upotusten yhdistämisestä ja kognites matching -lähestymistapojen yhdistelmästä. Kattavat kielet ovat ranska, englanti, saksa, venäjä ja espanja. Kokonaisuudessaan järjestelmäsekoittimien yhdistäminen ja täydellinen kognaattien täsmäytys saavuttivat parhaat tulokset verrattuna yksittäisiin strategioihin, lukuun ottamatta englannin-venäjän ja venäjän-englannin kielipareja, joiden osalta conatenaatiomenetelmä oli suositeltu.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ha>@ info Kayya, ko da na farko da mataimaki uku:(i) wata magana mai embedded a kanzu a kan Fast Text embeddings; help-action Sa'an nan kuma, muna halatar da kimar da aka yi amfani da wa aikin da aka raba shi, wanda ke cikin komai da samfanin samuran samura da sami-sami masu samu'i. The covered languages are French, English, German, Russian and Spanish.  A jumla, na'asarmu da ke haɗa kokoma da kohannayen da ke kami da kamfani, ya sami mafi kyaun matsalari a lokacin da aka sammenliki takwaici masu yiwuni da takwara guda, sai fa da mazaunin Ingiriya-Ruushi da Ingirinsa-Ruushi wanda aka zaɓe hanyarwa zuwa gare su.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Ta prispevek opisuje sodelovanje sistema TALN/LS2N v skupni nalogi Gradnja in uporaba primerljivih korpusov (BUCC). Najprej predstavimo tri strategije: (i) pristop vključevanja besed, ki temelji na vključevanju fastText; (ii) pristop združevanja z uporabo modelov Skip-Gram znakov in CBOW znakov in končno (iii) pristop ujemanja znakov, ki temelji na podobnosti nizov natančnega ujemanja. Nato predstavljamo uporabljeno strategijo za skupno nalogo, ki je sestavljena iz kombinacije vgradnje konatenacije in priznanih pristopov ujemanja. Zajeti jeziki so francoščina, angleščina, nemščina, ruščina in španščina. Na splošno smo v primerjavi s posameznimi strategijami dosegli najboljše rezultate v primerjavi s posameznimi strategijami, razen za angleško-ruske in rusko-angleške jezikovne pare, za katere je bil najbolj priljubljen pristop konatenacije.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>העיתון הזה מתאר את השתתפות במערכת TALN/LS2N בבניין ושימוש בתפקיד משותף של Corpora שווה (BUCC). אנחנו קודם מכירים שלושה אסטרטגיות: (i) גישה של מילה שמבוססת על קישורים מהירים טקסט; (ii) גישה מתאימה בשימוש של דגמנים Skip-Gram ודגמנים CBOW, ולבסוף (iii) מתאימה גישה מתאימה מבוססת על דמיון מתאימה בדיוק. ואז, אנחנו מציגים את האסטרטגיה המתוקפת למשימה המשותפת שמתכתבת בשילוב של הקונקוטנציה והגישות המתאימות. השפות הכוסות הן צרפתית, אנגלית, גרמנית, רוסית וספרדית. באופן כללי, המערכת שלנו מעורבת התאמה של תוכניות ומתאימות של תוכניות מושלמות השיגה את התוצאות הטובות ביותר בהשוואה לאסטרטגיות אישיות, מלבד זוגות שפת אנגלית-רוסית-רוסית-אנגלית שהעדיפה הגישה של התאמה.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Ngetong iki rambarang kelas tanggal Sistem TarLN/L2N nang nggawe Bukak lan Ngawe Perintah Kopora komparasi (BIC). Awak dhéwé éntuk tanggal telu tasari: i) dadi sing beraksi basa gambar luwih (iii) a concatenation method use the same character Skip-Gram and character IBOw modes, and last (iii) a knowns match method supported on an exact match string Simlarity. Nambah, kita ngubah Program-aplikasi kanggo nggawe gerakan nggawe gerakan karo kowe ngubah ingkang sampulan iki luwih apik lan ingkang sampeyan ingkang sampeyan ingkang sampeyan ingkang sampeyan ingkang sampeyan nggawe Kapan olèhèké wong kuwi Perancis, Inggris, German, Russ lan Spanyol. Diwong-wong, sistem nambah sing ditambang sampeyan lan alam sing perusahaan nggawe barang nggawe barang sing luwih apik dhéwé, njuk kesempatan karo sistem sing nggawe gerarané karo perusahaan- ruso karo Perusahaan-ingles karo Perusahaan-ingles sing apik dhéwé, sing uwis dino sing api</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་བཟོ་བརྩིགས་དང་སྤྱད་ནས་མཇལ་རྩོམ་མཁན་གྱི་ལས་འགུལ་གྱི་TALN/LS2N་རིགས་འདིས་སྤྱོད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་དང་པོ་ནས་འཛམ་གླིང་གི་ཐབས་ལམ་གསུམ་སྟོན་པ་ཡིན། (ii) a concatenation approach using both character Skip-Gram and character CBOW models, and finally (iii) a cognates matching approach based on an exact match string similarity. འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་སྤྱད་སྤྱོད་པའི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་མཉམ་དུ་མཉམ་དུ་མཐུན་སྒྲིག ཁོང་ཡོད་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་ཚོར་ཡིག་དང་། དབྱིན་ཡིག་དང་། ཇར་མེན། རུ་ཤོས་ཡིག་དང་། སྐད་རིས། ཡིན་བཟུང་། ང་ཚོའི་མ་ལག་གི་མཉམ་སྦྲེལ་མཐུན་དང་མཐུན་རྣམས་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་ཐུབ་སྐྱེས་བ་རེད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>BUCC2020 : Bilingual Dictionary Induction using Cross-lingual Embedding<fixed-case>BUCC</fixed-case>2020: Bilingual Dictionary Induction using Cross-lingual Embedding</title>
      <author><first>Sanjanasri</first><last>JP</last></author>
      <author><first>Vijay Krishna</first><last>Menon</last></author>
      <author><first>Soman</first><last>KP</last></author>
      <pages>65–68</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning system</a> for the BUCC 2020 shared task : Bilingual dictionary induction from comparable corpora. We have submitted two runs for this shared Task, German (de) and English (en) language pair for closed track and Tamil (ta) and English (en) for the open track. Our core approach focuses on quantifying the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics of the language pairs</a>, so that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a> of two different language pairs can be compared or transfer learned. With the advent of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embeddings</a>, it is possible to quantify this. In this paper, we propose a deep learning approach which makes use of the supplied training data, to generate cross-lingual embedding. This is later used for inducting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bilingual_dictionary">bilingual dictionary</a> from comparable corpora.</abstract>
      <url hash="2e3ec71e">2020.bucc-1.11</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>jp-etal-2020-bucc2020</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>