<collection id="2020.computerm">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop on Computational Terminology</booktitle>
      <editor><first>B&#233;atrice</first><last>Daille</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kyo</first><last>Kageura</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ayla Rigouts</first><last>Terryn</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-57-3</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="4ff69a39">2020.computerm-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>computerm-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>A study of semantic projection from single word terms to multi-word terms in the environment domain</title>
      <author><first>Yizhe</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Beatrice</first><last>Daille</last></author>
      <author><first>Nabil</first><last>Hathout</last></author>
      <pages>50&#8211;54</pages>
      <abstract>The semantic projection method is often used in terminology structuring to infer semantic relations between terms. Semantic projection relies upon the assumption of semantic compositionality: the relation that links simple term pairs remains valid in pairs of complex terms built from these simple terms. This paper proposes to investigate whether this assumption commonly adopted in natural language processing is actually valid. First, we describe the process of constructing a list of semantically linked multi-word terms (MWTs) related to the environmental field through the extraction of semantic variants. Second, we present our analysis of the results from the semantic projection. We find that contexts play an essential role in defining the relations between MWTs.</abstract>
      <url hash="521b2431">2020.computerm-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>wang-etal-2020-study</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title><fixed-case>T</fixed-case>erm<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>val 2020: <fixed-case>RACAI</fixed-case>&#8217;s automatic term extraction system</title>
      <author><first>Vasile</first><last>Pais</last></author>
      <author><first>Radu</first><last>Ion</last></author>
      <pages>101&#8211;105</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes RACAI&#8217;s automatic term extraction system, which participated in the TermEval 2020 shared task on English monolingual term extraction. We discuss the system architecture, some of the challenges that we faced as well as present our results in the English competition.</abstract>
      <url hash="f2079a99">2020.computerm-1.14</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>pais-ion-2020-termeval</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>