<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.multilingualbio">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the LREC 2020 Workshop on Multilingual Biomedical Text Processing (MultilingualBIO 2020)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Maite</first><last>Melero</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-65-8</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="8a0c7457">2020.multilingualbio-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>multilingualbio-2020-lrec</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Detecting Adverse Drug Events from Swedish Electronic Health Records using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_mining">Text Mining</a><fixed-case>S</fixed-case>wedish Electronic Health Records using Text Mining</title>
      <author><first>Maria</first><last>Bampa</last></author>
      <author><first>Hercules</first><last>Dalianis</last></author>
      <pages>1–8</pages>
      <abstract>Electronic Health Records are a valuable source of patient information which can be leveraged to detect Adverse Drug Events (ADEs) and aid post-mark drug-surveillance. The overall aim of this study is to scrutinize text written by clinicians in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_health_record">EHRs</a> and build a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> for ADE detection that produces medically relevant predictions. Natural Language Processing techniques will be exploited to create important <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependent_and_independent_variables">predictors</a> and incorporate them into the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning">learning process</a>. The study focuses on the 5 most frequent ADE cases found ina Swedish electronic patient record corpus. The results indicate that considering textual features, rather than the structured, can improve the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a> performance by 15 % in some ADE cases. Additionally, variable patient history lengths are incorporated in the models, demonstrating the importance of the above decision rather than using an arbitrary number for a history length. The experimental findings suggest that the clinical text in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_health_record">EHRs</a> includes information that can capture data beyond the ones that are found in a structured format.</abstract>
      <url hash="335c5670">2020.multilingualbio-1.1</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>bampa-dalianis-2020-detecting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Localising the Clinical Terminology SNOMED CT by Semi-automated Creation of a German Interface Vocabulary<fixed-case>SNOMED</fixed-case> <fixed-case>CT</fixed-case> by Semi-automated Creation of a <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>erman Interface Vocabulary</title>
      <author><first>Stefan</first><last>Schulz</last></author>
      <author><first>Larissa</first><last>Hammer</last></author>
      <author><first>David</first><last>Hashemian-Nik</last></author>
      <author><first>Markus</first><last>Kreuzthaler</last></author>
      <pages>15–20</pages>
      <abstract>Medical language exhibits great variations regarding users, institutions and language registers. With large parts of clinical documents in free text, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> is playing a more and more important role in unlocking re-usable and interoperable meaning from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medical_record">medical records</a>. This study describes the architectural principles and the evolution of a German interface vocabulary, combining <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a> with human annotation and rule-based term generation, yielding a resource with 7.7 million raw entries, each of which linked to the reference terminology <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SNOMED_CT">SNOMED CT</a>, an international standard with about 350 thousand concepts. The purpose is to offer a high coverage of medical jargon in order to optimise terminology grounding of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medicine">clinical texts</a> by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_mining">text mining systems</a>. The core resource is a manually curated table of English-to-German word and chunk translations, supported by a set of language generation rules. The work describes a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Workflow">workflow</a> consisting the enrichment and modification of this table with human and machine efforts, manually enriched by grammarspecific tags. Top-down and bottom-up methods for terminology population used in parallel. The final interface terms are produced by a term generator, which creates one-to-many German variants per SNOMED CT English description. Filtering against a large collection of domain terminologies and corpora drastically reduces the size of the vocabulary in favour of more realistic terms or terms that can reasonably be expected to match clinical text passages within a text-mining pipeline. An evaluation was performed by a comparison between the current version of the German interface vocabulary and the English description table of the SNOMED CT International release. An exact term matching was performed with a small <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_corpus">parallel corpus</a> constituted by text snippets from different clinical documents. With overall low retrieval parameters (with F-values around 30 %), the performance of the German language scenario reaches 80   90 % of the English one. Interestingly, annotations are slightly better with machine-translated (German   English) texts, using the International SNOMED CT resource only.</abstract>
      <url hash="310802e5">2020.multilingualbio-1.3</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>schulz-etal-2020-localising</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Localizando a terminologia clínica SNOMED CT pela criação semiautomatizada de um vocabulário de interface em alemão</title_pt>
      <title_ar>توطين المصطلحات السريرية SNOMED CT من خلال الإنشاء شبه الآلي لمفردات الواجهة الألمانية</title_ar>
      <title_es>Localización de la terminología clínica SNOMED CT mediante la creación semiautomática de un vocabulario de interfaz en alemán</title_es>
      <title_ja>ドイツ語インターフェース語彙の半自動作成による臨床用語SNOMED CTのローカライズ</title_ja>
      <title_hi>एक जर्मन इंटरफ़ेस शब्दावली के अर्ध-स्वचालित निर्माण द्वारा नैदानिक शब्दावली SNOMED सीटी स्थानीयकरण</title_hi>
      <title_zh>因半自动创德语界面词汇以本地化临床术语 SNOMED CT</title_zh>
      <title_ga>An Téarmaíocht Chliniciúil a Logánú SNOMED CT trí Stór Focal Comhéadan Gearmánach a Chruthú go Leath-uathoibríoch</title_ga>
      <title_ka>კლინიკური ტერმინოლოგიის ლოკალიზაცია SNOMED CT- ს პერიმანეთის ინტერფესტის სიტყვებულაციის ნაწილად ავტომატიური შექმნა</title_ka>
      <title_el>Εντοπισμός της Κλινικής Ορολογίας με ημιαυτοματοποιημένη δημιουργία λεξιλογίου γερμανικής διεπαφής</title_el>
      <title_hu>A klinikai terminológia SNOMED CT lokalizálása egy német interfész szókincs félautomatizált létrehozásával</title_hu>
      <title_it>Localizzazione della terminologia clinica SNOMED CT mediante creazione semi-automatica di un vocabolario di interfaccia tedesca</title_it>
      <title_lt>Klinikinės terminologijos SNOMED CT lokalizavimas pusiau automatizuota Vokietijos sąsajos žodyno kūrimu</title_lt>
      <title_kk>Клиниялық терминология SNOMED CT дегенді неміс интерфейстің сөздерін жарты автоматты түрде құру</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Localising the Clinical Terminology SNOMED CT by Semi-automated Creation of a German Interface Vocabulary</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Menglokalisasi Terminologi Klinik SNOMED CT oleh Penciptaan Semi-Automatik Katalaluan Antaramuka Jerman</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ജര്‍മ്മന്‍ ഇന്റര്‍മെസ്റ്റ് വാക്കുകളുടെ സെമി- സ്വയം സൃഷ്ടിക്കുന്നതിനാല്‍ ക്ലിനിക്കല്‍ ടെര്‍മിനോളജി സ്നോമെഡ് സിറ</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Lokalizzazzjoni tat-Terminoloġija Klinika SNOMED CT permezz tal-ħolqien semiawtomatizzat ta’ Vokabularju Ġermaniż tal-Interfaċċja</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Германы интерфейс үг бий болгон төлөвлөгөөс хагас автоматжуулан бүтээж</title_mn>
      <title_no>Lokaliserer kliniske terminologien SNOMED CT ved halvautomatisk oppretting av eit tysk grensesnitt- ordbokstav</title_no>
      <title_pl>Lokalizacja terminologii klinicznej SNOMED CT poprzez półautomatyczne tworzenie słownika interfejsu niemieckiego</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Localizarea terminologiei clinice SNOMED CT prin crearea semi-automată a unui vocabular de interfață germană</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Lokalizacija kliničke terminologije SNOMED CT od strane polu-automatskog stvorenja njemačkog reči interfejsa</title_sr>
      <title_si>ස්ථානික විද්‍යාවය SNOMED CT නිසා ජර්මාන් අන්තර්භාව ශබ්ද විද්‍යාවක් නිර්මාණය</title_si>
      <title_so>Horumarinta Terminology SNOMED CT</title_so>
      <title_sv>Lokalisering av den kliniska terminologin SNOMED CT genom semiautomatiserad skapande av ett tyskt gränssnitt ordförråd</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>جرمن انٹرفس واکوبلری کی نصف اتوماٹی ایجاد کے ذریعے کلینیک ٹرمینولوجی SNOMED CT کو لوکالیز کر رہا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Định vị kỹ thuật khoa lâm sàng kết cấu kết nối kết nối bằng lắp ghép thần dược.</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_bg>Локализиране на клиничната терминология чрез полуавтоматизирано създаване на немски интерфейсен речник</title_bg>
      <title_da>Lokalisering af den kliniske terminologi SNOMED CT ved semi-automatiseret oprettelse af et tysk interface ordforråd</title_da>
      <title_nl>Lokaliseren van de klinische terminologie SNOMED CT door semi-geautomatiseerde creatie van een Duitse interfacewoordenschat</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Lokaliziranje kliničke terminologije SNOMED CT-a polu-automatskim stvorenjem riječi o njemačkom interfejsu</title_hr>
      <title_de>Lokalisierung der klinischen Terminologie SNOMED CT durch halbautomatische Erstellung eines deutschen Interface Vokabulars</title_de>
      <title_ko>반자동화된 독일어 인터페이스 용어를 사용하여 임상 용어 SNOMED CT 현지화</title_ko>
      <title_id>Lokalisasi Terminologi Klinik SNOMED CT oleh Penciptaan Semi-Automatis Kamus Interface Jerman</title_id>
      <title_sw>Akiweka kituo cha Terminalology SNOMED CT na Uumbuzi wa lugha ya Ujerumani</title_sw>
      <title_fa>Localizing the Clinical Terminology SNOMED CT by Semi-automated Creation of a German Interface Vocabulary</title_fa>
      <title_af>Lokaliseer die Kliniske Terminologie SNOMED CT deur 'n Duitse Koppelvlak Voorbeeld</title_af>
      <title_tr>Semi-otomatik bir Alman arayüz sözleri tarapyndan Kliniki Terminologiýany SNOMED CT'i ýerleşdirilýär</title_tr>
      <title_am>የተለመደው ጭብጥ</title_am>
      <title_hy>Գերմանական ինտերֆեյսի բառարանի կիսաավտոմատիկ ստեղծման միջոցով</title_hy>
      <title_sq>Lokalizimi i Terminologjisë Klinike SNOMED CT nga Krijimi gjysmë-automatizuar i një fjalori të interfaqes gjermane</title_sq>
      <title_az>Alman Interface SNOMED CT'nin yarısı-avtomatik Yapılması</title_az>
      <title_bs>Lokaliziranje kliničke terminologije SNOMED CT-a polu-automatskim stvaranjem njemačkog ročnika interfejsa</title_bs>
      <title_bn>জার্মান ইন্টারফেস শব্দভাণ্ডারের সেমি স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে স্থানীয় ক্লিনিক টার্মিনিলজি স্নোমেড সিটি স্থানীয়</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Localització de la Terminologia Clínica SNOMED CT per creació semi-automatitzada d'un vocabulari d'interfície alemanya</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Lokalizace klinické terminologie SNOMED CT poloautomatickým vytvořením slovní zásoby německého rozhraní</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Kliinisen terminologian SNOMED CT paikantaminen puoliautomaattisella saksan rajapinnan sanaston luomisella</title_fi>
      <title_et>Kliinilise terminoloogia SNOMED CT lokaliseerimine poolautomaatse saksa liidese sõnavara loomise abil</title_et>
      <title_jv>lokalising klènik Terminal inuksi</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Lokalizacija klinične terminologije SNOMED CT s polavtomatiziranim ustvarjanjem nemškega vmesnika besednjaka</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>המיקום של טרמינולוגיה קלינית SNOMED CT על ידי יצירת מילון ממשק גרמני חצי אוטומטי</title_he>
      <title_bo>རང་བཞིན་གྱིས་Aleman་གདོང་རིས་འདྲ་བརྗོད་ཐོག་དང་རང་འགུལ་གྱིས་ཟུར་བ་ནས་Clinical Terminology SNOMED CT སྒྲིག་འགོད་པ།</title_bo>
      <abstract_pt>A linguagem médica apresenta grandes variações em relação aos usuários, instituições e registros linguísticos. Com grande parte dos documentos clínicos em texto livre, a PNL está desempenhando um papel cada vez mais importante na liberação de significados reutilizáveis e interoperáveis dos registros médicos. Este estudo descreve os princípios arquitetônicos e a evolução de um vocabulário de interface alemão, combinando tradução automática com anotação humana e geração de termos baseados em regras, resultando em um recurso com 7,7 milhões de entradas brutas, cada uma delas vinculada à terminologia de referência SNOMED CT, um padrão com cerca de 350 mil conceitos. O objetivo é oferecer uma alta cobertura do jargão médico para otimizar a fundamentação terminológica de textos clínicos por sistemas de mineração de texto. O recurso principal é uma tabela com curadoria manual de traduções de palavras e partes do inglês para o alemão, suportada por um conjunto de regras de geração de idiomas. O trabalho descreve um workflow que consiste no enriquecimento e modificação desta tabela com esforços humanos e de máquina, enriquecidos manualmente por tags gramaticais específicas. Métodos de cima para baixo e de baixo para cima para população terminológica usados em paralelo. Os termos finais da interface são produzidos por um gerador de termos, que cria variantes alemãs de um para muitos de acordo com a descrição em inglês do SNOMED CT. A filtragem de uma grande coleção de terminologias de domínio e corpora reduz drasticamente o tamanho do vocabulário em favor de termos mais realistas ou termos que podem ser razoavelmente esperados para corresponder
passagens de texto clínico dentro de um pipeline de mineração de texto. Uma avaliação foi realizada por uma comparação entre a versão atual do vocabulário da interface em alemão e a tabela de descrição em inglês da versão SNOMED CT International. Foi realizada uma correspondência exata de termos com um pequeno corpus paralelo constituído por trechos de texto de diferentes documentos clínicos. Com parâmetros gerais de recuperação baixos (com valores F em torno de 30%), o desempenho do cenário do idioma alemão atinge 80 – 90% do inglês. Curiosamente, as anotações são um pouco melhores com textos traduzidos por máquina (alemão – inglês), usando apenas o recurso International SNOMED CT.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>تعرض اللغة الطبية اختلافات كبيرة فيما يتعلق بالمستخدمين والمؤسسات وسجلات اللغة. مع وجود أجزاء كبيرة من المستندات السريرية في نص حر ، تلعب البرمجة اللغوية العصبية دورًا أكثر أهمية في فتح المعنى القابل لإعادة الاستخدام والتشغيل المتبادل من السجلات الطبية. تصف هذه الدراسة المبادئ المعمارية وتطور مفردات الواجهة الألمانية ، وتجمع بين الترجمة الآلية والتعليقات التوضيحية البشرية وإنشاء المصطلحات القائمة على القواعد ، مما ينتج عنه موردًا يحتوي على 7.7 مليون مدخلات أولية ، وكل منها مرتبط بالمصطلحات المرجعية SNOMED CT ، وهي منظمة دولية قياسي بحوالي 350 ألف مفهوم. والغرض من ذلك هو تقديم تغطية عالية للمصطلحات الطبية من أجل تحسين أسس المصطلحات للنصوص السريرية من خلال أنظمة التنقيب عن النصوص. المورد الأساسي هو جدول منسق يدويًا للترجمات المقطوعة للكلمات من الإنجليزية إلى الألمانية ، مدعومًا بمجموعة من قواعد إنشاء اللغة. يصف العمل سير عمل يتكون من إثراء وتعديل هذا الجدول بجهود بشرية وآلية ، مدعم يدويًا بعلامات خاصة بقواعد النحو. يتم استخدام طرق من أعلى إلى أسفل ومن أسفل إلى أعلى لمجموعات المصطلحات بالتوازي. يتم إنتاج شروط الواجهة النهائية بواسطة منشئ المصطلح ، والذي يقوم بإنشاء متغيرات ألمانية من واحد إلى العديد لكل وصف SNOMED CT باللغة الإنجليزية. التصفية مقابل مجموعة كبيرة من مصطلحات المجال والمجموعات يقلل بشكل كبير من حجم المفردات لصالح مصطلحات أو مصطلحات أكثر واقعية يمكن توقع تطابقها بشكل معقول
مقاطع النص السريري داخل خط أنابيب التنقيب عن النصوص. تم إجراء تقييم من خلال المقارنة بين الإصدار الحالي من مفردات الواجهة الألمانية وجدول الوصف الإنجليزي لإصدار SNOMED CT International. تم إجراء مطابقة دقيقة للمصطلح مع مجموعة موازية صغيرة مكونة من مقتطفات نصية من مستندات سريرية مختلفة. مع معلمات الاسترجاع المنخفضة الإجمالية (مع قيم F حوالي 30٪) ، يصل أداء سيناريو اللغة الألمانية إلى 80-90٪ من سيناريو اللغة الإنجليزية. ومن المثير للاهتمام ، أن التعليقات التوضيحية أفضل قليلاً مع النصوص المترجمة آليًا (الألمانية - الإنجليزية) ، باستخدام مورد SNOMED CT الدولي فقط.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>El lenguaje médico presenta grandes variaciones en cuanto a los usuarios, instituciones y registros lingüísticos. Con grandes partes de los documentos clínicos en texto libre, la PNL desempeña un papel cada vez más importante en la liberación del significado reutilizable e interoperable de los registros médicos. Este estudio describe los principios arquitectónicos y la evolución de un vocabulario de interfaz en alemán, combinando la traducción automática con anotación humana y la generación de términos basados en reglas, lo que produce un recurso con 7,7 millones de entradas sin procesar, cada una de las cuales está vinculada a la terminología de referencia SNOMED CT, un estándar con unos 350 mil conceptos. El propósito es ofrecer una alta cobertura de jerga médica para optimizar la base terminológica de los textos clínicos mediante sistemas de minería de textos. El recurso principal es una tabla seleccionada manualmente de traducciones de palabras y fragmentos del inglés al alemán, respaldada por un conjunto de reglas de generación de idiomas. El trabajo describe un flujo de trabajo que consiste en el enriquecimiento y la modificación de esta tabla con esfuerzos humanos y mecánicos, enriquecidos manualmente con etiquetas gramaticales específicas. Métodos de arriba hacia abajo y de abajo hacia arriba para la población terminológica utilizados en paralelo. Los términos finales de la interfaz son producidos por un generador de términos, que crea variantes en alemán de uno a muchos según la descripción en inglés de SNOMED CT. Filtrar contra una gran colección de terminologías de dominio y corpora reduce drásticamente el tamaño del vocabulario en favor de términos más realistas que se puede esperar razonablemente que coincidan
pasajes de textos clínicos dentro de una canalización de minería de textos. Se realizó una evaluación comparando la versión actual del vocabulario de la interfaz en alemán y la tabla de descripción en inglés de la versión internacional de SNOMED CT. Se realizó una correspondencia exacta de términos con un pequeño corpus paralelo constituido por fragmentos de texto de diferentes documentos clínicos. Con parámetros de recuperación bajos en general (con valores F de alrededor del 30%), el rendimiento del escenario del idioma alemán alcanza del 80 al 90% del inglés. Curiosamente, las anotaciones son ligeramente mejores con textos traducidos automáticamente (alemán — inglés), utilizando únicamente el recurso internacional SNOMED CT.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>医療用言語は、ユーザー、機関、言語レジスタに関して大きなバリエーションを示しています。 大部分の臨床文書がフリーテキストであるため、NLPは医療記録から再利用可能で相互運用可能な意味を解放する上でますます重要な役割を果たしています。 この研究では、機械翻訳とヒューマンアノテーションとルールベースの用語生成を組み合わせたドイツ語のインターフェースボキャブラリーのアーキテクチャ原理と進化を説明し、約35万の概念を持つ国際標準である参照用語SNOMED CTにリンクされた770万のRAWエントリを含むリソースを生成します。 その目的は、テキストマイニングシステムによる臨床テキストの用語の基礎付けを最適化するために、医療用語の高いカバレッジを提供することです。 コアリソースは、一連の言語生成ルールによってサポートされる、英語からドイツ語への単語およびチャンク翻訳の手動でキュレーションされたテーブルです。 この作業では、このテーブルを人間と機械の努力で充実させ、修正し、文法固有のタグで手動で充実させたワークフローについて説明します。 並行して使用される用語集団のトップダウンおよびボトムアップ法。 最終的なインターフェース用語は、SNOMED CT英語の説明に従って1対多数のドイツ語のバリアントを作成する用語ジェネレータによって生成されます。 ドメイン用語やコーパスの大規模なコレクションに対してフィルタリングすると、より現実的な用語や、合理的に一致することが期待できる用語を好むために、語彙のサイズが大幅に縮小されます。
テキストマイニングパイプライン内の臨床テキストパッセージ。現在のバージョンのドイツ語インターフェース語彙とSNOMED CT Internationalリリースの英語記述表との比較によって評価を行った。異なる臨床文書からのテキストスニペットで構成された小さな並列コーパスを用いて、正確な用語マッチングを実施した。全体的に低い検索パラメータ（ F値は約30 ％ ）で、ドイツ語シナリオのパフォーマンスは英語シナリオの80 ～ 90 ％に達します。興味深いことに、アノテーションは、国際SNOMED CTリソースのみを使用して、機械翻訳（ドイツ語–英語）テキストでやや優れています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ga>Tá éagsúlachtaí móra ag baint le teanga mhíochaine maidir le húsáideoirí, institiúidí agus cláir teangacha. Le codanna móra de dhoiciméid chliniciúla i saorthéacs, tá ról níos mó agus níos tábhachtaí ag NLP maidir le brí ath-inúsáidte agus idir-inoibritheach a dhíghlasáil ó thaifid leighis. Déanann an staidéar seo cur síos ar phrionsabail ailtireachta agus ar éabhlóid stór focal comhéadain Gearmánach, a chomhcheanglaíonn aistriúchán meaisín le anótáil dhaonna agus giniúint téarma bunaithe ar rialacha, a thugann acmhainn le 7.7 milliún iontráil amh, gach ceann acu nasctha leis an téarmaíocht tagartha SNOMED CT, institiúid idirnáisiúnta. caighdeánach le thart ar 350,000 coincheap. Is é an cuspóir atá ann ná clúdach ard ar bhéarlagair leighis a thairiscint chun bunús téarmaíochta na dtéacsanna cliniciúla a bharrfheabhsú trí chórais mhianadóireachta téacs. Is é an croí-acmhainn ná tábla de láimh coimeádta d’aistriúcháin focal agus smután Béarla-go-Gearmáinis, arna thacú ag sraith rialacha giniúna teanga. Déanann an saothar cur síos ar shreabhadh oibre ina bhfuil saibhriú agus modhnú an tábla seo le hiarrachtaí daonna agus meaisín, saibhrithe de láimh ag clibeanna gramadaí ar leith. Modhanna ó bharr anuas agus ó bhun aníos le haghaidh téarmaíochta daonra a úsáidtear go comhthreomhar. Táirgeann gineadóir téarma na téarmaí comhéadain deiridh, a chruthaíonn leaganacha Gearmánacha duine le go leor de réir tuairisc Bhéarla SNOMED CT. Laghdaítear go mór méid an stór focal má dhéantar scagadh i gcoinne cnuasach mór téarmaíochta fearainn agus corpora i bhfabhar téarmaí nó téarmaí níos réadúla ar féidir a bheith ag súil le réasún go mbeidís ag teacht leis.
sleachta cliniciúla téacs laistigh de phíblíne mianadóireachta téacs. Rinneadh meastóireacht trí chomparáid a dhéanamh idir an leagan reatha d’fhoclóir an chomhéadain Ghearmánaigh agus an tábla tuairisce Béarla d’eisiúint SNOMED CT International. Comhoiriúnaíodh téarma beacht le corpas beag comhthreomhar a bhí comhdhéanta de shleachta téacs ó dhoiciméid chliniciúla éagsúla. Agus paraiméadair aisghabhála ísle ar an iomlán (le luachanna-F thart ar 30%), sroicheann feidhmíocht chás na Gearmáinise 80 – 90% de chás an Bhéarla. Is díol spéise é go bhfuil nótaí beagán níos fearr le téacsanna meaisín-aistrithe (Gearmáinis - Béarla), ag baint úsáide as an acmhainn International SNOMED CT amháin.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hi>चिकित्सा भाषा उपयोगकर्ताओं, संस्थानों और भाषा रजिस्टरों के बारे में महान विविधताओं को प्रदर्शित करती है। मुक्त पाठ में नैदानिक दस्तावेजों के बड़े हिस्सों के साथ, एनएलपी चिकित्सा रिकॉर्ड से पुन: प्रयोज्य और इंटरऑपरेबल अर्थ को अनलॉक करने में अधिक से अधिक महत्वपूर्ण भूमिका निभा रहा है। यह अध्ययन आर्किटेक्चरल सिद्धांतों और जर्मन इंटरफ़ेस शब्दावली के विकास का वर्णन करता है, मानव एनोटेशन और नियम-आधारित शब्द पीढ़ी के साथ मशीन अनुवाद का संयोजन करता है, जो 7.7 मिलियन कच्ची प्रविष्टियों के साथ एक संसाधन उत्पन्न करता है, जिनमें से प्रत्येक संदर्भ शब्दावली SNOMED CT से जुड़ा हुआ है, जो लगभग 350 हजार अवधारणाओं के साथ एक अंतरराष्ट्रीय मानक है। इसका उद्देश्य पाठ खनन प्रणालियों द्वारा नैदानिक ग्रंथों की शब्दावली ग्राउंडिंग को अनुकूलित करने के लिए चिकित्सा शब्दजाल का एक उच्च कवरेज प्रदान करना है। कोर संसाधन अंग्रेजी-से-जर्मन शब्द और चंक अनुवाद की एक मैन्युअल रूप से क्यूरेट की गई तालिका है, जो भाषा पीढ़ी के नियमों के एक सेट द्वारा समर्थित है। कार्य मानव और मशीन प्रयासों के साथ इस तालिका के संवर्धन और संशोधन से युक्त एक वर्कफ़्लो का वर्णन करता है, जो मैन्युअल रूप से व्याकरण विशिष्ट टैग द्वारा समृद्ध होता है। समानांतर में उपयोग की जाने वाली शब्दावली जनसंख्या के लिए ऊपर-नीचे और नीचे-ऊपर विधियां। अंतिम इंटरफ़ेस शब्द एक शब्द जनरेटर द्वारा उत्पादित किए जाते हैं, जो SNOMED CT अंग्रेजी विवरण प्रति एक-से-कई जर्मन संस्करण बनाता है। डोमेन शब्दावली और कॉर्पोरेट के एक बड़े संग्रह के खिलाफ फ़िल्टरिंग अधिक यथार्थवादी शब्दों या शर्तों के पक्ष में शब्दावली के आकार को काफी कम कर देता है जो यथोचित रूप से मेल खाने की उम्मीद की जा सकती है
एक पाठ-खनन पाइपलाइन के भीतर नैदानिक पाठ मार्ग। जर्मन इंटरफ़ेस शब्दावली के वर्तमान संस्करण और SNOMED CT International रिलीज़ की अंग्रेज़ी विवरण तालिका के बीच तुलना करके एक मूल्यांकन किया गया था। एक सटीक शब्द मिलान विभिन्न नैदानिक दस्तावेजों से पाठ स्निपेट द्वारा गठित एक छोटे से समानांतर कॉर्पस के साथ किया गया था। समग्र रूप से कम पुनर्प्राप्ति मापदंडों के साथ (लगभग 30% एफ-मानों के साथ), जर्मन भाषा परिदृश्य का प्रदर्शन अंग्रेजी के 80 - 90% तक पहुंचता है। दिलचस्प बात यह है कि एनोटेशन मशीन-अनुवादित (जर्मन - अंग्रेजी) ग्रंथों के साथ थोड़ा बेहतर हैं, केवल अंतर्राष्ट्रीय SNOMED सीटी संसाधन का उपयोग करके।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>医言异于用户、司、言登记册。 大抵临床文档自由文本,NLP解锁医记可互操作之义益重。 本研述德语界面词汇表架构原理演变,机器翻译与人工注法之术语生成相合,生有770万个原始条目之资,每条目皆关参考术语SNOMED CT,SNOMED CT一约35万个之国际标准也。 所以资医术语之高覆,以掘优化临床本之术语基也。 核心资者,手动谋之英语至于德语单词、译表,由群言成法。 述一行事,人机器丰改,语法特定标手动富。 自上而下,与自下而上者术语充而用之。 终界面术语生于术语生成器,当生成器因 SNOMED CT 英语述创一双多德语变体。 刺大域术语、语料库,大大减少词汇表之大小,转用更术语、可豫配之术语
文本掘管道中临床文本段落。 校其德语界面词汇表SNOMED CT International英文描述表评之。 用异临床文档之文片段小并行语料库执精术语配。 检索参数总体上较低(F 值约为 30%),德语方案性能至英语方者 80- 90%。 有趣者,仅用国际SNOMED CT资,机器翻译(德语 - 英语)文本注稍佳。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ka>მედიციური ენაზე გამოყენება ძალიან განსხვავებები მომხმარებელი, ინსტუტისტურები და ენაზე რეგისტრისტურების შესახებ. კლინიკური დოკუმენტების დიდი ნაწილი თავისუფალი ტექსტში, NLP უფრო მნიშვნელოვანი როლილის გახსნა მედიციური და კონტაქტიური სანიშვნელოვანი მედიციური წიგნიდან. ამ სწავლაში აღწერს არქიტექტური პრინუმენტები და გერმანეთის ინტერფექტური სიტყვებლის ვოლუციას, მაქსინური გაგრძელება ადამიანის ანოტაციას და პროგრამის დაბათებული ტერმინზე, რომელიც 7,7 მილიონი წყალებით, რომელიც ყველაფერი განსა მიზეზია, რომ ტექსტის მინდონის სისტემისთან კლინიკური ტექსტის ფონტიფიკაციის ოპტიმიზაცია მედიცინური ჯაპონის უფრო დიდი კონფიკური ფონტიკური და მნიშვნელოვანი რესურსი არის ხელსახურად დაწყვეტილი ანგლისურად გერმანურად სიტყვების და დაწყვეტილი სიტყვების რაблицა, რომელიც ენის წარმოიქმნის წესების სამუშაო აღწერს სამუშაო გარეშე, რომელიც ამ ცხრილის გარეშე და შეცვალობა ადამიანის და მანქანის ძალადობით, რომელიც მანქანიურად გარეშე გრამიმაპერიფიკური ტერმინოლოგიის მოსახლეობისთვის ზემოთ და ქვემოთ მეტოვები პარალელად გამოყენებული. საბოლოო ინტერფექტის სიტყვები შექმნილია ტერმინის გენერატორი, რომელიც შექმნის ერთ-მეტი გერმანული განრამეტრების განსაზღვრებით SNOMED ფილტრირება დიომინური ტერმინოლოგიების და კოპორას დირასტიკურად გამოკლება სიტყვებულის ზომას, რომელიც უფრო რეალური სიტყვების ან სიტყვებისთვის, რომელიც შეუძლიათ წარმოდ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Il linguaggio medico presenta grandi variazioni per quanto riguarda utenti, istituzioni e registri linguistici. Con gran parte dei documenti clinici in testo libero, NLP sta giocando un ruolo sempre più importante nello sbloccare significati riutilizzabili e interoperabili dalle cartelle cliniche. Questo studio descrive i principi architettonici e l'evoluzione di un vocabolario di interfaccia tedesca, combinando la traduzione automatica con annotazione umana e generazione di termini basati su regole, dando vita a una risorsa con 7,7 milioni di voci grezze, ognuna delle quali legata alla terminologia di riferimento SNOMED CT, uno standard internazionale con circa 350 mila concetti. Lo scopo è quello di offrire un'elevata copertura del gergo medico al fine di ottimizzare la messa a terra terminologica dei testi clinici da parte di sistemi di estrazione di testo. La risorsa principale è una tabella curata manualmente di traduzioni di parole e pezzi da inglese a tedesco, supportata da un insieme di regole di generazione delle lingue. Il lavoro descrive un flusso di lavoro consistente nell'arricchimento e modifica di questa tabella con sforzi umani e macchina, arricchito manualmente da tag grammaticali specifici. Metodi top-down e bottom-up per la popolazione terminologica utilizzati in parallelo. I termini finali dell'interfaccia sono prodotti da un generatore di termini, che crea varianti tedesche one-to-many per descrizione SNOMED CT English. Filtrare contro una vasta collezione di terminologie di dominio e corpora riduce drasticamente le dimensioni del vocabolario a favore di termini o termini più realistici che ci si può ragionevolmente aspettare che corrispondano</abstract_it>
      <abstract_hu>Az orvosi nyelv nagy eltéréseket mutat a felhasználók, intézmények és nyelvi nyilvántartások tekintetében. Mivel a klinikai dokumentumok nagy része szabad szövegben van, az NLP egyre fontosabb szerepet játszik az újrahasználható és interoperábilis jelentések feloldásában az orvosi nyilvántartásokból. Ez a tanulmány egy német interfész szókincsének építészeti elveit és fejlődését ismerteti, amely ötvözi a gépi fordítást az emberi jegyzetekkel és a szabályokon alapuló kifejezések generálásával, 7,7 millió nyers bejegyzéssel rendelkező erőforrást eredményez, amelyek mindegyike a referencia terminológiához kapcsolódik, amely mintegy 350 ezer fogalmat tartalmazó nemzetközi szabványhoz. A cél az orvosi zsargonok nagy lefedettsége annak érdekében, hogy a klinikai szövegek terminológiai alapozásának optimalizálása szövegbányászati rendszerekkel történjen. Az alapvető erőforrás egy manuálisan összeállított táblázat angol-német szó és darab fordításokból, amelyeket számos nyelvgenerálási szabály támogat. A munka egy olyan munkafolyamatot ír le, amely a táblázat emberi és gépi erőfeszítésekkel gazdagítja és módosítja, manuálisan nyelvspecifikus címkékkel gazdagítva. A párhuzamosan használt terminológiai populáció felülről lefelé és alulról felfelé irányuló módszerei. A végső interfész kifejezéseket egy kifejezés generátor állítja elő, amely a SNOMED CT angol leírása szerint egy-a-sok német változatot hoz létre. A domain terminológiák és corporák nagy gyűjteményével történő szűrés drasztikusan csökkenti a szókincs méretét olyan reálisabb kifejezések vagy kifejezések javára, amelyek ésszerűen megfelelnek</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Η ιατρική γλώσσα παρουσιάζει μεγάλες παραλλαγές όσον αφορά τους χρήστες, τα ιδρύματα και τα γλωσσικά μητρώα. Με μεγάλα τμήματα κλινικών εγγράφων σε ελεύθερο κείμενο, η ΝΛΠ διαδραματίζει όλο και πιο σημαντικό ρόλο στο ξεκλειδώνοντας επαναχρησιμοποιήσιμο και διαλειτουργικό νόημα από τα ιατρικά αρχεία. Η μελέτη αυτή περιγράφει τις αρχιτεκτονικές αρχές και την εξέλιξη του λεξιλογίου της γερμανικής διεπαφής, συνδυάζοντας τη μηχανική μετάφραση με ανθρώπινη σχολιασμό και τη δημιουργία όρων βάσει κανόνων, δημιουργώντας έναν πόρο με 7,7 εκατομμύρια ακατέργαστες καταχωρήσεις, καθεμία από τις οποίες συνδέεται με την ορολογία αναφοράς ένα διεθνές πρότυπο με περίπου 350 χιλιάδες έννοιες. Σκοπός είναι η παροχή υψηλής κάλυψης της ιατρικής ορολογίας με σκοπό τη βελτιστοποίηση της ορολογίας των κλινικών κειμένων από συστήματα εξόρυξης κειμένου. Ο βασικός πόρος είναι ένας μη αυτόματο επιλεγμένος πίνακας μεταφράσεων λέξεων και κομματιών από Αγγλικά προς Γερμανικά, υποστηριζόμενος από ένα σύνολο κανόνων δημιουργίας γλωσσών. Η εργασία περιγράφει μια ροή εργασίας που συνίσταται στον εμπλουτισμό και την τροποποίηση αυτού του πίνακα με ανθρώπινες και μηχανικές προσπάθειες, εμπλουτισμένες χειροκίνητα με γραμματικές ετικέτες. Μέθοδοι από πάνω προς τα κάτω και από κάτω προς τα πάνω για τον πληθυσμό ορολογίας που χρησιμοποιούνται παράλληλα. Οι τελικοί όροι διεπαφής παράγονται από μια γεννήτρια όρων, η οποία δημιουργεί μία προς πολλές γερμανικές παραλλαγές ανά αγγλική περιγραφή. Φιλτράρισμα σε μια μεγάλη συλλογή ορολογίων και σωμάτων τομέων μειώνει δραστικά το μέγεθος του λεξιλογίου υπέρ πιο ρεαλιστικών όρων ή όρων που εύλογα αναμένεται να ταιριάζουν</abstract_el>
      <abstract_kk>Медицина тілі пайдаланушылар, институттар және тіл регистрациясы туралы көп айырмашылықтарды көрсетеді. Бос мәтіндегі клиникалық құжаттардың үлкен бөлшектері болса, NLP медицина жазулардан қайта қолданылатын және істей алатын мәліметті бөлшектерді бұғаттау үшін көп және маңы Бұл зерттеу архитектуралық принципаларды және неміс интерфейс сөздерінің эволюциясын түсіндіреді, компьютердің аудармасын адам жазбалары мен ережелер негізінде тұратын терминлерімен біріктіріп, 7,7 миллион сызық жазулармен ресурс береді. Әрбірінің сілтеме терминологиясы SNOMED Мақсат - мәтін бағыттау жүйелері бойынша клиникалық мәтіндерді бағыттау үшін медициналық жаргон жоғары мәтіндерді қолдану. Негізгі ресурс - ағылшын тілінен неміс тілдерді құру ережелерін қолдау үшін қолданылатын тілінен қалған тілінің кестесі. Жұмыс жұмыс жұмысын граммалық белгілерден қолмен бағалау және өзгерту кестесін бағалау және өзгерту дегенді анықтайды. Жоғарғы және төменгі жоғарғы әдістер параллелді қолданылатын терминологиялық жалпы. Соңғы интерфейс терминалары SNOMED CT ағылшын сипаттамасының бір- көп неміс варианттарын құрып береді. Домен терминологияларының үлкен жинақтарына сүзгілеу мен корпора драстикалық сөздігінің өлшемін бірнеше реалистикалық терминологияларына не шарттарына сәйкес келеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Gydytojų kalba labai skiriasi vartotojų, institucijų ir kalbų registrų atžvilgiu. Didelės klinikinių dokumentų dalys yra nemokamas, todėl NLP atlieka vis svarbesnį vaidmenį atskleidžiant pakartotinai naudojamą ir sąveikią medicinos įrašų reikšmę. Šiame tyrime aprašomi architektūriniai principai ir Vokietijos sąsajos žodyno raida, derinant mašininį vertimą su žmogaus anotacija ir taisyklėmis grindžiama terminų kūrimu, gaunant išteklių su 7,7 mln. žaliavinių įrašų, iš kurių kiekvienas susijęs su referencine terminologija SNOMED CT, tarptautiniu standartu su apie 350 tūkstančių sąvokų. Siekiama pasiūlyti aukštą medicininio žargono aprėptį siekiant optimizuoti klinikinių tekstų terminologinį pagrindą tekstų kasybos sistemomis. Pagrindinis išteklius yra rankiniu būdu sureguliuotas anglų ir vokiečių žodžių vertimų ir dalių lentelė, paremta kalbų kūrimo taisyklėmis. Darbuotoje aprašomas darbo srautas, kurį sudaro šios lentelės praturtinimas ir pakeitimas žmogaus ir mašinų pastangomis, rankiniu būdu praturtintas konkrečiomis gramatikos etiketėmis. Kartu naudojami terminologinės populiacijos iš viršaus į apačią ir iš apačios į viršų metodai. Galutinės sąsajos sąvokos gaminamos termino generatoriumi, kuris sukuria vieną ar kelis Vokietijos variantus pagal SNOMED CT anglų aprašymą. Filtruojant didelį domeno terminologijų ir korpros rinkinį drastiškai sumažinamas žodyno dydis siekiant realistiškesnių terminų ar terminų, kurie pagrįstai gali būti tikėtasi atitinkančių</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Медицинскиот јазик покажува големи варијации во врска со корисниците, институциите и јазичните регистри. Со големи делови од клиничките документи во бесплатен текст, НЛП игра сé поголема улога во отворањето на повторно употребливо и интераперативно значење од медицинските досиеја. Оваа студија ги опишува архитектурните принципи и еволуцијата на германскиот вокалар на интерфејс, комбинирајќи го машинскиот превод со човечката анотација и генерација на термини базирани на правила, давајќи ресурс со 7,7 милиони сурови записи, од кои секој поврзан со референтната терминологија SNOMED CT, меѓунар Целта е да се понуди високо покривање на медицинските јаргони со цел да се оптимизира терминологијата на клиничките тексти со текстовите рударски системи. Основниот ресурс е рачно курирана маса на англиски-германски преводи на зборови и парчиња, поддржана од множина правила за генерација на јазици. The work describes a workflow consisting the enrichment and modification of this table with human and machine efforts, manually enriched by grammarspecific tags.  Top-down and bottom-up methods for terminology population used in parallel.  Финалните термини на интерфејс се произведуваат од термин генератор, кој создава еден до многу германски варијанти по SNOMED CT англиски опис. Филтрирањето против голема колекција терминологии на домените и корпората драстично ја намалува големината на речникот во корист на пореални термини или термини кои може разумно да се очекува да се совпаѓаат</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Bahasa perubatan menunjukkan variasi besar mengenai pengguna, institusi dan daftar bahasa. Dengan bahagian besar dokumen klinik dalam teks bebas, NLP bermain peran yang semakin penting dalam membuka makna yang boleh digunakan semula dan interoperabel dari rekod perubatan. Ujian ini menggambarkan prinsip arkitektur dan evolusi vokbulari antaramuka Jerman, menggabungkan terjemahan mesin dengan anotasi manusia dan generasi term a berdasarkan peraturan, memberikan sumber dengan 7.7 juta masukan mentah, masing-masing berkaitan dengan terminologi rujukan SNOMED CT, piawai antarabangsa dengan sekitar 350 ribu konsep. Tujuan adalah untuk menawarkan perlindungan tinggi jargon perubatan untuk optimum pendaratan terminologi teks klinik oleh sistem penambangan teks. Sumber utama adalah jadual yang dikurasikan secara manual dari perkataan Inggeris-ke-Jerman dan terjemahan sepotong, disokong oleh set peraturan generasi bahasa. Kerja menggambarkan aliran kerja yang mengandungi pengkaya dan pengubahsuaian jadual ini dengan usaha manusia dan mesin, diperiksa secara manual oleh tag grammarspecific. Kaedah atas-bawah dan bawah-atas untuk populasi terminologi digunakan secara selari. Terma antaramuka terakhir dihasilkan oleh generator term a, yang mencipta varian Jerman satu-ke-banyak per keterangan Inggeris CT SNOMED. Penapis terhadap koleksi besar terminologi domain dan korpra mengurangkan secara drastik saiz vokbulari untuk terma atau terma yang lebih realistik yang boleh dijangka sepadan</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>മെഡിക്കല്‍ ഭാഷ ഉപയോക്താക്കള്‍, സ്ഥാനങ്ങള്‍, ഭാഷയുടെ രേജിസ്റ്ററുകളെക്കുറിച്ചും വലിയ വ്യത്യാസങ്ങള്‍  സ്വതന്ത്ര രേഖയില്‍ ക്ലിനിക്കല്‍ രേഖകളുടെ വലിയ ഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ കൊണ്ട്, NLP വീണ്ടും ഉപയോഗിക്കാവുന്നതും വീണ്ടും ഉപയോഗിക്കാന്‍ കഴിയുന്നതും  ഈ പഠനം ജര്‍മ്മന്‍ ഇന്റര്‍മെസ്റ്റ് വാക്കുകളുടെ സ്ഥാനത്തിന്റെ പ്രധാനപ്പെടുത്തുന്നതിനെയും പരിഭാഷ വിവരിക്കുന്നതിനെയും വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു. മെഷീന്‍ പരിഭാഷവും നിയമപരമായ വാക്കുതലമുറയെയും കൂട ടെക്സ്റ്റ് മൈനിങ്ങ് സിസ്റ്റം മൂലം ടെര്‍മിനിലോളജിയുടെ ടെര്‍മിനോളജി ഗ്രൂണിങ്ങിനെ ഉപയോഗിക്കാന്‍ മെഡിക്കല്‍ ജാര ഭാഷ തലമുറയുടെ നിയമങ്ങളാല്‍ പിന്തുണയ്ക്കപ്പെടുന്ന ആഗ്ലീഷ്- മുതല്‍ ജര്‍മ്മന്‍ വാക്കുകളുടെ കൈയ്യില്‍ നിര്‍ബന്ധിതമാ The work describes a workflow consisting the enrichment and modification of this table with human and machine efforts, manually enriched by grammarspecific tags.  തെര്‍മ്മിനോളജി ജനസംഖ്യത്തിനായി ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന മുകളില്‍ താഴേക്കും താഴേക്കും രീതികള്‍. അവസാന വിലാസങ്ങള്‍ ഒരു വാക്ക് ജനററേറ്റര്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയിരിക്കുന്നു. അത് സ്നോമെഡ് സിറ്റി ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് വിവരണങ്ങള്‍ക്ക്  ഒരു വലിയ ഡൊമൈന്‍ ടെര്‍മിനോളജിയുടെയും കോര്‍പ്പോരിയുടെയും സംഘത്തിന് വിരോധമായി ഫില്‍റ്റിങ്ങ് ചെയ്യുന്നു. വാക്കുകളുടെ വലിപ്പം കുറവ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_pl>Język medyczny wykazuje duże różnice w odniesieniu do użytkowników, instytucji i rejestrów językowych. Dzięki dużej części dokumentów klinicznych w wolnym tekście NLP odgrywa coraz ważniejszą rolę w odblokowaniu ponownego użytku i interoperacyjnego znaczenia z dokumentacji medycznej. Niniejsze opracowanie opisuje zasady architektury i ewolucję niemieckiego interfejsu słownictwa, łączącego tłumaczenie maszynowe z adnotacją ludzką i generowaniem terminów opartych na regułach, dając zasób z 7,7 milionów surowych wpisów, z których każdy powiązany jest z terminologią referencyjną SNOMED CT, międzynarodowym standardem o około 350-tysiącach pojęć. Celem jest zapewnienie szerokiego zakresu żargonu medycznego w celu optymalizacji uziemienia terminologicznego tekstów klinicznych za pomocą systemów eksploracji tekstów. Podstawowym zasobem jest ręcznie kuratorowana tabela tłumaczeń słów z angielskiego na niemiecki i fragmentów, obsługiwana przez zestaw reguł generowania języków. W pracy opisano przepływ pracy polegający na wzbogaceniu i modyfikacji tej tabeli wysiłkami człowieka i maszyny, ręcznie wzbogaconymi o znaczniki gramatyczne. Metody odgórne i oddolne dla populacji terminologii stosowane równolegle. Ostateczne terminy interfejsu są produkowane przez generator terminów, który tworzy jeden do wielu niemieckich wariantów według opisu SNOMED CT angielskiego. Filtrowanie na podstawie dużego zbioru terminologii domenowych i korpusów drastycznie zmniejsza wielkość słownictwa na rzecz bardziej realistycznych terminów lub terminów, których można oczekiwać, że będą pasować</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mt>Il-lingwa medika turi varjazzjonijiet kbar fir-rigward tal-utenti, l-istituzzjonijiet u r-reġistri tal-lingwi. B’partijiet kbar ta’ dokumenti kliniċi f’test ħieles, il-NLP qed taqdi rwol dejjem aktar importanti fil-ftuħ ta’ tifsira li tista’ terġa’ tintuża u interoperabbli mir-rekords mediċi. Dan l-istudju jiddeskrivi l-prinċipji arkitettoniċi u l-evoluzzjoni ta’ vokabulari tal-interfaċċja Ġermaniża, li jgħaqqad it-traduzzjoni tal-magna mal-annotazzjoni umana u l-ġenerazzjoni ta’ terminu bbażat fuq ir-regoli, u li jagħti riżorsa b’7.7 miljun entrata mhux ipproċessata, li kull waħda minnhom hija marbuta mat-terminoloġija ta’ referenza SNOMED CT, standard internazzjonali b’madwar 350,000 L-għan huwa li tiġi offruta kopertura għolja ta’ jargon mediku sabiex jiġi ottimizzat it-terminoloġija bbażata fuq it-testi kliniċi permezz ta’ sistemi ta’ tħaffir tat-testi. Ir-riżorsa ewlenija hija tabella kkurata manwalment ta’ traduzzjonijiet bil-kliem Ingliż-Ġermaniż u biċċiet, appoġġjata minn sett ta’ regoli tal-ġenerazzjoni tal-lingwi. Ix-xogħol jiddeskrivi fluss tax-xogħol li jikkonsisti fl-arrikkiment u l-modifika ta’ din it-tabella bl-isforzi umani u tal-magni, arrikkiti manwalment b’tikketti grammatiċi speċifiċi. Top-down and bottom-up methods for terminology population used in parallel.  The final interface terms are produced by a term generator, which creates one-to-many German variants per SNOMED CT English description.  L-iffiltrar kontra ġbir kbir ta’ terminoloġiji tad-dominju u korpra jnaqqas drastikament id-daqs tal-vokabulari favur termini jew termini aktar realistiċi li jistgħu raġonevolment ikunu mistennija li jaqblu</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Эмнэлгийн хэл хэрэглэгчид, байгууллагууд, хэлний регистрийн тухай маш олон өөрчлөлт үзүүлдэг. Мөн үнэгүй текст дээр эмнэлгийн баримтуудын ихэнх хэсэгт NLP эмнэлгийн бичил баримтуудаас дахин ашиглах болон харилцаа ашиглах боломжтой утгыг шинэчлэхэд илүү чухал үүрэг тоглож байна. Энэ судалгаанд Германы интерфейс үгийн хувьсалын архитектур зарчмыг тодорхойлж, хүн төрөлхтний нотолгоо болон дүрэм суурилсан үеийн хувьсалыг холбогдож, 7.7 сая цэвэр нэвтрэлтэй нөхцөл өгдөг. Энэ бүгдээрээ нийтлэл терминологи SNOMED CT-тай холбогдсон. Энэ Цаг нь эмнэлгийн загварын өндөр мэдээлэл өгөх нь текст сүүрсэн системээр клиникийн текстүүдийг нэмэгдүүлэх зорилго юм. Үндсэн нөхцөл нь англи-Германы үг болон хэлний үеийн төлөө дэмжигдэх хэлбэрийн хууль болон хэлбэрийн хэлбэрээс гараар зориулагдсан хүснэгт юм. Энэ ажлын урсгал нь хүн болон машины хичээлд баялагдсан хүснэгтийн хөгжлийн хөгжлийг тодорхойлж байна. Хоёр доош, доош болон доош арга нь параллель хэрэглэгддэг терминологийн хүн амын төлөө. Эцсийн интерфейс хэлбэрүүдийг SNOMED CT Англи хэлний тодорхойлолтын нэг-ээс олон германчууд бий болгодог. Томоохон терминологи болон корпора зэрэг цуглуулах нь илүү бодит хэмжээний тулд хэмжээний хэмжээг багасгаж чадна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Medisisk språk viser store variasjonar om brukarar, institusjonar og språkkregistrer. Med store deler av kliniske dokument i fri tekst spelar NLP ein meir og meir viktig rolle i å låsa opp nybrukbare og interoperabil mening frå medisinske opptak. Denne studien beskriver arkitektursprinsippene og evolusjonen av eit tysk grensesnittordbok, samanliknar maskineomsetjing med menneske annotasjon og regelbasert uttrykk, og gir ei ressurs med 7,7 millioner råoppføringar, kvar av dei som er knytta til referansterminologien SNOMED CT, eit internasjonal standard med omtrent 350 tusen konseptar. Målet er å tilbygge ein høg dekkjering av medisinske skyggen for å optimalisera terminologikkgrunnlegging av kliniske tekstar ved tekstminingssystemet. kjerneressursen er ei manuelt korrigert tabell med engelsk- til- tysk ord og blokkeoversettelsar, støtta av eit sett språk- genereringsreglar. Arbeidet beskriver eit arbeidsfløys som inneheld forstørring og endring av denne tabellen med menneskelige og maskinspørseler, manuelt røyd av gramspesifikke merker. Topp- nedst- og nedst- opp- metodar for terminologiske populasjon brukt i parallell. Den siste grensesnittvilkårene er produsert av eit termingenerator, som lagar ein til mange tyske variantar per SNOMED CT engelsk beskrivelse. Filtrering mot ein stor samling av domeneterminologiar og korpora drastisk reduserer storleiken på ordboka for meir realistiske vilkår eller vilkår som kan rett forventast å passa med</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Limbajul medical prezintă mari variații în ceea ce privește utilizatorii, instituțiile și registrele lingvistice. Cu o mare parte a documentelor clinice în text liber, PNL joacă un rol din ce în ce mai important în deblocarea semnificațiilor reutilizabile și interoperabile din dosarele medicale. Acest studiu descrie principiile arhitecturale și evoluția unui vocabular de interfață germană, combinând traducerea automată cu adnotarea umană și generarea de termeni bazate pe reguli, generând o resursă cu 7,7 milioane de intrări brute, fiecare dintre ele legate de terminologia de referință SNOMED CT, un standard internațional cu aproximativ 350 de mii de concepte. Scopul este de a oferi o acoperire înaltă a jargonului medical pentru a optimiza bazarea terminologiei textelor clinice de către sistemele de mining de text. Resursa principală este un tabel manual de traduceri de cuvinte din engleză în germană și bucată, susținut de un set de reguli de generare a limbilor. Lucrarea descrie un flux de lucru constând îmbogățirea și modificarea acestui tabel cu eforturi umane și de mașină, îmbogățit manual cu etichete gramaticale specifice. Metode de sus în jos și de jos în sus pentru populația terminologică utilizată în paralel. Termenii finali de interfață sunt produși de un generator de termeni, care creează unu-la-multe variante germane pentru descrierea în limba engleză SNOMED CT. Filtrarea în funcție de o colecție largă de terminologii de domeniu și corpore reduce drastic dimensiunea vocabularului în favoarea unor termeni sau termeni mai realisti care pot fi așteptați în mod rezonabil să se potrivească</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Medicinski jezik pokazuje velike razlike u vezi korisnika, institucija i jezičkih registrija. Sa velikim dijelovima kliničkih dokumenta u slobodnom tekstu, NLP igra važniju ulogu u otključanju ponovnog korištenja i interoperabilnog značenja iz medicinskih podataka. Ova studija opisuje arhitekturne principe i evoluciju njemačkog rečnika interfejsa, kombinirajući prevod mašine sa ljudskim annotacijom i generacijom termina na pravilima, pružajući resursu sa 7,7 miliona sirovih ulaza, svaki od kojih je povezan sa referentnim terminologijom SNOMED CT, međunarodnim standardom sa oko 350 hiljada koncepta. Svrha je ponuditi visoko pokrivanje medicinskog žargona kako bi optimalizirao terminologiju osnova kliničkih tekstova tekstskim rudarskim sistemima. Glavni resurs je ručno korišteni stol engleske na njemačke riječi i prevoda komada, podržavan grupom pravila generacije jezika. Rad opisuje radni tok koji sastoji od bogatstva i modifikacije ovog stola sa ljudskim i mašinskim naporima, ručno bogatim gramatičkim znakovima. Najgora i najgora metoda za terminološku populaciju koja se koristi paralelno. Konačni uslovi interfejsa proizvode termin generator, koji stvara jednu do mnoge nemačke variante po opisu SNOMED CT engleskog jezika. Filtriranje protiv velike kolekcije terminologija domena i korporacije drastično smanjuje veličinu rečenika u korist reālističkih uslova ili uslova koje se mogu razumno očekivati da će odgovarati</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Luqada caafimaadku wuxuu muujiyaa isbedelyo badan oo ku saabsan isticmaalayaasha, machadyada iyo diiwaangelinta luuqada. Goobaha dukumentiyada caafimaadka ee badan ee ku qoran qoraal xor ah, NLP wuxuu ka ciyaarayaa qayb aad iyo aad u muhiim ah oo ku saabsan furitaanka dib u isticmaalka iyo macnaheedka mid ka mid ah warqadaha caafimaadka. Waxbarashadan waxaa ku qoran qorniinka dhismaha iyo bedelka hadalka afka Jarmalka ah, kaas oo lagu soo ururiyaa tarjumaadda machine with human annotation and qoraal-based qarniga, kaasoo soo saara resource with 7.7 million oo raw galeenka, mid kastaba ku xiran terminology SNOMED CT, kaas oo ah standard caalami ah oo ku dhow 350 kun fekero. Ujeedadu waa in lagu bixiyaa dabool dhakhaatiir aad u dheer si aad u optimiso qoraalka dhakhtarka ee dhakhtarka ee qoraalka dhakhaatiirta lagu qoro nidaamka qoraalka. Source core is a manual curated table of Ingiriis-to-German word and chunk translations, supported by a set of rules of language generation. The work describes a workflow consisting the enrichment and modification of this table with human and machine efforts, manually enriched by grammarspecific tags.  Dhaqdooyinka hoose iyo hoose-hoose ee dadka terminology ee loogu isticmaalay si siman. Xiriikhda ugu dambeeya waxaa la soo saaraa qoraal dhaqaale ah, kaas oo sameeya mid-ka-badan oo Jarmal ah qoraalka ingiriisiga ee SNOMED CT. Tilmaamaha ku filanayaasha urur aad u weyn oo lagu soo ururiyo terminology iyo shirkadda ayaa si aad u hoosaysiiya tirada warqadda ku saabsan si ay u hesho sharciga runta ah ama shuruudaha looga suurtowdo inay si qumman u eg karto</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Medicinskt språk uppvisar stora variationer när det gäller användare, institutioner och språkregister. Med stora delar av kliniska dokument i fritext spelar NLP en allt viktigare roll för att låsa upp återanvändbar och interoperabel mening från medicinska journaler. Denna studie beskriver arkitektoniska principer och utvecklingen av ett tyskt gränssnitt ordförråd, som kombinerar maskinöversättning med mänsklig notering och regelbaserad termgenerering, vilket ger en resurs med 7,7 miljoner råposter, var och en kopplad till referensterminologin SNOMED CT, en internationell standard med cirka 350 tusen begrepp. Syftet är att erbjuda en hög täckning av medicinsk jargong för att optimera terminologigrundning av kliniska texter genom textminingssystem. Kärnressourcen är en manuellt redigerad tabell med engelska-till-tyska ord- och chunköversättningar, som stöds av en uppsättning regler för språkgenerering. Arbetet beskriver ett arbetsflöde bestående av berikning och modifiering av denna tabell med mänskliga och maskinmässiga insatser, manuellt berikad med grammatiska taggar. Metoder uppifrån och ner och uppifrån för terminologipopulation som används parallellt. De slutliga gränssnittsbeteckningarna produceras av en termgenerator, som skapar en-till-många tyska varianter per SNOMED CT engelsk beskrivning. Filtrering mot en stor samling domänterminologier och corpora minskar drastiskt ordförrådets storlek till förmån för mer realistiska termer eller termer som rimligen kan förväntas matcha</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>پزشکی زبان کے بارے میں بہت سی تفاوت نشان دیتی ہے کارساز، سازمان اور زبان رسیسٹر کے بارے میں۔ بے فائدہ ٹیکسٹ میں کلینیکی دفتروں کے بڑے حصے کے ساتھ، NLP پزشکی رکوردوں سے دوبارہ استعمال کرنے والے اور پیدا کرنے والے معنی کو کھولنے میں زیادہ اور اضافہ رکورد کرتا ہے. This study describes the architectural principles and the evolution of a German interface vocabulary, combining machine translation with human annotation and rule-based term generation, giving a resource with 7.7 million raw entries, each of which linked to the reference terminology SNOMED CT, an international standard with about 350 thousand concepts. مصنوعہ یہ ہے کہ ٹیکسٹ مینینگ سیسٹم کے ذریعے کلینیک ٹیکسٹ کی بنیاد کو اچھی طرح ترمینالوژی کے ذریعے اچھی دکھانے کے لئے دکھانے والی جرگن کا اظہار کرنا ہے. بنیادی رسورس انگلیسی سے جرمانی لفظ اور چانک ترجمہ کا ایک مجموعہ ہے جو زبان پیدا کرنے کے قانون کے ذریعہ مدد کی جاتی ہے. یہ کام ایک کام فول کی توصیف کرتا ہے جس میں اس ٹیبل کی امن اور بدلنے کی وجہ سے انسان اور ماشین کی تلاش کے ساتھ ہے، جسے گرم مشخص ٹاگ کے ذریعے اپنے ہاتھ سے ثروت دی جاتی ہے. ترمینلوژی جماعت کے لئے اوپر-نیچے اور نیچے-اوپر طریقے ہیں جو parallel میں استعمال کئے جاتے ہیں. آخری اینٹرفس شرایط ایک ٹمنڈ جینراٹر کے ذریعہ پیدا کئے جاتے ہیں، جس نے SNOMED CT انگلیسی سفرش کے بارے میں ایک سے بہت سی جرمن متفاوت پیدا کئے ہیں. ڈومین ٹریمولوجی اور کورپورا کی بڑی جمع کرنی کے خلاف فیلتر کرنا بہت حقیقی شرایط یا شرایط کے مطابق فیلتر کرتا ہے جو منطقی طور پر مل سکتی ہے</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_si>වෛද්‍ය භාෂාව ප්‍රකාශ කරනවා පාවිච්චිකරුවන්, සංස්ථානය සහ භාෂාව ලිස්ටර් ගැන නිදහස් පාළුවේ විශාල විද්‍යාත්මක විද්‍යාත්මක විද්‍යාවක් තියෙන්නේ, NLP විද්‍යාත්මක වැඩිය හා වැඩිය ප්‍රමාණයක් පි මේ විධානය විශ්වාස කරනවා ආර්කිටික්ටරිය ප්‍රධානය සහ ජර්මාන් අන්තර්භාව ශබ්ද භාවිතාවක්, මිනිස්සුන් අන්තර්භාව සහ නියෝජිතය සඳහා මිනිස්සුන් අන්තර්ජාව අරමුණය තමයි වෛද්‍ය වර්ගෝන්ගේ හොඳ ආරක්ෂණයක් දෙන්න, පාළ ප්‍රදේශ පද්ධතියෙන් ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක පද්ධති ප්‍රධාන සම්බන්ධය තමයි ඉංග්‍රීසියෙන් ජර්මන් වචනය සහ චංක් භාෂාවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් භාෂාව ප්‍රධා වැඩේ විස්තර කරනවා වැඩ ප්‍රවේශයක් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් මිනිස්සු සහ යන්ත්‍රය ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා මේ මේසේ විශේෂණය සඳහා වෙනස සාමාන්‍ය විදියට භාවිත කරන්න ප්‍රශ්න විදියට පහළ- පහළ හා පහළ- පහළ ප්‍රශ්න විදියට. අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිම අන්තිමයෙන් නිර්මාණකයෙන් නිර් ලොකු සංග්රහනයක් විරුද්ධ විශාලය සහ කොර්පෝරා විශාලයෙන් විරුද්ධ විශාල විරුද්ධ වෙනුවෙන් සංග්රහනය කරනවා වචනය</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>மருத்துவ மொழி பயனர், நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் மொழி பதிவுகள் பற்றிய மிக மாறுபாடுகளை காட்டுகிறது. இலவச உரையில் இருந்து பெரிய சுகார்ந்த ஆவணங்களின் பாகங்களுடன், NLP மீண்டும் பயன்படுத்தக்கூடிய மற்றும் முக்கியமான பொருளை திறக்கு இந்த ஆராய்ச்சி ஒரு ஜெர்மன் இடைமுகப்பு சொற்கோவையும் மாற்றத்தையும் குறிப்பிடுகிறது, மனிதன் அறிவிப்பு மற்றும் விதிமுறை உருவாக்கத்தை கூட்டுகிறது, 7. 7 மில்லியன் ராவ் உள்ளீடுகளுடன், ஒவ்வொரு மூலம உரை கட்டுப்பாட்டு அமைப்புகள் மூலம் சில உரைகளின் மூலம் முனைநோய் கூட்டத்தை தேர்வு செய்யும் பொருட்டு மருத்துவ கார்க்கு  The core resource is a manually curated table of English-to-German word and chunk translations, supported by a set of language generation rules.  இந்த அட்டவணையின் வளர்ச்சியையும் மாற்றுதலையும் மனிதன் மற்றும் இயந்திரம் முயற்சியையும் கைமுறையாக செலுத்தப்பட்டுள்ள ஒரு வேல இணைப்பில் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட முறையியல் மக்களுக்கு மேல் கீழ் மற்றும் கீழ் மேல் முறைகள். கடைசி முகப்பு வார்த்தைகள் ஒரு வார்த்தை உருவாக்குபவரால் உருவாக்கப்படுகிறது, அது SNOMED CT ஆங்கிலத்தின் விளக்கத்திற்க Name</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_vi>Ngôn ngữ y khoa có rất nhiều biến đổi về người dùng, cung cấp và thủ tục ngôn ngữ. Với phần lớn tài liệu lâm sàng trong văn bản tự do, Njala đang đóng vai trò ngày càng quan trọng trong việc tháo gỡ những ý nghĩa có thể tái sử dụng và có thể giải phẫu từ hồ sơ y khoa. Nghiên cứu này mô tả các nguyên tắc kiến trúc và sự phát triển của ngôn ngữ giao diện Đức, kết hợp dịch cơ bản với ghi chú con người và sản xuất từ ngữ quy định, cung cấp một nguồn tài nguyên với 7.7 triệu đoạn thô, mỗi đoạn được liên kết với các thuật ngữ tham khảo SNCC, một tiêu chuẩn quốc tế có khoảng 350 nghìn khái niệm. Mục đích là cung cấp một mức độ cao của ngôn ngữ y học để tối đa hóa nền ngữ thuật của các văn bản lâm sàng qua hệ thống khai thác văn bản. Nguyên nhân chính là một bàn được quản lý bằng tay của văn bản từ-sang-Đức và văn bản, được hỗ trợ bởi một bộ luật tạo ngôn ngữ. The work mô tả một dòng chảy liên quan đến việc làm giàu và sửa đổi chiếc bàn này với nỗ lực của người và máy, do đó được thêm vào bằng các thẻ đặc trưng. Phương pháp từ trên xuống và từ dưới lên dành cho dân số thuật ngữ song song. Các thuật ngữ giao diện cuối cùng được sản xuất bởi một máy phát từ, tạo ra nhiều biến thể Đức cho mỗi mô tả CT đã được mô tả. Bộ lọc đối với một bộ sưu tập các tiên tri miền và hạ sĩ giảm tối đa kích thước của Từ vựng cho những điều khoản thực tế hơn mà có thể dễ thấy thích hợp với nhau</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Davlat tili foydalanuvchilar, asasi va tillar roʻyxatlari haqida katta oʻzgarishlarni koʻrsatadi. Boʻsh matnning katta hujjatning qismlari bilan NLP tibbiy sahifalaridan qayta ishlab chiqaradi va yana boshqa ishlab chiqarish mumkin holatini boshlaydi. Bu o'qituvni tashkilotlar qoidasi va Olmoncha interfeys vositasining evolyutsiyatini anglatadi, inson annotatsiya va qoidadagi soʻzni birlashtirish va oddiy soʻzni birlashtirish mumkin. Bu bir narsa 7.7 million raw yozuvlari bilan bog'liq, har bir bir narsa SNOMED CTga bog'liq, 3.50 000 g'oyalar bilan bir dunyo'l standardi. Bu maqsadi, matn mining tizimi orqali terminolog matnlarini o'zgartirish uchun darajali narsalarni o'zgartirish uchun tibbiy narsalarni ajratish uchun. Name Vazifani qo'lbola grammarspecific taglar tomonidan qo'lbola yozilgan, bu jadvalning tarkibini o'zgartirish va o'zgartirib chiqaradi. Parallel boʻyicha ishlatiladigan terminology jamoasi uchun yuqori va pastki tugmalar tartibi. Name Name</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_de>Medizinische Sprache weist große Unterschiede in Bezug auf Benutzer, Institutionen und Sprachregister auf. Mit großen Teilen klinischer Dokumente im Freitext spielt NLP eine immer wichtigere Rolle bei der Erschließung wiederverwendbarer und interoperabler Bedeutung aus medizinischen Akten. Diese Studie beschreibt die architektonischen Prinzipien und die Entwicklung eines deutschen Interface Vokabulars, das maschinelle Übersetzung mit menschlicher Annotation und regelbasierter Termgenerierung kombiniert, und liefert eine Ressource mit 7,7 Millionen Roheinträgen, die jeweils mit der Referenzterminologie SNOMED CT verknüpft sind, einem internationalen Standard mit etwa 350-tausend Konzepten. Ziel ist es, eine hohe Abdeckung des medizinischen Fachjargons zu bieten, um die terminologische Begründung klinischer Texte durch Text Mining-Systeme zu optimieren. Die Kernressource ist eine manuell kuratierte Tabelle mit Englisch-Deutsch Wort- und Chunk-Übersetzungen, die von einer Reihe von Sprachgenerierungsregeln unterstützt wird. Die Arbeit beschreibt einen Workflow, der die Anreicherung und Modifikation dieser Tabelle durch menschliche und maschinelle Anstrengungen umfasst, manuell durch grammarspezifische Tags angereichert. Parallel verwendete Top-down- und Bottom-up-Methoden für die Terminologie-Population. Die endgültigen Schnittstellenbegriffe werden von einem Termgenerator erzeugt, der eine zu viele deutsche Varianten pro SNOMED CT englische Beschreibung erzeugt. Das Filtern gegen eine große Sammlung von Domänennamen und Korpora reduziert drastisch die Größe des Vokabulars zugunsten realistischerer Begriffe oder Begriffe, die vernünftigerweise übereinstimmen können</abstract_de>
      <abstract_da>Medicinsk sprog udviser store variationer med hensyn til brugere, institutioner og sprogregistre. Med store dele af kliniske dokumenter i fritekst spiller NLP en stadig vigtigere rolle i at låse op for genanvendelig og interoperabel betydning fra medicinsk journal. Dette studie beskriver de arkitektoniske principper og udviklingen af et tysk grænseflade ordforråd, der kombinerer maskinoversættelse med menneskelig annotation og regelbaseret termgenerering, hvilket giver en ressource med 7,7 millioner rå poster, som hver er knyttet til referenceterminologien SNOMED CT, en international standard med omkring 350 tusind begreber. Formålet er at tilbyde en høj dækning af medicinsk jargon med henblik på at optimere terminologibasering af kliniske tekster ved hjælp af tekstmining systemer. Kerneressourcen er en manuelt kurateret tabel med engelsk-til-tysk ord og chunk oversættelser, understøttet af et sæt sproggenereringsregler. Arbejdet beskriver en arbejdsgang, der består i berigelse og ændring af denne tabel med menneskelige og maskinelle indsatser, manuelt beriget med grammatiske tags. Top-down og bottom-up metoder for terminologipopulation anvendt parallelt. De endelige grænsefladebehandlinger produceres af en termgenerator, som skaber en-til-mange tyske varianter pr. SNOMED CT engelsk beskrivelse. Filtrering mod en stor samling af domæneterminologier og corpora reducerer drastisk størrelsen af ordforrådet til fordel for mere realistiske termer eller termer, der med rimelighed kan forventes at matche</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>Медицинският език показва големи вариации по отношение на потребителите, институциите и езиковите регистри. С голяма част от клиничните документи в свободен текст, НЛП играе все по-важна роля в отключването на повторно използваемо и оперативно съвместимо значение от медицинските досиета. Това изследване описва архитектурните принципи и еволюцията на немски интерфейсен речник, съчетаващ машинен превод с човешка анотация и генериране на термини въз основа на правила, като дава ресурс с 7,7 милиона сурови записа, всеки от които е свързан с референтната терминология международен стандарт с около 350 хиляди понятия. Целта е да се предложи високо покритие на медицинския жаргон, за да се оптимизира терминологичното обосноване на клиничните текстове чрез системи за извличане на текстове. Основният ресурс е ръчно подбрана таблица с преводи от английски на немски думи и парчета, поддържана от набор от правила за генериране на езици. Работата описва работен процес, състоящ се от обогатяване и модифициране на тази таблица с човешки и машинни усилия, ръчно обогатени с граматични тагове. Методи отгоре надолу и отдолу нагоре за терминологична популация, използвани паралелно. Крайните интерфейсни термини се произвеждат от генератор на термини, който създава един към много немски варианти според описанието на английски език. Филтрирането спрямо голяма колекция от терминологии и корпуси на домейна драстично намалява размера на речника в полза на по-реалистични термини или термини, които може разумно да се очаква да съвпадат</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Medische taal vertoont grote variaties met betrekking tot gebruikers, instellingen en taalregisters. Met grote delen van klinische documenten in vrije tekst speelt NLP een steeds belangrijkere rol in het ontsluiten van herbruikbare en interoperabele betekenis uit medische dossiers. Deze studie beschrijft de architectonische principes en de evolutie van een Duitse interface woordenschat, waarbij machinevertaling gecombineerd wordt met menselijke annotatie en regelgebaseerde termgeneratie, resulteert in een bron met 7,7 miljoen ruwe vermeldingen, die elk gekoppeld zijn aan de referentieterminologie SNOMED CT, een internationale standaard met ongeveer 350 duizend concepten. Het doel is een hoge dekking van medisch jargon te bieden om de terminologische grondslag van klinische teksten door text mining systemen te optimaliseren. De kernbron is een handmatig samengestelde tabel met Engels-naar-Duits woord- en chunk-vertalingen, ondersteund door een reeks regels voor het genereren van talen. Het werk beschrijft een workflow bestaande uit de verrijking en aanpassing van deze tabel met menselijke en machineinspanningen, handmatig verrijkt met grammatica-specifieke tags. Top-down en bottom-up methoden voor terminologiepopulatie die parallel worden gebruikt. De definitieve interfacetermen worden geproduceerd door een termgenerator, die één-op-vele Duitse varianten creëert per SNOMED CT Engelse beschrijving. Filteren tegen een grote verzameling domeinterminologieën en corpora vermindert drastisch de omvang van de woordenschat ten gunste van realistischere termen of termen die redelijker kunnen worden verwacht</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Medicinski jezik pokazuje velike razlike u vezi korisnika, institucija i jezičkih registrija. S velikim dijelovima kliničkih dokumenta u slobodnom tekstu, NLP igra važniju ulogu u otključanju ponovno korištenog i interoperabilnog značenja iz medicinskih zapisa. U ovom ispitivanju opisuju arhitekturne principe i evoluciju njemačkog ročnika interfejsa, kombinirajući prevod strojeva s ljudskim annotacijom i određenim izrazom na pravilima, pružajući resursu sa 7,7 milijuna sirovih ulaza, svaki od kojih je povezan s referentnim terminologijom SNOMED CT, međunarodnim standardom s oko 350 tisuća koncepta. Svrha je ponuditi visoko pokrivanje medicinskog žargona kako bi optimizirali terminologiju osnova kliničkih tekstova tekstskim rudarskim sustavima. Glavni resurs je ručno korišteni stol riječi engleskog do njemačkog riječi i prevoda komada, podržavan skupom pravila generacije jezika. Rad opisuje radni tok koji se sastoji od bogatstva i modifikacije ovog stola s ljudskim i strojnim naporima, ručno bogatim gramatičkim znakovima. Najgore i donje gore metode za populaciju terminologije koji se koristi paralelno. Posljednji termini interfejsa proizvode je termin generator, koji stvara jednu do mnoge njemačke variante po opisu SNOMED CT engleskog jezika. Filtriranje protiv velike kolekcije terminologija domena i korporacije drastično smanjuje veličinu riječnika u korist realnijih uvjeta ili uvjeta koje se može razumno očekivati odgovarati</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_ko>의학 언어는 사용자, 기구와 언어 영역에서 커다란 차이를 보인다.대량의 임상 문서가 자유 텍스트 형식으로 등장함에 따라 NLP는 병력에서 중복 사용과 상호작용의 의미를 방출하는 데 점점 중요한 역할을 발휘하고 있다.이 연구는 독일어 인터페이스 어휘의 체계적 구조 원리와 변화를 묘사하고 기계 번역과 인공 주석과 규칙을 바탕으로 하는 용어 생성을 결합시켜 770만 개의 원시 항목을 포함하는 자원을 형성했다. 각 항목은 참고 용어인 SNOMED CT와 관련이 있고 SNOMED CT는 약 35만 개의 개념을 포함하는 국제 표준이다.그 목적은 의학 용어의 높은 범위율을 제공하여 텍스트 발굴 시스템을 통해 임상 텍스트의 용어 기초를 최적화시키는 것이다.핵심 자원은 수동으로 정리된 영어부터 독일어 단어와 블록 번역표로 언어 생성 규칙이 지원된다.이 작업은 인공과 기계의 노력을 통해 이 표를 풍부하게 수정하고 문법의 특정한 표기를 통해 수동적으로 풍부하게 하는 작업 흐름을 묘사했다.위에서 아래로의 용어 충전 방법을 병행하여 사용하다.최종 인터페이스 용어는 SNOMED CT 영문 설명에 따라 하나 이상의 독일어 변형을 만드는 용어 생성기로 생성됩니다.대량의 영역 용어와 어료 라이브러리를 필터링하여 어휘의 크기를 크게 줄이고 더욱 현실적인 용어나 합리적으로 일치하는 용어를 사용하는 데 유리하다</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>زبان پزشکی تغییرات بزرگی در مورد کاربران، موسسات و ثبت زبان نشان می دهد. با بخش‌های بزرگ از مدارک کلینیک در متن آزاد، NLP نقش مهم‌تر و مهم‌تر در باز کردن معنی استفاده‌کننده‌ای از ثبت پزشکی است. این مطالعه اصولات معماری و تکامل کلمات ارتباط آلمانی را توصیف می‌کند، ترجمه ماشین با نویسندگی انسان و نسل‌های اصلی بر قوانین، منبعی را با 7.7 میلیون وارد خالی می‌دهد، هر کدام از آن با ترمینالوژی متصل SNOMED CT، استاندارد بین المللی با حدود 350 هزار فرض است. هدف این است که یک پوشش بالا از جارگان پزشکی را پیشنهاد کنیم تا پایگاه ترمینالوژی از متن کلینیکی را با سیستم مصنوعی متن بهترین کند. منابع اصلی یک میز کلمه انگلیسی به آلمانی و ترجمه‌های قطعی است که توسط مجموعه قوانین نسل زبانی پشتیبانی می‌شود. این کار یک جریان کاری را توصیف می‌کند که با تلاش انسان و ماشین، با برچسب‌های ویژه‌ای به دستی ثروت می‌کند. روش پایین و پایین پایین برای جمعیت ترمینالوژی که در موازی استفاده می‌شود. شرایط نهایی مرتبط توسط یک ژنراتور ترمیم تولید می‌شود، که در هر توصیف انگلیسی SNOMED CT یک تا بسیار متغیر آلمانی تولید می‌کند. Filtering against a large collection of domain terminology and corpora drastically reduces the size of the vocabulary in favour of more realistic terms or terms that can reasonably be expected to match</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Lugha ya kitabibu inaonyesha tofauti kubwa kuhusu watumiaji, taasisi na waandishi wa lugha. Wakati sehemu kubwa ya nyaraka za kliniki katika maandishi huru, NLP inacheza jukumu kubwa zaidi na muhimu zaidi katika kufungia maana ya kutumia tena na yasiyo na maana yanayofaa kutokana na rekodi za kitabibu. Utafiti huu unaelezea kanuni za ujenzi na mabadiliko ya lugha ya lugha ya Mjerumani, ikiunganisha tafsiri ya mashine kwa ajili ya matangazo ya binadamu na kizazi cha muhula wa utawala, na kusababisha rasilimali yenye viwanja vya mafuta milioni 7.7, ambavyo kila mmoja aliunganishwa na utambulisho wa kimataifa wa SNOMED CT, kiwango cha kimataifa kinachofikiri takriban mitazamo 350,000. Lengo ni kutoa habari kubwa za jarida la afya ili kupata matumaini makundi ya utambulisho wa maandishi ya kliniki kwa mfumo wa madini ya madini. rasilimali muhimu ni meza iliyopo mikononi ya neno la Kiingereza-hadi Ujerumani na tafsiri nyingi, zinazoungwa mkono na kanuni za kizazi cha lugha. Kazi hiyo inaelezea mbinu za kazi zinazojumuisha utajiri na mabadiliko ya meza hii kwa juhudi za binadamu na mashine, zilizotajiriwa kwa manufaa na viungo maalumu. Njia za juu na chini za chini kwa ajili ya watu wa tatizo zinazotumiwa kwa usambazaji. Mpango wa mwisho wa mahusiano yanatengenezwa na mtengenezaji wa muhula, ambao unatengeneza tofauti moja hadi nyingi za Kijerumani kwa maelezo ya Kiingereza ya SNOMED CT. Uchunguzi dhidi ya mkusanyiko mkubwa wa maadhimili ya ndani na makampuni yanapunguza ukubwa wa lugha kwa faida ya vipengele vya ukweli au vipengele vinavyotarajiwa kulingana na vizuri</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Lukmançy dil ullançylar, kurumlar we dil rejimeleri barada örän üýtgeşmeleri görünýär. Özgür metin içinde klinik senediň uly bölegi bilen, NLP täzeden ullanýan we işleýbilýän näme üçin has möhüm roli oýnaýar. Bu arhitekturylyk prinsiplerini we Alman interfejs sözleriniň evolusiýasyny tassyýar, maşynyň terjimesini adamlaryň ýagşyrymy we düzgün döredilmesi bilen birleştirilýär, 7.7 milliýon setir girişi bilen jemgyýet berilýär, her biri 350 müňe golaý düşünjä baglanýar. Meýdança, mekdepler ahyrlama sistemalary tarapyndan kliniki metinlerin ýerini optimizlemek üçin lukmanyň ýokary gabdalygy üýtgetmekdir. Esasy çeşmeler, iňlisçe-we-nemesçe sözleriniň üstine ýazylýan täblisidir. Diller döredilmeler üçin arkalanýar. Çalışmak üçin bu täblisiň zenginleşigi we üýtgetmegini adam we maşynyň çabalary bilen, gramatik tägleri bilen el baglanýar. Üst-aşak we aşak-aşak ýüze parallel işledilen terminologiýa ilatyny üçin Soňky interface şartlary SNOMED CT Iňlisçe waspyna görä bir termyn döredicisi tarapyndan üretilýär. Bir domeny terminologilerine ve korporatyň büyük bir koleksiyona karşı filtrelemek sözlerin ölçüsini daha gerçek şartlar we şartlar üçin düzgün bir şekilde eşleşebilir</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_hy>Բժշկական լեզուն ցույց է տալիս մեծ տարբերություններ օգտագործողների, հաստատությունների և լեզվի ռեստորանների վերաբերյալ: Անվճար տեքստում գտնվող կլինիկական փաստաթղթերի մեծ մասերի միջոցով, ՆԼՊ-ն ավելի ու ավելի կարևոր դեր է խաղում բժշկական փաստաթղթերի վերաօգտագործելի և փոխգործելի իմաստի բացահայտում: Այս ուսումնասիրությունը նկարագրում է ճարտարապետական սկզբունքները և գերմանացի ինտերֆեյսի բառարանի էվոլյուցիան, որը համադրում է մեքենային թարգմանությունը մարդկային նոտացիայի հետ և կանոններով հիմնված տերմինների ստեղծման հետ, և տալիս է ռեսուրսներ 7.7 միլիոն ապրանք, որոնցից յուրաքանչյուրը կապված է հանդի Նպատակը բժշկական ժարգոնի բարձր ծածկումն է, որպեսզի լավատեսենք կլինիկական տերմինոլոգիաների հիմքը տեքստի հանքային համակարգերի միջոցով: Հիմնական ռեսուրսը անգլերեն-գերմանացի բառերի և մասերի թարգմանությունների ձեռքով կառավարվող աղյուսակ է, որը աջակցում է լեզվի ստեղծման կանոնների մի շարք կողմից: Աշխատանքը նկարագրում է աշխատանքի հոսքը, որը կազմում է այս աղյուսակի հարստացումը և փոփոխությունը մարդկային և մեքենային ջանքերի միջոցով, ձեռքով հարստացված գրամային հատուկ նշաններով: Տերմինոլոգիական բնակչության վերևի և վերևի մեթոդները, որոնք օգտագործվում են զուգահեռ: Վերջին ինտերֆեյսի տերմինները արտադրվում են տերմին գեներատոր, որը ստեղծում է մեկ-շատերը գերմանացի տարբերակներ, ըստ ՍՆOMED CT անգլերենի նկարագրության: Ֆիլտրելը տիեզերական տերմինոլոգիաների և կառուցվածքի մեծ հավաքածուի դեմ խիստ նվազեցնում է բառարանի չափը ավելի իրական տերմինների կամ տերմինների օգնությամբ, որոնք կարելի է բացատրել, որ համապատասխանեն</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_af>Mediese taal vertoon groot veranderinge aangaande gebruikers, instellings en taalsregistre. Met groot dele van kliniske dokumente in vry teks speel NLP 'n meer en meer belangrik rol in die ontsluit van hergebruikbare en interoperaabele betekening van mediese rekorde. Hierdie studie beskrywe die arkitektuur prinsipels en die evolusie van 'n Duitse koppelvlak woordeboek, saam met masjien vertaling met menslike annotasie en reëlbaseerde term generasie, wat 'n hulpbron met 7.7 miljoen rooi inskrywings vergeet, elkeen van die verwysing terminologie SNOMED CT,  'n internasionale standaard met omtrent 350 duisend konsepte. Die doel is om 'n hoë dekking van mediese jargon te bring om terminologie grond van kliniske teks te optimaliseer deur teks mining stelsels. Die kern hulpbron is 'n handgewys tabel van Engels- na- Duitse woord en blok vertalings, ondersteun deur 'n stel taal generasie reëls. Die werk beskryf 'n werksvloei wat die verrykking en verandering van hierdie tabel bestaan met menslike en masjienversoekte, hand verryk deur grammarspesifieke etikette. Bo- onder- en onder- op-metodes vir terminologie bevolking gebruik in parallele. Die eindelike koppelvlak terme word uitgevoer deur 'n term genereerder, wat skep een na- veel Duitse variante per SNOMED CT Engels beskrywing. Filtering teen 'n groot versameling van domein terminologies en korpora drastiese verduur die grootte van die woordeboek in guns van meer realistiese bedrywe of bedrywe wat redelik verwag word om ooreenstem te word</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Gjuha mjekësore shfaq ndryshime të mëdha lidhur me përdoruesit, institucionet dhe regjistrat e gjuhës. Me pjesë të mëdha të dokumenteve klinike në tekst të lirë, NLP po luan një rol gjithnjë e më të rëndësishëm në hapjen e kuptimeve të përdorueshme dhe interoperable nga regjistrimet mjekësore. Ky studim përshkruan parimet arkitekturale dhe evolucionin e një fjalorini të interfaqes gjermane, duke kombinuar përkthimin e makinave me anotacionin njerëzor dhe gjenerimin e termave bazuar në rregulla, duke dhënë një burim me 7.7 milion hyrje të papërpunuara, secila prej të cilave lidhet me terminologjinë e referimit SNOMED CT, një standard ndërkombëtar me rreth 350 mijë koncepte. The purpose is to offer a high coverage of medical jargon in order to optimise terminology grounding of clinical texts by text mining systems.  Burimi thelbësor është një tabelë e kuruar manualisht me fjalë angleze-gjermane dhe përkthime copash, mbështetur nga një sërë rregullash të gjenerimit të gjuhës. Puna përshkruan një rrjedhë pune që përbëhet nga pasurimi dhe modifikimi i kësaj tabele me përpjekje njerëzore dhe makinash, të pasuruar manualisht me etiketa grammarspecifike. Metodat lart poshtë dhe poshtë lart për popullsinë terminologjike të përdorura në paralel. Termet e interfaqes përfundimtare prodhohen nga një gjenerator termi, i cili krijon një-në-shumë variante gjermane për përshkrimin anglez SNOMED CT. Filtruar kundër një koleksioni të madh terminologjish të dominit dhe korpra redukton drastikisht madhësinë e fjalorin në favor të termave apo termave më realiste që mund të pritet arsyesisht të përputhen</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>ጥምቀት ቋንቋ በተጠቃሚዎች፣ አካባቢዎች እና ቋንቋዎች መጻሕፍት ላይ ብዙ መለያየት ያሳያል፡፡ With large parts of clinical documents in free text, NLP is playing a more and more important role in unlocking re-usable and interoperable meaning from medical records.  ይህ ትምህርት የጀርመን አካባቢ ሕግ እና የጀርመን የፊደል ቋንቋ ቋንቋ አካባቢ እና የመኪና ትርጉም ትርጉም በሰው ማሳየት እና የሥርዓት ትውልድ ትውልድ ጋር በመቀላቀል ይናገራል፡፡ ጉዳዩ የቴክኖሎጂ ጽሑፎችን በጽሑፍ ማውጣት ስርዓት መክፈቻን ለማድረግ የድምፅ ማውጣት ነው፡፡ የቋንቋ ትውልድ ሕግ የተደገመ የንግግሊዝና-ጀርመን ቃላት እና የቋንቋ ትርጓሜዎች እና የተጠቃሚ ትርጉም ነው፡፡ ይህ ሥራ በሰው እና የመሳሳይ ድጋፍ በተመሳሳይ ተሟጋቾች በኃይል ባለጠጎች እና በሀብት የሥራ ፈሳሾችን የሚያሳውቀው ነው፡፡ በተለያዩ ውስጥ ለሚጠቀሙት የቲርኖሎጂ አካባቢዎች የመጨረሻው የፊደል ግንኙነት በ SNOMED CT ኢንጂልኛ ግንኙነት አንዲት ጀርመን ለብዙዎች የጀርመን መለያየት የሚያደርገው የቁጥጥር አዋጅ ነው፡፡ የዶሜን ተርሚኖሎጂ እና ኮርፖርት በሚያሳየው በአካባቢው ግንኙነት ወይም በተመሳሳይ ይታሰል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_id>Bahasa medis menunjukkan variasi besar mengenai pengguna, institusi dan daftar bahasa. Dengan bagian besar dari dokumen klinis dalam teks gratis, NLP bermain peran yang semakin penting dalam membuka arti yang dapat digunakan kembali dan interoperabel dari catatan medis. Studi ini menggambarkan prinsip arsitektur dan evolusi vokabular antarmuka Jerman, menggabungkan terjemahan mesin dengan anotasi manusia dan generasi term a berdasarkan aturan, memberikan sumber daya dengan 7,7 juta entri mentah, masing-masing terhubung dengan terminologi referensi SNOMED CT, standar internasional dengan sekitar 350 ribu konsep. Tujuan adalah untuk menawarkan penutupan tinggi jargon medis untuk optimisasi terminologi dasar teks klinis oleh sistem penambangan teks. The core resource is a manually curated table of English-to-German word and chunk translations, supported by a set of language generation rules.  Pekerjaan menggambarkan aliran kerja yang terdiri dari memperkaya dan modifikasi tabel ini dengan usaha manusia dan mesin, secara manual memperkaya dengan tag grammarspecific. Metode dari atas ke bawah dan dari bawah ke atas untuk populasi terminologi digunakan secara paralel. Terma antarmuka terakhir diproduksi oleh generator term a, yang menciptakan satu-ke-banyak varian Jerman per deskripsi bahasa Inggris CT SNOMED. Penapis terhadap koleksi besar dari terminologi domain dan corpora secara drastis mengurangi ukuran vokabular untuk istilah atau istilah yang lebih realistis yang mungkin diharapkan untuk cocok</abstract_id>
      <abstract_bn>মেডিকেল ভাষা ব্যবহারকারী , প্রতিষ্ঠান এবং ভাষা নিবন্ধনের ব্যাপারে বিশাল ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন মুক্ত টেক্সটের বিশাল ক্লিনিকিন্যাল ডকুমেন্টের সাথে এনএলপি আরো গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভূমিকা খেলেছে চিকিৎসা রেকর্ড থেকে পুনরা এই গবেষণাটি জার্মানের ইন্টারফেসের শব্দভাণ্ডারের প্রতিষ্ঠান নীতি এবং বিবর্তনের বিষয়টি বর্ণনা করে, মানুষের মন্তব্য এবং শাসনের ভিত্তিক মেশিন অনুবাদের সাথে একত্রিত করে, যা ৭. ৭ মিলিয়ন রূপ প প্রবেশ এর উদ্দেশ্য হচ্ছে মেডিকেল জ্যার্গুনের উচ্চ কাভারেজ প্রদান করার জন্য যাতে টার্মিনোলজি গ্রুউন্ডিং টেক্সটের মাধ্যমে টেক মূল সম্পদ হচ্ছে ইংরেজি থেকে জার্মান শব্দ এবং ভাষা প্রজন্মের নিয়ম দ্বারা সমর্থন করা হয়েছে। এই কাজের ব্যাখ্যা হচ্ছে এই টেবিলের সমৃদ্ধ এবং পরিবর্তনের সাথে মানুষ এবং মেশিন প্রচেষ্টার মাধ্যমে একটি কার্যফ্লোয়ার বর্ণনা করা হয়েছ প্যারালেলে ব্যবহৃত টার্মিনোলজি জনসংখ্যার জন্য উপর-নীচে এবং নীচের-আপ পদ্ধতি। চূড়ান্ত মুখোমুখি শব্দগুলো একটি মেয়াদ জেনারেটর দ্বারা তৈরি করেছে, যা প্রতি SNOMED CT ইংরেজী বর্ণনায় এক-থেকে অনেক জা বিশাল ডোমেইন টার্মিনোলজির বিরুদ্ধে ফিল্টার করা হচ্ছে এবং কোর্পোরার বিরুদ্ধে শব্দভাণ্ডারের আকার কমে যাচ্ছে বাস্তবতা বা শর্তের পক্</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Təbbi dil istifadəçilər, qurbanlar və dil reģistrləri haqqında böyük dəyişiklikləri göstərir. Özgür metin içində kliniki belələrin böyük parçaları ilə, NLP yenidən istifadə edilə bilən və müxtəlif məsələləri təkrarlaşdırmaq üçün daha çox və daha önemli rol oynadır. Bu araşdırma arhitektür əslindlərini və Alman interfejs sözlərinin dəyişməsini təsdiqləyir. Makina çevirilməsini insan annotation və qayda-təsdiqləyici termin nəsili ilə birləşdirir, 7.7 milyon səviyyədə istifadə edir. Məqsəd məlumat məlumat madenci sistemləri ilə kliniki məlumatların tərzlərini optimizləmək üçün tıbbi dövrünün yüksək örtüsünü təbliğ etməkdir. Mərkəzi kaynağı, İngilizə-Almanca sözlərinin və dil ürəkləri kuralları ilə dəstəkləndirilən mərkəzdir. İş, bu masanın varlıqlarını və dəyişikliklərini insanlar və makinelərin çabaları ilə bəxş edir, qramma müəyyən etiketləri ilə əllə zenginləndirir. Üst aşağı və aşağı yüksək metodlar paralelə istifadə edilən terminoloji nümunələri üçün. SNOMED CT İngilizə tanımlamasına görə son interfejs şartları bir termin generatörü ilə ürəklənir. Büyük bir domena terminoloğu və korpora ilə filtrlənmək səhifələrinin böyüklüyünü daha realistik şəkillərə və şəkillərə layiqincə uyğulanan şəkillərə layiqincə azaldır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_cs>Lékařský jazyk vykazuje velké variace týkající se uživatelů, institucí a jazykových registrů. S velkou částí klinických dokumentů ve volném textu hraje NLP stále důležitější roli v odhalování opakovaně použitelného a interoperabilního významu z lékařských záznamů. Tato studie popisuje architektonické principy a vývoj německé slovní zásoby rozhraní, kombinující strojový překlad s lidskou anotací a generováním termínů založených na pravidlech, což přináší zdroj se 7,7 miliony surových záznamů, z nichž každá je spojena s referenční terminologií SNOMED CT, mezinárodním standardem s asi 350 tisíci konceptů. Cílem je nabídnout vysoké pokrytí lékařského žargonu s cílem optimalizovat terminologické zakotvení klinických textů pomocí textových miningových systémů. Hlavním zdrojem je ručně vytvořená tabulka překladů slov z angličtiny do německého jazyka a částic podporovaná sadou pravidel generování jazyků. Práce popisuje pracovní postup spočívající v obohacení a modifikaci této tabulky lidským a strojovým úsilím, ručně obohacený gramaticky specifickými tagy. Metody shora dolů a zdola nahoru pro současně používané terminologické populace. Konečné termíny rozhraní jsou vytvořeny pomocí generátoru termínů, který vytváří jednu až mnoho německých variant podle anglického popisu SNOMED CT. Filtrování proti velké sbírce doménových terminologií a korpusů drasticky snižuje velikost slovní zásoby ve prospěch realističtějších termínů nebo termínů, které lze rozumně očekávat, že budou odpovídat</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_bs>Medicinski jezik pokazuje velike razlike u vezi korisnika, institucija i jezičkih registrija. Sa velikim dijelovima kliničkih dokumenta u slobodnom tekstu, NLP igra važniju ulogu u otključanju ponovnog korištenja i interoperabilnog značenja iz medicinskih podataka. U ovom ispitivanju opisuju arhitekturne principe i evoluciju njemačkog rečnika interfejsa, kombinirajući prevod mašine sa ljudskim annotacijom i generacijom termina na pravilima, koji daje resurse sa 7,7 miliona sirovih ulaza, svaki od kojih je povezan s referentnim terminologom SNOMED CT, međunarodnim standardom s oko 350 tisuća koncepta. Svrha je ponuditi visoko pokrivanje medicinskog žargona kako bi optimalizirao terminologiju osnova kliničkih tekstova tekstskim rudarskim sustavima. Glavni resurs je ručno korišteni stol engleske na njemačke riječi i prevoda komada, podržavan skupom pravila generacije jezika. Rad opisuje radni tok koji se sastoji od bogatstva i modifikacije ovog stola sa ljudskim i strojnim naporima, ručno bogatim gramatičkim znakovima. Najgora i najgora metoda za populaciju terminologije korištenu paralelno. Konačni uslovi interfejsa proizvode termin generator, koji stvara jednu do mnoge njemačke variante po opisu SNOMED CT engleskog jezika. Filtriranje protiv velike kolekcije terminologija domena i korporacije drastično smanjuje veličinu riječnika u korist realnijih uslova ili uslova koje se mogu razumno očekivati da će odgovarati</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Meditsiinikeeles esineb suuri erinevusi kasutajate, asutuste ja keeleregistrite osas. Kuna kliinilistest dokumentidest on suur osa vabas tekstis, mängib NLP üha olulisemat rolli taaskasutatava ja koostalitlusvõimelise tähenduse avamisel meditsiinilistest toimikutest. Käesolev uuring kirjeldab saksa liidese sõnavara arhitektuurilisi põhimõtteid ja arengut, kombineerides masintõlke inimmärgistuse ja reeglipõhise terminite genereerimisega, andes ressursi 7,7 miljoni toorkirjega, millest igaüks on seotud viiteterminoloogiaga SNOMED CT, rahvusvahelise standardiga, millel on umbes 350 000 kontseptsiooni. Eesmärk on pakkuda meditsiinilise žargooni ulatuslikku katvust, et optimeerida kliiniliste tekstide terminoloogilist alust tekstikaevandussüsteemide abil. Põhiressurss on käsitsi kureeritud tabel inglise-saksa sõna- ja tükkide tõlketest, mida toetavad keele genereerimise reeglid. Töös kirjeldatakse töövoogu, mis hõlmab selle tabeli rikastamist ja modifitseerimist inim- ja masinajõupingutustega, mis on käsitsi rikastatud grammatikaspetsiifiliste siltidega. Paralleelselt kasutatavad terminoloogilise populatsiooni ülalt alla- ja alt-üles-meetodid. Lõplikud liidese tingimused on toodetud terminite generaatori poolt, mis loob ühe-mitme saksa variandi SNOMED CT inglise kirjelduse järgi. Paljude domeeniterminoloogiate ja korpuste filtreerimine vähendab oluliselt sõnavara suurust, kasutades realistlikumaid termineid või termineid, mida võib mõistlikult eeldada sobivaks</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Lääketieteellisessä kielessä on suuria eroja käyttäjien, laitosten ja kielirekistereiden suhteen. Koska suuri osa kliinisistä asiakirjoista on vapaana tekstinä, NLP:llä on yhä tärkeämpi rooli uudelleenkäytettävän ja yhteentoimivan merkityksen avaamisessa potilastiedoista. Tässä tutkimuksessa kuvataan saksalaisen käyttöliittymäsanaston arkkitehtonisia periaatteita ja kehitystä yhdistäen konekäännöksen inhimilliseen merkintään ja sääntöpohjaiseen termien generointiin, tuottaen resurssin, jossa on 7,7 miljoonaa raaka-ainetta, joista jokainen liittyy viiteterminologiaan SNOMED CT, joka on kansainvälinen standardi, jossa on noin 350 000 käsitettä. Tarkoituksena on tarjota lääketieteen jargonin laaja kattavuus, jotta kliinisten tekstien terminologia voidaan optimoida tekstinkäsittelyjärjestelmien avulla. Keskeinen resurssi on manuaalisesti kuratoitu taulukko englanti-saksa sana- ja palakäännöksistä, jota tukevat joukko kieliä. Työ kuvaa työnkulkua, joka koostuu taulukon rikastamisesta ja muokkaamisesta ihmisen ja koneen ponnisteluilla, jotka rikastetaan manuaalisesti kieliopikohtaisilla tunnisteilla. Rinnakkaisesti käytettävät termistöpopulaation ylhäältä alas- ja alhaalta ylös -menetelmät. Lopulliset käyttöliittymätermit tuotetaan termigeneraattorilla, joka luo yhden-moneen saksankielistä versiota SNOMED CT English -kuvauksen mukaan. Suodattaminen moniin verkkotunnuksen terminologioihin ja korpusiin vähentää huomattavasti sanaston kokoa ja suosii realistisempia termejä tai termejä, joiden voidaan kohtuudella olettaa vastaavan toisiaan</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>La llengua mèdica mostra grans variacions en relació amb usuaris, institucions i registres de llenguatges. Amb grans parts de documents clínics en text lliure, NLP està jugant un paper cada cop més important en desbloquejar el sentit reutilitzable i interoperable dels registres mèdics. Aquest estudi descriu els principis arquitectònics i l'evolució d'un vocabulari d'interfície alemanya, combinant traducció màquina amb anotació human a i generació de termes basats en regles, donant un recurso amb 7,7 milions d'entrades brutes, cada una vinculada a la terminologia de referència SNOMED CT, un estàndard internacional amb uns 350 mil conceptes. L'objectiu és oferir una gran cobertura d'jargons mèdics per optimitzar el fonament terminològic dels textos clínics pels sistemes miners de text. The core resource is a manually curated table of English-to-German word and chunk translations, supported by a set of language generation rules.  La feina descriu un flux de treball que consisteix en enriquecer i modificar aquesta taula amb esforços humans i màquines, enriqueguts manualment amb etiquetes gramàtiques específices. Métodes de dalt a baix i de baix a dalt per a la població terminològica utilitzats parallelament. Els termes finals d'interfície estan produïts per un generador de termes, que crea una a moltes variants alemanes per descripció anglesa SNOMED CT. Filtrar contra una gran col·lecció de terminologies de domini i corpora redueix drasticament la mida del vocabulari en favor de termes o termes més realistes que es pot raonablement esperar que coincidin</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_sk>Medicinski jezik kaže velike razlike glede uporabnikov, ustanov in jezikovnih registrov. Z velikimi deli kliničnih dokumentov v prostem besedilu ima NLP vedno pomembnejšo vlogo pri odklepanju ponovne uporabe in interoperabilnosti pomena iz zdravstvenih kartotek. Ta študija opisuje arhitekturna načela in razvoj nemškega vmesniškega besedišča, ki združuje strojno prevajanje s človeškimi opombami in generiranjem izrazov na podlagi pravil, kar prinaša vir s 7,7 milijona surovih vnosov, od katerih je vsak povezan z referenčno terminologijo SNOMED CT, mednarodnim standardom s približno 350 tisoč koncepti. Namen je zagotoviti visoko pokritost medicinskega žargona, da bi optimizirali terminološko utemeljitev kliničnih besedil s sistemi besedilnega rudarjenja. Osrednji vir je ročno urejena tabela prevodov besed in kosov angleščine v nemščino, ki jo podpira nabor pravil za ustvarjanje jezikov. Delo opisuje potek dela, ki vključuje obogatitev in modifikacijo te tabele s človeškimi in strojnimi napori, ročno obogatitev s slovničnimi oznakami. Metode od zgoraj navzdol in od spodaj navzgor za terminološko populacijo, ki se uporabljajo vzporedno. Končne izraze vmesnika izdeluje generator izrazov, ki ustvarja eno do več nemških različic po SNOMED CT angleškem opisu. Filtriranje glede na veliko zbirko domenskih terminologij in korpusov drastično zmanjšuje velikost besedišča v korist bolj realističnih izrazov ali izrazov, za katere se lahko razumno pričakuje, da se ujemajo
klinični besedilni odlomki znotraj cevovoda za iskanje besedila. Ocena je bila opravljena s primerjavo trenutne različice besedišča nemškega vmesnika in angleške opisne tabele izdaje SNOMED CT International. Natančno ujemanje izrazov je bilo opravljeno z majhnim vzporednim korpusom, sestavljenim iz odlomkov besedila iz različnih kliničnih dokumentov. S splošno nizkimi parametri pridobivanja (z vrednostmi F okoli 30%) zmogljivost nemškega jezika doseže 80–90% angleškega scenarija. Zanimivo je, da so opombe nekoliko boljše pri strojno prevedenih (nemško-angleško) besedilih, ki uporabljajo samo vir International SNOMED CT.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Basa sing resang maneh akeh pisan neng sampeyan gak bener, akeh-institusi lan registron langkung. Gambar barêng-barêng sing dibêngé dokumen klènik nang teks layar, NLP iso kelalah basa sing luwih akeh lan basa sing dikarepaké ora iso nggawe ngubah ketahanan pangan lan ujaran oleh operasi ning terakhir dhéwé. Ndhèwèké iki basa rakèh sabên kelompok arkhitektural karo evolusyon kelangan kelangan kelangan sampek, ngregani kelangan kelangan karo a éwan sing nganggep tanggal uwong karo perbudhakan lan jênêmêr. Hehing kanggo ngilanggar taung langgar sawar kuwi nggona, dadi kapan kanggo ngerasai tèknologi sing nyimpen kanggo ngwala sing basa banter, ingkang sistem sing ngregani Ressource Workspace Names Ngawe Terasai bukal sing dibutuhke kelompok nggo kelompok, sing sampek tanggal sampek butine Jagad sampek kang sampek butine Jagad sampek kanggo Kelangan Wang
text-box-mode Wang Perintah sing dibutuhke dipun Per kalaha kelas telu parameters (gambar) Iso ngenggo-ngenggo, dadi entuk sing luwih luwih apik karo gambar kelas telas telas telas (German - Inggris), gambar kelas usul NNOMED</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Lugha na madaidaici na nuna variant mai girma game da masu amfani da masu amfani da, asashi da shiryoyin harshe. game da yawa na takardun kwanan kwanan kwanan a cikin matsayin, NLP yana yin aiki na ƙaranci kuma mafi muhimu a cikin kuɓutar da amfani da yin amfani da shi na da fassarar aiki daga rekodin da za'a iya amfani da shi. Wannan littãfin yana bayyana rubutun da kwamfyutan maganar Jajeruman, mai haɗa fassarar maɓalli da kungiyar maganar mutane da danne-danne na rubutun, mai nuna wata resource da marubucin raw 7.7 millions, dukansu yana da muhalli na maganar tarminogi SNAMED AT, wata kimatarwa na da taki 300,000 zaɓen hanyoyi. Jigon ya so kawai, za'a bãyar da rufe rufe na jargon ɗin da aka yi amfani da, dõmin a yi amfani da cire-matsayi na rubutun na matsayi. @ info: whatsthis Yin aikin na bayyana wani shirin aiki wanda yana da rikitanci da gyare wa wannan tabar da aikin mutum da mashine, yana rikitacce da hannayen tagogi na grammarspecific. Top-down and bottom-up methods for terminology population used in parallel.  Tsarin interfece na samar da wata matsayi mai gabatar da shi, mai ƙiƙiro variants guda-zuwa-wasu jama'a kowace SNAMED AT ta Ingiriya. Fililin wa mai girma a haɗi taƙaitori na guda da koronata yana ƙara girmar maganar da aka faɓa wa tsarin da masu gaske ko ƙayyade masu yiwuwa wanda za'a iya ƙayyade shi da inganci
@ info: whatsthis An samar da wani evaluci na sami'a tsakanin version na yanzu na maganar jeruman da zanen faɗa ɗar Ingiriya na SNAMED ATANTA. An cika wani ƙayyade mai daidaita da wani nau'in rubutu mai ƙaranci da aka ƙididdige na rubutu daga takardun daraja daban. Ga da jumla da parameters masu iya ƙaranci (da F-value taki 30%), mai cikakken fasarin harshen Jamanci ya kai 80 - 90% na Ingiriya. Ina amfani da shi, zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane-zane ne mafi alhẽri a yi amfani da kimar Kimatar SNAMED'ar resource kawai.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>שפה רפואית מציגה שונות גדולות בנוגע למשתמשים, מוסדות ומרשומות שפות. עם חלקים גדולים של מסמכים קליניים בטקסט חינם, NLP משחק תפקיד חשוב יותר ויותר לפתוח משמעות חד-שימושית ומשתמשת מרשומות רפואיים. המחקר הזה מתאר את העקרונות הארכיטקטוניים והאבולוציה של מילון מידע ממשק גרמני, שילוב התרגום מכונת עם ציון אנושי ודור מונח מבוסס על חוקים, ומביא משאב עם 7.7 מיליון קובצים חומרים, שכל אחד מהם קשור לטרמונולוגיה התייחסות SNOMED CT, סטנדרט בינלאומי עם כ-350,000 מו המטרה היא להציע כיסוי גבוה של ג'ארגון רפואי כדי לאופטימום את הטרמונולוגיה של טקסטים קליניים על ידי מערכות מכרות טקסטים. המשאב העיקרי הוא שולחן משומר מילים אנגלית לגרמנית ומתומך על ידי קבוצת חוקי יוצר שפה. העבודה מתארת זרם עבודה שמכיל את העשיר והשינוי של השולחן הזה עם מאמץ אנושי ומכונה, מיושר ידנית על ידי תוויות גרמטיות ספציפיות. Top-down and bottom-up methods for terminology population used in parallel.  מונחי הממשך האחרונים יוצרים על ידי גנרטור מונחים, אשר יוצר שינויים גרמניים אחד עד רבים על פי תיאור אנגלי סי-טי SNOMED. הסנן נגד אוסף גדול של טמינולוגיות שטח וקופורה מופחה דרסטית את גודל המילים לטובת תנאים או תנאים יותר מציאותיים
מעברים טקסטים קליניים בתוך צינור מכרות טקסטים. הערכה נעשתה על ידי השוואה בין הגרסה הנוכחית של מילון המשקף הגרמני ולשולחן התיאור האנגלית של השחרור הבינלאומי של SNOMED CT. תואמת מונח מדויקת הופעה עם קורפוס מקביל קטן שנבנה על ידי חתיכות טקסט ממסמכים קליניים שונים. עם פרמטרים גבוהים של השיגה (עם ערכים F בסביבות 30%), ההופעה של תרחיש השפה הגרמנית מגיעה ל-80 - 90% מהאנגלית. מעניין, הערות הן קצת יותר טובות עם טקסטים מתרגמים במכונה (גרמנית - אנגלית), בשימוש במקור סי.טי.טי בינלאומי בלבד.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>སྨྲ་བའི་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་ནི་སྤྱོད་མཁན་དང་། སྒྲིག་འཛིན་དང་སྐད་རིགས་ཟིན་ཐོ་འགོད་མང་པོ་སྟོན་ཐུབ་པ རང་དབང་ཡིག་གི་ཡིག་གེ་ནང་སྡེབ་སྤྱོད་པའི་ཡིག་ཆ་ཆ་ཆེ་ཤོས་ཡོད་པས། NLP ནི་སྨན་ཐོག This study describes the architectural principles and the evolution of a German interface vocabulary, combining machine translation with human annotation and rule-based term generation, yielding a resource with 7.7 million raw entries, each of which linked to the reference terminology SNOMED CT, an international standard with about 350 thousand concepts. དམིགས་ཡུལ་ནི་ཕྱོགས་ཀྱི་གཟུགས་རིས་མཐོ་རིམ་པ་ཞིག་གི་འཇིག་རྟེན་འདི་ཆེ་རྐྱེན་བཟོ་བ་ཡིན། The core resource is a manual curated table of English-to-German words and chunk translations, supported by a set of language generation rules. ལས་ཀ་འདིས་རྩོལ་འཁོར་སྐྱོད་པ་ཞིག་གིས་མེད་པའི་གློག་རིམ་གྱི་ཆེ་རྐྱེན་དང་བཟོ་བཅོས་བྱེད་པའི་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ཉེན་ཁ Top-down and bottom-up methods for terminology population used in parallel. The final interface terms are produced by a term generator, which creates one-to-many German variants per SNOMED CT English description. Filtering against a large collection of domain terminologies and corpora drastically reduces the size of the vocabulary in favour of more realistic terms or terms that can reasonably be expected to match
གཏན་རིམ་གྱི་ཡིག་གེ་ཞིབ་ཀློག་འཇུག་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་གཏོང་ཁེལ་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། དབྱིན་ཡིག་གཟུགས་རིས་ཀྱི་ནང གནད་དོན་མིན་འདུག With overall low retrieval parameters (with F-values around 30%), the performance of the German language scenario reaches 80 – 90% of the English one. འདི་ལྟ་བུའི་བརྡ་སྟོན་ཚུལ་གཅིག་ཁག་ལས་མིན་འདུག</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Multilingual enrichment of disease biomedical ontologies</title>
      <author><first>Léo</first><last>Bouscarrat</last></author>
      <author><first>Antoine</first><last>Bonnefoy</last></author>
      <author><first>Cécile</first><last>Capponi</last></author>
      <author><first>Carlos</first><last>Ramisch</last></author>
      <pages>21–28</pages>
      <abstract>Translating biomedical ontologies is an important challenge, but doing it manually requires much time and money. We study the possibility to use open-source knowledge bases to translate biomedical ontologies. We focus on two aspects : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coverage_(telecommunication)">coverage</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quality_(business)">quality</a>. We look at the coverage of two biomedical ontologies focusing on diseases with respect to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikidata">Wikidata</a> for 9 European languages (Czech, Dutch, English, French, German, Italian, Polish, Portuguese and Spanish) for both, plus <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic">Arabic</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_language">Russian</a> for the second. We first use direct links between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikidata">Wikidata</a> and the studied <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ontology_(information_science)">ontologies</a> and then use second-order links by going through other intermediate ontologies. We then compare the quality of the translations obtained thanks to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikidata">Wikidata</a> with a commercial machine translation tool, here Google Cloud Translation.</abstract>
      <url hash="bcd74b95">2020.multilingualbio-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>bouscarrat-etal-2020-multilingual</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/euranova/orphanet_translation" additional="true">euranova/orphanet_translation</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Automated Processing of Multilingual Online News for the Monitoring of Animal Infectious Diseases</title>
      <author><first>Sarah</first><last>Valentin</last></author>
      <author><first>Renaud</first><last>Lancelot</last></author>
      <author><first>Mathieu</first><last>Roche</last></author>
      <pages>33–36</pages>
      <abstract>The Platform for Automated extraction of animal Disease Information from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web">web</a> (PADI-web) is an automated system which monitors the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web">web</a> for monitoring and detecting emerging animal infectious diseases. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tool</a> automatically collects news via customised multilingual queries, classifies them and extracts <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epidemiology">epidemiological information</a>. We detail the processing of multilingual online sources by PADI-web and analyse the translated outputs in a case study</abstract>
      <url hash="4ed57f23">2020.multilingualbio-1.6</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>valentin-etal-2020-automated</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>