<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.latechclfl">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the The 4th Joint SIGHUM Workshop on Computational Linguistics for Cultural Heritage, Social Sciences, Humanities and Literature</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Stefania</first><last>DeGaetano</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Kazantseva</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nils</first><last>Reiter</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Stan</first><last>Szpakowicz</last></editor>
      <publisher>International Committee on Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="3b16801f">2020.latechclfl-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>latechclfl-2020-joint</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Automatic Topological Field Identification in (Historical) German Texts<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>erman Texts</title>
      <author><first>Katrin</first><last>Ortmann</last></author>
      <pages>10–18</pages>
      <abstract>For the study of certain <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistics">linguistic phenomena</a> and their development over time, large amounts of textual data must be enriched with relevant <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotations</a>. Since the manual creation of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotations</a> requires a lot of effort, automating the process with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP methods</a> would be convenient. But the required amounts of training data are usually not available for non-standard or historical language. The present study investigates whether <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> trained on modern newspaper text can be used to automatically identify <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Topology">topological fields</a>, i.e. syntactic structures, in different modern and historical German texts. The evaluation shows that, in general, it is possible to transfer a parser model to other registers or time periods with overall F1-scores 92 %. However, an error analysis makes clear that additional rules and domain-specific training data would be beneficial if <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_(linguistics)">sentence structures</a> differ significantly from the training data, e.g. in the case of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Early_New_High_German">Early New High German</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="199e90f9">2020.latechclfl-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>ortmann-2020-automatic</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/rubcompling/latech2020" additional="false">rubcompling/latech2020</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Neural Machine Translation of Artwork Titles Using Iconclass Codes</title>
      <author><first>Nikolay</first><last>Banar</last></author>
      <author><first>Walter</first><last>Daelemans</last></author>
      <author><first>Mike</first><last>Kestemont</last></author>
      <pages>42–51</pages>
      <abstract>We investigate the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iconclass">Iconclass</a> in the context of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_machine_translation">neural machine translation</a> for NL-EN artwork titles. Iconclass is a widely used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iconography">iconographic classification system</a> used in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cultural_heritage">cultural heritage domain</a> to describe and retrieve subjects represented in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_arts">visual arts</a>. The resource contains keywords and definitions to encode the presence of objects, people, events and ideas depicted in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Work_of_art">artworks</a>, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Painting">paintings</a>. We propose a simple concatenation approach that improves the quality of automatically generated title translations for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Work_of_art">artworks</a>, by leveraging textual information extracted from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iconclass">Iconclass</a>. Our results demonstrate that a neural machine translation system is able to exploit this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata">metadata</a> to boost the translation performance of artwork titles. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technology">technology</a> enables interesting applications of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning</a> in resource-scarce domains in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture">cultural sector</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="f06236e9">2020.latechclfl-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>banar-etal-2020-neural</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Vital Records : Uncover the past from historical handwritten records</title>
      <author><first>Herve</first><last>Dejean</last></author>
      <author><first>Jean-Luc</first><last>Meunier</last></author>
      <pages>69–73</pages>
      <abstract>We present Vital Records, a demonstrator based on deep-learning approaches to handwritten-text recognition, table processing and information extraction, which enables data from century-old documents to be parsed and analysed, making it possible to explore death records in space and time. This demonstrator provides a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_interface">user interface</a> for browsing and visualising data extracted from 80,000 handwritten pages of tabular data.</abstract>
      <url hash="f55170c3">2020.latechclfl-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>dejean-meunier-2020-vital</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Registros Vitais: Descubra o passado a partir de registros manuscritos históricos</title_pt>
      <title_es>Registros vitales: descubra el pasado de los registros históricos escritos a mano</title_es>
      <title_ar>السجلات الحيوية: كشف الماضي من السجلات التاريخية المكتوبة بخط اليد</title_ar>
      <title_ja>バイタルレコード：歴史的な手書きレコードから過去を明らかにする</title_ja>
      <title_zh>其要记:见于史记</title_zh>
      <title_hi>महत्वपूर्ण रिकॉर्ड: ऐतिहासिक हस्तलिखित रिकॉर्ड से अतीत को उजागर करें</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Taifid Beatha: Faigh an t-am atá thart ó thaifid stairiúla lámhscríofa</title_ga>
      <title_el>ζωτικά αρχεία: Αποκαλύψτε το παρελθόν από ιστορικά χειρόγραφα αρχεία</title_el>
      <title_ka>ცხოვრებული წიგნი: ისტორიური ხელის წიგნიდან გადახსნა</title_ka>
      <title_it>Vital Records: scopri il passato dai dischi storici scritti a mano</title_it>
      <title_hu>Vital Records: Fedezd fel a múltat a történelmi kézzel írt feljegyzésekből</title_hu>
      <title_lt>Vital Records: Uncover the past from historical handwritten records</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Rekod Vital: Buka masa lalu dari rekod tertulis tangan sejarah</title_ms>
      <title_kk>Жетілді жазулар:</title_kk>
      <title_ml>കഠിനമായ റെക്കോര്‍ഡുകള്‍: ചരിത്രത്തിലെ കൈഎഴുതിയ രേഖകളില്‍ നിന്നും കഴിഞ്ഞുപോയി മൂടുക</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Амьдралын бичлэг: Түүний гар бичигдсэн бичлэгээс өмнө нь</title_mn>
      <title_mk>Vital Records: Uncover the past from historical handwritten records</title_mk>
      <title_no>Vital opptak: Uncover the past from historical handwritten records</title_no>
      <title_ro>Înregistrări vitale: Descoperă trecutul din înregistrările istorice scrise de mână</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Vital Records: Otkrijte prošlost iz istorijskih rukopisa</title_sr>
      <title_so>Kutubaha sharafta ah: Ka qarin wixii hore oo ka soo qoran warqadaha taariikhda</title_so>
      <title_sv>Vital Records: Upptäck det förflutna från historiska handskrivna skivor</title_sv>
      <title_mt>Rekords Vitali: Żvela l-passat minn rekords storiċi miktuba bl-idejn</title_mt>
      <title_ta>சரியான பதிவுகள்:</title_ta>
      <title_pl>Vital Records: Odkryj przeszłość z historycznych ręcznie pisanych zapisów</title_pl>
      <title_si>Vital Records: අතිත්‍යාත්මක වාර්තාව ලියපු ලියාකාරයෙන් අතිත්‍යාත්මක වාර්තාව අවධානය කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_ur>تاریخی ہاتھ لکھی ہوئی رکوردوں سے پہلے چھپاؤ</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Muhim yozuvlar: past history handwritten records dan bekor qilish</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Vital Records: vạch trần quá khứ từ những ghi chép tay</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Vital Records: Ontdek het verleden van historische handgeschreven records</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Жизнени записи: Открийте миналото от исторически ръкописни записи</title_bg>
      <title_da>Vital Records: Afslør fortiden fra historiske håndskrevne optegnelser</title_da>
      <title_hr>Vital Records: Otkrijte prošlost iz povijesnih rukopisa</title_hr>
      <title_id>Rekaman Vital: Menjelaskan masa lalu dari rekaman tertulis tangan sejarah</title_id>
      <title_de>Vital Records: Enthüllen Sie die Vergangenheit aus historischen handschriftlichen Aufzeichnungen</title_de>
      <title_ko>생명기록: 역사 필기 기록에서 과거 발견</title_ko>
      <title_fa>ثبت‌نامه‌های زنده: گذشته را از ثبت‌نامه‌های تاریخی مخفی کنید</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Records Vibaya: Unafunguza historia kutoka kwenye rekodi za kihistoria zilizoandikwa</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Sayısal kayıtlar:Geçmişi el kayıtlarından uzaklaştır</title_tr>
      <title_af>Vital Opneem: Ondekk die verlede van historiese handskryfe opneem</title_af>
      <title_am>አጥፉ</title_am>
      <title_az>Yaxınlıq Kitabları</title_az>
      <title_bn>গুরুত্বপূর্ণ রেকর্ড: ঐতিহাসিক হ্যান্ডারলেখা রেকর্ড থেকে অতীতের আড়াল করা হবে</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Կենսական ձայնագրություններ. Անհայտել անցյալը պատմական ձեռքով գրված ձայնագրություններից</title_hy>
      <title_ca>Vital Records: Uncover the past from historical handwritten records</title_ca>
      <title_bs>Vital Records: Otkrijte prošlost iz istorijskih rukopisa</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Vital Records: Odkryjte minulost z historických ručně psaných záznamů</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Vital Records: Löydä menneisyys historiallisista käsinkirjoitetuista tallenteista</title_fi>
      <title_et>Vital Records: avasta minevik ajaloolistest käsitsi kirjutatud salvestistest</title_et>
      <title_sq>Rekordet Vitale: Zbulo të kaluarën nga regjistrimet historike të shkruara me dorë</title_sq>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>רשומות חיוניות: לחשוף את העבר מהרשומות היסטוריות כתבות יד</title_he>
      <title_sk>Vital Records: Odkrijte preteklost iz zgodovinskih ročno napisanih zapisov</title_sk>
      <title_jv>ReplyForward</title_jv>
      <title_bo>Vital Records: Uncover the past from historical handwritten records</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم Vital Records ، وهو متظاهر يعتمد على مناهج التعلم العميق للتعرف على النص المكتوب بخط اليد ومعالجة الجدول واستخراج المعلومات ، مما يتيح تحليل وتحليل البيانات من المستندات القديمة ، مما يجعل من الممكن استكشاف سجلات الموت في المكان والزمان . يوفر هذا المتظاهر واجهة مستخدم لتصفح وتصور البيانات المستخرجة من 80000 صفحة مكتوبة بخط اليد من البيانات الجدولية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_ja>私たちは、手書きテキスト認識、テーブル処理、情報抽出の深層学習アプローチに基づくデモンストレーターであるVital Recordsを発表します。これにより、百年前の文書からのデータを解析して分析することができ、空間と時間で死亡記録を探索することができます。このデモンストレーターは、80,000ページの手書きの表形式データから抽出されたデータを閲覧および視覚化するためのユーザーインターフェースを提供します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos o Vital Records, um demonstrador baseado em abordagens de deep learning para reconhecimento de texto manuscrito, processamento de tabelas e extração de informações, que permite analisar e analisar dados de documentos centenários, possibilitando explorar registros de óbitos no espaço e no tempo . Este demonstrador fornece uma interface de usuário para navegar e visualizar dados extraídos de 80.000 páginas manuscritas de dados tabulares.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos Vital Records, un demostrador basado en enfoques de aprendizaje profundo para el reconocimiento de texto escrito a mano, el procesamiento de tablas y la extracción de información, que permite analizar y analizar datos de documentos centenarios, lo que permite explorar los registros de defunción en el espacio y el tiempo. Este demostrador proporciona una interfaz de usuario para explorar y visualizar datos extraídos de 80 000 páginas manuscritas de datos tabulares.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_hi>हम महत्वपूर्ण रिकॉर्ड्स प्रस्तुत करते हैं, हस्तलिखित-पाठ मान्यता, तालिका प्रसंस्करण और सूचना निष्कर्षण के लिए गहरे सीखने के दृष्टिकोण के आधार पर एक प्रदर्शनकारी, जो सदी पुराने दस्तावेजों से डेटा को पार्स और विश्लेषण करने में सक्षम बनाता है, जिससे अंतरिक्ष और समय में मृत्यु रिकॉर्ड का पता लगाना संभव हो जाता है। यह प्रदर्शक सारणीबद्ध डेटा के 80,000 हस्तलिखित पृष्ठों से निकाले गए डेटा को ब्राउज़ करने और विज़ुअलाइज़ करने के लिए एक उपयोगकर्ता इंटरफ़ेस प्रदान करता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>吾示Vital Records,此深学之示器也,以手书识之,表格处息取之,使百年之文档数可得而解析析也,可以间索死亡。 此演示器供一用户界面,以览可视化从 80,000 手书表格数取之。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid i láthair Vital Records, taispeántóir atá bunaithe ar chur chuige domhainfhoghlama maidir le haithint lámhscríofa-téacs, próiseáil táblaí agus eastóscadh faisnéise, a ligeann do shonraí ó dhoiciméid céad bliain d'aois a pharsáil agus a anailísiú, rud a fhágann gur féidir taifid báis a iniúchadh i spás agus in am. . Soláthraíonn an taispeántóir seo comhéadan úsáideora chun sonraí a bhaintear as 80,000 leathanach lámhscríofa de shonraí táblaí a bhrabhsáil agus a léirshamhlú.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Bemutatjuk a Vital Records-t, amely a kézzel írt szövegfelismerés, a táblázatfeldolgozás és az információkinyerés mélytanulási megközelítésein alapul, amely lehetővé teszi az évszázados dokumentumok adatainak elemzését és elemzését, lehetővé téve a halálnyilvántartások térben és időben történő feltárását. Ez a demonstrátor felhasználói felületet biztosít 80 000 kézzel írt oldalból kinyert adatok böngészéséhez és megjelenítéséhez.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε μια επίδειξη βασισμένη σε προσεγγίσεις βαθιάς μάθησης για την αναγνώριση χειρόγραφου κειμένου, την επεξεργασία πινάκων και την εξαγωγή πληροφοριών, η οποία επιτρέπει την ανάλυση δεδομένων από έγγραφα αιώνων, καθιστώντας δυνατή την εξερεύνηση αρχείων θανάτου σε χώρο και χρόνο. Αυτή η επίδειξη παρέχει μια διεπαφή χρήστη για την περιήγηση και την απεικόνιση δεδομένων που εξάγονται από 80.000 χειρόγραφες σελίδες πινάκων δεδομένων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo Vital Records, un dimostratore basato su approcci di deep learning al riconoscimento del testo scritto a mano, all'elaborazione di tabelle e all'estrazione di informazioni, che consente di analizzare e analizzare i dati provenienti da documenti centenari, rendendo possibile esplorare i record di morte nello spazio e nel tempo. Questo dimostratore fornisce un'interfaccia utente per la navigazione e la visualizzazione dei dati estratti da 80.000 pagine manoscritte di dati tabulari.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ ვიყვანეთ Vital Records, დემონსტრატორი, რომელიც ძალიან სწავლის მიზეზებით ხელსაწერილი ტექსტის განაცნობის, ცხრილის პროცესი და ინფორმაციის ექსტრაქციის მიზეზებით, რომელიც უკეთესი წლის დოკუმენტების მო Name</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_mk>Ние ги претставуваме Виталните рекорди, демонстрант базиран на пристапи на длабоко учење за препознавање на рачно напишани тексти, обработување на маса и извлекување информации, што овозможува анализирање и анализирање на податоците од векови документи, овозможувајќи истражување на см Овој демонстрант обезбедува кориснички интерфејс за прелистување и визуелизација на податоци извадени од 80.000 рачно напишани страници на табуларни податоци.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami mempersembahkan Rekod Vital, demonstrator berdasarkan pendekatan belajar dalam untuk pengenalan teks tulis-tangan, pemprosesan jadual dan ekstraksi maklumat, yang membolehkan data dari dokumen abad-lama untuk dihapus dan dianalisis, membolehkan untuk mengeksplorasi rekod kematian dalam ruang dan masa. Name</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ആഴത്തില്‍ പഠിക്കുന്നതിന് അടിസ്ഥാനമായ ഒരു പ്രതികാരിയെ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. നൂറ്റാണ്ടുവയസ്സുള്ള രേഖകളില്‍ നിന്നും വിവരങ്ങള്‍ പാര്‍സ് ചെയ്യു ഈ പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്ന ഉപയോക്താവിന്റെ ഇന്റര്‍ഫെസ് നല്‍കുന്നു. 80,000 കൈഎഴുതിയ വിവരങ്ങളില്‍ നിന്നും എടുത്തുകൊണ്ട</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Бид Vital Records-г харуулж, гүн гүнзгий суралцах арга зам дээр гар бичсэн текст хүлээн зөвшөөрөх, ширээний үйлдвэрлэл болон мэдээллийн хэрэглэх арга зам дээр суралцаж байна. Энэ нь зууны үеийн баримтуудын мэдээллийг хуваалцаж, шинжилгээ хийх боломжтой.  Энэ үзүүлэгч нь 80,000 гар бичигдсэн өгөгдлийн хуудас хайрлах, дүрслэх өгөгдлийг ашиглах хэрэглэгчийн интерфейсийг хангадаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nippreżentaw Rekords Vitali, dimostrant ibbażat fuq approċċi ta’ tagħlim profond għar-rikonoxximent bil-miktub bl-idejn tat-test, l-ipproċessar tat-tabella u l-estrazzjoni tal-informazzjoni, li jippermetti li d-dejta minn dokumenti ta’ seklu tiġi analizzata u analizzata, u b’hekk ikun possibbli li jiġu esplorati rekords tal-mewt fl-ispazju u This demonstrator provides a user interface for browsing and visualising data extracted from 80,000 handwritten pages of tabular data.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_kk>Қол жазылған мәтінді анықтау, кестелерді өзгерту және мәліметті тарқатуға негізделген демонстраторды көрсетедік. Бұл ғасырдың ескі құжаттардың деректерін талдау және анализ ету мүмкіндігін мүмкіндік береді. Бұл демонстратор 80 000 қолмен жазылған кестелердің деректерін шолу және визуализациялау үшін пайдаланушының интерфейсін береді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer Vital Records, eit demonstrator basert på dype læringstilnærmingar til å gjenkjenne handskrivne tekst, tabellehandsaming og utpakke informasjon, som gjer at data frå århundre gamle dokument skal tolkast og analyserast, og gjer det mogleg å utforske dødsoppføringar i mellomrom og tid. Denne demonstrasjonen gjev eit brukargrensesnitt for å lesa og visualisera data ut frå 80 000 handskrivne sider av tabulatordata.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_lt>Mes pristatome gyvybinius įrašus, demonstratorių, grindžiamą gilaus mokymosi metodais, susijusiais su rankiniu teksto pripažinimu, stalo apdorojimu ir informacijos gavimu, kurie leidžia išanalizuoti ir išanalizuoti amžiaus dokumentų duomenis, kad būtų galima ištirti mirties įrašus erdvėje ir laike. Šis demonstratorius suteikia naudotojo sąsają, skirtą naršyti ir vizualizuoti duomenis, gautus iš 80 000 rankomis rašytų lentelės duomenų puslapių.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_si>අපි Vital Records ප්‍රදේශකයෙන්, ගොඩක් ඉගෙන ගන්න ප්‍රදේශකයෙන් අතිරික්ෂණය සඳහා අතිරික්ෂණය සඳහා අතිරික්ෂණය සහ තොරතුරු අතිරික්ෂණය සඳහා ප්‍රදේශකයෙන් දත්ත Name</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Waxaannu soo bandhignaynaa warqadaha galmada ah, demonstrate ku saleysan qaababka waxbarashada hoose-dheer, aqoonsashada qoraalka qoran, ka baaraandegista miiska iyo soo bixinta macluumaadka, kaas oo macluumaad ka heli kara dukumentiyada qarnigii hore in la koobi karo oo la baaraandegayo, waxaana ka dhigi karaa in lagu baaraandegayo warqadaha dhimashada ee wakhtiga iyo wakhtiga Muujinuhu wuxuu isticmaalka u fidiyaa baaraandegista iyo bandhigyada macluumaadka laga soo saaray 80,000 buugaagta lagu qoray macluumaadka caadiga ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar Vital Records, en demonstrator baserad på djupinlärningsmetoder för handskriven textigenkänning, databehandling och informationsutvinning, som gör det möjligt att tolka och analysera data från hundraåriga dokument, vilket gör det möjligt att utforska dödsregister i rum och tid. Denna demonstrator ger ett användargränssnitt för att bläddra och visualisera data som extraheras från 80 000 handskrivna sidor med tabelldata.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாங்கள் விகிதமான பதிவுகளை காண்பிக்கிறோம், ஆழமான கற்றுக்கொள்ளும் முறைகளை அடிப்படையில் சார்ந்த ஒரு பாகுபாட்டாளர், நூற்றாண்டாக இருந்த ஆவணங்களிலிருந்து தகவல்  இந்த காட்சியாளர் தனிப்பட்ட தரவுகளிலிருந்து 80,000 கையேட்டு பக்கங்களிலிருந்து வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட தகவலை உலாவுவதற்கான பயனர்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_pl>Przedstawiamy Vital Records, demonstrator oparty na podejściu głębokiego uczenia do rozpoznawania tekstu pisanego ręcznie, przetwarzania tabeli i ekstrakcji informacji, który umożliwia analizę danych z wiekowych dokumentów, umożliwiając badanie zapisów zgonu w przestrzeni i czasie. Ten demonstrator zapewnia interfejs użytkownika do przeglądania i wizualizacji danych pochodzących z 80.000 ręcznie pisanych stron danych tabelarnych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo Vital Records, demonstrator koji je baziran na dubokom učenju pristupima priznanju ručnog teksta, obradu stola i izvlačenju informacija, koji omogućava da podaci iz vekovih dokumenta budu analizirani i analizirani, omogućavajući istraživanje smrtnih ploča u svemiru i vremenu. Ovaj demonstrator pruža korisnički interfejs za pretraživanje i vizualizaciju podataka izvedenih iz 80.000 rukopisanih stranica tabularnih podataka.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ro>Vă prezentăm Vital Records, un demonstrator bazat pe abordări profunde de învățare a recunoașterii textelor scrise de mână, prelucrare a tabelului și extragere a informațiilor, care permite analizarea și analizarea datelor din documente vechi de secole, făcând posibilă explorarea înregistrărilor morții în spațiu și timp. Acest demonstrator oferă o interfață de utilizator pentru navigarea și vizualizarea datelor extrase din 80.000 de pagini scrise manual de date tabelare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_ur>ہم ایک دکھانے والی ریکورد کو پیش کریں گے، ایک دکھانے والی سیکھانے والی طریقے پر بنیاد رکھتا ہے جو ہاتھ لکھی ہوئی پیغام پہچان کرتی ہے، ٹیبل پرسس کرتی ہے اور معلومات اضافہ کرتی ہے، جسے قرن کے قدیمی دکھانے سے ڈاٹ کا اختلاف اور تحلیل کرنا اجازت دیتا ہے،  یہ دکھانے والے نے 80 000 ہاتھ لکھی صفحے سے استعمال کیے گئے تابلوری ڈیٹا کے لئے بروز کرنا اور تصویزی کرنا کے لئے کارساز انٹرنیفٹ پیدا کیا ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Biz yuqori o'rganish muvaffaqiyatlariga qo'llangan matnni aniqlash, jadvalni boshqarish va maʼlumotni ajratish imkoniyatini hozir qilamiz. Bu asrlar hujjatdagi maʼlumotni ajratish va analyzlashga imkoniyatli beradi. Vaqt va vaqtda o'rganish mumkin. Name</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi giới thiệu Vital Records, một demonstrater dựa trên các phương pháp nghiên cứu sâu về kỹ thuật nhận dạng chữ viết tay, xử lý bàn và moi thông tin, giúp dữ liệu từ những tài liệu cũ kỷ lục được phân tích, làm cho phép khám phá các dữ liệu tử trong không gian và thời gian. Bộ đo quỷ này cung cấp một giao diện người dùng để duyệt và hình dung dữ liệu chiết xuất từ 80,000, viết tay của dữ liệu tabilar.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме демонстрант, базиран на подходи за дълбоко обучение за разпознаване на ръкописни текстове, обработка на таблици и извличане на информация, който дава възможност данните от вековни документи да бъдат анализирани и анализирани, което дава възможност да се изследват записите на смърт в пространството и времето. Този демонстратор предоставя потребителски интерфейс за сърфиране и визуализация на данни, извлечени от 80 000 ръчно написани страници с таблични данни.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren Vital Records, een demonstrator gebaseerd op deep-learning benaderingen voor handgeschreven tekstherkenning, tabelverwerking en informatieextractie, waarmee gegevens uit eeuwenoude documenten kunnen worden geparseerd en geanalyseerd, waardoor het mogelijk is om overlijdensakten in ruimte en tijd te verkennen. Deze demonstrator biedt een gebruikersinterface voor het bladeren en visualiseren van gegevens uit 80.000 handgeschreven pagina's van tabelgegevens.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer Vital Records, en demonstrator baseret på dyb læring tilgang til håndskrevet tekst genkendelse, tabelbehandling og informationsudvinding, som gør det muligt at analysere og analysere data fra århundredegamle dokumenter, hvilket gør det muligt at udforske dødsoptegnelser i rum og tid. Denne demonstrator giver en brugergrænseflade til browsing og visualisering af data udvundet fra 80.000 håndskrevne sider med tabeldata.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Wir präsentieren Vital Records, einen Demonstrator, der auf Deep-Learning-Ansätzen zur handschriftlichen Texterkennung, Tabellenverarbeitung und Informationsextraktion basiert, mit dem Daten aus jahrhundertealten Dokumenten analysiert und analysiert werden können, um Todesakte in Raum und Zeit zu erforschen. Dieser Demonstrator bietet eine Benutzeroberfläche zum Durchsuchen und Visualisieren von Daten, die aus 80.000 handgeschriebenen Seiten tabellarischer Daten extrahiert wurden.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>We present Vital Records, a demonstrator based on deep-learning approaches to handwritten-text recognition, table processing and information extraction, which enables data from century-old documents to be parsed and analysed, making it possible to explore death records in space and time.  This demonstrator provides a user interface for browsing and visualising data extracted from 80,000 handwritten pages of tabular data.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>Vital Records는 100년 전 문서에서 나온 데이터를 손수 작성한 텍스트 인식, 표 처리, 정보 추출을 기반으로 한 딥러닝 방법의 데모기로서 공간과 시간에 걸쳐 사망 기록을 탐색할 수 있는 프레젠테이션입니다.이 프레젠테이션은 8만 페이지의 손으로 쓴 표 데이터에서 추출한 데이터를 조회하고 시각화하는 사용자 인터페이스를 제공합니다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_hr>Predstavljamo Vital Records, demonstrator koji se temelji na dubokom učenju pristupa priznanju ručno pisanog teksta, obradu stola i izvlačenju informacija, što omogućava analizirati i analizirati podatke iz stoljeća starih dokumenta, omogućavajući istraživanje smrtnih ploča u svemiru i vremenu. Ovaj demonstrator pruža korisnički interfejs za pretraživanje i vizualizaciju podataka izvučenih iz 80.000 rukopisanih stranica tabularnih podataka.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_tr>Biz Vital Kaynakları, derin öwrenmek üzere el yazısı tanımlama, täblik işleme ve bilgi çıkarma vasitçilerine dayanýarys. Bu yüzden geçen senediň analizi ve analizi edilmesini mümkin edip, uzayda we zamanda ölüm kaynaklarını keşfetmek mümkin edir. Bu demonstrator 80,000 el ýazylan maglumatyň taramasy we görkezilmesi üçin ullanýan ullançy interfejesini temin edýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_fa>ما نشان دهیم که یک نمایش‌کننده بر روی روش‌های یادگیری عمیق برای شناسایی متن‌نوشته‌شده‌اند، پردازش میز و اخراج اطلاعات، که می‌تواند داده‌ها از سند‌های قدیمی قرن را بررسی و تحلیل کند، و می‌تواند ثبت‌های مرگ را در فضا و زمان تحقیق کند. این نمایش‌کننده برای بررسی و تصویر داده‌هایی که از ۸۰ هزار صفحه‌های دستی نوشته شده‌اند از داده‌های تابلوی استفاده می‌کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaweza kuweka kumbukumbu za Vitali, mwandamanaji anayeishi kwenye njia za kujifunza kwa kina za kina za kutambua maandiko yanayoandikwa mikononi, upasuaji wa mezani na utoaji wa habari, ambazo inawezesha taarifa kutoka nyaraka za karne zilizopita kuchapishwa na kuchambuliwa, na kufanya uwezekano wa kuchunguza rekodi za vifo katika anga na wakati. Mwandamanaji huyu anatoa mtandao wa mtumiaji kwa ajili ya kutazama na kuonyesha taarifa zilizotolewa kutoka kurasa 80,000 zilizoandikwa mikononi ya taarifa za tabia.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք ներկայացնում ենք կենսական ձայնագրություններ, մի ցուցադրություն, որը հիմնված է ձեռքով գրված տեքստի ճանաչելու, աղյուսակի վերամշակման և տեղեկատվության վերացման խորը սովորելու մոտեցումների վրա, որը հնարավորություն է տալիս հարյուրավոր փաստաթղթերի տվյալները վերլուծել և վերլուծել, հնարավորություն Այս ցուցադրողը տրամադրում է օգտագործողի ինտերֆեյսը աղյուսակի տվյալների 80,000 ձեռքով գրված էջից ստացված տվյալների նայելու և տեսողացման համար:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>በሀይት ዘመን ጀምሮ ካሉት ሰነዶች ዳታዎችን ለመለፍ እና ለመረጃ እና ለማስተዋል የሚችል የጥልቅ ትምህርት፣ የጽሑፍ ማስታወቂያ፣ ገበታው ማቀናጃ እና የመረጃ ማውጣት የሚደረገውን ሰራዊት ሰነቶች ማሳየት እና ማረጃ እንዲችል እናደርጋለን፡፡ ይህ አዲስ አካባቢው ከ80,000 እጁን የተጻፈ የዳታ ገጾች ለመመቃኛ እና ለማሳየት የተጠቃሚ የኢንተርኔት интерфейсን ይሰጣል።</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim Rekordet Vitale, një demonstrues bazuar në metodat e mësimit të thellë për njohjen e tekstit të shkruar me dorë, procesimin e tavolinës dhe nxjerrjen e informacionit, që lejon të analizohen dhe analizohen të dhënat nga dokumentet e shekullit të vjetër, duke e bërë të mundur eksplorimin e regjistrimeve të vdekjes në hapësirë dhe kohë. Ky demonstrues ofron një interfaqe përdoruesi për shfletimin dhe vizualizimin e të dhënave të nxjerra nga 80,000 faqe të shkruara me dorë të të dhënave tabulare.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_af>Ons stel die Vital Records voor te stel, 'n demonstrasie gebaseer op diep-leer toegang tot handskryf-teks herken, tabel verwerking en inligting uittrekking, wat data van century-ou dokumente kan ontlees en analiseer word, maak dit moontlik om doodsopneem in spasie en tyd te ondersoek. Hierdie demonstrasie verskaf 'n gebruikerkoppelvlak vir blaai en visualisering van data uitgevoer van 80 000 handskryfde bladsye van tabulêre data.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_az>Biz Vital Records'i, əl yazılmış metin tanımlaması, masa işləməsi və məlumat çıxartması üçün dəlilik öyrənən bir göstəricisi göstəririk. Bu yüzyıl əvvəlkilərin məlumatlarını analiz və analiz edər, kosmos və zamanda ölüm kayıtlarını keşfetməsi mümkün edər. Bu göstəricisi 80.000 əl yazılmış səhifələrdən istifadəçi interfejsini təmin edir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা গুরুত্বপূর্ণ রেকর্ডকে উপস্থাপন করি, হাতে লেখা লেখা স্বীকৃতি এবং টেবিল প্রক্রিয়া এবং তথ্য বিস্তারিত প্রতিবাদকারী হাতে ভিত্তিক এক বিক্ষোভকারী প্রতিবাদকা এই বিক্ষোভকারীরা ট্যাবলিলাল ডাটা থেকে ৮০,০০০ হাতে বের করা তথ্য ব্যবহারকারী ইন্টারফেস দেখানোর জন্য ব্যবহারকারীর ইন্</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo Vital Records, demonstrator koji se temelji na dubokom učenju pristupa priznanju rukopisanog teksta, procesiranju stola i izvlačenju informacija, koji omogućava analizirati i analizirati podatke iz stoljeća starih dokumenta, omogućavajući istraživanje smrtnih ploča u svemiru i vremenu. Ovaj demonstrator pruža korisnički interfejs za pretraživanje i vizualizaciju podataka izvučenih iz 80.000 rukopisanih stranica tabularnih podataka.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Presentam Records Vitals, un demostrador basat en enfocaments d'aprenentatge profund en el reconeixement de textos escrits a mà, el processament de taules i l'extracció d'informació, que permet analitzar i analitzar les dades dels documents de segle i permet explorar els registres de mort en espai i temps. Aquest demostrador proporciona una interfície d'usuari per navegar i visualitzar les dades extraites de 80.000 pàgines manuscrites de dades tabulars.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme Vital Records, demonstrátor založený na hlubokém učení k rozpoznávání ručně psaného textu, zpracování tabulek a extrakci informací, který umožňuje analyzovat a analyzovat data z stoletých dokumentů a umožňuje tak prozkoumat záznamy úmrtí v prostoru a čase. Tento demonstrátor poskytuje uživatelské rozhraní pro procházení a vizualizaci dat extrahovaných z 80.000 ručně psaných stránek tabulkových dat.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Tutvustame sügavõppe käsitsi kirjutatud teksti tuvastamisele, tabelitöötlusele ja informatsiooni väljavõtmisele põhinevat demonstraatorit Vital Records, mis võimaldab sajandite vanuste dokumentide andmeid analüüsida ja analüüsida, võimaldades uurida surmakirjeid ruumis ja ajas. See demonstraator pakub kasutajaliidest andmete sirvimiseks ja visualiseerimiseks, mis on saadud 80 000 käsitsi kirjutatud tabelindmete lehelt.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esittelemme Vital Records -demonstraattorin, joka perustuu syvälliseen oppimiseen käsinkirjoitetun tekstin tunnistamiseen, taulukkokäsittelyyn ja tiedonpoimintaan, jonka avulla vuosisatoja vanhojen asiakirjojen dataa voidaan jäsentää ja analysoida, jolloin kuolemantietueita voidaan tutkia avaruudessa ja ajassa. Tämä demonstraattori tarjoaa käyttöliittymän 80 000 käsin kirjoitetusta taulukkodatasta poimittujen tietojen selaamiseen ja visualisointiin.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו מציגים רשומות חיוניות, מפגין מבוסס על גישות למידה עמוקה לזהות טקסט כתוב יד, עיבוד שולחן ומוציאת מידע, שמאפשר למחקר ונבחן נתונים ממסמכים שנתיים מאה, מה שאפשר לחקור רשומות מוות בחלל וזמן. המפגין הזה מספק ממשק משתמש לציור ויזואליזציה נתונים שנוצאים מ-80,000 עמודים כתבים יד של נתונים על לוח.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo Vital Records, demonstrator, ki temelji na pristopih globokega učenja k prepoznavanju ročno napisanega besedila, obdelavi tabel in pridobivanju informacij, ki omogoča razčlenitev in analizo podatkov iz stoletnih dokumentov, kar omogoča raziskovanje zapisov smrti v prostoru in času. Ta demonstrator zagotavlja uporabniški vmesnik za brskanje in vizualizacijo podatkov, pridobljenih iz 80.000 ročno napisanih strani tabelarnih podatkov.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna halatar da Takardan Kitalar, wani mai nuna da ke kan karatun masu ƙaranci a cikin littãfi na rubũtãwa, masu amfani da matsayin na rubutun rubũtãwa, da kuma masu zartar da zane-zane, wanda yana iya amfani da data daga takardun takardar farko na century, za'a yi parse da Ana yi, kuma yana iya samun karatun rekodin mutuwa cikin space da lokaci. Wannan shirin mai nuna yana da intafece wa mai amfani da wa'urar biraws da ake nuna data wanda aka fito daga kurasa 80,000 na hannayen da aka rubũta data na tabalin.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Kita gunakake Visal Reqs, daemonon sing basa supaya deep-Learning suku nggunakake manut, perusahaan langgambar lan extraksi informasi sing permisa data suku gadoh sing gadoh akeh dokumen sing bisa tarjamahan lan jeyane, iso nglanggar nglanggar pisar depiction Mbalasi iki bakal ngewehke sampeyan pengguna kanggo ngilanggar lan ngilanggar data mineng sa 60.000 sing ngaweh manut nang data tab</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>We present Vital Records, a demonstrator based on deep-learning approaches to handwritten-text recognition, table processing and information extraction, which enables data from century-old documents to be parsed and analysed, making it possible to explore death records in space and time. འཆར་སྟོན་པ་འདིས་ཤོག་བྱང་གི་ལག་ལེན་པའི་ངོས་འདྲ་བ་ལྟ་བཤེར་དང་མཐོང་ནུས་ཡིག་ཆ་གསར་བསྐྲུན་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Life still goes on : Analysing Australian WW1 Diaries through Distant Reading<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>ustralian <fixed-case>WW</fixed-case>1 Diaries through Distant Reading</title>
      <author><first>Ashley</first><last>Dennis-Henderson</last></author>
      <author><first>Matthew</first><last>Roughan</last></author>
      <author><first>Lewis</first><last>Mitchell</last></author>
      <author><first>Jonathan</first><last>Tuke</last></author>
      <pages>90–104</pages>
      <abstract>An increasing amount of historic data is now available in digital (text) formats. This gives quantitative researchers an opportunity to use distant reading techniques, as opposed to traditional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Close_reading">close reading</a>, in order to analyse larger quantities of historic data. Distant reading allows researchers to view overall patterns within the data and reduce researcher bias. One such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">data set</a> that has recently been transcribed is a collection of over 500 Australian World War I (WW1) diaries held by the State Library of New South Wales. Here we apply distant reading techniques to this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> to understand what soldiers wrote about and how they felt over the course of the war. Extracting dates accurately is important as it allows us to perform our analysis over time, however, it is very challenging due to the variety of date formats and abbreviations diarists use. But with that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a>, topic modelling and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> can then be applied to show trends, for instance, that despite the horrors of war, Australians in WW1 primarily wrote about their everyday routines and experiences. Our results detail some of the challenges likely to be encountered by quantitative researchers intending to analyse historical texts, and provide some approaches to these issues.</abstract>
      <url hash="0213c97c">2020.latechclfl-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>dennis-henderson-etal-2020-life</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Results of a Single Blind Literary Taste Test with Short Anonymized Novel Fragments</title>
      <author><first>Andreas</first><last>van Cranenburgh</last></author>
      <author><first>Corina</first><last>Koolen</last></author>
      <pages>121–126</pages>
      <abstract>It is an open question to what extent perceptions of literary quality are derived from text-intrinsic versus social factors. While supervised models can predict literary quality ratings from textual factors quite successfully, as shown in the Riddle of Literary Quality project (Koolen et al., 2020), this does not prove that social factors are not important, nor can we assume that readers make judgments on literary quality in the same way and based on the same information as machine learning models. We report the results of a pilot study to gauge the effect of textual features on literary ratings of Dutch-language novels by participants in a controlled experiment with 48 participants. In an exploratory analysis, we compare the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audience_measurement">ratings</a> to those from the large reader survey of the Riddle in which social factors were not excluded, and to machine learning predictions of those literary ratings. We find moderate to strong correlations of questionnaire ratings with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survey_methodology">survey ratings</a>, but the predictions are closer to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survey_methodology">survey ratings</a>. Code and data : https://github.com/andreasvc/litquest</abstract>
      <url hash="dfc08e87">2020.latechclfl-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>van-cranenburgh-koolen-2020-results</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/andreasvc/litquest" additional="false">andreasvc/litquest</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Interpretation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">Sentiment Analysis</a> in Aeschylus’s Greek Tragedy<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>reek Tragedy</title>
      <author><first>Vijaya Kumari</first><last>Yeruva</last></author>
      <author><first>Mayanka</first><last>ChandraShekar</last></author>
      <author><first>Yugyung</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Jeff</first><last>Rydberg-Cox</last></author>
      <author><first>Virginia</first><last>Blanton</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathan A</first><last>Oyler</last></author>
      <pages>138–146</pages>
      <abstract>Recent advancements in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning</a> have created unique challenges and opportunities for digital humanities research. In particular, there are ample opportunities for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> and machine learning researchers to analyze data from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Literature">literary texts</a> and to broaden our understanding of human sentiment in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greek_tragedy">classical Greek tragedy</a>. In this paper, we will explore the challenges and benefits from the human and machine collaboration for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greek_tragedy">Greek tragedy</a> and address some open questions related to the collaborative annotation for the sentiments in literary texts. We focus primarily on (i) an analysis of the challenges in sentiment analysis tasks for humans and machines, and (ii) whether consistent annotation results are generated from the multiple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">human annotators</a> and multiple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">machine annotators</a>. For human annotators, we have used a survey-based approach with about 60 college students. We have selected three popular sentiment analysis tools for machine annotators, including VADER, CoreNLP’s sentiment annotator, and TextBlob. We have conducted a qualitative and quantitative evaluation and confirmed our observations on sentiments in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greek_tragedy">Greek tragedy</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="c980bd19">2020.latechclfl-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>yeruva-etal-2020-interpretation</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>Finding and Generating a Missing Part for Story Completion</title>
      <author><first>Yusuke</first><last>Mori</last></author>
      <author><first>Hiroaki</first><last>Yamane</last></author>
      <author><first>Yusuke</first><last>Mukuta</last></author>
      <author><first>Tatsuya</first><last>Harada</last></author>
      <pages>156–166</pages>
      <abstract>Creating a story is difficult. Professional writers often experience a writer’s block. Thus, providing automatic support to writers is crucial but also challenging. Recently, in the field of generating and understanding stories, story completion (SC) has been proposed as a method for generating missing parts of an incomplete story. Despite this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a>’s usefulness in providing creative support, its applicability is currently limited because it requires the user to have prior knowledge of the missing part of a story. Writers do not always know which part of their writing is flawed. To overcome this problem, we propose a novel approach called missing position prediction (MPP). Given an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unfinished_creative_work">incomplete story</a>, we aim to predict the position of the missing part. We also propose a novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_method">method</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mean_time_between_failures">MPP</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mean_time_between_failures">SC</a>. We first conduct an experiment focusing on MPP, and our analysis shows that highly accurate predictions can be obtained when the missing part of a story is the beginning or the end. This suggests that if a story has a specific beginning or end, they play significant roles. We conduct an experiment on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Small_interfering_RNA">SC</a> using MPP, and our proposed method demonstrates promising results.</abstract>
      <url hash="76cbf0ef">2020.latechclfl-1.19</url>
      <bibkey>mori-etal-2020-finding</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/mil-tokyo/missing-position-prediction" additional="false">mil-tokyo/missing-position-prediction</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/rocstories">ROCStories</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>