<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.vardial">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 7th Workshop on NLP for Similar Languages, Varieties and Dialects</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Marcos</first><last>Zampieri</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Preslav</first><last>Nakov</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nikola</first><last>Ljubešić</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jörg</first><last>Tiedemann</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yves</first><last>Scherrer</last></editor>
      <publisher>International Committee on Computational Linguistics (ICCL)</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="3484dcef">2020.vardial-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>vardial-2020-nlp</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>ASR for Non-standardised Languages with Dialectal Variation : the case of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swiss_German">Swiss German</a><fixed-case>ASR</fixed-case> for Non-standardised Languages with Dialectal Variation: the case of <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>wiss <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>erman</title>
      <author><first>Iuliia</first><last>Nigmatulina</last></author>
      <author><first>Tannon</first><last>Kew</last></author>
      <author><first>Tanja</first><last>Samardzic</last></author>
      <pages>15–24</pages>
      <abstract>Strong regional variation, together with the lack of standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthography">orthography</a>, makes Swiss German automatic speech recognition (ASR) particularly difficult in a multi-dialectal setting. This paper focuses on one of the many challenges, namely, the choice of the output text to represent non-standardised Swiss German. We investigate two potential options : a) dialectal writing   approximate phonemic transcriptions that provide close correspondence between grapheme labels and the acoustic signal but are highly inconsistent and b) normalised writing   transcriptions resembling standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a> that are relatively consistent but distant from the acoustic signal. To find out which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writing">writing</a> facilitates Swiss German ASR, we build several systems using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaldi_(software)">Kaldi toolkit</a> and a dataset covering 14 regional varieties. A formal comparison shows that the system trained on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normalization_(statistics)">normalised transcriptions</a> achieves better results in word error rate (WER) (29.39 %) but underperforms at the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Character_(computing)">character level</a>, suggesting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transcription_(linguistics)">dialectal transcriptions</a> offer a viable solution for downstream applications where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">dialectal differences</a> are important. To better assess word-level performance for dialectal transcriptions, we use a flexible WER measure (FlexWER). When evaluated with this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metric</a>, the system trained on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transcription_(linguistics)">dialectal transcriptions</a> outperforms that trained on the normalised writing. Besides establishing a benchmark for Swiss German multi-dialectal ASR, our findings can be helpful in designing ASR systems for other languages without standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthography">orthography</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="7bab8437">2020.vardial-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>nigmatulina-etal-2020-asr</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Machine-oriented NMT Adaptation for Zero-shot NLP tasks : Comparing the Usefulness of Close and Distant Languages<fixed-case>NMT</fixed-case> Adaptation for Zero-shot <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> tasks: Comparing the Usefulness of Close and Distant Languages</title>
      <author><first>Amirhossein</first><last>Tebbifakhr</last></author>
      <author><first>Matteo</first><last>Negri</last></author>
      <author><first>Marco</first><last>Turchi</last></author>
      <pages>36–46</pages>
      <abstract>Neural Machine Translation (NMT) models are typically trained by considering humans as end-users and maximizing human-oriented objectives. However, in some scenarios, their output is consumed by automatic NLP components rather than by humans. In these scenarios, translations’ quality is measured in terms of their fitness for purpose (i.e. maximizing performance of external NLP tools) rather than in terms of standard human fluency / adequacy criteria. Recently, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">reinforcement learning techniques</a> exploiting the feedback from downstream NLP tools have been proposed for machine-oriented NMT adaptation. In this work, we tackle the problem in a multilingual setting where a single NMT model translates from multiple languages for downstream automatic processing in the target language. Knowledge sharing across close and distant languages allows to apply our machine-oriented approach in the zero-shot setting where no labeled data for the test language is seen at training time. Moreover, we incorporate multi-lingual BERT in the source side of our NMT system to benefit from the knowledge embedded in this model. Our experiments show coherent performance gains, for different language directions over both i) generic NMT models (trained for human consumption), and ii) fine-tuned multilingual BERT. This gain for zero-shot language directions (e.g. SpanishEnglish) is higher when the models are fine-tuned on a closely-related source language (Italian) than a distant one (German).</abstract>
      <url hash="935d1a6a">2020.vardial-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>tebbifakhr-etal-2020-machine</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Character Alignment in Morphologically Complex Translation Sets for Related Languages</title>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Gasser</last></author>
      <author><first>Binyam Ephrem</first><last>Seyoum</last></author>
      <author><first>Nazareth Amlesom</first><last>Kifle</last></author>
      <pages>47–56</pages>
      <abstract>For languages with complex morphology, word-to-word translation is a task with various potential applications, for example, in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">information retrieval</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_education">language instruction</a>, and dictionary creation, as well as in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>. In this paper, we confine ourselves to the subtask of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Character_alignment">character alignment</a> for the particular case of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_family">families of related languages</a> with very few resources for most or all members. There are many such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_family">families</a> ; we focus on the subgroup of Semitic languages spoken in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethiopia">Ethiopia</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eritrea">Eritrea</a>. We begin with an adaptation of the familiar <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequence_alignment">alignment algorithms</a> behind <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_machine_translation">statistical machine translation</a>, modifying them as appropriate for our task. We show how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Character_alignment">character alignment</a> can reveal morphological, phonological, and orthographic correspondences among related languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="637f0829">2020.vardial-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>gasser-etal-2020-character</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Bilingual Lexicon Induction across Orthographically-distinct Under-Resourced Dravidian Languages<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian Languages</title>
      <author><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></author>
      <author><first>Navaneethan</first><last>Rajasekaran</last></author>
      <author><first>Mihael</first><last>Arcan</last></author>
      <author><first>Kevin</first><last>McGuinness</last></author>
      <author><first>Noel</first><last>E. O’Connor</last></author>
      <author><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <pages>57–69</pages>
      <abstract>Bilingual lexicons are a vital tool for under-resourced languages and recent state-of-the-art approaches to this leverage pretrained monolingual word embeddings using supervised or semi-supervised approaches. However, these approaches require cross-lingual information such as seed dictionaries to train the model and find a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_map">linear transformation</a> between the word embedding spaces. Especially in the case of low-resourced languages, seed dictionaries are not readily available, and as such, these methods produce extremely weak results on these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Programming_language">languages</a>. In this work, we focus on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian languages</a>, namely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, which are even more challenging as they are written in unique scripts. To take advantage of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthography">orthographic information</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognate">cognates</a> in these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">languages</a>, we bring the related languages into a single script. Previous approaches have used linguistically sub-optimal measures such as the Levenshtein edit distance to detect cognates, whereby we demonstrate that the longest common sub-sequence is linguistically more sound and improves the performance of bilingual lexicon induction. We show that our approach can increase the accuracy of bilingual lexicon induction methods on these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">languages</a> many times, making bilingual lexicon induction approaches feasible for such under-resourced languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="99a051cf">2020.vardial-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>chakravarthi-etal-2020-bilingual</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Recycling and Comparing Morphological Annotation Models for Armenian Diachronic-Variational Corpus Processing<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rmenian Diachronic-Variational Corpus Processing</title>
      <author><first>Chahan</first><last>Vidal-Gorène</last></author>
      <author><first>Victoria</first><last>Khurshudyan</last></author>
      <author><first>Anaïd</first><last>Donabédian-Demopoulos</last></author>
      <pages>90–101</pages>
      <abstract>Armenian is a language with significant variation and unevenly distributed NLP resources for different varieties. An attempt is made to process an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio-frequency_identification">RNN model</a> for morphological annotation on the basis of different Armenian data (provided or not with morphologically annotated corpora), and to compare the annotation results of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio-frequency_identification">RNN</a> and rule-based models. Different tests were carried out to evaluate the reuse of an unspecialized model of lemmatization and POS-tagging for under-resourced language varieties. The research focused on three dialects and further extended to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_Armenian">Western Armenian</a> with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mean">mean accuracy</a> of 94,00 % in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lemmatization">lemmatization</a> and 97,02 % in POS-tagging, as well as a possible reusability of models to cover different other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armenian_language">Armenian varieties</a>. Interestingly, the comparison of an RNN model trained on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eastern_Armenian">Eastern Armenian</a> with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eastern_Armenian">Eastern Armenian National Corpus rule-based model</a> applied to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_Armenian">Western Armenian</a> showed an enhancement of 19 % in parsing. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> covers 88,79 % of a short heterogeneous dataset in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_Armenian">Western Armenian</a>, and could be a baseline for a massive corpus annotation in that standard. It is argued that an RNN-based model can be a valid alternative to a rule-based one giving consideration to such factors as time-consumption, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reusability">reusability</a> for different varieties of a target language and significant qualitative results in morphological annotation.</abstract>
      <url hash="167087bd">2020.vardial-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>vidal-gorene-etal-2020-recycling</bibkey>
    <title_ar>إعادة التدوير والمقارنة بين نماذج الشرح الصرفي لمعالجة الجسد الأرمني الرقمي المتغير</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Reciclando e Comparando Modelos de Anotação Morfológica para Processamento de Corpus Diacrônico-Variacional Armênio</title_pt>
      <title_es>Reciclaje y comparación de modelos de anotación morfológica para el procesamiento de corpus diacrónico-variacionales armenios</title_es>
      <title_ja>アルメニアのジアクロニック変異体処理のための形態学的注釈モデルのリサイクルと比較</title_ja>
      <title_hi>रीसाइक्लिंग और आर्मेनियाई डायक्रोनिक-परिवर्तनीय कॉर्पस प्रसंस्करण के लिए रूपात्मक एनोटेशन मॉडल की तुलना</title_hi>
      <title_zh>亚美尼亚历变分语料库回收与较形注模</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Múnlaí Anótála Moirfeolaíocha a Athchúrsáil agus a Chomparáid le haghaidh Próiseáil Chorpais Dhiachrónach-Athránaigh Airméinis</title_ga>
      <title_hu>Újrahasznosítás és morfológiai jegyzékmodellek összehasonlítása örmény diakrónikus variációs testfeldolgozáshoz</title_hu>
      <title_it>Riciclo e confronto dei modelli di annotazione morfologica per l'elaborazione dei corpi diacronici-variabili armeni</title_it>
      <title_lt>Perdirbimas ir morfologinių anotacijų modelių palyginimas Armėnijos diachroninio ir kintamojo kūno apdorojimo modeliams</title_lt>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Ανακύκλωση και σύγκριση μορφολογικών υποδειγμάτων για την Αρμενική Διαχρόνια-Μεταβλητική Επεξεργασία Σώματος</title_el>
      <title_ml>അര്‍മ്മേനിയന്‍ ഡയറക്രോണിക്- വേറിയേഷന്‍ കോര്‍പ്സ് പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനായി മോര്‍ഫോളിക്കല്‍ ആനോട്ടേഷന്‍ മോ</title_ml>
      <title_kk>Армениялық диагроникалық- айнымалы корпус процессері үшін морфологикалық жазбалар үлгілерін қайталау және салыстыру</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Рециклирање и споредба на моделите на морфолошка анотација за процес на ерменско дијахронично-варијационален корпус</title_mk>
      <title_mt>Ir-riċiklaġġ u t-tqabbil ta’ Mudelli ta’ Annotazzjoni Morfoloġika għall-Ipproċessar tal-Korpus Dijakroniku-Varjazzjonali Armenjan</title_mt>
      <title_ms>Mengulangi dan membandingkan Model Annotasi Morfologik untuk Pemprosesan Korpus Diakronik-Variasi Armenia</title_ms>
      <title_mn>Арменийн диагроник-өөрчлөлтийн биеийн процессийн морфологик загваруудыг дахин хэрэглэх болон харьцуулах</title_mn>
      <title_no>Rekyclering og sammenlikning av morfologiske notasjonsmodeller for Armensk diakronisk- variasjonal korpushandsaming</title_no>
      <title_pl>Recykling i porównanie modeli anotacji morfologicznych dla ormiańskiego przetwarzania korpusu diachronicznego</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Reciclarea și compararea modelelor de adnotare morfologică pentru procesarea corpului diacronic-variațional armen</title_ro>
      <title_sv>Återvinning och jämförelse av morfologiska noteringsmodeller för armenisk diakronisk variabel korpusbehandling</title_sv>
      <title_so>Dib-isticmaalidda iyo Comparinta Morphological Annotation Models for Armenian Diakroc-Variable Corpus Processing</title_so>
      <title_ur>Name</title_ur>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_ta>அர்மெனியாவின் டையாக்ரோனிக்- மாறிகள் செயல்பாடு</title_ta>
      <title_sr>Рециклирање и сравње модела морфологичких нотација за обработку армянских диагронично-вариационних корпуса</title_sr>
      <title_vi>Chế độ lặp lại và so sánh Morphological Chú giải thích Models for Armenia diaChronic-biến Quốc Tập sản</title_vi>
      <title_uz>ArmeniyaName</title_uz>
      <title_bg>Рециклиране и сравняване на морфологични анотационни модели за арменска диахронно-вариационна обработка на корпуса</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Recikliranje i usporedba modela morfoloških oznake za proces Armenskog dijagroničnog i varijantnog korpusa</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Recycling en vergelijking van morfologische annotatiemodellen voor Armeense diachronisch-variantionele korpusverwerking</title_nl>
      <title_da>Genbrug og sammenligning af morfologiske noteringsmodeller til armensk diakronisk variationsbehandling</title_da>
      <title_de>Recycling und Vergleich morphologischer Annotationsmodelle für die armenische diachronisch-variationelle Korpusverarbeitung</title_de>
      <title_ko>아르메니아어 역시 변분 어료 라이브러리 처리 중 형태 표기 모델의 회수와 비교</title_ko>
      <title_id>Recycling and Comparing Morphological Annotation Models for Armenian Diachronic-Variational Corpus Processing</title_id>
      <title_fa>بازسازی و مقایسه نمونه‌های نوشته‌های مورفیولوژیکی برای پرداخت کورپوس دیاکرونیک و متغیر ارمنی</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Mradi wa Tamko za Kimorphological Annotation for the Armenian Diakroc-Variable Corpus</title_sw>
      <title_af>Herwerklik en vergelyking van Morphological Annotation Models vir Armeniese Diakronise- Veranderlike Korpus Verwerking</title_af>
      <title_tr>Ermençe Diachronik-Çeşitli Körpüs işlemleri üçin Morfolojik duýgulama Modelleri</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Riçiklimi dhe krahasimi i modeleve të anotacionit morfologjik për procesimin e korpusit diakronik-variacional armen</title_sq>
      <title_am>ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_az>Ermenik Diakroniki-Variasiyonlu Cürpüs işləməsi üçün Morphological Annotation Modellərini yenidən istifadə etmək və Comparison</title_az>
      <title_hy>Հաշվի առնելու և համեմատելու մոդելները</title_hy>
      <title_bn>আর্মেনিয়ান ডায়ারোনিক- ভিয়েয়ারিয়েশন কোর্পাস প্রক্রিয়া</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Recikliranje i usporedba modela morfološke annotacije za proces Armenskog dijagroničnog-varijantnog korpusa</title_bs>
      <title_et>Armeenia diakroonilise variatsiooni korpuse töötlemise morfoloogiliste annotatsioonimudelite ringlussevõtt ja võrdlemine</title_et>
      <title_ca>Recycling and Comparing Morphological Annotation Models for Armenian Diachronic-Variational Corpus Processing</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Recyklace a srovnání morfologických anotací pro arménské diachronicko-variační zpracování korpusů</title_cs>
      <title_fi>KierrĂ¤tys ja morfologisten huomautusmallien vertailu Armenian diakroonisessa ja variaatiokorpuskĂ¤sittelyssĂ¤</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Reycling and Compring</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Recikliranje in primerjava morfoloških annotacijskih modelov za armensko diakronično-variacijsko obdelavo korpusa</title_sk>
      <title_he>Recycling and Comparing Morphological Annotation Models for Armenian Diachronic-Variational Corpus Processing</title_he>
      <title_bo>Recycling and Comparing Morphological Annotation Models for Armenian Diachronic-Variational Corpus Processing</title_bo>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <abstract_ar>الأرمينية هي لغة ذات تباين كبير وموارد البرمجة اللغوية العصبية الموزعة بشكل غير متساو لأنواع مختلفة. جرت محاولة لمعالجة نموذج RNN للتعليق التوضيحي المورفولوجي على أساس بيانات أرمينية مختلفة (مقدمة أو لا مع مجموعة مشروحة شكليًا) ، ولمقارنة نتائج التعليقات التوضيحية لـ RNN والنماذج المستندة إلى القواعد. تم إجراء اختبارات مختلفة لتقييم إعادة استخدام نموذج غير متخصص من اللماتة وعلامات نقاط البيع لأنواع اللغات منخفضة الموارد. ركز البحث على ثلاث لهجات وامتد إلى اللغة الأرمنية الغربية بمتوسط دقة 94،00٪ في lemmatization و 97،02٪ في علامات POS ، بالإضافة إلى إمكانية إعادة استخدام النماذج لتغطية مختلف الأصناف الأرمينية الأخرى. ومن المثير للاهتمام ، أن المقارنة بين نموذج RNN المدرب على الأرمينية الشرقية مع النموذج القائم على قاعدة الجسد القومي الأرمني الشرقي المطبق على الأرمينيين الغربيين أظهر تعزيزًا بنسبة 19 ٪ في الإعراب. يغطي هذا النموذج 88،79٪ من مجموعة بيانات قصيرة غير متجانسة باللغة الأرمينية الغربية ، ويمكن أن يكون أساسًا لتعليق توضيحي ضخم للمجموعة في هذا المعيار. يُقال أن النموذج القائم على RNN يمكن أن يكون بديلاً صالحًا للنموذج القائم على القواعد مع الأخذ في الاعتبار عوامل مثل استهلاك الوقت ، وإعادة الاستخدام لأنواع مختلفة من اللغة المستهدفة والنتائج النوعية المهمة في التعليق التوضيحي الصرفي.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>El armenio es un idioma con variaciones significativas y recursos de PNL distribuidos de manera desigual para diferentes variedades. Se intenta procesar un modelo RNN para anotación morfológica sobre la base de diferentes datos armenios (proporcionados o no con corpus anotados morfológicamente), y comparar los resultados de anotación de RNN y modelos basados en reglas. Se realizaron diferentes pruebas para evaluar la reutilización de un modelo no especializado de lematización y etiquetado POS para variedades lingüísticas de escasos recursos. La investigación se centró en tres dialectos y se extendió al armenio occidental con una precisión media del 94,00% en la lematización y del 97,02% en el etiquetado POS, así como una posible reutilización de modelos para cubrir otras variedades armenias diferentes. Curiosamente, la comparación de un modelo de RNN entrenado en armenio oriental con el modelo basado en reglas del Corpus Nacional de Armenia Oriental aplicado al armenio occidental mostró una mejora del 19% en el análisis sintáctico. Este modelo cubre el 88,79% de un conjunto de datos heterogéneo corto en armenio occidental, y podría ser una línea de base para una anotación masiva de corpus en ese estándar. Se argumenta que un modelo basado en RNN puede ser una alternativa válida a uno basado en reglas, teniendo en cuenta factores tales como el consumo de tiempo, la reutilización para diferentes variedades de un idioma de destino y los resultados cualitativos significativos en la anotación morfológica.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>O armênio é uma língua com variação significativa e recursos de PNL distribuídos de forma desigual para diferentes variedades. É feita uma tentativa de processar um modelo RNN para anotação morfológica com base em diferentes dados armênios (fornecidos ou não com corpora morfologicamente anotados) e comparar os resultados de anotação de RNN e modelos baseados em regras. Diferentes testes foram realizados para avaliar a reutilização de um modelo não especializado de lematização e POS-tagging para variedades linguísticas com poucos recursos. A pesquisa se concentrou em três dialetos e se estendeu ainda mais ao armênio ocidental com uma precisão média de 94,00% na lematização e 97,02% na marcação POS, bem como uma possível reutilização de modelos para cobrir diferentes outras variedades armênias. Curiosamente, a comparação de um modelo RNN treinado em armênio oriental com o modelo baseado em regras do Corpus Nacional da Armênia Oriental aplicado ao armênio ocidental mostrou um aprimoramento de 19% na análise. Este modelo cobre 88,79% de um conjunto de dados heterogêneo curto em armênio ocidental e pode ser uma linha de base para uma anotação de corpus maciça nesse padrão. Argumenta-se que um modelo baseado em RNN pode ser uma alternativa válida para um modelo baseado em regras, levando em consideração fatores como consumo de tempo, reusabilidade para diferentes variedades de uma língua-alvo e resultados qualitativos significativos na anotação morfológica.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_hi>अर्मेनियाई महत्वपूर्ण भिन्नता के साथ एक भाषा है और विभिन्न किस्मों के लिए असमान रूप से वितरित एनएलपी संसाधन। विभिन्न अर्मेनियाई डेटा (रूपात्मक रूप से एनोटेटेड कॉर्पोरेट के साथ प्रदान किए गए या नहीं) के आधार पर रूपात्मक एनोटेशन के लिए एक आरएनएन मॉडल को संसाधित करने का प्रयास किया जाता है, और आरएनएन और नियम-आधारित मॉडल के एनोटेशन परिणामों की तुलना करने के लिए। कम संसाधन वाली भाषा किस्मों के लिए लेमाटाइजेशन और पीओएस-टैगिंग के एक अनिर्दिष्ट मॉडल के पुन: उपयोग का मूल्यांकन करने के लिए विभिन्न परीक्षण किए गए थे। अनुसंधान ने तीन बोलियों पर ध्यान केंद्रित किया और आगे पश्चिमी अर्मेनियाई तक विस्तारित किया, जिसमें लेमेटाइजेशन में 94,00% और पीओएस-टैगिंग में 97,02% की औसत सटीकता के साथ-साथ विभिन्न अन्य अर्मेनियाई किस्मों को कवर करने के लिए मॉडल की संभावित पुनरावृत्ति भी थी। दिलचस्प बात यह है कि पूर्वी अर्मेनियाई पर प्रशिक्षित एक आरएनएन मॉडल की तुलना पूर्वी अर्मेनियाई राष्ट्रीय कॉर्पस नियम-आधारित मॉडल के साथ पश्चिमी अर्मेनियाई पर लागू की गई थी, जिसमें पार्सिंग में 19% की वृद्धि देखी गई थी। यह मॉडल पश्चिमी अर्मेनियाई में एक छोटे विषम डेटासेट के 88,79% को कवर करता है, और उस मानक में बड़े पैमाने पर कॉर्पस एनोटेशन के लिए एक आधार रेखा हो सकता है। यह तर्क दिया जाता है कि एक आरएनएन-आधारित मॉडल एक नियम-आधारित के लिए एक वैध विकल्प हो सकता है जो समय-खपत, लक्ष्य भाषा की विभिन्न किस्मों के लिए पुन: प्रयोज्य और रूपात्मक एनोटेशन में महत्वपूर्ण गुणात्मक परिणामों जैसे कारकों पर विचार करता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>亚美尼亚语者,显异NLP资布不均之言,宜于异变体。 尝试以亚美尼亚数(不给形注语料库)RNN模形以注之,较RNN与法注。 异试之试,以估资源贫乏之言变体者非殊词形还原与POS标模形之用。 治侧重于三言,益广西亚美尼亚语,词形还其均准确率为94,00%,POS其平准确率为97,02%其可用者涵盖其他亚美尼亚品。 有趣者,教于东亚美尼亚语RNN与西亚美尼亚语东亚美尼亚国语料库则较著,解析增19%。 盖西亚美尼亚语中短异构数集之88,79%可以为大率语料库注之基线。 或以为RNN可以为法者代方,兼虑日月消耗,语言不同变体者可用性及注释中显者定性素也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ja>アルメニア語は顕著なバリエーションを持つ言語であり、さまざまな品種のNLPリソースが不均等に分布しています。 異なるアルメニアのデータに基づいて形態学的注釈のためのRNNモデルを処理し（形態学的に注釈されたコーパスと共に提供されるかどうか）、RNNとルールベースのモデルの注釈結果を比較しようと試みる。 リソース不足の言語変異種に対するレマティゼーション及びＰＯＳタグ付けの非専門化モデルの再利用を評価するために、様々な試験を実施した。 この研究は3つの方言に焦点を当て、さらに西アルメニア語に拡張し、平均精度はレマティゼーションで94,00 ％、POSタグ付けで97,02 ％であり、他の異なるアルメニアの品種をカバーするためのモデルの再利用可能性の可能性もありました。 興味深いことに、東アルメニア語で訓練されたRNNモデルと、西アルメニア語に適用された東アルメニア国立コーパスルールベースのモデルとの比較は、構文解析において19%の増強を示した。 このモデルは、西アルメニア語の短い異種データセットの88,79%をカバーしており、その標準における大規模なコーパスアノテーションのベースラインとなる可能性があります。 RNNベースのモデルは、時間消費、ターゲット言語の異なる変種の再利用可能性、および形態学的注釈における有意な定性的結果などの要因を考慮して、ルールベースのモデルの有効な代替であり得ると主張されている。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ga>Is teanga í an Airméinis le héagsúlacht shuntasach agus acmhainní NLP dáilte go míchothrom do chineálacha éagsúla. Déantar iarracht samhail RNN a phróiseáil le haghaidh nóta moirfeolaíocha ar bhonn sonraí Airméinis éagsúla (ar fáil nó nach bhfuil le corpora anótáilte de réir moirfeolaíocha), agus comparáid a dhéanamh idir torthaí anótála RNN agus samhlacha bunaithe ar riail. Rinneadh tástálacha éagsúla chun meastóireacht a dhéanamh ar athúsáid samhail neamhspeisialaithe de leamatú agus le clibeáil POS do chineálacha teanga gann-acmhainní. Dhírigh an taighde ar thrí chanúint agus leathnaíodh é go dtí an Airméinis Thiar le cruinneas meánach 94,00 % i leamatúchán agus 97,02 % i gclibeáil POS, chomh maith le hathúsáid féidearthacht samhlacha chun cineálacha éagsúla Airméinis eile a chlúdach. Is díol suntais é gur léiríodh méadú 19% sa pharsáil nuair a cuireadh samhail RNN oilte ar an Airméinis Thoir i gcomparáid le múnla rialacha-bhunaithe Chorpais Náisiúnta Oirthear na hAirméine a cuireadh i bhfeidhm ar Airméinis Thiar. Clúdaíonn an tsamhail seo 88,79% de thacar sonraí gearr ilchineálach san Airméinis Thiar, agus d’fhéadfadh sé a bheith ina bhunlíne d’ollnótáil corpais sa chaighdeán sin. Áitítear gur féidir le samhail atá bunaithe ar RNN a bheith ina rogha bhailí eile seachas samhail atá bunaithe ar rialacha agus aird á tabhairt ar fhachtóirí mar chaitheamh ama, ath-inúsáidteacht do chineálacha éagsúla sprioctheanga agus torthaí cáilíochtúla suntasacha i anótáil mhoirfeolaíoch.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>აპერმიანი არის მნიშვნელოვანი განსხვავებების ენაა და მნიშვნელოვანი NLP რესურსი განსხვავებულ განსხვავებებისთვის. მორპოლოგიური მონაცემებისთვის RNN მოდელის პროცესება განსხვავებული არმენიური მონაცემებისთვის (მომპოროლოგიურად მონაცემებისთვის და არა) და RNN და rule-based მოდელის მონაცემების მონაცემებისთვის შემდგ განსხვავებული ტესტი გავაკეთებულია, რომ ლიმომატიზაციის და POS-მარტიზაციის განსხვავებული ენის განსხვავებებისთვის გამოყენება განსხვავებული მოდელის გამოყენება. პროცემები სამი დიალეკტებზე კონუქტირებულია და უფრო დასავლეთ აპერმენეთის გარეშე 94,00% სიმართლეში და 97,02% სიმართლეში POS-მართლში, და შესაძლებელი მოდელების გამოყენება სხვა აპერმენეთის განსხვავებების გა საინტერესოა, რომელიც დასავლეთ აპერმენეთისთვის პროგორმაცია, რომელიც ინტერესონალური აპერმენეთისთვის გასწავლა პროგორმაციის მოდელის შემდგომარება, რომელიც დასავლეთ აპერმენეთისთ ამ მოდელს 88,79%-ს დასავლეთ აპერმიანეთში ცოტა ჰეტეროგენური მონაცემების შესახებ, და შეიძლება იყოს მასიური კორპუსის ანტოციის ბაზი ხაზი. არგებულია, რომ RNN-დაბათებული მოდელი შეიძლება იყოს საჭირო ალტენტრუმენტი, რომელიც მხოლოდ გამოყენებული ფაქტორები, განსხვავებული სხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადას</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>L'armeno è una lingua con variazioni significative e risorse PNL distribuite in modo irregolare per diverse varietà. Si tenta di elaborare un modello RNN per l'annotazione morfologica sulla base di diversi dati armeni (forniti o meno con corpora annotata morfologicamente), e di confrontare i risultati di annotazione di RNN e modelli basati su regole. Sono stati effettuati diversi test per valutare il riutilizzo di un modello non specializzato di lemmatizzazione e POS-tagging per varietà linguistiche con scarse risorse. La ricerca si è concentrata su tre dialetti e si è ulteriormente estesa all'armeno occidentale con una precisione media del 94,00% nella lemmatizzazione e del 97,02% nella marcatura POS, nonché una possibile riutilizzabilità di modelli per coprire diverse altre varietà armene. È interessante notare che il confronto di un modello RNN addestrato sull'armeno orientale con il modello basato sul governo del Corpus nazionale armeno orientale applicato all'armeno occidentale ha mostrato un miglioramento del 19% nel parsing. Questo modello copre l'88,79% di un breve set di dati eterogeneo in armeno occidentale, e potrebbe essere una base di riferimento per una massiccia annotazione del corpus in tale standard. Si sostiene che un modello basato su RNN può essere una valida alternativa a uno basato su regole tenendo conto di fattori quali il consumo di tempo, la riutilizzabilità per diverse varietà di una lingua di destinazione e risultati qualitativi significativi nell'annotazione morfologica.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_el>Τα Αρμενικά είναι μια γλώσσα με σημαντική ποικιλία και άνισα κατανεμημένους πόρους για διαφορετικές ποικιλίες. Γίνεται προσπάθεια επεξεργασίας ενός μοντέλου για μορφολογική παρατήρηση με βάση διάφορα αρμενικά δεδομένα (που παρέχονται ή όχι με μορφολογικά σχολιασμένα σώματα) και σύγκρισης των αποτελεσμάτων σχολιασμού από μοντέλα με βάση κανόνες. Πραγματοποιήθηκαν διάφορες δοκιμές για να αξιολογηθεί η επαναχρησιμοποίηση ενός μη ειδικού μοντέλου λεμματοποίησης και σήμανσης για γλωσσικές ποικιλίες που δεν διαθέτουν επαρκείς πόρους. Η έρευνα επικεντρώθηκε σε τρεις διαλέκτους και επεκτάθηκε περαιτέρω στα Δυτικά Αρμενικά με μια μέση ακρίβεια 94,00% στη λεμματοποίηση και 97,02% στην επισήμανση, καθώς και μια πιθανή επαναχρησιμοποίηση των μοντέλων για να καλύψει διαφορετικές άλλες αρμενικές ποικιλίες. Ενδιαφέρον είναι ότι η σύγκριση ενός μοντέλου RNN εκπαιδευμένου στα Ανατολικά Αρμενικά με το μοντέλο που βασίζεται σε κανόνες του Ανατολικού Αρμενικού Εθνικού Σώματος που εφαρμόστηκε στα Δυτικά Αρμενικά έδειξε αύξηση 19% στην ανάλυση. Το μοντέλο αυτό καλύπτει 88,79% ενός μικρού ετερογενούς συνόλου δεδομένων στα Δυτικά Αρμενικά, και θα μπορούσε να αποτελέσει βάση για μια μαζική επισήμανση σώματος σε αυτό το πρότυπο. Υποστηρίζεται ότι ένα μοντέλο βασισμένο σε RNN μπορεί να αποτελέσει μια έγκυρη εναλλακτική λύση σε ένα μοντέλο βασισμένο σε κανόνες λαμβάνοντας υπόψη παράγοντες όπως η κατανάλωση χρόνου, η επαναχρησιμοποίηση για διαφορετικές ποικιλίες μιας γλώσσας-στόχου και σημαντικά ποιοτικά αποτελέσματα μορφολογικής σχολιασμού.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_lt>Armėnų kalba labai skiriasi ir skirtingų veislių NLP ištekliai paskirstomi nevienodai. Bandoma apdoroti RNN model į, skirtą morfologinei anotacijai, remiantis skirtingais Armėnijos duomenimis (pateikiami arba nenustatyti morfologiškai anotuoti korporai), ir palyginti RNN ir taisyklėmis pagrįstų modelių anotacijos rezultatus. Different tests were carried out to evaluate the reuse of an unspecialized model of lemmatization and POS-tagging for under-resourced language varieties.  Tyrimuose daugiausia dėmesio buvo skiriama trims dialektams ir toliau buvo skiriama Vakarų Armėnijai, vidutiniškai 94,00 % limmatizacijos ir 97,02 % POS žymėjimo tikslumui, taip pat galimam modelių pakartotiniam naudojimui skirtingoms kitoms Armėnijos veislėms. Įdomu, palyginus Rytų Armėnų kalba parengtą RNN model į su Rytų Armėnų nacionalinės korpuso taisyklėmis pagrįstu modeliu, taikytu Vakarų Armėnų kalba, tyrimo rezultatai padidėjo 19 %. Šis modelis apima 88,79 % trumpo heterogeninio duomenų rinkinio Vakarų Armėnijos kalba ir galėtų būti pagrindinis didelio korpuso anotacijos šiame standarte pagrindas. Manoma, kad RNN pagrįstas model is gali būti tinkama alternatyva taisyklėmis pagrįstam modeliui, kuriame atsižvelgiama į tokius veiksnius kaip laiko suvartojimas, pakartotinis naudojimas skirtingoms tikslinės kalbos veislėms ir reikšmingas kokybinis rezultatas – morfologinė anotacija.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_hu>Az örmény nyelv jelentős változatossággal és különböző fajták számára egyenlőtlenül elosztott NLP forrásokkal rendelkezik. Kísérletet teszünk arra, hogy feldolgozzuk az RNN modellt morfológiai jegyzetekhez különböző örmény adatok alapján (morfológiailag jegyzetekkel ellátott korpuszokkal), és összehasonlítsuk az RNN és a szabályalapú modellek jegyzetelési eredményeit. Különböző vizsgálatokat végeztünk a lemmatizáció és POS-címkézés speciális modelljének újrafelhasználásának értékelésére az alacsony forrásokkal rendelkező nyelvfajták esetében. A kutatás három dialektusra összpontosított és tovább terjedt a nyugat-örmény nyelvre, átlagosan 94,00%-os lemmatizációs pontossággal és 97,02%-os POS-címkézéssel, valamint a modellek lehetséges újrafelhasználhatóságával különböző örmény fajtákra. Érdekes módon a Kelet-Örményországon képzett RNN modell összehasonlítása a Kelet-Örményországon alkalmazott Nemzeti Corpus szabályalapú modell és a Nyugat-Örményországon alkalmazott modell 19%-os növekedést mutatott az elemzésben. Ez a modell egy rövid heterogén nyelvű adathalmaz 88,79%-át fedi le Nyugat-Örményországban, és alapjául szolgálhat egy masszív korpuszjegyzéshez ebben a szabványban. Azt állítják, hogy egy RNN-alapú modell érvényes alternatívája lehet egy szabályalapú modell helyett, figyelembe véve olyan tényezőket, mint az időfogyasztás, a célnyelv különböző fajtáinak újrafelhasználhatósága és a morfológiai jegyzetek jelentős minőségi eredményeit.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ms>Bahasa Armenia adalah bahasa dengan variasi yang signifikan dan sumber NLP yang tidak disebarkan secara sama untuk jenis yang berbeza. Cubaan dibuat untuk memproses model RNN untuk anotasi morfologi berdasarkan data Armenia yang berbeza (disediakan atau tidak dengan korpra yang anotasi morfologi), dan untuk membandingkan hasil anotasi RNN dan model berdasarkan peraturan. Ujian berbeza dilakukan untuk menilai penggunaan semula model lemmatisasi tidak spesialis dan tag POS untuk jenis bahasa yang tidak berkuasa. Penelitian ini fokus pada tiga dialekt dan lebih lanjut dilambangkan ke Armenia Barat dengan ketepatan rata-rata 94,00% dalam lemmatisasi dan 97,02% dalam POS-tagging, serta kemungkinan penggunaan semula model untuk menutupi berbagai jenis Armenia lain. Menarik, perbandingan model RNN yang dilatih di Armenia Timur dengan model yang berdasarkan peraturan Korpus Nasional Armenia Timur yang dilaksanakan pada Armenia Barat menunjukkan peningkatan 19% dalam penghuraian. Model ini meliputi 88,79% dari set data heterogeni pendek di Armenia Barat, dan boleh menjadi dasar untuk anotasi corpus besar dalam piawai itu. Ia disangka bahawa model berasaskan RNN boleh menjadi alternatif yang sah untuk faktor berasaskan peraturan yang mempertimbangkan faktor seperti penggunaan masa, penggunaan semula untuk berbagai jenis bahasa sasaran dan hasil kualitatif yang signifikan dalam anotasi morfologik.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>വ്യത്യസ്ത വ്യത്യാസങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് വേണ്ടി NLP വിഭവങ്ങള്‍ വിതരണം ചെയ്യുന്ന അര്‍മ്മേനിയന്‍ ഭാഷയാണ്. വ്യത്യസ്ത ആര്‍മേനിയയുടെ ഡാറ്റ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ ഒരു RNN മോഡല്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കാന്‍ ശ്രമിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു (മൊര്‍ഫോളജിക്കല്‍ കോര്‍പ്പോറയില്‍ പ്രസ്താവിക് Different tests were carried out to evaluate the reuse of an unspecialized model of lemmatization and POS-tagging for under-resourced language varieties.  ഈ ഗവേഷണം മൂന്നു ഡയലക്കേറ്റുകളിലേക്ക് ശ്രദ്ധിച്ചു വീണ്ടും പടിഞ്ഞാറന്‍ ആര്‍മേനിയയിലേക്ക് വികസിപ്പിക്കുകയും വ്യത്യസ്ത വ്യത്യസ്ത വ്യത്യാസങ്ങള്‍ മൂടുകയും ചെയ്യ കിഴക്കന്‍ അര്‍മേനിയയില്‍ പഠിപ്പിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഒരു RNN മോഡലിന്റെ താല്‍പര്യം കിഴക്കന്‍ അര്‍മേനിയന്‍ നാഷണല്‍ കോര്‍പ്പുസിന്റെ നിയമമോഡല്‍ പ്രയോഗിച്ചു പടിഞ ഈ മോഡല്‍ പടിഞ്ഞാറന്‍ അര്‍മ്മേനിയനിലെ കുറച്ച് ഹെട്രോജെനിസ് ഡാറ്റാസെറ്റില്‍ 88,79% പൂര്‍ണ്ണമാക്കുന്നു. അതിന്റെ ഒരു വലിയ കോര്‍പ്പ ഒരു RNN-അടിസ്ഥാനത്തിലുള്ള മോഡല്‍ ഒരു നിയമത്തിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തിലുള്ള ഒരു മാറ്റം ആയിരിക്കാന്‍ സാധിക്കുന്നു. സമയ-consumption, ലക്ഷ്യഭാഷ വ്യത്യസ്ത വ്യത്യസ്ത ഭാഷയ്ക്ക്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_kk>Армениялық - маңызды айырмашылық тіл және әртүрлі түрлерге NLP ресурстары таратылмаған. Түрлі армян деректерінің негізінде (морфологиялық корпораға келтірілген немесе емес) RNN морфологиялық жазбалардың нәтижесін салыстыру үшін RNN үлгісі жазылады. Төмендегі тіл түрлері үшін ерекшелмеген леммациялау мен POS- тегтерін қайта қолдану үшін әртүрлі сынақтар істелді. Сынақтар үш диалекттерге көздеген және Батыс Арменияның орташа лимматизациялық 94,00 % және POS тегтерінде 97,02 % деген диалекттерге көздеген және басқа армян түрлеріне қайта қолдануға мүмкін үлгілер қолданылады. Бірақ қызықты, Шығыс Армениялық RNN үлгісін Батыс Армениялық үлгілеріне қолданылатын Шығыс Армениялық Құрыптар үлгісімен салыстыру үлгісі, талдау үшін 19% дегенді көрсетті. Бұл үлгі Батыс Арменияндағы қысқа гетероген деректер жиының 88,79% деп жазылады. Осы стандартта маңызды корпус жазбаларының негізгі жолы болуы мүмкін. RNN негіздеген модель ережелердің негіздеген альтернативі болуы мүмкін, уақыт пайдалану, мақсатты тілдің әртүрлі түрлеріне қайта пайдалану мүмкіндігі және морфологиялық жазбаларының маңызды квалификациялық нәтижеле</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mt>L-Armenjan huwa lingwa b’varjazzjoni sinifikanti u riżorsi tal-NLP imqassma b’mod mhux ugwali għal varjetajiet differenti. Sar tentattiv biex jiġi pproċessat mudell ta’ RNN għall-annotazzjoni morfoloġika fuq il-bażi ta’ dejta Armenja differenti (ipprovduta jew le b’korpra morfoloġikament annotata), u biex jitqabblu r-riżultati tal-annotazzjoni ta’ RNN u mudelli bbażati fuq ir-regoli. Saru testijiet differenti biex jiġi evalwat l-użu mill-ġdid ta’ mudell mhux speċjalizzat ta’ limmatizzazzjoni u tikkettar POS għal varjetajiet lingwistiċi b’riżorsi baxxi. Ir-riċerka ffukat fuq tliet dijaletti u estendiet ulterjorment għall-Armenja tal-Punent b’preċiżjoni medja ta’ 94,00 % fil-limmatizzazzjoni u 97,02 % fit-tikkettar tal-POS, kif ukoll użu mill-ġdid possibbli ta’ mudelli biex ikopru varjetajiet Armenji oħra differenti. Interessant, it-tqabbil ta’ mudell ta’ RNN imħarreġ fuq l-Armenja tal-Lvant mal-mudell ibbażat fuq ir-regoli tal-Korp Nazzjonali Armenjan tal-Lvant applikat għall-Armenja tal-Punent wera titjib ta’ 19 % fl-analiżi. Dan il-mudell ikopri 88,79 % ta’ sett ta’ dejta eteroġenu qasir fl-Armenja tal-Punent, u jista’ jkun linja bażi għal annotazzjoni massiva tal-korpus f’dak l-istandard. Huwa argumentat li mudell ibbażat fuq RNN jista’ jkun alternattiva valid a għal waħda bbażata fuq ir-regoli li tikkunsidra fatturi bħal konsum ta’ ħin, użu mill-ġdid għal varjetajiet differenti ta’ lingwa fil-mira u riżultati kwalitattivi sinifikanti f’annotazzjoni morfoloġika.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Арменийн хэл бол маш чухал өөрчлөлт, өөр төрлийн NLP нөөц бүтээгдэхүүнтэй хэл юм. Өөр Арменийн өгөгдлийн үндсэн (морфологик анзаарагдсан корпора) дээр РНХ загварын морфологик анзаарлын загварыг үйлдвэрлэхэд хичээлдэг. Мөн РНХ болон дүрмийн үндсэн загварын үр дүнг харьцуулахын тулд. Өөр өөр тест хийгдсэн нь хэл төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн lemmatization болон POS-tagging загварыг дахин ашиглахын тулд өөр өөр өөр өөр загварууд. Судалгааны судалгаа 3 диалект дээр төвлөрсөн ба Барууны Армени хүртэл 94,00% лемматизацийн дундаж тодорхойлолтой, POS-тегт 97,02% болон бусад Арменийн төрлийн төрлийн загваруудыг дахин ашиглах боломжтой болсон. Хамгийн сонирхолтой нь зүүн Арменид сургалтын РНХ загварын харьцуулах нь Барууны Арменид хэрэглэгдсэн Барууны Арменийн улс төрийн хууль загвартай харьцуулахад 19%-ын нэмэгдүүлэлт үзүүлсэн. Энэ загвар нь Барууны Арменийн богино гетероген өгөгдлийн хувьд 88.79%-ийг агуулдаг. Энэ стандарт маш олон корпус илтгэлийн суурь шугам байж болно. РНХ-ын суурь загвар нь хууль хэрэглэх, зорилготой хэл төрлийн дахин ашиглах боломжтой болон морфологик анзаарлын үндсэн чадвартай үр дүнг зөвхөн хууль загварын үндсэн загвар юм.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Armensk er eit språk med signifikante variasjonar og ulik distribuert NLP-ressursar for ulike variasjonar. Ein prøv er gjennomført å handsama eit RNN-modell for morfologisk annotasjon på grunn av ulike Armenske data (oppgjeven eller ikkje med morfologisk annotasjon av korpora) og å sammenligna notasjonsresultatene av RNN- og regelbaserte modeller. Dei ulike testane vart gjennomført for å evaluera gjennombruken av eit ikkje spesialisert modell for lemmatisering og POS- merking for underressurserte språk- variasjonar. Forskningen fokuserte på tre dialektar og lenger utvidet til Vest-Armensk med gjennomsnittlig nøyaktighet med 94,00 % i lemmatisasjon og 97,02 % i POS-merking, og eit mulig gjenoppretting av modeller for å dekka ulike andre Armenske variasjonar. Interesantleg viste sammenligninga med eit RNN-modell som treng på øst-Armensk og den øst-Armenske nasjonale korpus-regelsbaserte modellen som er brukt til Vest-Armensk, at det er forbetra 19 % i tolking. Dette modellet dekkar 88,79 % av ein kort heterogenesk dataset i Vest-Armensk, og kan vera ein grunnlinje for ein massiv korpusannotasjon i denne standarden. Det er argumentert at ein RNN-basert modell kan vera ein gyldig alternativ til ein regelbasert, som gjer betre på slike faktorer som tidsbruk, gjenopprettbruk for ulike variasjonar av eit målspråk og signifikante kvalitative resultat i morfologiske annotasjon.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Ormiański jest językiem o znaczącym zróżnicowaniu i nierównomiernie rozprowadzonych zasobach NLP dla różnych odmian. Podjęto próbę przetworzenia modelu RNN dla adnotacji morfologicznej na podstawie różnych danych ormiańskich (dostarczonych lub nie z korpusami morfologicznymi) oraz porównania wyników adnotacji RNN i modeli opartych na regułach. Przeprowadzono różne testy w celu oceny ponownego wykorzystania niespecjalizowanego modelu lemmatyzacji i POS-tagowania dla niewyposażonych odmian językowych. Badania koncentrowały się na trzech dialektach i dalej rozszerzyły się na zachodnioormiański ze średnią dokładnością 94,00% w lemmatyzacji i 97,02% w tagowaniu POS, a także możliwością ponownego użytkowania modeli do pokrycia różnych innych odmian ormiańskich. Co ciekawe, porównanie modelu RNN trenowanego na Wschodnim Ormianie z modelem opartym na regułach Wschodnioormiańskiego Korpusu Narodowego zastosowanym na Zachodnim Ormianie wykazało wzrost 19% parsowania. Model ten obejmuje 88,79% krótkiego, heterogenicznego zbioru danych w języku zachodnim ormiańskim i mógłby stanowić bazę podstawową dla masywnej adnotacji korpusu w tym standardzie. Argumentuje się, że model oparty na RNN może być ważną alternatywą dla modelu opartego na regułach biorąc pod uwagę takie czynniki jak zużycie czasu, ponowne wykorzystanie dla różnych odmian języka docelowego oraz istotne wyniki jakościowe w adnotacji morfologicznej.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>Armenski je jezik sa značajnim varijacijom i nepravedno raspodijeljenim NLP resursima za različite raznolike. Pokušava se procesirati RNN model morfološke annotacije na osnovu različitih Armenskih podataka (pruženih ili ne morfološki annotiranih korpora) i usporediti rezultate annotacije RNN-a i modela na osnovu pravila. Provedeni su različiti testovi kako bi procenili ponovno upotrebu neprecijalnog modela limmatizacije i označavanja POS-a za neposredne jezičke vrste. Istraživanje se fokusiralo na tri dijalekta i dalje se proširilo na zapadnu Armensku s srednjom preciznošću od 94,00 % limmatizacije i 97,02 % na označavanju POS-a, kao i mogućom ponovnom korištenju modela za pokrivanje različitih Armenskih raznolika. Zanimljivo je da je usporedba modela RNN obučenog na istočnom Armeniju sa model nacionalnog korpusa iz Istoènog Armenskog nacionalnog korpusa koji se primjenjuje na zapadnu Armeniju pokazala povećanje od 19% u analizu. Ovaj model pokriva 88.79% kratkih heterogeneznih podataka u Zapadnoj Armeniji, i može biti osnovna linija za veliku korpusnu annotaciju u tom standardu. Tvrdi se da model na RNN-u može biti validna alternativa na pravilima koja daje obzir na takve faktore kao potrošenje vremena, ponovno korištenje različitih različitih različitih različitih različitih jezika ciljnog jezika i značajnih kvalitativnih rezultata morfološke annotacije.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Armeniyan waa luqad ay leeyihiin isbedelyo faro badan oo ay ku kala qaybsan yihiin raslimo aan u filnayn oo ay kala duduwan noocyo kala duduwan. Jahaadaa waxaa la sameeyaa in lagu sameeyo model RNN oo ku saabsan waraaqo morphological ah oo ku saabsan macluumaad kala duduwan oo Armenian (diyaarin ama aan ku qorin korpora si morphologically annotated), iyo in la barbardhigo midhihiisa xuquuqda ee RNN iyo sameynta sameynta sameynta noocyada xuquuqda. Imtixaano kala duduwan waxaa loo sameeyay in lagu qiimeeyo dib u isticmaalka tusaale aan la aqoonsan jimicsiga iyo POS-tagging oo ku qoran luuqadaha hoose-resourceed. Baaritaanku wuxuu ku kalsoonaaday saddex qalabka oo galbeed ah oo u sii kordhay Armenian, si sax ah looga dhigo 94,00 boqolkiiba barbaarinta iyo 97,02 boqolkiiba POS-tagging, sidoo kalena waxaa suurtagal ah dib u isticmaalka modelalka inay qariyaan kala duduwan Armeniyan oo kale. Si xiiso leh, iftiinkii RNN model lagu barto Bari Armenian iyo model ku saleysan qoraalka bariga Armenian National Corpus ee galbeed Armenian wuxuu tusay kordhis 19% baarlamaanka. Tusaaladan waxay ku daboolan 88,79 % oo ka mid ah macluumaad gaaban oo ay ku qoran yihiin galbeed Armenian, waxaana laga yaabaa inay u noqoto korpus oo aad u weyn. Waxaa loola hadlayaa in muusiko asalka RNN ah uu noqon karo mid suurtagal ah oo ku habboon sharciga, kaas oo ka fiirsan kara arrimaha tusaale ahaan isticmaalka waqtiga, dib u isticmaalidda luuqada kala duduwan ee loogu talagalay iyo waxyaabaha muhiimka ah oo ka soo jeeda suurtogal.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Armeniska är ett språk med betydande variation och ojämnt fördelade NLP-resurser för olika sorter. Ett försök görs att bearbeta en RNN-modell för morfologisk notering på grundval av olika armeniska data (försedda med eller inte med morfologiskt kommenterade corpora), och att jämföra noteringsresultaten för RNN och regelbaserade modeller. Olika tester genomfördes för att utvärdera återanvändningen av en ospecialiserad modell av lemmatisering och POS-märkning för underresurserade språksorter. Forskningen fokuserade på tre dialekter och utvidgades vidare till västra armeniska med en genomsnittlig noggrannhet på 94,00% i lemmatisering och 97,02% i POS-märkning, samt en möjlig återanvändbarhet av modeller för att täcka olika andra armeniska sorter. Intressant nog visade jämförelsen av en RNN-modell utbildad på östra armeniska med den östra armeniska nationella corpus regelbaserade modellen tillämpad på västra armeniska en förbättring av 19% i tolkning. Denna modell täcker 88,79% av en kort heterogen datamängd på västra armeniska, och kan vara en baslinje för en massiv korpusnotering i den standarden. Det hävdas att en RNN-baserad modell kan vara ett giltigt alternativ till en regelbaserad modell med hänsyn till sådana faktorer som tidsförbrukning, återanvändbarhet för olika sorter av ett målspråk och signifikanta kvalitativa resultat i morfologisk notering.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>அர்மேனியன் மொழியாகும் முக்கியமான மாறிகள் மற்றும் வேறு வித்தியாசமான மூலங்களுக்கு NLP மூலங்கள் வழங்கப் ஆர்மேனிய தகவல்களை அடிப்படையில் ஒரு ஆர்என்னி மாதிரியை செயல்படுத்த முயற்சி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது (வழங்கப்பட்டுள்ளது அல்லது குறிப்பிட்ட நிறுவனத்தில் இல்லை), மற்றும்  வேறு சோதனைகள் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது மூலத்திற்கு கீழ் வளர்ந்த மொழி மாறுபாடுகளுக்கு தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படாத மாதிரி மதிப்பிடும் மற்று இந்த ஆராய்ச்சி மூன்று விளக்கங்கள் மீது கவனம் செலுத்தப்பட்டது மற்றும் மேற்கு அர்மேனியாவிற்கு மேலும் விரிவாக்கப்பட்டது 94,00 சதவிகிதத்தின் சரியான சரித்திரம் மற்று கிழக்கு ஆர்மேனியன் மீது பயிற்சிக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு RNN மாதிரியின் ஒப்பீடு, கிழக்கு அர்மேனியாவின் நாடி கார்ப்ஸ் விதிமுறை மாதிரி மாதிரி முறையி இந்த மாதிரி 88,79% மேற்கு அர்மேனியனில் ஒரு சிறிய வெப்ரீஜன் தகவல் அமைப்பை மறைக்கிறது, மற்றும் அந்த நிலையில் ஒரு பெரிய கார்புஸ் விளக ஒரு RNN-அடிப்படையிலான மாதிரி ஒரு விதிமுறையாக இருக்கலாம் என்று வாக்கியம் செலுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, இது நேரம் பயன்படுத்தல், வேறு வித்தியாசமான மொழிக்கு மீண்டும் பயன்படுத</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_mk>Ерменецот е јазик со значителна варијација и нееднакво дистрибуирани ресурси на НЛП за различни различности. Се обидува да се процесира РНН модел за морфолошка анотација врз основа на различни ерменски податоци (обезбедени или не со морфолошки анотацирани корпора) и да се споредат резултатите на анотацијата на РНН и модели базирани на правила. Различни тестови беа спроведени за проценка на повторното употреба на неспецијализиран модел на лиматизација и POS-ознака за различни јазички различности. Истражувањата се фокусираа на три дијалекти и понатаму се проширија на Западен Ерменец со просечна точност од 94,00 отсто во лиматизацијата и 97,02 отсто во означувањето на POS, како и можна повторна употреба на моделите за покривање на различни други ерменски разнови. Интересно е што споредбата на РНН модел обучен на Источна Ерменска со моделот заснован на владеењето на Источна Ерменска Национална Корпус кој се применува на Западна Ерменска покажа зголемување од 19 отсто во анализирањето. Овој модел покрива 88,79 отсто од краток хетероген податок на западна Ерменска, и може да биде основа за масовна анотација на корпусот во тој стандард. Се тврди дека моделот базиран на РНН може да биде валидна алтернатива на еден базиран на правила, со оглед на факторите како што се временската потрошувачка, повторното употребливост за различни различности на јазик на целта и значителните квалитетни резултати во морфолошка анотација.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ro>Armena este o limbă cu variații semnificative și resurse PNL distribuite inegal pentru diferite soiuri. Se încearcă să proceseze un model RNN pentru adnotări morfologice pe baza diferitelor date armene (furnizate sau nu cu corpore adnotate morfologic), și să compare rezultatele adnotării RNN și modelele bazate pe reguli. Au fost efectuate teste diferite pentru a evalua reutilizarea unui model nespecializat de lemmatizare și etichetare POS pentru soiurile lingvistice cu resurse insuficiente. Cercetarea s-a concentrat pe trei dialecte și s-a extins în continuare la armena vestică cu o precizie medie de 94,00% în lemmatizare și 97,02% în etichetarea POS, precum și o posibilă reutilizare a modelelor pentru a acoperi diferite alte soiuri armene. Interesant este faptul că comparația dintre modelul RNN instruit pe armeanul estic și modelul Corpului național al armeanului estic aplicat pe armeanul vestic a arătat o creștere de 19% în analiză. Acest model acoperă 88,79% dintr-un set scurt de date eterogene în limba armenă vestică și ar putea fi o bază de referință pentru o adnotare masivă a corpului în acest standard. Se susține că un model bazat pe RNN poate fi o alternativă validă la unul bazat pe reguli, luând în considerare factori precum consumul de timp, reutilizarea pentru diferite varietăți ale unei limbi țintă și rezultatele calitative semnificative în adnotare morfologică.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>අර්මේනියානියාව තරම් විවිධ වර්ගයක් තියෙන භාෂාවක් හා විවිධ වර්ගයක් වෙනුවෙන් නැති විදි Name වෙනස් පරීක්ෂණාවල් පරීක්ෂණය කරලා ලෙම්මේස් සහ POS- ටැග් සඳහා භාෂා වර්ගයක් නොවිශේෂිත නිර්භාවිත විශේෂ කර පරීක්ෂණය තුනක් දායිලක්ට් එක්ක සැකසුම් කරලා පස්සේ අර්මේනියානුවෙන් ඉතිරිපත් කරලා තියෙන්නේ 94,00% විශේෂ සැකසුම් සහ 97,02% විශේෂය POS-ටැග් එක Interested, the comparison of a RNN Model Trained on East Armian with the East Armian National Corpus Rule-based Model Application to Western Armian Show an elevation of 19% in Parsing. මේ මොඩේල් 88,79% පැත්ත අර්මේනියානියාවේ පැත්ත අර්මේනියානියාවේ පොඩි සාමාන්‍ය දත්ත සූදානයක් ඇතුළු කරනවා, ඒ වගේම ඒක ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා RNN-අධාරිත මොඩල් එකක් නීති අධාරිත ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙන්න පුළුවන් නීති අධාරිත ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙන්න පුළුවන් විදිහට වි</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>آرمنیایی ایک زبان ہے جو بہت اہم تغییرات کے ساتھ ہے اور بغیر طرح طرح طرح طرح کے NLP منبع کے لئے تقسیم کئے گئے ہیں۔ ایک کوشش کی جاتی ہے کہ ایک RNN موڈل کے لئے مختلف ارمنی ڈاکٹوں کے بنیاد پر قائم کرے اور RNN اور قانون کے بنیاد رکھنے والے موڈل کے نتیجے مقایسہ کریں۔ مختلف آزمائش کی گئی تھی کہ لیموماٹیزی اور POS-ٹاگ کی نازل زبان مختلفوں کے لئے دوبارہ استعمال کریں۔ اس تحقیقات نے تین ڈیلکتوں پر تمرکز کیا اور مغرب آرمینی کی طرف مزید مزید لیمٹیزی میں 94,00% اور پوس ٹیگ میں 97,02%، اور دوسری آرمینی مختلف مختلف مختلف مختلف مختلف موجودات کے امکانات کی دوبارہ استعمال کرنے کی امکانات کی۔ غربی آرمینی کے ذریعہ مطابق غربی آرمینی کے ذریعے ایک RNN موڈل کے مقایسے کے طور پر مشرق آرمینی پر آموزش کی گئی تھی۔ یہ مدل مغربی آرمینی میں ایک چھوٹے غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غیر غ اس بات کو جھٹلایا گیا ہے کہ ایک RNN بنیاد موڈل ایک قانون بنیاد رکھنے والے کے لئے ایک معتبر الٹ بن سکتا ہے جس سے زمان مصرف کے ذریعے، ایک موجود زبان کے مختلف مختلف مختلف مختلف مختلف موجود کے لئے دوباره استعمال کرسکتا ہے اور موجود شناسی کے مطابق اضافہ کے</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>ArmaniyaName Name @ info: whatsthis Taʼminlovchi uchta dialeklarga qaragan va Gʻarbiy Armeniga o'zgarishga qaraydi, o'zgarishga 94,00 foiz haqida, POS tagning 97,02% va boshqa Armaniya turlarini qarish mumkin modellarni qayta ishlatish mumkin. Shunday qiziqarli, Sharqiy Armeniyaga o'rganilgan RNN modeliga o'rganish, Sharqiy Armeniya Tashqi Korpus qoidasi asosiy modeli Gʻarbiy Armeniga qo'llangan modeliga qo'llangan, 19% qo'yishni oshirishni ko'rsatadi. Name Bu qiymatda, RNN asosida yaratilgan model qoidagi boshqaruv bo'lishi mumkin. Vaqt foydalanish, turli tillar uchun qayta ishlatish va murakkab foydalanish natijalariga muhim qiymativ natijalari mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tiếng Armenia là ngôn ngữ có độ khác nhau và Độ phân phối độc lập. Một thử nghiệm xử lý mô hình RNN cho chú thích lịch lịch của chuẩn dựa trên các dữ liệu người Armenia khác nhau (cung cấp hay không có ghi chú lịch lịch lịch âm) và so sánh kết quả chú thích của RNN và các mô hình dựa trên quy định. Các thử nghiệm khác nhau đã được tiến hành để đánh giá lại cách sử dụng một mô hình chưa được công bố về giải thích cho các loại ngôn ngữ thiếu nguồn. Nghiên cứu tập trung vào ba phương ngữ và tiếp tục mở rộng cho miền tây Armenia với tỉ lệ chuẩn hàng đầu của 94,00 và 97,22+ trong kết quả POS-taging, và còn có khả năng tái sử dụng các mô- đun cho các loại khác nhau thuộc chủng tộc Armenia. Thật thú vị, so sánh một mô hình RNN được huấn luyện trên miền Đông Armenia với phương pháp luật của tập đoàn Mỹ phương đông áp dụng cho miền tây Armenia đã cho thấy nâng cao độ khó khó khăn trong việc phân tích. Mô hình này bao gồm 88,99=.=) của một tập tin nhỏ khác nhau ở miền tây Armenia, và có thể là cơ sở thực tế cho ghi chú y tích khổng lồ trong tiêu chuẩn đó. Nó được nói rằng mô hình dựa trên RNN có thể là một thay đổi hợp lệ với mô hình dựa trên quy tắc, dựa vào các yếu tố như tiêu thời gian, tái sử dụng cho các loại khác nhau của ngôn ngữ mục tiêu và kết quả về tiêu chuẩn lịch sử.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Арменският е език със значителни вариации и неравномерно разпределени ресурси на НЛП за различни сортове. Направен е опит да се обработи модел за морфологична анотация на базата на различни арменски данни (предоставени или не с морфологично анотирани корпуси), както и да се сравнят резултатите от анотацията на RNN и базирани на правила модели. Извършени са различни тестове за оценка на повторното използване на неспециализиран модел на лематизация и ПОС-маркиране за недоресурсни езикови сортове. Проучването се съсредоточи върху три диалекта и допълнително се разшири до Западна Армения със средна точност 94,00% при лематизация и 97,02% при ПОС-маркиране, както и възможна повторна възможност на модели за покриване на различни други арменски сортове. Интересното е, че сравнението на модела на РНН, обучен на Източна Армения, с модела на Източна Армения национален корпус, базиран на правила, приложен към Западна Армения, показва подобрение с 19% в анализирането. Този модел обхваща 88,79% от кратък хетерогенен набор от данни на Западна Армения и може да бъде основна база за масивна корпусна анотация в този стандарт. Твърди се, че базиран на RNN модел може да бъде валидна алтернатива на базиран на правила модел, като се вземат предвид фактори като консумация на време, повторна възможност за различни разновидности на целевия език и значителни качествени резултати в морфологичната анотация.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Armensk er et sprog med betydelig variation og ujævnt fordelt NLP ressourcer for forskellige sorter. Et forsøg er gjort på at behandle en RNN model til morfologisk annotering på grundlag af forskellige armenske data (leveret eller ej med morfologisk annoterede corpora), og at sammenligne annoteringsresultaterne af RNN og regelbaserede modeller. Forskellige tests blev udført for at evaluere genbrug af en uspecialiseret model for lemmatisering og POS-tagging for underressourcer sprogsorter. Forskningen fokuserede på tre dialekter og udvidede yderligere til vestarmensk med en gennemsnitlig nøjagtighed på 94,00% i lemmatisering og 97,02% i POS-mærkning, samt en mulig genanvendelse af modeller til at dække forskellige andre armenske sorter. Interessant nok viste sammenligningen af en RNN model uddannet på østlige armenske med den østlige armenske nationale korpus regelbaserede model anvendt på vestlige armenske en forbedring på 19% i parsing. Denne model dækker 88,79% af et kort heterogent datasæt på vestarmensk, og kunne være en baseline for en massiv corpus annotation i denne standard. Det fremføres, at en RNN-baseret model kan være et gyldigt alternativ til en regelbaseret model under hensyntagen til faktorer som tidsforbrug, genanvendelighed for forskellige sorter af et målsprog og betydelige kvalitative resultater i morfologisk notering.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Armeens is een taal met aanzienlijke variatie en ongelijk verdeeld NLP bronnen voor verschillende variëteiten. Er wordt geprobeerd om een RNN model te verwerken voor morfologische annotatie op basis van verschillende Armeense gegevens (al dan niet voorzien van morfologisch geanotateerde corpora), en de annotatieresultaten van RNN en op regels gebaseerde modellen te vergelijken. Verschillende tests werden uitgevoerd om het hergebruik van een ongespecialiseerd model van lemmatisatie en POS-tagging te evalueren voor taalvariëteiten met weinig middelen. Het onderzoek richtte zich op drie dialecten en breidde zich verder uit naar West-Armenisch met een gemiddelde nauwkeurigheid van 94,00% in lemmatisatie en 97,02% in POS-tagging, evenals een mogelijke herbruikbaarheid van modellen voor verschillende andere Armeense variëteiten. Interessant is dat de vergelijking van een RNN model getraind op Oost-Armeens met het Oost-Armeens National Corpus rule-based model toegepast op West-Armeens een toename van 19% in parsing toonde. Dit model bestrijkt 88,79% van een korte heterogene dataset in het West-Armenisch, en zou een basis kunnen zijn voor een massale corpusannotatie in die standaard. Er wordt betoogd dat een RNN-gebaseerd model een geldig alternatief kan zijn voor een regel-gebaseerd model waarbij rekening wordt gehouden met factoren als tijdsverbruik, herbruikbaarheid voor verschillende variëteiten van een doeltaal en significante kwalitatieve resultaten in morfologische annotatie.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Armenski je jezik sa značajnim varijacijom i nepravedno raspodijeljenim NLP resursima za različite razine. Pokušava se obraditi model RNN za morfološku annotaciju na temelju različitih Armenskih podataka (pruženih ili ne morfološki annotiranih tijela) i usporediti rezultate annotacije RNN-a i modela temeljenih na pravilima. Provedeni su različiti testovi kako bi procijenili ponovno primjenu neprecijalnog modela limmatizacije i označavanja POS-a za neposredne jezičke vrste. Istraživanje se fokusiralo na tri dijalekta i dalje se proširilo na zapadni Armenski s srednjom preciznošću od 94,00 % u lematizaciji i 97,02 % u označavanju POS-a, kao i mogućom ponovnom korištenju modela za pokrivanje različitih Armenskih raznolikova. Zanimljivo je, usporedba modela RNN obučenog na istočnom Armeniju s pravilima temeljenim na Istočnom Armenijskom nacionalnom korpusu primjenom na zapadni Armenski pokazala povećanje od 19% u analizu. Ovaj model pokriva 88.79% kratke heterogenezne podatke na zapadnoj Armenskoj, i može biti početna linija za veliku korpusnu annotaciju u tom standardu. Tvrdi se da model na RNN-u može biti validna alternativa na pravilima koja će razmotriti takve faktore kao potrošenje vremena, ponovno iskoristiti različite razine ciljnog jezika i značajne kvalitativne rezultate morfološke annotacije.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Armenisch ist eine Sprache mit erheblichen Variationen und ungleichmäßig verteilten NLP-Ressourcen für verschiedene Sorten. Es wird versucht, ein RNN-Modell für morphologische Annotation auf der Grundlage verschiedener armenischer Daten (bereitgestellt oder nicht mit morphologisch annotierten Korpora) zu verarbeiten und die Annotationsergebnisse von RNN und regelbasierten Modellen zu vergleichen. Verschiedene Tests wurden durchgeführt, um die Wiederverwendung eines unspezialisierten Lemmatisierungs- und POS-Tagging-Modells für unzureichend ausgestattete Sprachvarianten zu evaluieren. Die Forschung konzentrierte sich auf drei Dialekte und erweiterte sich weiter auf Westarmenisch mit einer mittleren Genauigkeit von 94,00% in Lemmatisierung und 97,02% in POS-Tagging, sowie einer möglichen Wiederverwendbarkeit von Modellen für verschiedene andere armenische Sorten. Interessanterweise zeigte der Vergleich eines RNN-Modells, das auf Ostarmenisch trainiert wurde, mit dem Ostarmenischen Nationalkorpus-Regelmodell, das auf Westarmenisch angewendet wurde, eine Steigerung von 19% im Parsing. Dieses Modell deckt 88,79% eines kurzen heterogenen Datensatzes in Westarmenisch ab und könnte eine Grundlage für eine massive Korpusannotation in diesem Standard sein. Es wird argumentiert, dass ein RNN-basiertes Modell eine valide Alternative zu einem regelbasierten Modell sein kann, wobei Faktoren wie Zeitverbrauch, Wiederverwendbarkeit für verschiedene Sorten einer Zielsprache und signifikante qualitative Ergebnisse in morphologischen Annotationen berücksichtigt werden.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>아르메니아어는 품종별로 NLP 자원의 분포가 고르지 않은 변이 현저한 언어다.형태 치수화에 사용되는 RNN 모델을 다양한 아르메니아 데이터(형태 치수 자료 라이브러리 제공 또는 미제공)에 따라 처리하고 RNN 모델과 규칙 기반 모델의 치수 결과를 비교하려 한다.자원이 부족한 언어 변체가 비전문화된 레몬화와 어성 표기 모델의 중용을 평가하기 위해 서로 다른 테스트를 실시했다.이 연구는 세 가지 사투리에 중심을 두고 서아메리카어까지 확대했다. 레몬화의 평균 정확도는 94,00%, 어성 표기의 평균 정확도는 97,02%, 그리고 모델의 중용성으로 다른 아르메니아어 품종을 커버했다.흥미로운 것은 동아르메니아어에서 훈련된 RNN 모델을 시아메니아어에 적용한 동아르메니아 국가어료고의 규칙 기반 모델과 비교해보니 해석 능력이 19% 향상된 것으로 나타났다.이 모델은 서아시아어 단이구 데이터 집합의 88.79%를 덮어 이 표준에서 대규모 어료 라이브러리 주석의 기선으로 삼을 수 있다.RNN 기반 모델은 규칙 기반 모델을 효과적으로 대체할 수 있으며, 시간 소모, 목표 언어의 다양한 종류의 중용성, 형태학 주석에서 현저한 정성 결과 등을 고려할 수 있다는 의견도 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_id>Bahasa Armenia adalah bahasa dengan variasi yang signifikan dan sumber daya NLP yang tidak sama untuk berbagai jenis. Sebuah percobaan dibuat untuk memproses model RNN untuk anotasi morfologi berdasarkan data Armenia yang berbeda (disediakan atau tidak dengan korpora yang anotasi morfologi), dan untuk membandingkan hasil anotasi RNN dan model berdasarkan aturan. Ujian yang berbeda dilakukan untuk mengevaluasi penggunaan ulang model lemmatisasi tidak spesialis dan POS-tagging untuk varietas bahasa yang tidak memiliki sumber daya. Penelitian ini fokus pada tiga dialekt dan lebih lanjut memperluas ke Armenia Barat dengan akurasi rata-rata 94,00 % dalam lemmatisasi dan 97,02 % dalam POS-tagging, serta kemungkinan penggunaan ulang model untuk menutupi berbagai jenis Armenia lainnya. Menarik, perbandingan dari model RNN yang dilatih di Armenia Timur dengan model yang berdasarkan peraturan Korpus Nasional Armenia Timur yang dipakai pada Armenia Barat menunjukkan peningkatan 19% dalam penghasilan. This model covers 88,79% of a short heterogeneous dataset in Western Armenian, and could be a baseline for a massive corpus annotation in that standard.  Diduga bahwa model berdasarkan RNN dapat menjadi alternatif yang valid untuk alternatif berdasarkan peraturan yang mempertimbangkan faktor seperti konsumsi waktu, penggunaan ulang untuk berbagai jenis bahasa sasaran dan hasil kualitatif yang signifikan dalam anotasi morfologis.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>ارمنی یک زبان با تغییرات بزرگی و منابع NLP بی‌نظیر برای مختلف مختلف است. یک تلاش برای پرداخت یک مدل RNN برای اظهار مورفولوژیکی بر اساس داده های ارمنی متفاوت (به عنوان شرکت مورفولوژیکی مشخص شده یا نه) و برای مقایسه نتیجه اظهار RNN و مدل‌های قانونی است. آزمایش‌های مختلف برای ارزیابی دوباره استفاده از یک مدل غیر ویژه‌ای از لیماتیزی و نقاشی POS برای مختلف زبانهای زیر منابع انجام شد. تحقیقات روی سه دیالکت تمرکز شده و به ارمنی غربی با دقیقات متوسط 94.00 درصد در لیماتیزی و 97.02 درصد در نقاشی POS، همچنین یک دوباره استفاده از مدل‌ها برای پوشاندن مختلف گونه‌های ارمنی است. Interestingly, comparison of an RNN model trained on Eastern Armenian with the Eastern Armenian National Corpus rule-based rule applied to Western Armenian showed an improvement of 19% in parsing. این مدل 88.79 درصد از یک مجموعه داده های غربی کوتاه در ارمنیان غربی پوشش می دهد، و می تواند یک خط بنیادی برای یک اظهار بزرگی در آن استاندارد باشد. گفته می‌شود که یک مدل بنیاد RNN می‌تواند جایگزینی قانونی باشد که به عنوان مصرف زمان، دوباره استفاده می‌کند برای مختلف گونه‌های زبان هدف و نتیجه‌های گونه‌ای بزرگی در نوشته‌های مورفولوژیک.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Ki-Armenia ni lugha yenye mabadiliko makubwa na kutolewa rasilimali za NLP kwa ajili ya tofauti tofauti. An attempt is made to process an RNN model for morphological annotation on the basis of different Armenian data (provided or not with morphologically annotated corpora), and to compare the annotation results of RNN and rule-based models.  Majaribio mbalimbali yalifanywa ili kutathmini matumizi ya upya ya mifano isiyo na ufanisi wa kutengeneza vifaa vya udhalilishaji na viungo vya POS kwa utofauti wa lugha yenye rasmi. Utafiti huo ulijikita kwenye lugha tatu na kuendelea zaidi nchini Armenia Magharibi kwa kiwango cha sahihi cha asilimia 94,00 katika viumbe vya umeme na asilimia 97,02 katika viungo vya POS, pamoja na uwezekano wa matumizi ya mifano ya kutangaza tofauti mbalimbali za ki-Armenia. Katika hali ya kushangaza, kulinganisha kwa muundo wa RNN ulioelekezwa kutoka Armenia Mashariki na muundo wa utawala wa National Corpus wa Armenia wa Mashariki uliotumika kwa Wa-Armenia wa Magharibi ulionyesha kuongezeka kwa asilimia 19 katika kuiba. Mfano huu unajumuisha asilimia 88,79 ya taarifa fupi za kibiashara nchini Armenia ya Magharibi, na inaweza kuwa msingi wa matangazo makubwa ya makampuni hayo katika hali hiyo. Inahoji kuwa muundo wa msingi wa RNN unaweza kuwa ni mbadala sahihi wa utawala ambao unafikiria kwa sababu kama vile matumizi ya muda, matumizi ya upya kwa lugha tofauti za lengo na matokeo makubwa yanayotokana na matatizo ya kifolojia.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Ermençe dürli çeşitlerde nLP çeşitleri üçin wajyp üýtgeşikli we daýlanmadyk bir dildir. Farklı Ermenik verilerine dayanarak RNN modelini işlemek için bir dene edildi ve RNN ve kural tabanlı modellerini karşılaştırmak için denedi. Diňe birnäçe testiler lemmatizasyonyň we POS-taglamasynyň düzümleri üçin ýene-de beýleki nusgalary barlamak üçin provelenýär. Araştyrmalar üç dialekte we Batarça Ermenistanyň 94,00 % lemmatizaçy bilen düýbünden geçirildi we POS taglamasynda 97,02% düýbünden başga düýbünden tapawutlygy bilen üýtgedi. Gyzykly bolsa, Gündogar Ermenistan derejesi bilen bilinen RNN nusgasynyň karşılaştyrylygy Gündogar Ermenistan Milli Korpus düzgünlerine daýan ýan nusgasy Batarça Ermenistana üýtgedilýän nusgasynda 19% köprügini görkezildi. Bu nusga Günbatar Ermenistanyň 88.79% köp deňli hasaplançylygyny daýanýar we bu standartda örän köp duýdurma çykyp biler. RNN tabanly bir nusga düzenlenen kural taýýarlanan bir nusga bolup, wagt tüketmesi ýaly faktörlere düşünerek, maksadyň dürli dili üçin ýene-de ulanylygy we morfolojik täzelikde wajyp görnüş netijesi bolup biler diýilýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Armeniese is 'n taal met betekende veranderinge en onheilig verdeelde NLP hulpbronne vir verskillende veranderinge. 'n Probeer is gemaak om 'n RNN model te proses vir morfologiese annotasie op die basis van verskillende Armeense data (verskaf of nie met morfologiese annotated corpora) en om die annotasie resultate van RNN en reël-gebaseerde modele te vergelyk. Verskillende toets is uitgevoer om die hergebruik van 'n ongespesialiseerde model van lemmatisasie en POS-etiket vir onder-hulpbron taal verskillighede te evalueer. Die ondersoek het op drie dialekte gefokus en verder uitgevoer na Wes-Armeniese met 'n gemiddelde presisie van 94,00 % in lemmatisasie en 97,02 % in POS-etiketing, en ook 'n moontlike hergebruikbaarheid van modele om verskillende Armeniese verskillighede te dekk. Interesantlik het die vergelyking van 'n RNN-model wat op Oosten-Armeniese opgelei is met die Oosten-Armeniese Nasionale Korpus-reël-gebaseerde model wat op Westen-Armeniese toepassing is, die vergelyking van 19% in vergelyking gewys. Hierdie model bedek 88,79% van 'n kort heterogeneese datastel in Wes-Armeniese, en kan 'n basisline wees vir 'n groot korpus annotasie in daardie standaard. Dit is argumenteer dat 'n RNN-gebaseerde model 'n geldige alternatief kan wees vir 'n reël-gebaseerde een wat aandag a an sodanige faktore as tyd-verbruik, hergebruikbaardigheid vir verskillende verskillende verskillende van 'n doel taal en betekende kwaliteit resultate in morfologiese annotasie.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Armenian është një gjuhë me variacione të rëndësishme dhe burime të shpërndarë në mënyrë të pabarazishme të NLP për varietete të ndryshme. Një përpjekje është bërë për të procesuar një model RNN për anotacion morfologjik në bazë të të dhënave të ndryshme armene (të dhëna apo jo me korpra të anotuar morfologjikisht) dhe për të krahasuar rezultatet e anotacionit të RNN dhe modeleve të bazuar në rregulla. U kryen teste të ndryshme për të vlerësuar përdorimin e përsëritur të një modeli të paspecializuar limmatizimi dhe etiketave POS për varietetet e gjuhës me pak burime. Kërkimi u përqëndrua në tre dialekte dhe u zgjerua më tej në armenin perëndimor me një saktësi mesatare 94,00 % në limmatizim dhe 97,02% në etiketën POS si dhe një përdorueshmëri të mundshme të modeleve për të mbuluar lloje të ndryshme armene të tjera. Interesante, krahasimi i një modeli RNN të stërvitur në armenin lindor me model in bazuar në rregullat e Korpus Kombëtar Armenian Lindor të aplikuar në armenin perëndimor tregoi një përmirësim prej 19% në analizimin. Ky model mbulon 88,79% të një grupi të dhënash të shkurtër heterogjene në armenin perëndimor dhe mund të jetë një bazë për një anotacion masiv të trupit në atë standard. Argumentohet se një model i bazuar në RNN mund të jetë një alternativë e vlefshme për një alternativë të bazuar në rregulla duke i konsideruar faktorë të tillë si konsumi i kohës, ripërdorueshmëria për llojet e ndryshme të një gjuhe objektive dhe rezultate të rëndësishme kualitative në anotacion morfologjik.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>አርሜኒያን ልዩ ልዩነት እና የNLP ሀብት ለልዩ ልዩ ልዩነት የተከፈለ ቋንቋ ነው። የRNN ሞዴል በተለዩ አርሜኒያን ዳታ (በሞሮፎሎጂ ወይም በኮርፖርት ላይ ባይታወቀ) እና RNN እና የሥርዓት ሥርዓት ዓይነቶችን ለመተካከል ነው፡፡ በተለየ ቋንቋዎች ውስጥ ያልታወቀ የኢሜያል እና የPOS-tagging ጥያቄ ለመጠቀም የተለያዩ ፈተናዎች ተፈተናል፡፡ ምርመራው የሦስት ዲያብሎክ እና ወደ ምዕራባዊ አርማኔናዊ ተጨማሪ የ94,00 በመቶ እርግጠኛ ማስረጃ እና 97,02 በመቶ በፖስስ ማተሚያ እና ሌሎችን አርሜኒያን ልዩ ልዩ ልዩ ልዩ ልዩነት እንዲሸፍኑ የሚችል ምሳሌዎችን ለመከላከል ይችላል፡፡ በምሥራቅ አርሜኒያን ከምሥራቅ አርሜኒያ የብሔራዊ ኮርፓስ ሥርዓት ሥርዓት የተደረገውን የRNN ሞዴል ምሳሌ በምዕራብ አርሜኒያን በፓርቲው ውስጥ 19 በመቶ ያበረታታል፡፡ ይህ ምሳሌ 88,79 በመቶ ምዕራብ አርሜኒያን የካለ አካባቢ ዳታዎችን ይሸፍናል፡፡ It is argued that an RNN-based model can be a valid alternative to a rule-based one giving consideration to such factors as time-consumption, reusability for different varieties of a target language and significant qualitative results in morphological annotation.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Armenian is a language with significant variation and unevenly distributed NLP resources for different varieties.  Մորֆոլոգիական annoտացիայի ՌՆԹ-ի մոդելը փորձվում է վերլուծել տարբեր արմենյան տվյալների հիմքում (տրամադրված կամ ոչ մորֆոլոգիապես annoտացված կոպորա) և համեմատել ՌՆԹ-ի և կանոններով հիմնված մոդելների annoտացիայի արդյունքները: Տարբեր թեստեր էին կատարվել, որպեսզի գնահատենք լեմմատիզացիայի և POS-ի անմասնավոր մոդելի կրկին օգտագործումը թերռեսուրսների լեզվի բազմազանությունների համար: Հետազոտությունը կենտրոնացավ երեք դիալեկտների վրա և շարունակեց ընդլայնվել Արևմտյան Էրմենիային, որի միջին ճշգրտությունը 94,00 տոկոս էր լիմմատիզացիայի մեջ և 97,02 տոկոս՝ POS-ի նշանների մեջ, ինչպես նաև մոդելների հնարավոր վերաօգտագործելիությունը,  Հետաքրքիր է, Արևելյան Էրմենիայից վարժեցված ՌՆԹ մոդելի համեմատությունը Արևելյան Էրմենիայի ազգային կորպոսի կանոններով հիմնված մոդելի հետ, որը կիրառվել է Արևելյան Էրմենիայի դեպքում, ցույց տվեց 19 տոկոսո Այս մոդելը ներառում է արևմտյան Էրմենիայի կարճ հետերոգեն տվյալների 88,79 տոկոսը, և կարող է լինել հիմք այդ ստանդարտի մեծ մարմնի նշումների համար: Պարզվում է, որ ՌՆԹ-ով հիմնված մոդելը կարող է լինել օրենքներով հիմնված մի ճշգրիտ այլընտրանք, որը հաշվի առնում է այնպիսի գործոններ, ինչպիսիք են ժամանակի սպառումը, նպատակային լեզու տարբեր տեսակների կրկին օգտագործելիությունը և նշանակալի որակական արդ</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>আর্মেনিয়ান একটি ভাষা যাদের গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ বিভিন্ন আর্মেনিয়ান ডাটা ভিত্তিক ভিত্তিতে একটি আরএনএন মডেল প্রক্রিয়ার প্রচেষ্টা করা হয়েছে (নৈতিক ভাবে কোর্পোরা প্রদান করা হয় বা না দিয়ে), আর আরএনএন এবং নিয়মিত মডেল Different tests were carried out to evaluate the reuse of an unspecialized model of lemmatization and POS-tagging for under-resourced language varieties.  গবেষণাটি তিনটি ডায়ালগের উপর মনোযোগ দিয়ে পশ্চিম আর্মেনিয়ানের দিকে আরো বাড়িয়ে দিয়েছে যার মানে সঠিকভাবে ৯৪,০০০% লাগবে এবং পোস ট্যাগিং এ ৭,২% এবং অন্য আর্মেনিয়ার মজার ব্যাপারে, পূর্ব আর্মেনিয়ান ন্যাশনাল কোর্পাস নিয়মের মডেলের প্রশিক্ষণ প্রদান করা এক আরএনএন মডেলের তুলনায় পশ্চিম আর্মেনিয়ার প্রতি পার্জিং এ ১৯%  এই মডেলটি পশ্চিম আর্মেনিয়ার সংক্ষিপ্ত বৈশিষ্ট্যাবলী তথ্যের মধ্যে ৮৮,৭৯% কাভার করে থাকে, এবং এই স্ট্যান্ডারে বিশাল কোর্পাসে এটি যুক্তি দেয়া হয়েছে যে একটি RNN ভিত্তিক মডেল একটি বৈধ বিকল্প হতে পারে যেখানে একটি নিয়ম ভিত্তিক বিকল্প হতে পারে যারা টাইমব্যবহার, বিভিন্ন ধরনের লক্ষ্য ভাষার পুনরায় ব্</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Ermenik müxtəlif çeşitlər üçün mövcud dəyişiklik və nLP kaynaqları olan dildir. Farklı Erminik məlumatlarının (morphologically annotated corpora təyin edilmiş və ya morfologically annotated corpora təyin edilmiş və ya yox edilmiş) tərzlərinin RNN modelini və hökmlərin təyin edilmiş modellerinin nəticələrini salmaq üçün bir nəsihət olunur. Müxtəlif sınaqlar limmatizasyonun və POS-etiketlərinin çoxluğunun yenidən istifadəsini değerləşdirmək üçün işlədilər. Bu araştırma üç dialektə odaqlandı və daha sonra Batı Ermini tərəfində lemmatizasyonda 94,00 % və POS etiketində 97,02 % tərəfində olan orta dəqiqliyi ilə uzatdı, başqa ərmini müxtəlif müxtəlif müxtəlif müxtəlif müxtəlif müxtəlif müxtəlif müxtəlif müxtəlif modellerin yenidən istifadə edilməsi də İlginç ki, Şərqi Ermeniyyətdə təhsil edilmiş RNN model in in şərqi Ermeniyyətdə təhsil edilən şərqi Ermeniyyətdə Qərqi Ermeniyyətə uyğulanmış qurbanlıq qurbanlıq modeli ilə müqayisədə 19%-dən artırmağını göstərdi. Bu model Batı Ermeniyyadakı qısa heterogenen veri setinin 88.79%-ini örtür və bu standartda böyük korpus annotasyonu olar. RNN-ə dayanan modellərin dəyişiklik alternatifi olaraq, zamanı istifadə etmək, məqsəd dillərinin fərqli cür növbətlərinin yenidən istifadə edilməsi və morfolojik növbətlərinin möhkəm qabiliyyətli sonuçları ilə düşünüb daxil edilən faktörlərə istifadə edilir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Armenski je jezik sa značajnim varijacijom i nepravedno raspodijeljenim NLP resursima za različite razine. Pokušava se obraditi model RNN za morfološku annotaciju na temelju različitih Armenskih podataka (pruženih ili ne morfološki annotiranih korpora) i usporediti rezultate annotacije RNN-a i modela baziranih na pravilima. Provedeni su različiti testovi kako bi procijenili ponovno upotrebu neopecijaliziranog modela limmatizacije i označavanja POS-a za neposredne jezičke razine. Istraživanje se fokusiralo na tri dijalekta i dalje se proširilo na zapadnu Armensku s srednjom preciznošću od 94,00 % u lematizaciji i 97,02 % u označavanju POS-a, kao i mogućom ponovnom korištenju modela za pokrivanje različitih Armenskih različitih vrsta. Zanimljivo je da je usporedba modela RNN obučenog na istočnoj Armeniji sa pravilnim modelom na istočnom Armenskom nacionalnom korpusu primjenom na zapadnu Armeniju pokazala poboljšanje od 19% u analizu. Ovaj model pokriva 88.79% kratke heterogenezne podatke na zapadnom Armenskom, i može biti početna linija za veliku korpusnu annotaciju u tom standardu. Tvrdi se da model na RNN-u može biti valjan alternativ na pravilima koji daje razmatranje faktorima poput potrošnje vremena, ponovno korištenja različitih različitih različitih različitih različitih jezika ciljnog jezika i značajnih kvalitativnih rezultata morfološke annotacije.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Arménština je jazyk s významnou variací a nerovnoměrně rozloženými zdroji NLP pro různé odrůdy. Je zkoušena zpracovat RNN model pro morfologickou anotaci na základě různých arménských dat (poskytnutých či nikoli s morfologicky anotovanými korpusy) a porovnat výsledky anotace RNN a pravidelně založené modely. Byly provedeny různé testy pro vyhodnocení opětovného využití nespecializovaného modelu lemmatizace a POS-tagging pro nedostatečně zdrojové jazykové odrůdy. Výzkum se zaměřil na tři dialekty a dále se rozšířil na západní arménštinu se střední přesností 94,00% v lemmatizaci a 97,02% v POS-tagging, stejně jako možné opakované použitelnosti modelů pro pokrytí různých dalších arménských odrůd. Zajímavé je, že porovnání RNN modelu trénovaného na východní Arménštině s východním arménským národním korpusem založeným na pravidlech aplikovaného na západní arménštině ukázalo zvýšení 19% v parsování. Tento model pokrývá 88,79% krátkého heterogenního datového souboru v západní arménštině a může být základním bodem pro masivní korpusovou anotaci v tomto standardu. Je argumentováno, že model založený na RNN může být platnou alternativou k modelu založenému na pravidlech s ohledem na faktory jako časová spotřeba, opakovaná použitelnost pro různé odrůdy cílového jazyka a významné kvalitativní výsledky morfologické anotace.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Armeenia keel on keel, millel on märkimisväärne varieeruvus ja erinevate sortide jaoks ebaühtlaselt jaotatud NLP ressursid. Püütakse töödelda RNN mudelit morfoloogiliste annotatsioonide jaoks erinevate Armeenia andmete põhjal (morfoloogiliselt annoteeritud korpustega või mitte) ning võrrelda RNN ja reeglipõhiste mudelite annotatsiooni tulemusi. Erinevad testid viidi läbi, et hinnata spetsialiseerimata lemmatiseerimise ja POS-märgistamise mudeli taaskasutamist alaressurssidega keelesortidele. Uuringud keskendusid kolmele dialektile ja laienesid Lääne-Armeeniale keskmise täpsusega 94,00% lemmatiseerimisel ja 97,02% POS-märgistamisel, samuti mudelite võimaliku taaskasutatavusega, et katta erinevad teised Armeenia sortid. Huvitav on, et Ida-Armeenia keelele koolitatud RNN mudeli võrdlemine Ida-Armeenia Rahvuskorpuse reeglitel põhineva mudeliga, mida rakendati Lääne-Armeenia keelele, näitas 19% paremat parsimist. See mudel hõlmab 88,79% Lääne-Armeenia keelsest lühikesest heterogeensest andmekogumist ja võib olla aluseks massiivsele korpuse annotatsioonile selles standardis. Väidetakse, et RNN-il põhinev mudel võib olla õige alternatiiv reeglitel põhinevale mudelile, võttes arvesse selliseid tegureid nagu aja tarbimine, sihtkeele eri sortide korduvkasutatavus ja märkimisväärsed kvalitatiivsed tulemused morfoloogilisel märgistamisel.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ca>L'armeni és un llenguatge amb variació significativa i recursos de NLP distribuïts desigualment per diferents varietats. S'intenta processar un model de RNN per anotació morfològica sobre la base de diferents dades armenes (proporcionades o no amb corpores morfològicament anotats), i comparar els resultats d'anotació dels RNN i dels models basats en regles. Es van fer diferents tests per avaluar la reutilització d'un model no especialitzat de limmatització i etiqueta POS per varietats de llenguatges poc resources. La investigació es va centrar en tres dialectes i s'estendre més a l'armenia occidental amb una mitjana de precisió del 94,00 % en la limmatització i del 97,02 % en l'etiquetage POS, així com una possibilitat de reutilització de models per cobrir diferents altres varietats armenes. Interessant, la comparació d'un model RNN entrenat en armeni oriental amb el model basat en la regla del Corps Nacional de l'Armenia oriental aplicat en armeni occidental va mostrar un increment del 19% en l'analització. Aquest model cobre el 88,79% d'un petit conjunt de dades heterogènes en armenia occidental, i podria ser la base d'una gran anotació de corpus en aquest estàndard. Se argumenta que un model basat en RNN pot ser una alternativa válida a una basada en regles, tenint en compte factors com el consum de temps, la reutilització per diferents varietats d'una llengua d'objectiu i resultats qualitatius significatius en anotació morfològica.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Armenia on kieli, jolla on merkittäviä vaihteluja ja epätasaisesti jakautuneita NLP-resursseja eri lajikkeille. Pyritään käsittelemään RNN-mallia morfologista annotointia varten erilaisten armenialaisten tietojen perusteella (morfologisesti annotoiduilla korpusilla tai ei) sekä vertailemaan RNN:n ja sääntöpohjaisten mallien annotointituloksia. Eri testejä suoritettiin arvioimaan, miten lemmatisaatio- ja POS-tagging-mallit uusitaan aliresurssoiduille kielilajikkeille. Tutkimuksessa keskityttiin kolmeen murteeseen ja laajennettiin edelleen Länsi-armeniaan keskimäärin 94,00% lemmatisoinnissa ja 97,02% POS-taggingissa sekä mahdollistettiin mallien uudelleenkäytettävyys kattamaan erilaisia armenialaisia lajikkeita. Mielenkiintoista on, että Itä-Armeniaan koulutetun RNN-mallin vertailu Itä-Armenian kansallisen korpusen sääntöpohjaiseen malliin, jota sovellettiin Länsi-Armeniaan, osoitti 19 prosentin parannuksen jäsentämisessä. Tämä malli kattaa 88,79% lyhyestä heterogeenisestä Länsi-armeniankielisestä aineistosta, ja voisi olla perusta massiiviselle korpusmerkinnälle kyseisessä standardissa. Väitetään, että RNN-pohjainen malli voi olla pätevä vaihtoehto sääntöpohjaiselle mallille, jossa otetaan huomioon muun muassa ajankulutus, kohdekielen uudelleenkäytettävyys eri lajikkeille ja merkittävät laadulliset tulokset morfologisessa merkinnässä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>pon Wang text-editor-action Awakdhéwé sing dipolehko nganggo telu dialectu lan nganggo sênêmêr sing katêpakan karo Armani sing basa, dadine kapan kanggo kalagayuté awak dhéwé, awak dhéwé karo 1994,00% lan lemmatirasyon lan 1997,02% lan tambah sing ditawak dhéwé, tambah kayiné ngejaraké model sing bisa ngejaraké koyo ngono ca Kowe isih, sampeyan karo model DNN sing ditambah 'Orient Armian' nganggo perusahaan Rasané Armani sing gawe barang nggawe barang kelas Jejaran Nalikasi model iki wis ngacah-cah bener PIN</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>Armenian is a language with significant variation and unevenly distributed NLP resources for different varieties.  ניסיון נעשה לעבד דוגמא RNN עבור הערות מורפולוגית על בסיס נתונים ארמנים שונים (שנספקים או לא עם גופורה מורפולוגית מורפולוגית), ולהשוות את תוצאות הערות של RNN ומדוגמנים מבוססים על חוקים. ביצעו בדיקות שונות כדי להעריך את השימוש מחדש של מודל לא מיוחד של לימטיזציה ומתג POS לסוגים שפות מתחת למשאבים. המחקר התמקד בשלושה דיאלקטים וממשיך להתרחב למערב ארמני עם מדויקת ממוצעת של 94,00% בלמטיזציה ו-97,02% בלמטגים POS, כמו גם ניתן להשתמש מחדש של דוגמנים כדי לכסות מגוונים ארמנים אחרים שונים. מעניין, השוואה של דוגמנית RNN מאומנת על ארמני מזרחי עם דוגמנית המבוססת על חוקי הקורפוס הלאומי המזרחי הארמני שמשתמשת על ארמני המערבי הראה שיפור של 19 אחוזים בפרקים. מודל זה מכסה 88,79% מסט נתונים היטרוגני קצר בארמנית המערבית, ויכול להיות בסיס עבור ציון גופוס מסיבי בסטנדרט הזה. טוענים שמודל מבוסס על RNN יכול להיות אלטרנטיבה נכונה לאחרונה מבוססת על חוקים שמשקלת גורמים כאלה הזמן-שימוש, שימוש מחדש למגוונים שונים של שפת המטרה ותוצאות איכותיות משמעותיות בהכתבה מורפולוגית.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>@ item Spelling dictionary An jarraba wani misãlin RNN wa mai zartar da shirin morfologi a kan bayan data masu buƙata na armanci (da aka azurta ko kuma ba da marofogi ya yi zartar da Corpo), kuma a sami matsalar fassaran zartarwa na RNN da misãlai masu rubutun. An aiko jarrabo dabam-daban dõmin a evaluate amfani da wata misali na lissafa da ba'a sani ba na salãmar da tagogi na mais-tagning wa wasu nau'i da ke ƙaranci-resource. Research na fokus a kan misalin uku na bayani kuma aka ƙara shi zuwa Tsarama na gabas, yana da ma'aunin taƙaitacce na 94,000% cikin lammasi da 97,01% cikin bastarwa na PoS-tagning, da sami mai yiwuwa ya yi amfani da misãlai dõmin su tsare wasu dabam-aram. Ina sha'anar, kafarin wani misalin RNN wanda aka yi wa tunkuɗe a gabas-arama na armani da misãlin rubutun National Corbus na gabas ya applied to West Aramenan ya nuna wani ƙari da 19% a parse. Wannan misalin na rufe 88,79% daga matsayin mutane na tsohon da aka samu a cikin Tsarama na Tsarama, kuma yana iya kasa wani basalin matsayi mai girma ga nau'in nan. Ana yi jãyayya da cewa wata misalin a kan RNN ya zama wata shida mai inganci wa wata rubutu mai inganci, wanda ya yi bincike da factori kamar matuƙar-amfani da lokaci, kuma yana amfani da nau'in wasu nau'i-harshe na walƙin da aka yi amfani da shi, da matsalar masu muhimmi na mutafalojiki.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Armenščina je jezik z velikimi variacijami in neenakomerno porazdeljenimi viri NLP za različne sorte. Poskušamo obdelati RNN model za morfološko označevanje na podlagi različnih armenskih podatkov (zagotovljenih ali ne z morfološko označenimi korpusi) in primerjati rezultate označevanja RNN in pravil temelječih modelov. Izvedeni so bili različni testi za oceno ponovne uporabe nespecializiranega modela lemmatizacije in POS-označevanja za premalo virov jezikovnih sort. Raziskava se je osredotočila na tri narečja in se nadalje razširila na zahodno armensko s povprečno natančnostjo 94,00% pri lemmatizaciji in 97,02% pri POS-označevanju ter možnostjo ponovne uporabe modelov za pokrivanje različnih drugih armenskih sort. Zanimivo je, da je primerjava modela RNN, usposobljenega na vzhodnem armenskem jeziku, z modelom vzhodnega armenskega narodnega korpusa, ki temelji na pravilih vzhodnega armenskega narodnega korpusa, ki se uporablja na zahodnem armenskem jeziku, pokazala 19-odstotno povečanje razčlenitve. Ta model zajema 88,79% kratkega heterogenega nabora podatkov v zahodnem armenskem jeziku in bi lahko bil osnova za množično korpusno označevanje v tem standardu. Trdi se, da je model, ki temelji na RNN, lahko veljavna alternativa pravilu in upošteva dejavnike, kot so poraba časa, ponovna uporabnost za različne sorte ciljnega jezika in pomembni kvalitativni rezultati pri morfološkem označevanju.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ཨར་མི་ནི་ཡིས་སྐད་ཡིག་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་མ་དང་ཐོག་ཁུངས་རྩིས་མེད་པའི་NLP རྒྱུ་དངོས་ཐོག An attempt is made to process an RNN model for morphological annotation on the basis of different Armenian data (provided or not with morphologically annotated corpora), and to compare the annotation results of RNN and rule-based models. སྐད་རིགས་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་དམིགས་འཛུགས་ཀྱི་མིག་གཟུགས་རིས་ལ་རྒྱབ་སྐྱོར་མེད་པའི་རྣམ་པ་ཞིག་ལས་བརྟག་དཔྱད་འགྱུར་བ་ཡིན་པས། འཚོལ་ཞིབ་འདིས་dialects གསུམ་གྱི་ནང་དུ་དམིགས་བསལ་ནུས་པ་ཡིན་མཁན་གྱི་ཨར་མེན་གྱི་ཕྱོགས་འགོད་སུ་ཡོད་པ་ལྟར་ན། དར་མེན་གྱི་རྒྱ་ཆ་ཚན་མ་འདྲ་བ་དང་97,02% Interestingly, the comparison of an RNN model trained on Eastern Armenian with the Eastern Armenian National Corpus rule-based model applied to Western Armenian Armenians showed an enhancement of 19% in parsing. རྣམ་གྲངས་འདིས་ནུབ་ཀྱི་ཨ་རམ་ཡིན་པའི་ཚད་གཞི་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་88.79%སྐོར་ཡོད། It is argued that an RNN-based model can be a valid alternative to a rule-based one giving consideration to such factors as time-consumption, reusability for different varieties of a target language and significant qualitative results in morphological annotation.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Uralic Language Identification (ULI) 2020 shared task dataset and the Wanca 2017 corpora<fixed-case>ULI</fixed-case>) 2020 shared task dataset and the Wanca 2017 corpora</title>
      <author><first>Tommi</first><last>Jauhiainen</last></author>
      <author><first>Heidi</first><last>Jauhiainen</last></author>
      <author><first>Niko</first><last>Partanen</last></author>
      <author><first>Krister</first><last>Lindén</last></author>
      <pages>173–185</pages>
      <abstract>This article introduces the Wanca 2017 web corpora from which the sentences written in minor Uralic languages were collected for the test set of the Uralic Language Identification (ULI) 2020 shared task. We describe the ULI shared task and how the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_set">test set</a> was constructed using the Wanca 2017 corpora and texts in different languages from the Leipzig corpora collection. We also provide the results of a baseline language identification experiment conducted using the ULI 2020 dataset.</abstract>
      <url hash="c77a4cfd">2020.vardial-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>jauhiainen-etal-2020-uralic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>HeLju@VarDial 2020 : Social Media Variety Geolocation with BERT Models<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>e<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ju@<fixed-case>V</fixed-case>ar<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ial 2020: Social Media Variety Geolocation with <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> Models</title>
      <author><first>Yves</first><last>Scherrer</last></author>
      <author><first>Nikola</first><last>Ljubešić</last></author>
      <pages>202–211</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the Helsinki-Ljubljana contribution to the VarDial shared task on social media variety geolocation. Our solutions are based on the BERT Transformer models, the constrained versions of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> reaching 1st place in two subtasks and 3rd place in one subtask, while our unconstrained models outperform all the constrained systems by a large margin. We show in our analyses that Transformer-based models outperform traditional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> by far, and that improvements obtained by pre-training <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> on large quantities of (mostly standard) text are significant, but not drastic, with single-language models also outperforming multilingual models. Our manual analysis shows that two types of signals are the most crucial for a (mis)prediction : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named_entity">named entities</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">dialectal features</a>, both of which are handled well by our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="8f99a4bf">2020.vardial-1.19</url>
      <bibkey>scherrer-ljubesic-2020-helju</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Experiments in Language Variety Geolocation and Dialect Identification</title>
      <author><first>Tommi</first><last>Jauhiainen</last></author>
      <author><first>Heidi</first><last>Jauhiainen</last></author>
      <author><first>Krister</first><last>Lindén</last></author>
      <pages>220–231</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we describe the systems we used when participating in the VarDial Evaluation Campaign organized as part of the 7th workshop on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> for similar languages, varieties and dialects. The shared tasks we participated in were the second edition of the Romanian Dialect Identification (RDI) and the first edition of the Social Media Variety Geolocation (SMG). The submissions of our SUKI team used generative language models based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naive_Bayes_classifier">Naive Bayes</a> and character n-grams.</abstract>
      <url hash="3c7daedc">2020.vardial-1.21</url>
      <bibkey>jauhiainen-etal-2020-experiments</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/moroco">MOROCO</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Exploring the Power of Romanian BERT for Dialect Identification<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>omanian <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> for Dialect Identification</title>
      <author><first>George-Eduard</first><last>Zaharia</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrei-Marius</first><last>Avram</last></author>
      <author><first>Dumitru-Clementin</first><last>Cercel</last></author>
      <author><first>Traian</first><last>Rebedea</last></author>
      <pages>232–241</pages>
      <abstract>Dialect identification represents a key aspect for improving a series of tasks, for example, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opinion_mining">opinion mining</a>, considering that the location of the speaker can greatly influence the attitude towards a subject. In this work, we describe the systems developed by our team for VarDial 2020 : Romanian Dialect Identification, a task specifically created for challenging participants to solve the previously mentioned issue. More specifically, we introduce a series of neural systems based on Transformers, that combine a BERT model exclusively pre-trained on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romanian_language">Romanian language</a> with techniques such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adversarial_system">adversarial training</a> or character-level embeddings. By using these approaches, we were able to obtain a 0.6475 macro F1 score on the test dataset, thus allowing us to be ranked 5th out of 8 participant teams.</abstract>
      <url hash="ba7812fd">2020.vardial-1.22</url>
      <bibkey>zaharia-etal-2020-exploring</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/moroco">MOROCO</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ronec">RONEC</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Geolocation of Tweets with a BiLSTM Regression Model<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>i<fixed-case>LSTM</fixed-case> Regression Model</title>
      <author><first>Piyush</first><last>Mishra</last></author>
      <pages>283–289</pages>
      <abstract>Identifying a user’s location can be useful for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recommender_system">recommendation systems</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demography">demographic analyses</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergency_management">disaster outbreak monitoring</a>. Although <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a> allows users to voluntarily reveal their location, such information is n’t universally available. Analyzing a tweet can provide a general estimation of a tweet location while giving insight into the dialect of the user and other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marker_(linguistics)">linguistic markers</a>. Such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">linguistic attributes</a> can be used to provide a regional approximation of tweet origins. In this paper, we present a neural regression model that can identify the linguistic intricacies of a tweet to predict the location of the user. The final <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> identifies the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">dialect</a> embedded in the tweet and predicts the location of the tweet.</abstract>
      <url hash="e9990a78">2020.vardial-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>mishra-2020-geolocation</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>