<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.sdp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Scholarly Document Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Muthu Kumar</first><last>Chandrasekaran</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anita</first><last>de Waard</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Guy</first><last>Feigenblat</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dayne</first><last>Freitag</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Tirthankar</first><last>Ghosal</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Eduard</first><last>Hovy</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Petr</first><last>Knoth</last></editor>
      <editor><first>David</first><last>Konopnicki</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Philipp</first><last>Mayr</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Robert M.</first><last>Patton</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Michal</first><last>Shmueli-Scheuer</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="a32476e4">2020.sdp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sdp-2020-scholarly</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>The future of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ArXiv">arXiv</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discovery_(observation)">knowledge discovery</a> in open science<fixed-case>X</fixed-case>iv and knowledge discovery in open science</title>
      <author><first>Steinn</first><last>Sigurdsson</last></author>
      <pages>7–9</pages>
      <abstract>arXiv, the preprint server for the physical and mathematical sciences, is in its third decade of operation. As the flow of new, open access research increases inexorably, the challenges to keep up with and discover research content also become greater. I will discuss the status and future of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ArXiv">arXiv</a>, and possibilities and plans to make more effective use of the research database to enhance ongoing research efforts.</abstract>
      <url hash="5babaa19">2020.sdp-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>sigurdsson-2020-future</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Acknowledgement Entity Recognition in CORD-19 Papers<fixed-case>CORD</fixed-case>-19 Papers</title>
      <author><first>Jian</first><last>Wu</last></author>
      <author><first>Pei</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Xin</first><last>Wei</last></author>
      <author><first>Sarah</first><last>Rajtmajer</last></author>
      <author><first>C. Lee</first><last>Giles</last></author>
      <author><first>Christopher</first><last>Griffin</last></author>
      <pages>10–19</pages>
      <abstract>Acknowledgements are ubiquitous in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Academic_publishing">scholarly papers</a>. Existing acknowledgement entity recognition methods assume all named entities are acknowledged. Here, we examine the nuances between acknowledged and named entities by analyzing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_(linguistics)">sentence structure</a>. We develop an acknowledgement extraction system, AckExtract based on open-source text mining software and evaluate our method using manually labeled data. AckExtract uses the PDF of a scholarly paper as input and outputs <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acknowledgement_(data_networks)">acknowledgement entities</a>. Results show an overall performance of F_1=0.92. We built a supplementary database by linking CORD-19 papers with acknowledgement entities extracted by AckExtract including persons and organizations and find that only up to 5060 % of named entities are actually acknowledged. We further analyze chronological trends of acknowledgement entities in CORD-19 papers. All codes and labeled data are publicly available at https://github.com/lamps-lab/ackextract.</abstract>
      <url hash="dc7c6b4d">2020.sdp-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.3</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940712" />
      <bibkey>wu-etal-2020-acknowledgement</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/lamps-lab/ackextract" additional="false">lamps-lab/ackextract</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Effective <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_representation">distributed representations</a> for academic expert search</title>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Berger</last></author>
      <author><first>Jakub</first><last>Zavrel</last></author>
      <author><first>Paul</first><last>Groth</last></author>
      <pages>56–71</pages>
      <abstract>Expert search aims to find and rank experts based on a user’s query. In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Academy">academia</a>, retrieving experts is an efficient way to navigate through a large amount of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outline_of_academic_disciplines">academic knowledge</a>. Here, we study how different distributed representations of academic papers (i.e. embeddings) impact academic expert retrieval. We use the Microsoft Academic Graph dataset and experiment with different configurations of a document-centric voting model for retrieval. In particular, we explore the impact of the use of contextualized embeddings on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_search_engine">search</a> performance. We also present results for paper embeddings that incorporate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citation">citation information</a> through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Retrofitting">retrofitting</a>. Additionally, experiments are conducted using different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_technique">techniques</a> for assigning author weights based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Author_order">author order</a>. We observe that using contextual embeddings produced by a transformer model trained for sentence similarity tasks produces the most effective paper representations for document-centric expert retrieval. However, retrofitting the paper embeddings and using elaborate author contribution weighting strategies did not improve retrieval performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="b792b177">2020.sdp-1.7</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.7</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940716" />
      <bibkey>berger-etal-2020-effective</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/mabergerx/SDP500_expert_search" additional="false">mabergerx/SDP500_expert_search</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/microsoft-academic-graph">Microsoft Academic Graph</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Multi-task Peer-Review Score Prediction</title>
      <author><first>Jiyi</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <author><first>Ayaka</first><last>Sato</last></author>
      <author><first>Kazuya</first><last>Shimura</last></author>
      <author><first>Fumiyo</first><last>Fukumoto</last></author>
      <pages>121–126</pages>
      <abstract>Automatic prediction on the peer-review aspect scores of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Academic_publishing">academic papers</a> can be a useful assistant tool for both reviewers and authors. To handle the small size of published datasets on the target aspect of scores, we propose a multi-task approach to leverage additional information from other aspects of scores for improving the performance of the target. Because one of the problems of building multi-task models is how to select the proper resources of auxiliary tasks and how to select the proper shared structures. We propose a multi-task shared structure encoding approach which automatically selects good shared network structures as well as good auxiliary resources. The experiments based on peer-review datasets show that our approach is effective and has better performance on the target scores than the single-task method and naive multi-task methods.</abstract>
      <url hash="b5f69f40">2020.sdp-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.14</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940727" />
      <bibkey>li-etal-2020-multi-task</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/peerread">PeerRead</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>ERLKG : Entity Representation Learning and Knowledge Graph based association analysis of COVID-19 through mining of unstructured biomedical corpora<fixed-case>ERLKG</fixed-case>: Entity Representation Learning and Knowledge Graph based association analysis of <fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 through mining of unstructured biomedical corpora</title>
      <author><first>Sayantan</first><last>Basu</last></author>
      <author><first>Sinchani</first><last>Chakraborty</last></author>
      <author><first>Atif</first><last>Hassan</last></author>
      <author><first>Sana</first><last>Siddique</last></author>
      <author><first>Ashish</first><last>Anand</last></author>
      <pages>127–137</pages>
      <abstract>We introduce a generic, human-out-of-the-loop pipeline, ERLKG, to perform rapid association analysis of any biomedical entity with other existing entities from a corpora of the same domain. Our pipeline consists of a Knowledge Graph (KG) created from the Open Source CORD-19 dataset by fully automating the procedure of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_extraction">information extraction</a> using SciBERT. The best latent entity representations are then found by benchnmarking different KG embedding techniques on the task of link prediction using a Graph Convolution Network Auto Encoder (GCN-AE). We demonstrate the utility of ERLKG with respect to COVID-19 through multiple qualitative evaluations. Due to the lack of a gold standard, we propose a relatively large intrinsic evaluation dataset for COVID-19 and use it for validating the top two performing KG embedding techniques. We find TransD to be the best performing KG embedding technique with Pearson and Spearman correlation scores of 0.4348 and 0.4570 respectively. We demonstrate that a considerable number of ERLKG’s top protein, chemical and disease predictions are currently in consideration for COVID-19 related research.</abstract>
      <url hash="a7ae7621">2020.sdp-1.15</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.15</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940725" />
      <bibkey>basu-etal-2020-erlkg</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/sayantanbasu05/ERKLG" additional="false">sayantanbasu05/ERKLG</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bc5cdr">BC5CDR</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/cord-19">CORD-19</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ncbi-disease-1">NCBI Disease</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Scaling Systematic Literature Reviews with Machine Learning Pipelines</title>
      <author><first>Seraphina</first><last>Goldfarb-Tarrant</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexander</first><last>Robertson</last></author>
      <author><first>Jasmina</first><last>Lazic</last></author>
      <author><first>Theodora</first><last>Tsouloufi</last></author>
      <author><first>Louise</first><last>Donnison</last></author>
      <author><first>Karen</first><last>Smyth</last></author>
      <pages>184–195</pages>
      <abstract>Systematic reviews, which entail the extraction of data from large numbers of scientific documents, are an ideal avenue for the application of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning</a>. They are vital to many fields of science and philanthropy, but are very time-consuming and require experts. Yet the three main stages of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systematic_review">systematic review</a> are easily done automatically : searching for documents can be done via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_programming_interface">APIs</a> and scrapers, selection of relevant documents can be done via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_classification">binary classification</a>, and extraction of data can be done via sequence-labelling classification. Despite the promise of automation for this field, little research exists that examines the various ways to automate each of these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a>. We construct a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pipeline_(software)">pipeline</a> that automates each of these aspects, and experiment with many human-time vs. system quality trade-offs. We test the ability of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifiers</a> to work well on small amounts of data and to generalise to data from countries not represented in the training data. We test different types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_extraction">data extraction</a> with varying difficulty in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation</a>, and five different neural architectures to do the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_extraction">extraction</a>. We find that we can get surprising <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> and generalisability of the whole <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pipeline_(software)">pipeline system</a> with only 2 weeks of human-expert annotation, which is only 15 % of the time it takes to do the whole review manually and can be repeated and extended to new data with no additional effort.</abstract>
      <url hash="2240aaf3">2020.sdp-1.21</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.21</doi>
      <bibkey>goldfarb-tarrant-etal-2020-scaling</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/seraphinatarrant/systematic_reviews" additional="false">seraphinatarrant/systematic_reviews</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Document-Level Definition Detection in Scholarly Documents : Existing Models, Error Analyses, and Future Directions</title>
      <author><first>Dongyeop</first><last>Kang</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrew</first><last>Head</last></author>
      <author><first>Risham</first><last>Sidhu</last></author>
      <author><first>Kyle</first><last>Lo</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Weld</last></author>
      <author><first>Marti A.</first><last>Hearst</last></author>
      <pages>196–206</pages>
      <abstract>The task of definition detection is important for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Academic_publishing">scholarly papers</a>, because papers often make use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jargon">technical terminology</a> that may be unfamiliar to readers. Despite prior work on definition detection, current approaches are far from being accurate enough to use in realworld applications. In this paper, we first perform in-depth error analysis of the current best performing definition detection system and discover major causes of errors. Based on this analysis, we develop a new definition detection system, HEDDEx, that utilizes syntactic features, transformer encoders, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuristic_(computer_science)">heuristic filters</a>, and evaluate it on a standard sentence-level benchmark. Because current <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benchmarking">benchmarks</a> evaluate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sampling_(statistics)">randomly sampled sentences</a>, we propose an alternative <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evaluation">evaluation</a> that assesses every sentence within a document. This allows for evaluating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a> in addition to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">precision</a>. HEDDEx outperforms the leading system on both the sentence-level and the document-level tasks, by 12.7 F1 points and 14.4 F1 points, respectively. We note that performance on the high-recall document-level task is much lower than in the standard evaluation approach, due to the necessity of incorporation of document structure as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_feature">features</a>. We discuss remaining challenges in document-level definition detection, ideas for improvements, and potential issues for the development of reading aid applications.</abstract>
      <url hash="f37ba031">2020.sdp-1.22</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="00000000">2020.sdp-1.22.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.22</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940724" />
      <bibkey>kang-etal-2020-document</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/allenai/scholarphi" additional="false">allenai/scholarphi</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>A New Neural Search and Insights Platform for Navigating and Organizing AI Research<fixed-case>AI</fixed-case> Research</title>
      <author><first>Marzieh</first><last>Fadaee</last></author>
      <author><first>Olga</first><last>Gureenkova</last></author>
      <author><first>Fernando</first><last>Rejon Barrera</last></author>
      <author><first>Carsten</first><last>Schnober</last></author>
      <author><first>Wouter</first><last>Weerkamp</last></author>
      <author><first>Jakub</first><last>Zavrel</last></author>
      <pages>207–213</pages>
      <abstract>To provide AI researchers with modern tools for dealing with the explosive growth of the research literature in their field, we introduce a new platform, AI Research Navigator, that combines classical <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keyword_search">keyword search</a> with neural retrieval to discover and organize relevant literature. The system provides <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_engine_technology">search</a> at multiple levels of textual granularity, from sentences to aggregations across documents, both in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language</a> and through navigation in a domain specific Knowledge Graph. We give an overview of the overall architecture of the system and of the components for document analysis, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Question_answering">question answering</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_engine_technology">search</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analytics">analytics</a>, expert search, and recommendations.</abstract>
      <url hash="23b1319d">2020.sdp-1.23</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.23</doi>
      <bibkey>fadaee-etal-2020-new</bibkey>
    <title_ar>منصة جديدة للبحث والرؤى العصبية للتنقل وتنظيم أبحاث الذكاء الاصطناعي</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Une nouvelle plateforme de recherche neuronale et d'informations pour naviguer et organiser la recherche sur l'IA</title_fr>
      <title_pt>Uma nova plataforma de pesquisa e insights neurais para navegar e organizar pesquisas de IA</title_pt>
      <title_es>Una nueva plataforma de búsqueda e información neuronal para navegar y organizar la investigación de IA</title_es>
      <title_ja>AI研究のナビゲートと整理のための新しいニューラルサーチとインサイトのプラットフォーム</title_ja>
      <title_zh>用导航、 AI 全新神经搜察平台</title_zh>
      <title_hi>नेविगेट करने और एआई अनुसंधान के आयोजन के लिए एक नया तंत्रिका खोज और अंतर्दृष्टि मंच</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Новая платформа нейронного поиска и анализа для навигации и организации исследований ИИ</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Ardán Nua Cuardaigh Néar agus Léargais chun Taighde AI a Loingseoireacht agus a Eagrú</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Új idegkeresési és betekintési platform az AI kutatások navigációjához és szervezéséhez</title_hu>
      <title_el>Μια νέα πλατφόρμα Νευρικής αναζήτησης και Γνώσεων για την πλοήγηση και την οργάνωση της έρευνας τεχνητής νοημοσύνης</title_el>
      <title_it>Una nuova piattaforma di ricerca e approfondimenti neurali per la navigazione e l'organizzazione della ricerca sull'intelligenza artificiale</title_it>
      <title_kk>Жаңа Ньюралды іздеу және Интинитт платформасы AI зерттеулерді баптау және баптау</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Nauja AI mokslinių tyrimų navigacijos ir organizavimo neurologinių paieškų ir apžvalgų platforma</title_lt>
      <title_ml>Name</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Pjattaforma Ġdida ta’ Tfittxija u Invista Newrali għan-Navigazzjoni u l-Organizzazzjoni tar-Riċerka tal-AI</title_mt>
      <title_mk>Нова платформа за неурално пребарување и набљудување за навигација и организација на истражување на AI</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Name</title_ms>
      <title_ro>O nouă platformă de căutare neurală și informații pentru navigarea și organizarea cercetării AI</title_ro>
      <title_mn>Шинэ сэтгэл судалгааны судалгааны шинэ сэтгэл судалгаа болон Интернэйтс</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Nowa platforma wyszukiwania i wglądów neuronowych do nawigacji i organizacji badań sztucznej inteligencji</title_pl>
      <title_si>අළුත් න්‍යුරාල් සොයාගන්න සහ ඉන්සිට්ස් ප්ලේට්ෆෝම්</title_si>
      <title_so>A New Neural Search and Insights Platform for Navigating and Organizing AI Research</title_so>
      <title_no>Name</title_no>
      <title_sr>Nova Neuralna potraga i Insights platforma za navigaciju i organizaciju istraživanja AI-a</title_sr>
      <title_sv>En ny plattform för neural sökning och insikter för att navigera och organisera AI-forskning</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>نیوی نیورال تلاش اور اینڈیٹس پلٹرومٹ</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Một chương trình tìm kiếm và tìm hiểu về thần kinh mới</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Нова платформа за неврално търсене и прозрения за навигиране и организиране на изследвания в ИИ</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Nova platforma neurološkog potraga i Insights za navigaciju i organizaciju istraživanja AI-a</title_hr>
      <title_da>En ny platform for neural søgning og indsigt til navigation og organisering af AI-forskning</title_da>
      <title_nl>Een nieuw platform voor neuronale zoekopdrachten en inzichten voor het navigeren en organiseren van AI-onderzoek</title_nl>
      <title_id>A New Neural Search and Insights Platform for Navigating and Organizing AI Research</title_id>
      <title_de>Eine neue Plattform für neuronale Suche und Erkenntnisse zur Navigation und Organisation der KI-Forschung</title_de>
      <title_fa>یک Platform New Neural Search and Insights for Navigation and Organizing AI Research</title_fa>
      <title_ko>내비게이션과 인공지능 연구를 조직하는 새로운 신경 검색과 통찰 플랫폼</title_ko>
      <title_tr>A New Neural Search and Insights Platform for Navigating and Organizing AI Research</title_tr>
      <title_af>'n Nuwe Neural Soek en Insights Platform vir Navigating en Organiseer AI Research</title_af>
      <title_sq>Një platformë e re kërkimi dhe vëzhgimi neuronal për navigimin dhe organizimin e kërkimeve të AI</title_sq>
      <title_sw>Jukwaa jipya la kutafuta na Mabadiliko ya Kiraia kwa ajili ya kutengeneza na kuandaa utafiti wa AI</title_sw>
      <title_am>አዲስ መረጃ ፈልግ እና Insights Platform for Navigating and Organizing AI Research</title_am>
      <title_hy>ԱԲ հետազոտությունների նավիգացիայի և կազմակերպման նոր նյարդային որոնման և հետազոտությունների պլատֆորմա</title_hy>
      <title_az>Navigating and Organizing AI Research Platform for New Neural Search and Insights</title_az>
      <title_bn>Name</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Una nova plataforma de recerca neuronal per navegar i organitzar recerca AI</title_ca>
      <title_bs>Nova platforma neurološke pretrage i Insights za navigaciju i organizaciju istraživanja AI-a</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Nová platforma neuronového vyhledávání a poznatků pro navigaci a organizaci výzkumu umělé inteligence</title_cs>
      <title_et>Uus neurootsingu ja teadmiste platvorm AI uuringute navigeerimiseks ja korraldamiseks</title_et>
      <title_fi>Uusi neurohakualusta tekoälytutkimuksen navigointiin ja organisointiin</title_fi>
      <title_sk>Nova platforma za živčno iskanje in vpogled za navigacijo in organizacijo raziskav umetne inteligence</title_sk>
      <title_he>פלטפורמת חיפוש וחיפוש נוירולי חדשה לניווט וארגן מחקר AI</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>A New Neural Search and Insights Platform for Navigating and Organizing AI Research</title_bo>
      <title_jv>A New Neral Search and Ingine Plaformfor navigating and Organising AI Search</title_jv>
      <abstract_ar>لتزويد الباحثين في مجال الذكاء الاصطناعي بالأدوات الحديثة للتعامل مع النمو الهائل للأدبيات البحثية في مجالهم ، نقدم منصة جديدة ، AI Research Navigator ، التي تجمع بين البحث عن الكلمات الرئيسية الكلاسيكية والاسترجاع العصبي لاكتشاف وتنظيم الأدبيات ذات الصلة. يوفر النظام البحث على مستويات متعددة من التفصيل النصي ، من الجمل إلى التجميعات عبر المستندات ، سواء في اللغة الطبيعية أو من خلال التنقل في نطاق معرفي معين. نقدم نظرة عامة على الهيكل العام للنظام ومكونات تحليل المستندات ، والإجابة على الأسئلة ، والبحث ، والتحليلات ، والبحث عن الخبراء ، والتوصيات.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Para proporcionar a los investigadores de IA herramientas modernas para hacer frente al crecimiento explosivo de la literatura de investigación en su campo, presentamos una nueva plataforma, AI Research Navigator, que combina la búsqueda clásica de palabras clave con la recuperación neuronal para descubrir y organizar la literatura relevante. El sistema proporciona búsqueda en múltiples niveles de granularidad textual, desde oraciones hasta agregaciones en documentos, tanto en lenguaje natural como a través de la navegación en un Knowledge Graph específico del dominio. Ofrecemos una visión general de la arquitectura general del sistema y de los componentes para el análisis de documentos, la respuesta a preguntas, la búsqueda, el análisis, la búsqueda de expertos y las recomendaciones.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>Afin de fournir aux chercheurs en IA des outils modernes pour faire face à la croissance fulgurante de la littérature scientifique dans leur domaine, nous lançons une nouvelle plateforme, AI Research Navigator, qui combine la recherche par mot-clé classique avec la récupération neuronale afin de découvrir et d'organiser la littérature pertinente. Le système fournit une recherche à plusieurs niveaux de granularité textuelle, des phrases aux agrégations de documents, à la fois en langage naturel et par la navigation dans un Knowledge Graph spécifique à un domaine. Nous donnons un aperçu de l'architecture globale du système et des composants pour l'analyse de documents, la réponse aux questions, la recherche, l'analyse, la recherche d'experts et les recommandations.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_pt>Para fornecer aos pesquisadores de IA ferramentas modernas para lidar com o crescimento explosivo da literatura de pesquisa em seu campo, apresentamos uma nova plataforma, AI Research Navigator, que combina pesquisa de palavras-chave clássica com recuperação neural para descobrir e organizar literatura relevante. O sistema fornece pesquisa em vários níveis de granularidade textual, de frases a agregações em documentos, tanto em linguagem natural quanto por meio de navegação em um gráfico de conhecimento específico do domínio. Fornecemos uma visão geral da arquitetura geral do sistema e dos componentes para análise de documentos, resposta a perguntas, pesquisa, análise, pesquisa de especialistas e recomendações.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>AI研究者に、その分野における研究文献の爆発的な成長に対処するための最新のツールを提供するために、古典的なキーワード検索とニューラル検索を組み合わせた新しいプラットフォーム、AI Research Navigatorを導入し、関連する文献を発見し、整理します。このシステムは、自然言語でも、特定のナレッジグラフのナビゲーションを通じて、文章からドキュメント間の集計まで、複数のレベルのテキスト粒度で検索を提供します。当社は、システムの全体的なアーキテクチャと、文書分析、質問回答、検索、分析、専門家の検索、および推奨のためのコンポーネントの概要を提供します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>अपने क्षेत्र में अनुसंधान साहित्य के विस्फोटक विकास से निपटने के लिए एआई शोधकर्ताओं को आधुनिक उपकरण प्रदान करने के लिए, हम एक नया मंच, एआई रिसर्च नेविगेटर पेश करते हैं, जो प्रासंगिक साहित्य की खोज और व्यवस्थित करने के लिए तंत्रिका पुनर्प्राप्ति के साथ शास्त्रीय कीवर्ड खोज को जोड़ता है। सिस्टम पाठ्य ग्रैन्युलैरिटी के कई स्तरों पर खोज प्रदान करता है, वाक्यों से लेकर दस्तावेजों में एकत्रीकरण तक, दोनों प्राकृतिक भाषा में और डोमेन विशिष्ट ज्ञान ग्राफ में नेविगेशन के माध्यम से। हम सिस्टम की समग्र वास्तुकला और दस्तावेज़ विश्लेषण, प्रश्न उत्तर, खोज, विश्लेषिकी, विशेषज्ञ खोज और सिफारिशों के लिए घटकों का अवलोकन देते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>为AI人治文爆炸式长,引入新平台AI Research Navigator,当平台索关键字与神经检索合,以见相关。 其统供数本粒度搜索,自句至跨文档之聚,无论自然语言特定领域图谱中导航。 吾概述系统之体架构及以文档析之,问答搜索,析之,专家搜议之组件。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>Чтобы предоставить исследователям ИИ современные инструменты для борьбы со взрывным ростом исследовательской литературы в своей области, мы вводим новую платформу, AI Research Navigator, которая сочетает в себе классический поиск по ключевым словам с нейронным поиском, чтобы обнаружить и упорядочить соответствующую литературу. Система обеспечивает поиск на нескольких уровнях текстовой детализации, от предложений до агрегаций по документам, как на естественном языке, так и посредством навигации в графе знаний конкретной области. Мы даем обзор общей архитектуры системы и компонентов для анализа документов, ответов на вопросы, поиска, аналитики, экспертного поиска и рекомендаций.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Chun uirlisí nua-aimseartha a sholáthar do thaighdeoirí AI chun déileáil le fás pléascach na litríochta taighde ina réimse, tugaimid ardán nua isteach, AI Research Navigator, a chomhcheanglaíonn cuardach eochairfhocal clasaiceach le haisghabháil néarúil chun litríocht ábhartha a fhionnadh agus a eagrú. Soláthraíonn an córas cuardach ar leibhéil iolracha de ghráinneacht téacs, ó abairtí go comhiomlánaithe trasna doiciméad, i dteanga nádúrtha agus trí loingseoireacht i nGraf Faisnéise sainiúil don fhearann. Tugaimid forbhreathnú ar ailtireacht fhoriomlán an chórais agus ar na comhpháirteanna le haghaidh anailíse doiciméad, freagra ceisteanna, cuardach, anailísíocht, cuardach saineolaithe, agus moltaí.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Για να παρέχουμε στους ερευνητές της τεχνητής νοημοσύνης σύγχρονα εργαλεία για την αντιμετώπιση της εκρηκτικής ανάπτυξης της ερευνητικής βιβλιογραφίας στον τομέα τους, εισάγουμε μια νέα πλατφόρμα, την οποία συνδυάζει την κλασική αναζήτηση λέξεων-κλειδιών με την νευρική ανάκτηση για να ανακαλύψει και να οργανώσει τη σχετική βιβλιογραφία. Το σύστημα παρέχει αναζήτηση σε πολλαπλά επίπεδα κοκκώδους κειμένου, από προτάσεις έως συγκεντρώσεις σε έγγραφα, τόσο στη φυσική γλώσσα όσο και μέσω πλοήγησης σε ένα συγκεκριμένο Γνωσιακό Γράφημα. Δίνουμε μια επισκόπηση της συνολικής αρχιτεκτονικής του συστήματος και των συστατικών για την ανάλυση εγγράφων, την απάντηση ερωτήσεων, την αναζήτηση, τις αναλύσεις, την αναζήτηση εμπειρογνωμόνων και τις συστάσεις.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Annak érdekében, hogy az AI kutatók modern eszközöket biztosítsunk a kutatási irodalom robbanékony növekedésének kezelésére a saját területükön, bevezetünk egy új platformot, az AI Research Navigatort, amely kombinálja a klasszikus kulcsszókeresést az idegi visszakereséssel a releváns irodalom felfedezéséhez és megszervezéséhez. A rendszer több szintű szövegrészletes keresést biztosít, a mondatoktól kezdve a dokumentumok összesítéséig, mind természetes nyelven, mind pedig egy tartományspecifikus Tudásgrafán keresztül. Áttekintést nyújtunk a rendszer általános architektúrájáról és a dokumentumalemzés, a kérdések megválaszolása, a keresés, az elemzés, a szakértői keresés és az ajánlások összetevőiről.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>რომელიც AI მსწავლობელებს მოდინარე ხელსაწყობილობით გამოსახულებლად სწავლობის ლიტურატიის ექსპლეციური პროგრამის გამოსახულებლად, ჩვენ შევცვალოთ ახალი პლატატრამის, AI განსწავლობის ნავიდატორი, რომელიც Name ჩვენ სისტემის ყველა არქტიქტურის და კომპონენტების შესახებ დოკუმენტის ანალიზაციისთვის, კითხვების პასუხისთვის, ძიებას, ანალიზატის, ექსპერტის ძიებას</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Per fornire ai ricercatori di AI strumenti moderni per affrontare la crescita esplosiva della letteratura di ricerca nel loro campo, presentiamo una nuova piattaforma, AI Research Navigator, che combina la ricerca classica di parole chiave con il recupero neurale per scoprire e organizzare la letteratura pertinente. Il sistema fornisce la ricerca a più livelli di granularità testuale, dalle frasi alle aggregazioni tra documenti, sia in linguaggio naturale che attraverso la navigazione in un Knowledge Graph specifico del dominio. Forniamo una panoramica dell'architettura complessiva del sistema e dei componenti per l'analisi dei documenti, la risposta alle domande, la ricerca, l'analisi, la ricerca di esperti e le raccomandazioni.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бірақ AI зерттеушілерін зерттеушілердің зерттеушілерінің көтерілік литературасының жетілдіру үшін қазіргі құрылғыларды қамтамасыз ету үшін оның өрісінде жаңа платформа, AI зерттеу навигаторы, классикалық түрде іздеу Жүйе бірнеше мәтіндік грануляриялық деңгейінде іздеу, сөздерден құжаттардың біріктіру графикасында, тәуелдік тілінде де және навигациялық диаграммасында. Біз жүйенің жалпы архитектурасын және құжатты анализ, сұрақ жауап, іздеу, аналитика, эксперттік іздеу және рекомендацияларын қарап береміз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Siekiant suteikti AI tyrėjams šiuolaikines priemones spręsti sprogstamą mokslinių tyrimų literatūros augimą jų srityje, mes įdiegime naują platform ą, AI mokslinių tyrimų navigatorių, kuri derina klasikinį raktinio žodžio paiešką su neurologiniu paieška, kad aptiktų ir organizuotų atitinkamą literatūrą. Sistema teikia paiešką įvairiais tekstinės granuliarumo lygiais, nuo sakinių iki dokumentų suvestinių, tiek natūralia kalba, tiek navigaciją konkrečioje srities žinių grafikoje. We give an overview of the overall architecture of the system and of the components for document analysis, question answering, search, analytics, expert search, and recommendations.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Untuk menyediakan peneliti AI dengan alat modern untuk menghadapi pertumbuhan letupan sastra penelitian di medan mereka, kami memperkenalkan platform baru, Navigator penelitian AI, yang menggabungkan pencarian kata kunci klasik dengan pencarian saraf untuk menemukan dan mengatur sastra yang relevan. Sistem menyediakan pencarian pada tahap berbilang granulariti teks, dari kalimat ke agregasi di seluruh dokumen, kedua-dua dalam bahasa semulajadi dan melalui navigasi dalam Graf Pengetahuan tertentu domain. Kami memberikan pandangan keseluruhan arkitektur sistem dan komponen untuk analisis dokumen, jawapan soalan, carian, analitik, carian pakar, dan cadangan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>അവരുടെ ഫീള്‍ഡിലെ പഠിക്കുന്ന സാഹിത്യത്തിന്‍റെ പൊട്ടിത്തെറിയുന്നതിനെക്കുറിച്ച് കണക്കാക്കുന്നതിനായി AI പരിശീലിക്കുന്നവര്‍ക്ക് ആധുനിക ഉപകരണങ്ങള്‍ കൊടുക്കാന്‍ നമ്മ സിസ്റ്റത്തില്‍ പല നിലങ്ങളിലും ടെക്സ്ചുള്‍ ഗ്രാന്റില്‍ നിന്നും രേഖകളിലേക്കുള്ള വാക്കുകളിലേക്കുള്ള പ്രധാനഭാഷയിലേക്കും പ്രത്യേക പര നമ്മള്‍ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ മൊത്തം ആര്‍ക്കിട്ടറിക്കുന്നതിനെക്കുറിച്ചും രേഖകള്‍ അന്വേഷിക്കുന്ന ഭാഗങ്ങളെക്കുറിച്ചും ശ്രദ്ധിക്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Судалгааны уран зохиолын гайхалтай өсөлттэй тулд орчин үеийн судлаачид боловсруулахын тулд бид шинэ платформ, AI Research Navigator-г танилцуулдаг. Энэ нь шинэ түлхүүр үг хайгуулах нь сэтгэл судлаачид хайгуулах, хамааралтай уран зохиолыг олох, зо Энэ систем нь олон хэмжээнд, өгүүлбэрээс баримтын нийлүүлэлт хүртэл, байгалийн хэл болон хувилбарын тулд мэдлэг график дээр судалгаа хангадаг. Бид системийн бүхий л архитектурыг, баримт шинжилгээ, асуулт хариулт, хайх, анализ, мэргэжилтний хайх, зөвлөмжүүдийн бүтэц бүтээгдэхүүнийг харуулж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mt>Biex ir-riċerkaturi tal-AI jingħataw għodod moderni biex jittrattaw it-tkabbir splussiv tal-letteratura tar-riċerka fil-qasam tagħhom, a ħna nintroduċu pjattaforma ġdida, in-Navigatur tar-Riċerka tal-AI, li tgħaqqad it-tiftix tal-kliem ewlieni klassiku mal-irkupru newrali biex niskopru u jorganizzaw il-letteratura rilevanti. Is-sistema tipprovdi tfittxija f’diversi livelli ta’ granularità testwali, minn sentenzi għal aggregazzjonijiet bejn id-dokumenti, kemm fil-lingwa naturali kif ukoll permezz tan-navigazzjoni fi Grafika ta’ Għarfien speċifika għad-dominju. Aħna nagħtu ħarsa ġenerali lejn l-arkitettura ġenerali tas-sistema u l-komponenti għall-analiżi tad-dokumenti, it-tweġiba għall-mistoqsijiet, it-tiftix, l-analitika, it-tiftix tal-esperti, u r-rakkomandazzjonijiet.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>For å tilbygge forskere av AI med moderne verktøy for å handtera eksplodivt vekst av forskningsliteraturen i feltet sine, introdusere vi eit ny plattform, AI-forskningsnavigator, som kombinerer klassisk nøkkelord søk med neuraloppleving for å oppdaga og organisera relevante literatur. Name Vi gjev ei oversikt over den generelle arkitekturen av systemet og komponentane for dokumentanalyse, svar på spørsmål, søk, analyser, ekspertsøk og anbefalingar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Aby zapewnić naukowcom sztucznej inteligencji nowoczesne narzędzia do radzenia sobie z wybuchowym rozwojem literatury badawczej w swojej dziedzinie, wprowadzamy nową platformę, AI Research Navigator, która łączy klasyczne wyszukiwanie słów kluczowych z odzyskiwaniem neuronalnym w celu odkrywania i organizowania odpowiedniej literatury. System umożliwia wyszukiwanie na wielu poziomach granularności tekstowej, od zdań po agregacje w dokumentach, zarówno w języku naturalnym, jak i poprzez nawigację w specyficznym dla domeny wykresie wiedzy. Podajemy przegląd ogólnej architektury systemu oraz komponentów do analizy dokumentów, odpowiedzi na pytania, wyszukiwania, analizy, wyszukiwania ekspertów i rekomendacji.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Pentru a oferi cercetătorilor AI instrumente moderne pentru a face față creșterii explozive a literaturii de cercetare în domeniul lor, introducem o nouă platformă, AI Research Navigator, care combină căutarea clasică a cuvintelor cheie cu recuperarea neurală pentru a descoperi și organiza literatura relevantă. Sistemul oferă căutare la mai multe niveluri de granularitate textuală, de la propoziții la agregări în documente, atât în limbaj natural, cât și prin navigarea într-un Knowledge Graph specific domeniului. Oferim o imagine de ansamblu a arhitecturii globale a sistemului și a componentelor pentru analiza documentelor, răspunsul la întrebări, căutare, analiză, căutare de experți și recomandări.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mk>За да им обезбедиме модерни алатки на истражувачите на AI за справување со експлозивниот раст на истражувачката литература на нивното поле, воведуваме нова платформа, AI Research Navigator, која ги комбинира класичните потрага по клучни зборови со неуралното преземање за откривање и организација на реле Системот обезбедува пребарување на повеќе нивоа на текстуална грануларност, од реченици до агрегации меѓу документите, како на природен јазик, така и преку навигација во специфичен домен знање граф. Ние даваме преглед на целокупната архитектура на системот и на компонентите за анализа на документите, одговори на прашања, пребарување, аналитика, експертска пребарување и препораки.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_sr>Da bi omogućili istraživačima AI-a moderne alate za rješavanje eksplozivnog rasta istraživačke literature na njihovom polju, predstavljamo novu platformu, AI istraživačku navigatoru, koja kombinuje klasičnu potragu ključnih riječi sa neuralnim povlačenjem da bi otkrila i organizovala relevantnu literaturu. Sistem pruža potragu na višestrukim nivoima tekstualne granularnosti, od rečenica do aggregacija širom dokumenta, i na prirodnom jeziku i kroz navigaciju u domenu specifičnom znanstvenom grafiku. Pregled sveukupne arhitekture sistema i komponenta za analizu dokumenta, odgovor na pitanja, pretragu, analitiku, potragu stručnjaka i preporuke.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>AI ஆராய்ச்சியாளர் Name நாம் கணினியின் மொத்த கட்டுப்பாட்டு மற்றும் ஆவணத்தை ஆய்வு, கேள்வி பதில், தேடு, ஆராய்ச்சி, தேடல் மற்றும் பரிந்துரைகளின் பொருள்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_si>AI පරීක්ෂකයන්ට අධ්‍යාත්මක උපකරණය සමග උපකරණය සමග උපකරණය කරන්න ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රධානයේ පරීක්ෂණ ප්‍රධානයේ විශාල ප්‍රධානයක් සමග උපකරණය කරනවා, අපි අළ පද්ධතිය පද්ධතිය පරීක්ෂණය විශේෂ ස්තූතියේ විශේෂ ස්තූතිය, වාක්ෂාවයෙන් ලිපිණියෙන් සම්බන්ධ විශේෂ කර අපි පද්ධතියේ සම්පූර්ණ විශ්ලේෂණය, ප්‍රශ්න ප්‍රතිච්චාරය, පරීක්ෂණය, විශ්ලේෂණය, විශ්ලේෂණය, විශ්වාසික ස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Si aan u siiyo baaritaanka AI qalabka cusub ee la xiriira koritaanka akhriska baaritaanka ee beerahooda, waxaynu soo bandhignaynaa qorshaxan cusub oo ah maamulka AI baaritaanka, kaas oo ku soo ururiya raadinta kalkaaliska qorniinka si uu u soo ogaado oo uu u qabanqaabiyo qorshaha la xiriira. Isticmaalku wuxuu wax ka raadinayaa heerar kala duduwan oo qoraal ah, dhamaadka iyo qeybta warqadaha oo dhan, luqada dabiicadda ah iyo baaritaanka ku qoran qoraalka aqoonta gaarka ah. Waxaannu ka fiirinaynaa dhismaha nidaamka oo dhan iyo qeybaha loo sameynayo baaritaanka dukumentiga, jawaabta su'aalaha, raadinta, baaritaanka, raadinta kharashka, raadinta kharashka iyo talooyin.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>För att ge AI-forskare moderna verktyg för att hantera den explosiva tillväxten av forskningslitteraturen inom sitt område introducerar vi en ny plattform, AI Research Navigator, som kombinerar klassisk sökordssökning med neural hämtning för att upptäcka och organisera relevant litteratur. Systemet ger sökning på flera nivåer av textgranularitet, från meningar till aggregeringar över dokument, både på naturligt språk och genom navigering i en domänspecifik kunskapsgraf. Vi ger en översikt över systemets övergripande arkitektur och komponenterna för dokumentanalys, frågesvar, sökning, analys, expertsökning och rekommendationer.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>اس لئے کہ AI تحقیقات کرنے والوں کو مدرنی ابزار کے ذریعہ ان کے کھیلے میں تحقیقات ادبیات کی پھیلانے کے لئے استعمال کرنے کے لئے، ہم نے ایک نوی پلٹورم، AI Research Navigator کو معرفی کرلیا ہے، جس نے کلاسیک کلیسی لفظ تحقیقات کو نئورل پھیلانے کے ساتھ پیدا کیا ہے اور اس کے لئے سیسٹم ٹیکسٹل کی بہت سی سطح پر جہاد کرتا ہے، کلمات سے دلیلیں میں جمع کرتا ہے، دونوں طبیعی زبان میں اور ایک ڈومین کی مخصوص علم گراف میں ناوگانی کے ذریعہ۔ ہم نے سیسٹم کے سارے سارے معماری اور دفتر تحلیل کے مطابق مطابق، سوال جواب، تلاش، تحلیل، مطابق تلاش، اور سفارش کے مطابق مطابق کا ایک نظر دیتے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>To provide AI researchers with modern tools for dealing with the explosive growth of the research literature in their field, we introduce a new platform, AI Research Navigator, that combines classical keyword search with neural retrieval to discover and organize relevant literature.  Name Biz tizimning hamma maktablarini va hujjatni analyzer, savol javob beradi, qidirish, analytika, ekspert qidirish va soʻzlar uchun komponentlarni ko'rib chiqaramiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Để cung cấp cho các nhà nghiên cứu AI các công cụ hiện đại để xử lý sự phát triển bùng nổ của văn học nghiên cứu trong lĩnh vực của chúng, chúng ta sẽ giới thiệu một nền tảng mới, Al Research Navigator, kết hợp từ khoá cổ điển với việc lấy lại hệ thần kinh để khám phá và tổ chức văn học liên quan. Hệ thống này cung cấp việc tìm kiếm với nhiều mức độ hạt cấu trúc, từ câu cho đến tổng hợp qua các tài liệu, cả trong ngôn ngữ tự nhiên và qua việc di chuyển trong một Thứ đồ tri thức cụ thể miền. Chúng tôi cung cấp một hình ảnh tổng kiến trúc của hệ thống và các thành phần phân tích tài liệu, câu hỏi, tìm kiếm, phân tích, tìm kiếm chuyên gia, và lời khuyên.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>За да предоставим на изследователите по изкуствен интелект съвременни инструменти за справяне с експлозивния растеж на научноизследователската литература в тяхната област, ние въвеждаме нова платформа, която съчетава класическото търсене на ключови думи с невронно извличане, за да открие и организира съответната литература. Системата осигурява търсене на множество нива на текстова гранулираност, от изречения до агрегиране между документи, както на естествен език, така и чрез навигация в специфична област Графика на знанието. Представяме обзор на цялостната архитектура на системата и на компонентите за анализ на документи, отговор на въпроси, търсене, анализ, експертно търсене и препоръки.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Om AI-onderzoekers moderne tools te bieden voor het omgaan met de explosieve groei van de onderzoeksliteratuur in hun vakgebied, introduceren we een nieuw platform, AI Research Navigator, dat klassieke zoekwoorden combineert met neural retrieval om relevante literatuur te ontdekken en te organiseren. Het systeem biedt zoeken op meerdere niveaus van tekstgranulariteit, van zinnen tot aggregaties in documenten, zowel in de natuurlijke taal als via navigatie in een domein specifieke Knowledge Graph. We geven een overzicht van de algemene architectuur van het systeem en van de componenten voor documentanalyse, vragenantwoord, zoeken, analytics, expert search en aanbevelingen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Da bi omogućili istraživačima AI-a moderne alate za rješavanje eksplozivnog rasta istraživačke književnosti na njihovom polju, predstavljamo novu platformu, istraživačku navigaciju AI-a, koja kombinira klasičnu potragu ključnih riječi sa neuralnom povratkom kako bi otkrila i organizirala relevantnu književnost. Sistem pruža potragu na višestrukim razinama tekstualne granularnosti, od rečenica do skupljanja kroz dokumente, kako na prirodnom jeziku i kroz navigaciju u specifičnom znanstvenom grafiku domena. Pregled cjelokupne arhitekture sustava i komponenta za analizu dokumenta, odgovor na pitanja, pretragu, analitiku, potragu stručnjaka i preporuke.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>For at give AI-forskere moderne værktøjer til at håndtere den eksplosive vækst i forskningslitteraturen på deres område, introducerer vi en ny platform, AI Research Navigator, der kombinerer klassisk søgeordssøgning med neural hentning for at opdage og organisere relevant litteratur. Systemet giver søgning på flere niveauer af tekstgranularitet, fra sætninger til aggregeringer på tværs af dokumenter, både på naturligt sprog og gennem navigation i et domænespecifikt vidensdiagram. Vi giver et overblik over systemets overordnede arkitektur og af komponenterne til dokumentanalyse, spørgsmål besvarelse, søgning, analyse, ekspertsøgning og anbefalinger.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Um KI-Forschern moderne Werkzeuge für den Umgang mit dem explosiven Wachstum der Forschungsliteratur in ihrem Fachgebiet zur Verfügung zu stellen, stellen wir eine neue Plattform vor, KI Research Navigator, die klassische Keyword-Suche mit neuronalem Retrieval kombiniert, um relevante Literatur zu entdecken und zu organisieren. Das System bietet die Suche auf mehreren Ebenen der textlichen Granularität, von Sätzen bis hin zu Aggregationen in Dokumenten, sowohl in natürlicher Sprache als auch durch Navigation in einem domänenspezifischen Knowledge Graph. Wir geben einen Überblick über die Gesamtarchitektur des Systems und der Komponenten für Dokumentenanalyse, Fragestellung, Suche, Analytik, Expertensuche und Empfehlungen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>인공지능 연구원들에게 현대 도구를 제공하여 그 분야의 연구 문헌의 폭발적인 증가에 대응하기 위해 우리는 새로운 플랫폼을 도입했다. 인공지능 연구 네비게이션은 고전 키워드 검색과 신경 검색을 결합시켜 관련 문헌을 발견하고 조직하는 것이다.이 시스템은 문장부터 크로스 문서 집합까지의 다차원 텍스트 입도 검색을 제공하는데 자연 언어 검색과 특정 분야의 지식도 내비게이션 검색을 포함한다.우리는 시스템의 전체적인 구조와 문서 분석, 질문 대답, 검색, 분석, 전문가 검색과 건의에 사용되는 구성 요소를 개술했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_id>Untuk menyediakan peneliti AI dengan alat modern untuk menghadapi pertumbuhan ledak dari literatur penelitian di lapangan mereka, kami memperkenalkan platform baru, Navigator penelitian AI, yang menggabungkan pencarian kata kunci klasik dengan penelitian saraf untuk menemukan dan mengatur literatur relevan. Sistem menyediakan pencarian di berbagai tingkat granularitas tekstual, dari kalimat ke agregasi di seluruh dokumen, baik dalam bahasa alami maupun melalui navigasi dalam Graf Pengetahuan khusus domain. Kami memberikan overview dari arsitektur keseluruhan sistem dan komponen untuk analisis dokumen, jawaban pertanyaan, pencarian, analitik, pencarian ahli, dan rekomendasi.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Ili kuwapa watafiti wa AI na nyenzo za kisasa za kuhusiana na ukuaji wa mlipuko wa fasihi za utafiti katika maeneo yao, tunaanzisha jukwaa mpya, Mtafiti wa Utafiti wa AI, linalounganisha utafiti wa neno la kiklasia kwa ajili ya kutafuta upya wa kisasa kwa ajili ya kutafuta na kuandaa fasihi zinazohusiana. Mfumo huo unatoa utafutaji katika ngazi mbalimbali za ubora wa kuandika, kuanzia sentensi hadi kuongezeka kwa nyaraka zote, kwa lugha ya asili na kupitia usafiri katika Graph maalum ya Ujuzi. Tunatoa maoni ya ujenzi wa mfumo wa jumla na vifaa vya uchambuzi wa nyaraka, majibu, kutafuta, uchambuzi, kutafuta wataalam na mapendekezo.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Om AI-ondersoekers te verskaf met moderne nutsprogramme om met die eksplosiewe groei van die ondersoek literature in hul veld te verwerp, introduseer ons 'n nuwe platform, AI Research Navigator, wat klassieke sleutelwoord soek met neurale ontvang om relevante literaat te ontdek en organiseer. Die stelsel verskaf soektog by veelvuldige vlakke van tekstuele granulariteit, van setings tot bymekaar dokumente, beide in natuurlike taal en deur navigasie in 'n domein spesifieke kennis graf. Ons gee 'n oorskou van die hele arkitektuur van die stelsel en van die komponente vir dokumentanaliseer, vraag antwoord, soek, analiseer, ekspertiese soek en rekening.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_fa>تا محققان AI را با ابزارهای مدرن برای حل با رشد انفجار ادبیات تحقیقات در زمینه آنها، یک پلاکتر جدید، Navigator Research AI را معرفی کنیم، که جستجوی کلاسیک کلاسیک را با بازیابی عصبی برای کشف و سازمان ادبیات مربوط به آن ترکیب می کند. سیستم در سطح‌های متعدد گرانولیت متن، از جمله‌ها تا جمع‌آوری از جمله‌های سند، هر دو در زبان طبیعی و از طریق کشوری در یک گراف دانش ویژه، جستجو می‌کند. ما یک نظر از ساختار عمومی سیستم و عناصر برای تحلیل سند، جواب سوال، جستجو، تحلیل، جستجوی متخصص و پیشنهاد می دهیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>AI araştyranlaryny öz alanlaryndaky ylmy edebiýatynyň explosiýasyny çykmak üçin modern aletleri bilen üýtgetmek üçin, biz Täze plataforma, AI Araştyrma Nawigatöri bilen tanyşdyrýarys we relevantny edebiýatyny tapmak we çykmak üçin klassiýaly a çyk sözleri neural almak bilen birleştirilýäris. Sistem sendiň birnäçe derejesinde, sözleriň çerçe senediň ýygnamalaryna , tebigy dilinde hem bilim grafisinde nawiga görýär. Biz sistemiň ähli arhitektura we desktap analýusisi, soragy, gözlemek, analýtik, uzmanlaryň arama we maslahatlary üçin üns berýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Për të siguruar kërkuesit e AI me mjete moderne për trajtimin e rritjes eksplozive të letraturës së kërkimit në fushën e tyre, ne futim një platform ë të re, AI Research Navigator, që kombinon kërkimin klasik të fjalëve kyçe me marrjen nervore për të zbuluar dhe organizuar letraturën e rëndësishme. Sistemi ofron kërkim në nivele të shumta të granularitetit tekstual, nga fjalët në agregacione nëpërmjet dokumenteve, si në gjuhën natyrore, ashtu edhe nëpërmjet navigimit në një grafik të njohurive specifike në domeni. Ne japim një përmbledhje të arkitekturës së përgjithshme të sistemit dhe të komponenteve për analizën e dokumenteve, përgjigjen e pyetjeve, kërkimin, analitikën, kërkimin e ekspertëve dhe rekomandimet.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>አዲስ የ.আই ምርመራዎችን በአዲስ ደረጃዎች ለመጠቀም የአዲስ ደረጃዎችን ለመጠቀም፣ የአዲስ ደረጃዎች፣ አዲስ ፕሮግራም፣ የክላሲካዊ የክሊሲክ ቃላት ፈለጎትን ለማግኘት እና ተቃውሞ በሐሳብን ለማግኘት እና ለመቀጠል እና ለማስጠጋት እናስጠጋለን፡፡ ሲስተምሩ በተለያዩ ደረጃዎች፣ ከሥርዓት ወደ ሰነድ ማቅረብ፣ በአዳባዊ ቋንቋ እና በዶሜን በተለየ እውቀት መግለጫ ውስጥ መፍጠርን የሚያደርግ ፍለጋት ነው፡፡ የሲስተም አካውንት እና የሰነድ አካባቢዎችን፣ ጥያቄን መልስ፣ ፍለጋን፣ ትምህርት፣ አስተያየት፣ ምርጫዎች እና መግለጫ እናደርጋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>ԱԲ-ի հետազոտողներին տրամադրելու ժամանակակից գործիքներ ուսումնասիրության գրականության պայծառ աճի հետ իրենց ոլորտում, մենք ներկայացնում ենք նոր հարթակներ, ԱԲ-ի հետազոտության նավիգատոր, որը համադրում է դասական բառերի որոնումը նյարդային վերականգնման հետ, որպեսզի բացահայտե Համակարգը հնարավորություն է տալիս փնտրել տեքստալ գրանիալիության բազմաթիվ մակարդակներում, նախադասություններից մինչև փաստաթղթերի համախմբումները, ինչպես բնական լեզվով, և նավիգացիայի միջոցով գիտելիքի գրաֆում: Մենք ներկայացնում ենք համակարգի ընդհանուր ճարտարապետության և փաստաթղթերի վերլուծության, հարցերի պատասխանի, որոնման, վերլուծության, մասնագետների որոնման և խորհուրդների մասին:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>AI araştırmalarını araşdırmaq üçün onların sahəsindəki araştırma edebiyatının patlayıcı büyünməsi üçün moderni vasitələrlə müəyyən etmək üçün yeni platformu, AI Araştırma Navigatoru təşkil edirik ki, nöral alınması ilə klasik anahtar sözlər araştırmağı əlaqələrini keşf etmək və məlumatları düzəltmək Sistem məlumatların çoxlu səviyyələrində, cümlələrdən təbiətli dildə və məlumatların müəyyən edilmiş Bilgi Grafında təbiətli dildə və navigatiya vasitəsilə araşdırır. Biz sistemin bütün arhitektürünü və beləliklə analizi, sual cavab vermək, arama, analitik, ekspertlər arama və tövsiyələr üçün komponentlərin nəzəriyyəti veririk.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>তাদের ক্ষেত্রে গবেষণা সাহিত্যের বিস্ফোরণের বিস্ফোরণের মাধ্যমে বিস্ফোরণ করার জন্য AI গবেষকদের আধুনিক টুল দিতে আমরা একটি নতুন প্লাটফর্ম, AI গবেষণা ন্যাভিগেটর, যা ক্লাসিক্ The system provides search at multiple levels of textual granularity, from sentences to aggregations across documents, both in natural language and through navigation in a domain specific Knowledge Graph.  আমরা সিস্টেমের সাধারণ স্থাপত্য এবং নথি বিশ্লেষণ, প্রশ্নের উত্তর, অনুসন্ধান, বিশেষজ্ঞ, অনুসন্ধান এবং পরামর্শের জন্য প্রতিষ্ঠানের সাধারণ</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Da bi omogućili istraživačima AI-a moderne alate za rješavanje eksplozivnog rasta istraživačke književnosti na njihovom polju, predstavljamo novu platformu, AI istraživačku navigatoru, koja kombinira klasičnu potragu ključnih riječi sa neuralnim povlačenjem da bi otkrila i organizirala relevantnu literaturu. Sistem pruža potragu na višestrukim nivoima tekstualne granularnosti, od rečenica do aggregacija kroz dokumente, kako na prirodnom jeziku i kroz navigaciju u specifičnom znanstvenom grafiku domena. Pregled sveukupne arhitekture sustava i komponenta za analizu dokumenta, odgovor na pitanja, pretragu, analitiku, potragu stručnjaka i preporuke.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Per proporcionar als investigadors d'AI eines modernes per tractar amb el creixement explosiu de la literatura de recerca en el seu camp, introduïm una nova plataforma, AI Research Navigator, que combina la recerca clàssica de paraules clau amb la recuperació neuronal per descobrir i organitzar literatura rellevant. El sistema proporciona cerca a múltiples nivells de granularitat textual, des de frases a agregacions entre documents, tant en llenguatge natural com a través de la navegació en un gràfic de coneixements específic de domini. Fem una visió general de l'arquitectura global del sistema i dels components per a l'an àlisi de documents, resposta a preguntes, busca, anàlisi, busca d'experts i recomanacions.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Abychom výzkumníkům umělé inteligence poskytli moderní nástroje pro řešení výbušného růstu výzkumné literatury ve svém oboru, představujeme novou platformu AI Research Navigator, která kombinuje klasické vyhledávání klíčových slov s neuronovým retrievem pro objevování a organizaci relevantní literatury. Systém poskytuje vyhledávání na několika úrovních textové granularity, od vět po agregace napříč dokumenty, a to jak v přirozeném jazyce, tak prostřednictvím navigace ve znalostním grafu specifickém pro doménu. Poskytujeme přehled o celkové architektuře systému a komponentách pro analýzu dokumentů, zodpovězení otázek, vyhledávání, analýzu, odborné vyhledávání a doporučení.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Jotta tekoälytutkijat saisivat käyttöönsä modernit työkalut oman alansa tutkimuskirjallisuuden räjähdysmäiseen kasvuun, esittelemme uuden alustan, AI Research Navigatorin, joka yhdistää klassisen avainsanahaun ja neurohaun löytääkseen ja organisoidakseen relevanttia kirjallisuutta. Järjestelmä tarjoaa haun useilla tekstien tarkkuustasoilla lauseista dokumenttien yhdistämiseen sekä luonnollisella kielellä että toimialueekohtaisen Knowledge Graphin navigoinnin kautta. Annamme yleiskuvan järjestelmän kokonaisarkkitehtuurista sekä dokumenttianalyysin, kysymyksenvastauksen, haun, analytiikan, asiantuntijahaun ja suositusten komponenteista.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Selleks et pakkuda AI teadlastele kaasaegseid vahendeid oma valdkonna teaduskirjanduse plahvatusliku kasvuga toimetulekuks, tutvustame uut platvormi, AI Research Navigator, mis ühendab klassikalise märksõna otsingu ja närviotsingu asjakohase kirjanduse avastamiseks ja korraldamiseks. Süsteem pakub otsinguid mitmel tekstilise granulaarsuse tasemel alates lausetest kuni dokumentide koondamiseni nii looduskeeles kui ka navigeerimise kaudu domeenispetsiifilises teadmisgraafikus. Anname ülevaate süsteemi üldisest arhitektuurist ning dokumentide analüüsi, küsimustele vastamise, otsingu, analüüsi, ekspertotsingu ja soovituste komponentidest.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ha>Ina iya bãyar da watafitin AI na zance masu yanzu wa masu husũma da matuƙar na littafan littafan da aka sanar littafan a shawansu, za mu introduce wani na-platform na AI, wanda ya haɗa tafarkin kalma na fasasa da rabo na gane da kuma ke organize littafan da muhimmada. @ action: button Munã nuna kowace matsayin tsarin na'urar da na'ura da ƙan an an takardar, da masu jiba wa tambayar, da tambayi, da kiyayyuta, da shagala, da nemi masu amfani da masu shawara.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>כדי לספק למחקרים AI כלים מודרניים להתמודד עם הגידול הפיצוץ של ספרות המחקר בשטח שלהם, אנחנו מכירים פלטפורמה חדשה, AI Research Navigator, שמשולבת חיפוש מילים מפתחות קלאסיים עם השיגור עצבי כדי לגלות ולארגן ספרות רלוונטית. The system provides search at multiple levels of textual granularity, from sentences to aggregations across documents, both in natural language and through navigation in a domain specific Knowledge Graph.  אנחנו נותנים מבט כללי על הארכיטקטורה הכללית של המערכת והרכיבים לניתוח מסמכים, עניין שאלות, חיפוש, אנליטיקה, חיפוש מומחה ומלצות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Da bi raziskovalcem umetne inteligence zagotovili sodobna orodja za soočanje z eksplozivno rastjo raziskovalne literature na svojem področju, predstavljamo novo platformo, AI Research Navigator, ki združuje klasično iskanje ključnih besed z nevronskim iskanjem za odkrivanje in organiziranje ustrezne literature. Sistem zagotavlja iskanje na več ravneh besedilne natančnosti, od stavkov do združevanja po dokumentih, tako v naravnem jeziku kot prek navigacije v grafikonu znanja, specifičnem za domeno. Podamo pregled celotne arhitekture sistema in komponent za analizo dokumentov, odgovarjanje na vprašanja, iskanje, analitiko, strokovno iskanje in priporočila.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>To provide AI researchers with modern tools for dealing with the explosive growth of the research literature in their field, we introduce a new platform, AI Research Navigator, that combines classical keyword search with neural retrieval to discover and organize relevant literature. The system provides search at multiple levels of textual granularity, from sentences to aggregations across documents, both in natural language and through navigation in a domain specific Knowledge Graph. ང་ཚོས་ཡིག་གི་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་དང་། རྩིས་ཐོག་གི་སྒྲིག་ཆ་ཡོངས་ཀྱི་ཆ་ཁོངས་ཀྱི་བསྡུས་ཀློག་ཆོག་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_jv>Mbok ngewehke kamuran AI karo alat sing manggad kanggo ngilanggar aturan sing paling kanggo tukang winih kanggo tukang winih sing dibutuhke ingkang kesempatan, awak dhéwé ngetokake sistem sing bagian, navigation AI, sing beraksi pergambar kelas kuwi alat sing dibutungan lan ijol-ijolan winih hayo nggawe tarjamahan lan ijol-ijolan winih. System Awak dhéwé mengko nglanggar aturan gak nggawe architecture ning sistem lan alam sing dikarepaké kanggo anara dhèwèké, gambaran, bukêrané, penarané, nyatakake punika lan toranêm.</abstract_jv>
      </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Overview and Insights from the Shared Tasks at Scholarly Document Processing 2020 : CL-SciSumm, LaySumm and LongSumm<fixed-case>CL</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>ci<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>umm, <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ay<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>umm and <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ong<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>umm</title>
      <author><first>Muthu Kumar</first><last>Chandrasekaran</last></author>
      <author><first>Guy</first><last>Feigenblat</last></author>
      <author><first>Eduard</first><last>Hovy</last></author>
      <author><first>Abhilasha</first><last>Ravichander</last></author>
      <author><first>Michal</first><last>Shmueli-Scheuer</last></author>
      <author><first>Anita</first><last>de Waard</last></author>
      <pages>214–224</pages>
      <abstract>We present the results of three Shared Tasks held at the Scholarly Document Processing Workshop at EMNLP2020 : CL-SciSumm, LaySumm and LongSumm. We report on each of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a>, which received 18 submissions in total, with some submissions addressing two or three of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a>. In summary, the quality and quantity of the submissions show that there is ample interest in scholarly document summarization, and the state of the art in this domain is at a midway point between being an impossible task and one that is fully resolved.</abstract>
      <url hash="30019fc2">2020.sdp-1.24</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.24</doi>
      <revision id="1" href="2020.sdp-1.24v1" hash="38d9bf57" />
      <revision id="2" href="2020.sdp-1.24v2" hash="30019fc2" date="2021-01-01">Added missing reference to DUCS (Chaturvedi et al., 2020).</revision>
      <bibkey>chandrasekaran-etal-2020-overview-insights</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="32">
      <title>Team MLU@CL-SciSumm20 : Methods for Computational Linguistics Scientific Citation Linkage<fixed-case>MLU</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>CL</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>ci<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>umm20: Methods for Computational Linguistics Scientific Citation Linkage</title>
      <author><first>Rong</first><last>Huang</last></author>
      <author><first>Kseniia</first><last>Krylova</last></author>
      <pages>282–287</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our approach to the CL-SciSumm 2020 shared task toward the problem of identifying reference span of the citing article in the referred article. In Task 1a, we apply and compare different methods in combination with similarity scores to identify spans of the reference text for the given citance. In Task 1b, we use a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_regression">logistic regression</a> to classifying the discourse facets.</abstract>
      <url hash="717d0e75">2020.sdp-1.32</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.32</doi>
      <bibkey>huang-krylova-2020-team</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="36">
      <title>ARTU / TU Wien and Artificial Researcher@ LongSumm 20<fixed-case>ARTU</fixed-case> / <fixed-case>TU</fixed-case> <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ien and Artificial Researcher@ <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ong<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>umm 20</title>
      <author><first>Alaa</first><last>El-Ebshihy</last></author>
      <author><first>Annisa Maulida</first><last>Ningtyas</last></author>
      <author><first>Linda</first><last>Andersson</last></author>
      <author><first>Florina</first><last>Piroi</last></author>
      <author><first>Andreas</first><last>Rauber</last></author>
      <pages>310–317</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we present our approach to solve the LongSumm 2020 Shared Task, at the 1st Workshop on Scholarly Document Processing. The objective of the long summaries task is to generate long summaries that cover salient information in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_literature">scientific articles</a>. The task is to generate abstractive and extractive summaries of a given <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_literature">scientific article</a>. In the proposed approach, we are inspired by the concept of Argumentative Zoning (AZ) that de- fines the main rhetorical structure in scientific articles. We define two aspects that should be covered in scientific paper summary, namely Claim / Method and Conclusion / Result aspects. We use Solr index to expand the sentences of the paper abstract. We formulate each abstract sentence in a given publication as query to retrieve similar sentences from the text body of the document itself. We utilize a sentence selection algorithm described in previous literature to select sentences for the final summary that covers the two aforementioned aspects.</abstract>
      <url hash="1b9d1bba">2020.sdp-1.36</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.36</doi>
      <bibkey>el-ebshihy-etal-2020-artu</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="40">
      <title>Divide and Conquer : From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complexity">Complexity</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simplicity">Simplicity</a> for Lay Summarization</title>
      <author><first>Rochana</first><last>Chaturvedi</last></author>
      <author><first>Saachi</first><last>.</last></author>
      <author><first>Jaspreet Singh</first><last>Dhani</last></author>
      <author><first>Anurag</first><last>Joshi</last></author>
      <author><first>Ankush</first><last>Khanna</last></author>
      <author><first>Neha</first><last>Tomar</last></author>
      <author><first>Swagata</first><last>Duari</last></author>
      <author><first>Alka</first><last>Khurana</last></author>
      <author><first>Vasudha</first><last>Bhatnagar</last></author>
      <pages>344–355</pages>
      <abstract>We describe our approach for the 1st Computational Linguistics Lay Summary Shared Task CL-LaySumm20. The task is to produce non-technical summaries of scholarly documents. The summary should be within easy grasp of a layman who may not be well versed with the domain of the research article. We propose a two step divide-and-conquer approach. First, we judiciously select segments of the documents that are not overly pedantic and are likely to be of interest to the laity, and over-extract sentences from each segment using an unsupervised network based method. Next, we perform abstractive summarization on these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstraction_(computer_science)">extractions</a> and systematically merge the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstraction_(computer_science)">abstractions</a>. We run ablation studies to establish that each step in our pipeline is critical for improvement in the quality of lay summary. Our approach leverages state-of-the-art pre-trained deep neural network based models as zero-shot learners to achieve high scores on the task.</abstract>
      <url hash="d1fa233a">2020.sdp-1.40</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="b1c1bf76">2020.sdp-1.40.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.sdp-1.40</doi>
      <bibkey>chaturvedi-etal-2020-divide</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/anuragjoshi3519/laysumm20" additional="false">anuragjoshi3519/laysumm20</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>