<collection id="2020.readi">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on Tools and Resources to Empower People with REAding DIfficulties (READI)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>N&#250;ria</first><last>Gala</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Rodrigo</first><last>Wilkens</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-45-0</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="7f25a2c1">2020.readi-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>readi-2020-tools</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Automatically Assess Children&#8217;s Reading Skills</title>
      <author><first>Ornella</first><last>Mich</last></author>
      <author><first>Nadia</first><last>Mana</last></author>
      <author><first>Roberto</first><last>Gretter</last></author>
      <author><first>Marco</first><last>Matassoni</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniele</first><last>Falavigna</last></author>
      <pages>20&#8211;26</pages>
      <abstract>Assessing reading skills is an important task teachers have to perform at the beginning of a new scholastic year to evaluate the starting level of the class and properly plan next learning activities. Digital tools based on automatic speech recognition (ASR) may be really useful to support teachers in this task, currently very time consuming and prone to human errors. This paper presents a web application for automatically assessing fluency and accuracy of oral reading in children attending Italian primary and lower secondary schools. Our system, based on ASR technology, implements the Cornoldi&#8217;s MT battery, which is a well-known Italian test to assess reading skills. The front-end of the system has been designed following the participatory design approach by involving end users from the beginning of the creation process. Teachers may use our system to both test student&#8217;s reading skills and monitor their performance over time. In fact, the system offers an effective graphical visualization of the assessment results for both individual students and entire class. The paper also presents the results of a pilot study to evaluate the system usability with teachers.</abstract>
      <url hash="66aabc96">2020.readi-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>mich-etal-2020-automatically</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Text Simplification to Help Individuals with Low Vision Read More Fluently</title>
      <author><first>Lauren</first><last>Sauvan</last></author>
      <author><first>Natacha</first><last>Stolowy</last></author>
      <author><first>Carlos</first><last>Aguilar</last></author>
      <author><first>Thomas</first><last>Fran&#231;ois</last></author>
      <author><first>N&#250;ria</first><last>Gala</last></author>
      <author><first>Fr&#233;d&#233;ric</first><last>Matonti</last></author>
      <author><first>Eric</first><last>Castet</last></author>
      <author><first>Aur&#233;lie</first><last>Calabr&#232;se</last></author>
      <pages>27&#8211;32</pages>
      <abstract>The objective of this work is to introduce text simplification as a potential reading aid to help improve the poor reading performance experienced by visually impaired individuals. As a first step, we explore what makes a text especially complex when read with low vision, by assessing the individual effect of three word properties (frequency, orthographic similarity and length) on reading speed in the presence of Central visual Field Loss (CFL). Individuals with bilateral CFL induced by macular diseases read pairs of French sentences displayed with the self-paced reading method. For each sentence pair, sentence n contained a target word matched with a synonym word of the same length included in sentence n+1. Reading time was recorded for each target word. Given the corpus we used, our results show that (1) word frequency has a significant effect on reading time (the more frequent the faster the reading speed) with larger amplitude (in the range of seconds) compared to normal vision; (2) word neighborhood size has a significant effect on reading time (the more neighbors the slower the reading speed), this effect being rather small in amplitude, but interestingly reversed compared to normal vision; (3) word length has no significant effect on reading time. Supporting the development of new and more effective assistive technology to help low vision is an important and timely issue, with massive potential implications for social and rehabilitation practices. The end goal of this project will be to use our findings to custom text simplification to this specific population and use it as an optimal and efficient reading aid.</abstract>
      <url hash="af173928">2020.readi-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>sauvan-etal-2020-text</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title><fixed-case>L</fixed-case>agun<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>est: A <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Based Application to Enhance Reading Comprehension</title>
      <author><first>Kepa</first><last>Bengoetxea</last></author>
      <author><first>Itziar</first><last>Gonzalez-Dios</last></author>
      <author><first>Amaia</first><last>Aguirregoitia</last></author>
      <pages>63&#8211;69</pages>
      <abstract>The ability to read and understand written texts plays an important role in education, above all in the last years of primary education. This is especially pertinent in language immersion educational programmes, where some students have low linguistic competence in the languages of instruction. In this context, adapting the texts to the individual needs of each student requires a considerable effort by education professionals. However, language technologies can facilitate the laborious adaptation of materials in order to enhance reading comprehension. In this paper, we present LagunTest, a NLP based application that takes as input a text in Basque or English, and offers synonyms, definitions, examples of the words in different contexts and presents some linguistic characteristics as well as visualizations. LagunTest is based on reusable and open multilingual and multimodal tools, and it is also distributed with an open license. LagunTest is intended to ease the burden of education professionals in the task of adapting materials, and the output should always be supervised by them.</abstract>
      <url hash="6cf9848c">2020.readi-1.10</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>bengoetxea-etal-2020-laguntest</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>A Lexical Simplification Tool for Promoting Health Literacy</title>
      <author><first>Leonardo</first><last>Zilio</last></author>
      <author><first>Liana</first><last>Braga Paraguassu</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis Antonio</first><last>Leiva Hercules</last></author>
      <author><first>Gabriel</first><last>Ponomarenko</last></author>
      <author><first>Laura</first><last>Berwanger</last></author>
      <author><first>Maria Jos&#233;</first><last>Bocorny Finatto</last></author>
      <pages>70&#8211;76</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents MedSimples, an authoring tool that combines Natural Language Processing, Corpus Linguistics and Terminology to help writers to convert health-related information into a more accessible version for people with low literacy skills. MedSimples applies parsing methods associated with lexical resources to automatically evaluate a text and present simplification suggestions that are more suitable for the target audience. Using the suggestions provided by the tool, the author can adapt the original text and make it more accessible. The focus of MedSimples lies on texts for special purposes, so that it not only deals with general vocabulary, but also with specialized terms. The tool is currently under development, but an online working prototype exists and can be tested freely. An assessment of MedSimples was carried out aiming at evaluating its current performance with some promising results, especially for informing the future developments that are planned for the tool.</abstract>
      <url hash="68c9b2a5">2020.readi-1.11</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>zilio-etal-2020-lexical</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>A multi-lingual and cross-domain analysis of features for text simplification</title>
      <author><first>Regina</first><last>Stodden</last></author>
      <author><first>Laura</first><last>Kallmeyer</last></author>
      <pages>77&#8211;84</pages>
      <abstract>In text simplification and readability research, several features have been proposed to estimate or simplify a complex text, e.g., readability scores, sentence length, or proportion of POS tags. These features are however mainly developed for English. In this paper, we investigate their relevance for Czech, German, English, Spanish, and Italian text simplification corpora. Our multi-lingual and multi-domain corpus analysis shows that the relevance of different features for text simplification is different per corpora, language, and domain. For example, the relevance of the lexical complexity is different across all languages, the BLEU score across all domains, and 14 features within the web domain corpora. Overall, the negative statistical tests regarding the other features across and within domains and languages lead to the assumption that text simplification models may be transferable between different domains or different languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="34148313">2020.readi-1.12</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>stodden-kallmeyer-2020-multi</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>