<collection id="2020.mmw">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the LREC 2020 Workshop on Multimodal Wordnets (MMW2020)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Thierry</first><last>Declerk</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Itziar</first><last>Gonzalez-Dios</last></editor>
      <editor><first>German</first><last>Rigau</last></editor>
      <publisher>The European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-41-2</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="68b831a4">2020.mmw-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>mmw-2020-lrec</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title><fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et 2020: Improving and Extending a <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et for <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish using an Open-Source Methodology</title>
      <author><first>John Philip</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexandre</first><last>Rademaker</last></author>
      <author><first>Ewa</first><last>Rudnicka</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <pages>14&#8211;19</pages>
      <abstract>WordNet, while one of the most widely used resources for NLP, has not been updated for a long time, and as such a new project English WordNet has arisen to continue the development of the model under an open-source paradigm. In this paper, we detail the second release of this resource entitled &#8220;English WordNet 2020&#8221;. The work has focused firstly, on the introduction of new synsets and senses and developing guidelines for this and secondly, on the integration of contributions from other projects. We present the changes in this edition, which total over 15,000 changes over the previous release.</abstract>
      <url hash="5b8530e9">2020.mmw-1.3</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>mccrae-etal-2020-english</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Adding Pronunciation Information to Wordnets</title>
      <author><first>Thierry</first><last>Declerck</last></author>
      <author><first>Lenka</first><last>Bajcetic</last></author>
      <author><first>Melanie</first><last>Siegel</last></author>
      <pages>39&#8211;44</pages>
      <abstract>We describe on-going work consisting in adding pronunciation information to wordnets, as such information can indicate specific senses of a word. Many wordnets associate with their senses only a lemma form and a part-of-speech tag. At the same time, we are aware that additional linguistic information can be useful for identifying a specific sense of a wordnet lemma when encountered in a corpus. While work already deals with the addition of grammatical number or grammatical gender information to wordnet lemmas,we are investigating the linking of wordnet lemmas to pronunciation information, adding thus a speech-related modality to wordnets</abstract>
      <url hash="66a1e156">2020.mmw-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>declerck-etal-2020-adding</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>