<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.peoples">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Computational Modeling of People's Opinions, Personality, and Emotion's in Social Media</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Malvina</first><last>Nissim</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Viviana</first><last>Patti</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Barbara</first><last>Plank</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Esin</first><last>Durmus</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9f683407">2020.peoples-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>peoples-2020-modeling</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Persuasiveness of News Editorials depending on Ideology and Personality</title>
      <author><first>Roxanne</first><last>El Baff</last></author>
      <author><first>Khalid</first><last>Al Khatib</last></author>
      <author><first>Benno</first><last>Stein</last></author>
      <author><first>Henning</first><last>Wachsmuth</last></author>
      <pages>29–40</pages>
      <abstract>News editorials aim to shape the opinions of their readership and the general public on timely controversial issues. The impact of an editorial on the reader’s opinion does not only depend on its content and style, but also on the reader’s profile. Previous work has studied the effect of editorial style depending on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ideology">general political ideologies</a> (liberals vs.conservatives). In our work, we dig deeper into the persuasiveness of both content and style, exploring the role of the intensity of an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ideology">ideology</a> (lean vs.extreme) and the reader’s personality traits (agreeableness, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conscientiousness">conscientiousness</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraversion_and_introversion">extraversion</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuroticism">neuroticism</a>, and openness). Concretely, we train content- and style-based models on New York Times editorials for different ideology- and personality-specific groups. Our results suggest that particularly readers with extreme ideology and non role model personalities are impacted by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Style_(manner_of_address)">style</a>. We further analyze the importance of various text features with respect to the editorials’ impact, the readers’ profile, and the editorials’ geographical scope.</abstract>
      <url hash="735e8007">2020.peoples-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>el-baff-etal-2020-persuasiveness</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>KanCMD : Kannada CodeMixed Dataset for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">Sentiment Analysis</a> and Offensive Language Detection<fixed-case>K</fixed-case>an<fixed-case>CMD</fixed-case>: <fixed-case>K</fixed-case>annada <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ode<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>ixed Dataset for Sentiment Analysis and Offensive Language Detection</title>
      <author><first>Adeep</first><last>Hande</last></author>
      <author><first>Ruba</first><last>Priyadharshini</last></author>
      <author><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></author>
      <pages>54–63</pages>
      <abstract>We introduce Kannada CodeMixed Dataset (KanCMD), a multi-task learning dataset for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> and offensive language identification. The KanCMD dataset highlights two real-world issues from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media text</a>. First, it contains actual comments in code mixed text posted by users on YouTube social media, rather than in monolingual text from the textbook. Second, it has been annotated for two tasks, namely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> and offensive language detection for under-resourced Kannada language. Hence, KanCMD is meant to stimulate research in under-resourced Kannada language on real-world code-mixed social media text and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-task_learning">multi-task learning</a>. KanCMD was obtained by crawling the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube">YouTube</a>, and a minimum of three annotators annotates each comment. We release KanCMD 7,671 comments for multitask learning research purpose.</abstract>
      <url hash="5df5d2e3">2020.peoples-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>hande-etal-2020-kancmd</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Contextual Augmentation of Pretrained Language Models for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_recognition">Emotion Recognition</a> in Conversations</title>
      <author><first>Jonggu</first><last>Kim</last></author>
      <author><first>Hyeonmok</first><last>Ko</last></author>
      <author><first>Seoha</first><last>Song</last></author>
      <author><first>Saebom</first><last>Jang</last></author>
      <author><first>Jiyeon</first><last>Hong</last></author>
      <pages>64–73</pages>
      <abstract>Since language model pretraining to learn contextualized word representations has been proposed, pretrained language models have made success in many natural language processing tasks. That is because it is helpful to use individual contextualized representations of self-attention layers as to initialize parameters for downstream tasks. Yet, unfortunately, use of pretrained language models for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_recognition">emotion recognition</a> in conversations has not been studied enough. We firstly use ELECTRA which is a state-of-the-art pretrained language model and validate the performance on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_recognition">emotion recognition</a> in conversations. Furthermore, we propose contextual augmentation of pretrained language models for emotion recognition in conversations, which is to consider not only previous utterances, but also conversation-related information such as speakers, speech acts and topics. We classify information based on what the information is related to, and propose position of words corresponding to the information in the entire input sequence. To validate the proposed method, we conduct experiments on the DailyDialog dataset which contains abundant annotated information of conversations. The experiments show that the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> achieves state-of-the-art F1 scores on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> and significantly improves the performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="c1492b63">2020.peoples-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>kim-etal-2020-contextual</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/dailydialog">DailyDialog</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Multilingual Emoticon Prediction of Tweets about COVID-19<fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19</title>
      <author><first>Stefanos</first><last>Stoikos</last></author>
      <author><first>Mike</first><last>Izbicki</last></author>
      <pages>109–118</pages>
      <abstract>Emojis are a widely used tool for encoding emotional content in informal messages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">tweets</a>, and predicting which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emoji</a> corresponds to a piece of text can be used as a proxy for measuring the emotional content in the text. This paper presents the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> for predicting emojis in highly multilingual text. Our BERTmoticon model is a fine-tuned version of the BERT model, and it can predict emojis for text written in 102 different languages. We trained our BERTmoticon model on 54.2 million geolocated tweets sent in the first 6 months of 2020,and we apply the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> to a case study analyzing the emotional reaction of Twitter users to news about the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coronavirus">coronavirus</a>. Example findings include a spike in sadness when the World Health Organization (WHO) declared that coronavirus was a global pandemic, and a spike in anger and disgust when the number of COVID-19 related deaths in the United States surpassed one hundred thousand. We provide an easy-to-use and open source python library for predicting emojis with BERTmoticon so that the model can easily be applied to other data mining tasks.</abstract>
      <url hash="e5732990">2020.peoples-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>stoikos-izbicki-2020-multilingual</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/stefanos-stk/bertmoticon" additional="false">stefanos-stk/bertmoticon</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Experiencers, Stimuli, or Targets : Which Semantic Roles Enable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">Machine Learning</a> to Infer the Emotions?</title>
      <author><first>Laura Ana Maria</first><last>Oberländer</last></author>
      <author><first>Kevin</first><last>Reich</last></author>
      <author><first>Roman</first><last>Klinger</last></author>
      <pages>119–128</pages>
      <abstract>Emotion recognition is predominantly formulated as text classification in which textual units are assigned to an emotion from a predefined inventory (e.g., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear">fear</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joy">joy</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anger">anger</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disgust">disgust</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sadness">sadness</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Surprise_(emotion)">surprise</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trust_(social_science)">trust</a>, anticipation). More recently, semantic role labeling approaches have been developed to extract structures from the text to answer questions like : who is described to feel the emotion? (experiencer), what causes this emotion? (stimulus), and at which entity is it directed? (target). Though it has been shown that jointly modeling stimulus and emotion category prediction is beneficial for both subtasks, it remains unclear which of these semantic roles enables a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classifier_(linguistics)">classifier</a> to infer the emotion. Is it the experiencer, because the identity of a person is biased towards a particular emotion (X is always happy)? Is it a particular target (everybody loves X) or a stimulus (doing X makes everybody sad)? We answer these questions by training emotion classification models on five available datasets annotated with at least one semantic role by masking the fillers of these roles in the text in a controlled manner and find that across multiple corpora, stimuli and targets carry emotion information, while the experiencer might be considered a confounder. Further, we analyze if informing the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> about the position of the role improves the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification decision</a>. Particularly on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">literature corpora</a> we find that the role information improves the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_classification">emotion classification</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="51a4fc17">2020.peoples-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>oberlander-etal-2020-experiencers</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Experimentadores, estímulos ou alvos: quais papéis semânticos permitem que o aprendizado de máquina infira as emoções?</title_pt>
      <title_ar>المتمرسون أو المحفزات أو الأهداف: ما هي الأدوار الدلالية التي تمكن التعلم الآلي من استنتاج المشاعر؟</title_ar>
      <title_es>Experimentadores, estímulos u objetivos: ¿qué roles semánticos permiten al aprendizaje automático inferir las emociones?</title_es>
      <title_ja>経験者、刺激、またはターゲット：どのセマンティックな役割が感情を推論する機械学習を可能にしますか？</title_ja>
      <title_zh>验者、刺激、趋向:何语义角色使机器学能推断出情?</title_zh>
      <title_hi>अनुभवकर्ता, उत्तेजना, या लक्ष्य: कौन सी शब्दार्थ भूमिकाएं भावनाओं का अनुमान लगाने के लिए मशीन लर्निंग को सक्षम करती हैं?</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Eispéiris, Spreagthaigh, nó Spriocanna: Cad iad na Róil Shéimeantacha a Chumasóidh Foghlaim le Meaisín chun na Mothúcháin a Tátal?</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ექსპერიმენტები, სტიმული, ან მიზეზები: რომელსაც სემანტიკური პროლის შესაძლებელია მაქსინის სწავლებას ემიოციების გახსნა?</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Tapasztalatok, ösztönzők vagy célok: Milyen szemantikus szerepek teszik lehetővé a gépi tanulás számára az érzelmek fertőzését?</title_hu>
      <title_it>Esperti, stimoli o obiettivi: quali ruoli semantici consentono al machine learning di infettare le emozioni?</title_it>
      <title_el>Εμπειρητές, διεγερτικά ή στόχοι: Ποιοι σημασιολογικοί ρόλοι επιτρέπουν τη μηχανική μάθηση να συναγάγει τα συναισθήματα;</title_el>
      <title_kk>Эксперименттер, Стимули немесе Мақсаттары: Қай семантикалық рольдер көңіл көңіл көңіл көңіл күйін түсіруге мүмкіндік береді?</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Pengalaman, Stimuli, atau Sasaran: Rol Semantik mana yang Membolehkan Mesin Belajar untuk Melebuhkan Emosi?</title_ms>
      <title_lt>Patikrininkai, stimuliai arba tikslai: kokie Semantiniai vaidmenys leidžia mašinų mokymąsi įžeisti emocijas?</title_lt>
      <title_ml>പരിചയപ്പെട്ടവര്‍, സ്റ്റിമുലി, അല്ലെങ്കില്‍ ലക്ഷ്യങ്ങള്‍: ഏത് സെമാന്റിക് റോള്‍സ് മെഷീന്‍ പഠിക്കുന്നത് പ്രാവര്‍ത്തികമാ</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Эмч хүмүүс, Стимули, эсвэл Царлын төлөө: Хоёр семантик нөлөөлөл нь машин суралцах мэдрэмжүүдийг бууруулах боломжтой вэ?</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Doświadczeni, stymuli lub cele: Jakie role semantyczne umożliwiają uczenie maszynowe wywoływanie emocji?</title_pl>
      <title_mk>Експериментари, стимули или цели: Кои семантични улоги овозможуваат машинско учење да ги внесе емоциите?</title_mk>
      <title_ro>Experienți, stimuli sau ținte: Ce roluri semantice permit învățării automate să infecteze emoțiile?</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Iskusnici, Stimuli ili ciljevi: Koje semantičke uloge omogućavaju naučenje mašine da podnese emocije?</title_sr>
      <title_si>පරීක්ෂකයෝ, ස්ටිමුලී, නැත්තම් ඉලක්කයෝ: මොන සෙමැන්ටික් භාවිතාවක්ද යන්ත්‍රය ඉගෙන ගන්න පුළුවන්ද?</title_si>
      <title_mt>Experiencers, Stimuli, or Targets: Which Semantic Roles Enable Machine Learning to Infer the Emotions?</title_mt>
      <title_so>Aqoonsada, Stimuli, ama Targeeyinka: Qaybaha Semantic Roles ee Mashinka ku habboon karta barashada si uu u qabsado Emiraaniyada?</title_so>
      <title_no>Comment</title_no>
      <title_ta>பயிற்சிகள், ஸ்டிமுலி அல்லது சேர்க்கைகள்: எது செமாண்டிக் குறிப்பிடும் இயந்திரம் உணர்வுகளை புகுத்துவதற்கு கற்றுக் க</title_ta>
      <title_ur>آزمائش کرنے والے، سٹیمولی یا تارژیٹ: کس سیمنٹی رول کو ماشین سکھانے کے لئے امکان دینے کے لئے امکان کرتا ہے؟</title_ur>
      <title_sv>Erfarenheter, stimuli eller mål: Vilka semantiska roller gör det möjligt för maskininlärning att infektera känslorna?</title_sv>
      <title_uz>Eʼtibor beruvchilar, Stimuli yoki maqolalar: Emotionalarni ishga tushirish uchun qanday semantik qoidalari mashinani yoqish mumkin?</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Các chuyên gia du hành, Stimuli, or Target: vai nào là Semantic outfit Machine learn to infer the Emotions?</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Опитници, стимули или цели: кои семантични роли позволяват машинното обучение да влоши емоциите?</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Iskusnici, Stimuli ili ciljevi: Koje semantičke uloge omogućavaju naučenje strojeva da ublaže emocije?</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Ervaringen, stimuli of doelen: Welke semantische rollen maken Machine Learning in staat om emoties op te leiden?</title_nl>
      <title_da>Erfaringere, stimuli eller mål: Hvilke semantiske roller gør det muligt for maskinlæring at inficere følelserne?</title_da>
      <title_id>Pengalaman, Stimuli, atau Target: Rol Semantik Mana Membolehkan Mesin Belajar untuk Menyebabkan Emosi?</title_id>
      <title_de>Erfahrungen, Anregungen oder Ziele: Welche semantischen Rollen ermöglichen maschinelles Lernen, Emotionen zu leiten?</title_de>
      <title_ko>체험자, 자극물 또는 목표: 어떤 의미 역할이 기계 학습으로 하여금 감정을 추측할 수 있게 합니까?</title_ko>
      <title_fa>تجربه‌کنندگان، استیمولی، یا هدف: کدام نقش‌های سیمانتیک برای یادگیری ماشین برای تزریق احساسات فعال می‌کند؟</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Wataalamu, Stimuli, au Tarehe: Ni Mashindano gani ya Semantic Roles Yawezesha Mashine Kujifunza Kuingiza Matukio?</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Deneyciler, Stimuli veya hedefler:Hangi semantik roller Duyguları aşamaya çalışabilir?</title_tr>
      <title_af>Eksperimenteerders, Stimuli of Teëls: Watter semantiese roles Aktiveer Masjien Leer om die Emotisies te Infer?</title_af>
      <title_am>አዋቂዎች፥ ስቱሙሊ ወይም ትዕግስት፤ ማንኛው ሰሜናቲክ ሮሊስ ወደ ማሳየት የመሳፍን መሳሪያን ያስችላል?</title_am>
      <title_sq>Përvojësit, Stimuli apo Objektivat: Cilat role Semantike Aktivizojnë Mësimin e Mësimit për të Inferuar Emocionet?</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Փորձառություններ, Ստիմուլի կամ նպատակներ. ո՞ր սեմանտիկ դերեր են հնարավորություն տալիս մեքենայի սովորելը ներխուժելու զգացմունքները:</title_hy>
      <title_az>İşləyici, Stimuli, ya da Tariqlər: Hangi Semantik Rullər Duyguları Açırmaq üçün Makina Öyrənməsini Qabilleştir?</title_az>
      <title_bn>অভিজ্ঞদের, স্টিমুলি অথবা টার্গেট: কোন সেম্যান্টিক রোলেস সেম্যান্টিক কোন মেশিন ইমুটিকগুলো প্রবাহিত করতে শিক্ষ</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Experiencers, Stimuli, or Targets: Which Semantic Roles Enable Machine Learning to Infer the Emotions?</title_ca>
      <title_bs>Iskusnici, Stimuli ili ciljevi: Koje semantičke uloge omogućavaju naučenje mašine da ublaže emocije?</title_bs>
      <title_fi>Kokejat, stimuloijat tai tavoitteet: Mitkä semanttiset roolit mahdollistavat koneoppimisen heikentämään tunteita?</title_fi>
      <title_cs>Zkušenosti, stimuly nebo cíle: Které sémantické role umožňují strojovému učení vyvodit emoce?</title_cs>
      <title_et>Kogemused, stiimulid või eesmärgid: millised semantilised rollid võimaldavad masinõppel tundeid vähendada?</title_et>
      <title_jv>Sampeyan, Stimuli, opo TarGet:Sampeyan sematik Dowek Inggal Majin Jejaring Bapak Jejaring?</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Izkušenci, stimuli ali cilji: Katere semantične vloge omogočajo strojno učenje, da zmanjša čustva?</title_sk>
      <title_he>חווים, סטימולי, או מטרות: איזה תפקידים סמנטיים מאפשרים למכונה ללמוד להפריע לרגשות?</title_he>
      <title_bo>སྒེར་ཚོགས་དང་། སྦུང་བྱེད་པའམ་དམིགས་ཡུལ། སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་རྩིས་འཁོར་གྱི་ལག་ལེན་སྟངས་གང་ཞིག་ནུས</title_bo>
      <title_ha>Wata Citiyyar, Dakata, ko da Taraja: Nane Mai Gayya wa Role na Semantic Mai Shirin da Akwai Tafiyar da Cikaktan da?</title_ha>
      <abstract_pt>O reconhecimento de emoções é predominantemente formulado como classificação de texto em que unidades textuais são atribuídas a uma emoção a partir de um inventário predefinido (por exemplo, medo, alegria, raiva, desgosto, tristeza, surpresa, confiança, antecipação). Mais recentemente, abordagens de rotulagem de papéis semânticos foram desenvolvidas para extrair estruturas do texto para responder a perguntas como: “quem é descrito para sentir a emoção?” (experimentador), “o que causa essa emoção?” (estímulo), e para qual entidade é direcionado?” (alvo). Embora tenha sido demonstrado que a modelagem conjunta de estímulo e previsão de categoria de emoção é benéfica para ambas as subtarefas, ainda não está claro qual desses papéis semânticos permite que um classificador infira a emoção. É o experimentador, porque a identidade de uma pessoa é tendenciosa para uma emoção particular (X está sempre feliz)? É um alvo específico (todos amam X) ou um estímulo (fazer X deixa todos tristes)? Respondemos a essas perguntas treinando modelos de classificação de emoções em cinco conjuntos de dados disponíveis anotados com pelo menos um papel semântico, mascarando os preenchimentos desses papéis no texto de maneira controlada e descobrimos que em vários corpora, estímulos e alvos carregam informações de emoção, enquanto o experimentador pode ser considerado um confundidor. Além disso, analisamos se informar ao modelo sobre a posição do papel melhora a decisão de classificação. Particularmente nos corpora da literatura encontramos que a informação do papel melhora a classificação da emoção.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>تتم صياغة التعرف على المشاعر في الغالب كتصنيف للنص يتم فيه تخصيص الوحدات النصية لعاطفة من قائمة جرد محددة مسبقًا (على سبيل المثال ، الخوف ، الفرح ، الغضب ، الاشمئزاز ، الحزن ، المفاجأة ، الثقة ، الترقب). في الآونة الأخيرة ، تم تطوير مناهج تصنيف الأدوار الدلالية لاستخراج الهياكل من النص للإجابة على أسئلة مثل: "من الموصوف ليشعر بالعواطف؟" (مجرب) ، "ما الذي يسبب هذه المشاعر؟" (التحفيز) ، وإلى أي كيان يتم توجيهه؟ " (هدف). على الرغم من أنه قد ثبت أن النمذجة المشتركة لتنبؤ فئة التحفيز والعاطفة مفيدة لكلتا المهمتين الفرعيتين ، إلا أنه لا يزال من غير الواضح أي من هذه الأدوار الدلالية يمكّن المصنف من استنتاج المشاعر. هل هو المجرب ، لأن هوية الشخص منحازة تجاه عاطفة معينة (X دائمًا سعيد)؟ هل هو هدف معين (الجميع يحب X) أم حافزًا (فعل X يجعل الجميع حزينًا)؟ نجيب على هذه الأسئلة من خلال تدريب نماذج تصنيف المشاعر على خمس مجموعات بيانات متاحة مشروحة بدور دلالي واحد على الأقل عن طريق إخفاء مواد ملء هذه الأدوار في النص بطريقة مسيطر عليها ونجد أنه عبر مجموعات متعددة ، تحمل المحفزات والأهداف معلومات عاطفية ، بينما المجرب قد يعتبر مؤكد. علاوة على ذلك ، نقوم بتحليل ما إذا كان إبلاغ النموذج عن منصب الدور يحسن قرار التصنيف. على وجه الخصوص في مجموعات الأدب نجد أن معلومات الدور تعمل على تحسين تصنيف المشاعر.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>El reconocimiento de emociones se formula predominantemente como una clasificación de texto en la que se asignan unidades textuales a una emoción de un inventario predefinido (por ejemplo, miedo, alegría, enfado, disgusto, tristeza, sorpresa, confianza, anticipación). Más recientemente, se han desarrollado enfoques de etiquetado semántico de roles para extraer estructuras del texto para responder a preguntas como: «¿a quién se describe para sentir la emoción?» (experimentador), «¿qué causa esta emoción?» (estímulo), y ¿a qué entidad se dirige?» (objetivo). Aunque se ha demostrado que modelar conjuntamente la predicción de la categoría de estímulos y emociones es beneficioso para ambas subtareas, no está claro cuál de estos roles semánticos permite a un clasificador inferir la emoción. ¿Es el experimentador, porque la identidad de una persona está sesgada hacia una emoción en particular (X siempre es feliz)? ¿Es un objetivo en particular (a todo el mundo le gusta X) o un estímulo (hacer X entristece a todos)? Respondemos a estas preguntas entrenando modelos de clasificación de emociones en cinco conjuntos de datos disponibles anotados con al menos un rol semántico, enmascarando los rellenos de estos roles en el texto de manera controlada y descubrimos que a través de múltiples cuerpos, los estímulos y los objetivos llevan información sobre las emociones, mientras que el el experimentador podría considerarse un factor de confusión. Además, analizamos si informar al modelo sobre la posición del rol mejora la decisión de clasificación. Particularmente en los corpus de la literatura encontramos que la información del rol mejora la clasificación de las emociones.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>感情認識は、テキスト単位が事前定義された目録（例えば、恐怖、喜び、怒り、嫌悪、悲しみ、驚き、信頼、予想）から感情に割り当てられるテキスト分類として主に定式化される。 最近では、「誰が感情を感じるように記述されているか」（経験者）、「この感情を引き起こすものは何か」（刺激）、そしてそれがどの実体に向けられているか」（ターゲット）などの質問に答えるために、テキストから構造を抽出するための意味的役割ラベリングのアプローチが開発されている。 刺激と感情のカテゴリ予測を共同でモデル化することは、両方のサブタスクにとって有益であることが示されているが、これらの意味的役割のうちのどれが分類子が感情を推論することを可能にするかはまだ不明である。 人のアイデンティティが特定の感情に偏っているため（ Xは常に幸せです）、経験者ですか？ 特定のターゲット（誰もがXを愛している）または刺激（ Xをすると誰もが悲しくなる）ですか？ 私たちは、これらの質問に答えるために、少なくとも1つのセマンティックロールで注釈された5つの利用可能なデータセット上で感情分類モデルをトレーニングし、これらのロールの記入者を制御された方法でテキストにマスクし、複数のコーパスにわたって刺激とターゲットが感情情報を持つことを発見しますが、経験者は混乱者と見なされる可能性があります。 さらに、役割の位置をモデルに知らせることが分類決定を改善するかどうかを分析します。 特にコーパスに関する文献では、役割情報が感情の分類を改善することがわかります。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>情识主表为文本分类,其文本单位从预定义清单(如,恐惧喜怒,厌恶悲伤,惊讶信任,预期)中分配。 近者,已发语义角标法,取构于文本以对,"谁述以感情? (验者):"何以致此?" (激),其孰为实? ()。 虽已证合建模激情类,皆有益于二子,而未详其语义角色者,使分类器得而推之。 体验者,以一人偏于特定情(X常乐之)乎? 一特定之所适(人之所好X)犹激(为X令人悲)? 五可以数集上练情类以应之,集以受控数以掩其填充物,见于数语料库,激趣携息,而体验者或以为杂也。 此外,我们分析向模形通角色位位改善了分类。 特在文学语料库上,角色信情类。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>भावना मान्यता मुख्य रूप से पाठ वर्गीकरण के रूप में तैयार की जाती है जिसमें पाठ्य इकाइयों को एक पूर्वनिर्धारित सूची (जैसे, भय, खुशी, क्रोध, घृणा, उदासी, आश्चर्य, विश्वास, प्रत्याशा) से एक भावना को सौंपा जाता है। हाल ही में, शब्दार्थ भूमिका लेबलिंग दृष्टिकोण ों को पाठ से संरचनाओं को निकालने के लिए विकसित किया गया है जैसे सवालों का जवाब देने के लिए: "भावनाओं को महसूस करने के लिए किसका वर्णन किया गया है? (अनुभवकर्ता), "इस भावना का क्या कारण है? (उत्तेजना), और यह किस इकाई पर निर्देशित है? (लक्ष्य)। हालांकि यह दिखाया गया है कि संयुक्त रूप से मॉडलिंग उत्तेजना और भावना श्रेणी की भविष्यवाणी दोनों उप-कार्यों के लिए फायदेमंद है, यह स्पष्ट नहीं है कि इनमें से कौन सी शब्दार्थ भूमिकाएं भावनाओं का अनुमान लगाने के लिए क्लासिफायर को सक्षम बनाती हैं। क्या यह अनुभवकर्ता है, क्योंकि किसी व्यक्ति की पहचान एक विशेष भावना के प्रति पक्षपाती है (एक्स हमेशा खुश रहता है)? क्या यह एक विशेष लक्ष्य है (हर कोई एक्स से प्यार करता है) या एक उत्तेजना (एक्स करने से हर कोई दुखी हो जाता है)? हम इन सवालों के जवाब पांच उपलब्ध डेटासेट पर भावना वर्गीकरण मॉडल को प्रशिक्षित करके देते हैं, जो कम से कम एक शब्दार्थ भूमिका के साथ एनोटेट किए गए हैं, जो पाठ में इन भूमिकाओं के भरावों को एक नियंत्रित तरीके से मास्क करके और पाते हैं कि कई कॉर्पोरेट, उत्तेजनाओं और लक्ष्यों में भावना की जानकारी होती है, जबकि अनुभवकर्ता को एक confounder माना जा सकता है। इसके अलावा, हम विश्लेषण करते हैं कि क्या भूमिका की स्थिति के बारे में मॉडल को सूचित करने से वर्गीकरण निर्णय में सुधार होता है। विशेष रूप से साहित्य निगम पर हम पाते हैं कि भूमिका की जानकारी भावना वर्गीकरण में सुधार करती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cruthaítear aithint mhothúcháin go príomha mar aicmiú téacs ina sanntar aonaid théacsacha do mhothúchán ó fhardal réamhshainithe (m.sh., eagla, áthas, fearg, náire, brón, iontas, muinín, oirchill). Le déanaí, forbraíodh cuir chuige um lipéadú ról shéimeantach chun struchtúir a bhaint as an téacs chun ceisteanna mar: “cé a gcuirtear síos air a bhraitheann an mhothúchán?” (taithí), “cad is cúis leis an mothúchán seo?” (spreagadh), agus ar cén eintiteas a bhfuil sé dírithe?” (sprioc). Cé go bhfuil sé léirithe go bhfuil buntáiste ag baint le comhmhúnlú spreagthach agus réamh-mheastachán ar chatagóir na mothúchán don dá fhothasc, níl sé soiléir cé acu de na róil shéimeantacha seo a chuireann ar chumas aicmitheora an mhothúchán a thuiscint. An é an taithí atá ann, toisc go bhfuil féiniúlacht duine claonta i dtreo mothúchán ar leith (tá X sásta i gcónaí)? An sprioc faoi leith é (is breá le gach éinne X) nó spreagadh (déanann X brón ar gach éinne)? Freagraimid na ceisteanna seo trí mhúnlaí aicmithe mothúcháin a oiliúint ar chúig thacar sonraí atá ar fáil agus anót orthu le ról shéimeantach amháin ar a laghad trí líontóirí na róil seo sa téacs a chumhdach ar bhealach rialaithe agus faighimid amach go n-iompraíonn faisnéis mhothúcháin ar fud corpora, spreagthaí agus spriocanna iolracha, agus an d'fhéadfaí a mheas mar thaithíoir. Ina theannta sin, déanaimid anailís ar an bhfeabhsaítear an cinneadh aicmithe trí chur in iúl don mhúnla faoi shuíomh an róil. Go háirithe maidir le corpora litríochta feicimid go bhfeabhsaíonn an fhaisnéis róil an t-aicmiú mothúchán.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>Emotion recognition is predominantly formulated as text classification in which textual units are assigned to an emotion from a predefined inventory (e.g. fear, joy, anger, disgust, sad, surprise, trust, anticipation). უფრო ახლა, სემონტიკური პროლის მარტიკური მიღებები განვითარებულია ტექსტიდან სტრუქტურების გამოყენებას, როგორც "ვინ აღწერებულია ემოციონის გამოყენებას (გამოცდილებელი), 'რა იქნება ეს ემოციას?' (სტიმულ) და რომელსაც ინტერტიკოს მიერებულია? (მისამართი). თუმცა ჩვენ ჩვენებულია, რომ ერთადერთი მოდელირება სტიმულის და ემოციონის კატეგორია წინაწერების გამოსახულებელია ორივე სტიმულის გამოსახულებელია, მას არ უცნობია, რომელიც ამ სემონტიკური პროლი იმიტომ, რომ ადამიანის ადამიანის იდენტიფიკაცია განსაკუთრებული ემოციონის მიხედვით (X ყოველთვის ღათელია)? ეს განსაკუთრებული მიზეზია (ყველა X-ს მიყვარს) ან სტიმულა (X-ს გავაკეთება ყველას ცუდის)? ჩვენ ამ კითხვების შესაბამისი ემოციონის კლასიფიკაციის მოდელების შესაბამისი ხუთი ხელსაწყოფილი მონაცემების კონტროლიკაციის მოდელზე, რომელსაც უნდა ერთი სიმენტიკური პროლია, რომელსაც ტექსტის კონტროლისურად მაქსირებით ამ პროლის ნაწილე დამატებით, ვიანალიზებთ თუ მოდელის ინფორმაცია როლის პოციაციის პოციაციის შესახებ კლასიფიკაციის განსაზღვრებას. განსაკუთრებით ლიტერატურის კოპორაზე ჩვენ აღმოჩნეთ, რომ პროლური ინფორმაცია უფრო მეტადებს ემოციონის კლასიფიკაციას.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Il riconoscimento emotivo è formulato principalmente come classificazione testuale in cui unità testuali sono assegnate a un'emozione da un inventario predefinito (ad esempio paura, gioia, rabbia, disgusto, tristezza, sorpresa, fiducia, anticipazione). Più recentemente, sono stati sviluppati approcci semantici di etichettatura dei ruoli per estrarre strutture dal testo per rispondere a domande come: "Chi è descritto per sentire l'emozione?" (sperimentatore), 'cosa causa questa emozione?' (stimolo), e a quale entità è diretta?" (target). Anche se è stato dimostrato che la modellazione congiunta dello stimolo e della previsione delle categorie emotive è utile per entrambe le sottoattività, non è chiaro quale di questi ruoli semantici consenta a un classificatore di dedurre l'emozione. È l'sperimentatore, perché l'identità di una persona è di parte verso una particolare emozione (X è sempre felice)? È un obiettivo particolare (tutti amano X) o uno stimolo (fare X rende tutti tristi)? Rispondiamo a queste domande addestrando modelli di classificazione emotiva su cinque dataset disponibili annotati con almeno un ruolo semantico mascherando i riempitori di questi ruoli nel testo in modo controllato e scopriamo che attraverso più corpi, stimoli e bersagli trasportano informazioni emotive, mentre l'sperimentatore potrebbe essere considerato un confondente. Inoltre, analizziamo se informare il modello sulla posizione del ruolo migliora la decisione di classificazione. In particolare sui corpora letterari troviamo che l'informazione del ruolo migliora la classificazione emotiva.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_el>Η αναγνώριση συναισθημάτων διατυπώνεται κυρίως ως ταξινόμηση κειμένου στην οποία οι ενότητες κειμένου αντιστοιχούν σε ένα συναίσθημα από προκαθορισμένο κατάλογο (π.χ. φόβος, χαρά, θυμός, αηδία, θλίψη, έκπληξη, εμπιστοσύνη, προσδοκία). Πιο πρόσφατα, έχουν αναπτυχθεί προσεγγίσεις σημασιολογικής σήμανσης ρόλων για την εξαγωγή δομών από το κείμενο για να απαντήσουν σε ερωτήσεις όπως: "ποιος περιγράφεται για να αισθανθεί το συναίσθημα;" "Τι προκαλεί αυτό το συναίσθημα;" (ερέθισμα), και σε ποια οντότητα κατευθύνεται;" (στόχος). Αν και έχει αποδειχθεί ότι από κοινού η μοντελοποίηση ερεθίσματος και πρόβλεψης κατηγορίας συναισθημάτων είναι ευεργετική και για τις δύο δευτερεύουσες εργασίες, παραμένει ασαφές ποιος από αυτούς τους σημασιολογικούς ρόλους επιτρέπει σε έναν ταξινομητή να συναχθεί το συναίσθημα. Είναι ο βιωτής, επειδή η ταυτότητα ενός ατόμου είναι προκατειλημμένη προς ένα συγκεκριμένο συναίσθημα (ο Χ είναι πάντα χαρούμενος); Είναι ένας συγκεκριμένος στόχος (όλοι αγαπούν το Χ) ή ένα ερέθισμα (κάνοντας το Χ τους στενοχωρεί); Απαντώνουμε σε αυτές τις ερωτήσεις εκπαιδεύοντας μοντέλα ταξινόμησης συναισθημάτων σε πέντε διαθέσιμα σύνολα δεδομένων που σχολιάζονται με τουλάχιστον έναν σημασιολογικό ρόλο συγκαλύπτοντας τα πληρωτικά αυτών των ρόλων στο κείμενο με ελεγχόμενο τρόπο και διαπιστώνουμε ότι σε πολλαπλά σώματα, τα ερεθίσματα και οι στόχοι μεταφέρουν πληροφορίες συναισθημάτων, ενώ ο βιωτής μπορεί να θεωρηθεί σύγχυση. Επιπλέον, αναλύουμε εάν η ενημέρωση του μοντέλου για τη θέση του ρόλου βελτιώνει την απόφαση ταξινόμησης. Ιδιαίτερα σε λογοτεχνικά σώματα διαπιστώνουμε ότι οι πληροφορίες ρόλων βελτιώνουν την ταξινόμηση συναισθημάτων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az érzelmi felismerés elsősorban olyan szövegosztályozásként kerül megfogalmazásra, amelyben egy előre meghatározott leltárból (pl. félelem, öröm, harag, undor, szomorúság, meglepetés, bizalom, várakozás) szövegegységeket rendelnek egy érzelemhez. A közelmúltban szemantikus szerepjelölési megközelítéseket fejlesztettek ki a szövegből olyan struktúrák kivonására, amelyek megválaszolják a következő kérdéseket: "Ki érzi az érzelmet?" "Mi okozza ezt az érzelmet?" (ösztönzés), és melyik entitásra irányul?" (cél). Bár bebizonyították, hogy az inger és az érzelmi kategória előrejelzése együttes modellezése mindkét alcsoport számára előnyös, nem világos, hogy e szemantikai szerepek közül melyik teszi lehetővé az osztályozó számára az érzelem következtetését. Azért tapasztaló, mert egy személy identitása elfogult egy bizonyos érzelem iránt (X mindig boldog)? Ez egy bizonyos célpont (mindenki imádja az X-et) vagy egy ösztönző (az X-et mindenki elszomorítja)? Ezekre a kérdésekre úgy válaszolunk, hogy öt rendelkezésre álló, legalább egy szemantikai szereppel megjegyzett adatkészleten érzelmi osztályozási modelleket képzünk, ellenőrzött módon leplezve ezeknek a szerepeknek a betöltőit a szövegben, és megállapítjuk, hogy több corporán az ingerek és célpontok érzelmi információt hordoznak, míg a tapasztaló összezavarnak tekinthető. Továbbá elemezzük, hogy a modell tájékoztatása a szerep helyzetéről javítja-e a besorolási döntést. Különösen az irodalmi corporákon találjuk, hogy a szerep információja javítja az érzelmi osztályozást.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_mk>Признавањето на емоциите е претежно формулирано како класификација на текст во која текстуалните единици се придружени на емоции од претходно дефиниран inventory (на пример страв, радост, бес, одвратност, тага, изненадување, доверба, очекување). Неодамна се развиени пристапи за семантично означување на улогата за извлекување структури од текстот за одговор на прашања како: „Кој е опишан за чувство на емоциите?“ "Што ја предизвикува оваа емоција?" (стимул), и на кој ентитет е насочен? " (мета). Иако се покажа дека заедничкото моделирање на стимулот и предвидувањето на емоционалната категорија е корисно за двете потпрашања, останува нејасно која од овие семантични улоги овозможува класификаторот да ја заклучи емоцијата. Дали е тоа искуството, бидејќи идентитетот на личност е пристрасен кон одредена емоција (Х е секогаш среќен)? Is it a particular target (everybody loves X) or a stimulus (doing X makes everybody sad)?  Ние одговараме на овие прашања со обука на модели за класификација на емоции на пет достапни датотеки анотирани со најмалку една семантична улога со маскирање на исполнувањата на овие улоги во текстот на контролиран начин и откриваме дека низ повеќето корпора, стимулии и мети носат емоционални информации, додека искус Покрај тоа, анализираме дали информирањето на моделот за позицијата на улогата ја подобрува одлуката за класификација. Особено во врска со литературата, откриваме дека информациите за улогата ја подобруваат емоционалната класификација.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Emocijų pripažinimas daugiausia suformuluojamas kaip teksto klasifikacija, kurioje tekstiniai vienetai priskiriami emocijoms iš iš anksto apibrėžto sąrašo (pvz., baimė, džiaugsmas, pyktis, bjaurys, liūdnas, nuostaba, pasitikėjimas, tikėjimas). Neseniai buvo sukurti semantiniai vaidmens ženklinimo metodai, siekiant ištraukti struktūras iš teksto ir atsakyti į tokius klausimus kaip: "kas apibūdintas jausti emocijas?". "Kas sukelia šią emociją?" (stimulas) ir kuriam subjektui jis nukreiptas?“ (taikinys). Nors buvo įrodyta, kad bendras stimuliavimo modeliavimas ir emocijų kategorijos prognozė yra naudinga abiem paklausoms, vis dar neaišku, kuris iš šių semantinių vaidmenų leidžia klasifikatoriui daryti išvadą apie emocijas. Ar tai patiriantis asmuo, nes asmens tapatybė yra šališka tam tikrai emocijai (X visada laiminga)? Ar tai konkretus tikslas (visi myli X) arba stimulas (X darymas visiems liūdna)? Atsakydami į šiuos klausimus apmokome emocijų klasifikavimo modelius penkiuose turimuose duomenų rinkiniuose, kuriuose užfiksuotas bent vienas semantinis vaidmuo, paslėpdami šių vaidmenų užpildytus tekste kontroliuojamu būdu ir nustatydami, kad daugelyje kūnų, stimuliai ir tikslai nešioja emocinę informaciją, o patiriantis gali būti laikomas susipainiojančiu. Be to, analizuojame, ar modelio informavimas apie vaidmens padėtį gerina sprendimą dėl klasifikavimo. Ypač dėl literatūros korporai mes matome, kad informacija apie vaidmenį gerina emocijų klasifikaciją.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Pengenalan emosi terutamanya dibentuk sebagai klasifikasi teks di mana unit teks ditugaskan kepada emosi dari inventori terdefinisi (cth., ketakutan, kegembiraan, kemarahan, kesedihan, kejutan, kepercayaan, jangkaan). Baru-baru ini, pendekatan label peranan semantik telah dikembangkan untuk mengekstrak struktur dari teks untuk menjawab soalan seperti: 'siapa yang diterangkan untuk merasakan emosi?' "Apa yang menyebabkan emosi ini?" "Dan kepada makhluk-makhluk yang mana ia diharapkan?" (sasaran). Though it has been shown that jointly modeling stimulus and emotion category prediction is beneficial for both subtasks, it remains unclear which of these semantic roles enables a classifier to infer the emotion.  Adakah ia pengalaman, kerana identiti seseorang biased terhadap emosi tertentu (X sentiasa bahagia)? Adakah ia sasaran tertentu (semua orang suka X) atau stimulus (melakukan X membuat semua orang sedih)? Kami menjawab soalan ini dengan melatih model klasifikasi emosi pada lima set data yang tersedia yang dicatat dengan sekurang-kurangnya satu peranan semantik dengan menutup penuhi peranan ini dalam teks dengan cara yang dikawal dan mencari bahawa di seluruh korpra berbilang, stimuli dan sasaran membawa maklumat emosi, sementara pengalaman mungkin dianggap sebagai pengganggu. Lagipun, kita menganalisis jika memberitahu model mengenai kedudukan peran memperbaiki keputusan kelasukan. Terutama pada korpra literatur kita mendapati bahawa maklumat peran memperbaiki kelasukan emosi.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഇമോട്ടോഷന്‍ തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നത് പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട ട ടെക്സ്കൂള്‍ യൂണിറ്റുകള്‍ മുന്‍കൂട്ടി നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഒരു തട്ടില്‍ നിന്നുള്ള വികാരങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് വ അടുത്തിടെയുള്ള സെമാന്റിക് റോള്‍ ലേബിള്‍ ചെയ്യുന്നതിനുള്ള അടിസ്ഥാനങ്ങള്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. വാക്കുകളില (അനുഭവപ്പെട്ടവന്‍), എന്താണ് ഈ വികാരം? ആരാണ് അതിനെ നേര്‍വഴിയിലാക്കിയത്? (target).  ഒരുമിച്ചിട്ടുള്ള സ്റ്റോമിളുസും വികാരങ്ങളുടെ വിഭാഗവും പ്രവചനങ്ങളുടെ പ്രവചനങ്ങള്‍ രണ്ടുപേര്‍ക്കും പ്രയോജനകരമാണെന്ന് തെളിയിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നുവെ ഒരാളുടെ തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നതിനാല്‍ ഒരു പ്രത്യേക വികാരത്തിന്‍റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തിലേക്ക് തെറ്റായിരിക്കുന്നു (എ അതൊരു പ്രത്യേക ലക്ഷ്യം ആണോ (എല്ലാവരും X ഇഷ്ടപ്പെടുന്നു) അല്ലെങ്കില്‍ ഒരു സ്റ്റിമൂലസ് ആണോ (X ചെയ്യുന്നത് എല ഈ ചോദ്യങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഉത്തരം നല്‍കുന്നത് അഞ്ച് ലഭ്യമായ ഡാറ്റാസറ്റുകളില്‍ അഞ്ച് പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട വിവരങ്ങളില്‍ പരിശീലനത്തിന്റെ മോഡലുകള്‍ പരിശീലിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനാല്‍ ഈ ചോദ്യങ്ങളുട അതിനുശേഷം, നമ്മള്‍ അന്വേഷിക്കുന്നു, ഈ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനത്തിന്റെ സ്ഥാനത്തെപ്പറ്റി മോഡലിനെ അറിയിക്കുന്നുണ്ടോ എന പ്രത്യേകിച്ച് സാഹിത്രത്തിന്റെ കോര്‍പ്പോരിയെക്കുറിച്ച് നമ്മള്‍ കണ്ടെത്തുന്നു, പ്രഭാവ വ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ വ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Emotion recognition is predominantly formulated as text classification in which textual units are assigned to an emotion from a predefined inventory (e.g., fear, joy, anger, disgust, sadness, surprise, trust, anticipation).  More recently, semantic role labeling approaches have been developed to extract structures from the text to answer questions like: 'who is described to feel the emotion?'  (esperjent), 'x'jikkawża din l-emozzjoni?' (stimolu), u lejn liema entità hija diretta?” (mira). Għalkemm intwera li mudell konġunt ta’ stimolu u tbassir tal-kategorija tal-emozzjonijiet huwa ta’ benefiċċju għa ż-żewġ sottomistoqsijiet, għadu mhux ċar liema minn dawn ir-rwoli semantiċi jippermetti li klassifikatur jikkonkludi l-emozzjoni. Is it the experiencer, because the identity of a person is biased towards a particular emotion (X is always happy)?  Hija mira partikolari (kulħadd iħabba x) jew stimolu (li tagħmel X jagħmel lil kulħadd tristi)? Aħna nwieġbu dawn il-mistoqsijiet billi nħarrġu mudelli ta’ klassifikazzjoni tal-emozzjonijiet fuq ħames settijiet ta’ dejta disponibbli annotati b’mill-inqas rwol semantiku wieħed billi nħassu l-mili ta’ dawn ir-rwoli fit-test b’mod ikkontrollat u ssibu li madwar korporazzjonijiet multipli, stimuli u miri jġorru informazzjoni emozzjonali, filwaqt li l-esperjenzatur jista’ jitqies bħala konfużur. Barra minn hekk, nagħmlu analiżi dwar jekk l-infurmar tal-mudell dwar il-pożizzjoni tar-rwol itejjeb id-deċiżjoni tal-klassifikazzjoni. Particularly on literature corpora we find that the role information improves the emotion classification.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Хүмүүсийн мэдрэмжийг илүү ихэвчлэн текст хэлбэрээр тодорхойлогдож байгаа юм. Өмнө тодорхойлогдсон бүтээгдэхүүнээс сэтгэл хөдлөлд зориулагдсан сэтгэл хөдлөлд (жишээ нь, айдас, баяр баясал, уур, аймшигтай, гунигтай, гайха Хамгийн сүүлийн үед хэн сэтгэл хөдлөлийг мэдрэхдээ тайлбарласан бөгөөд хэн сэтгэл хөдлөлийг мэдрэх вэ гэдгийг хариулах боломжтой болсон юм. "Энэ сэтгэл хөдлөлийг ямар шалтгаалж байна вэ?" (сэтгэл хөдлөл) (зорилго) Хэдийгээр энэхүү сэтгэл хөдлөл болон сэтгэл хөдлөлийн хэлбэрийг нийлүүлэх нь хоёр дотор хоёуланг нь ашигтай гэдгийг харуулсан ч гэсэн эдгээр семантийн хэлбэрүүдийн хэн нь сэтгэл хөдлөлийг бууруулах боломжтой байдаг. Хүн төрөлхтний мэдрэмж тодорхой сэтгэл хөдлөл рүү зайлсхийгддэг учраас тэр хүн төрөлхтний мэдрэмж (X үргэлж аз жаргалтай байдаг)? Энэ бол тодорхой зорилго уу (хүн бүр X-г дуртай) эсвэл урам зорилго уу (X-г бүгдийг гунигтай болгодог)? Бид эдгээр асуултуудад сэтгэл хөдлөлийн хэвлэлийн загварыг дасгал хангалттай таван өгөгдлийн хэлбэрээр хамгийн бага нэг семантик хэлбэрээр дүүрэгчийг удирдлагатай аргаар дүүргэдэг бөгөөд олон корпора, сэтгэл хөдлөл, зорилго сэтгэл хөдлөлийн мэдээллийг авч, тур Дараа нь бид загварыг хэлэхэд дүрслэлийн байр суурь талаар мэдээллийг шинжилгээ хийх хэрэгтэй. Ялангуяа уран зохиолын корпоратын талаар бид мэдээллийн үүрэг сэтгэл хөдлөлийн хуваалтыг сайжруулдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Førehandsvisinga er hovudsakelig formert som tekstklassifikasjon der teksteiningar vert tildelt til e in følelse frå eit føredefinert inventor (f.eks. frykt, glede, grid, frykt, triste, surprise, tillit, forventing). Nyleg er det utvikla tilnærmingane for semantisk rolletiketting for å pakka ut strukturer frå teksten for å svara på spørsmåla som: "Kva er beskriven for å føle følelsen?" (oppleverande), kva fører denne følelsen? (stimulus), og på kva eining er det direktert? (mål). Selv om det er vist at forhåndsvising av stimulus og emosjonskategori er nyttig for begge underspørsmål, er det ikkje klart kva av desse semantiske rollene kan ein klassifiserer å infere emosjonen. Er det oppleverande, fordi identiteten til ein person er forvirra mot ein spesielt følelse (X er alltid lykkeleg)? Er det ein bestemt mål (alle elskar X) eller ein stimulus (gjer X alle trist)? Vi svarar på desse spørsmålene ved å opplære emosjonsklassifikasjonsmodular på fem tilgjengelege datasett merkt med minst éin semantisk rolle ved å maskera fylleren av desse rollene i teksten på ein kontrollt måte og finna at over fleire korporar, stimuler og mål bær emosjonsinformasjon, mens oppleverande kan vera kalla som ein konfounder. I tillegg analyserer vi dersom du informerer modellen om posisjonen på rolen forbetrar klassifikasjonsslutninga. Dette finn vi spesielt på literaturkorpora at rolinformasjonen forbedrar emosjonsklassifikasjonen.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Priznavanje emocija je uglavnom formulisano kao klasifikacija teksta u kojoj su tekstualne jedinice dodeljene emociji iz predodređenog inventara (npr. strah, radost, besa, odvratnost, tuga, iznenađenje, povjerenje, očekivanje). Nedavno su razvili pristupe označavanja semantičke uloge kako bi izvukli strukture iz teksta da bi odgovorili na pitanja poput: "Ko je opisan da oseti emocije?" Šta uzrokuje ovu emociju? (stimulus), i u kojoj je entiteti upućen?" (Meta). Iako je pokazalo da je zajedničko modeliranje stimulus a i predviđanje kategorije emocija korisno za obe poduzeće, ostaje nepoznato koje od tih semantičkih uloga omogućava klasifikatoru da inficira emocije. Da li je to iskustvo, jer je identitet osobe predrasudan prema posebnoj emociji (X je uvek sretan)? Da li je to posebna meta (svi vole X) ili stimulus (radi X čini sve tužnim)? Odgovaramo na ta pitanja, obučavajući modele klasifikacije emocija na pet dostupnih podataka koji su najmanje jednu semantičku ulogu, maskirajući ispunjavatelje tih uloga u tekstu na kontrolnom naèinu i saznajući da preko višestruke tela, stimuliranja i cilja nose emocionalne informacije, dok se iskustvo može smatrati konfliktatom. Nadalje, analiziramo ako obavijestimo model o poziciji uloge poboljšava odluku o klasifikaciji. Posebno u književnoj korporaciji nalazimo da informacije o ulozi poboljšavaju klasifikaciju emocija.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_pl>Rozpoznawanie emocji jest sformułowane głównie jako klasyfikacja tekstowa, w której jednostki tekstowe są przypisywane do emocji z wcześniej zdefiniowanej inwentaryzacji (np. strach, radość, gniew, obrzydzenie, smutek, zaskoczenie, zaufanie, oczekiwanie). Ostatnio opracowano semantyczne metody oznaczania roli, aby wyodrębnić struktury z tekstu, aby odpowiedzieć na pytania takie jak: "kto jest opisany, aby odczuwać emocje?". "Co powoduje tę emocję?" (bodźce) i do jakiego podmiotu jest on skierowany?" (cel). Chociaż wykazano, że wspólne modelowanie bodźców i przewidywania kategorii emocji jest korzystne dla obu podzadań, pozostaje niejasne, która z tych semantycznych ról pozwala klasyfikować emocję. Czy to doświadczający, ponieważ tożsamość osoby jest stronnicza wobec konkretnej emocji (X zawsze jest szczęśliwy)? Czy jest to konkretny cel (wszyscy kochają X) czy bodziec (robienie X sprawia, że wszyscy są smutni)? Odpowiadamy na te pytania, trenując modele klasyfikacji emocji na pięciu dostępnych zbiorach danych adnotacyjnych o co najmniej jedną rolę semantyczną poprzez kontrolowane maskowanie wypełniaczy tych ról w tekście i stwierdzamy, że w wielu korpusach bodźce i cele przenoszą informacje o emocjach, podczas gdy doświadczający może być uznany za zakłócający. Ponadto analizujemy, czy informowanie modelu o pozycji roli poprawia decyzję klasyfikacyjną. Szczególnie na korpusach literatury odkrywamy, że informacje o rolach poprawiają klasyfikację emocji.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Recunoașterea emoțională este formulată în principal ca clasificare text în care unitățile textuale sunt atribuite unei emoții dintr-un inventar predefinit (de exemplu, frică, bucurie, furie, dezgust, tristețe, surpriză, încredere, anticipare). Mai recent, abordările semantice de etichetare a rolurilor au fost dezvoltate pentru a extrage structuri din text pentru a răspunde la întrebări precum: "Cine este descris să simtă emoția?" "Ce cauzează această emoţie?" (stimulare), și către ce entitate este direcționată?" (țintă). Deși s-a arătat că modelarea simultană a stimulului și predicția categoriilor emoționale este benefică pentru ambele subactivități, rămâne neclar care dintre aceste roluri semantice permite unui clasificator să deducă emoția. Este experimentatorul, deoarece identitatea unei persoane este părtinitoare față de o anumită emoție (X este întotdeauna fericit)? Este o anumită țintă (toată lumea iubește X) sau un stimulent (făcând X îi întristează pe toți)? Răspundem la aceste întrebări prin instruirea modelelor de clasificare a emoțiilor pe cinci seturi de date disponibile adnotate cu cel puțin un rol semantic prin mascarea materialelor de umplere ale acestor roluri în text într-o manieră controlată și descoperim că pe mai multe corpuri, stimuli și ținte poartă informații emoționale, în timp ce experiența poate fi considerată un confundator. Mai mult, analizăm dacă informarea modelului despre poziția rolului îmbunătățește decizia de clasificare. Mai ales pe literatură corpora constatăm că informația rolului îmbunătățește clasificarea emoțiilor.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sv>Känslighetsigenkänning formuleras huvudsakligen som textklassificering där textenheter tilldelas en känsla från en fördefinierad inventering (t.ex. rädsla, glädje, ilska, avsky, sorg, överraskning, tillit, förväntan). På senare tid har semantiska rollmärkningsmetoder utvecklats för att extrahera strukturer ur texten för att besvara frågor som: "Vem beskrivs för att känna känslan?" "Vad orsakar denna känsla?" (stimulans), och vilken enhet riktas den?" (mål). Även om det har visat sig att gemensamt modellering av stimuli och känslokategoriprediktion är fördelaktigt för båda underaktiviteterna, är det fortfarande oklart vilken av dessa semantiska roller som gör det möjligt för en klassificerare att härleda känslorna. Är det upplevaren, eftersom en persons identitet är partisk mot en viss känsla (X är alltid lycklig)? Är det ett visst mål (alla älskar X) eller en stimulans (att göra X gör alla ledsna)? Vi besvarar dessa frågor genom att träna känsloklassificeringsmodeller på fem tillgängliga datauppsättningar kommenterade med minst en semantisk roll genom att maskera fyllarna av dessa roller i texten på ett kontrollerat sätt och upptäcka att över flera korpora bär stimuli och mål känsloinformation, medan erfarenheten kan betraktas som en förvirrande. Vidare analyserar vi om information till modellen om rollens position förbättrar klassificeringsbeslutet. Särskilt på litteraturcorpora finner vi att rollinformationen förbättrar känsloklassificeringen.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>Emotion අඳුරණය ප්‍රධානයෙන් පැත්තක් විශේෂණයෙන් පෙළුවන් විශේෂණයෙන් පෙළුවන් විශේෂණයෙන් පෙළුවන් විශේෂණයෙන් පෙළුවන් හැඟීමක් වලි ඊට පස්සේ, සෙමැන්ටික් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ලේබිල් එක්ක ප්‍රශ්නයක් පිළිබඳින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් පිළිබඳ කරන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක්  (අභියාසකයා), 'මේ හැඟීම මොකක්ද වෙන්නේ? (ස්තුතියි), ඒ වගේම ඒක කොච්චර අයිතියක් තියෙන්නේ? (ලක්ෂණය). හැබැයි ඒක පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන් වුණා කියලා සාමාන්‍ය විද්‍යාව සහ හ හැඟීම් වර්ගය ප්‍රශ්නයක් දෙන්නම් ප්‍රයෝජනයක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රයෝජන ඒක අභියෝගකයෙක්, මොකද මිනිස්සුගේ අඳුරණය විශේෂ භාවිතාවක් වෙනුවෙන් පිළිබඳින්නේ (X හැම මේක විශේෂ ඉලක්කයක්ද (හැමෝම X කැමතියි) නැත්තම් ප්‍රශ්නයක්ද (X කරනවා හැමෝම දුක්කු වෙන්න අපි මේ ප්‍රශ්නවට උත්තර දෙන්න පුළුවන් දත්ත සෙට් පහක් වලින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වලින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වලින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරන්න පුළුවන් දත්ත සැකසුම තවත්, අපි විශ්ලේෂණය කරනවා විශ්ලේෂණය විශ්ලේෂණය කරන්නේ නිර්මාණය සඳහා ප්‍රතිකාරයේ තීරණය වැඩ කරන් විශේෂයෙන්ම සාක්ෂික කොර්පෝරා ගැන අපිට හොයාගන්න පුළුවන් කියලා ලොකු තොරතුරු හොයාගන්න</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>احساسات شناسایی اکثر متن کلاسی کے طور پر فرمول کی جاتی ہے جس میں متن یونیٹوں کو پہلے مقرر کیا گیا ہے (مثل: خوف, خوشی, غصہ, غصہ، غصہ، تعجب، اعتماد، انتظار) سے ایک احساسات کے لئے مقرر کیا جاتا ہے۔ اچھے سے، سیمنٹی رول لیبلینگ کی طریقے ٹیکسٹ سے ساختاروں کو نکالنے کے لئے توسعہ کیا گیا ہے جیسے سوال جواب دینے کے لئے: (تجربہ) یہ احساس کیا وجہ دیتا ہے؟ اور یہ کس چیز کی طرف ہدایت کی گئی ہے؟ (target) اگرچہ اس کو دکھایا گیا ہے کہ ان دونوں سٹسٹسٹ کے لئے مفید ہے جو ان سٹسٹیٹی رول میں سے کس کا کلیسی کرنے والا احساسات کے ذریعہ سے کمزور کر سکتا ہے۔ کیا یہ تجربہ ہے، کیونکہ ایک شخص کی شناخت ایک مخصوص احساس کی طرف متوجہ ہوتی ہے (X ہمیشہ خوش ہے)؟ کیا یہ ایک مخصوص موقع ہے (سب X کو محبت رکھتے ہیں) یا ایک تحقیق ہے (X کرنا سب کو غمگین کرتا ہے)؟ ہم ان سوالوں کی تعلیم کے ذریعہ پانچ موجود ڈیٹ سٹ پر احساسات کلاسیفوں کی مدل کی تعلیم کے ذریعہ ان سوالوں کو جواب دیتے ہیں جو ان رولیوں کو متن میں کنٹرول طریقے سے ماسک کر دیتے ہیں اور یہ دیکھتے ہیں کہ بہت سی کورپور، انگیز اور موجودات میں احساسات معلومات لے رہے ہیں، حالانکہ تجربے کو بہت سا اور اس کے بعد، ہم تحقیق کرتے ہیں اگر موڈل کو رول کے موقعیت کے بارے میں خبردار کریں تو کلاسیفوں کا فیصلہ بہتر کرے گا۔ مخصوصاً ادبیات کورپور پر ہم دیکھتے ہیں کہ رول معلومات احساسات کلاسیفوں کو بہتر کر دیتی ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_so>Aqoonsashada xasaradda waxaa ugu horeeyaa qoraal ahaan loo qoray qoraal, kaas oo kooxaha qoraalka ah loo qeybiyaa emoon ka soo horeeyey qoraalka hore (tusaale ahaan cabsi, farxad, cadho, cadowgooda, murugta, yaabka, rajada, rajaynaya, rajaynaya). Muddo ugu dhowaad waxaa loo hormariyey qaabab la soo qorayo in laga soo bixiyo dhismaha qoraalka si ay ugu jawaabaan su'aalo sida: "Yaa loo soo qoray in la moodo fikrada?" (taqaan), maxay sababtaa fikradan? Jidkeedana lagu hanuuniyay. (goal). In kastoo la muujiyey in qaababka iskaashatada ah la sameynayo wax u faa’iido ah oo la sii sheegayo tababarka iskuullada iyo iskuulka hissiga, waxana la sii ogaanayaa, qaybtaas semantikaan ayaa ku habboon kara mid ka mid ah inuu kalsooneeyo fikrada. Ma aqoonta qof, sababtoo ah aqoonsiga qof uu u geystaa fikrad gaar ah (X mar walba waa farxad?) Ma waxyaabo gaar ah (qof waluba wuxuu jecel yahay X) ama qallooc leh (sameynta X qof kastaba wuu ka calool xumayaa?) Waxaannu ugu jawaabnaa su'aalahan ku tababarida masaallo fasaxa emotion oo ku qoran shanta databased oo la heli karo oo ugu yaraan hal qayb ah, si qaab la ilaaliyo, waxaynu ka ogaanaynaa in kooporada kala duduwan, dhaqaalaha iyo waxyaabaha la jeedo ay macluumaad la xiriiraan emoodka, iyadoo arimaha la aqoonsan looga tirin karo mid isku mid ah. Furan, waxaynu baaritaannaa in tusaale ahaan loo sheego meeshii ay leedahay inuu horumariyo go’aanka fasalka. Si gaar ah shirkadaha farshaxanku waxaan ka helaynaa in macluumaadka qaybta lagu jiro uu kordhiyo fasaxa fikrada.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>உணர்வு அறிவிப்பு முக்கியமாக உரை வகைப்பாடாக உரை உருவாக்கப்பட்டது, அதில் மென்பொருள் அலகுகள் ஒரு முன்னிருப்பு கண்டுபிடிப்பிலிருந்து ஒரு உணர்வுக்கு ஒப்பிடு சமீபத்தில் இருந்து உரையிலிருந்து அமைப்புகளை வெளியேற்றுவதற்கு அரைப்புரிய விளையாட்டு செயல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது போன்ற கேள்வ (அனுபவமானவர்), "இந்த உணர்வு என்ன காரணம்?" எந்த பொருளுக்கு நேர்வழி காட்டப்பட்டது? (இலக்கு) ஒருங்கிணைக்கப்பட்டிருந்தாலும் உணர்வு வகுப்பு முறைமையான முறைமையாக்குதல் இருவரும் துணை பணிகளுக்கு நன்மையானது என்பதை காண்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, இந் ஒரு மனிதனின் அடையாளத்தை ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட உணர்வுக்கு எதிராக புரிந்து கொள்கிறது ஏனெனில் இது அனுபவம் இருக்கிறதா? இது ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட இலக்கு உள்ளதா (எல்லாரும் X விரும்புகிறார்கள்) அல்லது ஒரு ஆர்வம் (X செய்து அனைவருக்கும் த நாம் இந்த கேள்விகளுக்கு பதில் அளிக்கிறோம் உணர்வு வகைப்பாட்டு மாதிரிகளை ஐந்து கிடைக்கக்கூடிய தகவல் அமைப்புகளில் பயிற்சி செய்து, குறைந்தது ஒரு பாமான்டிக் பங்கு கூடிய ஒரு பங் மேலும், வகுப்பு தீர்ப்பு முறைமையை பற்றி மாதிரியை அறிவித்தால் நாம் ஆராய்ச்சி செய்கிறோம். குறிப்பாக எழுத்துரு நிறுவனத்தில் நாம் கண்டுபிடிக்கிறோம் விளையாட்டு தகவல் உணர்வு வகைப்பை மேம்படுத்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_kk>Көңіл көңіл түсініктемесі әдетте мәтін классификациясы ретінде, мәтін бірліктері алдында анықталған инвентариялық емоцияларға беріледі (мысалы, қорқыныш, қуаныш, қаттық, қауіпсіздік, қауіпсіздік, сені Соңғы уақытта, мәтіннен құрылымдарды тарқату үшін "емоциялық сезімін кім сипатталған?" деген сұрақтардың жауабына жауап беру үшін семантикалық рольді жарлықтау жағдайлары жа (тәжірибе), 'Бұл емоцияларды не себеп береді?' (стимул) Ол қай жағдайда бар? (мақсат). Бұл стимул мен эмоциялық санаттарды біріктіру үшін біріктіру үшін екі ішкі сұрақтар үшін пайдалы болады дегенді көрсетілді, бірақ бұл семантикалық рольдердің қайсының эмоциялық күйін түсіруге мүмкіндік беретін Бұл тәжірибесі бар ма, себебі адамның идентификациясы өзгертілген емоцияларға (X әрқашан бақытты)? Бұл нақты мақсат (барлығы X- ді сақтайды) немесе стимул (X- ді жасау әрбірін қауіпке салады) ма? Біз осы сұрақтарды бес қол жеткізетін деректер қорларындағы эмоциялық классификациялық үлгілеріне жауап береміз, кемінде бір семантикалық роль мәтіндегі рольдарды бақылау тәртібімен қалқалап, бірнеше корпора, стимулиялық және мақсаттарында эмоциял Келесіден бұл үлгі рөлінің орналасуын туралы туралы мәліметті жаңарту үшін анализ етеді. Біз әдебиеттік корпорасындағы мәліметтердің емоциялық секретін жақсартатын деп ойлаймыз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_uz>Hujjatni tasdiqlash asosida matn classifikasi deb hisoblanadi. Bu yerda matn birikmalarni oldingi muvaffaqiyatlarni hisoblash mumkin (masalan, қўрқиш, хавфсирлик, ғамгин, хавфсирлик, суҳбат, ишонч, kutilgan edi). Yaqinda, semantik role lab chiqarish qoidalari matnning tuzilishiga murakkablarini chiqarish uchun "hissiyotni hisoblash mumkin" deb javob beradi. bu hissiyotni nima sababi? (stimulus), and at which entity is it directed?'  (maydon). Agar ko'rsatish mumkin, birlashtirilgan stimulus va hissiyotning turini taqdim qilish ikkita vazifalar uchun foydalanuvchi bo'ladi, bu semantik qobiliyatlaridan foydalanishi mumkin. Bu tajriba, chunki bir odamning shaxsiyati bir hisobga qaragan (X har doim baxtli?) Bu foydalanuvchi (hamma X ni yaxshi) yoki hamma odamlarni bajarish mumkin? Biz bu savollarni boshqarish usuli bilan 5 mavjud maʼlumot tarkibini o'rganish modellariga javob beramiz. Bu amallarni matnning boshqarish usulida qo'llab qo'yish mumkin va ko'pchilik kompaniya, stimullik va goallar bilan hissiyot maʼlumotini olib tashlash mumkin. Koʻrsatganda, biz modelni boshqa holatning joyini haqida hamma narsalar haqida o'ylaymiz. Muammo o o'lim kompaniya haqida biz o'ylaymiz, ma'lumotning xulosi hissiyotning darajasini o'zgartiradi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Nhận dạng cảm xúc được phát âm chủ yếu như là phân tích văn bản nơi các đơn vị văn bản được g án cho cảm xúc từ một bản kiểm kê đã xác định (ví dụ, sợ hãi, vui mừng, tức giận, ghê tởm, buồn bã, ngạc nhiên, tin tưởng, tiên đoán). Gần đây, các phương pháp phân biệt chữ nghĩa vụ đã được phát triển để trích các cấu trúc trong văn bản để trả lời câu hỏi như: "Ai được mô tả để cảm nhận cảm xúc?" "Điều gì gây ra cảm xúc này?" (chất kích thích) và thực thể nào bị điều khiển? (mục tiêu) Mặc dù đã được cho thấy rằng dự đoán kiểu mẫu chung của kích thích và các loại cảm xúc sẽ có lợi cho cả hai mặt phụ đề, nhưng vẫn chưa rõ vai trò nào theo ngữ nghĩa thì cho phép người phân loại nhận ra cảm xúc. Có phải đó là kinh nghiệm, bởi vì danh tính của một người có khuynh hướng với một cảm xúc đặc biệt (X luôn hạnh phúc? Nó có phải là mục tiêu cụ thể (ai cũng yêu X) hay là kích thích (làm X làm mọi người buồn không? Chúng tôi trả lời các câu hỏi bằng cách huấn luyện các mô hình cảm xúc trên năm bộ dữ liệu sẵn sàng ghi chú với ít nhất một vai ngữ pháp bằng cách che giấu những người lấp các vai trò này trong văn bản theo cách kiểm soát và thấy rằng trên nhiều cơ thể, kích thích và mục tiêu mang thông tin về cảm xúc, trong khi người kinh nghiệm có thể được xem là một người lộn xộn. Chúng tôi cũng phân tích nếu thông báo cho mô hình về vị trí của vai trò cải thiện quyết định phân loại. Đặc biệt trong văn học Hạ sĩ, chúng tôi thấy vai trò của thông tin cải thiện phân loại cảm xúc.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Емоционалното разпознаване се формулира предимно като текстова класификация, при която текстови единици са причислени към емоция от предварително определен опис (напр. страх, радост, гняв, отвращение, тъга, изненада, доверие, очакване). Наскоро бяха разработени семантични подходи за етикетиране на роли, за да извлечем структури от текста, за да отговорим на въпроси като: "Кой е описан, за да усети емоцията?" "Какво причинява тази емоция?" (стимул), и към коя същност е насочена?" (цел). Въпреки че е доказано, че съвместното моделиране на стимули и предсказване на емоционалната категория е полезно и за двете подзадачи, остава неясно коя от тези семантични роли позволява на класификатора да заключи емоцията. Дали е експериментаторът, защото идентичността на човек е предубедена към определена емоция (Х винаги е щастлив)? Дали е определена цел (всеки обича Х) или стимул (правенето на Х прави всички тъжни)? Отговаряме на тези въпроси, като тренираме модели за класификация на емоциите върху пет налични набора от данни, анотирани с поне една семантична роля, като маскираме пълнителите на тези роли в текста по контролиран начин и откриваме, че в множество корпуси стимулите и мишените носят емоционална информация, докато експериментаторът може да се счита за объркващ. Освен това анализираме дали информирането на модела за позицията на ролята подобрява решението за класификация. Особено в литературните корпуси откриваме, че ролевата информация подобрява класификацията на емоциите.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Følelsesgenkendelse er overvejende formuleret som tekstklassifikation, hvor tekstenheder tildeles en følelse fra en foruddefineret opgørelse (fx frygt, glæde, vrede, afsky, sorg, overraskelse, tillid, forventning). For nylig er semantisk rollemærkning blevet udviklet tilgange til at udtrække strukturer fra teksten for at besvare spørgsmål som: "Hvem er beskrevet til at føle følelserne?" "Hvad forårsager denne følelse?" (stimulering), og hvilken enhed er den rettet mod?" (mål). Selvom det er blevet vist, at modellering af stimuli og følelseskategoriforudsigelse i fællesskab er gavnlig for begge underopgaver, er det stadig uklart, hvilken af disse semantiske roller der gør det muligt for en klassificering at udlede følelsen. Er det oplevelsespersonen, fordi identiteten af en person er partisk over for en bestemt følelse (X er altid glad)? Er det et bestemt mål (alle elsker X) eller en stimulans (at gøre X gør alle kede af det)? Vi besvarer disse spørgsmål ved at træne følelsesklassificeringsmodeller på fem tilgængelige datasæt kommenteret med mindst én semantisk rolle ved at maskere fyldstofferne til disse roller i teksten på en kontrolleret måde og finde ud af, at på tværs af flere corpora, stimuli og mål bærer følelsesinformation, mens erfaringsmanden kan betragtes som en forvirrende. Desuden analyserer vi, om oplysning af modellen om rollens position forbedrer klassificeringsbeslutningen. Især på litteraturcorpora finder vi, at rolleinformationen forbedrer følelsesklassificeringen.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Priznavanje emocija je uglavnom formulirano kao klasifikacija teksta u kojoj su tekstualne jedinice dodijeljene emocijama iz predodređenog inventara (npr. strah, radost, bijes, odvratnost, tuga, iznenađenje, povjerenje, očekivanje). Nedavno se razvijaju pristupi označavanju semantičke uloge kako bi izvukli strukture iz teksta kako bi odgovorili na pitanja poput: "tko je opisano osjećati emocije?" Što uzrokuje ovu emociju? (stimulus), i u kojoj je entiteti upućen?" (cilj). Iako je pokazalo da je zajedničko modeliranje stimula i predviđanje kategorije emocija korisno za obje podstaze, ostaje jasno koji od tih semantičkih uloga omogućava klasifikatoru inficirati emocije. Je li to iskustvo, jer je identitet osobe predrasudan prema posebnoj emociji (X je uvijek sretan)? Je li to određena meta (svi vole X) ili stimulus (radi X čini sve tužnim)? Odgovaramo na te pitanja, vježbamo modele klasifikacije emocija na pet dostupnih podataka koji su najmanje jednu semantičku ulogu, maskirajući ispunjavatelje tih uloga u tekstu kontroliranim načinom i pronaći da u višestrukoj tijelu, stimuliranju i ciljevima nose emocionalne informacije, dok bi iskustvo moglo biti smatrano zbunjenim. Nadalje, analiziramo ako obavijestimo model o poziciji uloge poboljšava odluku o klasifikaciji. Posebno u književnoj korporaciji nalazimo da informacije o ulozi poboljšavaju klasifikaciju emocija.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Emotieherkenning wordt voornamelijk geformuleerd als tekstclassificatie waarbij teksteenheden worden toegewezen aan een emotie uit een vooraf gedefinieerde inventaris (bijvoorbeeld angst, vreugde, woede, walging, verdriet, verrassing, vertrouwen, anticipatie). Meer recent zijn semantische rollabeling benaderingen ontwikkeld om structuren uit de tekst te halen om vragen te beantwoorden als: 'wie wordt beschreven om de emotie te voelen?' 'Wat veroorzaakt deze emotie?' (stimulus), en op welke entiteit is het gericht?' (doelwit). Hoewel is aangetoond dat het gezamenlijk modelleren van stimulus en emotiecategorie voorspelling gunstig is voor beide subtaken, blijft het onduidelijk welke van deze semantische rollen een classificator in staat stelt om de emotie te concluderen. Is het de ervaringer, omdat de identiteit van een persoon bevooroordeeld is naar een bepaalde emotie (X is altijd gelukkig)? Is het een bepaald doel (iedereen houdt van X) of een stimulus (X doen maakt iedereen verdrietig)? We beantwoorden deze vragen door emotieclassificatiemodellen te trainen op vijf beschikbare datasets die met minstens één semantische rol geannoteerd zijn door de vullers van deze rollen in de tekst op een gecontroleerde manier te maskeren en te ontdekken dat stimuli en doelen over meerdere corpora heen emotionele informatie bevatten, terwijl de ervaringer beschouwd kan worden als een confounder. Verder analyseren we of het informeren van het model over de positie van de rol de classificatiebeslissing verbetert. Vooral op literatuurcorpora blijkt dat de rolinformatie de emotieclassificatie verbetert.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Emotionserkennung wird vorwiegend als Textklassifikation formuliert, bei der einer Emotion aus einem vordefinierten Inventar (z.B. Angst, Freude, Wut, Ekel, Traurigkeit, Überraschung, Vertrauen, Vorfreude) Texteinheiten zugeordnet werden. In jüngster Zeit wurden semantische Rollenbeschriftungsansätze entwickelt, um Strukturen aus dem Text zu extrahieren, um Fragen wie: "Wer wird beschrieben, um die Emotion zu fühlen?" zu beantworten. (Erfahrener), 'Was verursacht diese Emotion?' (Stimulus) und an welche Entität richtet er sich?" (Ziel). Obwohl gezeigt wurde, dass die gemeinsame Modellierung von Stimulus und Emotionskategorien für beide Teilaufgaben vorteilhaft ist, bleibt unklar, welche dieser semantischen Rollen es einem Klassifikator ermöglicht, die Emotion zu schließen. Ist es der Erfahrende, weil die Identität einer Person gegenüber einer bestimmten Emotion voreingenommen ist (X ist immer glücklich)? Ist es ein bestimmtes Ziel (jeder liebt X) oder ein Reiz (X zu tun macht alle traurig)? Wir beantworten diese Fragen, indem wir Emotionsklassifikationsmodelle auf fünf verfügbaren Datensätzen trainieren, die mindestens eine semantische Rolle annotiert haben, indem wir die Füller dieser Rollen im Text kontrolliert maskieren und feststellen, dass Stimuli und Ziele über mehrere Korpora hinweg Emotionsinformationen tragen, während der Erfahrende als Konfounder betrachtet werden könnte. Weiterhin analysieren wir, ob die Information des Modells über die Position der Rolle die Klassifizierungsentscheidung verbessert. Insbesondere auf Literaturkorpora finden wir, dass die Rolleninformationen die Emotionsklassifizierung verbessern.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>شناسایی احساسات بیشتر به عنوان تنظیم متن فرموده می‌شود که واحدهای متن در آن برای احساساتی از یک اختراع پیش‌فرض قرار داده می‌شوند (مثلاً ترس، شادی، خشم، ناخوشایند، غمگین، سورپرایز، اعتماد، پیش‌بینی). اخیراً برای اخراج ساختاری از متن برای پاسخ از سوالات مثل: چه کسی برای احساس احساسات توصیف شده است؟ (تجربه کننده), 'چه باعث این احساسات است؟' و به کدام شرکت هدایت شده؟ (هدف). اگرچه نشان داده شده که پیش‌بینی از انگیزه‌ها و فرقه‌های احساسات با هم مدل‌سازی برای هر دو فرقه‌ای منافع است، آن هنوز معلوم نیست که کدامین از این نقش‌های semantic به یک فرقه‌ای اجازه می‌دهد که احساسات را آلوده کند. آیا این تجربه کننده است، زیرا هویت یک شخص به یک احساس خاصی مخالف است (X همیشه خوشحال است)؟ آیا هدف خاصی است (همه عاشق X) یا تحریک (کار X همه را ناراحت می‌کند)؟ ما این سوالات را با آموزش مدل‌های مختلف احساسات در پنج مجموعه داده‌های موجود پاسخ می‌دهیم که با حداقل یک نقش semantic با مشخص کردن پر‌کنندگان این نقش‌ها در متن به طریق کنترل و پیدا می‌کنیم که در طول چندین شرکت، تحریک و هدف اطلاعات احساسات را حمل می‌کنند، در حالی که تجربه‌کنند بعلاوه، ما تحلیل می‌کنیم که آیا مدل را درباره موقعیت نقشه‌ای اطلاع می‌دهیم تصمیم‌گیری را بهتر می‌کند. مخصوصاً در مورد شرکت ادبیات ما پیدا می کنیم که اطلاعات نقش نقش محرمانه احساسات را بهتر می کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Pengenalan emosi terutama terbentuk sebagai klasifikasi teks di mana unit teks ditugaskan untuk emosi dari inventaris terdefinisi (contohnya, ketakutan, kegembiraan, kemarahan, rasa sedih, kejutan, kepercayaan, antisipasi). Baru-baru ini, pendekatan label peran semantis telah dikembangkan untuk mengekstrak struktur dari teks untuk menjawab pertanyaan seperti: 'siapa yang disebut untuk merasakan emosi?' (pengalaman), "Apa yang menyebabkan emosi ini?" (stimulus), and at which entity is it directed?'  (target). Though it has been shown that jointly modeling stimulus and emotion category prediction is beneficial for both subtasks, it remains unclear which of these semantic roles enables a classifier to infer the emotion.  Apakah itu pengalaman, karena identitas seseorang biased terhadap emosi tertentu (X selalu bahagia)? Apakah itu target tertentu (semua orang mencintai X) atau stimulus (melakukan X membuat semua orang sedih)? Kami menjawab pertanyaan-pertanyaan ini dengan melatih model klasifikasi emosi pada lima set data yang tersedia annotasi dengan setidaknya satu peran semantis dengan menyembunyikan penutup peran-peran ini dalam teks dengan cara terkendali dan menemukan bahwa di seluruh banyak korpora, stimuli dan target membawa informasi emosi, sementara pengalaman mungkin dianggap mengacaukan. Selain itu, kita menganalisis jika memberitahu model tentang posisi perannya memperbaiki keputusan klasifikasi. Particularly on literature corpora we find that the role information improves the emotion classification.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>정서 식별은 주로 텍스트 분류로 표현되고 그 중에서 텍스트 단위는 미리 정의된 목록에 있는 정서(예를 들어 두려움, 기쁨, 분노, 혐오, 슬픔, 놀라움, 신뢰, 기대)에 분배된다.최근에 의미 역할 표기 방법이 개발되어 텍스트에서 구조를 추출하여 이런 질문에 대답하는 데 사용되었다.'누가 감정을 느끼는 것으로 묘사되었는가?'(체험자), "무엇이 이런 감정을 야기합니까?"(자극) 어떤 실체를 겨냥하는가?(목표).비록 자극과 정서 유형 예측에 대한 연합 모델링이 이 두 가지 임무에 모두 유익하다는 것이 증명되었지만, 이러한 의미 역할 중 어느 것이 분류기로 하여금 정서를 추측하게 할 수 있는지는 아직 분명하지 않다.체험자인가, 한 사람의 신분이 특정한 감정에 치우치기 때문에(X는 항상 즐겁다)?그것은 특정한 목표(모든 사람이 X를 사랑한다)입니까 아니면 자극(X를 하면 모든 사람이 슬퍼한다)입니까?우리는 다섯 개의 사용 가능한 데이터 집합에서 정서 분류 모델을 훈련시켜 이런 질문에 대답한다. 이런 데이터 집합은 최소한 하나의 의미 역할을 표시하고 통제된 방식으로 텍스트에 있는 이러한 역할의 충전자를 덮어준다. 우리는 여러 개의 자료 라이브러리에서 정서 정보를 자극하고 소지하는 것을 발견했다. 체험자는 혼합 요소로 여겨질 수 있다.그 밖에 역할의 위치를 모델에 알리는 것이 분류 결정을 개선할 수 있는지도 분석했다.특히 문헌 자료 라이브러리에서 우리는 역할 정보가 정서 분류를 개선한 것을 발견했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Kutambuliwa kwa hisia zinatengenezwa kwa mara nyingi kama kutangazwa kwa maandishi ambapo vitengo vya viungo vya maandishi viliwekwa hisia kutoka kwenye orodha ya awali (kama vile hofu, furaha, hasira, kuchukiwa, huzuni, kushangaza, imani, matumaini). More recently, semantic role labeling approaches have been developed to extract structures from the text to answer questions like: 'who is described to feel the emotion?'  (mwenye uzoefu), “ni nini kinasababisha hisia hii?” Ni nani aliye ongozwa kwa njia gani? (lengo). Ingawa imeonyeshwa kuwa utabiri wa pamoja wa utabiri wa hisia unafaa kwa kazi hizo mbili, bado haujajulikana ni nani kati ya jukumu hili la kigaidi linawezesha kutambua hisia hizo. Is it the experiencer, because the identity of a person is biased towards a particular emotion (X is always happy)?  Je, ni lengo maalumu (kila mmoja anapenda X) au msisimko (kufanya X huwafanya kila mtu masikitiko?) Tunawajibu maswali haya kwa kufundisha mifano ya usambazaji wa hisia katika seti tano zilizopatikana zinazoelezwa na angalau jukumu la kimapenzi moja kwa kuwavaa filamu za kazi hizi kwa njia ya kudhibitiwa na kutambua kuwa katika makampuni mbalimbali, msimulizi na malengo yanabeba taarifa za hisia, wakati mtazamo huyo anaweza kuchukuliwa kuwa ni sawa. Zaidi ya hayo, tunachambua kama tukiwasilisha muundo kuhusu nafasi ya nafasi hiyo inaboresha uamuzi wa usambazaji. hasa kwenye kampuni ya fasihi tunagundua kuwa taarifa za kazi zinaongezea sifa za hisia.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Duýdury tanamak öň bellenen hili metin birimleri metin klasifikasy hökmünde (meselâ, gorky, bagly, g a ýgylyk, gaýgylyk, alyp sowgat, g üýçlendirme, umyt etmek üçin) duýgular ýaly tassyklandyrylýar. Soňky wagtlar, semantik näme etiketleme golaýlary metinden gurnalary açmak üçin "duýgyny duýmak üçin kim tassyklandyrylýar?" "Bu duýgyny näme sebäp edýär?" we bu ýerde haýsy gural edildi? (maksady). Bu semantik rollaryň haýsy bir nusga we duýgular kategoriýasyny çaklamak hem özüne bir fayda ýok bolýandygyny görkezildi. Bu semantik rolleriň hansynyň duýgularyny azaltmagy mümkin edýändigini a ýdyp bilmeýär. Bir adamyň kimligi häzirki duýgyna görä tertiblenýärmi (X hemişe bagtly)? Bu bir maksadymy (hemme kişi X'i söýýär) ýa-da bir rugsat (X etmek hemme kişini gaharlandyrýar)? Biz bu soraglary duýgularyň klasifikasy nusgalaryndan be ş bar veri setirlerinde iň azyndan bir semantik roli bilen duýgulanýan, bu rollaryň dolduranlaryny kontrol ýoly bilen maskararlap, we bu soraglary birnäçe korpora, stimuli we maksadlaryň içinde duýgular maglumatlaryny taýýarlap bilýäris, terjibe edeniň gaty ajaýyp bolup biler gö Daha da, nusga näme üçin näme üçin soraglarynyň aýratyny üýtgedýändigini analyz edýäris. Adatça edebiýat korporasynda biz munyň rol maglumaty duýgyş klasifikasyny gowuraýar diýip pikir edýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Njohja e emocioneve është formuar kryesisht si klasifikim teksti në të cilin njësitë tekstuale janë caktuar një emocion nga një inventar i paracaktuar (për shembull, frikë, g ëzim, zemërim, hidhërim, trishtim, befasi, besim, parashikim). Më së fundmi, janë zhvilluar metoda semantike për të etiketuar rolin për të nxjerrë strukturat nga teksti për të përgjigjur pyetje si: "kush është përshkruar për të ndjerë emocionin?". (përvojës), "Çka shkakton këtë emocion?" (stimulues) dhe në cilën njësi është drejtuar?” (objektiv). Ndonse është treguar se modelimi i përbashkët i stimulimit dhe parashikimi i kategorisë së emocioneve është i dobishëm për të dy nënpyetjet, mbetet i paqartë cili nga këto role semantike lejon një klasifikues të përfundojë emocionet. A është përvojuesi, sepse identiteti i një person është i paragjykuar ndaj një emocioni të veçantë (X është gjithmonë i lumtur)? A është një objektiv i veçantë (të gjithë duan X) apo një stimul (duke bërë X i bën të gjithë të trishtuar)? We answer these questions by training emotion classification models on five available datasets annotated with at least one semantic role by masking the fillers of these roles in the text in a controlled manner and find that across multiple corpora, stimuli and targets carry emotion information, while the experiencer might be considered a confounder.  Për më tepër, ne analizojmë nëse informimi i modelit rreth pozicionit të rolit përmirëson vendimin e klasifikimit. Veçanërisht për korprën e letërsisë ne zbulojmë se roli i informacionit përmirëson klasifikimin e emocioneve.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_af>Emosie herkenning is voorskynlik formeer as teks klasifikasie waarin teks eenhede a an 'n emosie van 'n vooraf definieerde inventorie aangewys word (bv. vrees, vrees, vreugde, toorn, ongeluk, triste, verrassing, vertrou, verwagting). En meer onlangs is semantiese roletiketeertoegange ontwikkel om strukture uit die teks te uitpak om vrae te antwoord soos: "Wie is beskrywe om die emosie te voel?" "Wat veroorsaak hierdie emosie?" (stimulus), en op watter eenheid is dit voorgeskryf? " (doel). Alhoewel dit vertoon is dat joint modeling van stimulus en emosie kategorie voorskou is nuttig vir beide subtaske, bly dit onbekende wat van hierdie semantiese roles 'n klassifiseerder kan maak om die emosie te onderskou. Is dit die erfaring, omdat die identiteit van 'n persoon voorspoedig is teen 'n bepaalde emosie (X is altyd gelukkig)? Is dit 'n bepaalde doel (almal lief van X) of 'n stimulus (doen van X maak almal treurig)? Ons antwoord hierdie vrae deur oefening van emosie klassifikasie modele op vyf beskikbare datastelle wat met minste een semantiese rol aangeteken word deur die vullers van hierdie role in die teks op 'n kontroleerde manier te maskeer en vind dat deur veelvuldige korpore, stimuleer en doels emosie inligting dra, terwyl die erfaring dalk 'n skandeerder aangeteken word. Verder, ons analyseer indien die model inligting oor die posisie van die rol die klasifikasie besluit verbeter. Spesiaal op literateitskorpora vind ons dat die rolinligting die emosie klasifikasie verbeter.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>የስህተት ማውቀት በመጀመሪያ የጽሑፍ ክፍል ነው፡፡ በቅርብ ዘመን፣ የsemantic role labeling approach is developed to extract structures from text to answer questions like ‹feelings ማን እንደተወው› የሚል? (ፈቃድ)፣ ይህች ስብሰባ ምን ምክንያት ነው? ወደ ማንኛውም ነገር ተመራ ? (target).  ምንም እንኳን በአንድነት መተላለፊያ እና የስሜት ክፍል ትንቢት ለሁለቱ ስርዓቶች ጥቅም ቢሆን፣ እነዚህም ተግባሮች ማንኛቸው ስህተቱን የሚያሳስብ ይችላል፡፡ Is it the experiencer, because the identity of a person is biased towards a particular emotion (X is always happy)?  ይህ የተለየ ዕቅድ ነውን (ሁሉም X የሚወድዱ X) ወይም የ (X እያደረጉ ሁሉን ያሳዝን)? እነዚህን ጥያቄዎች በአምስት በተገኘው ዳታዎችን በማስተካከል በሚያሰናከሉ እናመልሳለን፡፡ በተጨማሪም፣ የምሳሌውን በሥርዓት መኖሪያ ማሳየትን እናሳውቃለን፡፡ በተለይም በሐሳብት ኮርፖር ላይ የኢትዮጵያዊውን መግለጫ ማድረግ እናገኘዋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>স্বীকৃতি প্রাথমিকভাবে টেক্সটাল বিভাগ হিসেবে তৈরি করা হয়েছে যেখানে টেক্সচুয়াল ইউনিট পূর্ববর্তীকালীন তথ্যচিত্র থেকে একটি অনুভূতির দায়িত্ব দেয়া হয় ( More recently, semantic role labeling approaches have been developed to extract structures from the text to answer questions like: 'who is described to feel the emotion?'  (অভিজ্ঞতা) এই আবেগের কারণ কি? (উৎসাহিত) এবং কোন বস্তুকে নির্দেশ দেয়া হয়? (লক্ষ্য) যদিও এটি দেখা যাচ্ছে যে যুক্তরাষ্ট্র এবং আবেগের বিভাগের ধারাবাহিক মডেলিং দুজনের সাবটাকাজের জন্য উপকারী, তবুও এটা এখনো পরিষ্কার যে এই সেমেন্টিক ভূম এটা কি অভিজ্ঞতা, কারণ একজন ব্যক্তির পরিচয় বিশেষ অনুভূতির প্রতি বিরোধীতা (এক্স সবসময় খুশি? এটা কি একটি বিশেষ লক্ষ্য (সবাই এক্স ভালোবাসে) নাকি উৎসাহিত (এক্স করার জন্য সবাইকে দুঃখিত করে? আমরা এই প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিচ্ছি এই প্রশ্নের মাধ্যমে পাঁচটি বিদ্যমান ডাটাসেটে প্রশিক্ষণের মডেলের প্রশিক্ষণের মাধ্যমে যারা অন্তত একটি সেমান্টিক ভূমিকা দিয়ে এই ভূমিকাকে নিয়ন্ত্রণের ভাবে ম এছাড়াও, আমরা বিশ্লেষণ করি যে মডেলটিকে ভূমিকার অবস্থান সম্পর্কে জানানো যায় কিনা ক্লাসিফেশনের সিদ্ধান্ত উন্ বিশেষ করে সাহিত্য কোর্পোরা সম্পর্কে আমরা দেখতে পাচ্ছি যে ভূমিকা তথ্য এই আবেগের বিভিন্ন সংক্রান্ত ক্লাসে</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Emotion recognition is predominantly formulated as text classification in which textual units are assigned to an emotion from a predefined inventory (e.g., fear, joy, anger, disgust, sadness, surprise, trust, anticipation).  Վերջերս ստեղծվել են սեմանտիկ դեր պիտակավորելու մոտեցումներ, որոնք ստեղծվել են տեքստից կառուցվածքներ հանելու համար, որպեսզի պատասխանեն հարցերին, ինչպիսիք են. «Ո՞վ է նկարագրված զգալու զգացմու «Ի՞նչն է պատճառում այս զգացմունքը»: (stimulus), and at which entity is it directed?'  (նպատակ): Though it has been shown that jointly modeling stimulus and emotion category prediction is beneficial for both subtasks, it remains unclear which of these semantic roles enables a classifier to infer the emotion.  Is it the experiencer, because the identity of a person is biased towards a particular emotion (X is always happy)?  Is it a particular target (everybody loves X) or a stimulus (doing X makes everybody sad)?  We answer these questions by training emotion classification models on five available datasets annotated with at least one semantic role by masking the fillers of these roles in the text in a controlled manner and find that across multiple corpora, stimuli and targets carry emotion information, while the experiencer might be considered a confounder.  Further, we analyze if informing the model about the position of the role improves the classification decision.  Particularly on literature corpora we find that the role information improves the emotion classification.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bs>Priznavanje emocija je uglavnom formulirano kao klasifikacija teksta u kojoj su tekstualne jedinice dodijeljene emociji iz predodređenog inventara (npr. strah, radost, bijes, odvratnost, tuga, iznenađenje, povjerenje, očekivanje). Nedavnije, razvijene su pristupe označavanja semantičke uloge za izvlačenje struktura iz teksta kako bi odgovorili na pitanja poput: "ko je opisan da osjeti emocije?" Šta uzrokuje ovu emociju? I u kojoj je entiteti upućen? (meta). Iako je pokazalo da je zajedničko modeliranje stimulus a i predviđanje kategorije emocija korisno za obe podstažnosti, ostalo je jasno koji od tih semantičkih uloga omogućava klasifikatoru inficirati emocije. Da li je to iskustvo, jer je identitet osobe predrasuden prema posebnoj emociji (X je uvijek sretan)? Da li je to određena meta (svi vole X) ili stimula (radi X čini sve tužnim)? Odgovaramo na te pitanja, vježbamo modele klasifikacije emocija na pet dostupnih podataka koji su najmanje jednu semantičku ulogu, maskirajući punitelje tih uloga u tekstu na kontrolirani način, i saznamo da preko višestrukih tijela, stimuliranja i cilja nose emocionalne informacije, dok bi iskustvo moglo biti smatrano zbunjenim. Nadalje, analiziramo ako obavijestimo model o poziciji uloge poboljšava odluku o klasifikaciji. Posebno u književnoj korporaciji nalazimo da informacije o ulozi poboljšavaju klasifikaciju emocija.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_az>Emotiyon tanıması çox mətn klasifikasyonu kimi formüllənir ki, içində mətn ünvanları əvvəlcə belə təyin edilmiş bir quruluşdan bir duygu təyin edilir. Son zamanlarda, semantik rol etiketləmə yaxınlıqları məktublardan yapıları çıxartmaq üçün "emosyonu hiss etmək üçün kimin təfsil edildi?" sorularına cavab vermək üçün təhsil edildi. "Bu duyguların nə səbəbi var?" hansı tərəfə doğru yolu göstərildi? (hedef). Halbuki bu semantik rollərin hansının hissəsini düzəltməyə qadir olduğunu göstərilmişdir. Bu təcrübəcüdür, çünki kişinin kimliğin müəyyən bir duygulara qarşı təcrübəcüdür (X həmişə xoşbəxtdir)? Bu müəyyən bir məsafədir (hər kəs X sevər) yoxsa bir stimuludur (X etmək hər kəsi üzgün edir)? Biz bu sualları, be ş mümkün verilən verilən məlumat quruluğu təhsil edərək, ən az bir semantik rolü ilə təhsil edilən, məlumat quruluğu ilə məlumatların doldurduqlarını gizlədirək və çoxlu korpora, stimuli və məlumatların hərəkətində emosyon məlumatlarını daşıyaraq, təcrübəcülərin daha qarışıqlıq hesabı olaraq,  Daha sonra, modelini xəbər verib rolünün məqamı barəsində xəbər verilməsini analiz edirik. Özellikle də qismət korporasında rol məlumatının emosiyalıq səviyyəsini daha yaxşılaşdırdığını görürük.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_cs>Rozpoznávání emocí je formulováno převážně jako textová klasifikace, ve které jsou textové jednotky přiřazeny k emoci z předem definovaného inventáře (např. strach, radost, hněv, znechucení, smutek, překvapení, důvěra, očekávání). V poslední době byly vyvinuty přístupy sémantického označování rolí, které z textu extrahují struktury a odpovědí na otázky jako: "Kdo je popsán, aby cítil emoci?" "Co způsobuje tuto emoci?" (stimul) a na který subjekt je směřován?" (cíl). Přestože bylo prokázáno, že společné modelování stimulu a predikce emočních kategorií je přínosné pro oba podúkoly, zůstává nejasné, která z těchto sémantických rolí umožňuje klasifikátoru vyvodit emoci. Je to zkušenost, protože identita člověka je zaujatá k určité emoci (X je vždy šťastný)? Je to konkrétní cíl (každý miluje X) nebo stimul (dělat X všechny smutné)? Na tyto otázky odpovídáme tréninkem klasifikačních modelů emocí na pěti dostupných datových sadách anotovaných alespoň jednou sémantickou rolí tím, že kontrolovaným způsobem maskujeme výplně těchto rolí v textu a zjišťujeme, že napříč více korpusy, stimuly a cíle nesou emoční informace, zatímco zkušenost může být považován za konfounder. Dále analyzujeme, zda informování modelu o pozici role zlepšuje rozhodnutí o klasifikaci. Zejména na literárních korpusech zjišťujeme, že informace o rolích zlepšují klasifikaci emocí.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Emotsioonide äratundmine sõnastatakse peamiselt tekstiklassifikatsioonina, kus tekstiüksused määratakse emotsioonile eelnevalt määratletud inventuurist (nt hirm, rõõm, viha, vastik, kurbus, üllatus, usaldus, ootus). Hiljuti on välja töötatud semantilised rollimärgistuse lähenemisviisid, et ekstraheerida tekstist struktuure, et vastata sellistele küsimustele nagu: "keda kirjeldatakse emotsiooni tundma?" (kogeja), 'mis põhjustab seda emotsiooni?' (stiimul) ja millisele olemile see suunatakse?" (sihtmärk). Kuigi on näidatud, et stiimulite ja emotsioonikategooria prognoosimine on mõlema alamülesande jaoks kasulik, jääb ebaselgeks, milline neist semantilistest rollidest võimaldab klassifitseerijal emotsiooni järeldada. Kas see on kogendaja, sest inimese identiteet on erapooletu konkreetse emotsiooni poole (X on alati õnnelik)? Kas see on konkreetne sihtmärk (kõik armastavad X) või stiimul (X tegemine teeb kõik kurvaks)? Vastame neile küsimustele, treenides emotsioonide klassifitseerimise mudeleid viiel olemasoleval andmekogumil, millel on vähemalt üks semantiline roll, maskeerides nende rollide täiteained tekstis kontrollitult ning leiame, et mitmes korpuses kannavad stiimulid ja sihtmärgid emotsiooniteavet, samas kui kogendajat võib pidada segajaks. Lisaks analüüsime, kas mudeli teavitamine rolli positsioonist parandab klassifitseerimisotsust. Eriti kirjanduskorpustes leiame, et rolliinfo parandab emotsioonide klassifikatsiooni.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tunteiden tunnistus on pääasiassa muotoiltu tekstiluokitteluksi, jossa tekstiyksiköitä osoitetaan tunnetiedolle ennalta määritellystä inventaariosta (esim. pelko, ilo, viha, inho, suru, yllätys, luottamus, ennakointi). Viime aikoina on kehitetty semanttisia roolimerkintöjä, joiden avulla voidaan poimia tekstistä rakenteita vastaamaan esimerkiksi kysymyksiin: "Kuka kuvaillaan tuntemaan tunteen?" (Kokeja), 'mikä aiheuttaa tämän tunteen?' (ärsyke), ja mihin kokonaisuuteen se on suunnattu?" (tavoite). Vaikka on osoitettu, että ärsykkeen ja tunnetason ennustamisen yhteismallintaminen hyödyttää molempia osatehtäviä, on epäselvää, mikä näistä semanttisista rooleista mahdollistaa luokittelijan päätellä tunteen. Onko se kokeja, koska henkilön identiteetti on puolueellinen tiettyyn tunteeseen (X on aina onnellinen)? Onko se tietty kohde (kaikki rakastavat X:tä) vai ärsyke (X:n tekeminen tekee kaikki surullisiksi)? Vastaamme näihin kysymyksiin harjoittelemalla tunteiden luokittelumalleja viiteen saatavilla olevaan aineistoon, joissa on vähintään yksi semanttinen rooli, peittämällä näiden roolien täyteaineet tekstissä kontrolloidusti ja havaitsemme, että eri korpussa ärsykkeet ja kohteet kantavat tunteiden tietoa, kun taas kokejaa voidaan pitää hämmentävänä. Lisäksi analysoimme, parantaako mallin ilmoittaminen roolin asemasta luokituspäätöstä. Erityisesti kirjallisuuskorporassa huomaamme, että roolitieto parantaa tunteiden luokittelua.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>Emotion recognition is predominantly formulated as text classification in which textual units are assigned to an emotion from a predefined inventory (e.g., fear, joy, anger, disgust, sadness, surprise, trust, anticipation).  More recently, semantic role labeling approaches have been developed to extract structures from the text to answer questions like: 'who is described to feel the emotion?'  (experiencer), 'what causes this emotion?'  (stimulus), and at which entity is it directed?'  (target).  Though it has been shown that jointly modeling stimulus and emotion category prediction is beneficial for both subtasks, it remains unclear which of these semantic roles enables a classifier to infer the emotion.  Is it the experiencer, because the identity of a person is biased towards a particular emotion (X is always happy)?  Is it a particular target (everybody loves X) or a stimulus (doing X makes everybody sad)?  We answer these questions by training emotion classification models on five available datasets annotated with at least one semantic role by masking the fillers of these roles in the text in a controlled manner and find that across multiple corpora, stimuli and targets carry emotion information, while the experiencer might be considered a confounder.  Further, we analyze if informing the model about the position of the role improves the classification decision.  Particularly on literature corpora we find that the role information improves the emotion classification.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_sk>Prepoznavanje čustev je predvsem formulirano kot klasifikacija besedila, v kateri so besedilne enote dodeljene čustvu iz vnaprej določenega inventarja (npr. strah, radost, jeza, gnus, žalost, presenečenje, zaupanje, pričakovanje). V zadnjem času so bili razviti pristopi semantičnega označevanja vlog, da bi iz besedila izvlekli strukture in odgovorili na vprašanja, kot je: "Kdo je opisan, da čuti čustvo?" (izkuševalec), "kaj povzroča to čustvo?" (spodbuda) in na katero entiteto je usmerjena?" (cilj). Čeprav je bilo dokazano, da je skupno modeliranje dražljajev in napovedi kategorije čustev koristno za obe podnalogi, ostaja nejasno, katera od teh semantičnih vlog omogoča klasifikatorju sklepanje čustev. Je to izkuševalec, ker je identiteta osebe pristranska do določenega čustva (X je vedno srečen)? Je to določena tarča (vsi imajo radi X) ali spodbuda (delanje X vse žalosti)? Na ta vprašanja odgovarjamo tako, da usposabljamo modele klasifikacije čustev na petih razpoložljivih naborih podatkov z vsaj eno semantično vlogo tako, da nadzorovano prikrijemo polnila teh vlog v besedilu in ugotovimo, da dražljaji in tarče v več korpusih prenašajo informacije o čustvih, medtem ko je izkuševalec lahko zmedeljevalec. Nadalje analiziramo, ali obveščanje modela o položaju vloge izboljša odločitev o klasifikaciji. Predvsem v literarnih korpusih ugotavljamo, da informacije o vlogi izboljšujejo klasifikacijo čustev.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Ana danna aikin kwamfyuta an a ƙayyade shi mainli kamar classified matsayi, a cikinsa akwai ayõyin ayuka na littafi zuwa wani hisabi daga birnin da aka riga (misali, tsoron, fari, haske, baƙin ciki, da mãkirci, na yi amfani). A yanzu, an buɗe masu aikin rubutu na semanti-roli dõmin ya nuna matsayin daga matsayin dõmin ya karɓa wa maswali kamar "Wãne ne ake bayyana wa za'a shafi aikin?" Mẽne ne ke halatar da wannan zato?" To, wãne ne ake shiryarwa?" (goa). Haƙĩƙa, kuma an nuna cewa, shirin sami mai motsi da categori na ƙanni na ɗabi'a yana da amfani ga aikin dukansu, kuma yana kasancẽwa ga wanne daga wannan aikin na semantiki zai iya ƙara wani fasasafi ga hisãbin. Shin, yana da shawarar wani mutum ne wanda ke karkaci zuwa wani hisia'a mai ƙayyadadde (X ke yi farin ciki)? Shin, yana da jigon da aka ƙayyade (ko dukkan mutum yana son X) ko kuma yana da mai sauri (da X ke aikata duk ɗaya)? Munã karɓa wa masu tambayar su game da shirin misãlai masu tabar da ke samun mutane shan wanda ke iya haɗuwa da shi, ko da kuma a rage rabo guda, ko kuma muna kiyaye filin waɗannan rolayen a cikin matsayin da aka lissafa, kuma munã gane cewa, a kangara masu yawa karkacin, ko kuma masu amfani da zai iya ɗauki maɓallin hisãbi, kuma a lokacin da ya kamata mai musanyawa a sami. Furan, za mu yi anadi idan ka bã shi lãbãri ga misalin a kan wurin da ke ƙara umarin-fasalin. Kayyai da kamera na littafan, tuna gane cewa ma'anar aikin da ke ƙara fasalin hisani.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Rasané awak dhéwé iku podho kelas teks sing dirampakan karo unidadi textual sing nyebutne karo nthasakno sing dumadhil suku kelas éndah (bisa, nggalakno, nggalakno, nggalakno, njujak, njujak, iso dianggap, nggunakake, nglanggar). Nyong-ngopo, sithik karo sematik penting nggawe dolanan pawaran kanggo nggawe structural dumateng seneng pisan seneng pisan koyo: 'sapa sing paling apik dhéwé Seneng sampek ? ' (alam), "piye rasane kuwi, opo sing dirasaane kuwi?" (Stimul), lan uwis seneng Entire sing diralok ? (goal). Genjer-genjer paling iki ngono kuwi nggawe sistem tarjamahan lan alam-alam kuwi bener kanggo supoyo urip kuwi duluran, kuwi mau kuwi ora ngerasakno sing karo rol sematik iki iso mlebu mengko koyo sak cara-malah sing duwé. Opo kuwi lanjut sing perasaanku, mergane sampeyan perbudhakan kang éneng sampeyan sing apik (X saiki jati) Apa bener ya wis biasa (gak saben luwih dumateng X) Uto mbok (nggawe X seneng luwih apik saben) Awak dhéwé mbugal gawe iki luwih-luwih ning model kuwi nggawe alam sing perusahaan an sampek sing gawe dataset sing wis ana sing entuk dhéwé, ngono ingkang semantar sampek kanggo masakno perusahaan karo perangkat kuwi nggawe nguasai perusahaan lan tambah kuwi kesempatan sampek karo sak kudu, sekondi lan cilik kuwi alam kuwi informasi alam, terus akya politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertive ngomong nik babasane piye basa piye basa ning awak dhéwé kuwi informasi ingkang ngerasahan seneng luwih apik dhéwé.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>Emotion recognition is predominantly formulated as text classification in which textual units are assigned to an emotion from a predefined inventory (e.g., fear, joy, anger, disgust, sadness, surprise, trust, anticipation).  More recently, semantic role labeling approaches have been developed to extract structures from the text to answer questions like: 'who is described to feel the emotion?'  "מה גורם לרגשות האלה?" (גירוי), ואיזו יחידה היא מכוונת? (מטרה). למרות שהוכיח שדגמה משותפת של גירוי וקטגוריה רגשותית היא תועלת לשני השאלות, נשאר לא ברור איזה מהתפקידים הסמנטיים האלה מאפשרים לקlassifikatור להוציא את הרגשות. האם זה החווי, כי זהותו של אדם מועמדת כלפי רגש מסוים (X תמיד מאושר)? האם זה מטרה מסוימת (כולם אוהבים X) או גירום (לעשות X עושה את כולם עצובים)? We answer these questions by training emotion classification models on five available datasets annotated with at least one semantic role by masking the fillers of these roles in the text in a controlled manner and find that across multiple corpora, stimuli and targets carry emotion information, while the experiencer might be considered a confounder.  חוץ מזה, אנו מנתחים אם מידע למודל על עמדתו של התפקיד משפר את החלטת ההקלטה. Particularly on literature corpora we find that the role information improves the emotion classification.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>སེམས་བརྗོད་རྟོགས་འདི་predominantly formulated as text classification in which textual units are assigned to an emotion from a predefined inventory (e.g., fear, joy, anger, disgust, sad, surprise, trust, anticipation). More recently, semantic role labeling approaches have been developed to extract structures from the text to answer questions like: 'who is described to feel the emotion?' (དགོད་པ་) སེམས་ཚོར་འདི་ཅི་རྐྱེན་བྱས་པ་རེད། (stimulus)ཡིན་ནམ། གང་ཞིག་ཡིན་ནམ། (དམིགས་ཡུལ) སྤྱིར་བཏང་བ་དང་སེམས་ཚོར་མཁན་དབྱིབས་མཐུན་རྣམས་ལས་མཐུན་རྣམས་ལས། མི་ཞིག་གི་ངོ་བོ་དེ་ནས་དབང་ཆ་ཡིན་ནམ་མེད་པས་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་ངོ་བོ་སྣང་དང་མཉམ་དུ་འཇུག་སྲིད་པ་ཡིན་ནམ། འདི་ལ་དམིགས་ཡུལ་ཁྱད་པར་ཞིག་ཡིན་ནམ(མི་ཚང་མས་X དགའ་པོ) ཡང་ན་སྒུལ་ཤུགས་ཞིག་ཡིན་ནམ། ང་ཚོས་སྤྲོ་བ་འདི་དག་གི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལྟར་དབྱེ་བ་ཐབས་ལམ་གནང་བ་ཡོད་པའི་གནད་སྡུད་ཅིག་ལ་བསྟུན་ནས་གནད་སྡུད་པའི་ནང་དུ་ཉུང་མཐའ་རང འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་དབྱིབས་དཔེ་དབྱིབས་ཞིབ་བྱེད་ན་མིན་དཔེ་གཏོང་གི་གནས་ཡུལ་སྐོར་གྱི་གནས་ཡུལ་ལ་གཏོང ཁྱད་དུ་འཕགས་པའི་ཞིབ་དཔུད་སྐྲུན་གྱི་ཐོག་ལས་ང་ཚོར་རྣམས་ཀྱི་ལས་འགྲེལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་སྣང་ཚུལ་མཐོང་དང་།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>