<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.rdsm">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 3rd International Workshop on Rumours and Deception in Social Media (RDSM)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ahmet</first><last>Aker</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Arkaitz</first><last>Zubiaga</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="feee157f">2020.rdsm-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>rdsm-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Covid or not Covid? Topic Shift in Information Cascades on Twitter<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter</title>
      <author><first>Liana</first><last>Ermakova</last></author>
      <author><first>Diana</first><last>Nurbakova</last></author>
      <author><first>Irina</first><last>Ovchinnikova</last></author>
      <pages>32–37</pages>
      <abstract>Social media have become a valuable source of information. However, its power to shape <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_opinion">public opinion</a> can be dangerous, especially in the case of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misinformation">misinformation</a>. The existing studies on misinformation detection hypothesise that the initial message is fake. In contrast, we focus on information distortion occurring in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_cascade">cascades</a> as the initial message is quoted or receives a reply. We show a significant topic shift in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_cascade">information cascades</a> on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a> during the Covid-19 pandemic providing valuable insights for the automatic analysis of information distortion.</abstract>
      <url hash="bf0cfef3">2020.rdsm-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>ermakova-etal-2020-covid</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Automatic Detection of Hungarian Clickbait and Entertaining Fake News<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>ungarian Clickbait and Entertaining Fake News</title>
      <author><first>Veronika</first><last>Vincze</last></author>
      <author><first>Martina Katalin</first><last>Szabó</last></author>
      <pages>58–69</pages>
      <abstract>Online news do not always come from reliable sources and they are not always even realistic. The constantly growing number of online textual data has raised the need for detecting deception and bias in texts from different domains recently. In this paper, we identify different types of unrealistic news (clickbait and fake news written for entertainment purposes) written in Hungarian on the basis of a rich feature set and with the help of machine learning methods. Our tool achieves competitive scores : it is able to classify <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clickbait">clickbait</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake news</a> written for entertainment purposes and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News">real news</a> with an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of over 80 %. It is also highlighted that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphology_(biology)">morphological features</a> perform the best in this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification task</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="a3b39f5e">2020.rdsm-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>vincze-szabo-2020-automatic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Fake or Real? A Study of Arabic Satirical Fake News<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic Satirical Fake News</title>
      <author><first>Hadeel</first><last>Saadany</last></author>
      <author><first>Constantin</first><last>Orasan</last></author>
      <author><first>Emad</first><last>Mohamed</last></author>
      <pages>70–80</pages>
      <abstract>One very common type of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake news</a> is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satire">satire</a> which comes in a form of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_newspaper">news website</a> or an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_newspaper">online platform</a> that parodies reputable real news agencies to create a sarcastic version of reality. This type of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake news</a> is often disseminated by individuals on their online platforms as it has a much stronger effect in delivering criticism than through a straightforward message. However, when the satirical text is disseminated via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> without mention of its source, it can be mistaken for real news. This study conducts several exploratory analyses to identify the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistics">linguistic properties</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">Arabic fake news</a> with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satire">satirical content</a>. It shows that although it parodies <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News">real news</a>, Arabic satirical news has distinguishing features on the lexico-grammatical level. We exploit these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> to build a number of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning models</a> capable of identifying satirical fake news with an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of up to 98.6 %. The study introduces a new dataset (3185 articles) scraped from two Arabic satirical news websites (‘Al-Hudood’ and ‘Al-Ahram Al-Mexici’) which consists of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake news</a>. The real news dataset consists of 3710 articles collected from three official news sites : the ‘BBC-Arabic’, the ‘CNN-Arabic’ and ‘Al-Jazeera news’. Both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> are concerned with political issues related to the Middle East.</abstract>
      <url hash="9ce73187">2020.rdsm-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>saadany-etal-2020-fake</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/sadanyh/Satirical-Fake-News-Dataset" additional="false">sadanyh/Satirical-Fake-News-Dataset</pwccode>
    <title_pt>Falso ou real? Um estudo de notícias falsas satíricas árabes</title_pt>
      <title_ar>وهمية أو حقيقية؟ دراسة الأخبار الكاذبة العربية الساخرة</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Faux ou Réel ? Une étude des fausses nouvelles satiriques arabes</title_fr>
      <title_es>¿Falso o real? Un estudio de las noticias falsas satíricas árabes</title_es>
      <title_zh>假者真邪? 阿拉伯刺假新闻究</title_zh>
      <title_ja>フェイクとリアル？アラビア風刺フェイクニュースの研究</title_ja>
      <title_hi>नकली या असली? अरबी व्यंग्यात्मक नकली समाचार का एक अध्ययन</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Поддельные или реальные? Исследование арабских сатирических фейковых новостей</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Bréige nó Fíor? Staidéar ar Nuacht Bhréige Aoir Araibis</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ტალა თლთ პვალნა? Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Hamis vagy igazi? Az arab szatirikus hamis hírek tanulmánya</title_hu>
      <title_el>Ψεύτικο ή αληθινό; Μια μελέτη των αραβικών σατιρικών πλαστών ειδήσεων</title_el>
      <title_it>Falso o reale? Uno studio di notizie false satiriche arabe</title_it>
      <title_lt>Klaidingas ar tikras? Arabų satirikos suklastotų naujienų tyrimas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Лажна или вистинска? Name</title_mk>
      <title_kk>Жалған немесе шын? Араб сатирикалық жаңалықтарды оқытуName</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Salah atau nyata? Name</title_ms>
      <title_ml>കള്ളം അല്ലെങ്കില്‍ യഥാര്‍ത്ഥം? അറബി സാറ്റിരിക്കല്‍ ഫെയ്ക് വാര്‍ത്തകളുടെ ഒരു പഠനം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Falz jew Reali? Studju ta’ A ħbarijiet Falsi Satiriċi Għarab</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Хуудал эсвэл үнэн үү? Араб дагуулын хуурамч мэдээллийн судалгаа</title_mn>
      <title_no>Falsk eller verkeleg? Name</title_no>
      <title_pl>Fałszywy czy prawdziwy? Badanie arabskiej satyrycznej fałszywej wiadomości</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Fals sau real? Un studiu al știrilor false satirice arabe</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Lažna ili stvarna? Proučavanje arapskih satiričkih lažnih vijesti</title_sr>
      <title_si>ඇත්තද? Name</title_si>
      <title_so>Dhaqso ama dhab? A Study of Arabic Satirical Fake News</title_so>
      <title_sv>Falsk eller äkta? En studie av arabiska satiriska falska nyheter</title_sv>
      <title_ta>பொய் அல்லது உண்மையா? Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>جھوٹا یا سچا؟ عربی سٹریک فاسق خبروں کی تعلیم</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Fayl yoki haqiqiy? Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Giả hay thật? A study of Arab Satical Fake news</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Фалшив или истински? Изследване на арабските сатирични фалшиви новини</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Nep of echt? Een studie van Arabisch satirisch nepnieuws</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Lažna ili stvarna? Proučavanje arapskih satiričkih lažnih vijesti</title_hr>
      <title_da>Falsk eller ægte? En undersøgelse af arabisk satirisk falske nyheder</title_da>
      <title_de>Fake oder Real? Eine Studie arabischer satirischer Fake News</title_de>
      <title_fa>دروغ يا حقيقت؟ Name</title_fa>
      <title_ko>가짜야, 진짜야?아랍 풍자 가짜 뉴스 연구</title_ko>
      <title_id>Fake atau Real? Sebuah studi berita palsu satiris Arab</title_id>
      <title_sw>Ukweli au ukweli? Utafiti wa Habari za Udanganyiko wa Kiarabu</title_sw>
      <title_sq>Falsifikuar apo i vërtetë? Një studim i lajmeve të rreme satirike arabe</title_sq>
      <title_tr>Yalanmış mı, gerçek mi? Arapça Satirik ýalňyş Haýtalaryň öwrenmesi</title_tr>
      <title_af>Verfal of Real? Name</title_af>
      <title_am>ውሸት ወይም እውነተኛ? የዐረብኛ ሳቲካል የውሸት ዜናዎች ትምህርት</title_am>
      <title_hy>Կարծես թե իրական՞: Արաբական սաթիրական կեղծ նորությունների ուսումնասիրությունը</title_hy>
      <title_bn>Fake or Real?  আরবী সাতিরিক ফ্যাক সংবাদের একটি গবেষণা</title_bn>
      <title_az>YalanmńĪŇü v…ô ya h…ôqiq…ôt? Arap√ßa Satirical Fake Haberl…ôri √Ėyr…ônm…ôsi</title_az>
      <title_bs>Lažna ili stvarna? Proučavanje arapskih satiričkih lažnih vijesti</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Falsa o real? Un estudi de notícies falses satèriques àrabs</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Falešný nebo skutečný? Studie arabských satirických falešných zpráv</title_cs>
      <title_et>Võlts või päris? Uuring araabia satiirilistest võltsitud uudistest</title_et>
      <title_fi>Väärennetty vai aito? A Study of Arabic Satirical Fake News</title_fi>
      <title_he>מזויף או אמיתי? A Study of Arabic Satirical Fake News</title_he>
      <title_sk>Lažno ali resnično? Študija arabskih satiričnih lažnih novic</title_sk>
      <title_jv>Iki lak utowo nek tenan ? Workspace of Gabon</title_jv>
      <title_bo>སླ་ཕམ་པ་ཡང་ན་དངོས་བདེན་པོ་ཞིག་ཡིན་ནམ། ཨ་རབ་ཀྱི་སྒྲ་ཚིགས་ཀྱི་ཕྲ་རིང་གི་བརྡ་ཞིབ་བྱས་པ་ཡིན།</title_bo>
      <title_ha>QDialogButtonBox A Research of Arabic Satirical Fake News</title_ha>
      <abstract_ar>أحد الأنواع الشائعة جدًا للأخبار المزيفة هو السخرية التي تأتي في شكل موقع إخباري أو منصة على الإنترنت تسخر من وكالات أنباء حقيقية ذات سمعة طيبة لإنشاء نسخة ساخرة من الواقع. غالبًا ما يتم نشر هذا النوع من الأخبار المزيفة من قبل الأفراد على منصاتهم عبر الإنترنت حيث يكون لها تأثير أقوى بكثير في توجيه النقد أكثر من الرسائل المباشرة. ومع ذلك ، عندما يتم نشر النص الساخر عبر وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي دون ذكر مصدره ، يمكن اعتباره خاطئًا على أنه أخبار حقيقية. تقوم هذه الدراسة بإجراء العديد من التحليلات الاستكشافية للتعرف على الخصائص اللغوية للأخبار العربية المزيفة ذات المحتوى الساخر. يظهر أنه على الرغم من كونه يسخر من الأخبار الحقيقية ، إلا أن الأخبار العربية الساخرة لها سمات مميزة على المستوى المعجمي النحوي. نستغل هذه الميزات لبناء عدد من نماذج التعلم الآلي القادرة على تحديد الأخبار الكاذبة الساخرة بدقة تصل إلى 98.6٪. تقدم الدراسة مجموعة بيانات جديدة (3185 مقالة) مأخوذة من موقعين إخباريين عرب ساخرين (الحدود والأهرام المكسيكي) تتكون من أخبار كاذبة. تتكون مجموعة بيانات الأخبار الحقيقية من 3710 مقالاً تم جمعها من ثلاثة مواقع إخبارية رسمية: "BBC-Arabic" و "CNN-Arabic" و "الجزيرة الإخبارية". كلا مجموعتي البيانات معنيين بالقضايا السياسية المتعلقة بالشرق الأوسط.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Un tipo muy común de noticias falsas es la sátira, que viene en forma de un sitio web de noticias o una plataforma en línea que parodia a las agencias de noticias reales de buena reputación para crear una versión sarcástica de la realidad. Este tipo de noticias falsas a menudo son difundidas por personas en sus plataformas en línea, ya que tienen un efecto mucho más fuerte en la entrega de críticas que a través de un mensaje directo. Sin embargo, cuando el texto satírico se difunde a través de las redes sociales sin mencionar su fuente, puede confundirse con noticias reales. Este estudio lleva a cabo varios análisis exploratorios para identificar las propiedades lingüísticas de las noticias falsas árabes con contenido satírico. Demuestra que, aunque parodia las noticias reales, las noticias satíricas árabes tienen características distintivas a nivel léxico-gramatical. Aprovechamos estas funciones para crear una serie de modelos de aprendizaje automático capaces de identificar noticias falsas satíricas con una precisión de hasta el 98,6%. El estudio introduce un nuevo conjunto de datos (3185 artículos) extraído de dos sitios web de noticias satíricas árabes (`Al-Hudood' y `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') que consiste en noticias falsas. El conjunto de datos de noticias reales consta de 3710 artículos recopilados de tres sitios de noticias oficiales: el `BBC-Arabic', el `CNN-Arabic' y `Al-Jazeera news'. Ambos conjuntos de datos se refieren a cuestiones políticas relacionadas con Oriente Medio.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Um tipo muito comum de notícias falsas é a sátira que vem na forma de um site de notícias ou uma plataforma online que parodia agências de notícias reais respeitáveis para criar uma versão sarcástica da realidade. Esse tipo de notícia falsa é frequentemente disseminado por indivíduos em suas plataformas online, pois tem um efeito muito mais forte na entrega de críticas do que por meio de uma mensagem direta. No entanto, quando o texto satírico é divulgado via redes sociais sem menção de sua fonte, pode ser confundido com notícias reais. Este estudo realiza diversas análises exploratórias para identificar as propriedades linguísticas de notícias falsas árabes com conteúdo satírico. Mostra que, apesar de parodiar notícias reais, as notícias satíricas árabes possuem características distintivas no nível léxico-gramatical. Exploramos esses recursos para construir uma série de modelos de aprendizado de máquina capazes de identificar notícias falsas satíricas com uma precisão de até 98,6%. O estudo apresenta um novo conjunto de dados (3185 artigos) extraídos de dois sites de notícias satíricas árabes ('Al-Hudood' e 'Al-Ahram Al-Mexici'), que consiste em notícias falsas. O conjunto de dados de notícias reais consiste em 3710 artigos coletados de três sites oficiais de notícias: o 'BBC-Árabe', o 'CNN-Árabe' e o 'Notícias da Al-Jazeera'. Ambos os conjuntos de dados estão preocupados com questões políticas relacionadas ao Oriente Médio.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Un type très courant de fake news est la satire, qui se présente sous la forme d'un site Web d'information ou d'une plateforme en ligne qui parodie de vraies agences de presse réputées pour créer une version sarcastique de la réalité. Ce type de fake news est souvent diffusé par des individus sur leurs plateformes en ligne, car il a un effet beaucoup plus important sur la diffusion de critiques que par le biais d'un simple message. Cependant, lorsque le texte satirique est diffusé via les réseaux sociaux sans mention de sa source, il peut être confondu avec de vraies nouvelles. Cette étude mène plusieurs analyses exploratoires afin d'identifier les propriétés linguistiques des fake news arabes au contenu satirique. Elle montre que, bien qu'elle parodie les informations réelles, les actualités satiriques arabes présentent des caractéristiques distinctives au niveau lexico-grammatical. Nous exploitons ces fonctionnalités pour créer un certain nombre de modèles d'apprentissage automatique capables d'identifier les fausses nouvelles satiriques avec une précision allant jusqu'à 98,6 %. L'étude introduit un nouvel ensemble de données (3185 articles) extraits de deux sites d'actualités satiriques arabes (« Al-Hudood » et « Al-Ahram Al-Mexici ») qui consiste en de fausses nouvelles. L'ensemble de données d'actualités réelles comprend 3710 articles collectés sur trois sites d'information officiels : « BBC-Arabic », « CNN-Arabic » et « Al-Jazeera news ». Les deux ensembles de données concernent des questions politiques liées au Moyen-Orient.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>フェイクニュースの一般的なタイプの1つは、ニュースサイトやオンラインプラットフォームの形式で現実の風刺的なバージョンを作成するために評判の良い本物のニュースエージェンシーをパロディする風刺です。 この種のフェイクニュースは、ストレートなメッセージよりも批判を伝える効果がはるかに強いため、オンラインプラットフォーム上で個人によって発信されることがよくあります。 しかし、風刺的な文章がその出典に言及せずにソーシャルメディアを介して流布されると、実際のニュースと誤認される可能性があります。 この研究は、風刺的な内容を持つアラビア語のフェイクニュースの言語的特性を特定するために、いくつかの探索的分析を行っている。 実際のニュースをパロディしていますが、アラビア語の風刺ニュースは辞書的レベルで際立った特徴を持っています。 これらの機能を利用して、最大98.6%の精度で風刺的なフェイクニュースを識別できる機械学習モデルを多数構築しています。 この研究では、フェイクニュースで構成される2つのアラビア語風刺ニュースウェブサイト（「Al - Hudood」と「Al - Ahram Al - Mexici」）から削られた新しいデータセット（ 3185記事）が紹介されています。 本物のニュースデータセットは、「BBC - Arabic」、「CNN - Arabic」、「Al - Jazeera news」の3つの公式ニュースサイトから収集された3710の記事で構成されています。 両方のデータセットは、中東に関連する政治的な問題に関係しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>नकली समाचार का एक बहुत ही सामान्य प्रकार व्यंग्य है जो एक समाचार वेबसाइट या एक ऑनलाइन प्लेटफ़ॉर्म के रूप में आता है जो वास्तविकता का एक व्यंग्यात्मक संस्करण बनाने के लिए सम्मानित वास्तविक समाचार एजेंसियों को पैरोडी करता है। इस प्रकार की नकली खबरों को अक्सर व्यक्तियों द्वारा अपने ऑनलाइन प्लेटफार्मों पर प्रसारित किया जाता है क्योंकि इसका एक सीधा संदेश की तुलना में आलोचना देने में बहुत मजबूत प्रभाव पड़ता है। हालांकि, जब व्यंग्य पाठ को इसके स्रोत के उल्लेख के बिना सोशल मीडिया के माध्यम से प्रसारित किया जाता है, तो इसे वास्तविक समाचार के लिए गलत किया जा सकता है। यह अध्ययन व्यंग्यात्मक सामग्री के साथ अरबी नकली समाचारों के भाषाई गुणों की पहचान करने के लिए कई अन्वेषणात्मक विश्लेषण करता है। यह दिखाता है कि यद्यपि यह वास्तविक समाचारों को पैरोडी करता है, अरबी व्यंग्यात्मक समाचार में लेक्सिको-व्याकरणिक स्तर पर विशिष्ट विशेषताएं हैं। हम इन विशेषताओं का फायदा उठाने के लिए मशीन लर्निंग मॉडल की एक संख्या का निर्माण करने के लिए 98.6% तक की सटीकता के साथ व्यंग्यात्मक नकली समाचार की पहचान करने में सक्षम हैं। अध्ययन एक नए डेटासेट (3185 लेख) का परिचय देता है जो दो अरबी व्यंग्यात्मक समाचार वेबसाइटों ('अल-हुदूद' और 'अल-अहराम अल-मेक्सिसी') से स्क्रैप किया गया है, जिसमें नकली समाचार शामिल हैं। वास्तविक समाचार डेटासेट में तीन आधिकारिक समाचार साइटों से एकत्र किए गए 3710 लेख शामिल हैं: 'बीबीसी-अरबी', 'सीएनएन-अरबी' और 'अल-जज़ीरा समाचार'। दोनों डेटासेट मध्य पूर्व से संबंधित राजनीतिक मुद्दों से संबंधित हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>常见之假新闻刺,以新闻网站在线台,象信新闻司,以造刺本。 凡此诸假新闻,人传于在线台之上,以其大于直言也。 然讥本因社交媒体而不及源,或误以为实新闻。 本研数探索性,以定讥阿拉伯假新闻之性。 虽仿佛真新闻,阿拉伯语讥新闻著于词汇语法层面也。 因功构机器学模形,以高达98.6%准确率识讽刺性假新闻。 该研引入一新数据集(3185篇),该数集从两阿拉伯语刺新闻网站("Al-Hudood"、"Al-Ahram Al-Mexici")中抓取,其中包假新闻。 真新闻数集三官新闻网站所集3710篇云:"BBC-Arabic","CNN-Arabic"、"Al-Jazeera news"。 此二数者集都皆关中东之政。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>Одним из самых распространенных типов фейковых новостей является сатира, которая приходит в виде новостного сайта или онлайн-платформы, которая пародирует авторитетные реальные новостные агентства, чтобы создать саркастическую версию реальности. Этот тип фейковых новостей часто распространяется отдельными лицами на их онлайн-платформах, поскольку он имеет гораздо более сильный эффект в донесении критики, чем через прямое сообщение. Однако, когда сатирический текст распространяется через социальные сети без упоминания его источника, его можно принять за реальную новость. Это исследование проводит несколько поисковых анализов для выявления лингвистических свойств арабских фейковых новостей с сатирическим содержанием. Он показывает, что, хотя он и пародирует реальные новости, арабские сатирические новости имеют отличительные черты на лексико-грамматическом уровне. Мы используем эти возможности для создания ряда моделей машинного обучения, способных идентифицировать сатирические фейковые новости с точностью до 98,6%. В исследовании представлен новый набор данных (3185 статей), взятых из двух арабских сатирических новостных сайтов («Аль-Худуд» и «Аль-Ахрам Аль-Мексики»), который состоит из фейковых новостей. Реальный набор новостей состоит из 3710 статей, собранных с трех официальных новостных сайтов: «Би-би-си-Арабик», «Си-эн-эн-Арабик» и «Аль-Джазира ньюс». Оба набора данных касаются политических вопросов, связанных с Ближним Востоком.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Cineál an-choitianta nuachta bréige amháin is ea aoir a thagann i bhfoirm láithreán gréasáin nuachta nó ardán ar líne a dhéanann scigaithris ar ghníomhaireachtaí fíor-nuachta a bhfuil cáil orthu chun leagan sarcastic den réaltacht a chruthú. Is minic a scaipeann daoine aonair an cineál seo nuachta bréige ar a n-ardáin ar líne mar go mbíonn éifeacht i bhfad níos láidre aige ar sheachadadh critice ná trí theachtaireacht dhíreach. Mar sin féin, nuair a scaiptear an téacs aoir ar na meáin shóisialta gan trácht ar a fhoinse, is féidir é a chur amú mar fhíor-nuacht. Déanann an staidéar seo roinnt anailísí taiscéalaíoch chun airíonna teanga na nuachta bréige Araibise a aithint le hábhar aoir. Léiríonn sé cé go ndéanann sé scigaithris ar an bhfíorscéal, go bhfuil gnéithe idirdhealaitheacha ag nuacht aoir na hAraibe ar an leibhéal foclóireachta-gramadaí. Bainimid leas as na gnéithe seo chun roinnt samhlacha meaisínfhoghlama a thógáil a bheidh in ann nuacht bhréige aoir a aithint le cruinneas suas le 98.6%. Tugann an staidéar isteach tacar sonraí nua (3185 alt) a scríobadh ó dhá shuíomh Gréasáin aoir Araibis (`Al-Hudood' agus `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') arb éard atá ann nuacht bhréige. Cuimsíonn an tacar sonraí fíornuachta 3710 alt a bailíodh ó thrí shuíomh oifigiúla nuachta: an `BBC-Arabic', an `CNN-Arabic' agus `Al-Jazeera news'. Baineann an dá thacar sonraí le saincheisteanna polaitiúla a bhaineann leis an Meánoirthear.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Ένας πολύ κοινός τύπος ψεύτικων ειδήσεων είναι η σάτιρα που έρχεται σε μορφή ιστοσελίδας ειδήσεων ή διαδικτυακής πλατφόρμας που παρωδίζει αξιόπιστα πρακτορεία ειδήσεων για να δημιουργήσει μια σαρκαστική εκδοχή της πραγματικότητας. Αυτό το είδος ψεύτικων ειδήσεων συχνά διαδίδεται από άτομα στις διαδικτυακές πλατφόρμες τους, καθώς έχει πολύ ισχυρότερο αποτέλεσμα στην παροχή κριτικής παρά μέσω ενός απλού μηνύματος. Ωστόσο, όταν το σατιρικό κείμενο διαδίδεται μέσω των μέσων κοινωνικής δικτύωσης χωρίς να αναφέρεται η πηγή του, μπορεί να παραπλανηθεί ως πραγματική είδηση. Η μελέτη αυτή διεξάγει διάφορες διερευνητικές αναλύσεις για τον προσδιορισμό των γλωσσικών ιδιοτήτων των αραβικών ψεύτικων ειδήσεων με σατιρικό περιεχόμενο. Δείχνει ότι αν και παρωδία πραγματικών ειδήσεων, οι αραβικές σατιρικές ειδήσεις έχουν διακριτικά χαρακτηριστικά στο λεξικό-γραμματικό επίπεδο. Εκμεταλλευόμαστε αυτά τα χαρακτηριστικά για να οικοδομήσουμε ένα αριθμό μοντέλων μηχανικής μάθησης ικανών να εντοπίσουν σατιρικές ψεύτικες ειδήσεις με ακρίβεια έως 98.6%. Η μελέτη εισάγει ένα νέο σύνολο δεδομένων (3185 άρθρα) από δύο αραβικές σατιρικές ιστοσελίδες ειδήσεων (`Al-Hudood' και `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') το οποίο αποτελείται από ψεύτικες ειδήσεις. Το πραγματικό σύνολο δεδομένων ειδήσεων αποτελείται από 3710 άρθρα που συλλέγονται από τρεις επίσημες ιστοσελίδες ειδήσεων: το BBC-Arabic, το CNN-Arabic και το Al-Jazeera news. Και τα δύο σύνολα δεδομένων αφορούν πολιτικά ζητήματα που σχετίζονται με τη Μέση Ανατολή.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A hamis hírek egyik nagyon gyakori fajtája a szatíra, amely egy híradó weboldal vagy egy online platform formájában jön létre, amely parodizálja a híres igazi hírügynökségeket, hogy létrehozza a valóság szarkasztikus verzióját. Az ilyen fajta hamis híreket gyakran terjesztik az egyének online platformjaikon, mivel sokkal erősebb hatással van a kritika kiadására, mint egy egyszerű üzenet. Ha azonban a szatirikus szöveget közösségi médián keresztül terjesztik forrásának megemlítése nélkül, összetéveszthető valódi hírrel. A tanulmány több feltáró elemzést végez az arab álhírek szatirikus tartalmú nyelvi tulajdonságainak azonosítására. Azt mutatja, hogy bár valódi híreket parodizál, az arab szatirikus híreknek lexiko-nyelvtani szinten megkülönböztető jellemzői vannak. Ezeket a funkciókat arra használjuk ki, hogy olyan gépi tanulási modelleket építsünk, amelyek akár 98,6%-os pontossággal azonosítani tudják a szatirikus hamis híreket. A tanulmány egy új adatkészletet (3185 cikk) mutat be, amely két arab szatirikus híroldalról (`Al-Hudood' és `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') származik, amely hamis hírekből áll. A valódi híradatkészlet 3710 cikkből áll, amelyeket három hivatalos híroldalról gyűjtöttek össze: a BBC-Arabic, a CNN-Arabic és az Al-Jazeera news. Mindkét adatkészlet a Közel-Kelettel kapcsolatos politikai kérdésekkel foglalkozik.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ერთი ძალიან საერთო ტიპი ტალქტური ნუზები არის სატიპი, რომელიც ახალგაზრულების საბეტატის ფორმაში ან ინტერნეტი პლატატიპში მოხდება, რომელიც პოპორიცია რესტალური ნუზის ამ ტიპის ტალქტიკური ნუტაციები ბევრად ადამიანები იყოს თავის ინტერნეტიური პლატატურებში, რადგან ის აქვს ძალიან ძალიან ეფექტიკა კრიტიკური გაგზავნა, ვიდრე საკუთ მაგრამ, როდესაც საცირური ტექსტი სოციალური მედიაზე გახსნილია, მისი წიგნის შესახებ, შეიძლება შეცდომა სინამდვილეებისთვის. ამ სწავლაში რამდენიმე განსხვავებული ანალიზები გავაკეთებს, რომ აპაბიური ტალქტური ახალგაზების ლუნგური საქატიური შესახებით განსაცნობა. ის ჩვენებს, რომ თუმცა ის პოპორიცია რეალური ნუზები, აპაბური სატირიკური ნუზები განსხვავებს ლექსიკჲ-გრამიკური დონეზე. ჩვენ გამოვიყენებთ ეს ფუნქციები, რომ მაქანის სწავლების რამდენიმე მოდელის შესაძლებლობად სატატიური ტალქტური ახალგაზების განსაცნობა 98.6%-ზე. სწავლად ახალი მონაცემების სექტი (3185 არექტიკები) გადატანა ორი აპაბიური სიატირიკური საბოლო საბოლო საბოლოდან (`ალ-ჰუედი' და `ალ-აჰრამი ალ-მექსიკური') რომელიც შექმნა რეალური ინფორმაციის მონაცემების საქაღალდე შექმნილი 3710 არქეტების შეფარდება, რომელიც სამუშაო ინფორმაციული სახლიდან შექმნილი: `BBC-Arabic', `CNN-Arabic' და `Al-Jazeera news'. ორივე მონაცემების კონფიგურაცია პოლიტიკური პრობლემების შესახებ ბრძელი თვალზე.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Un tipo molto comune di fake news è la satira che si presenta sotto forma di un sito di notizie o di una piattaforma online che parodia agenzie di stampa reali affidabili per creare una versione sarcastica della realtà. Questo tipo di fake news è spesso diffuso dagli individui sulle loro piattaforme online in quanto ha un effetto molto più forte nel fornire critiche che attraverso un messaggio semplice. Tuttavia, quando il testo satirico viene diffuso attraverso i social media senza menzionare la sua fonte, può essere scambiato per notizie reali. Questo studio conduce diverse analisi esplorative per identificare le proprietà linguistiche delle fake news arabe con contenuti satirici. Dimostra che sebbene parodia notizie reali, le notizie satiriche arabe hanno caratteristiche distintive a livello lessico-grammaticale. Sfruttamo queste funzionalità per costruire una serie di modelli di machine learning in grado di identificare fake news satiriche con una precisione fino al 98,6%. Lo studio introduce un nuovo dataset (3185 articoli) raschiato da due siti di notizie satiriche arabe (`Al-Hudood' e `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') che consiste in fake news. Il dataset delle notizie reali è costituito da 3710 articoli raccolti da tre siti ufficiali di notizie: la "BBC-Arabic", la "CNN-Arabic" e la "Al-Jazeera news". Entrambi i set di dati riguardano questioni politiche legate al Medio Oriente.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Еден многу обичен тип на лажни вести е сатир кој доаѓа во форма на веб-страница за вести или онлајн платформа која условува репутабилни новински агенции за создавање саркастична верзија на реалноста. Овој вид лажни вести честопати се шират од страна на поединци на нивните онлајн платформи бидејќи има многу посилен ефект во давањето критики отколку преку едноставна порака. Сепак, кога сатиричкиот текст се шири преку социјалните медиуми без да се спомне неговиот извор, може да се греши за вистинските вести. Оваа студија спроведува неколку експлоаторни анализи за идентификување на јазичните сопствености на лажните арапски вести со сатирична содржина. Истата покажува дека и покрај тоа што се пародизира вистински вести, арапските сатирични вести имаат различни карактеристики на лексико-граматично ниво. Ги искористуваме овие карактеристики за да изградиме голем број модели за машинско учење способни да идентификуваат сатирични лажни вести со точност од 98,6 отсто. Студијата претставува нови податоци (3185 статии) отстранети од две сатирични веб-сајтови на арапските вести („Ал-Худуд“ и „Ал-Ахрам Ал-Мексики“), кои се состојат од лажни вести. Вистинскиот новински податок се состои од 3710 статии собрани од три официјални новински сајтови: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic и Al-Jazeera. Двете податоци се загрижени за политичките прашања поврзани со Блискиот Исток.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Бір жалғыз жаңалық жаңалық түрі - сайт - жаңалық вебсайт немесе онлайн платформасында жаңалық жаңалық агенцияларды қайталау үшін саркастикалық нұсқасын құру үшін жаңалық жаңалық агенциял Бұл жалғыз жаңалық түрі онлайн платформаларында адамдар таратылады, себебі бұл жалғыз жаңалықтарды көбірек хабарлама арқылы критиктік көмегімен көбірек әсер етеді. Бірақ сатирикалық мәтін социалдық медиақтар көзіне айтпаса, ол шын жаңалықтар үшін қате болуы мүмкін. Бұл зерттеу сатирикалық мазмұнымен араб тілдік жаңалықтардың лингвистикалық қасиеттерін анықтау үшін бірнеше зерттеуші анализ істейді. Бұл шын жаңалықтарды пароциялау үшін, араб сатириялық жаңалықтар лексика- грамматикалық деңгейінде қасиеттерді таңдауға болады. Біз бұл мүмкіндіктерді машинаны оқыту үлгілерін құру үшін сатитикалық жаңалықтарды анықтауға мүмкіндік береді. 98,6% дегенге дейін. Бұл зерттеу жаңа деректер жинағын (3185 мақалалар) араб сатирикалық жаңалық сайттарынан (Ал- Худуд және «Ал- Ахрам Ал- Мексика» жалғыз жаңалық сайттарынан алып тастаған. Шынымен жаңалық деректер жинағында 3710 мақала бар: үш официальны жаңалық сайттардан, BBC-арабша, CNN-арабша және 'Al-Jazeera жаңалықтары'. Екі деректер жиындары Орталық Шығыс қатынасындағы саяси мәселелерімен қатынасыз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ml>ഒരു പൊതുവായ വാര്‍ത്തകം വ്യാജവാര്‍ത്തകള്‍ ഒരു സാധാരണ വ്യാജവാര്‍ത്ഥ്യത്തില്‍ വരുന്നതോ അല്ലെങ്കില്‍ ഒരു ഓണ്‍ലൈന്‍ പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോമില്‍ വരുന്നതോ അത ഈ കള്ള വാര്‍ത്തകള്‍ പലപ്പോഴും അവരുടെ ഓണ്‍ലൈന്‍ പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോമുകളില്‍ വ്യക്തികള്‍ വിതരണം ചെയ്യുന്നു. ഒരു നേരിട്ട സന്ദേശത്തില്‍ നിന്നും  എന്നാലും, സോഷ്യല്‍ മാധ്യമങ്ങളില്‍ നിന്നും അതിന്‍റെ സോര്‍സ്സ് പ്രസ്താവിക്കാതെ സാമൂഹ്യമായ പദാവലികള്‍ വിതരണം ചെയ ഈ പഠനത്തില്‍ കുറച്ച് പരിശോധന വിശദീകരണങ്ങള്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. അറബി ഭാഷ വ്യാജവാര്‍ത്തകളുടെ വിശേഷതകള്‍ പരി യഥാര്‍ത്ഥ വാര്‍ത്തകള്‍ പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്നുവെങ്കിലും അറബിയിലെ സങ്കീര്‍ത്തന വാര്‍ത്തകള്‍ ലെക്സിക്കോ ഗ്രാമാമ് We exploit these features to build a number of machine learning models capable of identifying satirical fake news with an accuracy of up to 98.6%.  ഈ പഠനത്തില്‍ ഒരു പുതിയ ഡാറ്റാസേറ്റ് (3185 ലേഖനങ്ങള്‍) പരിചയപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു. രണ്ട് അറബിക്ക് വിദ്യസന്തോഷവാര്‍ത്തകളുടെ ('അല്‍-ഹുദുദ്' അല്‍ 'അഹ്രാം അല്‍ -മെ യഥാര്‍ത്ഥ വാര്‍ത്തയുടെ ഡാറ്റാസറ്റ് 3710 പേരുകളില്‍ നിന്നും മൂന്നു ഓഫീസല്‍ വാര്‍ത്തകളുടെ സൈറ്റുകളില്‍ നിന്നും ശേഖരിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. ബി രണ്ട് ഡാറ്റാസറ്റുകളും മദ്ധ്യ കിഴക്കിനോട് ബന്ധപ്പെട്ട രാഷ്ട്രീയ പ്രശ്നങ്ങളെക്കുറിച</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Tip komuni ħafna ta’ a ħbarijiet foloz huwa satire li jiġi f’form a ta’ websajt tal-aħbarijiet jew pjattaforma onlajn li tipparatedixxi aġenziji tal-aħbarijiet reali li huma reputabbli biex to ħloq verżjoni sarkastika tar-realtà. Dan it-tip ta’ a ħbarijiet foloz spiss jinxtered minn individwi fuq il-pjattaformi onlajn tagħhom minħabba li għandu effett ferm aktar b’saħħtu fit-twassil ta’ kritika milli permezz ta’ messaġġ sempliċi. Madankollu, meta t-test satiriku jinxtered permezz tal-midja soċjali mingħajr ma jissemma s-sors tiegħu, jista’ jkun żbaljat għal aħbarijiet reali. Dan l-istudju jwettaq diversi analiżi esploratorji biex jidentifika l-proprjetajiet lingwistiċi tal-aħbarijiet foloz Għarab b’kontenut satiriku. Dan juri li minkejja li juri aħbarijiet reali, l-aħbarijiet satiriċi Għarab għandhom karatteristiċi distinti fuq il-livell lexikogrammatiku. Aħna nesfruttaw dawn il-karatteristiċi biex nibnu għadd ta’ mudelli ta’ tagħlim bil-magni li kapaċi jidentifikaw a ħbarijiet satiriċi foloz b’preċiżjoni sa 98,6 %. L-istudju jintroduċi sett ġdid ta’ dejta (3185 artikolu) skartat minn żewġ websajts tal-a ħbarijiet satiriċi Għarab (`Al-Hudood' u `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') li jikkonsisti f’aħbarijiet foloz. Is-sett tad-dejta reali tal-aħbarijiet jikkonsisti minn 3710 artikolu miġbura minn tliet siti uffiċjali tal-aħbarijiet: il-‘BBC-Arabic’, is-‘CNN-Arabic’ u l-‘Al-Jazeera news’. Iż-żewġ settijiet ta’ dejta huma kkonċernati bi kwistjonijiet politiċi relatati mal-Lvant Nofsani.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_lt>Viena iš labai įprastų suklastotų naujienų rūšių yra satiras, kuris atsiranda naujienų interneto svetainės arba interneto platformos form a, kuri parodo reputacines tikrąsias naujienų agentūras, kad sukurtų sarkastinę tikrovės versiją. Tokių suklastotų naujienų dažnai platina asmenys savo internetinėse platformose, nes jos daro daug didesnį poveikį kritikai nei paprasta žinia. Tačiau, kai satirinis tekstas skleidžiamas per socialinę žiniasklaidą nepaminėtas jo šaltinis, jis gali būti klaidingas dėl tikrų naujienų. Šiame tyrime atliekamos kelios tiriamosios analizės, skirtos nustatyti netikslių arabų naujienų, turinčių satirinį turinį, kalbines savybes. Tai rodo, kad nors ji parodo tikrąsias naujienas, arabų satirikos naujienos turi išskirtines savybes lexikogramatiniu lygmeniu. Mes naudojame šias savybes, kad sukurtume keletą mašinų mokymosi modelių, galinčių nustatyti satirinių suklastotų naujienų tikslumą iki 98,6 %. Tyrime pateikiamas naujas duomenų rinkinys (3185 straipsniai), išbrauktas iš dviejų arabų satirinių žinių interneto svetainių (`Al-Hudood' ir `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici'), sudarytų iš suklastotų žinių. The real news dataset consists of 3710 articles collected from three official news sites: the `BBC-Arabic', the `CNN-Arabic' and `Al-Jazeera news'.  Abu duomenų rinkiniai susiję su politiniais klausimais, susijusiais su Artimaisiais Rytais.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mn>Нэг хуурамч мэдээ бол мэдээллийн вебсайт эсвэл онлайн платформ юм. Энэ нь жинхэнэ мэдээллийн агентлагууд бодит байдлыг бүтээх шаргуу хувилбар юм. Энэ төрлийн хуурамч мэдээ ихэвчлэн онлайн платформуудын хувьд хэн нэгэн хүмүүс хуурамч байдаг. Учир нь энэ нь шууд мэдээллээс илүү хүчтэй нөлөөтэй. Гэвч, сэтгэл хөдлөлийн текст нийгмийн мэдээлэл дээр түүний эх үүсвэрийг хэлэхгүй нэмэгдүүлэхэд үнэндээ мэдээлэл дээр алдагдах боломжтой. Энэ судалгаанд олон судалгааны шинжилгээ хийдэг. Арабын хуурамч мэдээний хэл боловсруулалтын тухай хэлбэртэй мэдээллийг тодорхойлдог. Энэ нь жинхэнэ мэдээг шалгаж байгаа ч, Арабын зурагтай мэдээг лексико-грамматикийн түвшинд өөрчлөгдөж байна. Бид эдгээрийг машин суралцах загваруудыг ашиглаж 98.6% хүртэл зөв мэдээг олж мэдэх боломжтой машин суралцах загваруудыг ашиглаж байна. Судалгаанд шинэ өгөгдлийн санг (3185 баримт) Араб хоёр уйтгар мэдээллийн вебсайтаас (Аль-Худудуд, Ал-Ахрам Ал-Мексик) худлаа мэдээлэл бүрдсэн. Үнэндээ мэдээлэл өгөгдлийн сангууд нь 3710 өгөгдлийн сангуудын 3 официально мэдээлэл сайтаас цуглуулагдсан: BBC-Араб, CNN-Араб, Al-Jazeera мэдээлэл. Хоёр дахин өгөгдлийн сангууд нь Ойрхи дорноос холбогдсон улс төрийн асуудалтай хамааралтай.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Eit veldig vanleg type falske nyhetar er satir som kommer i ein form av ein nyhetseidt eller eit nettplattform som parodier gjennomsiktig reelle nyhetseigenskaper for å laga ein sarkastisk versjon av virkelighet. Denne typen falske nyhetar er ofte spredt av individuar på internetplattformene sine, sidan han har mykje sterkere effekt i å levera kritikk enn gjennom ei enkelt melding. Men når satriske teksten vert distribuert via sosiale medier utan å gjere kjelden sin, kan det vera feil i verkeleg nyhetar. Denne studien gjer fleire utforskingslane for å identifisera lingviske eigenskapane for falske nyhetar i arabisk med satriske innhald. Det viser at selv om det parodierer reale nyhetar, har arabiske satiske nyhetar forskjellige funksjonar på lexico- grammatisk nivå. Vi bruker desse funksjonane for å bygge mange maskinelæringsmodeller som kan identifisera satiriske falske nyhetar med nøyaktighet opp til 98,6%. Studiene introduserer eit nytt dataset (3185 artiklar) skrått frå to arabiske satiske nettsider («Al-Hudood» og «Al-Ahram Al-Mexici»), som inneheld falske nyhetar. Den verkelege nyhetsinnstillingane inneheld 3710 artiklar samla frå tre offisielle nyhetsinnstillingane: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic og Al-Jazeera-nyhetane. Begge datasett er bekymret på politiske problemer som er relatert til Middeløst.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ms>Satu jenis berita palsu yang sangat umum adalah satire yang datang dalam bentuk laman web berita atau platform online yang parodi agensi berita yang terkenal untuk mencipta versi sarkastik realiti. Jenis berita palsu ini sering disebarkan oleh individu di platform online mereka kerana ia mempunyai kesan yang lebih kuat dalam memberikan kritik daripada melalui mesej yang jelas. Namun, apabila teks satirik disebarkan melalui media sosial tanpa menyebut sumbernya, ia boleh salah dengan berita sebenar. This study conducts several exploratory analyses to identify the linguistic properties of Arabic fake news with satirical content.  Ia menunjukkan bahawa walaupun ia parodi berita sebenar, berita satirik Arab mempunyai ciri-ciri yang berbeza pada tahap leksiko-grammatik. Kami mengeksploitasi ciri-ciri ini untuk membina sejumlah model pembelajaran mesin yang mampu mengenali berita palsu satirik dengan ketepatan sehingga 98.6%. Ujian ini memperkenalkan set data baru (3185 artikel) yang dicabut dari dua laman web berita satirik Arab (`Al-Hudood' dan `Al-Ahram Al-Mexico') yang terdiri dari berita palsu. Set data berita sebenar terdiri dari 3710 artikel yang dikumpulkan dari tiga laman berita rasmi: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic dan Al-Jazeera. Kedua-dua set data berkaitan dengan isu politik yang berkaitan dengan Timur Tengah.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_pl>Bardzo powszechnym rodzajem fałszywych wiadomości jest satyra, która pojawia się w formie strony internetowej lub platformy internetowej, która parodiuje renomowane prawdziwe agencje informacyjne, aby stworzyć sarkastyczną wersję rzeczywistości. Ten rodzaj fałszywych wiadomości jest często rozpowszechniany przez osoby na ich platformach internetowych, ponieważ ma znacznie silniejszy wpływ na dostarczanie krytyki niż poprzez proste przekazy. Jednak kiedy tekst satyryczny jest rozpowszechniany za pośrednictwem mediów społecznościowych bez wspomnienia o jego źródle, można go pomylić z prawdziwą wiadomością. W niniejszym badaniu przeprowadzono kilka analiz eksploracyjnych w celu zidentyfikowania językowych właściwości arabskich fake news z zawartością satyryczną. Pokazuje, że chociaż parodiuje prawdziwe wiadomości, arabskie satyryczne wiadomości mają charakterystyczne cechy na poziomie leksykogramatycznym. Wykorzystujemy te funkcje do zbudowania szeregu modeli uczenia maszynowego zdolnych do identyfikacji satyrycznych fałszywych wiadomości z dokładnością do 98,6%. W opracowaniu wprowadzono nowy zestaw danych (artykuły 3185) zebrany z dwóch arabskich satyrycznych stron internetowych (`Al-Hudood' i `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') składający się z fałszywych wiadomości. Prawdziwy zestaw danych dotyczących wiadomości składa się z 3710 artykułów zebranych z trzech oficjalnych stron informacyjnych: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic i Al-Jazeera news. Oba zbiory danych dotyczą kwestii politycznych związanych z Bliskim Wschodem.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Un tip foarte comun de știri false este satira care vine sub forma unui site de știri sau a unei platforme online care parodizează agenții de știri reale de renume pentru a crea o versiune sarcastică a realității. Acest tip de știri false este adesea diseminat de către indivizi pe platformele lor online, deoarece are un efect mult mai puternic în livrarea criticilor decât printr-un mesaj simplu. Cu toate acestea, atunci când textul satiric este difuzat prin intermediul rețelelor sociale fără a menționa sursa sa, poate fi confundat cu știri reale. Acest studiu efectuează mai multe analize exploratorii pentru identificarea proprietăților lingvistice ale știrilor false arabe cu conținut satiric. Aceasta arată că, deși parodiează știri reale, știrile satirice arabe au trăsături distinctive la nivel lexico-gramatical. Exploatăm aceste caracteristici pentru a construi un număr de modele de machine learning capabile să identifice știrile false satirice cu o precizie de până la 98,6%. Studiul introduce un nou set de date (3185 articole) extras de pe două site-uri arabe de știri satirice (`Al-Hudood' și `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici'), care constă în știri false. Setul real de date de știri constă din 3710 articole colectate de pe trei site-uri oficiale de știri: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic și Al-Jazeera news. Ambele seturi de date se referă la probleme politice legate de Orientul Mijlociu.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Jedna vrlo zajednička vrsta lažnih vijesti je satir koji dolazi u oblik novinskog sajta ili internetske platforme koja parodiše republiraju prave novinske agencije kako bi stvorila sarkastičnu verziju realnosti. Ova vrsta lažnih vesti često se pojedinci šire na njihovim online platformama jer ima mnogo jači uticaj u donošenje kritike nego kroz jednostavnu poruku. Međutim, kada se satirski tekst širi putem društvenih medija bez spomena svog izvora, može se pogriješiti za prave vesti. Ova studija vodi nekoliko istraživačkih analiza kako bi identifikovali jezičke vlasništva lažnih vesti arapske lažne vesti sa satirskim sadržajem. Pokazuje da, iako parodiše prave vijesti, arapske satričke vijesti razlikuju karakteristike na leksiko-gramatičkom nivou. Koristimo te karakteristike da izgradimo broj modela za učenje mašine sposobnih da identifikujemo satrične lažne vijesti sa preciznošću do 98,6%. Istraživanje predstavlja novi set podataka (3185 članaka) koji se sklanjaju iz dva arapska satirijska vijesti (Al-Hudood) i 'Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') koji se sastoji od lažnih vijesti. Prava vijestinska seta podataka sastoji od 3710 članaka prikupljenih iz tri zvanična vijesti: BBC-Arapska, CNN-Arapska i 'Al-Jazeera vijesti'. Obje podatke se brinu o političkim pitanjima povezanim sa Bliskom istoku.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Warar been ah oo aad u caadi ah waa mid ku dhaqdhaqaaq ah oo ku imaanaya bogga internetka ee warbixinta ama jardiinada shabakadda oo ku qoran hay'adaha warbixinta ee runta ah si ay u sameeyaan warqad xaaladeed. Warkan been ah waxaa inta badan lagu kala faafiyaa qof ka mid ah shabakadahooda internetka, sababtoo ah waxay leedahay saameyn aad u adag in lagu soo dhiibo kriinimo ka sii badan warqad toos ah. Si kastaba ha ahaatee marka warqadda dhaqdhaqaaqa lagu faafiyo macluumaadka bulshada iyadoon la sheegin warbixinta xaqiiqa ah, waxaa khaldan kara. Waxbarashadan wuxuu sameeyaa baaritaano badan si ay u aqoonsadaan noocyada afka Carabiga ee warbixinta been ah oo ku qoran waxyaabaha lagu khiyaaneeyo. It shows that although it parodies real news, Arabic satirical news has distinguishing features on the lexico-grammatical level.  Waxaynu isticmaalnaa qaababkan si a an u dhisno qaabab waxbarasho oo machine ah oo awoodi karo in la caddeeyo warbixinta khiyaanada ah oo la saxday ilaa 98.6%. Waxbarashada waxaa lagu soo bandhigayaa sawir cusub (3185 articles) oo laga soo bandhigay labada bogagga warqada ee Carabiga (Al-Hudood) iyo `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') oo ku jira warar been ah. Taariikhda warbixinta ee runta ah waxaa ka mid ah 3710 warqadood oo laga soo ururiyey saddex meelood oo rasmi ah oo ay ka soo ururiyaan bogagga “BBC-Carabi”, “CNN-Carabi” iyo `Al-Jazeera News”. Labada database waxay ka welwelsan yihiin arimaha siyaasada ee la xiriira bari dhexe.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>En mycket vanlig typ av fake news är satir som kommer i form av en nyhetswebbplats eller en online-plattform som parodierar ansedda riktiga nyhetsbyråer för att skapa en sarkastisk version av verkligheten. Denna typ av falska nyheter sprids ofta av individer på deras onlineplattformar eftersom det har en mycket starkare effekt i att leverera kritik än genom ett okomplicerat budskap. Men när den satiriska texten sprids via sociala medier utan att ange källan kan den förväxlas med riktiga nyheter. Denna studie genomför flera undersökande analyser för att identifiera språkliga egenskaper hos arabiska fake news med satiriskt innehåll. Det visar att även om det parodierar verkliga nyheter, arabiska satiriska nyheter har särskiljande drag på lexiko-grammatisk nivå. Vi utnyttjar dessa funktioner för att bygga ett antal maskininlärningsmodeller som kan identifiera satiriska falska nyheter med en noggrannhet på upp till 98,6%. Studien introducerar ett nytt dataset (3185 artiklar) skrapat från två arabiska satiriska nyhetswebbplatser (`Al-Hudood' och `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') som består av fake news. Det verkliga nyhetsdatasetet består av 3710 artiklar som samlats in från tre officiella nyhetssajter: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic och Al-Jazeera news. Båda datauppsättningarna handlar om politiska frågor som rör Mellanöstern.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>ஒரு பொதுவான பொய் செய்திகள் ஒரு செய்தி வலைதளத்தில் அல்லது ஒரு இணைய தளம் வடிவத்தில் வருகிறது உண்மையான செய்தி நிறுவனங்களை பெருமைப் படுத்தும் ஒரு  பொய் செய்தி ஆயினும், அது அதன் மூலம் குறிப்பிடாமல் விளையாடும் போது, உண்மையான செய்திகளுக்கு தவறு செய்யலாம். இந்த ஆராய்ச்சியின் பொய் செய்திகளை விளையாட்டும் உள்ளடக்கங்களை கொண்டு அரபி பொய் செய்தியின் மொழிப்பு பண்புகள இது உண்மையான செய்திகளை குறிக்கும் போதும், அரேபிய செய்திகள் லெக்சிகோ-கிராமாட்டிக் மட்டத்தில் உள்ள தன்மைகளை வேறுபட நாம் இந்த குணங்களை பயன்படுத்தி சில இயந்திரம் கற்றுக்கொள்ள மாதிரிகளை உருவாக்குவதற்கு முடியும் வேடிக்கையான பொய் செய்தி The study introduces a new dataset (3185 articles) scraped from two Arabic satirical news websites (`Al-Hudood' and `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') which consists of fake news.  உண்மையான செய்தி தகவல் அமைப்பு 3710 கட்டுரைகள் மூன்று அரசியல் செய்தி தளங்களிலிருந்து சேகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது 'பிபிசி- அரபி', சிஎன்ன்- அரபி மற்ற இரண்டு தரவு அமைப்புகளும் மத்திய கிழக்குத் தொடர்புடைய அரசியல் பிரச்சனைகளை பற்றி கவலைப்படுகி</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_si>ගොඩක් සාමාන්‍ය වාර්තාවක් තමයි වාර්තාවක් වැඩසටහනයක් නැත්නම් අන්තර්ජාන ප්ලේටෆ්ටෝම් එකක් වෙනවා ඒක ඇත්තම වාර්තාවක මේ වගේ බොරු ආරංචියක් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් විශේෂ කරනවා ඔවුන්ගේ ඇන්ලයින් ප්ලේටෆෝටර්ම් වලින් ප්‍රතිකාරයෙන් විශ නමුත්, සාමාජික මිඩියාවෙන් සාමාජික මාධ්‍යමයෙන් විශේෂ කළොත්, ඒක ඇත්ත ආරංචියක් වැරදියි. මේ පරීක්ෂණය විශේෂ විශ්ලේෂණයක් වෙනුවෙන් අරාබික් බොරු වාර්තාවේ භාෂාවික විශේෂ විශේෂණයක්  ඒක පෙන්වන්නේ ඒක ඇත්ත ආරංචික ආරංචික ආරංචික ආරංචික ආරංචික ආරංචියක් ලෙක්සිකෝ-ග්‍රැමැති අපි මේ විශේෂතාවක් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා මැෂින් ඉගෙන ගන්න පුළුවන් මෝඩේල් ගොඩක් නිර්මාණය කරගන්න සක්ෂිත විදියට 98. The study presents a new data set (3195 texts) scraped from both Arab satirical news webwebwebwebwebwebs (`Al-Hudood' and `Al-Ohramal-Mexica') that is composed of fax news. ඇත්ත ආරංචික දත්ත සෙට් එක්ක 3710 පිළිපත් තුන්දෙනුවෙන්, සාධාරික ආරංචික තුන්දෙනුවෙන්, `BBC-Arab', 'CNN-Arab' සහ `Al-Jazeera දෙන්නම දත්ත සැට් දෙන්නම ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා මධ්‍යම පුරුද්ධයෙන් සම්බන්ධ විදියට.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>ایک بہت معمول نویس کی طرح یہ ہے کہ ایک نویس ویب سایت یا آنلاین پلٹورم کی شکل میں آتی ہے جس کی پاروڈی کرتی ہے کہ حقیقت کے سارکاسٹ ویب سائٹ بنانے کے لئے واقعی نویس آژانسوں کو پاروڈی کرتی ہے۔ یہ غلط خبروں کی طرح اکثر افراد ان کے آنلاین پٹروم پر پھیلائے جاتے ہیں کیونکہ اس کے لئے ایک سیدھے پیغام کے ذریعہ سے زیادہ سخت اثر ہے۔ لیکن جب سوسیل میڈیا کے ذریعے اس کے سورج کے ذریعے بغیر مفصل کے متن پھیلائے جاتے ہیں، یہ حقیقی خبر کے لئے غلط ہو سکتا ہے. یہ مطالعہ بہت سی تحقیقات کی تحقیقات کرتا ہے کہ عربی جھوٹی خبروں کی زبان تعریفیں معلوم کریں جن کے ذریعہ مذہب کے ساتھ۔ یہ دکھاتا ہے کہ اگرچہ وہ واقعی خبریں پاروڈی کرتا ہے، عربی سیٹریک خبریں لکسیکو-گراماتیکی سطح پر فرق کرتی ہیں۔ ہم نے ان وینٹیوں کو استعمال کر رکھا ہے کہ 98.6% تک پہچان سکتے ہیں مہینے کی تعلیم کی موڈل بنانے کے لئے۔ اس مطالعہ میں ایک نئی ڈاٹ سٹ (3185 articles) معلوم کرتی ہے جو دو عربی سایٹریک نویس سٹی (Al-Hudood) اور Al-Ahram Al-Mexici سے پھینک دی گئی ہے۔ حقیقی خبر ڈیٹ سٹ میں 3710 لکھے ہوئے تین رسمی خبر سائٹوں سے جمع کئے گئے ہیں: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic اور Al-Jazeera خبریں۔ دونوں ڈاٹ سٹ متوسط مشرق کے معاملہ میں سیاسی مسائل سے مشغول ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bitta oddiy xabar turi - yangilik tovush tovushi yoki online platformi shaklida keladi. Bu haqiqiqiy sarkastik versiyasini yaratish uchun haqiqiqiy xabar organislarini ajratish mumkin. Bu ko'pincha fake news odamlar tarmoq platformlaridagi odamlar bilan ajratiladi, chunki u toʻgʻri xabar yordamida criticism yordamida ko'p ishlatish mumkin. Lekin, bu haqiqiqiy xabar uchun xabar emas. Bu o'qituvni ko'plab o'qituvchi tarkibi arabdagi falsk news xossalarini aniqlashga bajaradi. Ko'rsatish mumkin, agar bu haqiqiqiy xabarlarni ko'rsatish mumkin, arabcha kekkizlik xabarlari Leksika grammatik darajadagi xususiyatlarni o'zgartiradi. We exploit these features to build a number of machine learning models capable of identifying satirical fake news with an accuracy of up to 98.6%.  Арабча маълумотлар (3185 мақолотлар) жуфт маълумотлардан (Al-Hudood ва `Al-Ahram Al-Meksik') янги маълумотни ўрнатади. Xato xabar maʼlumoti uchta xabari sahifadagi 3710 maqoladan iborat: BBC-arab, CNN-arab va Al-Jazeera хабарлари. Икки маълумот тафсирлари ўртасидаги сиёсий маслаҳатларга эга.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Một kiểu tin giả rất phổ biến là châm biếm xuất hiện bằng một trang web tin tức hoặc một kênh trực tuyến sản xuất những hãng tin tức có uy tín để tạo ra một phiên bản mỉa mai của thực tại. Loại tin giả này thường được phát tán bởi những cá nhân trên bục phát biểu trực tuyến vì nó có tác động mạnh mẽ hơn nhiều khi đưa ra những lời phê bình thông điệp đơn giản. Tuy nhiên, khi văn bản châm biếm được phát tán qua các phương tiện xã hội mà không cần nhắc tới nguồn gốc của nó, nó có thể bị nhầm lẫn với tin tức thật sự. Nghiên cứu này tiến hành nhiều nghiên cứu thăm dò để xác định tính chất ngôn ngữ của tin giả tiếng Ả Rập bằng nội dung châm biếm. Nó cho thấy mặc dù nó chế tạo được tin tức thật sự, tin buồn mỉa Á Á Rập có yếu tố đặc biệt về ngôn ngữ. Chúng tôi tận dụng những tính năng này để xây dựng một số mô hình học máy có khả năng nhận diện tin giả châm biếm với độ chính xác cao tới tận tê-96. The study introduced a new dataset (185 articles) raw from two Arab satirical news website ('Al-Hudood'và'Al-Ahram Al-Mexizi') which consists of fake news. The real news dataset is of 310 articles thu thập từ ba tin tức chính thức: the'BBC-Ả Rập', the'CNN-Ả Rập'và'Al-Jazeera news'. Cả hai bộ dữ liệu đều liên quan đến các vấn đề chính trị liên quan đến Trung Đông.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Един много често срещан вид фалшиви новини е сатира, която идва под формата на новинарски сайт или онлайн платформа, която пародира реномирани реални новинарски агенции, за да създаде саркастична версия на реалността. Този вид фалшиви новини често се разпространяват от физически лица на техните онлайн платформи, тъй като имат много по-силен ефект при отправянето на критики, отколкото чрез просто послание. Когато сатиричният текст обаче се разпространява чрез социалните медии, без да се споменава източника му, той може да бъде объркан с реални новини. Проучването провежда няколко проучвателни анализи за идентифициране на езиковите свойства на арабските фалшиви новини със сатирично съдържание. Тя показва, че макар да пародира реалните новини, арабските сатирични новини имат отличителни черти на лексико-граматическо ниво. Ние използваме тези функции, за да изградим редица модели за машинно обучение, способни да идентифицират сатирични фалшиви новини с точност до 98,6%. Изследването представя нов набор от данни (3185 статии), изстъргани от два арабски сатирични новинарски уебсайта ("Ал-Худуд" и "Ал-Ахрам Ал-Мексичи"), който се състои от фалшиви новини. Истинският набор от данни за новините се състои от 3710 статии, събрани от три официални новинарски сайта: Би Би Си Арабски, Си Ен Ен Арабски и Ал Джазира новини. И двата набора от данни са свързани с политически въпроси, свързани с Близкия изток.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Een veel voorkomende vorm van nepnieuws is satire die komt in de vorm van een nieuwswebsite of een online platform dat gerenommeerde echte nieuwsbureaus parodieert om een sarcastische versie van de werkelijkheid te creëren. Dit soort nepnieuws wordt vaak verspreid door individuen op hun online platforms omdat het een veel sterker effect heeft in het leveren van kritiek dan door middel van een eenvoudige boodschap. Wanneer de satirische tekst echter wordt verspreid via sociale media zonder vermelding van de bron, kan het verward worden met echt nieuws. Dit onderzoek voert verschillende verkennende analyses uit om de taalkundige eigenschappen van Arabisch fake news met satirische inhoud te identificeren. Het toont aan dat hoewel het echt nieuws parodieert, Arabisch satirisch nieuws onderscheidende kenmerken heeft op lexico-grammaticaal niveau. We gebruiken deze functies om een aantal machine learning modellen te bouwen die satirisch nepnieuws kunnen identificeren met een nauwkeurigheid van 98,6%. Het onderzoek introduceert een nieuwe dataset (3185 artikelen) geschraapt van twee Arabische satirische nieuwswebsites (`Al-Hudood' en `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') die bestaat uit fake news. De echte nieuwsdata bestaat uit 3710 artikelen verzameld op drie officiële nieuwssites: de BBC-Arabic, het CNN-Arabic en het Al-Jazeera nieuws. Beide datasets hebben betrekking op politieke vraagstukken in verband met het Midden-Oosten.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>En meget almindelig type falske nyheder er satire, som kommer i form af en nyhedshjemmeside eller en online platform, der parodierer velrenommerede ægte nyhedsbureauer for at skabe en sarkastisk version af virkeligheden. Denne type falske nyheder formidles ofte af enkeltpersoner på deres online platforme, da det har en meget stærkere effekt i at levere kritik end gennem en ligetil besked. Men når den satiriske tekst formidles via sociale medier uden at nævne kilden, kan den forveksles med rigtige nyheder. Denne undersøgelse gennemfører flere eksperimenterende analyser for at identificere de sproglige egenskaber af arabisk fake news med satirisk indhold. Det viser, at selv om det parodierer virkelige nyheder, arabiske satiriske nyheder har kendetegn på det leksiko-grammatiske niveau. Vi udnytter disse funktioner til at opbygge en række maskinlæringsmodeller, der er i stand til at identificere satiriske fake news med en nøjagtighed på op til 98,6%. Undersøgelsen introducerer et nyt datasæt (3185 artikler), der er skrabet fra to arabiske satiriske nyhedshjemmesider (`Al-Hudood' og `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici'), som består af fake news. Det reelle nyhedsdatasæt består af 3710 artikler indsamlet fra tre officielle nyhedssider: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic og Al-Jazeera news. Begge datasæt beskæftiger sig med politiske spørgsmål relateret til Mellemøsten.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Eine sehr verbreitete Art von Fake News ist Satire, die in Form einer Nachrichtenwebsite oder einer Online-Plattform kommt, die seriöse echte Nachrichtenagenturen parodiert, um eine sarkastische Version der Realität zu schaffen. Diese Art von Fake News wird oft von Einzelpersonen auf ihren Online-Plattformen verbreitet, da sie eine viel stärkere Wirkung bei der Abgabe von Kritik hat als durch eine einfache Nachricht. Wenn der satirische Text jedoch über soziale Medien verbreitet wird, ohne seine Quelle zu erwähnen, kann er mit echten Nachrichten verwechselt werden. Diese Studie führt mehrere explorative Analysen durch, um die sprachlichen Eigenschaften arabischer Fake News mit satirischen Inhalten zu identifizieren. Es zeigt, dass arabische satirische Nachrichten, obwohl sie echte Nachrichten parodieren, auf lexikogrammatischer Ebene Unterscheidungsmerkmale aufweisen. Wir nutzen diese Funktionen, um eine Reihe von Machine Learning Modellen zu entwickeln, die satirische Fake News mit einer Genauigkeit von bis zu 98,6% identifizieren können. Die Studie stellt einen neuen Datensatz (3185 Artikel) vor, der von zwei arabischen satirischen Nachrichtenseiten (`Al-Hudood' und `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') geschraubt wurde, der aus Fake News besteht. Der eigentliche Nachrichtendatensatz besteht aus 3710 Artikeln, die von drei offiziellen Nachrichtenseiten gesammelt wurden: der BBC-Arabic, der CNN-Arabic und der Al-Jazeera News. Beide Datensätze beschäftigen sich mit politischen Fragen im Nahen Osten.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Satu jenis berita palsu yang sangat umum adalah satire yang datang dalam bentuk situs berita atau platform online yang parodi agensi berita yang terkenal untuk menciptakan versi sarkastik realitas. Tipe berita palsu ini sering disebarkan oleh individu di platform online mereka karena itu memiliki efek yang jauh lebih kuat dalam memberikan kritik daripada melalui pesan yang sederhana. Namun, ketika teks satiris disebarkan melalui media sosial tanpa menyebutkan sumbernya, itu bisa salah dengan berita nyata. Studi ini melakukan beberapa analisis eksplorator untuk mengidentifikasi properti bahasa berita palsu Arab dengan isi satiris. Hal ini menunjukkan bahwa meskipun itu parodi berita nyata, berita satiris Arab memiliki ciri-ciri yang membedakan di tingkat lexico-grammatical. Kami mengeksploitasi fitur-fitur ini untuk membangun sejumlah model belajar mesin yang mampu mengidentifikasi berita palsu satiris dengan ketepatan sampai 98,6%. Studi ini memperkenalkan dataset baru (3185 artikel) yang dicabut dari dua situs web berita satiris Arab (`Al-Hudood' dan `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') yang terdiri dari berita palsu. Set data berita nyata terdiri dari 3710 artikel yang dikumpulkan dari tiga situs berita resmi: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic dan Al-Jazeera. Kedua dataset berkaitan dengan masalah politik yang berhubungan dengan Timur Tengah.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>یک نوع اخبار خیلی مشترک است که در یک شکل وب‌سایت اخبار یا یک پلاکتر آنلاین می‌آید که آژانس‌های خبر واقعی را معروف می‌کند تا نسخه‌ی سارکاستیک واقعیت را ایجاد کند. این نوع خبرهای دروغگویی اغلب توسط فردی ها روی platformهای آنلاین ایشان پراکنده می شوند، زیرا تاثیر بسیار قوی در انتقاد کردن انتقاد بیشتر از توسط پیغام ساده‌ای دارد. با این حال، وقتی متن مذاکره با وسیله رسانه‌های اجتماعی بدون اشاره به منبعش پراکنده می‌شود، می‌تواند برای اخبار واقعی اشتباه شود. این مطالعه چندین تحقیقات تحقیقاتی را انجام می دهد تا ویژه‌های زبان‌شناسی خبرهای دروغ عربی را با محتوای مذاکره شناسایی کند. این نشان می‌دهد که اخبار واقعی را در حالی که آزمایش می‌کند، اخبار مذاکره عربی در سطح لکسیکو گراماتیک تفاوت می‌دهد. ما این ویژگی‌ها را استفاده می‌کنیم تا بسازیم بسیاری از مدل‌های یادگیری ماشین که قادر به شناسایی اخبار مذاکره‌ای با دقیق تا 98.6 درصد است. این مطالعه، مجموعه داده‌های جدید (3185 articles) را معرفی می‌کند که از دو وب‌سایت‌های خبرهای مذاکره‌ای عربی (Al-Hudood) و Al-Ahram Al-Mexici است. مجموعه داده‌های واقعی از ۳۳۰ مقاله‌ای است که از سه سایت‌های خبری رسمی جمع شده‌اند: بریسی-عربی، بریسی-عربی و بریسی-عربی. هر دو مجموعه اطلاعات نگران مسائل سیاسی که مربوط به شرق میانه هستند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Aina moja ya habari potofu sana ni uchochezi ambao unakuja katika a in a ya tovuti ya habari au jukwaa la mtandaoni ambalo linaonyesha taasisi za habari zinazosifu kweli ili kutengeneza toleo la kejeli la ukweli. Habari hizi za uongo mara nyingi zinasambazwa na watu kwenye jukwaa lao la mtandaoni kwa sababu in a athari kubwa zaidi ya kutoa ukosoaji kuliko kupitia ujumbe wa moja kwa moja. Hata hivyo, pale ujumbe wa kejeli utasambazwa kupitia mitandao ya kijamii bila kutaja chanzo chake, unaweza kuwa kosa kwa habari halisi. Utafiti huu unafanya uchambuzi kadhaa wa uchunguzi ili kutambua utaalamu wa lugha za habari bandia za Kiarabu na maudhui ya kejeli. Inaonyesha kwamba ingawa inaweka taarifa halisi, habari za kejeli za Kiarabu zinatofautiana na vipengele vya kiuchumi vya lexico. Tunatumia vipengele hivi ili kujenga miundo kadhaa ya kujifunza mashine yenye uwezo wa kutambua habari za uongo za kejeli kwa uhakika wa asilimia 98.6. Utafiti huo unaonyesha seti mpya ya taarifa (makala 3185) iliyochapishwa kutoka tovuti mbili za habari za kejeli za Kiarabu ('Al-Hudood' na 'Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') ambayo ina habari potofu. Taarifa halisi ya habari zinajumuisha makala 3710 zilizokusanywa kutoka tovuti tatu za habari:  ‘BBC-Kiarabu’ ‘CNN-Kiarabu’ na ‘habari za Al-Jazeera’. Taasisi hizo mbili zinahusiana na masuala ya kisiasa yanayohusiana na Mashariki ya Kati.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Bir ýalňyş täp ýalňyş haberler bolan satyrdyr. Bu täzelikleriň habatynyň ýada internet platformasynda, parodyşlar hakyky haberler agenciýalaryny bejermek üçin bir sarkastik wersiýa döretýär. Bu ýalňyş haberler köplenç online platformalarynda adamlaryň tarapyndan daşyrylýar, sebäbi ol kritiýa düzgün mesaj bilen düzgün hatlary saýlamak üçin has güçli täsiri bar. Ýöne, soňky metin sosyal medýýatlar tarapyndan özüniň çeşmesini aýtmadan aýdylan bolsa, bu hakyky täzelikleriň üçin ýalňyşlyk bolup biler. Bu araşdyrma satyk mazmunlary bilen arabça sahte täzelikleriniň lingwistiki hasaplamak üçin birnäçe gezek analyzasyny edýär. Bu hatlar gerçek haberleri taýýarlap bilýändigini görkezýär. Arapça sazly haberler leksik-gramatik derejede hatlary tapawutlaýar. Biz bu özellikleri satyn ýalňyşlyk bilen 98.6% ýagdaýa çenli maşyny öwrenmek nusgalaryny gurmak üçin ulanýarys. Bu araşdyrma ýalňyş haberler bolan iki arapça satçylyk habatyndan tarapylan täze bir dataseti (3185 sany) goşulýar. Haýyp maglumatlar 3 resmi haberdan toplanýan 3710 sany meňzeýär: `BBC-Arabça', 'CNN-Arabça' we `Al-Jazeera habarlar'. Iki sany sany Orta Gündogar bilen ilgili syýasy meselelere alada edýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Een baie gemeenskap tipe falske nuus is satir wat kom in 'n vorm van 'n nuus webwerk of 'n online platform a wat parodier reël nuus agencies herbenaamd om 'n sarkasiese weergawe van realiteit te skep. Hierdie tipe falske nuus is dikwels versprei deur individue op hul aanlyn platforme omdat dit 'n baie sterker effek het in die laai van kritike as deur 'n eenvoudige boodskap. Maar wanneer die satirike teks deur sosiale media versprei word sonder om sy bron te mention, kan dit verkeerd wees vir regte nuus. Hierdie studie doen verskeie ondersoek analiseerdes om die lingwisiese eienskappe van Arabiese falske nuus te identifiseer met satirike inhoud. Dit wys dat, alhoewel dit regte nuus parodier, het Arabiese satirike nuus die eienskappe op die lexico-grammatiese vlak uitdeling. Ons gebruik hierdie funksies om 'n aantal masjien leer modele te bou wat kan identifiseer satirike falske nuus met 'n presies tot 98,6%. Die studie introduseer 'n nuwe datastel (3185 artikels) wat van twee Arabiese satirike nuuswebwerke geskryf word (`Al-Hudood' en `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') wat bestaan van falske nuus. Die regte nuusdatumset bestaan van 3710 artikels wat van drie offisiele nuuswebwerke versamel is: die "BBC-Arabic", die "CNN-Arabic" en "Al-Jazeera nuus". Beide datastelle is bekommerd met politieke probleme wat met die Middelooste verwante is.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hr>Jedna vrlo zajednička vrsta lažnih vijesti je satir koji dolazi u oblik vijestinske stranice ili internetske platforme koja parodija poznaje prave vijestinske agencije kako bi stvorila sarkastičnu verziju realnosti. Ova vrsta lažnih vijesti često se pojedinci šire na njihovim online platformama jer ima mnogo jači učinak u donošenju kritike nego prostom porukom. Međutim, kada se satirski tekst širi putem društvenih medija bez spominjanja svog izvora, može se pogriješiti za prave vijesti. U ovom ispitivanju vodi nekoliko istraživačkih analiza kako bi identifikovali jezičke vlasništva lažnih vijesti arapske lažne vijesti sa satirskim sadržajem. Pokazuje da, iako parodijira prave vijesti, arapske satirijske vijesti razlikuju karakteristike na leksikogramatičkoj razini. Koristimo te karakteristike da izgradimo broj modela za učenje strojeva sposobnih identificiranja satirskih lažnih vijesti sa preciznošću do 98,6%. Istraživanje predstavlja novu kompletu podataka (3185 članaka) izvedenu iz dva arapske satričke vijesti (Al-Hudood i Al-Ahram Al-Mexici), koja se sastoji od lažnih vijesti. Prava vijestinska seta podataka sastoji od 3710 članaka prikupljenih iz tri službena vijesti: BBC-Arapske, CNN-Arapske i 'Al-Jazeera vijesti'. Obje podatke su zabrinute političkim pitanjima povezanim s Bliskom istoku.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_ko>매우 흔히 볼 수 있는 가짜 뉴스는 풍자이다. 뉴스 사이트나 온라인 플랫폼의 형식으로 등장하여 유명한 진실한 뉴스 기구를 모방하여 풍자판의 현실을 창조한다.이런 가짜 뉴스는 보통 개인이 온라인 플랫폼에서 전파하는데 직접적인 정보에 비해 비판을 전달하는 효과가 훨씬 강하기 때문이다.그러나 풍자 텍스트가 소셜 미디어를 통해 전파되고 그 출처를 언급하지 않을 때 진정한 뉴스로 오인될 수 있다.본 연구는 풍자적인 내용을 포함하는 아랍 가짜 뉴스의 언어 특징을 탐색적 분석했다.이것은 비록 진실한 뉴스를 모방하지만 아랍 풍자 뉴스는 어휘 문법 차원에서 독특한 특징을 가지고 있음을 나타낸다.우리는 이러한 특징을 이용하여 많은 기계 학습 모델을 구축하여 풍자적인 가짜 뉴스를 식별할 수 있는데 정확도는 98.6%에 달한다.이 연구는 두 아랍어 풍자 뉴스 사이트('Al Hudood'와'Al Ahram Al Mexici')에서 추출한 새로운 데이터 세트(3천185편의 글)를 도입했다.리얼뉴스 데이터집은 3개 공식 뉴스 사이트에서 수집한 3710편의 기사로 구성돼 있다. 'BBC 아랍어', 'CNN 아랍어', '반도 텔레비전 뉴스'.이 두 데이터 집합은 모두 중동과 관련된 정치 문제와 관련된다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_am>የሐሰት ዜና አንድ የተለየ የሐሰት ዓይነት ነው፡፡ ይህ ዓይነት የሐሰት ዜና ብዙ ጊዜ በጋዜጠኞች ላይ በመስመር ፕሮፎርማኖቻቸው ይለካል፡፡ ነገር ግን የፀሐይ ጽሑፉ በማኅበራዊ ሚዲያ በተለየ ጊዜ፣ የመጀመሪያው ዜና ስህተት ይችላል፡፡ ይሄ ትምህርት በሐሰተኛ ዜና ላይ በሐሰት ጥያቄ የቋንቋ እውስቶችን ለማግኘት ብዙዎችን የሚያሳውቃል፡፡ እውነተኛ ዜና ምንም እንኳ ቢገልጽ አረብኛ የሳታሪክ ዜና በሊክሲኮ-ግራማቲ ደረጃ ላይ የተለየ ነው፡፡ የሐሰት ዜና በቁጥር 98.6 በመቶ የሚችሉትን የሐሰት ዜናዎችን ለማግኘት የሚችሉትን ብዙዎችን መሳሪያዎች ለመሥራት እናደርጋለን፡፡ ትምህርት የሐሰት ዜና ከሁለቱ አረብኛ የጣዖት ዜና ድረ ገጾች (አል-Hudood እና `አል-አሕራም አል-ሜክሲ› የተለየ አዲስ ዳታተርጉስን (3185 ጽሑፎች) ያስተካክላል፡፡ እውነተኛው የዜና ዳርተሮች ከሦስት ባለሥልጣናት ዜና ገጾች የተሰበሰቡ 3710 ጽሑፎች ናቸው ‹BBC-አረቢያ›› የCNN-ዐረብኛ እና ‹አል-ያዜራ ዜና›› ሁለቱም የዳታ ሰርቨሮች መካከል ምሥራቅ የተገኘ የፖለቲካ ጉዳዮች ናቸው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>একটি খুব সাধারণ মিথ্যা সংবাদ হচ্ছে বিদ্রূপ যা একটি সংবাদ ওয়েবসাইট বা একটি অনলাইন প্ল্যাটফর্মে এসেছে যা বাস্তবতার বাস্তবতার একটি বিদ্রূপ সংস্ এই ধরনের মিথ্যা সংবাদ প্রায়শই তাদের অনলাইন প্ল্যাটফর্মে ব্যক্তিদের প্রচার করেছে, কারণ সোজা বার্তার মাধ্যমে সমালোচনা প্রদানে তবে যখন বিদ্রোহী লেখাটি সোশ্যাল মিডিয়ার মাধ্যমে প্রচার করা হয় তার উৎস উল্লেখ করা ছাড়াই, এটা সত্যিকারের সংবাদের জন এই গবেষণা বেশ কয়েকটি তদন্ত বিশ্লেষণ করেছে যাতে আরবী ভাষার ভাষার বৈশিষ্ট্য পরিচয় করার জন্য এবং বিদ্রূপ বিষয়বস্তু নিয়ে  এটি দেখাচ্ছে যে যদিও এটি সত্যিকারের সংবাদ প্রদান করে, তবুও আরবী বিদ্রোহীত সংবাদ লেক্সিকো গ্রামাটিক্যাল পর্যায়ে বিভা আমরা এই বৈশিষ্ট্য ব্যবহার করি বেশ কয়েকটি মেশিন শিক্ষা মডেল তৈরি করতে যারা বিদ্রূপ বিভ্রান্ত সংবাদ চিহ্নিত করতে পারে যা ৯৮. এই গবেষণা দুই আরবী ব্যাসারিক সংবাদ ওয়েবসাইট ('আল-হুদুদ' এবং 'আল-আহরাম আল-মেক্সিকি') থেকে সংক্রান্ত একটি নতুন ডাটাসেট (৩১৫৫ প্রবন্ধ) প্রকাশ করেছে, যা মি সত্যিকারের সংবাদ তথ্যের মধ্যে ৩৭০ প্রবন্ধ রয়েছে: বিবিসি-আরবী, 'সিএনএন-আরবী' এবং 'আল-জাজিরা সংবাদ। Both datasets are concerned with political issues related to the Middle East.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Շատ ընդհանուր կեղծ նորությունների մի տեսակը սաթիրը է, որը գալիս է նորությունների վեբ կայքի կամ առցանց հարթակի տեսքով, որն արտահայտում է հայտնի իրական նորությունների գործակալությունները իրականության սարկաստական տարբերակը ստեղծելու համար: Այս տեսակի կեղծ նորությունները հաճախ տարածվում են անհատների կողմից իրենց առցանց պլատֆորմերում, քանի որ այն շատ ավելի ուժեղ ազդեցություն ունի քննադատություն տալիս, քան պարզ հաղորդագրության միջոցով: Սակայն, երբ սաթիրիկական տեքստը տարածվում է սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցների միջոցով առանց նշելու դրա աղբյուրը, այն կարող է սխալ լինել իրական նորությունների համար: This study conducts several exploratory analyses to identify the linguistic properties of Arabic fake news with satirical content.  Այն ցույց է տալիս, որ չնայած նրան, որ այն պարոնիա է տալիս իրական նորություններին, արաբական սաթիրիկական նորությունները տարբերականներ ունեն լեքսիկո-գրամատիկ մակարդակում: Մենք օգտագործում ենք այս առանձնահատկությունները մեքենային ուսումնասիրության մի շարք մոդելներ կառուցելու համար, որոնք կարողանում են հայտնաբերել կեղծ աստիրական նորությունները մինչև 98.6 տոկոսի ճշգրտությամբ: Հետազոտությունը ներկայացնում է նոր տվյալների համակարգ (3185 հոդվածներ), որը վերացված է երկու արաբական սաթիրիկական նորությունների վեբկայքից (`Ալ-Հուդուդ' և `Ալ-Ահարամ Ալ-Մեքսիկի'), որոնք կազմված են կեղծ նորություններից: Իրական նորությունների տվյալները կազմված են 3710 հոդվածից, որոնք հավաքվել են երեք պաշտոնական նորությունների կայքերից՝ BBC-Արաբեն, CNN-Արաբեն և al-Ջազերա նորություններից: Երկու տվյալների համակարգերը մտահոգված են Միջին Արևելքի քաղաքական հարցերով:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_sq>Një lloj i zakonshëm i lajmeve të rreme është satiri i cili vjen në form ë të një uebsajti të lajmeve apo një platform ë online që paraqes agjensitë e famshme të lajmeve të vërteta për të krijuar një version sarkastik të realitetit. Ky lloj lajmesh të rreme shpesh përhapet nga individët në platformet e tyre online pasi ka një efekt shumë më të fortë në dhënien e kritikave sesa nëpërmjet një mesazhi të thjeshtë. Megjithatë, kur teksti satirik shpërndahet nëpërmjet mediave shoqërore pa përmendur burimin e tij, mund të gabohet me lajme të vërteta. Ky studim kryen disa analiza eksploruese për të identifikuar pronësitë gjuhësore të lajmeve të rreme arabe me përmbajtje satirike. Ajo tregon se megjithëse paraqet lajme të vërteta, lajmet satirike arabe kanë karakteristika të dalluar në nivelin lexiko-grammatik. Ne i shfrytëzojmë këto karakteristika për të ndërtuar një numër modelesh mësimi automatik të aftë për të identifikuar lajme të rreme satirike me një saktësi deri në 98.6%. Studimi fut një grup të ri të dhënash (3185 artikuj) të shkëputur nga dy faqet e lajmeve satirike arabe (`Al-Hudood' dhe `Al-Ahram Al-Meksiki') që përbëhet nga lajme të rreme. Të dhënat e vërteta të lajmeve përbëhen nga 3710 artikuj të mbledhur nga tre faqe zyrtare të lajmeve: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic dhe Al-Jazeera. Të dy grupet e të dhënave janë të shqetësuara me çështje politike lidhur me Lindjen e Mesme.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_cs>Jedním z velmi běžných typů falešných zpráv je satira, která přichází ve formě zpravodajských stránek nebo online platformy, která parodizuje renomované skutečné zpravodajské agentury, aby vytvořila sarkastickou verzi reality. Tento typ falešných zpráv je často šířen jednotlivci na jejich online platformách, protože má mnohem silnější účinek při doručování kritiky než prostřednictvím přímočaré zprávy. Nicméně, když je satirický text šířen prostřednictvím sociálních médií bez zmínky o jeho zdroji, může být zaměněn za skutečnou zprávu. Tato studie provádí několik průzkumných analýz k identifikaci jazykových vlastností arabských falešných zpráv se satirickým obsahem. Ukazuje, že ačkoli parodizuje skutečné zprávy, arabské satirické zprávy mají na lexikogramatické úrovni charakteristické rysy. Tyto funkce využíváme k vytvoření řady modelů strojového učení schopných identifikovat satirické falešné zprávy s přesností až 98,6%. Studie představuje nový datový soubor (3185 články) vyškrábaný ze dvou arabských satirických zpravodajských webů (`Al-Hudood' a `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') obsahující falešné zprávy. Skutečný datový soubor zpráv se skládá z 3710 článků shromážděných ze tří oficiálních zpravodajských stránek: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic a Al-Jazeera news. Oba datové soubory se zabývají politickými otázkami souvisejícími s Blízkým východem.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Üks väga levinud valeuudiste tüüp on satiir, mis tuleb uudiste veebisaidi või veebiplatvormi kujul, mis parodeerib mainekaid reaalseid uudisteagentuure, et luua sarkastiline versioon reaalsusest. Seda tüüpi valeuudiseid levitavad sageli üksikisikud oma veebiplatvormidel, kuna need avaldavad kriitikat palju tugevamalt kui lihtsa sõnumi kaudu. Kuid kui satiirilist teksti levitatakse sotsiaalmeedia kaudu ilma allikat mainimata, võib seda segi ajada reaalsete uudistega. Käesolev uuring viib läbi mitmeid uurivaid analüüse, et tuvastada araabia libauudiste keelelisi omadusi satiirilise sisuga. See näitab, et kuigi see parodeerib reaalseid uudiseid, on araabia satiirilised uudised leksikogrammatilisel tasandil eristuvad tunnused. Me kasutame neid funktsioone, et luua mitmeid masinõppe mudeleid, mis suudavad tuvastada satiirilisi valeuudiseid täpsusega kuni 98,6%. Uuringus tutvustatakse uut andmekogumit (3185 artiklit), mis on kraapitud kahelt Araabia satiiriliselt uudiste veebisaidilt (`Al-Hudood' ja `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici'), mis koosneb valeuudistest. Tegelikud uudised koosnevad 3710 artiklist, mis on kogutud kolmelt ametlikult uudiste lehelt: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic ja Al-Jazeera uudised. Mõlemad andmekogumid käsitlevad Lähis-Idaga seotud poliitilisi küsimusi.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Yksi hyvin yleinen valeuutisten tyyppi on satiiri, joka tulee uutissivuston tai verkkoalustan muodossa, joka parodioi hyvämaineisia oikeita uutistoimistoja luodakseen sarkastisen version todellisuudesta. Yksityishenkilöt levittävät usein tällaisia valeuutisia verkkoalustoillaan, koska niillä on paljon voimakkaampi vaikutus kritisointiin kuin suoraviivaisen viestin kautta. Kun satiirista tekstiä levitetään sosiaalisessa mediassa mainitsematta sen lähdettä, sitä voidaan kuitenkin pitää oikeina uutisina. Tässä tutkimuksessa tehdään useita eksploratiivisia analyysejä arabialaisten valeuutisten kielellisten ominaisuuksien tunnistamiseksi satiirisella sisällöllä. Se osoittaa, että vaikka se parodioi todellisia uutisia, arabialaisilla satiirisilla uutisilla on tunnusmerkkejä leksiko-kieliopillisella tasolla. Hyödynnämme näitä ominaisuuksia rakentaaksemme useita koneoppimismalleja, jotka pystyvät tunnistamaan satiiriset valeuutiset jopa 98,6 prosentin tarkkuudella. Tutkimus esittelee uuden aineiston (3185 artikkelia), joka on kerätty kahdesta arabialaisesta satiirisesta uutissivustosta (`Al-Hudood' ja `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici'), joka koostuu valeuutisista. Todellinen uutisaineisto koostuu 3710 artikkelista, jotka on kerätty kolmelta viralliselta uutissivustolta: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic ja Al-Jazeera news. Molemmat aineistot koskevat Lähi-itään liittyviä poliittisia kysymyksiä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bs>Jedna vrlo zajednička vrsta lažnih vijesti je satir koji dolazi u oblik vijestinskog sajta ili internetske platforme koja parodija poznaje prave vijestinske agencije kako bi stvorila sarkastičnu verziju realnosti. Ova vrsta lažnih vijesti često se pojedinci šire na njihovim online platformama jer ima mnogo jači učinak u donošenju kritike nego prostom porukom. Međutim, kada se satirski tekst širi putem društvenih medija bez spominjanja svog izvora, može se pogriješiti za prave vijesti. Ova studija vodi nekoliko istraživačkih analiza kako bi identifikovali jezičke vlasništva lažnih vijesti arapske lažne vijesti sa satirskim sadržajem. Pokazuje da, iako parodiše prave vijesti, arapske satričke vijesti razlikuju karakteristike na leksikogramatičkom nivou. Koristimo te karakteristike da izgradimo broj modela za učenje mašine sposobnih identificiranja satirskih lažnih vijesti sa preciznošću do 98,6%. Istraživanje predstavlja novu kompletu podataka (3185 članaka) izvedenu iz dva arapska satirska vijesti (Al-Hudood i Al-Ahram Al-Mexici), koja se sastoji od lažnih vijesti. Prava vijestinska seta podataka sastoji se od 3710 članaka prikupljenih iz tri zvanična vijesti: vijesti BBC-Arapske, CNN-Arapske i Al-Jazeere. Obje podatke su zabrinute političkim pitanjima vezanim za Bliski Istok.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Un tipus molt comú de notícies falses és el satèr que apareix en una form a de web de notícies o plataforma on-line que paròdia agències de notícies famoses per crear una versió sarcàstica de la realitat. Aquest tipus de notícies falses sovint està difundit per individus a les seves plataformes on-line perquè té un efecte molt més fort en donar crítiques que a través d'un missatge senzill. No obstant això, quan el text satèric es difunde a través dels mitjans socials sense mencionar la seva font, es pot equivocar amb notícies reals. This study conducts several exploratory analyses to identify the linguistic properties of Arabic fake news with satirical content.  Mostra que tot i que parodi notícies reals, les notícies satèriques àrabs tenen característiques diferents a nivell lèxico-gramàtic. Exploitem aquestes característiques per construir un cert nombre de models d'aprenentatge màquinari capaços d'identificar notícies falses satèriques amb una precisió fins al 98,6%. L'estudi introdueix un nou conjunt de dades (3185 articles) extraït de dos llocs web àrabs de notícies satèriques (`Al-Hudood' i `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') que consisteixen en notícies falses. El conjunt de dades de notícies real consisteix en 3710 articles recollits de tres llocs oficials de notícies: la BBC-àrab, la CNN-àrab i la Al-Jazeera. Both datasets are concerned with political issues related to the Middle East.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_az>Yaxınlıq xəbərlərin çox ortaq bir türü satir. Bu, bir xəbər sitesinin və ya online platformunun şəkilində gəlir ki, həqiqət xəbər a ģentūrlarını şəriətə müvəffəq etmək üçün sarkastik bir versiyonu yaradır. Bu sahte xəbərlər çox zaman onlayn platformlarında kişilər tarafından yayılır, çünki bu xəbəri düzgün bir mesaj vasitəsilə kritik verməkdən daha qüvvətli olar. Lakin, satrikli məktub sosyal media vasitəsilə yayıldığında, özünün mənbəsini xatırlamadan, həqiqət xəbərlər üçün yanlış olar. Bu təcrübə məlumatı satıcı olaraq ərəbcə sahte xəbərlərin dil özelliklərini tanıtmaq üçün çoxlu keşif analizi təşkil edir. Bu, həqiqət xəbərlər parodyasına baxmayaraq, ərəb satik xəbərləri leksiko-grammatik səviyyəsində fərqləndirir. Biz bu xüsusiyyətləri bir neçə maşın öyrənməsi modellərini yaratmaq üçün istifadə edirik ki, satrikli sahte xəbərləri 98.6%-ə qədər doğruluqla tanıyabilir. Bu araşdırma sahte xəbərlər içərisində olan iki ərəbcə satrikli xəbər sitələrindən çıxarılmış yeni verilən quruluş (3185 məktub) təşkil edir. Gerçek xəbər verilər qurulması üç resmi xəbər sitəsindən toplanmış 3710 məktublardır: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic və Al-Jazeera xəbərləri. İki veri qurğuları Orta Şərqi ilə bağlı siyasi məsələlərə məğlub edir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ha>Babu nau'in da ɗayan lãbãri ba ta zama na ƙarya ba, ta zo cikin wata mace ta zama mai shagala a website, ko wata platform na Online, wanda ke jarraba zane-zane-zane-zane-zane masu bastarwa da masu gaskiya dõmin ya samo wani sigar sarcastic na gaskiyar. Wannan warar ƙarya ko da yawa aka wãtsa mutum a kan bangonsu, kamar yadda yana da mafi ƙaranci matsayi ga kusa da kursiga ko kuma a bayan wani manzo na daidaita. A lokacin da aka wãtsa matsayin sarki a tsakanin mitandai da jamii bã da an ambaci cẽtonsa, za'a iya ɓace wa lãbãrin gaskiya. Wannan littafin yana tafiyar da baƙalumai masu bastarwa dõmin a gane wasu littafin cikin harshen Larabci da lãbãri na ƙarya da ke cikin cikin shirin. Ina nuna cewa, kuma kõ da shi ke gauraya da lãbãri masu gaskiya, ma'abũcin bushãra na Larabci ya rarrabe masu tsari kan daraja na-grammati. We exploit these features to build a number of machine learning models capable of identifying satirical fake news with an accuracy of up to 98.6%.  Ana ƙunsa da wani takardar da aka yi takarda daga website biyu na Larabci na bushãra ('Al-HuDag' da `Al-Ahram Al-Meksi') wanda ke cikin babban lãbãri na ƙarya. Danna na gaskiya na ƙunsa da 3710 makala masu samun daga wurãren lãbãri uku rasmi: the 'BBC-Arabic', the 'CNN-Arabic' da 'Al-Jazeera news'. Dukan database biyu suna cikin masu sihiri masu husũma da Mashariki ta tsakani.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Sing juara sing perkaran kelas perkaran uwong ing satir sing dumateng kapan bener tentang kita bener tentang karo perusahaan online sing perusahaan kelas perusahaan bener awak dhéwé iso nggawe perusahaan versi sarkastik sing apik perusahaan. Kaya bener perbudhakan sing nguasai nggawe barang sampeyan nguasai perbudhakan liyane karo sistem online kaya sing luwih akeh lan nguasai winih sing luwih apik dhéwé ngerasai percisa sing sampeyan tambah. Nanging, meh metik satir kang disebarke ning media sotiki, sane mengko ajeng-ajeng ngenggo kuwi, isa diapakake kama kanggo barang kelas Wuraning iki dadi karo akeh akeh sampeyan kanggo nggawe perintasi alat sing nganggep ingkang dilangustik karo barang dhéwé kuwi kapan satêr. Rasané punika dipunangé, nganggo akeh basa sing resanié, basa satêr arab sing apik basa sing digalam nggawe barang kelikso-gram. Awak dhéwé nggunaké karo nganggo akeh akeh model sing sampeyan ngono nggawe barang sistem sing gawe kudu nggawe barang satêr neng sabêt dumadhi sak, sampeyan ngono sabêr dumadhi lunak-sabêr dumadhi liyane Pirisih sing ngandhani soko perusahaan dataset sing dibutung (bendhik-bendhik) sing dibutunge ning duruha sithik sing basa sawita arap ('Al-hudu' lan 'Al-AhramAl-Meksici') sing sembarang akeh basa. Daftar berkas sing nganggo limang telu atik nang telu saiki offisisi: telu alam sing dibutuhke 'obuk-obuk' (obuk-obuk'), terus 'banget-arab' lan 'Al-Jaséra barang). Sampeyan éwé datasing sing sing gawe akèh politik sing ngejaraké kang Kasabagan sing Afos</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Ena zelo pogosta vrsta lažnih novic je satira, ki prihaja v obliki spletne strani z novicami ali spletne platforme, ki parodira ugledne resnične novičarske agencije in ustvari sarkastično različico resničnosti. Te vrste lažnih novic pogosto razširjajo posamezniki na svojih spletnih platformah, saj ima veliko močnejši učinek pri kritiki kot prek preprostega sporočila. Kadar pa satirično besedilo razširjamo prek družbenih medijev brez omenjanja vira, ga lahko zamenjamo za resnične novice. Ta študija izvaja več raziskovalnih analiz za ugotavljanje jezikovnih lastnosti arabskih lažnih novic s satirično vsebino. Pokazuje, da ima arabska satirična novica, čeprav parodira resnične novice, različne značilnosti na leksikoslovnični ravni. Te funkcije izkoriščamo za izdelavo številnih modelov strojnega učenja, ki lahko prepoznajo satirične lažne novice z natančnostjo do 98,6%. Študija uvaja nov nabor podatkov (3185 člankov), sestavljen iz dveh arabskih satiričnih novic ("Al-Hudood" in "Al-Ahram Al-Mexici"), ki je sestavljen iz lažnih novic. Pravi nabor podatkov o novicah sestavlja 3710 člankov, zbranih s treh uradnih novičarskih strani: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic in Al-Jazeera news. Obe zbirki podatkov se nanašata na politična vprašanja, povezana z Bližnjim vzhodom.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>סוג אחד מאוד נפוץ של חדשות מזויפות הוא סאטיר שבא בצורה של אתר חדשות או פלטפורמה באינטרנט שמפרודיה סוכנויות חדשות אמיתיות מוכרות ליצור גרסה סרקסטית של מציאות. סוג זה של חדשות מזויפות הוא לעתים קרובות מפורסם על ידי אנשים על הפלטפורמות האינטרנט שלהם, כיוון שיש לו השפעה הרבה יותר חזקה בהביקורת מאשר דרך הודעה פשוטה. עם זאת, כאשר הטקסט הסטירי מתפשט באמצעות התקשורת החברתית בלי להזכיר את המקור שלה, זה יכול לטעות בחדשות אמיתיות. המחקר הזה מבצע כמה ניתוחים חקיריים לזהות את תכונות השפה של חדשות מזויפות ערביות עם תוכן סאטירי. זה מראה כי למרות שזה פרודי חדשות אמיתיות, חדשות סאטיריות ערביות יש תכונות מבחינות ברמה לקסיקו-גרמטית. אנו מנצלים את המאפיינים האלה כדי לבנות מספר דוגמנים ללמוד מכונות מסוגלים לזהות חדשות מזויפות satirical עם מדויקה עד 98.6%. המחקר מציג קבוצת נתונים חדשה (3185 מאמרים) שרוטה משני אתרי חדשות סאטיריות ערביים (`אל-הודוד' ו `אל-אהרם אל-מקסיקי') שמכילים בחדשות מזויפות. מסגרת הנתונים האמיתית היא 3710 מאמרים שנאספו משלושה אתרי חדשות רשמיים: BBC-Arabic, CNN-Arabic, Al-Jazeera. שני מסמכי נתונים מודאגים בנושאים פוליטיים שקשורים למזרח התיכון.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ཆེན་པོ་ཞིག་ནི་བཟོ་བཅོས་འགོད་པ་ཞིག་ཡིན་པས་གསར་འགོད་ཀྱི་དྲ་རྒྱ་སྟངས་དང་དྲ་རྒྱའི་གླེང་སྟེགས་ཞིག་ཡིན་པས་གསར་འགོད་བྱེད་རྒྱུ་ བཟོ་བྱས་ཡོད་པའི་བརྡ་ཞིག་འདི་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་གྱི་དྲ་རྒྱང་གླིང་ཐོག་ཏུ་སྒེར་ཚོས་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་གླིང་ཐོག་ནས་སྐྱོན་བརྗོད་པ་མང་ཙ ཡིན་ནའང་། འདྲ་བཟོ་གླེང་ཡིག་གེ་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་དྲ་རྒྱའི་ནང་དུ་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་བ་མངོན་གསལ་བརྗོད་མེད་དུས་ན་གསར འདིས་བརྟག་ཞིབ་ཀྱིས་སྐད་རིགས་ཀྱི་སྐད་རིགས་ཆ་རྣམས་ཀྱི་ངོ་བོའི་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་གཞན་མང་པོ་ཞིག་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། འདི་ལྟ་བུའི་བརྡ་སྤྲོད་ཀྱི་ངོ་དོན་དག་དེ་ལྟ་བུའི་བརྡ་སྤྲོད་ཀྱི་ཡོད་པ་ཚོས་ཁྱད་པར་ངོ་སྣང་ཚུལ་ངོ་བོར་ལབ་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་རང་ཉིད་འདི་དག་གི་ཁྱད་ཆོས་གཅིག་ནས་མ་ལག་གི་རྩིས་འཁོར་གྱི་མིག་ཆས་མང་པོ་ཞིག་སྟོན་རུང་། The study introduces a new dataset (3185 articles) scraped from two Arabic satirical news websites (`Al-Hudood' and `Al-Ahram Al-Mexici') which consists of fake news. གསར་འགོད་གནད་དོན་ཀྱི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་སྒྲིག་ནང་དུ་གཞུང་འབྲེལ་བའི་བརྡ་དོན་ཚན་གསུམ་ལས་སྒྲིག་ཡིག་ཆ་3710 ཞིག་ཡིན། དབུས་མཐུད་ཤར་ལ་ཡོད་པའི་ཆབ་སྲིད་ཀྱི་གནད་དོན་གཉིས་ཀྱིས་གནད་དོན་དགོས།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>