<collection id="2020.dmr">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Second International Workshop on Designing Meaning Representations</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Nianwen</first><last>Xue</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Johan</first><last>Bos</last></editor>
      <editor><first>William</first><last>Croft</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jan</first><last>Haji&#269;</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Chu-Ren</first><last>Huang</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Stephan</first><last>Oepen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Martha</first><last>Palmer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>James</first><last>Pustejovsky</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona Spain (online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="4276e725">2020.dmr-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>dmr-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Cross-lingual annotation: a road map for low- and no-resource languages</title>
      <author><first>Meagan</first><last>Vigus</last></author>
      <author><first>Jens E. L.</first><last>Van Gysel</last></author>
      <author><first>Tim</first><last>O&#8217;Gorman</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrew</first><last>Cowell</last></author>
      <author><first>Rosa</first><last>Vallejos</last></author>
      <author><first>William</first><last>Croft</last></author>
      <pages>30&#8211;40</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents a &#8220;road map&#8221; for the annotation of semantic categories in typologically diverse languages, with potentially few linguistic resources, and often no existing computational resources. Past semantic annotation efforts have focused largely on high-resource languages, or relatively low-resource languages with a large number of native speakers. However, there are certain typological traits, namely the synthesis of multiple concepts into a single word, that are more common in languages with a smaller speech community. For example, what is expressed as a sentence in a more analytic language like English, may be expressed as a single word in a more synthetic language like Arapaho. This paper proposes solutions for annotating analytic and synthetic languages in a comparable way based on existing typological research, and introduces a road map for the annotation of languages with a dearth of resources.</abstract>
      <url hash="305a3f9b">2020.dmr-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>vigus-etal-2020-cross</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>K-<fixed-case>SNACS</fixed-case>: Annotating <fixed-case>K</fixed-case>orean Adposition Semantics</title>
      <author><first>Jena D.</first><last>Hwang</last></author>
      <author><first>Hanwool</first><last>Choe</last></author>
      <author><first>Na-Rae</first><last>Han</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathan</first><last>Schneider</last></author>
      <pages>53&#8211;66</pages>
      <abstract>While many languages use adpositions to encode semantic relationships between content words in a sentence (e.g., agentivity or temporality), the details of how adpositions work vary widely across languages with respect to both form and meaning. In this paper, we empirically adapt the SNACS framework (Schneider et al., 2018) to Korean, a language that is typologically distant from English&#8212;the language SNACS was based on. We apply the SNACS framework to annotate the highly popular novellaThe Little Prince with semantic supersense labels over allKorean postpositions. Thus, we introduce the first broad-coverage corpus annotated with Korean postposition semantics and provide a detailed analysis of the corpus with an apples-to-apples comparison between Korean and English annotations</abstract>
      <url hash="a692e159">2020.dmr-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>hwang-etal-2020-k</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>