<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.lt4hala">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of LT4HALA 2020 - 1st Workshop on Language Technologies for Historical and Ancient Languages</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Rachele</first><last>Sprugnoli</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Marco</first><last>Passarotti</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-53-5</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="cbe27ee8">2020.lt4hala-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>lt4hala-2020-lt4hala</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Using LatInfLexi for an Entropy-Based Assessment of Predictability in Latin Inflection<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>at<fixed-case>I</fixed-case>nf<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>exi for an Entropy-Based Assessment of Predictability in <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>atin Inflection</title>
      <author><first>Matteo</first><last>Pellegrini</last></author>
      <pages>37–46</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents LatInfLexi, a large inflected lexicon of Latin providing information on all the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Latin-script_digraphs">inflected wordforms</a> of 3,348 verbs and 1,038 nouns. After a description of the structure of the resource and some data on its size, the procedure followed to obtain the lexicon from the database of the Lemlat 3.0 morphological analyzer is detailed, as well as the choices made regarding overabundant and defective cells. The way in which the data of LatInfLexi can be exploited in order to perform a quantitative assessment of predictability in Latin verb inflection is then illustrated : results obtained by computing the conditional entropy of guessing the content of a paradigm cell assuming knowledge of one wordform or multiple wordforms are presented in turn, highlighting the descriptive and theoretical relevance of the analysis. Lastly, the paper envisages the advantages of an inclusion of LatInfLexi into the LiLa knowledge base, both for the presented resource and for the knowledge base itself.</abstract>
      <url hash="04497ef1">2020.lt4hala-1.6</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>pellegrini-2020-using</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>A Tool for Facilitating OCR Postediting in Historical Documents<fixed-case>OCR</fixed-case> Postediting in Historical Documents</title>
      <author><first>Alberto</first><last>Poncelas</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammad</first><last>Aboomar</last></author>
      <author><first>Jan</first><last>Buts</last></author>
      <author><first>James</first><last>Hadley</last></author>
      <author><first>Andy</first><last>Way</last></author>
      <pages>47–51</pages>
      <abstract>Optical character recognition (OCR) for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Historical_document">historical documents</a> is a complex procedure subject to a unique set of material issues, including inconsistencies in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typeface">typefaces</a> and low quality scanning. Consequently, even the most sophisticated <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_character_recognition">OCR engines</a> produce errors. This paper reports on a tool built for postediting the output of Tesseract, more specifically for correcting common errors in digitized historical documents. The proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tool</a> suggests alternatives for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">word forms</a> not found in a specified vocabulary. The assumed error is replaced by a presumably correct alternative in the post-edition based on the scores of a Language Model (LM). The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tool</a> is tested on a chapter of the book An Essay Towards Regulating the Trade and Employing the Poor of this Kingdom (Cary, 1719). As demonstrated below, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tool</a> is successful in correcting a number of common errors. If sometimes unreliable, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It_(2017_film)">it</a> is also transparent and subject to human intervention.</abstract>
      <url hash="c046e2f0">2020.lt4hala-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>poncelas-etal-2020-tool</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/alberto-poncelas/tesseract_postprocess" additional="false">alberto-poncelas/tesseract_postprocess</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>A Thesaurus for Biblical Hebrew<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>ebrew</title>
      <author><first>Miriam</first><last>Azar</last></author>
      <author><first>Aliza</first><last>Pahmer</last></author>
      <author><first>Joshua</first><last>Waxman</last></author>
      <pages>68–73</pages>
      <abstract>We built a thesaurus for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biblical_Hebrew">Biblical Hebrew</a>, with connections between roots based on phonetic, semantic, and distributional similarity. To this end, we apply established <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithms</a> to find connections between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Headword">headwords</a> based on existing lexicons and other digital resources. For semantic similarity, we utilize the cosine-similarity of tf-idf vectors of English gloss text of Hebrew headwords from Ernest Klein’s A Comprehensive Etymological Dictionary of the Hebrew Language for Readers of English as well as to Brown-Driver-Brigg’s Hebrew Lexicon. For phonetic similarity, we digitize part of Matityahu Clark’s Etymological Dictionary of Biblical Hebrew, grouping Hebrew roots into phonemic classes, and establish phonetic relationships between headwords in Klein’s Dictionary. For distributional similarity, we consider the cosine similarity of PPMI vectors of Hebrew roots and also, in a somewhat novel approach, apply Word2Vec to a Biblical corpus reduced to its lexemes. The resulting resource is helpful to those trying to understand <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biblical_Hebrew">Biblical Hebrew</a>, and also stands as a good basis for programs trying to process the Biblical text.</abstract>
      <url hash="06b60503">2020.lt4hala-1.10</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>azar-etal-2020-thesaurus</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Comparing Statistical and Neural Models for Learning Sound Correspondences</title>
      <author><first>Clémentine</first><last>Fourrier</last></author>
      <author><first>Benoît</first><last>Sagot</last></author>
      <pages>79–83</pages>
      <abstract>Cognate prediction and proto-form reconstruction are key tasks in computational historical linguistics that rely on the study of sound change regularity. Solving these tasks appears to be very similar to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>, though methods from that field have barely been applied to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Historical_linguistics">historical linguistics</a>. Therefore, in this paper, we investigate the learnability of sound correspondences between a proto-language and daughter languages for two machine-translation-inspired models, one statistical, the other neural. We first carry out our experiments on plausible artificial languages, without <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noise_(signal_processing)">noise</a>, in order to study the role of each parameter on the algorithms respective performance under almost perfect conditions. We then study real languages, namely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latin">Latin</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_language">Italian</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_language">Spanish</a>, to see if those performances generalise well. We show that both model types manage to learn sound changes despite data scarcity, although the best performing model type depends on several parameters such as the size of the training data, the ambiguity, and the prediction direction.</abstract>
      <url hash="50e462e3">2020.lt4hala-1.12</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>fourrier-sagot-2020-comparing</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/clefourrier/PLexGen" additional="false">clefourrier/PLexGen</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/etymdb-2-0">EtymDB 2.0</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine Translation : from the Bible to Saint Augustine<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>atin-<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>panish Neural Machine Translation: from the <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>ible to Saint Augustine</title>
      <author><first>Eva</first><last>Martínez Garcia</last></author>
      <author><first>Álvaro</first><last>García Tejedor</last></author>
      <pages>94–99</pages>
      <abstract>Although there are several sources where to find historical texts, they usually are available in the original language that makes them generally inaccessible. This paper presents the development of state-of-the-art Neural Machine Systems for the low-resourced Latin-Spanish language pair. First, we build a Transformer-based Machine Translation system on the Bible parallel corpus. Then, we build a comparable corpus from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augustine_of_Hippo">Saint Augustine texts</a> and their translations. We use this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> to study the domain adaptation case from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bible">Bible texts</a> to Saint Augustine’s works. Results show the difficulties of handling a low-resourced language as Latin. First, we noticed the importance of having enough data, since the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> do not achieve high BLEU scores. Regarding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_adaptation">domain adaptation</a>, results show how using in-domain data helps <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> to achieve a better quality translation. Also, we observed that it is needed a higher amount of data to perform an effective vocabulary extension that includes in-domain vocabulary.</abstract>
      <url hash="662ea4ca">2020.lt4hala-1.14</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>martinez-garcia-garcia-tejedor-2020-latin</bibkey>
    <title_ar>الترجمة الآلية العصبية اللاتينية الإسبانية: من الكتاب المقدس إلى القديس أوغسطين</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Tradução automática neural latino-espanhol: da Bíblia a Santo Agostinho</title_pt>
      <title_fr>Traduction automatique neuronale latino-espagnole : de la Bible à saint Augustin</title_fr>
      <title_es>Traducción automática neuronal latín-español: de la Biblia a San Agustín</title_es>
      <title_zh>拉丁语-西班牙语神经机器翻译:自圣经至圣奥古斯丁</title_zh>
      <title_ja>ラテン語-スペイン語神経機械翻訳：聖書から聖アウグスティヌスへ</title_ja>
      <title_hi>लैटिन-स्पेनिश न्यूरल मशीन अनुवाद: बाइबल से सेंट ऑगस्टीन तक</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Латинско-испанский нейронный машинный перевод: от Библии до Святого Августина</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Aistriúchán Meaisín Neural Laidin-Spáinnis: ón mBíobla go dtí Naomh Agaistín</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_it>Traduzione automatica neurale latino-spagnola: dalla Bibbia a Sant'Agostino</title_it>
      <title_kk>Латын- Испан ньюрал машинаның аудармасы: Библиядан Сент- Агустинге</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Латинско-шпанско превод на неврална машина: од Библијата до Св. Августин</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Lotynų ir Ispanijos nervinės mašinos vertimas: nuo Biblijos iki Šv. Augustino</title_lt>
      <title_el>Λατινικά-Ισπανική Νευρική Μηχανική Μετάφραση: από τη Βίβλο στον Άγιο Αυγουστίνο</title_el>
      <title_ms>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine Translation: from the Bible to Saint Augustine</title_ms>
      <title_hu>Latin-spanyol Neurális Gépi Fordítás: a Bibliából Szent Ágostonba</title_hu>
      <title_mt>Traduzzjoni tal-Magna Newrali Latina-Spanjola: mill-Bibla għal Saint Augustine</title_mt>
      <title_pl>Łacińsko-hiszpańskie neuronalne tłumaczenie maszynowe: z Biblii do świętego Augustyna</title_pl>
      <title_ml>ലാറ്റിന്‍- സ്പാനിഷ് നെയുറല്‍ മെഷീന്‍ പരിഭാഷപ്പെടുത്തുക: ബൈബിളില്‍ നിന്നും സെന്റ് ആഗസ്റ്റന്‍</title_ml>
      <title_no>Latin- spansk neuralmaskinsomsetjing: frå bibelet til Saint Augustine</title_no>
      <title_mn>Латин-Испан мэдрэлийн машины хөгжүүлэлт: Библиоос Санкт Агустин хүртэл</title_mn>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_ro>Traducere automată latină-spaniolă neurală: de la Biblie la Sfântul Augustin</title_ro>
      <title_so>Translation: from the Bible to Saint Augustine</title_so>
      <title_ur>لاتین-اسپانیایی نیورال ماشین ترجمہ: بنیبل سے سنت آگوستین تک</title_ur>
      <title_ta>லாட்டின்- ஸ்பானிஷ் நெயுரல் இயந்திரம் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு: பைபிலிருந்து செய்தி ஆகஸ்டின்</title_ta>
      <title_sr>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine Translation: from the Bible to Saint Augustine</title_sr>
      <title_sv>Latin-Spansk Neural Machine Översättning: från Bibeln till Saint Augustine</title_sv>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Dịch sang thần kinh Tây Ban Nha: từ Kinh Thánh cho tới thánh Augustine</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Latijns-Spaans Neurale Machine Translation: van de Bijbel naar Sint Augustinus</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Латино-испански неврален машинен превод: от Библията до Свети Августин</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine Translation: from the Bible to Saint Augustine</title_hr>
      <title_da>Latin-spansk Neural Machine Oversættelse: fra Bibelen til Saint Augustine</title_da>
      <title_id>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine Translation: from the Bible to Saint Augustine</title_id>
      <title_de>Lateinisch-Spanisch Neuronale Maschinelle Übersetzung: Von der Bibel zum Heiligen Augustinus</title_de>
      <title_ko>성경에서 세인트 오구스틴까지</title_ko>
      <title_fa>ترجمه ماشین عصبی لاتین- اسپانیایی: از انجیل به سنت آگوستین</title_fa>
      <title_af>Latyn- Spaanse Neurale Masjien Vertaling: van die Bibel tot Saint Augustine</title_af>
      <title_sq>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine Translation: from the Bible to Saint Augustine</title_sq>
      <title_sw>Tafsiri ya Mashine ya Kihispania ya Neural: kutoka Biblia hadi Saint Augustin</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Latin-Ispanýolça Neural Makine terjime: Bibliýadan St. Augustine'a çevrilen</title_tr>
      <title_hy>Լատինական-իսպանական նյարդային մեքենայի թարգմանություն. Աստվածագրից Սուրբ Ավգուստին</title_hy>
      <title_az>Latinc톛-캻spanyol N칬ral Makina 칂eviri: Bibliyadan St. Augustine'톛 q톛d톛r</title_az>
      <title_am>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine ትርጉም: ከBible to Saint Augustin</title_am>
      <title_bn>ল্যাটিন-স্প্যানিশ নেউরাল মেশিন অনুবাদ: বাইবেল থেকে সেন্ট আগস্টাইন পর্যন্ত</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Traducció de màquina neural llatí-espanyol: de la Bíblia a Saint Augustine</title_ca>
      <title_et>Ladina-hispaania neuraalne masintõlge: Piiblist Püha Augustiini</title_et>
      <title_bs>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine Translation: from the Bible to Saint Augustine</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Latinsko-španělsko-neurální strojový překlad: z Bible do svatého Augustina</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Latino-espanja neuraalinen konekäännös: Raamatusta Pyhään Augustinukseen</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Ngucap Latir-Spanyol Neral Masine Terjamahan: suku Biblel nganggo Sent Gajustne</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ item Spelling dictionary</title_ha>
      <title_he>התרגום של מכונת עצבית לטינית-ספרדית: מהתנ"ך לסנט אוגוסטין</title_he>
      <title_sk>Latinsko-špansko nevralno strojno prevajanje: iz Svetega pisma v svetega Avguština</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Latin-Spanish Neural Machine Translation: from the Bible to Saint Augustine</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>على الرغم من وجود العديد من المصادر حيث يمكن العثور على النصوص التاريخية ، إلا أنها عادة ما تكون متاحة باللغة الأصلية مما يجعل الوصول إليها غير ممكن بشكل عام. تقدم هذه الورقة تطوير أنظمة الآلات العصبية الحديثة للزوج اللغوي اللاتيني-الأسباني منخفض الموارد. أولاً ، نقوم ببناء نظام ترجمة آلية قائم على المحولات على مجموعة الكتابات الموازية للكتاب المقدس. ثم نبني مجموعة قابلة للمقارنة من نصوص القديس أوغسطينوس وترجماتها. نستخدم هذه المجموعة لدراسة حالة تكييف المجال من نصوص الكتاب المقدس إلى أعمال القديس أوغسطين. تظهر النتائج صعوبات التعامل مع لغة منخفضة الموارد مثل اللاتينية. أولاً ، لاحظنا أهمية وجود بيانات كافية ، لأن الأنظمة لا تحقق درجات عالية في BLEU. فيما يتعلق بتكييف المجال ، تُظهر النتائج كيف يساعد استخدام البيانات في المجال الأنظمة على تحقيق ترجمة ذات جودة أفضل. لاحظنا أيضًا أن هناك حاجة إلى قدر أكبر من البيانات لإجراء ملحق مفردات فعال يتضمن مفردات في المجال.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Aunque hay varias fuentes donde encontrar textos históricos, por lo general están disponibles en el idioma original, lo que los hace generalmente inaccesibles. Este artículo presenta el desarrollo de sistemas de máquinas neuronales de última generación para el par de idiomas latín-español de bajos recursos. Primero, construimos un sistema de traducción automática basado en Transformer en el corpus paralelo de la Biblia. Luego, construimos un corpus comparable a partir de textos de San Agustín y sus traducciones. Utilizamos este corpus para estudiar el caso de adaptación de dominios de los textos bíblicos a las obras de San Agustín. Los resultados muestran las dificultades de manejar un idioma de escasos recursos como el latín. En primer lugar, nos dimos cuenta de la importancia de contar con datos suficientes, ya que los sistemas no consiguen puntuaciones altas de BLEU. En cuanto a la adaptación de dominios, los resultados muestran cómo el uso de datos dentro del dominio ayuda a los sistemas a lograr una traducción de mejor Además, observamos que se necesita una mayor cantidad de datos para realizar una extensión de vocabulario eficaz que incluya vocabulario dentro del dominio.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Embora existam várias fontes onde encontrar textos históricos, eles geralmente estão disponíveis no idioma original que os torna geralmente inacessíveis. Este artigo apresenta o desenvolvimento de sistemas de máquinas neurais de última geração para o par de idiomas latino-espanhol de poucos recursos. Primeiro, construímos um sistema de tradução automática baseado em Transformer no corpus paralelo da Bíblia. Em seguida, construímos um corpus comparável a partir de textos de Santo Agostinho e suas traduções. Utilizamos este corpus para estudar o caso de adaptação do domínio dos textos bíblicos às obras de Santo Agostinho. Os resultados mostram as dificuldades de lidar com uma língua de poucos recursos como o latim. Em primeiro lugar, notamos a importância de ter dados suficientes, uma vez que os sistemas não atingem altos escores BLEU. Em relação à adaptação de domínio, os resultados mostram como o uso de dados no domínio ajuda os sistemas a obter uma tradução de melhor qualidade. Além disso, observamos que é necessária uma quantidade maior de dados para realizar uma extensão de vocabulário efetiva que inclua o vocabulário do domínio.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Bien qu'il existe plusieurs sources où trouver des textes historiques, ils sont généralement disponibles dans la langue d'origine, ce qui les rend généralement inaccessibles. Cet article présente le développement de systèmes de machines neuronales de pointe pour le couple linguistique latin-espagnol à faibles ressources. Tout d'abord, nous construisons un système de traduction automatique basé sur Transformer sur le corpus parallèle de la Bible. Ensuite, nous construisons un corpus comparable à partir des textes de saint Augustin et de leurs traductions. Nous utilisons ce corpus pour étudier le cas d'adaptation du domaine des textes bibliques aux œuvres de saint Augustin. Les résultats montrent les difficultés liées à la gestion d'une langue peu riche comme le latin. Tout d'abord, nous avons remarqué l'importance de disposer de suffisamment de données, étant donné que les systèmes n'obtiennent pas de scores UEBL élevés. En ce qui concerne l'adaptation du domaine, les résultats montrent comment l'utilisation de données internes au domaine aide les systèmes à obtenir une traduction de meilleure qualité Nous avons également observé qu'une plus grande quantité de données est nécessaire pour réaliser une extension de vocabulaire efficace qui inclut le vocabulaire dans le domaine.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>歴史的なテキストを見つけるにはいくつかのソースがありますが、それらは通常、それらを一般的にアクセスできないようにする元の言語で利用できます。 低資源のラテン・スペイン語ペアのための最先端のニューラル・マシン・システムの開発を紹介する。 まず、聖書のパラレルコーパスにトランスフォーマーベースの機械翻訳システムを構築します。 そして、聖アウグスティヌスのテキストとその翻訳から、同等のコーパスを構築します。 このコーパスを使用して、聖書のテキストから聖アウグスティヌスの作品までの領域適応ケースを研究します。 結果は、ラテン語のような資源の少ない言語を扱うことの困難さを示している。 まず、システムが高いBLEUスコアを達成していないため、十分なデータを持つことの重要性に気付きました。 ドメインの適応について、結果は、ドメイン内データを使用することが、システムがより質の高い翻訳を達成するのにどのように役立つかを示しています。 また、ドメイン内ボキャブラリーを含む効果的なボキャブラリー拡張を実行するためには、より多くのデータが必要であることを観察しました。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>虽有数源可得,然常以原始语言供,使常无法访问也。 本文引为资源匮乏者拉丁语-西班牙语最先进之神经机器。 先于圣经并行语料库上构一变形金刚之机器翻译统。 然后于圣奥古斯丁文本及译中构一类语料库。 以此语料库来究圣经本圣奥古斯丁领域应例。 结果显示以资源匮乏之言处拉丁语之难。 先之以数,统不得高BLEU分也。 域中应之,结果显示用域内数据何以助高质量译。 观所须益多之数以行有效者词汇广之,包域内词汇。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हालांकि ऐसे कई स्रोत हैं जहां ऐतिहासिक ग्रंथों को ढूंढना है, वे आमतौर पर मूल भाषा में उपलब्ध होते हैं जो उन्हें आम तौर पर दुर्गम बनाते हैं। यह पेपर कम संसाधन वाले लैटिन-स्पेनिश भाषा जोड़ी के लिए अत्याधुनिक न्यूरल मशीन सिस्टम के विकास को प्रस्तुत करता है। सबसे पहले, हम बाइबल समानांतर कॉर्पस पर एक ट्रांसफॉर्मर-आधारित मशीन अनुवाद प्रणाली का निर्माण करते हैं। फिर, हम सेंट ऑगस्टीन ग्रंथों और उनके अनुवादों से एक तुलनीय कॉर्पस का निर्माण करते हैं। हम इस कॉर्पस का उपयोग बाइबल ग्रंथों से सेंट ऑगस्टीन के कार्यों तक डोमेन अनुकूलन मामले का अध्ययन करने के लिए करते हैं। परिणाम लैटिन के रूप में कम संसाधन वाली भाषा को संभालने की कठिनाइयों को दिखाते हैं। सबसे पहले, हमने पर्याप्त डेटा होने के महत्व को देखा, क्योंकि सिस्टम उच्च BLEU स्कोर प्राप्त नहीं करते हैं। डोमेन अनुकूलन के बारे में, परिणाम बताते हैं कि इन-डोमेन डेटा का उपयोग करने से सिस्टम को बेहतर गुणवत्ता वाले अनुवाद को प्राप्त करने में मदद मिलती है। इसके अलावा, हमने देखा कि एक प्रभावी शब्दावली विस्तार करने के लिए उच्च मात्रा में डेटा की आवश्यकता होती है जिसमें इन-डोमेन शब्दावली शामिल होती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Хотя есть несколько источников, где можно найти исторические тексты, они обычно доступны на языке оригинала, что делает их, как правило, недоступными. В данной работе представлена разработка новейших нейронно-машинных систем для малоресурсной латиноамериканско-испанской языковой пары. Во-первых, мы создаем систему машинного перевода на основе трансформаторов на параллельном корпусе Библии. Затем мы строим сопоставимый корпус из текстов Святого Августина и их переводов. Мы используем этот корпус для изучения случая адаптации домена из библейских текстов к произведениям святого Августина. Результаты свидетельствуют о трудностях, связанных с использованием в качестве латинского языка языка, не обеспеченного достаточными ресурсами. Во-первых, мы заметили важность наличия достаточного количества данных, так как системы не достигают высоких баллов по БЛЮ. Что касается адаптации домена, результаты показывают, как использование внутридоменных данных помогает системам достичь лучшего качества перевода. Кроме того, мы заметили, что для выполнения эффективного расширения словарного запаса, которое включает в себя внутридоменную лексику, требуется больший объем данных.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Cé go bhfuil go leor foinsí ann inar féidir teacht ar théacsanna stairiúla, is gnách go mbíonn siad ar fáil sa bhunteanga rud a fhágann nach bhfuil rochtain orthu go ginearálta. Cuirtear i láthair sa pháipéar seo forbairt na gCóras Néar-Innealaithe den scoth don phéire teanga Laidin-Spáinnis ar acmhainní ísle. Ar dtús, tógaimid córas Trasfhoirmeoir-bhunaithe Aistriúchán Meaisín ar an gcorpas comhthreomhar Bíobla. Ansin, tógaimid corpas inchomparáide ó théacsanna San Agaistín agus a gcuid aistriúcháin. Bainimid úsáid as an gcorpas seo chun staidéar a dhéanamh ar chás oiriúnú an fhearainn ó théacsanna an Bhíobla go saothair San Agaistín. Léiríonn torthaí na deacrachtaí a bhaineann le láimhseáil teanga íseal-acmhainní mar Laidin. Ar an gcéad dul síos, thugamar faoi deara a thábhachtaí atá sé dóthain sonraí a bheith againn, toisc nach mbaineann na córais scóir arda BLEU amach. Maidir le hoiriúnú fearainn, léiríonn torthaí an chaoi a gcabhraíonn sonraí in-fearainn le córais aistriúchán ar chaighdeán níos fearr a bhaint amach. Chomh maith leis sin, thugamar faoi deara go bhfuil gá le méid níos mó sonraí chun síneadh foclóra éifeachtach a dhéanamh a chuimsíonn stór focal in-fhearainn.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Bár több forrás is van, ahol történelmi szövegeket találhatunk, azok általában az eredeti nyelven érhetők el, ami általában elérhetetlenné teszi őket. Ez a tanulmány bemutatja a legkorszerűbb Neural Machine Systems fejlesztését az alacsony forrású latin-spanyol nyelvpár számára. Először egy transzformátor alapú Gépi Fordító rendszert építünk a Biblia párhuzamos korpuszára. Ezután összehasonlítható korpuszt építünk Szent Ágoston szövegekből és azok fordításaiból. Ezt a korpuszt arra használjuk, hogy tanulmányozzuk a domain adaptációs esetet a bibliai szövegektől Szent Ágoston műveiig. Az eredmények azt mutatják, hogy egy alacsony forrású nyelv latinként való kezelésének nehézségei vannak. Először is észrevettük, hogy elegendő adat rendelkezésre áll, mivel a rendszerek nem érnek el magas BLEU pontszámot. A domain adaptációt illetően az eredmények azt mutatják, hogy a domain adatok használata hogyan segít a rendszerek jobb minőségű fordítást elérni. Megfigyeltük továbbá, hogy nagyobb mennyiségű adatra van szükség egy hatékony szókincskiterjesztés elvégzéséhez, amely tartalmazza a domain szókincset.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>თუმცა არსებობს რამდენიმე მსოფლიოს, სადაც ისტორიური ტექსტები მოიძებნა, ისინი საერთოდ არსებობენ ორიგინალური ენაში, რომელიც ისინი საერთოდ დახმარე ეს დოკუმენტი აჩვენებს სახელსაწყისი ნეიროლური მაქინის სისტემის განვითარებას ლატინური-სპანული ენის ზოგლის დამატებისთვის. პირველად, ჩვენ შევქმნით ტრანფორმეტრების მაქსინური ტრანფორმეციის სისტემა ბიბლის პარალელი კორპუსზე. შემდეგ, ჩვენ შევქმნით შემდგომარებელი კორპუს სანტი აგუსტინის ტექსტიდან და მათი შეცვლებიდან. ჩვენ გამოვიყენებთ ეს კორპუსს, რომ სწავლოთ დიომინური ადაპტიფიკაციის შემთხვევაში ბიბლის ტექსტიდან სანტი აგსტინის სამუშაოდ. შედეგები გამოჩვენება სიტყვანის მარტივი რესურსური ენაზე როგორც ლატინული. პირველი, ჩვენ დავხედავთ, რომ საჭირო მონაცემების გასანიშვნელობა, რადგან სისტემები არ მიიღებენ უფრო დიდი BLEU მონაცემები. დემომინის აკაპეტიფიკაციის შესახებ, შესახებ დემომინის მონაცემების გამოყენება სისტემებს უკეთესი კანგალიტის გადაწყენება. ჩვენ დავხედავთ, რომ უფრო მეტი მონაცემები უნდა იყოს, რომ ეფექტიური სიტყვებულის გაფართვა, რომელიც სადომინში სიტყვებულია.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Αν και υπάρχουν αρκετές πηγές όπου μπορείτε να βρείτε ιστορικά κείμενα, συνήθως είναι διαθέσιμα στην αρχική γλώσσα που τα καθιστά γενικά δυσπρόσιτα. Η παρούσα εργασία παρουσιάζει την ανάπτυξη σύγχρονων συστημάτων νευρωνικών μηχανών για το ζευγάρι λατινικών-ισπανικών γλωσσών με χαμηλούς πόρους. Πρώτον, χτίζουμε ένα σύστημα μηχανικής μετάφρασης βασισμένο στον μετασχηματιστή πάνω στο παράλληλο σώμα της Βίβλου. Στη συνέχεια, χτίζουμε ένα συγκρίσιμο σώμα από κείμενα του Αγίου Αυγουστίνου και τις μεταφράσεις τους. Χρησιμοποιούμε αυτό το σώμα για να μελετήσουμε την περίπτωση προσαρμογής του τομέα από τα βιβλικά κείμενα στα έργα του Αγίου Αυγουστίνου. Τα αποτελέσματα δείχνουν τις δυσκολίες του χειρισμού μιας γλώσσας με χαμηλούς πόρους ως λατινικά. Πρώτον, παρατηρήσαμε τη σημασία της ύπαρξης επαρκών δεδομένων, δεδομένου ότι τα συστήματα δεν επιτυγχάνουν υψηλές βαθμολογίες BLEU. Όσον αφορά την προσαρμογή των τομέων, τα αποτελέσματα δείχνουν πώς η χρήση δεδομένων εντός του τομέα βοηθά τα συστήματα να επιτύχουν μια καλύτερη ποιότητα μετάφρασης. Επίσης, παρατηρήσαμε ότι απαιτείται μεγαλύτερη ποσότητα δεδομένων για την εκτέλεση μιας αποτελεσματικής επέκτασης λεξιλογίου που περιλαμβάνει λεξιλόγιο εντός του τομέα.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Sebbene ci siano diverse fonti in cui trovare testi storici, di solito sono disponibili nella lingua originale che li rende generalmente inaccessibili. Questo articolo presenta lo sviluppo di sistemi di macchine neurali all'avanguardia per la coppia di lingue latino-spagnolo con scarse risorse. In primo luogo, costruiamo un sistema di traduzione automatica basato su Transformer sul corpus parallelo biblico. Poi, costruiamo un corpus comparabile dai testi di sant'Agostino e dalle loro traduzioni. Usiamo questo corpus per studiare il caso di adattamento del dominio dai testi biblici alle opere di sant'Agostino. I risultati mostrano le difficoltà di gestire una lingua con scarse risorse come latino. In primo luogo, abbiamo notato l'importanza di disporre di dati sufficienti, dal momento che i sistemi non raggiungono punteggi BLEU elevati. Per quanto riguarda l'adattamento del dominio, i risultati mostrano come l'utilizzo di dati in-domain aiuti i sistemi a ottenere una traduzione di migliore qualità. Inoltre, abbiamo osservato che è necessaria una maggiore quantità di dati per eseguire un'estensione efficace del vocabolario che include il vocabolario nel dominio.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Nors yra keli šaltiniai, kuriuose galima rasti istorinius tekstus, jie paprastai pateikiami originalia kalba, dėl kurios jie paprastai neprieinami. This paper presents the development of state-of-the-art Neural Machine Systems for the low-resourced Latin-Spanish language pair.  Pirma, mes statome Transformuojančios mašinos vertimo sistemą Biblijos lygiagrečiu korpusu. Tada sukuriame panašų korpusą iš Šv. Augustino tekstų ir jų vertimų. Mes naudojame šį korpusą, kad ištirtume domeno pritaikymo atvejį nuo Biblijos tekstų iki Sen Augustino kūrinių. Iš rezultatų matyti, kad sunku tvarkyti mažai išteklių turinčią kalbą Lotynų kalba. Pirma, pastebėjome, kad svarbu turėti pakankamai duomenų, nes sistemos nepasiekia didelių BLEU rezultatų. Dėl domeno pritaikymo rezultatai rodo, kaip domeno duomenų naudojimas padeda sistemoms pasiekti geresnę vertimo kokybę. Be to, pastebėjome, kad veiksmingam žodyno išplėtimui atlikti reikia daugiau duomenų, įskaitant domeninį žodyną.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бірнеше түсті мәтінді табу көбірек көзі бар, әдетте олар бастапқы тілде қол жеткізілмейді. Бұл қағаз латын- испан тілдерінің күй- жайындағы невралдық механизм жүйелерін жасайды. Біріншіден, Библияның параллель корпус арқылы машинаны аудару жүйесін құрамыз. Содан соң, Сент Агустин мәтіндерінен және олардың аудармаларынан салыстырылатын корпус құрамыз. Біз бұл корпусты Библияның мәтіндерінен Сент Агустин жұмысына ауыстыру үшін доменнің адаптациясын зерттейміз. Нәтижелер латын тіліне төмен ресурс тілді қалау қиындығын көрсетеді. Біріншіден, біз мәліметтерді жеткілікті болу маңызды түсіндік, өйткені жүйелер BLEU нәтижесін жеткілмейді. Домендің адаптациясы туралы, домендің деректерін қалай қолдану жүйелерді жақсы сапатты аудару үшін көмектесетін нәтижелер көрсетіледі. Сонымен қатар, домендегі сөздік сөздігінде болатын эффективті сөздік кеңейтуі үшін оның көптеген мәліметтің жоғары керек деп белгіледік.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Иако постојат неколку извори каде да се најдат историски тексти, тие обично се достапни на оригиналниот јазик кој ги прави генерално непристапни. Овој весник го претставува развојот на најсовремените неврални машински системи за парот со ниски ресурси на латинско-шпански јазик. Прво, градиме трансформски систем за машински преведувања на паралелниот корпус на Библијата. Потоа изградивме споредлив корпус од текстовите од Св. Августин и нивните преводи. Го користиме овој корпус за да го проучуваме случајот на адаптација на доменот од библиските тексти до делата на Св. Августин. Резултатите покажуваат тешкотии во односот со нискоресурсен јазик како латински. Прво, забележавме дека е важно да се имаат доволни податоци, бидејќи системите не постигнуваат високи БЛЕ резултати. Во врска со адаптацијата на доменот, резултатите покажуваат како употребата на податоци во доменот помага на системите да постигнат подобар квалитетен превод. Also, we observed that it is needed a higher amount of data to perform an effective vocabulary extension that includes in-domain vocabulary.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Walaupun terdapat beberapa sumber di mana untuk mencari teks sejarah, mereka biasanya tersedia dalam bahasa asal yang menjadikannya umumnya tidak boleh dicapai. Kertas ini memperkenalkan pembangunan sistem Mesin Neural state-of-the-art untuk pasangan bahasa Latin-Spanyol yang mempunyai sumber rendah. Pertama, kita membangun sistem Transformer-based Machine Translation pada korpus selari Alkitab. Kemudian, kita membuat corpus yang sama dari teks Saint Augustine dan terjemahan mereka. Kami menggunakan korpus ini untuk mempelajari kes penyesuaian domain dari teks Alkitab ke kerja Saint Augustine. Hasil menunjukkan kesulitan mengendalikan bahasa sumber rendah sebagai Latin. Pertama, kami perasan penting mempunyai data yang cukup, kerana sistem tidak mencapai skor BLEU yang tinggi. Regarding domain adaptation, results show how using in-domain data helps systems to achieve a better quality translation. Juga, kami memperhatikan bahawa ia memerlukan jumlah data yang lebih tinggi untuk melaksanakan sambungan vokbulari yang berkesan yang termasuk vokbulari dalam domain.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ചരിത്രത്തിലെ പദാവലികള്‍ കണ്ടെത്താന്‍ കുറച്ച് സ്രോതസ്സുകളുണ്ടെങ്കിലും, അത് സാധാരണയായി അസാധാരണമായി അസാധാരണമാക്കു ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ ലാറ്റിന്‍ -സ്പാനിഷ് ഭാഷ ജോടികള്‍ക്കായി ന്യൂറല്‍ മെഷീന്‍ സിസ്റ്റമുള്ള രാജ്യത്തിന്‍റെ വികസിപ്പിന്‍റെ വി ആദ്യം, നമ്മള്‍ ഒരു ട്രാന്‍സ്ഫോര്‍മാന്‍സ് അടിസ്ഥാനമായ മെഷീന്‍ പരിഭാഷ സിസ്റ്റം പണിയുന്നു. ബൈബിള്‍ പാരാള്‍ പിന്നെ നമ്മള്‍ സെന്റ് ആഗസ്റ്റിന്റെ ടെക്സ്റ്റുകളില്‍ നിന്നും തുല്യമായ ഒരു കോര്‍പ്പസ് പണിയുന്നു. ബൈബിള്‍ ടെക്സ്റ്റുകളില്‍ നിന്നും സെന്റ് ആഗസ്റ്റിന്റെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങളിലേക്കും ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഈ കോര്‍പ്പസ് ഉപയോഗിക്കുന ഫലങ്ങള്‍ ലാറ്റിനെപ്പോലെ കൈകാര്യം ചെയ്യുന്നതിന്റെ പ്രയാസങ്ങള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു. First, we noticed the importance of having enough data, since the systems do not achieve high BLEU scores.  ഡൊമെയിന്‍ ആഡാപ്റ്റേഷന്‍ ചെയ്യുന്നതിനെക്കുറിച്ച് ഫലങ്ങള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നത് എങ്ങനെയാണ് ഡോമെയിന്‍ ഡേറ്റാ ഉപയോ പിന്നെ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടുപിടിച്ചു കൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു അതിന്റെ കൂടുതല്‍ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ആവശ്യമുണ്ടെന്ന്. അത് ഡൊമെയിനിലെ വാക്കുപ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Għalkemm hemm diversi sorsi fejn jinstabu testi storiċi, huma ġeneralment disponibbli fil-lingwa oriġinali li tagħmilhom ġeneralment inaċċessibbli. Dan id-dokument jippreżenta l-iżvilupp ta’ Sistemi ta’ Magni Newrali l-aktar avvanzati għall-pari tal-lingwa Latina-Spanjola b’riżorsi baxxi. L-ewwel nett, nibnu sistema ta’ traduzzjoni tal-Magni bbażata fuq it-Trasformer fuq il-korpus parallel tal-Bibla. Imbagħad, nibnu korpus komparabbli mit-testi ta’ Saint Augustine u t-traduzzjonijiet tagħhom. Aħna nużaw dan il-korpus biex nistudjaw il-każ ta’ adattament tad-dominju mit-testi tal-Bibla għax-xogħlijiet ta’ Saint Augustine. Ir-riżultati juru d-diffikultajiet fl-immaniġġjar ta’ lingwa b’riżorsi baxxi bħala l-Latin a. L-ewwel nett, innotaw l-importanza li jkollna biżżejjed dejta, peress li s-sistemi ma jiksbux punteġġi għoljin tal-BLEU. Regarding domain adaptation, results show how using in-domain data helps systems to achieve a better quality translation.  Barra minn hekk, osservajna li hemm bżonn ta’ ammont ogħla ta’ dejta biex titwettaq estensjoni effettiva tal-vokabulari li tinkludi l-vokabulari fid-dominju.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Selv om det finst fleire kjelde der historiske tekstar skal finnast, er dei vanlegvis tilgjengelege i den originale språket som gjer dei vanlegvis ikkje tilgjengelege. Denne papiret viser utviklinga av tilstanden av kunstende neuralmaskinsystemet for den lav ressurserte latinske språksparen. Først bygger vi eit maskineoversettelsystem med transformeringsbasert på bibelet parallell korpus. Så bygger vi eit sammenlignbar korpus frå Saint Augustine-tekstar og oversettelsene sine. Vi bruker denne korpusen for å studiera domeneadaptasjonen frå bibelettekstane til Saint Augustine. Resultat viser vanskelighetane for handtering av ein låg ressursert språk som latinsk. Først har vi merke på at viktigheten for å ha nok data, sidan systemet ikkje oppnår høg BLEU-poeng. I tillegg til domeneadaptasjon viser resultatet korleis bruk i domenedata hjelper systemet til å oppnå ei betre kvalitetsverktøyring. Vi observerte også at det er nødvendig ein høgare mengd data for å utføra eit effektivt ordbokutviding som inneheld i domenet ordbokstavar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Chociaż istnieje kilka źródeł, w których można znaleźć teksty historyczne, zwykle są one dostępne w oryginalnym języku, co czyni je ogólnie niedostępnymi. W artykule przedstawiono rozwój najnowocześniejszych systemów maszyn neuronowych dla pary językowej łacińsko-hiszpańskiej o niskich zasobach. Najpierw budujemy system tłumaczenia maszynowego oparty na Transformerze na korpusie równoległym Biblii. Następnie budujemy porównywalny korpus z tekstów św. Augustyna i ich tłumaczeń. Korpus ten wykorzystujemy do badania przypadku adaptacji domeny z tekstów biblijnych do dzieł św. Augustyna. Wyniki wskazują na trudności w obsłudze języka łacińskiego o niskich zasobach. Po pierwsze zauważyliśmy znaczenie posiadania wystarczającej ilości danych, ponieważ systemy nie osiągają wysokich wyników BLEU. Jeśli chodzi o adaptację domeny, wyniki pokazują, jak wykorzystanie danych wewnątrz domeny pomaga systemom osiągnąć lepszą jakość tłumaczeń. Zauważyliśmy również, że potrzebna jest większa ilość danych do wykonania skutecznego rozszerzenia słownictwa obejmującego słownictwo wewnątrz domeny.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Түүний бичгийг олох хэд хэдэн эх үүсвэрүүд байдаг ч, түүхийн бичгийг ихэвчлэн ашиглах боломжгүй болгодог. Энэ цаас Латин-Испанийн хэл хоёрын бага асуудлын төвшин мэдрэлийн машин системийн төвшин хөгжлийг харуулдаг. Эхлээд Бид Библийн параллель корпус дээр Трансформ суурилсан Машин Трансформ системийг бүтээж байна. Тэгээд бид Санкт Аугустины бичиг болон тэдний орчуулалтын харьцуулагдмал корпус бүтээсэн. Бид энэ корпус хэрэглэж Библийн текстүүдээс Санкт Аугустины ажлыг судалж байна. Үүний үр дүнд бага хүчтэй хэл Латин хэлбэртэй болгох хэцүү байдлыг харуулдаг. Эхлээд бид хангалттай өгөгдлийн чухал ач холбогдолыг анзаарсан. Яагаад гэвэл системүүд өндөр BLEU оноо гаргахгүй. Домены загварын талаар үр дүнд домены өгөгдлийн хэрхэн хэрхэн ашиглах нь системүүд илүү сайн чанарын хөрөнгө оруулах тулд тусалдаг байдаг. Мөн бид холбоотой үгийг нэмэгдүүлэхэд илүү их мэдээллийн хэрэгтэй гэдгийг анзаарсан.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Deși există mai multe surse în care se găsesc texte istorice, acestea sunt de obicei disponibile în limba originală, ceea ce le face în general inaccesibile. Această lucrare prezintă dezvoltarea sistemelor de mașini neurale de ultimă generație pentru perechea latină-spaniolă cu resurse reduse. În primul rând, construim un sistem de traducere automată bazat pe Transformer pe corpul paralel al Bibliei. Apoi, construim un corpus comparabil din textele Sfântului Augustin și traducerile lor. Folosim acest corpus pentru a studia cazul adaptării domeniului de la textele biblice la lucrările Sfântului Augustin. Rezultatele arată dificultățile de a gestiona o limbă cu resurse reduse ca latină. În primul rând, am observat importanța de a avea suficiente date, deoarece sistemele nu obțin scoruri BLEU ridicate. În ceea ce privește adaptarea domeniului, rezultatele arată cum utilizarea datelor în domeniu ajută sistemele să obțină o traducere de calitate mai bună. De asemenea, am observat că este nevoie de o cantitate mai mare de date pentru a efectua o extensie eficientă de vocabular care include vocabularul în domeniu.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Iako postoje nekoliko izvora gde bi pronašli istorijske tekste, obično su dostupni na originalnom jeziku koji ih čini općenito neposlušnim. Ovaj papir predstavlja razvoj državnih neuralnih mašinskih sustava za manje sredstvene latinske-španjolske parove. Prvo, izgradimo sistem za prevod mašine na transformaciji na biblijskom paralelnom korpusu. Onda izgradimo usporedbeni korpus iz tekstova Svetog Augustina i njihovih prevoda. Koristimo ovaj korpus da proučimo slučaj adaptacije domena iz biblijskih tekstova do radova Svetog Augustina. Rezultati pokazuju teškoće rješavanja jezika s niskim resursima kao latinski. Prvo smo primetili važnost imati dovoljno podataka, pošto sistemi ne postižu visoke rezultate BLEU-a. Što se tiče adaptacije domena, rezultati pokazuju kako korištenje podataka u domenu pomaže sistemima da postignu bolji prevod kvalitete. Takođe smo primetili da je potrebna veća količina podataka za izvršavanje efikasnog proširenja rečnika koja uključuje rečnik u domenu.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Även om det finns flera källor där man kan hitta historiska texter, är de vanligtvis tillgängliga på originalspråket vilket gör dem allmänt otillgängliga. Denna uppsats presenterar utvecklingen av state-of-the-art Neural Machine System för lågresurserade latin-spanska språkpar. Först bygger vi ett Transformer-baserat maskinöversättningssystem på Bibelns parallella korpus. Sedan bygger vi en jämförbar korpus från Saint Augustine texter och deras översättningar. Vi använder denna korpus för att studera domänanpassningsfallet från bibeltexterna till Augustinus verk. Resultaten visar på svårigheterna att hantera ett lågresursspråk som latin. För det första märkte vi vikten av att ha tillräckligt med data, eftersom systemen inte uppnår höga BLEU-poäng. När det gäller domänanpassning visar resultaten hur användning av in-domain data hjälper system att uppnå en bättre kvalitet på översättning. Vi observerade också att det behövs en högre mängd data för att utföra ett effektivt ordförråd tillägg som inkluderar in-domän ordförråd.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>ඉතිහාසික වාර්තාව හොයාගන්න තියෙනවා නමුත් ඔවුන් සාමාන්‍යයෙන්ම ප්‍රධාන භාෂාවට පුළුවන් වෙනවා ඒකෙන මේ පත්තර පෙනුවෙන් ලැටින්-ස්පැනිස් භාෂා ජෝඩාව සඳහා ප්‍රධානයක් තියෙනවා. මුලින්ම, අපි බිබිල් එක්ක සමාන්‍ය කොර්පුස් වලින් පද්ධතියක් නිර්මාණය කරනවා. ඊට පස්සේ, අපි සෙන්ට් අගුස්ටින් වලින් පණිවිඩය සහ ඔවුන්ගේ වාර්තාවක් නිර්මාණය කරනවා. අපි මේ කොර්පස් එක පාවිච්චි කරනවා බායිබල් පාළුවෙන් සෙන්ට් අගුස්ටින්ගේ වැඩවල් විදිහට ප්‍රශ් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලැටින් වලින් අඩු සම්පූර්ණ භාෂයක් පාලනය කරන අමාරුය පෙන්වන්නේ. මුලින්ම, අපි දැනගත්තා ඇති තොරතුරු තියෙන්නේ වැදගත් වැදගත්තා, පද්ධතියේ බ්ලූස් ප්‍රමාණයක් ලැබ ඩොමේන් සැකසුම් ගැන, ප්‍රතිචාරය පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන් ඩොමේන් එකේ දත්ත භාවිතා කරන්න ප්‍රවේශයක් හොඳ ඒවගේම, අපි බලන්නේ ඒක ගොඩක් අවශ්‍ය දත්ත අවශ්‍ය වෙන්නේ ප්‍රභාවිත ශබ්ද භාෂාවක් සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Inta kastoo ay leeyihiin manfacyo badan oo laga heli karo qoraalo taariikhda ah, sida caadiga ah waxaa lagu heli karaa luqada asalka ah oo si caadiga ah u suurtagal. Kanu warqaddan wuxuu soo bandhigaa horumarinta-state-of-the-art Neural machine systems for the low-resourced luqada Latin-Spanish labo. Marka ugu horeysa, waxaynu dhisaynaa nidaam turjumista machine-based ah oo ku qoran korpuska isku mid ah ee Bibelka. Markaas waxaynu dhisnaa korpus la mid ah oo ka soo qoraya qorniinka Saint Augustin iyo turjumaadkooda. Waxaynu u isticmaalnaa qofkan si aan u barano xaaladda bedelka ee buugaagta ama u barano shaqada Saint Augustine. Resultadu waxay muuqataa dhibaatooyin ku saabsan in luqada hoose-resourceed ah sida Latin. Marka ugu horeysa, waxaynu ogaanay muhiim u ah in ay lahaayeen macluumaad ku filan, sababtoo ah nidaamka ma gaadho scoro sare oo BLEU ah. Regarding domain adaptation, results show how using in-domain data helps systems to achieve a better quality translation.  Sidoo kale waxaynu aragnay in loo baahan yahay macluumaad dheeraad ah, si loo sameyno mid faa’iido ah oo afka gudaha ku jira.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>ஆயினும் வரலாற்று உரைகளை கண்டுபிடிக்கும் பல மூலங்கள் இருந்தாலும், அவை வழக்கமாக முதல் மொழியில் கிடைக்கும். அது பொதுவா இந்த தாள் குறைந்த லாட்டின்- ஸ்பானிஷ் மொழி ஜோடிக்கான நெயுரல் இயந்திரம் அமைப்புகளின் மாநிலையை உருவாக்குகிறது. First, we build a Transformer-based Machine Translation system on the Bible parallel corpus.  பின்னர், நாம் செய்தி ஆகஸ்டின் உரைகளில் இருந்து ஒப்பிட்ட கார்ப்ஸ் கட்டுகிறோம் மற்றும் அவற்றின் மொழி நாம் இந்த கார்ப்புஸ் பயன்படுத்தி டொமைன் ஒதுக்கீட்டு விஷயத்தை பைப்பிள் உரைகளில் இருந்து சென்ட் ஆகஸ்டின் வே @ info: whatsthis முதலில், நாம் போதுமான தகவல் இருக்கும் முக்கியம் கவனித்தோம், ஏனெனில் அமைப்புகள் உயர்ந்த BLEU மதிப்பு டோமைன் ஒதுக்கீட்டை பற்றிய, முடிவுகள் எப்படி உள்ளமைப்பு தரவை பயன்படுத்தி சிறந்த தரமான மொழிபெயர்ப்பை பெற உதவுகிறது  மேலும், நாங்கள் கண்டறிந்தோம் அதிக தரவு தேவைப்பட்டுள்ளது குறிப்பிட்ட சொல்வளத்தின் விரிவாக்கம் செயல்படுத்தப்படும்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>اگرچہ بہت سی سراسر ہیں جہاں تاریخی ٹیکسٹ پیدا کریں، ان کو معمولاً اصلی زبان میں موجود ہوتا ہے جو ان کو معمولاً دسترسی نہیں دیتا۔ یہ کاغذ کم رسورس لاتین-اسپانیایی زبان جوڑ کے لئے ایٹیٹ-اورٹ نیورال ماشین سیسٹم کی تولید کرتا ہے. پہلے، ہم ایک ٹرنفسر بنیادی ماشین ترجمہ سیستم بناتے ہیں بائبل کے پارلی کورپوس پر۔ اس کے بعد ہم ایک مثال قالب بناتے ہیں سنت آگوسٹین کے پیغام اور ان کی ترجمہ. ہم اس کورپوس کو استعمال کرتے ہیں کہ بائبل کے پیغام سے سنت آگوستین کے کاموں تک ڈومین اڈیٹ کیس کو پڑھنے کے لئے۔ نتیجے لٹینی کے طور پر کم رسسورٹ کی زبان کی مدد کرنے کی مشکلات دکھاتے ہیں. پہلی بار، ہم نے دیکھا کہ کافی ڈیٹا ملنے کا اہم ہے، کیونکہ سیسٹم بالا BLEU اسکور نہیں پہنچ سکتے۔ ڈومین ادامه کے بارے میں نتیجے دکھاتے ہیں کہ ڈومین میں ڈیٹا کیسے استعمال کرنا سیستموں کو بہتر کیفیت ترجمہ پہنچانے کے لئے مدد کرتا ہے. اور ہم نے دیکھا کہ اس کے لئے ایک عمدہ لکھنے والی استعمال کرنے کے لئے بہت زیادہ مقدار ڈیٹا کی ضرورت ہے جو دومین میں لکھنے والی لکھنے والی ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Ko'pchilik tarixi matnlarni topish uchun bir necha manbalar mavjud. Odatda ular umumiy imkoniyatli emas. Бу саҳифа Лотингча-Испанча тил жуфтлари учун камбағал манбаи система таркибида кўринади. Birinchi, biz Bible parallel corpus bilan tarjima tizimni bir tarjima qilamiz. Keyin biz Saint Augustin textlaridan va tarjimalarning bir qismlarini yaramiz. Biz Biblik matnlaridan Saint Augustinning vazifalarini o'rganish uchun bu kopusdan foydalanamiz. @ info: status Birinchisi, biz yetarli maʼlumot olishning muhimligini anglatdik, chunki tizimlar yuqori BLEU scorlarini topmaydi. Name Also, we observed that it is needed a higher amount of data to perform an effective vocabulary extension that includes in-domain vocabulary.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Mặc dù có nhiều nguồn cung cấp để tìm các văn bản lịch sử, nhưng chúng thường được cung cấp bằng ngôn ngữ gốc khiến chúng không có khả năng truy cập. Bài báo này giới thiệu sự phát triển hệ thống thần kinh cao nhất cho cặp ngôn ngữ Latin-Tây Ban Nha ít nguồn. Đầu tiên, chúng ta xây dựng một hệ thống dịch biến áp dựa trên Kinh Thánh. Sau đó, chúng tôi xây dựng một tập thể tương đương từ văn bản thánh Augustine và bản dịch của chúng. Chúng tôi dùng tập thể này để nghiên cứu trường hợp biến đổi miền từ các văn bản Kinh Thánh tới các tác phẩm thánh Augustine. Kết quả cho thấy khó khăn trong việc sử dụng ngôn ngữ ít nguồn như tiếng Latin. Trước tiên, chúng tôi nhận ra tầm quan trọng của việc có đủ dữ liệu, vì hệ thống không đạt được điểm cao của NIZ. Về phần sửa chữa miền, kết quả cho thấy cách sử dụng dữ liệu nội bộ giúp hệ thống đạt được chất lượng tốt hơn. Chúng tôi cũng quan sát rằng cần nhiều dữ liệu hơn để thực hiện một phần mở rộng ngôn ngữ có hiệu quả bao gồm cả từ trong miền.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Въпреки че има няколко източника, където да намерите исторически текстове, те обикновено са достъпни на оригиналния език, което ги прави като цяло недостъпни. Настоящата статия представя разработването на най-съвременни невронни машини за латино-испанската езикова двойка с ниски ресурси. Първо, ние изграждаме трансформаторна система за машинен превод върху паралелния корпус на Библията. След това изграждаме сравним корпус от текстовете на Свети Августин и техните преводи. Използваме този корпус, за да изучаваме случая с адаптация на домейна от библейските текстове към произведенията на Свети Августин. Резултатите показват трудностите при боравенето с нисък ресурс език като латински. Първо, забелязахме важността да имаме достатъчно данни, тъй като системите не постигат високи резултати. По отношение на адаптацията на домейна резултатите показват как използването на данни в домейна помага на системите да постигнат по-качествен превод. Също така, забелязахме, че е необходимо по-голямо количество данни, за да се извърши ефективно разширение на речника, което включва в домейна речник.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Selv om der er flere kilder, hvor man kan finde historiske tekster, er de normalt tilgængelige på originalsproget, hvilket gør dem generelt utilgængelige. Denne artikel præsenterer udviklingen af state-of-the-art Neural Machine Systems til lav ressource latin-spansk sprogpar. Først bygger vi et Transformer-baseret maskinoversættelsessystem på Bibelens parallelle korpus. Derefter bygger vi et sammenligneligt korpus ud fra Saint Augustine tekster og deres oversættelser. Vi bruger dette korpus til at studere domænetilpasningssagen fra bibelteksterne til Augustins værker. Resultaterne viser vanskelighederne ved at håndtere et lavt ressourcesprog som latin. For det første bemærkede vi vigtigheden af at have tilstrækkelige data, da systemerne ikke opnår høje BLEU-scorer. Med hensyn til domænetilpasning viser resultaterne, hvordan brug af in-domain data hjælper systemer med at opnå en bedre kvalitet oversættelse. Vi bemærkede også, at det er nødvendigt en højere mængde data for at udføre en effektiv ordforråd udvidelse, der omfatter in-domæne ordforråd.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Hoewel er verschillende bronnen zijn waar historische teksten te vinden zijn, zijn ze meestal beschikbaar in de originele taal waardoor ze over het algemeen ontoegankelijk zijn. Dit artikel presenteert de ontwikkeling van state-of-the-art Neural Machine Systems voor het Latijns-Spaanse taalpaar met lage resources. Eerst bouwen we een Transformer-gebaseerd Machine Translation systeem op het Bijbelse parallelle corpus. Vervolgens bouwen we een vergelijkbaar corpus op van Sint Augustinus teksten en hun vertalingen. We gebruiken dit corpus om de domeinadaptatiecase van de Bijbelteksten tot de werken van Sint Augustinus te bestuderen. De resultaten tonen aan dat het moeilijk is om een taal met lage middelen als Latijn te hanteren. Ten eerste merkten we het belang op van voldoende data, omdat de systemen geen hoge BLEU scores behalen. Met betrekking tot domeinaanpassing laten de resultaten zien hoe het gebruik van in-domain data systemen helpt om een betere vertaalkwaliteit te bereiken. Ook hebben we geconstateerd dat er een hogere hoeveelheid gegevens nodig is om een effectieve vocabulaire extensie uit te voeren die in-domein vocabulaire bevat.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Obwohl es mehrere Quellen gibt, wo historische Texte zu finden sind, sind sie in der Regel in der Originalsprache verfügbar, was sie generell unzugänglich macht. Dieser Beitrag stellt die Entwicklung modernster neuronaler Maschinensysteme für das lateinisch-spanische Sprachpaar vor. Zunächst bauen wir ein Transformer-basiertes Machine Translation System auf dem biblischen Parallelkorpus. Anschließend bauen wir aus Augustinus-Texten und deren Übersetzungen ein vergleichbares Korpus auf. Mit diesem Korpus untersuchen wir den Domänenanpassungsfall von den Bibeltexten bis zum Werk des heiligen Augustinus. Die Ergebnisse zeigen, dass es schwierig ist, eine Sprache mit geringen Ressourcen als Latein zu handhaben. Zunächst haben wir festgestellt, wie wichtig es ist, genügend Daten zu haben, da die Systeme keine hohen BLEU-Scores erzielen. In Bezug auf die Domain-Anpassung zeigen die Ergebnisse, wie die Verwendung von In-Domain-Daten Systemen hilft, eine bessere Übersetzungsqualität zu erreichen. Außerdem haben wir festgestellt, dass es eine höhere Datenmenge benötigt, um eine effektive Vokabelerweiterung durchzuführen, die In-Domain Vokabeln enthält.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_hr>Iako postoje nekoliko izvora gdje naći povijesni tekst, obično su dostupni na originalnom jeziku koji ih čini općenito neposlušnim. Ovaj papir predstavlja razvoj državnih neuronskih sustava za manje sredstvene latinske-španjolske jezičke parove. Prvo, izgradimo sustav prevoda stroja na transformatoru na Bibliji paralelnom korpusu. Onda izgradimo usporedbeni korpus iz tekstova Svetog Augustina i njihovih prevoda. Koristimo ovaj korpus da proučimo slučaj prilagodbe domena iz Biblije do radova Svetog Augustina. Rezultati pokazuju teškoće rješavanja jezika s niskim resursima kao latinski. Prvo smo primijetili važnost imati dovoljno podataka, jer sistemi ne postignu visoke rezultate BLEU-a. Što se tiče adaptacije domena, rezultati pokazuju kako korištenje podataka u domenu pomaže sustavima ostvariti bolji prevod kvalitete. Također smo primijetili da je potrebna veća količina podataka za izvršavanje učinkovitog proširenja riječnika koja uključuje riječnik u domenu.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_id>Meskipun ada beberapa sumber di mana untuk menemukan teks sejarah, mereka biasanya tersedia dalam bahasa asli yang membuat mereka umumnya tidak dapat diakses. Kertas ini menunjukkan perkembangan sistem mesin saraf terbaik untuk pasangan bahasa bahasa Latin-Spanyol yang memiliki sumber daya rendah. Pertama, kita membangun sistem Transformer-based Machine Translation pada Bible parallel corpus. Kemudian, kita membangun corpus yang sama dari teks Saint Augustine dan terjemahan mereka. Kami menggunakan korpus ini untuk mempelajari kasus adaptasi domain dari teks Alkitab ke karya Saint Augustine. Hasil menunjukkan kesulitan untuk menangani bahasa dengan sumber daya rendah sebagai bahasa Latin. Pertama, kami memperhatikan penting memiliki cukup data, karena sistem tidak mencapai nilai BLEU tinggi. Regarding domain adaptation, results show how using in-domain data helps systems to achieve a better quality translation.  Juga, kami memperhatikan bahwa jumlah data yang lebih tinggi diperlukan untuk melakukan estensi vokabular yang efektif yang termasuk vokabular dalam domain.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>몇 개의 출처가 역사 텍스트를 찾을 수 있지만, 그것들은 통상적으로 원시 언어로 제공되기 때문에 접근할 수 없다.본고는 자원이 부족한 라틴-스페인어 언어를 위해 가장 선진적인 신경기계 시스템 개발에 대해 소개한다.우선, 우리는 성경 평행 어료 라이브러리에 변환기를 기반으로 한 기계 번역 시스템을 구축했다.그리고 우리는 세인트 오구스틴의 텍스트와 번역에서 비교 가능한 어료 라이브러리를 구축했다.우리는 이 어료 라이브러리를 이용하여 성경 텍스트에서 세인트 오구스틴 작품까지의 영역 개편 사례를 연구한다.자원이 부족한 언어를 라틴어로 사용하기는 어렵다는 연구결과가 나왔다.우선, 이 시스템들이 높은 BLEU 점수를 얻지 못하기 때문에 충분한 데이터를 가지는 것이 중요하다는 것을 알아차렸다.도메인 적응에 대한 결과는 도메인 내 데이터를 사용하여 시스템이 더욱 높은 품질의 번역을 실현하도록 어떻게 도와주는지 보여 준다.그 밖에 우리는 영역 내의 어휘를 포함한 효과적인 어휘 확장을 실행하기 위해 더 많은 데이터가 필요하다는 것을 관찰했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>اگرچه چند منابع وجود دارد که متن تاریخی را پیدا کنند، معمولا در زبان اصلی موجود می شوند که آنها را معمولاً دسترسی ندارد. این کاغذ توسعه سیستم های ماشین عصبی ایالت و هنری برای جفت زبان لاتین و اسپانیایی پایین را نشان می دهد. اول، ما یک سیستم ترجمه ماشین بر اساس تغییر دهنده بر اساس کورپوس پارالی انجیل ساختیم. بعدش، ما یک قالب مقایسه از متن های سنت آگوستین و ترجمه های آنها را ساختیم. ما از این کورپوس استفاده می کنیم تا پرونده تغییر دادن دامنی را از متن انجیل به کارهای سنت آگوستین مطالعه کنیم. نتیجه‌ها مشکلاتی را به عنوان لاتین نشان می‌دهند که با یک زبان کم استفاده شده است. اول، ما متوجه اهمیت داده های کافی شدیم، زیرا سیستم ها امتیاز بلوپ بالا نمی رسند. در مورد تغییرات دامنی، نتیجه‌ها نشان می‌دهند که چگونه استفاده از داده‌های دامنی به سیستم‌ها کمک می‌کند تا یک ترجمه کیفیت بهتر را به دست آورد. همچنین، ما مشاهده کردیم که به مقدار بیشتری از داده‌ها نیاز دارد تا یک اضافه‌ای از کلمه‌های موثر انجام دهد که شامل کلمه‌های دامنه‌ای است.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Ingawa kuna vyanzo kadhaa ambapo hupata ujumbe wa kihistoria, mara nyingi huwa zinapatikana kwa lugha ya asili ambazo huwafanya hawawezi kuingia. Makala hii inaonyesha maendeleo ya mfumo wa mashine ya kiserikali kwa ajili ya mbili za lugha ya Kilatini na Kihispania wasio na rasmi. Kwanza, tunajenga mfumo wa Tafsiri wa Mashine anayeishi Transfer katika vifaa vinavyofanana Biblia. Kisha, tunajenga makampuni yanayofanana na kuandika ujumbe wa Saint Augustina na tafsiri zao. Tunatumia makampuni haya ili kusoma kesi ya mabadiliko ya ndani kutoka maandishi ya Biblia hadi kazi za Saint Augustine. Matokeo yanaonyesha matatizo ya kukabiliana na lugha yenye rasilimali duni kama Kilatini. Kwanza, tuligundua umuhimu wa kuwa na taarifa za kutosha, kwa sababu mifumo haifanikiwi vipimo vya juu vya BLEU. Kuhusu upatikanaji wa ndani, matokeo yanaonyesha jinsi ya kutumia taarifa za ndani inavyosaidia mifumo ya kufikia tafsiri bora ya ubora. Pia, tuliona kwamba inahitaji kiasi kikubwa cha taarifa ili kutengeneza ukuaji wa ufanisi wa lugha inayojumuisha lugha za ndani.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Taryhy metinleri tapmak üçin birnäçe çeşme bar bolsa-da, olar adatça öz dilinde elýeterli bolarlar. Bu kagyz Latin-Ispanýolça dil çift üçin gurşawy nural sistemalaryň döwletlerini tanaýar. Ilkinji gezek, Bibliýa parallel korpusda Transformer tabanly Makina terjime sistemasyny gurarys. Sonra, Saint Augustine'in metinlerinden ve çevirilerinden karşılaştırılabilir bir korpus inşa ediyoruz. Bu korpusu Saint Augustine'in çalışmalarına kadar İncil metinlerinden gelen domena uygulama davasını öğrenmek için kullanırız. Netijenler, latin dilinden iň az hereket edip bilmek kynçylygyny görkezýär. Birinjisi, biz özümize ýeterlik maglumatyň wajyplygyny düşündik, sebäbi sistemalar ýokary BLEU sanlaryny ýetmeýärler. domain adaptasyyla ilgili netijeler domençä maglumaty sistemlere kömek edip gowy kalitede terjime etmek üçin nähili ullanyşyny görkez. Ayrıca, domain sözlerinde dahil edilen sözleri etkinleştirmek üçin ýokaryk maglumaty gerektiğini gördük.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_hy>Չնայած կան մի քանի աղբյուրներ, որտեղ կարող ենք գտնել պատմական տեքստեր, նրանք սովորաբար հասանելի են սկզբնական լեզվով, որը դրանք ընդհանուր առմամբ անհասանելի է դարձնում: Այս հոդվածը ներկայացնում է ցածր ռեսուրսներով լատիներեն-իսպաներեն լեզվի զույգերի նորագույն նյարդային մեքենային համակարգերի զարգացումը: Առաջինը, մենք կառուցում ենք Աստվածքի զուգահեռ կորպոսի վրա վերածվող մեքենայի թարգմանման համակարգ: Then, we build a comparable corpus from Saint Augustine texts and their translations.  Մենք օգտագործում ենք այս կորպոսը, որպեսզի ուսումնասիրենք բնագավառի ադապտացիայի դեպքը Սուրբ Ավգուստինի տեքստներից մինչև Սուրբ Ավգուստինի գործերը: Results show the difficulties of handling a low-resourced language as Latin.  Նախ և առաջ, մենք նկատեցինք բավարար տվյալներ ունենալու կարևորությունը, քանի որ համակարգերը չեն հասնում բարձր ԲԼԵՎ գնահատականների: Ինչ վերաբերում է բնագավառի ադապտացիային, արդյունքները ցույց են տալիս, թե ինչպես բնագավառի տվյալների օգտագործումը օգնում է համակարգերին ավելի լավ որակային թարգմանություն հասնել: Մենք նաև նկատեցինք, որ անհրաժեշտ է ավելի մեծ տվյալներ, որպեսզի կատարենք էֆեկտիվ բառարանի ընդլայնումը, որը ներառում է տիեզերքում գտնվող բառարանը:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_sq>Megjithëse ka disa burime ku mund të gjejmë tekste historike, ato zakonisht janë në dispozicion në gjuhën origjinale që i bën ato përgjithësisht të papërshtatshme. Ky artikull paraqet zhvillimin e sistemeve moderne të makinave neuronale për çiftin e gjuhës latino-spanjolle me burime të ulta. Së pari, ne ndërtojmë një sistem të Transformimit të Makinës me bazë në Korpus paralel të Biblës. Pastaj, ne ndërtojmë një korpus të ngjashëm nga tekstet e Shën Augustin dhe përkthimet e tyre. Ne përdorim këtë korpus për të studiuar rastin e përshtatjes në domeni nga tekstet e Biblës në veprat e Shën Augustin. Rezultatet tregojnë vështirësitë e trajtimit të një gjuhe me burime të ulta si latin. Së pari, vëmë re rëndësinë e të dhënave të mjaftueshme, pasi sistemet nuk arrijnë rezultate të larta BLEU. Në lidhje me përshtatjen e domainit, rezultatet tregojnë se si përdorimi i të dhënave në domain ndihmon sistemet për të arritur një përkthim më të mirë cilësie. Gjithashtu, kemi vëzhguar se është e nevojshme një sasi më e lartë e të dhënave për të kryer një zgjerim efektiv fjalor që përfshin fjalorin në domeni.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>ምንም እንኳን ብዙዎች የታሪክ ጽሑፎችን ለማግኘት ቢኖሩ፣ በመጀመሪያው ቋንቋ በመጠቀም አይቻልላቸውም፡፡ ይህ ፕሮግራም የቋንቋ ቋንቋ ሁኔታ-የኔural machine ሲስተም ለታናሽ ሀብት የላቲን-ስፓኒሽ ቋንቋ ሁለቶችን የሚያሳውቅ ነው፡፡ First, we build a Transformer-based Machine Translation system on the Bible parallel corpus.  የዚያን ጊዜም ከሳንት አውግስቲን ጽሑፎች እና ትርጓሜዎቻቸውን የሚመስል ቆርፓስ እንሠራለን፡፡ ይህ ኮርፓስ የድሜን አካባቢል ጽሑፎችን ወደ ሳንቲ አውግስቲን ሥራ ለማስተምር ነው፡፡ ፍጥረቶቹ የጎደለው ቋንቋን እንደ ሎቲን መቆጣጠር ችግር ያሳያል፡፡ በመጀመሪያው፣ የጠቃሚ ዳታ መኖሩን አየን፣ ሲስተምሮቹ ከፍተኛ BLEU scores አይደርሱም፡፡ የዶሜን አቀማመጥ ሲጠይቁ ፍሬዎቹ እንዴት እንደሚጠቀም የዶሜን ዳታ ሲስተም በተሻለ ጥሩ ትርጉም እንዲያገኝ ይረዳሉ፡፡ ደግሞም በዲሞናዊ ቃላት ውስጥ የሚያስፈልገውን አካባቢ የመልእክት ግንኙነት ለመፈለግ የዳታ ብዛት እንዲያስፈልጋል አየን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>Alhoewel daar is verskeie bronne waar historiese teks te vind, is hulle gewoonlik beskikbaar in die oorspronklike taal wat hulle generelik ontoegang maak. Hierdie papier stel die ontwikkeling van staat van die kunste neurale masjien stelsels voor die lae hulpbronne Latyn-Spaanse taal paar. Eerste, ons bou 'n Transformer-gebaseerde Masjien Vertaling stelsel op die Bibel parallele korpus. Dan bou ons 'n vergelykbare korpus van Saint Augustine tekste en hulle vertalings. Ons gebruik hierdie korpus om die domein-adaptasie geval te studeer van die Bibeltekste na die werke van Saint Augustine. @ info Eerste het ons opgemerk die belangrikheid van genoeg data te hê, omdat die stelsels nie hoë BLEU-rekening bereik nie. Aangaande domein aanpassing, vertoon resultate hoe gebruik in domein data hulp stelsels om 'n beter kwaliteit vertaling te bereik. Ons het ook bevestig dat dit 'n hoër hoeveelheid data nodig is om 'n effektief woordeboek uitbreiding te doen wat in-domein woordeboek insluit.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_az>Əgər tarihi metinləri tapmaq üçün bir neçə çeşmə mənbələri vardır, bunlar genellikle başlanğıç dilində faydalanırlar ki, onları genellikle əlaqə edilməz. Bu kağıt Latin-İspanyol dil çiftərinin düşük qüvvətli Nöral Makina Sistemlərinin təhsil edilməsini göstərir. İlk dəfə, İncil paralel korpusu üzerində bir Transformer-tabanlı Makin Tercümə sistemi inşa edirik. Sonra biz St. Augustine yazılarından və onların tercümələrindən bənzər bir korpus inşa edirik. Biz bu korpusu Bibliyanın mətnlərindən St. Augustine'in əməllərinə qədər dəyişiklik sahəsini təhsil etmək üçün istifadə edirik. Sonuçlar Latinci olaraq düşük ressurslı dil işləmənin çətinliklərini göstərər. İlk dəfə, sistemlərin yüksək BLEU nöqtələrinə nail olmadığı üçün kifayət məlumatların olmasının vacibətini gördük. Domenin uyğunlaşdırması haqqında, sonuçlar domenin verilənlərinin istifadəsi sistemlərin daha xeyirli qiymətli tercümə gəlməsinə kömək edir. Və biz də belə gördük ki, domain sözləri içərisində olan effektiv sözlər uzatmaq üçün daha yüksək məlumat lazımdır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>যদিও বেশ কয়েকটি উৎস আছে যেখানে ঐতিহাসিক লেখা খুঁজে পাওয়া যায়, সাধারণত ত তারা প্রাথমিক ভাষায় পাওয়া যায় যা সাধারণত ত এই পত্রিকাটি ল্যাটিন-স্প্যানিশ ভাষার জোড়ার জন্য নিউরাল মেশিন সিস্টেমের রাষ্ট্র-অফ-শিল্পের উন্নয়নের উপস্থাপন করে প্রথমত, আমরা বাইবেল প্যারালেল কোর্পাসের উপর একটি ট্রান্সফারেন ভিত্তিক মেশিন অনুবাদ সিস্টেম তৈরি করি। তারপর আমরা সেন্ট অ্যাগাস্টিনের লেখা এবং তাদের অনুবাদ থেকে তুলনামূলক কোর্পাস তৈরি করি। We use this corpus to study the domain adaptation case from the Bible texts to Saint Augustine's works.  ফলাফল ল্যাটিন হিসেবে একটি কম সম্পদের ভাষা হাতিয়ে নেওয়ার কষ্ট প্রদর্শন করে। প্রথমত, যথেষ্ট তথ্য পাওয়ার গুরুত্ব আমরা লক্ষ্য করেছি, কারণ সিস্টেম উচ্চ বিলিউ স্কোর অর্জন করে না। ডোমেইন অ্যাডাপেটশনের ব্যাপারে ফলাফল দেখানো যায় কিভাবে ডোমেইন ডাটা ব্যবহার করে ভালো মান অনুবাদ অর্জনের জন্য সিস্ট এছাড়াও আমরা দেখেছি যে কার্যকর শব্দভাণ্ডারের বিস্তারিত বিশেষ পরিমাণ তথ্য প্রয়োজন যা ডোমেইন শব্দভাণ্ডারের মধ্যে রয়ে</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Iako postoje nekoliko izvora gdje su pronašli povijesni tekst, obično su dostupni na originalnom jeziku koji ih čini općenito neposlušnim. Ovaj papir predstavlja razvoj državnih neuroloških sustava za manje resursnog latinskog-španjolskog parova. Prvo, izgradimo sistem prevoda na transformatoru na biblijskom paralelnom korpusu. Onda izgradimo usporedbeni korpus iz tekstova Svetog Augustina i njihovih prevoda. Koristimo ovaj korpus da proučimo slučaj adaptacije domena iz biblijskih tekstova do radova Svetog Augustina. Rezultati pokazuju teškoće rješavanja jezika s niskim resursima kao latinski. Prvo smo primijetili važnost imati dovoljno podataka, jer sistemi ne postignu visoke rezultate BLEU-a. Što se tiče adaptacije domena, rezultati pokazuju kako korištenje podataka u domenu pomaže sistemima da postignu bolji prevod kvalitete. Također smo primijetili da je potrebna veća količina podataka za izvršavanje efikasnog proširenja rečnika koja uključuje rečnik u domenu.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Encara que hi ha diverses fonts on trobar textos històrics, normalment estan disponibles en la llengua original que els fa generalment inaccessibles. Aquest article presenta el desenvolupament de Sistemes Neurals d'última generació per a un parell de llenguatges llatí-espanyol amb baixos recursos. Primer, construïm un sistema de traducció de màquines basat en Transformer sobre el cos parallel de la Bíblia. Després construïm un corpus comparable a partir dels textos de Saint Augustine i les seves traduccions. We use this corpus to study the domain adaptation case from the Bible texts to Saint Augustine's works.  Els resultats mostren les dificultats de tractar un llenguatge amb baixos recursos com el llatí. En primer lloc, ens vam adonar de la importància de tenir prou dades, ja que els sistemes no aconsegueixen grans puntuacions BLEU. En relació a l'adaptació de dominis, els resultats mostran com l'ús de dades en domini ajuda els sistemes a aconseguir una traducció de millor qualitat. Also, we observed that it is needed a higher amount of data to perform an effective vocabulary extension that includes in-domain vocabulary.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Přestože existuje několik zdrojů, kde lze najít historické texty, obvykle jsou k dispozici v původním jazyce, což je obecně činí nedostupnými. Tento článek představuje vývoj nejmodernějších systémů neuronových strojů pro nízké zdroje latinsko-španělského jazykového páru. Nejprve postavíme systém strojového překladu založený na transformátoru na paralelním korpusu Bible. Následně vytvoříme srovnatelný korpus z textů svatého Augustina a jejich překladů. Tento korpus využíváme ke studiu doménového adaptačního případu od biblických textů na díla svatého Augustina. Výsledky ukazují potíže s manipulací s nízkými zdroji jazyka jako latiny. Nejprve jsme si všimli důležitosti mít dostatek dat, protože systémy nedosahují vysokého skóre BLEU. Pokud jde o adaptaci domén, výsledky ukazují, jak použití dat v doméně pomáhá systémům dosáhnout kvalitnějšího překladu. Také jsme pozorovali, že k provedení efektivního rozšíření slovní zásoby, které zahrnuje v doméně slovní zásobu, je potřeba vyšší množství dat.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Kuigi ajaloolisi tekste on mitmeid allikaid, on need tavaliselt kättesaadavad algkeeles, mis muudab need üldiselt kättesaamatuks. Käesolev töö tutvustab kaasaegsete neuromasinate süsteemide arendamist madala ressursiga ladina-hispaania keelepaarile. Esiteks ehitame Transformeril põhineva masintõlkesüsteemi Piibli paralleelkorpusele. Seejärel ehitame võrreldava korpuse Püha Augustinuse tekstidest ja nende tõlketest. Selle korpuse abil uurime domeeni kohandamise juhtumit Piibli tekstidest Püha Augustinuse teosteni. Tulemused näitavad raskusi käsitleda madala ressursiga keelt nagu ladina keel. Esiteks märkasime piisavalt andmeid, sest süsteemid ei saavuta kõrgeid BLEU tulemusi. Domeeni kohandamise osas näitavad tulemused, kuidas domeenisiseste andmete kasutamine aitab süsteemidel saavutada kvaliteetsema tõlke. Samuti täheldasime, et on vaja suuremat hulka andmeid, et teostada efektiivne sõnavara laiendus, mis sisaldab domeeni sõnavara.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Vaikka historiallisia tekstejä on useita lähteitä, ne ovat yleensä saatavilla alkuperäisellä kielellä, mikä tekee niistä yleisesti vaikean päästä käsiksi. Tässä artikkelissa esitellään viimeisimpien hermokonejärjestelmien kehittämistä vähävaraisille latinan ja espanjan kieliparille. Ensin rakennamme muuntajapohjaisen konekäännösjärjestelmän Raamatun rinnakkaiskorpuselle. Tämän jälkeen rakennamme vertailukelpoisen korpusen Pyhän Augustinuksen teksteistä ja niiden käännöksistä. Käytämme tätä korpusta tutkiaksemme Raamatun teksteistä Pyhän Augustinuksen teoksiin ulottuvaa verkkotunnuksen sopeutumista. Tulokset osoittavat, että vähävaraisen latinan kielen käsittely on vaikeaa. Ensinnäkin huomasimme riittävän tiedon tärkeyden, koska järjestelmät eivät saavuta korkeita BLEU-pisteitä. Domain-sopeutumisen osalta tulokset osoittavat, miten domain-datan käyttö auttaa järjestelmiä saavuttamaan laadukkaamman käännöksen. Huomasimme myös, että tarvitaan enemmän dataa tehokkaan sanaston laajennuksen suorittamiseen, joka sisältää oman sanaston.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Sing sing nduwe akeh sing paling-itik sing nggawe textus dadi, sedhaya iso ngomong nik nggawe Language sing dadi, akeh iso nggawe ora bisa teka-teka. Perintah iki rambarang nggawe sistem sistem sing Neral karo kuwi duluran kanggo kelas kuwi duluran idiang Latin é-Spanish. Awak dhéwé, kéné nggawe sistem Anyar Tubagian sing basa Transformer nang banter bangsane Jewel perusahaan bangsane. Amargi, awak dhéwé nggawe mripat karo perusahaan kanggo nyelarakno anu dodolan sing sepatu tapi, san uwong. We use this corus to read the domain modification Case from the Library texts to Saint Gajustne's Works. Pametuné ngertuk gampang kanggo nggawe barang kelas kuwi dianggonapakan ning Latin é. Awak dhéwé, ngéwé ngerti cara-cara sing pertama awak dhéwé, sedhaya sistem sing gak nggawe barang blok sing wis ana. Regarding domain modification, output show when use in-domain data help sistems to success a quality translation. Mungkin, we mulai ke butuh nggawe sistem sing gawe nggawe akeh luwih akeh data kanggo nyebute sistem sing tutanan sing nyebute nggo-domain sokolar</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Kuma kõ da da waɗansu sources masu iya sãmun littãfin na historical, sai ana iya da su a cikin harshen farko da ke yarda da su a gaba ɗaya. Wannan avir na bãyar da shirin ayuka na-state-of-the-art Neural Systems for the lower-resourced language-biyu. Kayyar da, muna samar da wani tsarin Tarjibu na Transformer a kan Biblican da aka daidaita. Sa'an nan kuma za mu samar da misalin mutane daga littafan Sake Augustuni da fassarorinsu. Yana amfani da wannan nauyi dõmin mu karanta kasar adaptation na Domen daga littãfin Littafin zuwa aikin Sagustan. Mataimakin ya nuna matsala don a yi amfani da lugha mai ƙas ƙanci kamar Latin. Kayyan, mun gane muhimu da za'a sami da data masu isa, saboda haka, tsarin ba su sami score na BLEU ba. Ga da shirin adadin ɗin ayuka, matsala ta nuna yadda zai yi amfani da data cikin-Domen, yana taimako da tsari don ya sami tsarin da ya fi kyau. Kuma kamar haka, mun gane cewa, an a ƙayyade kashi na da wasu data dõmin a cika wani faɗi mai amfani da maganar cikin-Domin.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Čeprav obstaja več virov, kjer najti zgodovinska besedila, so običajno na voljo v izvirnem jeziku, zaradi česar so na splošno nedostopni. V prispevku je predstavljen razvoj najsodobnejših nevronskih strojnih sistemov za nizko-sredstva latinsko-španski jezikovni par. Najprej smo zgradili sistem strojnega prevajanja, ki temelji na transformatorjih, na vzporednem korpusu Svetega pisma. Nato zgradimo primerljiv korpus iz besedil svetega Avguština in njihovih prevodov. Ta korpus uporabljamo za preučevanje primera prilagoditve domene od svetopisemskih besedil do dela svetega Avguština. Rezultati kažejo težave pri ravnanju z jezikom z nizkimi viri, kot je latinščina. Najprej smo opazili pomen imeti dovolj podatkov, saj sistemi ne dosegajo visokih rezultatov BLEU. V zvezi s prilagajanjem domen rezultati kažejo, kako uporaba notranjih podatkov sistemom pomaga doseči boljšo kakovost prevajanja. Opazili smo tudi, da je potrebna večja količina podatkov za izvedbo učinkovite razširitve besedišča, ki vključuje besedišče v domeni.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>למרות שיש מספר מקורות שבו למצוא טקסטים היסטוריים, הם בדרך כלל זמינים בשפה המקורית שמגרמת להם בדרך כלל בלתי אפשריים. העבודה הזו מציגה את הפיתוח של מערכות מכונות נוירוליות חדשות עבור זוג השפה הלטינית-ספרדית עם משאבים נמוכים. קודם כל, אנחנו בונים מערכת תרגום מכונות מבוססת על התנ"ך במקביל. ואז, אנחנו בונים קורפוס שווה מסמכים סנט אוגוסטין והתרגומות שלהם. אנו משתמשים בקורפוס הזה כדי לחקור את תיק ההתאמה לתחום מהטקסטים התנ"ך לעבודות של סנט אוגוסטין. התוצאות מראות את הקשויות לטפל בשפה עם משאבים נמוכים כמו לטינית. ראשית, שמנו לב לחשוב שיש לנו מספיק נתונים, מכיוון שהמערכות לא מגיעות לתוצאות BLEU גבוהות. Regarding domain adaptation, results show how using in-domain data helps systems to achieve a better quality translation.  בנוסף, הבחנו שצריך כמות גבוהה יותר של נתונים כדי לבצע מחדשת מילים יעילה שכוללת מילים בתחום.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>རྒྱུ་དངོས་ཐོག་ཁུངས་མང་པོ་ཡོད་ནའང་ལོ་རྒྱུས་ཀྱི་ཡིག་ཆ་རྙེད་ཀྱི་རྒྱུ་དངོས་ཀྱང་དེ་དག་ཐོག་མའི་སྐད་རིགས་ནང་དུ་ཡོ ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་ལྟ་བུ་ནི་རྒྱུ་དངོས་སྒེར་གྱི་གནས་སྟངས་དང་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་མ་ལག་སྟངས་ལ་ཡར་སྐྱེད་ཚད་གཅིག་པ་རེད། དང་པོ་དེ། ང་ཚོས་དབྱིབས་བཟོ་བརྒྱུད་པ་དང་གཞི་བརྟེན་ནས་བཟོ་རྩིས་འཁོར་གཞི་ཡོད་པའི་མ་ལག་སྐབས་ཆས་གཞི་བསྒྱུར་ཐབས དེ་ནས་ང་ཚོས་Saint Augustine ཡི་གེ་དང་ཁོང་ཚོའི་སྐད་ཡིག་ལས་མཉམ་འབྱུང་བའི་མཐུན་འབྲེལ་ཞིག་བཟོ་བ་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་ཀྱི་རྩིས་པ་འདི་སྤྱད་ནས་ཡིག་ཆ་ཚིག་ལས་དབུགས་ཁུལ་གྱི་བཟོ་བཅོས་རྣམ་པ་ཞིག་གཟུགས་རྩལ་བ་དང་། རྐྱེན་འབྲས་བ་དེའི་དཀའ་ངལ་ཡོད་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་ཉུང་བའི་བཟོ་བཅོས་ལ་མངོན་འཆར་བྱེད། དང་པོ་བརྗོད་ཀྱིས། ང་ཚོར་ཤེས་དུ་ཡོད་པའི་གལ་ཆེན་རྐྱེན་གྱིས་ཡིག་ཆ་ཡོད་པ་རྒྱུ་མཚན་ནི། Regarding domain adaptation, results show how using in-domain data helps systems to achieve a better quality translation. ད་དུང་། ངེད་ཚོར་མཐོང་ནི་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ཡིག་སྒྲུབ་གྱི་ཐ་སྙད་རིམ་ནང་དུ་འཇུག་སྤྱོད་པའི་བརྡ་སྤྲོད་ཀྱི་ཚད་མཐོ་རྩིས་ཡོ</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>A Gradient Boosting-Seq2Seq System for Latin POS Tagging and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lemmatization">Lemmatization</a><fixed-case>S</fixed-case>eq2<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>eq System for <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>atin <fixed-case>POS</fixed-case> Tagging and Lemmatization</title>
      <author><first>Giuseppe G. A.</first><last>Celano</last></author>
      <pages>119–123</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents the system used in the EvaLatin shared task to POS tag and lemmatize Latin. It consists of two components. A gradient boosting machine (LightGBM) is used for POS tagging, mainly fed with pre-computed word embeddings of a window of seven contiguous tokensthe token at hand plus the three preceding and following onesper target feature value. Word embeddings are trained on the texts of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perseus_Digital_Library">Perseus Digital Library</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patrologia_Latina">Patrologia Latina</a>, and Biblioteca Digitale di Testi Tardo Antichi, which together comprise a high number of texts of different genres from the Classical Age to Late Antiquity. Word forms plus the outputted POS labels are used to feed a seq2seq algorithm implemented in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keras">Keras</a> to predict lemmas. The final shared-task accuracies measured for Classical Latin texts are in line with state-of-the-art POS taggers (0.96) and lemmatizers (0.95).</abstract>
      <url hash="179587e2">2020.lt4hala-1.19</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>celano-2020-gradient</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>