<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.readi">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on Tools and Resources to Empower People with REAding DIfficulties (READI)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Núria</first><last>Gala</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Rodrigo</first><last>Wilkens</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-45-0</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="7f25a2c1">2020.readi-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>readi-2020-tools</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Automatically Assess Children’s Reading Skills</title>
      <author><first>Ornella</first><last>Mich</last></author>
      <author><first>Nadia</first><last>Mana</last></author>
      <author><first>Roberto</first><last>Gretter</last></author>
      <author><first>Marco</first><last>Matassoni</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniele</first><last>Falavigna</last></author>
      <pages>20–26</pages>
      <abstract>Assessing reading skills is an important task teachers have to perform at the beginning of a new scholastic year to evaluate the starting level of the class and properly plan next learning activities. Digital tools based on automatic speech recognition (ASR) may be really useful to support teachers in this task, currently very time consuming and prone to human errors. This paper presents a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_application">web application</a> for automatically assessing fluency and accuracy of oral reading in children attending Italian primary and lower secondary schools. Our system, based on ASR technology, implements the Cornoldi’s MT battery, which is a well-known Italian test to assess reading skills. The front-end of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> has been designed following the participatory design approach by involving end users from the beginning of the creation process. Teachers may use our system to both test student’s reading skills and monitor their performance over time. In fact, the system offers an effective graphical visualization of the assessment results for both individual students and entire class. The paper also presents the results of a pilot study to evaluate the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> usability with teachers.</abstract>
      <url hash="66aabc96">2020.readi-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>mich-etal-2020-automatically</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Text Simplification to Help Individuals with Low Vision Read More Fluently</title>
      <author><first>Lauren</first><last>Sauvan</last></author>
      <author><first>Natacha</first><last>Stolowy</last></author>
      <author><first>Carlos</first><last>Aguilar</last></author>
      <author><first>Thomas</first><last>François</last></author>
      <author><first>Núria</first><last>Gala</last></author>
      <author><first>Frédéric</first><last>Matonti</last></author>
      <author><first>Eric</first><last>Castet</last></author>
      <author><first>Aurélie</first><last>Calabrèse</last></author>
      <pages>27–32</pages>
      <abstract>The objective of this work is to introduce text simplification as a potential reading aid to help improve the poor reading performance experienced by visually impaired individuals. As a first step, we explore what makes a text especially complex when read with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_impairment">low vision</a>, by assessing the individual effect of three word properties (frequency, orthographic similarity and length) on reading speed in the presence of Central visual Field Loss (CFL). Individuals with bilateral CFL induced by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macular_degeneration">macular diseases</a> read pairs of French sentences displayed with the self-paced reading method. For each sentence pair, sentence n contained a target word matched with a synonym word of the same length included in sentence n+1. Reading time was recorded for each target word. Given the corpus we used, our results show that (1) word frequency has a significant effect on reading time (the more frequent the faster the reading speed) with larger amplitude (in the range of seconds) compared to normal vision ; (2) word neighborhood size has a significant effect on reading time (the more neighbors the slower the reading speed), this effect being rather small in amplitude, but interestingly reversed compared to normal vision ; (3) word length has no significant effect on reading time. Supporting the development of new and more effective <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assistive_technology">assistive technology</a> to help <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_impairment">low vision</a> is an important and timely issue, with massive potential implications for social and rehabilitation practices. The end goal of this project will be to use our findings to custom text simplification to this specific population and use it as an optimal and efficient reading aid.</abstract>
      <url hash="af173928">2020.readi-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>sauvan-etal-2020-text</bibkey>
    <title_ar>تبسيط النص لمساعدة الأفراد ضعاف البصر قراءة المزيد بطلاقة</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Simplification du texte pour aider les personnes malvoyantes Lire plus couramment</title_fr>
      <title_es>Simplificación de textos para ayudar a las personas con problemas de visión a leer con más fluidez</title_es>
      <title_pt>Simplificação de texto para ajudar pessoas com baixa visão a ler mais fluentemente</title_pt>
      <title_hi>पाठ सरलीकरण कम दृष्टि के साथ व्यक्तियों की मदद करने के लिए और अधिक धाराप्रवाह पढ़ें</title_hi>
      <title_ja>視力の低い個人がより流暢に読書できるようにテキストを簡素化</title_ja>
      <title_zh>文本简化,助视下者益畅读</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Simpliú Téacs chun Cabhrú le Daoine Aonair a bhfuil Léargas orthu Léigh Níos Líofa</title_ga>
      <title_ru>Упрощение текста, чтобы помочь людям с низким зрением читать более свободно</title_ru>
      <title_el>Απλοποίηση κειμένου για να βοηθήσει άτομα με χαμηλή όραση Διαβάστε πιο γρήγορα</title_el>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A szöveg egyszerűsítése, hogy segítsen az alacsony látású személyeknek Read More Fluently</title_hu>
      <title_it>Semplificazione del testo per aiutare le persone con scarsa visione</title_it>
      <title_kk>Көрініс төмен көріністерді көмектесу үшін мәтінді қарапайым оқуName</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Teksto supaprastinimas, siekiant padėti asmenims lengviau skaityti mažą viziją</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Name</title_mk>
      <title_ml>കുറഞ്ഞ ദര്‍ശനം കൊണ്ടുള്ള സഹായിക്കുന്നവര്‍ക്ക് വായിക്കാന്‍ വായിക്കുക</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Simplifikazzjoni tat-test biex jgħin lill-individwi b’viżjoni baxxa jaqraw b’mod aktar fluwidu</title_mt>
      <title_ms>Simplifikasi Teks untuk Bantu Individual dengan Pemandangan rendah Baca Lebih Mudah</title_ms>
      <title_ro>Simplificarea textului pentru a ajuta persoanele cu vedere slabă Citește mai mult Fluent</title_ro>
      <title_no>Comment</title_no>
      <title_pl>Uproszczenie tekstu, aby pomóc osobom z niskim wzrokiem Czytaj więcej płynnie</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Jednostavnost teksta za pomoć pojedincima s niskom vizijom pročitati lakše</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_mn>Хүн төрөлхтний харагдаж буй хүмүүст туслахын тулд Текст хялбарчлал илүү шингэн унших</title_mn>
      <title_so>Isku fududeynta ee caawimaadda dhaqaalaha aragtida yar akhri Faahfaahin dheeraad ah</title_so>
      <title_sv>Textförenkling för att hjälpa personer med nedsatt syn Läs mer Flytande</title_sv>
      <title_ur>Name</title_ur>
      <title_ta>Comment</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Comment</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Thay đổi cấu trúc văn bản giúp người có khả năng nhìn thấp</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Опростяване на текста, за да се помогне на хора с ниско зрение Прочетете повече плавно</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Tekst Vereenvoudiging om mensen met slecht zicht te helpen vloeiend meer te lezen</title_nl>
      <title_de>Textvereinfachung, um Menschen mit eingeschränktem Sehvermögen zu helfen</title_de>
      <title_id>Simplifikasi Teks untuk membantu Individual dengan Pandangan rendah Baca Lebih Mudah</title_id>
      <title_hr>Jednostavnost teksta za pomoć pojedincima s niskim vidom pročitati lakše</title_hr>
      <title_ko>글씨를 간소화하여 시력이 저하된 사람이 더욱 유창하게 읽을 수 있도록 돕다</title_ko>
      <title_da>Tekstforenkling for at hjælpe personer med nedsat syn Læs mere Flydende</title_da>
      <title_sw>Ukurahisha wa maandishi kwa kuwasaidia watu wenye Visheni ya chini Soma zaidi</title_sw>
      <title_sq>Simplifikimi i tekstit për të ndihmuar individët me vizion të ulët të lexojnë më lehtë</title_sq>
      <title_fa>Comment</title_fa>
      <title_hy>Comment</title_hy>
      <title_am>text-tool-action</title_am>
      <title_af>Comment</title_af>
      <title_bs>Jednostavnost teksta za pomoć pojedincima s niskom vizijom pročitati lakše</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Simplificació del text per ajudar individus amb baixa visió llegir més fluentment</title_ca>
      <title_bn>নিম্ন ভিশন দিয়ে সাহায্য করার জন্য টেক্সট সাধারণ করুন</title_bn>
      <title_cs>Zjednodušení textu, které pomáhá osobám se slabým zrakem Číst více plynule</title_cs>
      <title_et>Teksti lihtsustamine, et aidata halva nägemisega inimestel Loe edasi sujuvalt</title_et>
      <title_fi>Tekstin yksinkertaistaminen auttaa heikkonäköisiä henkilöitä Lue lisää sujuvasti</title_fi>
      <title_az>Aşağı Gözləri ilə İnsanlara Yardım etmək üçün Metin Basitleşdirilməsi</title_az>
      <title_tr>Otlary Az Görnüş bilen Ýabşyrmak üçin Metin Beslemek</title_tr>
      <title_jv>Simplification</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Poenostavitev besedila za pomoč posameznikom s slabim vidom Preberi več</title_sk>
      <title_he>פשטות טקסט כדי לעזור לאנשים עם חזון נמוך לקרוא באופן נוח יותר</title_he>
      <title_bo>ཕལ་མཐོང་བའི་མཐོང་སྣང་ཉར་མེད་པའི་རོགས་རམ་སྟངས་སྒྲིག་འགོད་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>الهدف من هذا العمل هو تقديم تبسيط النص كأداة مساعدة محتملة للقراءة للمساعدة في تحسين أداء القراءة الضعيف الذي يعاني منه الأشخاص ضعاف البصر. كخطوة أولى ، نستكشف ما الذي يجعل النص معقدًا بشكل خاص عند قراءته بضعف الرؤية ، من خلال تقييم التأثير الفردي لخصائص ثلاث كلمات (التكرار والتشابه الإملائي والطول) على سرعة القراءة في وجود فقدان المجال البصري المركزي (CFL) . الأفراد الذين يعانون من CFL الثنائي الناجم عن أمراض البقعة يقرأون أزواجًا من الجمل الفرنسية المعروضة بطريقة القراءة الذاتية. لكل زوج جملة ، احتوت الجملة n على كلمة مستهدفة متطابقة مع كلمة مرادفة من نفس الطول مدرجة في الجملة n + 1. تم تسجيل وقت القراءة لكل كلمة مستهدفة. بالنظر إلى المجموعة التي استخدمناها ، تُظهر نتائجنا أن (1) تردد الكلمات له تأثير كبير على وقت القراءة (كلما زاد تكرار سرعة القراءة أسرع) بسعة أكبر (في نطاق الثواني) مقارنة بالرؤية العادية ؛ (2) حجم حي الكلمة له تأثير كبير على وقت القراءة (كلما زاد عدد الجيران كانت سرعة القراءة أبطأ) ، وهذا التأثير صغير إلى حد ما في السعة ، ولكنه انعكس بشكل مثير للاهتمام مقارنة بالرؤية العادية ؛ (3) طول الكلمة ليس له تأثير معنوي على وقت القراءة. يعد دعم تطوير التكنولوجيا المساعدة الجديدة والأكثر فعالية لمساعدة ضعف البصر مسألة مهمة وفي الوقت المناسب ، مع آثار محتملة هائلة على الممارسات الاجتماعية وإعادة التأهيل. الهدف النهائي
سيستخدم هذا المشروع النتائج التي توصلنا إليها لتبسيط النص المخصص لهذه الفئة المحددة من السكان واستخدامها كأداة مساعدة للقراءة مثالية وفعالة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>O objetivo deste trabalho é apresentar a simplificação de texto como um potencial auxiliar de leitura para ajudar a melhorar o baixo desempenho de leitura vivenciado por pessoas com deficiência visual. Como primeiro passo, exploramos o que torna um texto especialmente complexo quando lido com baixa visão, avaliando o efeito individual de três propriedades de palavras (frequência, semelhança ortográfica e comprimento) na velocidade de leitura na presença de perda de campo visual central (CFL) . Indivíduos com LFC bilateral induzida por doenças maculares leram pares de frases em francês exibidas com o método de leitura auto-ritmada. Para cada par de frases, a frase n continha uma palavra-alvo combinada com uma palavra sinônima do mesmo comprimento incluída na frase n+1. O tempo de leitura foi registrado para cada palavra alvo. Dado o corpus utilizado, nossos resultados mostram que (1) a frequência das palavras tem um efeito significativo no tempo de leitura (quanto mais frequente, maior a velocidade de leitura) com maior amplitude (na faixa de segundos) em comparação com a visão normal; (2) o tamanho da vizinhança da palavra tem um efeito significativo no tempo de leitura (quanto mais vizinhos, mais lenta a velocidade de leitura), sendo este efeito bastante pequeno em amplitude, mas curiosamente invertido em comparação com a visão normal; (3) o comprimento da palavra não tem efeito significativo no tempo de leitura. Apoiar o desenvolvimento de tecnologias assistivas novas e mais eficazes para ajudar a baixa visão é uma questão importante e oportuna, com enormes implicações potenciais para as práticas sociais e de reabilitação. O objetivo final de
este projeto será usar nossas descobertas para simplificar o texto personalizado para essa população específica e usá-lo como um auxílio de leitura ideal e eficiente.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>El objetivo de este trabajo es introducir la simplificación del texto como una posible ayuda de lectura para ayudar a mejorar el pobre rendimiento de lectura que experimentan las personas con discapacidad visual. Como primer paso, exploramos qué hace que un texto sea especialmente complejo cuando se lee con baja visión, evaluando el efecto individual de las propiedades de tres palabras (frecuencia, similitud ortográfica y longitud) en la velocidad de lectura en presencia de pérdida de campo visual central (CFL). Los individuos con CFL bilateral inducida por enfermedades maculares leen pares de frases en francés mostradas con el método de lectura autodidacta. Para cada par de oraciones, la oración n contenía una palabra objetivo que coincidía con una palabra sinónimo de la misma longitud incluida en la oración n+1. Se registró el tiempo de lectura para cada palabra objetivo. Dado el corpus que utilizamos, nuestros resultados muestran que (1) la frecuencia de las palabras tiene un efecto significativo en el tiempo de lectura (cuanto más frecuente, más rápida es la velocidad de lectura) con mayor amplitud (en el rango de segundos) en comparación con la visión normal; (2) el tamaño del vecindario de palabras tiene un efecto significativo en el tiempo de lectura (cuanto más vecinos más lenta es la velocidad de lectura), siendo este efecto bastante pequeño en amplitud, pero curiosamente invertido en comparación con la visión normal; (3) la longitud de la palabra no tiene un efecto significativo en el tiempo de lectura. Apoyar el desarrollo de tecnología de asistencia nueva y más eficaz para ayudar a la baja visión es un tema importante y oportuno, con enormes implicaciones potenciales para las prácticas sociales y de rehabilitación. El objetivo final de
este proyecto será utilizar nuestros hallazgos para simplificar el texto a medida para esta población específica y usarlo como una ayuda de lectura óptima y eficiente.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>L'objectif de ce travail est d'introduire la simplification du texte comme aide à la lecture potentielle pour aider à améliorer les mauvaises performances de lecture des personnes malvoyantes. Dans un premier temps, nous explorons ce qui rend un texte particulièrement complexe lorsqu'il est lu en basse vision, en évaluant l'effet individuel de trois propriétés des mots (fréquence, similitude orthographique et longueur) sur la vitesse de lecture en présence d'une perte de champ visuel central (CFL). Les personnes atteintes de LCF bilatérale induite par des maladies maculaires lisent des paires de phrases en français affichées avec la méthode de lecture auto-rythmée. Pour chaque paire de phrases, la phrase n contenait un mot cible correspondant à un mot synonyme de même longueur inclus dans la phrase n+1. Le temps de lecture a été enregistré pour chaque mot cible. Compte tenu du corpus que nous avons utilisé, nos résultats montrent que (1) la fréquence des mots a un effet significatif sur le temps de lecture (plus la vitesse de lecture est fréquente) avec une amplitude plus grande (de l'ordre des secondes) par rapport à la vision normale ; (2) la taille du voisinage des mots a un effet significatif sur le temps de lecture (plus voisins plus la vitesse de lecture est lente), cet effet étant plutôt faible en amplitude, mais inversement intéressant par rapport à la vision normale ; (3) la longueur des mots n'a pas d'effet significatif sur le temps de lecture. Soutenir le développement de technologies d'assistance nouvelles et plus efficaces pour aider la basse vision est une question importante et opportune, avec des implications potentielles énormes pour les pratiques sociales et de réadaptation. L'objectif final de
ce projet sera d'utiliser nos résultats pour personnaliser la simplification de texte à cette population spécifique et de l'utiliser comme aide à la lecture optimale et efficace.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>本研究の目的は、視覚障害者が経験する貧弱な読書パフォーマンスを改善するための潜在的な読書支援としてテキストの簡略化を導入することである。 最初のステップとして、中央視野損失（ CFL ）の存在下で、3つの単語特性（頻度、正書法の類似性、および長さ）が読み取り速度に与える個々の影響を評価することによって、低視野で読むときにテキストを特に複雑にするものを探求します。 黄斑疾患によって誘発された両側CFLを有する個人は、自己ペースの読み取り法で表示されたフランス語の文章のペアを読み取ります。 各文ペアについて、文ｎは、文ｎ ＋ １に含まれる同じ長さの同義語と一致する対象語を含んでいた。 対象単語ごとに読み取り時間を記録した。 我々が使用したコーパスを考えると、我々の結果は、(1)単語の頻度は、通常の視覚と比較して大きな振幅（秒の範囲内）を持つ読み取り時間に有意な影響（頻度が高いほど読み取り速度が速い）を与えること、(2)単語の近隣サイズは、読み取り時間に有意な影響を持つこと（近隣の人ほど読み取り速度が遅い）、この効果は振幅がかなり小さいが、通常の視覚と比較して興味深い逆転すること、(3)単語の長さは、読み取り時間に有意な影響を持たないことを示している。 低視力を助けるための新しい、より効果的な支援技術の開発を支援することは、重要でタイムリーな問題であり、社会的およびリハビリテーション実践に大きな潜在的影響を与えます。の最終目標
このプロジェクトでは、調査結果を使用して、この特定の母集団にテキストの簡略化をカスタマイズし、最適で効率的な読み取り支援として使用します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>所以引入文本简化为潜读辅助工具,以助改善视障士之读为不佳。 第一步,评估三单词属性(频率,正交相似性与长短)在中央视野丧(CFL),以观其个体,以求下视力阅读所以异也。 由黄斑病者双侧CFL读以自定进度读法者对法语句。 凡句之对, n 包一单词,当单词与句 n+1 同长同义词匹。 每单词记读日月。 鉴吾用之语料库,吾之的结果表明(1)视,有大振幅(于几秒钟之内)者单词频率读时(读之愈数,读取愈疾)有显之。 (2)字邻域大小著于读时(邻数越多,读速越慢),其效振幅小,反于常视; (3)字长于读时无显损。 佐开发新者,所以助下视也;持时者,所以助下也。 最终目标
此目将用吾辈定义文本简化至此特定者,并以为最佳、有效者读辅助工具。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>इस काम का उद्देश्य दृष्टिहीन व्यक्तियों द्वारा अनुभव किए गए खराब पढ़ने के प्रदर्शन को बेहतर बनाने में मदद करने के लिए एक संभावित पठन सहायता के रूप में पाठ सरलीकरण को पेश करना है। पहले चरण के रूप में, हम यह पता लगाते हैं कि केंद्रीय दृश्य क्षेत्र हानि (सीएफएल) की उपस्थिति में पढ़ने की गति पर तीन शब्द गुणों (आवृत्ति, ऑर्थोग्राफिक समानता और लंबाई) के व्यक्तिगत प्रभाव का आकलन करके, कम दृष्टि के साथ पढ़ने पर एक पाठ को विशेष रूप से जटिल बनाता है। मैकुलर रोगों से प्रेरित द्विपक्षीय सीएफएल वाले व्यक्ति स्व-पुस्तक पढ़ने की विधि के साथ प्रदर्शित फ्रांसीसी वाक्यों के जोड़े पढ़ते हैं। प्रत्येक वाक्य जोड़ी के लिए, वाक्य n में एक लक्ष्य शब्द होता है जो वाक्य n + 1 में शामिल समान लंबाई के समानार्थी शब्द के साथ मेल खाता है। प्रत्येक लक्ष्य शब्द के लिए पढ़ने का समय दर्ज किया गया था। हमारे द्वारा उपयोग किए जाने वाले कॉर्पस को देखते हुए, हमारे परिणाम बताते हैं कि (1) शब्द आवृत्ति का सामान्य दृष्टि की तुलना में बड़े आयाम (सेकंड की सीमा में) के साथ पढ़ने के समय (पढ़ने की गति जितनी अधिक बार तेज होती है) पर महत्वपूर्ण प्रभाव पड़ता है; (2) शब्द पड़ोस के आकार का पढ़ने के समय पर एक महत्वपूर्ण प्रभाव पड़ता है (अधिक पड़ोसियों को पढ़ने की गति धीमी होती है), यह प्रभाव आयाम में छोटा होता है, लेकिन सामान्य दृष्टि की तुलना में दिलचस्प रूप से उलट जाता है; (3) शब्द की लंबाई का पढ़ने के समय पर कोई महत्वपूर्ण प्रभाव नहीं पड़ता है। कम दृष्टि में मदद करने के लिए नई और अधिक प्रभावी सहायक प्रौद्योगिकी के विकास का समर्थन करना एक महत्वपूर्ण और समय पर मुद्दा है, जिसमें सामाजिक और पुनर्वास प्रथाओं के लिए बड़े पैमाने पर संभावित निहितार्थ हैं। का अंतिम लक्ष्य
इस परियोजना के लिए इस विशिष्ट आबादी के लिए कस्टम पाठ सरलीकरण के लिए हमारे निष्कर्षों का उपयोग करने के लिए और एक इष्टतम और कुशल पढ़ने की सहायता के रूप में यह उपयोग करने के लिए किया जाएगा।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Is é cuspóir na hoibre seo ná simpliú téacs a thabhairt isteach mar áis léitheoireachta fhéideartha chun cabhrú le feabhas a chur ar an drochfheidhmíocht léitheoireachta a bhíonn ag daoine le lagamhairc. Mar chéad chéim, déanaimid iniúchadh ar cad a dhéanann téacs an-chasta agus é á léamh le hamharc lag, trí mheasúnú a dhéanamh ar éifeacht aonair airíonna trí fhocal (minicíocht, cosúlacht ortagrafach agus fad) ar luas léitheoireachta i láthair Caillteanas Réimse Amhairc Lárnach (CFL). . Léann daoine aonair a bhfuil CFL déthaobhach acu de bharr galair mhacúlach péirí abairtí Fraincise ar taispeáint leis an modh léitheoireachta féinluais. I gcás gach péire abairte, bhí spriocfhocal in abairt n meaitseáilte le focal comhchiallach den fhad céanna in abairt n+1. Taifeadadh am léitheoireachta do gach spriocfhocal. I bhfianaise an chorpais a d’úsáideamar, léiríonn ár dtorthaí go bhfuil (1) minicíocht focal tionchar suntasach ar am léitheoireachta (dá minice is tapúla an luas léitheoireachta) le aimplitiúid níos mó (i raon na soicind) i gcomparáid le fís gnáth; (2) tá tionchar suntasach ag méid comharsanachta na bhfocal ar an am léitheoireachta (dá mhéad comharsana is moille an luas léitheoireachta), tá an éifeacht seo sách beag i aimplitiúid, ach go suimiúil droim ar ais i gcomparáid le gnáthfhís; (3) níl aon éifeacht shuntasach ag fad focal ar am léitheoireachta. Is saincheist thábhachtach agus thráthúil é tacú le forbairt teicneolaíochta cúnta nua agus níos éifeachtaí chun cabhrú le lagamhairc, le himpleachtaí ollmhóra féideartha do chleachtais shóisialta agus athshlánúcháin. An sprioc deiridh de
Beidh an tionscadal seo chun ár dtorthaí a úsáid chun simpliú téacs a shaincheapadh don daonra sonrach seo agus é a úsáid mar áis léitheoireachta optamach agus éifeachtach.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ru>Целью этой работы является введение упрощения текста в качестве потенциального средства чтения, чтобы помочь улучшить плохое чтение, испытываемое людьми с нарушениями зрения. В качестве первого шага мы исследуем, что делает текст особенно сложным при чтении с низким зрением, оценивая индивидуальное влияние трех свойств слова (частота, ортографическое сходство и длина) на скорость чтения в присутствии центральной потери поля зрения (ЦПВП). Лица с двусторонним CFL, индуцированным макулярными заболеваниями, читают пары французских предложений, отображаемых с помощью метода самостоятельного считывания. Для каждой пары предложений предложение n содержало целевое слово, соответствующее синонимичному слову одинаковой длины, включенному в предложение n+1. Время считывания записывалось для каждого целевого слова. Учитывая корпус, который мы использовали, наши результаты показывают, что (1) частота слов оказывает значительное влияние на время чтения (чем чаще скорость чтения) с большей амплитудой (в диапазоне секунд) по сравнению с нормальным зрением; (2) размер окружения слова оказывает значительное влияние на время чтения (чем больше соседей, тем медленнее скорость чтения), этот эффект является довольно небольшим по амплитуде, но, что интересно, обратным по сравнению с нормальным зрением; (3) длина слова не оказывает существенного влияния на время чтения. Поддержка разработки новых и более эффективных вспомогательных технологий, способствующих ухудшению зрения, является важным и своевременным вопросом, чреватым огромными потенциальными последствиями для социальной практики и практики реабилитации. Конечная цель
этот проект будет использовать наши выводы для упрощения текста для этой конкретной популяции и использовать его в качестве оптимального и эффективного средства чтения.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ka>ეს პროექტი იქნება ჩვენი მონაცემების გამოყენება ამ განსაკუთრებული მოსახლეობისთვის ტექსტის განსაკუთრებისთვის და გამოყენება ის როგორც ოპტიმალური და ეფექტი</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Questo progetto sarà quello di utilizzare i nostri risultati per semplificare il testo personalizzato a questa specifica popolazione e usarlo come un ausilio di lettura ottimale ed efficiente.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_el>Αυτό το έργο θα είναι να χρησιμοποιήσουμε τα ευρήματά μας για την απλούστευση προσαρμοσμένων κειμένων σε αυτόν τον συγκεκριμένο πληθυσμό και να το χρησιμοποιήσουμε ως βέλτιστο και αποτελεσματικό βοήθημα ανάγνωσης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a projekt arra irányul, hogy az eredményeinket arra használjuk fel, hogy az adott lakosság számára egyedi szövegeket egyszerűsítsünk, és optimális és hatékony olvasósegédként használjuk fel.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл жоба біздің табуларымызды осы адамдарға өзгертілген мәтінді қарапайымдастыру үшін қолданатын және оқу көмегі ретінде қолданатын.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Овој проект ќе биде да ги искористиме нашите откритија за соодветно поедноставување на текстот за оваа специфична популација и да го искористиме како оптимална и ефикасна помош за читање.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>projek ini akan menggunakan penemuan kita untuk mempermudahkan teks suai untuk populasi spesifik ini dan menggunakannya sebagai bantuan pembacaan yang optimal dan efisien.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പദ്ധതിയില്‍ ഞങ്ങളുടെ കണ്ടുപിടികള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത് ഈ പ്രത്യേകിച്ചുള്ള ആളുകള്‍ക്ക് വേണ്ടി പദാവലി ലളിതമാക്കുവാ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>dan il-proġett se jkun li jintużaw is-sejbiet tagħna biex issimplifika t-test personalizzat għal din il-popolazzjoni speċifika u jużaha bħala għajnuna għall-aqwa u effiċjenti fil-qari.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ төсөл бидний ололтуудыг энэ тодорхой хүн амын хувьд хувийн текст хялбарчлалын тулд ашиглаж, нээлттэй, үр дүнтэй унших тусламж болно.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Acest proiect va fi de a utiliza constatările noastre pentru simplificarea textului personalizat pentru această populație specifică și de a-l utiliza ca un ajutor optim și eficient de citire.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj projekt će biti da iskoristimo naše nalaze za pojednostavljenje teksta u određenoj populaciji i koristimo ga kao optimalnu i efikasnu pomoć čitanja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය අපේ හොයාගන්න පුළුවන් විතරයි මේ විශේෂ ජාතියෙන් පුළුවන් පාළුවන් පරික්ෂණය සඳහා ඒක ව</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Projekadan waxey u isticmaali doontaa baaritaankeenna si ay u isticmaalaan fududaanka qoraalka ee dadkan cayiman una isticmaalaan caawimaad la akhriso oo faa’iido ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_lt>Šis projektas bus naudojamas mūsų išvadomis supaprastinti tekstus konkrečiai gyventojų grupei ir jį naudoti kaip optimalią ir veiksmingą skaitymo pagalbą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_sv>Detta projekt kommer att vara att använda våra resultat för att anpassa textförenkling till denna specifika befolkning och använda den som ett optimalt och effektivt läshjälpmedel.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>this project will be to use our findings to custom text simplification to this specific population and use it as an optimal and efficient reading aid.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_pl>Projekt ten polega na wykorzystaniu naszych wyników do niestandardowego uproszczenia tekstu dla tej konkretnej populacji i wykorzystaniu go jako optymalnego i skutecznego pomocy w czytaniu.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Denne prosjektet vil vera å bruka våre finningar for å sjølvvalde tekstforenkling til denne spesifikke populasjonen og bruka det som optimal og effektivt lesingshjelp.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ur>یہ پروژہ یہ ہے کہ ہمارے نتیجے اس مخصوص جماعت کے لئے تنبیہ پیغام کے لئے استعمال کریں اور اسے اچھی اور عمدہ پڑھنے کی مدد کے طور پر استعمال کریں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu loyihani bu muammolar matnning soddalash uchun ishlatiladi va uni optik va effektiv o'qish yordam sifatida ishlatish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>dự án này sẽ dùng kết quả của chúng ta để mô phỏng văn bản mô phỏng con người đặc biệt này và sử dụng nó như một trợ giúp đọc tối ưu và hiệu quả.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Целта на тази работа е да се въведе опростяване на текста като потенциално средство за четене, което да помогне за подобряване на лошото четене, преживяно от хора със зрително увреждане. Като първа стъпка изследваме какво прави текста особено сложен при четене с ниско зрение, като оценяваме индивидуалния ефект на трите думи свойства (честота, ортографска прилика и дължина) върху скоростта на четене в присъствието на Централна загуба на зрително поле. Лица с двустранна ХХЛ, индуцирана от макулни заболявания, четат двойки френски изречения, показани по метода на самозадвижване. За всяка двойка изречения изречение n съдържа целева дума, съответстваща на синоним дума със същата дължина, включена в изречение n+1. За всяка целева дума е записано време за четене. Предвид използвания от нас корпус резултатите показват, че (1) честотата на думите има значителен ефект върху времето за четене (колкото по-често, толкова по-бърза е скоростта на четене) с по-голяма амплитуда (в диапазона на секунди) в сравнение с нормалното зрение; (2) размерът на думата съседство има значителен ефект върху времето за четене (колкото повече съседи, толкова по-бавна е скоростта на четене), този ефект е доста малък по амплитуда, но интересно обратен в сравнение с нормалното зрение; (3) дължината на думата няма значителен ефект върху времето за четене. Подкрепата за развитието на нови и по-ефективни асистиращи технологии за подпомагане на слабото зрение е важен и навременен въпрос с огромни потенциални последици за социалните и рехабилитационните практики. Крайната цел на
Този проект ще бъде да използваме нашите констатации за персонализирано опростяване на текста за тази конкретна популация и да го използваме като оптимално и ефективно средство за четене.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Cilj ovog rada je uvođenje pojednostavljivanja teksta kao potencijalnu pomoć čitanja kako bi pomoglo poboljšati lošu učinku čitanja koja su iskusila vizualno oštećene osobe. Kao prvi korak, istražujemo ono što čini tekst posebno složen kada čitamo s niskim vidom, procjenjivajući pojedinačni učinak tri riječne vlasništva (frekvencija, ortografska sličnost i dužin a) na brzinu čitanja u prisutnosti gubitka središnjeg vizualnog polja (CFL). Individualni s bilateralnim CFL-om induciranim makularnim bolestima čitaju par francuskih rečenica koji se pokazuju s metodom čitanja samostalno. Za svaki par rečenica, rečenica n sadržala je ciljnu riječ odgovarajuću sinonim riječi iste dužine uključene u rečenicu n+1. Čitanje je snimljeno za svaku ciljnu riječ. S obzirom na korpus koji smo koristili, naši rezultati pokazuju da (1) frekvencija riječi ima značajan učinak na vrijeme čitanja (što češće brže brže čitanja) s većom amplitudom (u rasponu sekundi) u usporedbi s normalnim vidom; (2) veličin a riječi susjedstva ima značajan učinak na vrijeme čitanja (što više susjeda usporava brzinu čitanja), taj učinak je prilično mali u proširenju, ali interesantno okrenut u usporedbi s normalnim vidom; (3) Dužina riječi nema značajnog učinka na vrijeme čitanja. Podrška razvoju nove i učinkovitije pomoćne tehnologije za pomoć niskog vida je važan i vrijedno pitanje, s velikim potencijalnim posljedicama za prakse socijalne i rehabilitacije. Cilj kraja
Ovaj projekt će biti iskoristiti naše nalaze za pojednostavljanje teksta u određenoj populaciji i koristiti ga kao optimalnu i učinkovitu pomoć čitanja.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Ziel dieser Arbeit ist es, Textvereinfachung als potenzielle Lesehilfe einzuführen, um die schlechte Leseleistung sehbehinderter Menschen zu verbessern. In einem ersten Schritt untersuchen wir, was einen Text besonders komplex macht, wenn er mit Sehschwäche gelesen wird, indem wir den individuellen Effekt von drei Worteigenschaften (Frequenz, orthographische Ähnlichkeit und Länge) auf die Lesegeschwindigkeit bei Vorhandensein von Central Visual Field Loss (CFL) beurteilen. Personen mit bilateraler CFL induziert durch Makulaerkrankungen lesen Paare französischer Sätze, die mit der selbstgesteuerten Lesemethode dargestellt werden. Für jedes Satzpaar enthielt Satz n ein Zielwort, das mit einem Synonymwort der gleichen Länge übereinstimmt, das im Satz n+1 enthalten ist. Die Lesezeit wurde für jedes Zielwort aufgezeichnet. Angesichts des verwendeten Korpus zeigen unsere Ergebnisse, dass (1) Wortfrequenz einen signifikanten Einfluss auf die Lesezeit hat (je häufiger, desto schneller die Lesegeschwindigkeit) mit größerer Amplitude (im Bereich von Sekunden) im Vergleich zu normalem Sehen; (2) Wortnachbarkeitsgröße hat einen signifikanten Einfluss auf die Lesezeit (je mehr Nachbarn, desto langsamer die Lesegeschwindigkeit), dieser Effekt ist eher klein in der Amplitude, aber interessanterweise umgekehrt im Vergleich zu normalem Sehen; (3) Wortlänge hat keinen signifikanten Einfluss auf die Lesezeit. Die Unterstützung der Entwicklung neuer und effektiverer Hilfstechnologien zur Unterstützung von Sehschwäche ist ein wichtiges und zeitgemäßes Thema, das erhebliche potenzielle Auswirkungen auf soziale und Rehabilitationspraktiken hat. Das Endziel von
In diesem Projekt wird es darum gehen, unsere Erkenntnisse zur individuellen Textvereinfachung für diese spezifische Bevölkerung zu nutzen und sie als optimale und effiziente Lesehilfe zu nutzen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_nl>Het doel van dit werk is om tekstvereenvoudiging te introduceren als een potentieel leeshulpmiddel om de slechte leesprestaties van slechtzienden te verbeteren. In een eerste stap onderzoeken we wat een tekst bijzonder complex maakt bij slechtziend lezen, door het individuele effect van drie woordeigenschappen (frequentie, orthografische gelijkenis en lengte) op leessnelheid te beoordelen in aanwezigheid van Central Visual Field Loss (CFL). Personen met bilaterale CFL veroorzaakt door maculaziekten lezen paren Franse zinnen weergegeven met de zelftempo leesmethode. Voor elk zinnenpaar bevatte zin n een doelwoord dat overeenkwam met een synoniemwoord van dezelfde lengte in zin n+1. De leestijd werd geregistreerd voor elk doelwoord. Gezien het gebruikte corpus tonen onze resultaten aan dat (1) woordfrequentie een significant effect heeft op de leestijd (hoe frequenter hoe sneller de leessnelheid) met een grotere amplitude (in het bereik van seconden) in vergelijking met normaal zicht; (2) de grootte van de woordbuurt heeft een significant effect op leestijd (hoe meer buren hoe langzamer de leessnelheid), dit effect is vrij klein in amplitude, maar interessant omgekeerd in vergelijking met normaal zicht; (3) woordlengte heeft geen significant effect op de leestijd. Het ondersteunen van de ontwikkeling van nieuwe en effectievere ondersteunende technologie om slechtziend zicht te helpen is een belangrijk en tijdig probleem, met enorme potentiële gevolgen voor sociale en revalidatiepraktijken. Het einddoel van
Dit project zal zijn om onze bevindingen te gebruiken om tekst vereenvoudiging op maat te maken voor deze specifieke bevolking en het te gebruiken als een optimaal en efficiënt leeshulpmiddel.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Formålet med dette arbejde er at indføre tekstforenkling som et potentielt læsehjælpemiddel for at hjælpe med at forbedre den dårlige læsevne hos synshæmmede personer. Som et første skridt undersøger vi, hvad der gør en tekst særligt kompleks, når den læses med svagt syn, ved at vurdere den individuelle effekt af tre ord egenskaber (hyppighed, ortografisk lighed og længde) på læsehastigheden i tilstedeværelse af Central Visual Field Loss (CFL). Personer med bilateral CFL induceret af makulære sygdomme læser par franske sætninger vist med selvstændig læsesmetode. For hvert sætningspar indeholdt sætning n et målord matchet med et synonymt ord af samme længde inkluderet i sætning n+1. Læsetid blev registreret for hvert målord. I betragtning af det korpus, vi anvendte, viser vores resultater, at (1) ordfrekvens har en betydelig effekt på læsetiden (jo hyppigere jo hurtigere læsehastighed) med større amplitude (inden for sekunder) sammenlignet med normalt syn; (2) ord naboskabsstørrelse har en betydelig effekt på læsetiden (jo flere naboer jo langsommere læsehastighed), denne effekt er temmelig lille i amplitude, men interessant omvendt sammenlignet med normalt syn; (3) Ordlængden har ingen væsentlig indvirkning på læsetiden. Støtte til udvikling af ny og mere effektiv hjælpeteknologi til nedsat syn er et vigtigt og rettidigt spørgsmål med massive potentielle konsekvenser for social praksis og rehabilitering. Det endelige mål
Dette projekt vil være at bruge vores resultater til skræddersyet tekst forenkling til denne specifikke befolkning og bruge det som et optimalt og effektivt læsehjælpemiddel.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Tujuan pekerjaan ini adalah untuk memperkenalkan penyimplifikasi teks sebagai bantuan pembacaan potensial untuk membantu meningkatkan prestasi pembacaan yang buruk yang mengalami individu yang berpengaruh visual. Sebagai langkah pertama, kami mengeksplorasi apa yang membuat teks khusus kompleks ketika dibaca dengan penglihatan rendah, dengan menilai efek individu dari tiga properti kata (frekuensi, persamaan ortografik dan panjang) pada kecepatan pembacaan di hadapan Kehilangan Field Visual Tengah (CFL). Individual dengan CFL bilateral yang disebabkan oleh penyakit makular membaca sepasang kalimat Perancis yang ditampilkan dengan metode pembacaan sendiri. Untuk setiap pasangan kalimat, kalimat n mengandung kata sasaran yang cocok dengan kata sinonim panjang yang sama termasuk dalam kalimat n+1. Waktu membaca direkam untuk setiap kata sasaran. Mengingat corpus yang kami gunakan, hasil kami menunjukkan bahwa (1) frekuensi kata memiliki efek signifikan pada waktu pembacaan (semakin sering kecepatan pembacaan) dengan amplitud yang lebih besar (dalam jangkauan detik) dibandingkan dengan penglihatan normal; (2) ukuran lingkungan kata memiliki efek yang signifikan pada waktu membaca (semakin banyak tetangga semakin lambat kecepatan membaca), efek ini agak kecil dalam amplitud, tetapi menarik terbalik dibandingkan dengan penglihatan normal; (3) panjang kata tidak memiliki efek signifikan pada waktu membaca. Membantu pengembangan teknologi asisten baru dan lebih efektif untuk membantu penglihatan rendah adalah masalah penting dan tepat waktu, dengan implikasi potensial besar untuk praktek sosial dan rehabilitasi. Tujuan akhir
proyek ini akan menggunakan penemuan kita untuk menyederhanakan teks sesuai untuk populasi spesifik ini dan menggunakannya sebagai bantuan pembacaan yang optimal dan efisien.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>هدف این کار این است که ساده‌سازی متن را به عنوان کمک پتانسیل خواندن برای کمک به بهترین عملکرد خواندن بیچاره‌ای که توسط افراد ناتوان به نظر می‌رسد معرفی کنیم. به عنوان یک قدم اول، ما تحقیق می‌کنیم چه چیزی متن را مخصوصا پیچیده می‌کند وقتی با دیده‌های پایین خوانده می‌شود، با ارزیابی اثر شخصی از سه ویژه‌های کلمه (فرکانس، شباهت orthographic و طول) بر سرعت خواندن در حضور خسارت‌های زمینه‌ی بینایی مرکزی individuals with two-teral CFL induced by macular diseases read pairs of French sentences displayed with the self-paced reading method. برای هر جفت جمله ، جمله n یک کلمه هدف دارد که با یک کلمه سینونیم همان طول که در جمله n+1 شامل شده است. زمان خواندن برای هر کلمه هدف ثبت شده بود. با توجه به کورپوس که ما استفاده کردیم، نتیجه‌هایمان نشان می‌دهند که فرکانس (۱) کلمه‌ها بر زمان خواندن (سرعت خواندن سریع‌تر) اثر مهم‌ای دارند، با افزایش بزرگتر (در مجموعه ثانیه) در مقایسه با دید عادی است. (۲) اندازه کلمه همسایه‌ی کلمه اثر مهم بر زمان خواندن (همسایه‌های بیشتری سرعت خواندن) دارد، این اثر به اندازه‌ی اندازه‌ی اندازه‌ای کوچک می‌شود، ولی جالب در مقایسه با دیده‌های عادی برگردانده شده است. Name پشتیبانی توسعه تکنولوژی جدید و تاثیر بیشتری برای کمک به دیدگاه پایین یک مسئله مهم و زمانی است، با اثرات پتانسیل بزرگی برای تمرین اجتماعی و بازسازی. هدف پایان
این پروژه برای استفاده از نتیجه‌های ما برای ساده‌سازی متن خاص برای این جمعیت خاص است و از آن به عنوان کمک خواندن بهترین و موثرت استفاده می‌کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>이 작업의 목적은 텍스트를 간소화하는 것을 잠재적인 읽기 보조 수단으로 삼아 시력 손상자의 읽기 표현을 개선하는 데 도움을 주는 것이다.첫 번째 단계로 우리는 세 단어의 특성(주파수, 정교 유사성과 길이)이 중앙시야상실(CFL) 상황에서 읽는 속도에 미치는 개체적 영향을 평가함으로써 저시력으로 읽을 때 텍스트가 특히 복잡한 원인을 탐색한다.황반질환이 유발하는 양측 CFL 환자는 자정 리듬 읽기법으로 표시된 프랑스어 문장 쌍을 읽는다.각 문장에 대해 문장 n은 하나의 목표어를 포함하고 문장 n+1에 포함된 동일한 길이의 동의어와 일치한다.각 대상 단어의 읽기 시간을 기록합니다.우리가 사용한 어료 라이브러리에 의하면 (1) 정상적인 시력에 비해 단어의 빈도는 읽기 시간(빈도가 높을수록 읽기 속도가 빨라진다)에 현저한 영향을 미치고 폭이 크다(초 범위 내에서).(2) 단어의 이웃 크기는 읽는 시간에 현저한 영향을 미친다(이웃이 많을수록 읽는 속도가 느리다). 이런 영향의 폭은 매우 작지만 흥미로운 것은 정상적인 시력에 비해 이런 영향은 상반된다.(3) 글자의 길이는 읽는 시간에 현저한 영향을 미치지 않는다.새로운, 더욱 효과적인 보조 기술의 개발을 지원하여 저시력을 돕는 것은 중요하고 신속한 문제로 사회와 재활 실천에 커다란 잠재적인 영향을 미친다.최종 목표
본 프로젝트는 이 특정 사용자를 대상으로 맞춤형 텍스트를 간소화하고 이를 최상의 효율적인 읽기 보조 도구로 활용하는 연구 결과를 활용할 것이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_tr>Bu işiň maksady - görsel hassyz adamlaryň tarapyndan täsirli okamak üçin metin bejerilmesini okamak üçin mümkin bir kömekleşendirmekdir. Birinci adım olarak, Merkezi Görsel alan Kayıtlarında (CFL) okuma hızynda metin özellikle karmaşık bir şekilde oluşturduğunu çözeriz. Makular kesirleri tarapyndan ýetişikli CFL bilen özi-özüni alan okama yöntemi bilen görkezilen Fransuz sözleriniň çift sanyny okaýarlar. Her çift üçin, sözlemde n+1 sözlemde meňzeşli bir maksady söz bar. Saýlaw zamany her maksad söz üçin ýazdy. Kullandygymyz korpusa görä, netijelerimiz (1) sözlerin frekwensiýasynda (okamak tizliginiň çalt iň çalt geçirmegi) düzgün görünüşüne görä has möhüm täsiri bar; (2) Gaýratyn golaýdaky söz ululykynda okamak wagtynda örän wajyp täsiri bar (köp goňşy okamak hızynda ýakynlaşýar), bu täsiri genişlikde kiçi bolar, ýöne normal a ýanlygy bilen görä gyzyklanýar; (3) söz durmuşy okamakda wajyp täsiri ýok. Täze we täze kömek teknolojiň gelişmesini kömek etmek üçin azat görünüşüne kömek etmek wajyp we wagt meseledir, sosyal we ýene-de durmuş praktikalar üçin örän uly täsirler bar. Ahyry maksady
Bu proýet tapylşymyzy bu häzirki ilatyň ýeňşikliklerine şahsy metin bejermek üçin ullanmak we muny optimal we täsirli okamak kömegi üçin ullamak üçin ullanacak.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Lengo la kazi hii ni kuwasilisha urahisi wa maandishi kama msaada wa kusoma uwezekano wa kusaidia kuboresha utendaji wa kusoma masikini uliojabiliwa na watu walioathirika na kuona. Kama hatua ya kwanza, tunachunguza kile kinachofanya ujumbe wa maandishi hususani unaposomwa kwa maono ya chini, kwa kutathmini athari ya moja ya utaalamu wa maneno matatu (frequency, orthographic and length) kuhusu kusoma kwa haraka katika uwepo wa kupoteza kwa mlima wa kati (CFL). Watu wenye CFL inayotengenezwa na magonjwa makubwa yanasomeka hukumu mbili za Kifaransa zinazoonyesha kwa njia ya kusoma yenyewe haraka. Kwa kila hukumu wawili, hukumu iliyohusika n a neno la lengo linalolinganisha na neno la ushirikiano wa urefu huo ulijumuisha kwenye hukumu n+1. Kusoma muda ulirekodiwa kwa kila neno la lengo. Kwa kuzingatia makampuni tuliyotumia, matokeo yetu yanaonyesha kuwa kiwango cha maneno (1) kina athari kubwa kwa muda wa kusoma (mara nyingi zaidi kwa haraka sana ya kusoma) kwa kiwango kikubwa (kwa kiwango cha sekunde) ukilinganisha na maono ya kawaida; (2) Ukubwa wa neno la majirani una athari kubwa kwa muda wa kusoma (ndivyo jirani zaidi kawaida kwa kasi ya kusoma), athari hii ni ndogo sana kwa ukubwa, lakini imebadilishwa kwa kiasi kikubwa ukilinganishwa na maono ya kawaida; (3) Uongezeko wa maneno hauna madhara makubwa kwa muda wa kusoma. Kuunga mkono maendeleo ya teknolojia mpya na yenye ufanisi zaidi ya kusaidia kuonyesha ndoa ni suala muhimu na la muda mrefu, ambalo ina madhara makubwa kwa vitendo vya kijamii na rehabilita. Lengo la mwisho la
this project will be to use our findings to custom text simplification to this specific population and use it as an optimal and efficient reading aid.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Die doel van hierdie werk is om teks eenvoudiging te introduseer as 'n potensieele lees hulp te help om die arme lees-prestasie wat deur visuele geïnvoudige individuele te verbeter. As 'n eerste stap, ondersoek ons wat 'n teks besonder kompleks maak wanneer lees met lae gesig, deur die individuele effek van drie woord eienskappe (frekwensie, orthografiese gelykenis en lengte) te vurk op lees spoed in die voorsiening van Sentraal Visuele Veld Verloor (CFL). Individuele met bilaterale CFL wat deur makkulêre siektes aangedoen is, lees pare van Franse setnings wat met die selfpakte lees metode vertoon word. For each sentence pair, sentence n contained a target word matched with a synonym word of the same length included in sentence n+1. Lees tyd is opgeneem vir elke doel woord. Giens die korpus wat ons gebruik het, ons resultate wys dat (1) woord frekwensie 'n betekende effek het op lees tyd (die meer dikwels die vinniger die lees spoed) met groter amplitude (in die omvang van sekondes) vergelyk met normale gesig; (2) woord naaste grootte het 'n betekende effek op lees tyd (die meer naboeste die stadiger lees spoed), hierdie effek is eerder klein in ampliteit, maar interessant omgekeerde in vergelyking met normale gesig; (3) Woordlengte het geen betekende effek op lees tyd nie. Ondersteun van die ontwikkeling van nuwe en meer effektief assistiewe teknologie om lae gesigte te help is 'n belangrike en tydelik probleem met massiewe potensiele implikasies vir sosiale en rehabilitasie-praksies. Die einde doel van
Hierdie projek sal ons gevinde gebruik word om pasmaak teks vereenvoudiging te gebruik aan hierdie spesifieke bevolking en dit as 'n optimal en effektief lees hulp te gebruik.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Այս աշխատանքի նպատակն է ներկայացնել տեքստի պարզաբանությունը որպես պոտենցիալ կարդալու օգնություն, որպեսզի օգնենք բարելավել տեսողական խնդիրներ ունեցող անհատների վատ կարդալու արդյունքները: As a first step, we explore what makes a text especially complex when read with low vision, by assessing the individual effect of three word properties (frequency, orthographic similarity and length) on reading speed in the presence of Central visual Field Loss (CFL).  Մակուլյար հիվանդությունների պատճառով արտադրված երկրորդ անհատները կարդում են ֆրանսիացի նախադասությունների երկու զույգ, որոնք ցույց են տալիս ինքնաարագ կարդալու մեթոդով: Յուրաքանչյուր նախադասության զույգի համար n նախադասությունը պարունակում էր նպատակային բառ, որը համապատասխանում է n+1 նախադասության նույն երկարությամբ սինոնիմային բառին: Ամեն նպատակային բառի համար ձայնագրվել է ընթերցման ժամանակը: Given the corpus we used, our results show that (1) word frequency has a significant effect on reading time (the more frequent the faster the reading speed) with larger amplitude (in the range of seconds) compared to normal vision;  (2) բառի հարևանության չափը նշանակալի ազդեցություն ունի ընթերցման ժամանակի վրա (ինչքան ավելի շատ հարևաններ են, այնքան ավելի դանդաղ է ընթերցման արագությունը), այս ազդեցությունը բավականին փոքր է ամպլիտուդի մեջ, բայց հետաքրքիր է հակառակվել,  (3) բառի երկարությունը չի ազդում կարդալու ժամանակի վրա: Նոր և ավելի արդյունավետ օգնական տեխնոլոգիաների զարգացման աջակցությունը ցածր տեսողության օգնելու համար կարևոր և ժամանակական խնդիր է, որն ունի հսկայական պոտենցիալ հետևանքներ սոցիալական և վերականգնողական գործողությունների վրա: The end goal of
this project will be to use our findings to custom text simplification to this specific population and use it as an optimal and efficient reading aid.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>The objective of this work is to introduce text simplification as a potential reading aid to help improve the poor reading performance experienced by visually impaired individuals.  በመጀመሪያው ደረጃ፣ ጽሑፉን በተጨነቀ ራእይ ሲያነብ፣ የሦስት ቃላት ምርጫዎች (frequency, orthographic similarity እና ርዝመት) በሚያነብ ፍጥረት (CFL) በመካከለኛዊ ራእይ መሬት ሳንቀሳቅስ (CFL) ሲሆን የጽሑፉን አካባቢ የሚያደርገውን እናሳውቃለን፡ በሁለት የCFL ደዌዎች የተነሳ የፍሪስዳን ደንቦች የራሳቸውን የራሳቸውን አነብብ ሥርዓት የተገለጡትን ሁለት ዓይነቶች ያነብባሉ፡፡ ለሁሉም ዓይነት ሁለት እኩል ክፈት በ+1 ክፍል ውስጥ የተመሳሰለ የስናኒም ቃላት በሚያስተካክሉ መክፈት ነው። የአሁኑን ፋይል አስቀምጥ ካርፓስ በተጠቀምን ጊዜ፣ (1) የቃላት ቁጥጥር ለመነበብ ጊዜ የሚያስፈልገው (በቶሎ ለመነበብ ፍጥረት) በተለየው ከፍተኛ (በክፍለ ክፍል) በተለየው ራእይ ይታያል፡፡ (2) የቃላት ጎረቤት መጠን በማንበብ ሰዓት ላይ የበለጠ ጥያቄ አለበት (የጎረቤቶቹ ፈጥኖ ለማንበብ ፈጥኖ እየዘገየ) ይህ ጥያቄ እጅግ ትንሽ ነው ነገር ግን በአዳማዊ ራእይ በተያይነ ይለውጣል፡፡ (3) የንግግር ርዝመት በአነበብ ጊዜ ምንም significant effect የለውም ትንሽ ራእይን ለመረዳት አዲስ እና የበለጠ ጥያቄ ቴክሎጂ ለመደገፍ የሚደግፍ የጊዜው ጉዳይ ነው፡፡ መጨረሻ
ይሄ ፕሮጀክት የጽሑፉን ቀላል ለመገልጽ እና ለዚህ የተለየ ሕዝብ ማቀናጃ እና ማሻሻለኛ እና ጥቅም ለመነበብ እርዳታ ለመጠቀም ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Qëllimi i kësaj pune është të futet thjeshtësimi i tekstit si një ndihmë e mundshme leximi për të ndihmuar përmirësimin e paraqitjes së dobët leximi përjetuar nga individët me dëm vizual. Si hap i parë, ne eksplorojmë se çfarë bën një tekst veçanërisht kompleks kur lexohet me pamje të ulët, duke vlerësuar efektin individual të tre pronësive të fjalëve (frekuencë, ngjashmëri ortografike dhe gjatësi) në shpejtësinë e leximit në praninë e humbjes së fushës vizuale qendrore (CFL). Individët me CFL dypalëshe të induktuar nga sëmundjet makulare lexojnë çifte fjalësh franceze të shfaqura me metodën e leximit të vetëshpejtë. Për çdo çift fjalësh, fjala n përmban një fjalë objektive të përshtatshme me një fjalë sinonim të të njëjtës gjatësie të përfshirë n ë fjalë n+1. Koha e leximit u regjistrua për çdo fjalë objektive. Duke pasur parasysh korpusin që përdorëm, rezultatet tona tregojnë se (1) frekuenca e fjalës ka një efekt të rëndësishëm në kohën e leximit (aq më shpesh është shpejtësia e leximit) me amplitudë më të madhe (në intervalin e sekondave) krahasuar me pamjen normale; (2) madhësia e fjalës fqinjësi ka një efekt të rëndësishëm në kohën e leximit (sa më shumë fqinjë më ngadalë është shpejtësia e leximit), ky efekt është shumë i vogël në amplitudë, por interesant e kthyer krahasuar me pamjen normale; (3) length of word has no significant effect on reading time. Mbështetja e zhvillimit të teknologjisë së re dhe më të efektshme ndihmëse për të ndihmuar vizionin e ulët është një çështje e rëndësishme dhe në kohë, me pasoja masive të mundshme për praktikat shoqërore dhe rehabilituese. The end goal of
ky projekt do të jetë për të përdorur gjetjet tona për të përshtatur thjeshtësimin e tekstit për këtë popullsi specifike dhe për ta përdorur atë si një ndihmë optimale dhe efikase leximi.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bn>এই কাজের উদ্দেশ্য হচ্ছে টেক্সট সুস্পষ্ট ব্যক্তিদের দৃশ্যমান ক্ষতিগ্রস্ত ব্যক্তিদের দেখা যাচ্ছে দরিদ্র ব্যক্তিদের পাঠকর্ প্রথম পদক্ষেপ হিসেবে আমরা খুঁজে বের করি কি বিশেষ করে একটি লেখা জটিল করে যখন নিম্ন দৃষ্টিভঙ্গিতে পড়ে, তিনটি শব্দের বৈশিষ্ট্যের প্রভাবের মাধ্যমে তিনটি শব্দের ব্যক্তিগত ম্যাকুল রোগের দ্বারা ব্যাটারেল সিএফএল শুরু করা বিভিন্ন ব্যক্তিরা নিজেদের পাঠের মাধ্যমে প্রকাশিত ফরাসী বাক্যের দ প্রত্যেক বাক্যের জোড়ার জন্য, শাস্তির মধ্যে একটি লক্ষ্য শব্দ আছে যা একই দীর্ঘদিনের সাথে যুক্ত, যার মধ্যে এন+1 বাক্যে আছে। প্রত্যেক লক্ষ্য শব্দের জন্য সময় পাঠ করা হয়েছে। আমরা যে কোর্পাস ব্যবহার করেছিলাম তা দেখিয়ে আমাদের ফলাফল দেখাচ্ছে (১) শব্দের ফ্রেঞ্জের বিশাল প্রভাব পাঠ করেছে (যতদ্রুত পাঠের গতি) বৃহত্তর (সেকেন্ডের সাথ (২) শব্দের প্রতিবেশীর আকার পড়ার সময়ের উপর গুরুত্বপূর্ণ প্রভাব রয়েছে (যতদিন প্রতিবেশীরা ধীরে পড়তে থাকে), এই প্রভাব বেশী বৃদ্ধিতে ছোট, ক (3) শব্দের দীর্ঘ সময় পড়তে কোন গুরুত্বপূর্ণ প্রভাব নেই। Supporting the development of new and more effective assistive technology to help low vision is an important and timely issue, with massive potential implications for social and rehabilitation practices.  শেষ লক্ষ্য
এই প্রকল্প আমাদের খুঁজে ব্যবহার করা হবে এই বিশেষ জনসংখ্যার জন্য লেখার স্বনির্ধারিত লেখা সুস্পষ্ট করার জন্য এবং এটি একটি অপ্র</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Cílem této práce je představit zjednodušení textu jako potenciální pomůcku čtení, která pomáhá zlepšit špatnou čtenářskou výkonnost, kterou zažívají zrakově postižení. V prvním kroku zkoumáme, co dělá text obzvláště složitým při čtení se slabým zrakem, posouzením individuálního vlivu tří vlastností slova (frekvence, ortografická podobnost a délka) na rychlost čtení v přítomnosti Centrální ztráty vizuálního pole (CFL). Jednotlivci s bilaterálním CFL indukovaným makulárním onemocněním čtou dvojice francouzských vět zobrazených metodou čtení. Pro každý pár vět obsahovala věta n cílové slovo shodné se synonymním slovem stejné délky obsaženým ve větě n+1. Čas čtení byl zaznamenán pro každé cílové slovo. Vzhledem k použitému korpusu naše výsledky ukazují, že (1) frekvence slova má významný vliv na časovou dobu (čím častější, tím rychlejší je rychlost čtení) s větší amplitudou (v rozsahu sekund) ve srovnání s normálním viděním; (2) velikost sousedství slova má významný vliv na čas čtení (čím více sousedů, tím pomalejší je rychlost čtení), tento efekt je poměrně malý amplitudou, ale zajímavě obrácený ve srovnání s normálním viděním; (3) délka slova nemá žádný významný vliv na dobu čtení. Podpora vývoje nových a účinnějších asistenčních technologií na pomoc slabému zraku je důležitým a včasným problémem, který má obrovské potenciální dopady na sociální a rehabilitační postupy. Konečný cíl
Tento projekt bude využít naše zjištění k vlastnímu zjednodušení textu této konkrétní populaci a využít jej jako optimální a efektivní pomůcky pro čtení.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>L'objectiu d'aquesta feina és introduir la simplificació del text com una ajuda de lectura potencial per ajudar a millorar el mal rendiment de lectura experimentat per individus amb deficiències visuals. Com a primer pas, explorem el que fa que un text sigui especialment complexe quan es llegeix amb baixa visió, evaluant l'efecte individual de les propietats de tres paraules (freqüència, similitud ortogràfica i llargada) en la velocitat de lectura en presença de Perda de Camp visual Central (CFL). Els individus amb LFC bilateral induït per malalties maculars llegeixen parells de frases franceses mostrades amb el mètode de lectura autoràpida. Per cada parell de frases, la frase n contenia una paraula alvo que coincidi amb una paraula sinonimàtica de la mateixa llargada inclúida en la frase n+1. Es va gravar el temps de llegir per cada paraula alvo. Tenint en compte el cos que vam utilitzar, els nostres resultats mostren que (1) la freqüència de paraules té un efecte significatiu en el temps de lectura (més freqüent és la velocitat de lectura més ràpida) amb una amplitud més gran (en el interval de segons) comparat amb la visió normal; (2) la mida del barri de paraules té un efecte significatiu en el temps de lectura (com més veïns més lents és la velocitat de lectura), aquest efecte és bastant petit en amplitud, però interessant invertit comparat amb la visió normal; (3) La llargada de la paraula no té cap efecte significatiu en el temps de lectura. Suportar el desenvolupament de tecnologia assistiva nova i més efectiva per ajudar a la baixa visió és un tema important i oportun, amb conseqüències potencials massives per les pràctiques socials i de rehabilitació. L'objectiu final
aquest projecte serà utilitzar els nostres descobriments per adaptar la simplificació del text a aquesta població específica i utilitzar-lo com una ajuda de lectura optima i eficient.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Töö eesmärk on tutvustada teksti lihtsustamist kui võimalikku lugemisabi, mis aitab parandada nägemispuudega inimeste halva lugemisvõime. Esimese sammuna uurime, mis muudab teksti eriti keeruliseks halva nägemisega lugemisel, hinnates kolme sõna omaduse (sagedus, ortograafiline sarnasus ja pikkus) individuaalset mõju lugemiskiirusele tsentraalse nägemisvälja kadu (CFL) olemasolul. Makulaarhaigustest tingitud kahepoolse CFL-ga isikud loevad enesetempolise lugemismeetodiga kuvatavaid prantsuse lausepaare. Iga lausepaari puhul sisaldas lause n sihtsõna, mis sobitus lauses n+1 sisalduva sama pikkusega sünonüümsõnaga. Iga sihtsõna lugemisaeg salvestati. Arvestades korpust, mida me kasutasime, näitavad meie tulemused, et (1) sõnasagedusel on oluline mõju lugemisajale (mida sagedamini, seda kiiremini lugemiskiirus) suurema amplituudiga (sekundite vahemikus) võrreldes normaalse nägemisega; (2) sõna naabruskonna suurusel on oluline mõju lugemisajale (mida rohkem naabreid, seda aeglasem on lugemiskiirus), see mõju on üsna väike amplituudi poolest, kuid huvitavalt pööratud võrreldes normaalse nägemisega; (3) sõna pikkusel ei ole olulist mõju lugemisajale. Uue ja tõhusama abitehnoloogia arendamise toetamine halva nägemise toetamiseks on oluline ja õigeaegne küsimus, millel on tohutu potentsiaalne mõju sotsiaalsetele ja rehabilitatsioonitavadele. Lõppeesmärk
Selle projekti eesmärk on kasutada meie tulemusi kohandatud teksti lihtsustamiseks sellele konkreetsele populatsioonile ning kasutada seda optimaalse ja tõhusa lugemisahendina.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tämän työn tavoitteena on ottaa tekstin yksinkertaistaminen käyttöön mahdollisena lukuapuvälineenä, joka auttaa parantamaan näkövammaisten kokemaa huonoa lukukykyä. Ensimmäisessä vaiheessa tutkimme, mikä tekee tekstistä erityisen monimutkaisen, kun sitä luetaan heikolla näköalalla, arvioimalla kolmen sanan ominaisuuksien (taajuus, ortografinen samankaltaisuus ja pituus) yksilöllistä vaikutusta lukunopeuteen keskitetyn näkökentän menetyksen (CFL) läsnä ollessa. Henkilöt, joilla on makulaarisairauksien aiheuttama bilateraalinen CFL, lukevat ranskalaisia lausepareja, jotka on esitetty itsetahtisella lukumenetelmällä. Jokaisen lauseparin kohdalla lause n sisälsi kohdesanan, joka vastasi lauseeseen n+1 sisältyvää samanpituista synonyymisanaa. Jokaiselle kohdesanalle kirjattiin lukuaika. Käyttämämme korpus huomioon ottaen tulokset osoittavat, että (1) sanataajuudella on merkittävä vaikutus lukuaikaan (mitä useammin, sitä nopeammin lukunopeus) ja suurempi amplitudi (sekuntien alueella) verrattuna normaalinäköön; (2) sanan naapuruston koolla on merkittävä vaikutus lukuaikaan (mitä enemmän naapureita, sitä hitaampi lukunopeus), tämä vaikutus on melko pieni amplitudilta, mutta mielenkiintoisen käänteinen verrattuna normaaliin näkökykyyn; (3) sanan pituudella ei ole merkittävää vaikutusta lukuaikaan. Uuden ja tehokkaamman näkövammaisen avustavan teknologian kehittämisen tukeminen on tärkeä ja oikea-aikainen kysymys, jolla voi olla valtavia vaikutuksia sosiaalisiin ja kuntoutuskäytäntöihin. Lopputavoite
Tämän projektin tarkoituksena on käyttää havaintojamme tekstien yksinkertaistamiseen ja käyttää sitä optimaalisena ja tehokkaana lukuapuvälineenä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_az>Bu işin məqsədi, göylərdə zəif kişilər tarafından təcrübə edilən pis oxunmaq performansını yaxşılaşdırmaq üçün mümkün olaraq metin oxunmasını təşkil etməkdir. İlk adım olaraq, düşük görünüş ilə oxunduğu zaman, üç söz özelliklərinin (frequency, orthographic similarity və uzunluğu) oxunması üçün mətn olaraq çox kompleks olanı keşfetirik. Makular xəstəliklərdən təşkil edilən iki-tərəfli CFL olan kişilər özünü-tərəfli oxumaq metodu ilə göstərilən Fransız cümlələri oxuyarlar. Hər cümlən in çift üçün n cümləsi n cümlənin n+1 içində daxil edilən sinonim sözün ə uyğun bir məqsəd sözü vardır. Okuma vaxtı hər məqsəd sözü üçün kaydedildi. Qullandığımız korpus sayəsində, sonuçlarımız (1) sözlərin frekvencinin oxunma vaxtı üzərində böyük amplitudi (saniyələr arasında) normal görünüş ilə qarşılaşdığını göstərir. (2) Səviyyət ətrafının böyüklüyü oxumaq vaxtı üzərində möhkəm bir etkisi vardır (oxumaq sürətini daha yavaşlaşdırır), bu etkisi çox böyüklüyündə kiçik idi, amma normal görünüş ilə dəyişiklik olaraq dəyişiklik edir. (3) Söz uzunluğu oxunmaq vaxtında möhkəm bir etkisi yoxdur. Düşük görünüşünü kömək etmək üçün yeni və daha etkili yardım edən teknolojinin gelişməsini dəstəkləndirmək, sosyal və rehabilitasyon praksiləri üçün böyük mümkün və vaxtlı bir problemdir. Sonun məqsədi
Bu proyekt bizim tapındıqlarımızı bu məxluqatın şəkildə tərzim tərzim olaraq istifadə etmək və onu optimal və etkili oxumaq yardımı olaraq istifadə etmək olacaq.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Cilj ovog rada je uvođenje pojednostavljanja teksta kao potencijalnu pomoć čitanja kako bi pomoglo poboljšati lošu učinku čitanja iskusili vizualno oštećeni pojedinci. Kao prvi korak, istražujemo ono što čini tekst posebno složen kada čitamo s niskim vizijom, procjenjivanjem pojedinačnog učinka tri vlasništva riječi (frekvencija, ortografska sličnost i dužin a) na brzinu čitanja u prisutnosti gubitka centralnog vizualnog polja (CFL). Individualni s bilateralnim CFL-om induciranim makularnim bolestima čitaju par francuskih rečenica koji se pokazuju metodom čitanja samoporučenog. Za svaki par rečenica, rečenica n sadrži ciljnu riječ odgovarajuću sinonimskom riječima iste dužine uključenom u rečenicu n+1. Čitanje je snimljeno za svaku ciljnu riječ. S obzirom na korpus koji smo koristili, naši rezultati pokazuju da (1) frekvencija riječi ima značajan uticaj na vrijeme čitanja (što češće brže brže čitanja) sa većom amplitudom (u rasponu sekundi) u usporedbi sa normalnom vizijom; (2) veličin a riječi susjedstva ima značajan učinak na vrijeme čitanja (što više susjeda sporije brzinu čitanja), taj učinak je prilično mali u amplitudiji, ali interesantno okrenut u usporedbi sa normalnom vizijom; (3) Dužina riječi nema značajnog utjecaja na vrijeme čitanja. Podrška razvoju novih i efikasnijih pomoćnih tehnologija za pomoć niskog vida je važan i vremenski problem, s velikim potencijalnim posljedicama za prakse socijalne i rehabilitacije. Cilj kraja
Ovaj projekt će biti da iskoristimo naše nalaze za pojednostavljanje teksta u određenoj populaciji i koristimo ga kao optimalnu i efikasnu pomoć čitanja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_jv>Layout</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>wannan shirin ayuka zai yi amfani da misalinmu zuwa na ɗabi'a masu sauƙi na matsayin zuwa wannan mutane na ƙayyade kuma ya yi amfani da shi kamar mataimaki na amfani da karatun karatun masu yiwuwa.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>הפרויקט הזה יהיה להשתמש בממצאים שלנו כדי להפשיט טקסט מתאים לאופולציה המיוחדת הזו ולהשתמש בה כעזרה לקרוא אופטימית ויעילה.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Ta projekt bo uporabil naše ugotovitve za poenostavitev besedila po meri tej specifični populaciji in ga uporabil kot optimalno in učinkovito branje.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ལས་འགུལ་འདི་ནི་ང་ཚོའི་རྗེས་སུ་རང་བཟོས་ཡི་གེའི་ཡིག་གེ་ཆེས་ཉིད་ཀྱི་མི་འབོར་སྟངས་འདིས་རང་བཟོས་བའི་ཡིག་གེ་སྟོང་རྒྱུ་</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>LagunTest : A NLP Based Application to Enhance Reading Comprehension<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>agun<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>est: A <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Based Application to Enhance Reading Comprehension</title>
      <author><first>Kepa</first><last>Bengoetxea</last></author>
      <author><first>Itziar</first><last>Gonzalez-Dios</last></author>
      <author><first>Amaia</first><last>Aguirregoitia</last></author>
      <pages>63–69</pages>
      <abstract>The ability to read and understand written texts plays an important role in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Education">education</a>, above all in the last years of primary education. This is especially pertinent in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_immersion">language immersion educational programmes</a>, where some students have low linguistic competence in the languages of instruction. In this context, adapting the texts to the individual needs of each student requires a considerable effort by education professionals. However, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_technology">language technologies</a> can facilitate the laborious adaptation of materials in order to enhance <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reading_comprehension">reading comprehension</a>. In this paper, we present LagunTest, a NLP based application that takes as input a text in Basque or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, and offers synonyms, definitions, examples of the words in different contexts and presents some linguistic characteristics as well as visualizations. LagunTest is based on reusable and open multilingual and multimodal tools, and it is also distributed with an open license. LagunTest is intended to ease the burden of education professionals in the task of adapting materials, and the output should always be supervised by them.</abstract>
      <url hash="6cf9848c">2020.readi-1.10</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>bengoetxea-etal-2020-laguntest</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>A Lexical Simplification Tool for Promoting Health Literacy</title>
      <author><first>Leonardo</first><last>Zilio</last></author>
      <author><first>Liana</first><last>Braga Paraguassu</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis Antonio</first><last>Leiva Hercules</last></author>
      <author><first>Gabriel</first><last>Ponomarenko</last></author>
      <author><first>Laura</first><last>Berwanger</last></author>
      <author><first>Maria José</first><last>Bocorny Finatto</last></author>
      <pages>70–76</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents MedSimples, an authoring tool that combines <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corpus_linguistics">Corpus Linguistics</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminology">Terminology</a> to help writers to convert health-related information into a more accessible version for people with low literacy skills. MedSimples applies parsing methods associated with lexical resources to automatically evaluate a text and present simplification suggestions that are more suitable for the target audience. Using the suggestions provided by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tool</a>, the author can adapt the original text and make it more accessible. The focus of MedSimples lies on texts for special purposes, so that it not only deals with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vocabulary">general vocabulary</a>, but also with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Specialization_(functional)">specialized terms</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tool</a> is currently under development, but an online working prototype exists and can be tested freely. An assessment of MedSimples was carried out aiming at evaluating its current performance with some promising results, especially for informing the future developments that are planned for the tool.</abstract>
      <url hash="68c9b2a5">2020.readi-1.11</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>zilio-etal-2020-lexical</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>A multi-lingual and cross-domain analysis of features for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_simplification">text simplification</a></title>
      <author><first>Regina</first><last>Stodden</last></author>
      <author><first>Laura</first><last>Kallmeyer</last></author>
      <pages>77–84</pages>
      <abstract>In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_simplification">text simplification</a> and readability research, several features have been proposed to estimate or simplify a complex text, e.g., readability scores, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_(linguistics)">sentence length</a>, or proportion of POS tags. These <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_feature">features</a> are however mainly developed for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>. In this paper, we investigate their relevance for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Czech_language">Czech</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a>, English, Spanish, and Italian text simplification corpora. Our multi-lingual and multi-domain corpus analysis shows that the relevance of different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> for text simplification is different per corpora, language, and domain. For example, the relevance of the lexical complexity is different across all languages, the BLEU score across all domains, and 14 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> within the web domain corpora. Overall, the negative statistical tests regarding the other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a> across and within domains and languages lead to the assumption that text simplification models may be transferable between different domains or different languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="34148313">2020.readi-1.12</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>stodden-kallmeyer-2020-multi</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>