<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nl4xai">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-01-18">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>2nd Workshop on Interactive Natural Language Technology for Explainable Artificial Intelligence</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Jose M.</first><last>Alonso</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alejandro</first><last>Catala</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Dublin, Ireland</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <url hash="19c711f4">2020.nl4xai-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="0ca3b076">2020.nl4xai-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nl4xai-2020-interactive</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Bias in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence">AI-systems</a> : A multi-step approach<fixed-case>AI</fixed-case>-systems: A multi-step approach</title>
      <author><first>Eirini</first><last>Ntoutsi</last></author>
      <pages>3–4</pages>
      <abstract>Algorithmic-based decision making powered via AI and (big) data has already penetrated into almost all spheres of human life, from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recommender_system">content recommendation</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Health_care">healthcare</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Predictive_policing">predictive policing</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-driving_car">autonomous driving</a>, deeply affecting everyone, anywhere, anytime. While <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technology">technology</a> allows previously unthinkable optimizations in the automation of expensive human decision making, the risks that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technology">technology</a> can pose are also high, leading to an ever increasing public concern about the impact of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technology">technology</a> in our lives. The area of responsible AI has recently emerged in an attempt to put humans at the center of AI-based systems by considering aspects, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_justice">fairness</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliability_engineering">reliability</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Privacy">privacy of decision-making systems</a>. In this talk, we will focus on the fairness aspect. We will start with understanding the many sources of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a> and how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">biases</a> can enter at each step of the learning process and even get propagated / amplified from previous steps. We will continue with methods for mitigating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a> which typically focus on some step of the pipeline (data, algorithms or results) and why it is important to target bias in each step and collectively, in the whole (machine) learning pipeline. We will conclude this talk by discussing accountability issues in connection to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a> and in particular, proactive consideration via bias-aware data collection, processing and algorithmic selection and retroactive consideration via explanations.</abstract>
      <url hash="4aecb088">2020.nl4xai-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>ntoutsi-2020-bias</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Content Selection for Explanation Requests in Customer-Care Domain</title>
      <author><first>Luca</first><last>Anselma</last></author>
      <author><first>Mirko</first><last>Di Lascio</last></author>
      <author><first>Dario</first><last>Mana</last></author>
      <author><first>Alessandro</first><last>Mazzei</last></author>
      <author><first>Manuela</first><last>Sanguinetti</last></author>
      <pages>5–10</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes a content selection module for the generation of explanations in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue_system">dialogue system</a> designed for customer care domain. First we describe the construction of a corpus of a dialogues containing explanation requests from customers to a virtual agent of a telco, and second we study and formalize the importance of a specific information content for the generated message. In particular, we adapt the notions of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Importance">importance</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relevance">relevance</a> in the case of schematic knowledge bases.</abstract>
      <url hash="c092c1a7">2020.nl4xai-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>anselma-etal-2020-content</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>The Natural Language Pipeline, Neural Text Generation and Explainability</title>
      <author><first>Juliette</first><last>Faille</last></author>
      <author><first>Albert</first><last>Gatt</last></author>
      <author><first>Claire</first><last>Gardent</last></author>
      <pages>16–21</pages>
      <abstract>End-to-end encoder-decoder approaches to data-to-text generation are often black boxes whose predictions are difficult to explain. Breaking up the end-to-end model into sub-modules is a natural way to address this problem. The traditional pre-neural Natural Language Generation (NLG) pipeline provides a framework for breaking up the end-to-end encoder-decoder. We survey recent papers that integrate traditional NLG submodules in neural approaches and analyse their explainability. Our survey is a first step towards building explainable neural NLG models.</abstract>
      <url hash="fc3dbb07">2020.nl4xai-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>faille-etal-2020-natural</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Toward Natural Language Mitigation Strategies for Cognitive Biases in Recommender Systems</title>
      <author><first>Alisa</first><last>Rieger</last></author>
      <author><first>Mariët</first><last>Theune</last></author>
      <author><first>Nava</first><last>Tintarev</last></author>
      <pages>50–54</pages>
      <abstract>Cognitive biases in the context of consuming online information filtered by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recommender_system">recommender systems</a> may lead to sub-optimal choices. One approach to mitigate such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">biases</a> is through interface and interaction design. This survey reviews studies focused on cognitive bias mitigation of recommender system users during two processes : 1) item selection and 2) preference elicitation. It highlights a number of promising directions for Natural Language Generation research for mitigating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_bias">cognitive bias</a> including : the need for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personalization">personalization</a>, as well as for transparency and control.</abstract>
      <url hash="f27efe74">2020.nl4xai-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>rieger-etal-2020-toward</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Learning from Explanations and Demonstrations : A Pilot Study</title>
      <author><first>Silvia</first><last>Tulli</last></author>
      <author><first>Sebastian</first><last>Wallkötter</last></author>
      <author><first>Ana</first><last>Paiva</last></author>
      <author><first>Francisco S.</first><last>Melo</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohamed</first><last>Chetouani</last></author>
      <pages>61–66</pages>
      <abstract>AI has become prominent in a growing number of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a>, and, as a direct consequence, the desire for explainability in such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> has become prominent as well. To build explainable systems, a large portion of existing research uses various kinds of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language technologies</a>, e.g., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_synthesis">text-to-speech mechanisms</a>, or string visualizations. Here, we provide an overview of the challenges associated with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-language_understanding">natural language explanations</a> by reviewing existing literature. Additionally, we discuss the relationship between explainability and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_transfer">knowledge transfer</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">reinforcement learning</a>. We argue that explainability methods, in particular <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> that model the recipient of an explanation, might help increasing sample efficiency. For this, we present a computational approach to optimize the learner’s performance using explanations of another agent and discuss our results in light of effective natural language explanations for humans.</abstract>
      <url hash="80ec638a">2020.nl4xai-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>tulli-etal-2020-learning</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Generating Explanations of Action Failures in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_robotics">Cognitive Robotic Architecture</a></title>
      <author><first>Ravenna</first><last>Thielstrom</last></author>
      <author><first>Antonio</first><last>Roque</last></author>
      <author><first>Meia</first><last>Chita-Tegmark</last></author>
      <author><first>Matthias</first><last>Scheutz</last></author>
      <pages>67–72</pages>
      <abstract>We describe an approach to generating explanations about why robot actions fail, focusing on the considerations of robots that are run by cognitive robotic architectures. We define a set of Failure Types and Explanation Templates, motivating them by the needs and constraints of cognitive architectures that use action scripts and interpretable belief states, and describe content realization and surface realization in this context. We then describe an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evaluation">evaluation</a> that can be extended to further study the effects of varying the explanation templates.</abstract>
      <url hash="fd005fb3">2020.nl4xai-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>thielstrom-etal-2020-generating</bibkey>
    <title_ar>توليد تفسيرات لفشل العمل في العمارة الروبوتية المعرفية</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Gerando explicações de falhas de ação em uma arquitetura robótica cognitiva</title_pt>
      <title_es>Generación de explicaciones de fallas de acción en una arquitectura robótica cognitiva</title_es>
      <title_ja>認知ロボットアーキテクチャにおけるアクションの失敗の説明の生成</title_ja>
      <title_zh>成识机器人架构中操作败说</title_zh>
      <title_hi>एक संज्ञानात्मक रोबोट वास्तुकला में कार्रवाई विफलताओं के स्पष्टीकरण उत्पन्न करना</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Mínithe ar Theipeanna Gníomhaíochta in Ailtireacht Chognaíoch Robotic a Ghiniúint</title_ga>
      <title_ka>მოქმედების შეცდომილებების შექმნა კოგენტიური პრობოტიკური აქტიქტურაში</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A cselekvési hibák magyarázatainak generálása egy kognitív robotarchitektúrában</title_hu>
      <title_el>Δημιουργία επεξηγήσεων για αποτυχίες δράσης σε μια γνωστική ρομποτική αρχιτεκτονική</title_el>
      <title_it>Generare spiegazioni dei fallimenti di azione in un'architettura robotica cognitiva</title_it>
      <title_kk>Когнитивті робот архитектурасында әрекеттің түсініктемелерін жасау қатесі</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Veiksmų trūkumų paaiškinimai pažintinėje robotinėje architektūroje</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Генерирање објаснувања за неуспехови во коњитивната роботичка архитектура</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Menjana Penjelasan Kegagalan Tindakan dalam Arkitektur Robotik Cognitive</title_ms>
      <title_ml>പ്രവര്‍ത്തനത്തിന്റെ എക്സ്പ്ലാനേഷന്‍ സൃഷ്ടിക്കുന്നതില്‍ പരാജയപ്പെട്ടു</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Cognitive Robotic Architecture-д үйл ажиллагааны амжилтын тодорхойлолтуудыг бий болгох</title_mn>
      <title_mt>Il-Ġenerazzjoni ta’ Spjegazzjonijiet ta’ Nuqqasijiet ta’ Azzjoni f’Arkitettura Robotika Konjittiva</title_mt>
      <title_no>Lagar forklaringar av handlingsfeilar i ein kognitiv robotisk arkitektur</title_no>
      <title_pl>Generowanie wyjaśnień awarii działania w poznawczej architekturze robotycznej</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Generarea de explicații ale eșecurilor de acțiune într-o arhitectură robotică cognitivă</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Napravljanje objašnjenja akcijskih neuspjeha u kognitivnoj robotskoj arhitekturi</title_sr>
      <title_si>ක්‍රියාව ප්‍රකාශනයක් නිර්මාණය කරනවා අවස්ථාවක රොබෝටික් විස්තර</title_si>
      <title_so>Generating Explanations of Action failed in a Cognitive Robotic Architecture</title_so>
      <title_sv>Generera förklaringar till åtgärder misslyckas i en kognitiv robotarkitektur</title_sv>
      <title_ta>செயல் வெளியீட்டை உருவாக்க முடியவில்லை</title_ta>
      <title_ur>ایک Cognitive Robotic Architecture میں اقدام فساد کی تفصیل پیدا کی جاتی ہے</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Amalni yaratish muvaffaqiyatsiz tugadi</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Giải thích về thất bại hành động trong kiến trúc Rô-bốt có nhận thức</title_vi>
      <title_hr>Generiranje objašnjenja akcijskih neuspjeha u kognitivnoj robotičkoj arhitekturi</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Генериране на обяснения за неуспехи в действие в когнитивна роботична архитектура</title_bg>
      <title_da>Generere forklaringer af handlingsfejl i en kognitiv robotarkitektur</title_da>
      <title_nl>Het genereren van verklaringen van actie mislukken in een cognitieve robotarchitectuur</title_nl>
      <title_de>Generierung von Handlungserklärungen in einer kognitiven Roboterarchitektur</title_de>
      <title_fa>توضیح‌های فعالیت در یک معماری روباتیک شناخته</title_fa>
      <title_id>Menjana Penjelasan Kegagalan Aksi dalam Arkitektur Robotik Cognitive</title_id>
      <title_ko>인지 로봇 구조에서 동작 생성 실패에 대한 해석</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Kutengeneza Mazungumzo ya Action imeshindwa katika Kiongozi cha Robotic</title_sw>
      <title_af>Genereer Verklarings van Aksie Mislukkings in 'n Cognitive Robotic Architecture</title_af>
      <title_am>ዶሴ `%s'ን ማስፈጠር አልተቻለም፦ %s</title_am>
      <title_sq>Gjenerimi i shpjegimeve të dështimeve të veprimit në një arkitekturë njohëse robotike</title_sq>
      <title_tr>Bilinmegi Robotik arhitektura içinde eylem hatalarynyň düşündirilmegini döredi</title_tr>
      <title_bn>কোগনিটিভ রোবটিক আর্কিটেক্টারে কাজের এক্সপ্ল্যানেশন ব্যর্থ</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Generating Explanations of Action Failures in a Cognitive Robotic Architecture</title_hy>
      <title_az>Bir Cognitive Robotic Architecture i칞ind톛 eyleml톛rin s톛hvl톛rini yaratmaq</title_az>
      <title_bs>Generiranje objašnjenja akcijskih neuspjeha u kognitivnoj robotičkoj arhitekturi</title_bs>
      <title_ca>generar explicacions de fracassos d'acció en una arquitectura robòtica cognitiva</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Generování vysvětlení akčních selhání v kognitivní robotické architektuře</title_cs>
      <title_et>Kognitiivse robotarhitektuuri tegevusvigade selgitamine</title_et>
      <title_fi>Toimintavirheiden selitysten luominen kognitiivisessa robottiarkkitehtuurissa</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Gagal Keterangan Aksi Gagal Rusak barêng nang sampeyan CoGNIVE</title_jv>
      <title_he>יצירת הסברים על כישלונות פעולה בארכיטקטורה רובוטית מכירה</title_he>
      <title_sk>Ustvarjanje pojasnil napak pri delovanju v kognitivni robotski arhitekturi</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>Cognitive Robotic Architecture ཐོག་ཏུ་བྱ་འགུལ་གྱི་གནོད་སྤྱད་པར་བཟོ་བ</title_bo>
      <abstract_pt>Descrevemos uma abordagem para gerar explicações sobre por que as ações do robô falham, focando nas considerações de robôs que são executados por arquiteturas robóticas cognitivas. Definimos um conjunto de Tipos de Falha e Modelos de Explicação, motivando-os pelas necessidades e restrições de arquiteturas cognitivas que usam scripts de ação e estados de crença interpretáveis, e descrevemos a realização de conteúdo e a realização de superfície neste contexto. Em seguida, descrevemos uma avaliação que pode ser estendida para estudar ainda mais os efeitos da variação dos modelos de explicação.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>نصف نهجًا لتوليد تفسيرات حول سبب فشل إجراءات الروبوت ، مع التركيز على اعتبارات الروبوتات التي تديرها البنى الروبوتية المعرفية. نحدد مجموعة من أنواع الفشل وقوالب التفسير ، ونحفزهم من خلال احتياجات وقيود البنى المعرفية التي تستخدم نصوص الإجراءات وحالات الاعتقاد القابلة للتفسير ، ووصف إدراك المحتوى وإدراك السطح في هذا السياق. ثم نصف تقييمًا يمكن تمديده لمزيد من الدراسة لتأثيرات تغيير قوالب التفسير.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Describimos un enfoque para generar explicaciones sobre por qué fallan las acciones de los robots, centrándonos en las consideraciones de los robots que funcionan con arquitecturas robóticas cognitivas. Definimos un conjunto de tipos de fallos y plantillas de explicación, motivándolos por las necesidades y limitaciones de las arquitecturas cognitivas que utilizan guiones de acción y estados de creencias interpretables, y describimos la realización del contenido y la realización de la superficie en este contexto. A continuación, describimos una evaluación que puede ampliarse para estudiar más a fondo los efectos de variar las plantillas de explicación.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>認知ロボットアーキテクチャによって実行されるロボットの考察に焦点を当てて、ロボットアクションが失敗する理由についての説明を生成するアプローチを説明します。私たちは、失敗のタイプと説明テンプレートのセットを定義し、アクションスクリプトと解釈可能な信念状態を使用する認知アーキテクチャのニーズと制約によってそれらを動機づけ、この文脈でコンテンツの実現と表面の実現を説明します。次に、説明テンプレートを変更することの効果をさらに研究するために拡張できる評価について説明します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>述生成机器人所以败者,重以知机器人架构行之机器人虑也。 吾义败模板,以动作脚本解架构求约束以厉之,言其上下文中之情可得而言也。 然后述其可广之评,以究变模板之渐。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम इस बारे में स्पष्टीकरण उत्पन्न करने के लिए एक दृष्टिकोण का वर्णन करते हैं कि रोबोट क्रियाएं क्यों विफल होती हैं, रोबोट के विचारों पर ध्यान केंद्रित करते हैं जो संज्ञानात्मक रोबोट आर्किटेक्चर द्वारा चलाए जाते हैं। हम विफलता प्रकार और स्पष्टीकरण टेम्पलेट्स के एक सेट को परिभाषित करते हैं, उन्हें संज्ञानात्मक आर्किटेक्चर की जरूरतों और बाधाओं से प्रेरित करते हैं जो कार्रवाई स्क्रिप्ट और व्याख्यायोग्य विश्वास राज्यों का उपयोग करते हैं, और इस संदर्भ में सामग्री प्राप्ति और सतह प्राप्ति का वर्णन करते हैं। फिर हम एक मूल्यांकन का वर्णन करते हैं जिसे स्पष्टीकरण टेम्पलेट्स को अलग करने के प्रभावों का आगे अध्ययन करने के लिए बढ़ाया जा सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Déanaimid cur síos ar chur chuige maidir le míniúcháin a ghiniúint faoi cén fáth a dteipeann ar ghníomhartha robot, ag díriú ar bhreithnithe robots atá á reáchtáil ag ailtireachtaí robotic cognaíocha. Sainmhínímid sraith de Chineálacha Teip agus Teimpléad Mínithe, á spreagadh ag riachtanais agus srianta na hailtireachta cognaíocha a úsáideann scripteanna gníomhaíochta agus stáit chreidimh inmhínithe, agus déantar cur síos ar réadú ábhair agus réadú dromchla sa chomhthéacs seo. Déanaimid cur síos ansin ar mheastóireacht is féidir a leathnú chun staidéar breise a dhéanamh ar na héifeachtaí a bhaineann le teimpléid mhínithe a athrú.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ აღწერეთ პრობოტების შესახებ, რომელსაც პრობოტები აქციქტირების შესახებ არ შედგა, რომელიც პრობოტების შესახებ, რომელიც კონციგური პრობოტიური აქტიქტი ჩვენ განსაზღვრებთ შეცდომა ტიპები და განახსნა შაბლოები, რომლებიც ისინი მოტივირებენ კონციგური აქტიქტურების საჭიროებები და ზომილებები, რომლებიც აქციის სკრიპტების გამოყენება და ინტერუქტური წარმოდ შემდეგ ჩვენ აღწერეთ განსაზღვრება, რომელიც შეიძლება გავაკეთოთ სხვადასხვა განსაზღვრების შაბლონების ეფექტის შესახებ.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Leírjuk a robottevékenységek kudarcára vonatkozó magyarázatokat, fókuszálva a kognitív robotarchitektúrák által működtetett robotok megfontolásaira. Meghatározzuk a Hiba típusokat és magyarázatokat, motiválva azokat a kognitív architektúrák igényei és korlátai által, amelyek akciószkripteket és értelmezhető hitállapotokat használnak, és leírjuk a tartalom megvalósítását és felületi megvalósítását ebben a kontextusban. Ezután leírunk egy értékelést, amely kiterjeszthető a magyarázatsablonok változásának hatásainak további tanulmányozására.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Περιγράφουμε μια προσέγγιση για τη δημιουργία εξηγήσεων σχετικά με το γιατί οι ενέργειες ρομπότ αποτυγχάνουν, εστιάζοντας στις εκτιμήσεις των ρομπότ που διοικούνται από γνωστικές ρομποτικές αρχιτεκτονικές. Καθορίζουμε ένα σύνολο τύπων αποτυχίας και προτύπων επεξήγησης, παρακινούμενοι τα από τις ανάγκες και τους περιορισμούς των γνωστικών αρχιτεκτονικών που χρησιμοποιούν σενάρια δράσης και ερμηνευτές καταστάσεις πεποιθήσεων, και περιγράφουμε την πραγματοποίηση περιεχομένου και την επιφανειακή υλοποίηση σε αυτό το πλαίσιο. Στη συνέχεια περιγράφουμε μια αξιολόγηση που μπορεί να επεκταθεί για περαιτέρω μελέτη των επιπτώσεων της διαφοροποίησης των προτύπων επεξήγησης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Descriviamo un approccio per generare spiegazioni sul perché le azioni dei robot falliscono, concentrandoci sulle considerazioni dei robot gestiti da architetture robotiche cognitive. Definiamo un insieme di Tipi di Fallimento e Modelli di Spiegazione, motivandoli dalle esigenze e dai vincoli delle architetture cognitive che utilizzano script di azione e stati di credenza interpretabili, e descriviamo la realizzazione dei contenuti e la realizzazione superficiale in questo contesto. Descriviamo quindi una valutazione che può essere estesa per studiare ulteriormente gli effetti della variazione dei modelli di spiegazione.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Біз роботтың әрекеттері қайталанғанын түсініктемелерді жасау арқылы түсініктемелерді таңдаймыз, конитивті роботтық архитектураларды орындайтын роботтардың түсініктемелеріне көздей Біз әрекетті скрипттерді және аударуға мүмкіндік беретін мәліметтің реализациясын және қарапайым архитектуралардың қажеттіліктері мен шектеулерін түсіндіреді. Содан кейін, түсіндіру үлгілерінің өзгертілген нәтижелерін зерттеуге болатын оқиғаны таңдап береміз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Mes apibūdiname metodą, kaip sukurti paaiškinimus, kodėl robot ų veiksmai žlugsta, daugiausia dėmesio skiriant robotų, kuriuos valdo kognityvinės robotų architektūros, svarstymams. Mes apibrėžiame nesėkmės tipų ir paaiškinimo šablonų rinkinį, motyvuodami juos pažintinių architektūrų poreikiais ir apribojimais, kurie naudoja veiksmų scenarijus ir aiškinamąsias tikėjimo būkles, ir apibūdiname turinio suvokimą ir paviršiaus suvokimą šioje srityje. Tada apibūdiname vertinimą, kuris gali būti išplėstas ir toliau tiriamas įvairių paaiškinimų šablonų poveikis.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Опишуваме пристап до генерирање објаснувања за тоа зошто роботските активности не успеваат, фокусирајќи се на размислувањата на роботите кои се управуваат со когнитивните роботски архитектури. Ние дефинираме сет типови на неуспех и шаблони на објаснување, мотивирајќи ги од потребите и ограничувањата на когнитивните архитектури кои користат акциони скрипти и интерпретабилни верувачки состојби, и опишуваат реализација на содржината и површина реализација во овој контекст. Потоа опишуваме евалуација која може да се прошири за понатамошна студија на ефектите од различните шаблони на објаснување.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami menggambarkan pendekatan untuk menghasilkan penjelasan mengapa tindakan robot gagal, fokus pada pertimbangan robot yang dijalankan oleh arkitektur robot kognitif. Kami menentukan set Jenis Kegagalan dan Templat Penjelasan, memotivasikan mereka dengan keperluan dan keterangan arkitektur kognitif yang menggunakan skrip tindakan dan keadaan kepercayaan yang boleh diterangkan, dan menggambarkan penyelesaian kandungan dan penyelesaian permukaan dalam konteks ini. Kemudian kami menggambarkan penilaian yang boleh dilambangkan untuk mempelajari lebih lanjut kesan perbezaan templat penjelasan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>റോബോട്ട് പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ പരാജയപ്പെടുന്നതിനെക്കുറിച്ച് വിശദീകരിക്കാനുള്ള ഒരു വഴി നാം വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു. റോബോട്ടുകാരുടെ  പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന സ്ക്രിപ്റ്റുകളും വ്യാഖ്യാനിക്കുന്ന വിശ്വാസത്തിന്റെ സ്ഥാനങ്ങളും ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന തരത്തില്‍ പരാജയപ്പെടുത്തുന്ന ഒരു കൂട്ടം  പിന്നീട് വ്യക്തമായ വിശദീകരണങ്ങളുടെ പ്രഭാവങ്ങള്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ പഠിപ്പിക്കാന്‍ വേണ്ടി ഒരു വിശദീകരണത്തെ വിവരി</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna niddeskrivu approċċ biex niġġeneraw spjegazzjonijiet dwar għaliex l-azzjonijiet tar-robots ifallu, b’enfasi fuq il-kunsiderazzjonijiet tar-robots li huma mmexxija minn arkitetturi robotiċi konjittivi. Aħna niddefinixxu sett ta' Tipi ta' Falliment u Templati ta' Spjegazzjoni, li jimmotivawhom mill-ħtiġijiet u r-restrizzjonijiet ta' arkitetturi konjittivi li jużaw skripti ta' azzjoni u stati ta' twemmin interpretabbli, u jiddeskrivu r-realizzazzjoni tal-kontenut u r-realizzazzjoni tal-wiċċ f'dan il-kuntest. We then describe an evaluation that can be extended to further study the effects of varying the explanation templates.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Бид роботын үйл ажиллагаа яагаад бүтэлгүйтсэн талаар тодорхойлдох арга замыг тайлбарлаж, мэдлэгтэй роботын барилгуудын ажиллагаанд анхаарлаа төвлөрүүлдэг. Бид эдгээрийг үйл ажиллагааны скрипт, итгэл үнэмшил байдлыг ашигладаг мэдлэгийн архитектуруудын хэрэгцээ, хязгаарлалтын шаардлагатай бүтээлүүдийг тодорхойлж, үүнийг тодорхойлж, гадаргуу бодит байдлыг тайлбарлаж байна. Дараа нь бид тайлбарлалын шалгалтыг өөрчлөх нөлөөг судалж болно.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Vi beskriver ein tilnærming til å laga forklaringar om hvorfor robotiske handlingar mislukkast, og fokuserer på forstålingane av roboter som køyrer av kognitiv robotiske arkitektur. Vi definerer eit sett av feiltypar og utforskingsmalar, som motiverer dei ved behov og begrensningar av kognitiv arkitektur som brukar handlingskript og tolkbare trosstyr, og beskriver innhaldsrealisering og overflatingsrealisering i denne konteksten. Vi beskriver så eit evaluering som kan utvidast til å forstørra effekten av forskjellige eksplikasjonsmalene.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Opisujemy podejście do generowania wyjaśnień, dlaczego działania robotów zawodzą, koncentrując się na rozważaniach robotów, które są uruchamiane przez kognitywne architektury robotów. Definiujemy zestaw typów awarii i szablonów wyjaśnień, motywując je potrzebami i ograniczeniami architektur poznawczych, które wykorzystują skrypty akcji i interpretowalne stany przekonań oraz opisujemy realizację treści i realizację powierzchniową w tym kontekście. Następnie opisujemy ocenę, którą można rozszerzyć o dalsze badanie efektów zmiany szablonów wyjaśnień.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Descriem o abordare pentru generarea de explicații despre motivul pentru care acțiunile robotului eșuează, concentrându-se pe considerațiile roboților care sunt conduși de arhitecturi robotice cognitive. Definim un set de tipuri de eșec și șabloane de explicație, motivandu-le prin nevoile și constrângerile arhitecturilor cognitive care utilizează scripturi de acțiune și stări de credință interpretabile, și descriem realizarea conținutului și realizarea suprafeței în acest context. Apoi descriem o evaluare care poate fi extinsă pentru a studia în continuare efectele variației șabloanelor de explicații.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Opišemo pristup stvaranju objašnjenja o tome zašto roboti nisu uspeli, fokusirajući se na razmišljanja robota koje vode kognitivne robotičke arhitekture. Definiramo set tipa neuspjeha i obrazovanja šablona, motivirajući ih potrebama i ograničenjima kognitivnih arhitektura koji koriste akcijske skriptove i interpretabilne države verovanja i opisuju realizaciju sadržaja i realizaciju površine u ovom kontekstu. Onda opišemo procjenu koja se može proširiti do daljnjeg proučavanja učinka različitih šablona objašnjenja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අපි විස්තර කරන්නේ රොබෝට් ක්‍රියාවල් අසාර්ථක විස්තරයක් නිර්මාණය කරන්න, රොබෝට් ක්‍රියාවල් අසාර්ථක වෙන්නේ රොබෝට් ව අපි වැරදි වර්ගයක් සහ ප්‍රශ්නයක් වර්ගයක් සැකසුම් විශ්වාස කරනවා, ඔවුන්ට මුළුවන්ගේ අවශ්‍යය සහ අවශ්‍ය විශ්වාස කරනවා ක්‍රියාත්මක ස්ක්‍රි ඊට පස්සේ අපි විශ්වාස කරන්න පුළුවන් විශ්වාස කරන්න පුළුවන් විශ්වාස කරන්න පුළුවන් විශ්වාස කරපු වි</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>We describe an approach to generating explanations about why robot actions fail, focusing on the considerations of robots that are run by cognitive robotic architectures.  Waxaannu qoraynaa noocyo qalloocan ah iyo macbudo qalloocan ah, taasoo ku dhaqdhaqaaqsan baahida iyo xadhiidka dhismaha aqoonta ee isticmaalaya qoraalka waxqabadka iyo qoraalka macluumaadka turjumaadda, waxaana ku qoraynaa macluumaadka garsooridda iyo garashada dhulka. Markaas waxaynu sawiraynaa qiimeynta lagu sii kordhi karo si aad u sii barato saamaynta qaabilaada kala duduwanta qoraalka.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Vi beskriver ett tillvägagångssätt för att generera förklaringar till varför robotaktioner misslyckas, med fokus på överväganden av robotar som drivs av kognitiva robotarkitekturer. Vi definierar en uppsättning misslyckande typer och förklaringsmallar, motiverar dem av behoven och begränsningarna hos kognitiva arkitekturer som använder handlingsskript och tolkningsbara trostillstånd, och beskriver innehållsrealisering och ytrealisering i detta sammanhang. Därefter beskriver vi en utvärdering som kan utökas för att ytterligare studera effekterna av att variera förklaringsmallarna.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாம் விவரிக்கிறோம் ஏன் ரோபோட்ட் செயல்கள் தோல்வியுற்றது என்பதை பற்றி விளக்கம் உருவாக்க ஒரு வழியை விளக்குகிறோம், குறிப்பிட் நாம் ஒரு சில தோல்வியான வகைகளை மற்றும் வெளியீட்டு வார்ப்புருக்களை வரையறுக்கிறோம், அவற்றை தேவைகள் மற்றும் அறிந்து கொள்ளும் கட்டுப்பாடுகளின் கட்டுப்பாடுகள விளக்க வார்ப்புருக்களின் விளைவுகளை மேலும் படிக்க முடியும்.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم نے روبوت کے کام کیوں ناکام ہوتے ہیں اور روبوت کے مطابق مطابق دکھائے جاتے ہیں جو معلوم روبوت معماروں سے چلتے ہیں۔ ہم ایک مجموعہ غلطی طریقے اور پتفصیل ٹیپلٹوں کی تعریف کرتے ہیں، ان کی ضرورت اور محدودیت کے ذریعہ ان کی پیدائش کرتے ہیں جن کے ذریعہ اقتدار لکھائی اور قابل تعریف کے قابل ایمانوں کو استعمال کرتے ہیں، اور ان کی محدودیت میں موجود حقیقت اور سطح حقیقت پھر ہم ایک ارزیابی کا مطابق بیان کرتے ہیں جو پھیلائے جاتے ہیں اور پھیلائے جاتے ہیں کہ تفصیلات کے معاملات میں مختلف اثرات</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Biz qanday robot amallari muvaffaqiyatli bajarayotganligini rivojlanishimiz haqida o'ylaymiz, biz qo'shimcha robot maktablari bilan boshqaradigan narsalarning fikrlarini anglatamiz. Biz muvaffaqiyatli turlar va Explanation Namunalarni aniqlasamiz. Ularni amallar skriptlaridan foydalanish va tarjima qilish imkoniyatlaridan foydalanish kerakli va qatlamlar bilan ishlatiladi. Keyin biz bir qiymatni aytib beramiz, bir qatlamni o'zgartirish uchun o'zgartirish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi mô tả phương pháp phát triển giải thích tại sao các hành động robot thất bại, tập trung vào các quan điểm của robot được điều hành bởi kiến trúc robot nhận thức. Chúng tôi xác định một loạt các kiểu thất bại và giải thích các biểu tượng, thúc đẩy chúng dựa trên nhu cầu và giới hạn của kiến trúc nhận thức sử dụng các văn bản hành động và các tiểu bang có thể hiểu được, và mô tả thực hiện nội dung và thực hiện bề mặt trong bối cảnh này. Sau đó chúng tôi mô tả một đánh giá có thể được mở rộng để nghiên cứu thêm về hiệu quả của việc thay đổi các mẫu giải thích.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>Opišemo pristup stvaranju objašnjenja o tome zašto roboti nisu uspjeli, fokusirajući se na razmišljanja robota koje vode kognitivne robotičke arhitekture. Definiramo skup tipa neuspjeha i šablona objašnjenja, motivirajući ih potrebama i ograničenjima kognitivnih arhitektura koji koriste akcijske skriptove i uvjerljive države vjerovanja i opisuju realizaciju sadržaja i realizaciju površine u ovom kontekstu. Onda opisujemo procjenu koja se može proširiti do daljnjeg proučavanja učinka različitih šablona objašnjenja.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi beskriver en tilgang til at generere forklaringer om, hvorfor robothandlinger mislykkes, med fokus på overvejelserne om robotter, der drives af kognitive robotarkitekturer. Vi definerer et sæt af Failure Types og Forklaringsskabeloner, der motiverer dem ved hjælp af behov og begrænsninger i kognitive arkitekturer, der bruger handlingsskrifter og fortolkelige trostilstande, og beskriver indholdsrealisering og overfladebehandling i denne sammenhæng. Vi beskriver derefter en evaluering, der kan udvides til yderligere at studere effekten af at variere forklaringsskabelonerne.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Kami menggambarkan pendekatan untuk menghasilkan penjelasan mengapa tindakan robot gagal, fokus pada pertimbangan robot yang dijalankan oleh arsitektur robot kognitif. Kami mendefinisikan set Jenis Kegagalan dan Templat Penjelasan, mendorongnya dengan kebutuhan dan batas arsitektur kognitif yang menggunakan skrip aksi dan keadaan keyakinan yang dapat diterjemahkan, dan menggambarkan realizasi isi dan realizasi permukaan dalam konteks ini. Kemudian kami menggambarkan sebuah evaluasi yang dapat diperluaskan untuk mempelajari lebih lanjut efek dari variasi templat penjelasan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 로봇 동작의 실패 원인을 설명하는 방법을 묘사했고 인지 로봇 체계 구조로 운행하는 로봇에 중점을 두었다.우리는 고장 유형과 해석 템플릿을 정의하여 동작 스크립트와 해석 가능한 신념 상태의 인지 구조의 수요와 제약을 사용하여 그들을 격려하고 이 배경에서 내용의 실현과 표면적인 실현을 묘사한다.그리고 우리는 서로 다른 해석 템플릿의 영향을 더욱 연구하기 위해 확장할 수 있는 평가를 묘사했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_nl>We beschrijven een benadering om uitleg te genereren over waarom robotacties mislukken, waarbij we ons concentreren op de overwegingen van robots die worden beheerd door cognitieve robotarchitecturen. We definiëren een set van mislukkingstypes en verklaringssjablonen, die hen motiveren door de behoeften en beperkingen van cognitieve architecturen die actiescripts en interpreteerbare geloofsstanden gebruiken, en beschrijven content realisatie en oppervlakterealisatie in deze context. Vervolgens beschrijven we een evaluatie die uitgebreid kan worden om de effecten van het variëren van de verklaringssjablonen verder te bestuderen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Описваме подход за генериране на обяснения защо действията на роботите се провалят, фокусирайки се върху съображенията на роботите, които се управляват от когнитивни роботизирани архитектури. Определяме набор от типове провали и шаблони за обяснение, мотивирайки ги от нуждите и ограниченията на когнитивните архитектури, които използват скриптове за действие и тълкуваеми състояния на вярване, и описваме реализацията на съдържанието и реализацията на повърхността в този контекст. След това описваме оценка, която може да бъде разширена, за да се проучат допълнително ефектите от промяна на шаблоните за обяснение.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_fa>ما روش توضیح می‌کنیم که توضیح‌ها در مورد چگونه عمل روبات شکست خورد، تمرکز به توضیح روبات‌ها که توسط معماری روبات شناخته می‌شوند. ما یک مجموعه از نوع غلطی و کلمات توضیح را تعریف می‌کنیم، که آنها را توسط نیازهای و محدودیت معماری شناسی که از نوشته‌های اقدام و ایجاد باوری قابل تعریف استفاده می‌کنند، انگیزه می‌کنند، و در این محیط واقعیت محتویات و واقعیت سطح را توصیف سپس یک ارزیابی را توصیف می کنیم که می تواند برای مطالعه بیشتر اثرات تغییر الگوهای توضیح تغییر دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_de>Wir beschreiben einen Ansatz zur Generierung von Erklärungen darüber, warum Roboteraktionen scheitern, wobei wir uns auf die Überlegungen von Robotern konzentrieren, die von kognitiven Roboterarchitekturen betrieben werden. Wir definieren eine Reihe von Fehlertypen und Erläuterungsvorlagen, motivieren sie durch die Bedürfnisse und Einschränkungen kognitiver Architekturen, die Aktionsskripte und interpretierbare Glaubenszustände verwenden, und beschreiben Inhaltsrealisierung und Oberflächenrealisierung in diesem Kontext. Anschließend beschreiben wir eine Evaluation, die erweitert werden kann, um die Auswirkungen der Variation der Erklärungsvorlagen weiter zu untersuchen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaelezea namna ya kutengeneza maelezo kuhusu kwa nini vitendo vya roboti vinavyoshindwa, kwa lengo la kutafakari za roboti zinazoendeshwa na majengo ya roboti maarufu. Tunaweza kufafanua mfululizo wa Vyombo vya Matumizi na Maelezo ya Kushindwa, na kuwahamasisha kwa mahitaji na vikwazo vya majengo ya maarufu vinavyotumia vitabu vya hatua na matamko ya imani yanayotafsiri, na kuelezea kutambua maudhui na kutambua sura katika muktadha huu. Kisha tunaelezea tathmini ambazo zinaweza kuongezeka zaidi ili kusoma madhara ya mabadiliko ya misitu ya ufafanuzi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_am>የሮቦት ተግባሮች ለምን መሳሰል፣ የሮቦቶች መሠረት መሠረት የሚቆሙትን የሮቦቶች አካባቢዎች ማሳየት እናሳውቃለን፡፡ የስህተት ዓይነት እና የስህተት መክፈቻን እና የፍላጎት መክፈቻን እና የሥርዓት ጽሑፎችን እና ትርጉም እምነትን የሚጠይቁ የሥርዓት መሠረቶች እና ግንኙነቶችን በሚያሳስቱ እና የጥያቄ ማውቀትን እና የsurface ማውቀትን በመግለጥ እና ይዘረጋለን፡፡ የዚያን ጊዜም የመረጃ መልዕክቶች የልዩ ትርጓሜዎችን ለማስተምር የሚችሉትን ማስታወቂያውን እናሳውቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_tr>Biz robot eylemleriniň näme üçin boýunça düşünmesi barada düşündirişi ýaly düşündirip, bilgili robot arhitektarlarynyň düşünmesine üns berýäris. Biz ýalňyş hiller we düşündirim modalaryny tassyklaýarys, olary bu kontekstde bolan bilgili arhitektarlaryň gereklikleri we çäreleri tarapyndan süýtgedýäris. Sonra çözümlerde farklı bir şekilde düzenlenebilir değerlendirme çarpıyoruz.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Ons beskrywe 'n toegang om uitduidelings te genereer oor hoekom robot aksies misluk het, fokus op die aandagings van robots wat deur kognitiewe robotiese arkitektuure hardloop word. Ons definieer 'n stel van Mislukkige Tipe en Verduideling Sjabloane, wat hulle motiveer deur die behoefte en beheinings van kognitiewe arkitektuur wat aksie skripte gebruik en uittelbare geloof staatste, en beskryf inhoud realisasie en oorspronklike realisasie in hierdie konteks. Ons beskrywe dan 'n evaluering wat kan verleng word na verdere ondersoek die effekte van verandering van die uitduidelike templates.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_az>Biz robot eylemlərinin niyə başarısız olması haqqında açıqlama təşkil etmək üçün bir yol təşkil edirik, bilikli robot arhitektarları təşkil edən robotların düşüncələrinə odaqlanır. Biz səhv Türələri və Explosion Şablonlarını təsdiqləyirik, onları hərəkət skriptlərini və təfsil edilə bilən kognitiv arhitektirlərin ehtiyaçları və sərhələri ilə təsdiqləyirik, məlumatların realizasyonu və üzərini bu məlumatlarda təsdiqləyirik. Sonra müxtəlif şəkillərin dəyişikliklərinin etkisini daha çox öyrənmək üçün uzaqlaşdırılabilir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք նկարագրում ենք բացատրություններ ստեղծելու մոտեցումը, թե ինչու են ռոբոտային գործողությունները ձախողվում, կենտրոնացնելով ռոբոտների վերլուծումների վրա, որոնք ղեկավարվում են ճանաչողական ռոբոտային ճարտարապետություններով: Մենք սահմանում ենք ձախողումների և բացատրության մի շարք ձևեր, որոնք խթանում են դրանք ճանաչողական ճարտարապետությունների կարիքների և սահմանափակումների վրա, որոնք օգտագործում են գործողության գրառումներ և թարգմանելի հավատալի վիճակներ, և նկարագրում են պարունակության իրականացումը և մակերեսի իրա Այնուհետև մենք նկարագրում ենք մի գնահատում, որը կարող է ընդլայնվել հետագա ուսումնասիրելու համար բացատրության մոդելների տարբեր ազդեցությունները:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>We describe an approach to generating explanations about why robot actions fail, focusing on the considerations of robots that are run by cognitive robotic architectures.  আমরা ব্যর্থ ধরন এবং এক্সপ্ল্যানেশন মন্দিরগুলো নির্ধারণ করি, যারা কাজের স্ক্রিপ্ট এবং ব্যাখ্যাত বিশ্বাস ব্যবহার করে তাদের প্রয়োজন এবং সংক্রান্ত স্ক্রিপ্ট ব্যবহা তারপর আমরা একটি মূল্য বর্ণনা করি যা ব্যাখ্যা মন্দির প্রভাব বিভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Opišemo pristup stvaranju objašnjenja o tome zašto roboti nisu uspjeli, fokusirajući se na razmišljanja robota koje vode kognitivne robotičke arhitekture. Definiramo skup tipa neuspjeha i obrazovanja šablona, motivirajući ih potrebama i ograničenjima kognitivnih arhitektura koji koriste akcijske skriptove i interpretabilne države vjerovanja i opisuju realizaciju sadržaja i realizaciju površine u ovom kontekstu. Onda opisujemo procjenu koja se može proširiti do daljnjeg proučavanja učinka različitih šablona objašnjenja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Popisujeme přístup k generování vysvětlení, proč akce robotů selhávají, se zaměřením na úvahy robotů, které jsou řízeny kognitivními robotickými architekturami. Definujeme sadu typů selhání a šablon vysvětlení, motivujeme je potřebami a omezeními kognitivních architektur, které využívají akční skripty a interpretovatelné stavy víry, a popisujeme realizaci obsahu a povrchovou realizaci v tomto kontextu. Následně popisujeme hodnocení, které lze rozšířit o další studium účinků změny vysvětlovacích šablon.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_sq>We describe an approach to generating explanations about why robot actions fail, focusing on the considerations of robots that are run by cognitive robotic architectures.  Ne përcaktojmë një sërë llojeve të dështimit dhe modeleve të shpjegimit, duke i motivuar ata nga nevojat dhe kufizimet e arkitekturave kognitive që përdorin skripte veprimi dhe shtete të interpretueshme besimi dhe përshkruajnë realizimin e përmbajtjes dhe realizimin e sipërfaqes në këtë kontekst. Pastaj përshkruajmë një vlerësim që mund të zgjerohet për të studiuar më tej efektet e ndryshimit të modeleve të shpjegimit.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_et>Kirjeldame lähenemisviisi, kuidas luua selgitusi selle kohta, miks robotitegevus ebaõnnestub, keskendudes kognitiivse robotiarhitektuuriga juhitavate robotite kaalutlustele. Määratleme veatüüpide ja selgitusmallide komplekti, motiveerides neid kognitiivsete arhitektuuride vajaduste ja piirangutega, mis kasutavad tegevuskripte ja tõlgendatavaid uskumusi, ning kirjeldame sisu realiseerimist ja pinna realiseerimist selles kontekstis. Seejärel kirjeldame hindamist, mida saab laiendada selgitusmallide muutmise mõju edasiseks uurimiseks.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ca>Descrivem un enfocament a generar explicacions sobre per què les accions dels robots fracassen, centrant-nos en les consideracions dels robots que estan dirigits per arquitectures robòtiques cognitives. Definim un conjunt de tipus de fracàs i models d'explicació, motivant-los per les necessitats i restriccions de les arquitectures cognitives que utilitzen escriptures d'acció i estats de creença interpretables, i descriuen la concretització del contingut i la concretització de la superfície en aquest context. Després descrivim una evaluació que es pot estendre a estudiar més sobre els efectes de variar els patrons d'explicació.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Kuvailemme tapaa tuottaa selityksiä siitä, miksi robottitoimet epäonnistuvat, keskittyen kognitiivisen robottiarkkiteektuurin pyörittämiin robotteihin. Määrittelemme joukon epäonnistumistyyppejä ja selittämismalleja motivoimalla niitä toimintaskriptejä ja tulkittavia uskomustiloja käyttävien kognitiivisten arkkitehtuurien tarpeiden ja rajoitusten perusteella ja kuvaamme sisällön toteutumista ja pintatoteutumista tässä yhteydessä. Tämän jälkeen kuvaamme arviointia, jota voidaan laajentaa tutkimaan tarkemmin selitysmallien vaihtelun vaikutuksia.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna bayyana wani hanyoyi zuwa ta ƙãga fassarar bayani a kan mẽne ne aikin mashukini za'a ɓace, kuma tuna makini ga masu riƙon mashukini na tafiyar da kognitive Roboti. Mu ƙayyade wasu irin Template na Babu'a da Explanation, masu motsa su da buƙata na matsayi masu yiwuwa da ake amfani da manuscriptun aiki da misãlai masu fassarawa, kuma masu bayyana ganin maɓalli da gane sura cikin wannan muhalli. Sa'an nan kuma Munã bayyana wani rayi wanda za'a iya ƙara shi dõmin a karanta matsayin ayõyin da aka rarrabe kayan-ayukan.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>We describe an approach to generating explanations about why robot actions fail, focusing on the considerations of robots that are run by cognitive robotic architectures.  אנחנו מגדירים קבוצה של טיפוסי כישלון ודגמנים להסבירה, שמניעים אותם על ידי הצרכים והמחסומים של ארכיטקטורות קוגניטיביות שמשתמשים בתסריטים פעולה ומדינות אמונה אפשריות, ותארו את ההבנה של התוכן ואת ההבנה של השטח בתוך הקשר הזה. ואז אנחנו מתארים עריכה שאפשר להאריך לחקור נוסף את ההשפעות של שינוי מודלים ההסבר.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Awakdhéwé éntuk dadi kanggo nggawe akeh pancene kapan ning acara aksi bot sing ora jalaké, nik nggawe barang nggawe barang bot sing nguasara architecture bot sing sampeyan biya. Awak dhéwé ngpisan Kemerdekaan Tipe sing Gawe Kasunyatan karo Kejahatan Kasunyatan Awak dhéwé éntuk pisan éntuk sing iso nggambar ngéwé, lan uwis njaluk kanggo mulai njaluk kanggo nyelaraké modènan pancening.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Opisujemo pristop k ustvarjanju razlag o neuspehu delovanja robotov, s poudarkom na premislekih robotov, ki jih vodijo kognitivne robotske arhitekture. Opredelimo nabor vrst napak in predlog za pojasnjevanje, ki jih motiviramo s potrebami in omejitvami kognitivnih arhitektur, ki uporabljajo akcijske skripte in razložljiva stanja prepričanja, ter opisujemo realizacijo vsebine in površinsko realizacijo v tem kontekstu. Nato opišemo oceno, ki jo je mogoče razširiti za nadaljnje preučevanje učinkov spreminjanja predlog pojasnil.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་Robot བྱ་འགུལ་གྱི་གནད་སྡུད་འདི་ཇི་ལྟར་འགྱུར་བའི་སྐོར་ལས་འགྲེལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ཞིག་མི་སྟོན་པར་གཏོང་ཡོད། We define a set of Failure Types and Explanation Templates, motivating them by the needs and constraints of cognitive architectures that use action scripts and interpretable belief states, and describe content realization and surface realization in this context. འོན་ཀྱང་།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>