<collection id="2020.framenet">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the International FrameNet Workshop 2020: Towards a Global, Multilingual FrameNet</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Tiago T.</first><last>Torrent</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Collin F.</first><last>Baker</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Oliver</first><last>Czulo</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kyoko</first><last>Ohara</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Miriam R. L.</first><last>Petruck</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-58-0</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9b12a8db">2020.framenet-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>framenet-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Finding Corresponding Constructions in <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish and <fixed-case>J</fixed-case>apanese in a <fixed-case>TED</fixed-case> Talk Parallel Corpus using Frames-and-Constructions Analysis</title>
      <author><first>Kyoko</first><last>Ohara</last></author>
      <pages>8&#8211;12</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports on an effort to search for corresponding constructions in English and Japanese in a TED Talk parallel corpus, using frames-and-constructions analysis (Ohara, 2019; Ohara and Okubo, 2020; cf. Czulo, 2013, 2017). The purpose of the paper is two-fold: (1) to demonstrate the validity of frames-and-constructions analysis to search for corresponding constructions in typologically unrelated languages; and (2) to assess whether the &#8220;Do schools kill creativity?&#8221; TED Talk parallel corpus, annotated in various languages for Multilingual FrameNet, is a good starting place for building a multilingual constructicon. The analysis showed that similar to our previous findings involving texts in a Japanese to English bilingual children&#8217;s book, the TED Talk bilingual transcripts include pairs of constructions that share similar pragmatic functions. While the TED Talk parallel corpus constitutes a good resource for frame semantic annotation in multiple languages, it may not be the ideal place to start aligning constructions among typologically unrelated languages. Finally, this work shows that the proposed method, which focuses on heads of sentences, seems valid for searching for corresponding constructions in transcripts of spoken data, as well as in written data of typologically-unrelated languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="4a76dec0">2020.framenet-1.2</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>ohara-2020-finding</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title><fixed-case>G</fixed-case>reek within the Global <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>rame<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et Initiative: Challenges and Conclusions so far</title>
      <author><first>Voula</first><last>Giouli</last></author>
      <author><first>Vera</first><last>Pilitsidou</last></author>
      <author><first>Hephaestion</first><last>Christopoulos</last></author>
      <pages>48&#8211;55</pages>
      <abstract>Large coverage lexical resources that bear deep linguistic information have always been considered useful for many natural language processing (NLP) applications including Machine Translation (MT). In this respect, Frame-based resources have been developed for many languages following Frame Semantics and the Berkeley FrameNet project. However, to a great extent, all those efforts have been kept fragmented. Consequentially, the Global FrameNet initiative has been conceived of as a joint effort to bring together FrameNets in different languages. The proposed paper is aimed at describing ongoing work towards developing the Greek (EL) counterpart of the Global FrameNet and our efforts to contribute to the Shared Annotation Task. In the paper, we will elaborate on the annotation methodology employed, the current status and progress made so far, as well as the problems raised during annotation.</abstract>
      <url hash="ec031005">2020.framenet-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>giouli-etal-2020-greek</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Exploring Crosslinguistic Frame Alignment</title>
      <author><first>Collin F.</first><last>Baker</last></author>
      <author><first>Arthur</first><last>Lorenzi</last></author>
      <pages>77&#8211;84</pages>
      <abstract>The FrameNet (FN) project at the International Computer Science Institute in Berkeley (ICSI), which documents the core vocabulary of contemporary English, was the first lexical resource based on Fillmore&#8217;s theory of Frame Semantics. Berkeley FrameNet has inspired related projects in roughly a dozen other languages, which have evolved somewhat independently; the current Multilingual FrameNet project (MLFN) is an attempt to find alignments between all of them. The alignment problem is complicated by the fact that these projects have adhered to the Berkeley FrameNet model to varying degrees, and they were also founded at different times, when different versions of the Berkeley FrameNet data were available. We describe several new methods for finding relations of similarity between semantic frames across languages. We will demonstrate ViToXF, a new tool which provides interactive visualizations of these cross-lingual relations, between frames, lexical units, and frame elements, based on resources such as multilingual dictionaries and on shared distributional vector spaces, making clear the strengths and weaknesses of different alignment methods.</abstract>
      <url hash="05813073">2020.framenet-1.11</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>baker-lorenzi-2020-exploring</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>