<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.knlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-12-02">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of Knowledgeable NLP: the First Workshop on Integrating Structured Knowledge and Neural Networks for NLP</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Oren Sar</first><last>Shalom</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alexander</first><last>Panchenko</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Cicero</first><last>dos Santos</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Varvara</first><last>Logacheva</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alessandro</first><last>Moschitti</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ido</first><last>Dagan</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Suzhou, China</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="61ff76fc">2020.knlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>knlp-2020-knowledgeable</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Social Media Medical Concept Normalization using RoBERTa in Ontology Enriched Text Similarity Framework<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>a in Ontology Enriched Text Similarity Framework</title>
      <author><first>Katikapalli Subramanyam</first><last>Kalyan</last></author>
      <author><first>Sivanesan</first><last>Sangeetha</last></author>
      <pages>21–26</pages>
      <abstract>Pattisapu et al. (2020) formulate medical concept normalization (MCN) as text similarity problem and propose a model based on RoBERTa and graph embedding based target concept vectors. However, graph embedding techniques ignore valuable information available in the clinical ontology like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">concept description</a> and synonyms. In this work, we enhance the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> of Pattisapu et al. (2020) with two novel changes. First, we use retrofitted target concept vectors instead of graph embedding based vectors. It is the first work to leverage both concept description and synonyms to represent concepts in the form of retrofitted target concept vectors in text similarity framework based social media MCN. Second, we generate both concept and concept mention vectors with same size which eliminates the need of dense layers to project concept mention vectors into the target concept embedding space. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> outperforms existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> with improvements up to 3.75 % on two standard datasets. Further when trained only on mapping lexicon synonyms, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> outperforms existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> with significant improvements up to 14.61 %. We attribute these significant improvements to the two novel changes introduced.</abstract>
      <url hash="ff2a5c1b">2020.knlp-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>kalyan-sangeetha-2020-social</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>BERTChem-DDI : Improved Drug-Drug Interaction Prediction from text using Chemical Structure Information<fixed-case>BERTC</fixed-case>hem-<fixed-case>DDI</fixed-case> : Improved Drug-Drug Interaction Prediction from text using Chemical Structure Information</title>
      <author><first>Ishani</first><last>Mondal</last></author>
      <pages>27–32</pages>
      <abstract>Traditional biomedical version of embeddings obtained from pre-trained language models have recently shown state-of-the-art results for relation extraction (RE) tasks in the medical domain. In this paper, we explore how to incorporate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_knowledge">domain knowledge</a>, available in the form of molecular structure of drugs, for predicting Drug-Drug Interaction from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">textual corpus</a>. We propose a method, BERTChem-DDI, to efficiently combine drug embeddings obtained from the rich chemical structure of drugs (encoded in SMILES) along with off-the-shelf domain-specific BioBERT embedding-based RE architecture. Experiments conducted on the DDIExtraction 2013 corpus clearly indicate that this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy">strategy</a> improves other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">strong baselines architectures</a> by 3.4 % <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macro_(computer_science)">macro F1-score</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="873fd0c4">2020.knlp-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>mondal-2020-bertchem</bibkey>
    <title_ar>BERTChem-DDI: تحسين التنبؤ بالتفاعل بين الأدوية والعقاقير من النص باستخدام معلومات التركيب الكيميائي</title_ar>
      <title_es>Bertchem-DDI: predicción mejorada de la interacción entre fármacos a partir del texto utilizando información de estructura química</title_es>
      <title_pt>BERTChem-DDI: Predição de interação droga-droga aprimorada a partir de texto usando informações de estrutura química</title_pt>
      <title_ja>BERTChem - DDI ：化学構造情報を使用したテキストからの改善された薬物-薬物相互作用予測</title_ja>
      <title_hi>BERTChem-DDI: रासायनिक संरचना जानकारी का उपयोग कर पाठ से बेहतर दवा-ड्रग इंटरैक्शन भविष्यवाणी</title_hi>
      <title_zh>BERTChem-DDI 曰: 用化学结信-药用相知也</title_zh>
      <title_ga>BERTChem-DDI : Réamh-mheastachán Feabhsaithe maidir le hIdirghníomhaíocht Drugaí-Drugaí ó théacs ag úsáid Faisnéis ar Struchtúr Ceimiceach</title_ga>
      <title_hu>BERTChem-DDI: Javított gyógyszer-gyógyszer kölcsönhatás előrejelzése szövegből kémiai szerkezeti információk használatával</title_hu>
      <title_ka>BERTChem- DDI : გასაკეთებული ნაპროგრამის ინტერქექცია ტექსტიდან გამოყენებული ქიმიკური სტრუქტურის ინფორმაცია</title_ka>
      <title_el>Βελτιωμένη πρόβλεψη αλληλεπίδρασης φαρμάκων-φαρμάκων από κείμενο χρησιμοποιώντας πληροφορίες χημικής δομής</title_el>
      <title_it>BERTChem-DDI: Migliorata la previsione dell'interazione farmaco-farmaco dal testo utilizzando le informazioni sulla struttura chimica</title_it>
      <title_kk>BERTChem- DDI : Химикалық құрылғы мәліметін қолданатын мәтіннен құрылған наркотикалық интерфекциялық бағдарламасы</title_kk>
      <title_mk>BERTChem-DDI : Improved Drug-Drug Interaction Prediction from text using Chemical Structure Information</title_mk>
      <title_lt>BERTChem-DDI: Geresnis narkotikų sąveikos prognozė iš teksto, naudojant cheminės struktūros informaciją</title_lt>
      <title_mt>BERTChem-DDI : Tbassir imtejjeb tal-interazzjoni bejn id-drogi u d-drogi mit-test bl-użu ta’ Informazzjoni dwar l-Istruttura Kimika</title_mt>
      <title_ms>BERTChem-DDI : Pertamaan Perlakangan Interaksi dadah-dadah dari teks menggunakan Maklumat Struktur Kimia</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ബെര്‍ട്ടിചെമ്- ഡിഡിഐ: ചെമിക്കല്‍ സ്ട്രാക്ട്രൂക്ടര്‍ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ച് മയക്കുമരുന്നുവെട്ടിയുടെ വിവരങ്ങള്‍</title_ml>
      <title_mn>BERTChem-DDI : Improved Drug-Drug Interaction Prediction from text using Chemical Structure Information</title_mn>
      <title_no>BERTChem-DDI : Forhåndsvising av forbetra narkotika-interaksjon frå tekst ved hjelp av kjemiske struktureinformasjon</title_no>
      <title_sr>BERTChem-DDI : Poboljšana predviđanja interakcije droga iz teksta koristeći informacije o kemijskoj strukturi</title_sr>
      <title_pl>BERTChem-DDI: Udoskonalona predykcja interakcji lekowo-lekowych na podstawie tekstu z wykorzystaniem informacji o strukturze chemicznej</title_pl>
      <title_ro>BERTChem-DDI: Predicția îmbunătățită a interacțiunii medicament-medicament din text folosind informații privind structura chimică</title_ro>
      <title_so>BERTChem-DDI : Improved Drug-drug Interaction Prediction from text using Chemical Structure Information</title_so>
      <title_si>BERTChem</title_si>
      <title_sv>BERTChem-DDI: Förbättrad prognos för läkemedelsinteraktion från text med hjälp av kemisk strukturinformation</title_sv>
      <title_ta>BERTChem- DDI: சைமிக்கல் அமைப்பு தகவலை பயன்படுத்தி முன்னேற்றப்பட்ட Drug- Drug Interaction Prediction from text</title_ta>
      <title_ur>BERTChem-DDI : Chemical Structure Information using text from Improved Drug-Drug Interaction Prediction</title_ur>
      <title_uz>QUnicodeControlCharacterMenu</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Sự tương tác thuốc kích thích tốt từ văn bản dùng thông tin cấu trúc hóa học</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Подобрено прогнозиране на взаимодействието лекарство-лекарство от текст, използващ информация за химическата структура</title_bg>
      <title_da>BERTChem-DDI: Forbedret forudsigelse af lægemiddelinteraktion fra tekst ved hjælp af kemisk strukturinformation</title_da>
      <title_hr>BERTChem-DDI : Poboljšana interakcija droga iz teksta koristeći informacije o kemijskoj strukturi</title_hr>
      <title_nl>BERTChem-DDI: Verbeterde Drug-Drug Interactie Voorspelling op basis van tekst met behulp van Chemische Structuur Informatie</title_nl>
      <title_id>BERTChem-DDI : Perkiraan interaksi obat-obat meningkat dari teks menggunakan Informasi Struktur Kimia</title_id>
      <title_de>BERTChem-DDI: Verbesserte Vorhersage von Arzneimittel-Arzneimittel-Wechselwirkungen aus Texten unter Verwendung chemischer Strukturinformationen</title_de>
      <title_fa>BERTChem-DDI : پیشنهاد تفاوت مواد مخدر و مواد بهتر شده از متن استفاده از اطلاعات ساختار شیمیایی</title_fa>
      <title_sw>BERTChem-DDI : Udhibiti wa Ushirikiano wa dawa ulioboreshwa kutoka maandishi kwa kutumia taarifa za Miundombinu</title_sw>
      <title_ko>BERTChem DDI: 화학 구조 정보를 활용하여 텍스트에서 약물 상호작용 예측 개선</title_ko>
      <title_tr>BERTChem-DDI : Çimi struktur Maglumaty ullanýan metin üçin gelişmiş narkotik ilatyny</title_tr>
      <title_af>BERTChem- DDI : Geverbeterde Drug- Drug Interaksie Voorskou van teks gebruik Chemical Structure Information</title_af>
      <title_am>BERTChem-DDI : Improved Drug-Drug Interaction Prediction from text using Chemical Structure Information</title_am>
      <title_sq>BERTChem-DDI : Parashikimi i përmirësuar i ndërveprimit të drogës-drogës nga teksti duke përdorur informacionin e strukturës kimike</title_sq>
      <title_hy>BERCH-DRI. Թմրադեղերի և թմրադեղերի ինտերակցիայի բարելավված կանխատեսումը տեքստից, օգտագործելով քիմիական կառուցվածքի տեղեկատվություն</title_hy>
      <title_az>BERTChem-DDI : Chemical Structure Information vasit…ôsil…ô m…ôtnd…ôn uyuŇüturucu-uyuŇüturucu Interaction Prediction</title_az>
      <title_bn>BERTChem-DDI: কেমিক্যাল কাঠামো তথ্য ব্যবহার করে মাদক-মাদক ইন্টারনেশনের সুবিধা</title_bn>
      <title_bs>BERTChem-DDI : Poboljšana predviđanja interakcije droga iz teksta koristeći informacije o kemijskoj strukturi</title_bs>
      <title_ca>BERTChem-DDI: Improved Drug-Drug Interaction Prediction from text using Chemical Structure Information</title_ca>
      <title_cs>BERTChem-DDI: Zlepšená predikce interakce léčiv-léčiv z textu s využitím informací o chemické struktuře</title_cs>
      <title_et>BERTChem-DDI: ravimite ja ravimite parema koostoime prognoosimine keemilise struktuuri teabe abil</title_et>
      <title_fi>BERTChem-DDI: Parannettu lääkkeiden ja lääkkeiden yhteisvaikutuksen ennuste tekstistä käyttäen kemiallista rakennetta koskevia tietoja</title_fi>
      <title_jv>BERT Kemik-DDN: Bukak Drog-Drog interaction predikyon seng teks nggambar Kemik structural Informasi</title_jv>
      <title_sk>BERTChem-DDI: Napoved boljšega medsebojnega delovanja med zdravili iz besedila z uporabo informacij o kemijski strukturi</title_sk>
      <title_he>BERTChem-DDI: שיפור התאמה בין תרופות ולסמים מתוך טקסט באמצעות מידע מבנה כימי</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>BERTChem-DDI : Improved Drug-Drug Interaction Prediction from text using Chemical Structure Information</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>أظهرت النسخة الطبية الحيوية التقليدية للزفافات التي تم الحصول عليها من نماذج اللغة المدربة مسبقًا مؤخرًا أحدث النتائج لمهام استخراج العلاقة (RE) في المجال الطبي. في هذه الورقة ، نستكشف كيفية دمج معرفة المجال ، المتوفرة في شكل التركيب الجزيئي للأدوية ، للتنبؤ بالتفاعل بين الأدوية والعقاقير من مجموعة النصوص. نقترح طريقة ، BERTChem-DDI ، للجمع بكفاءة بين عمليات دمج الأدوية التي تم الحصول عليها من التركيب الكيميائي الغني للأدوية (المشفرة في SMILES) جنبًا إلى جنب مع بنية BioBERT القائمة على التضمين القائمة على المجال الجاهز. تشير التجارب التي أجريت على مجموعة DDIExtraction 2013 بوضوح إلى أن هذه الإستراتيجية تعمل على تحسين بنى خطوط الأساس القوية الأخرى بنسبة 3.4٪ من الدرجة الكلية F1.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Versões biomédicas tradicionais de embeddings obtidas a partir de modelos de linguagem pré-treinados mostraram recentemente resultados de última geração para tarefas de extração de relações (ER) no domínio médico. Neste artigo, exploramos como incorporar o conhecimento do domínio, disponível na forma de estrutura molecular de drogas, para prever a interação droga-droga a partir do corpus textual. Propomos um método, BERTChem-DDI, para combinar eficientemente incorporações de drogas obtidas a partir da rica estrutura química de drogas (codificadas em SMILES) juntamente com arquitetura de RE baseada em incorporação específica de domínio BioBERT pronta para uso. Experimentos conduzidos no corpus DDIExtraction 2013 indicam claramente que essa estratégia melhora outras arquiteturas de linhas de base fortes em 3,4% macro F1-score.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>La versión biomédica tradicional de las incorporaciones obtenidas de modelos lingüísticos previamente entrenados ha mostrado recientemente resultados de vanguardia para las tareas de extracción de relaciones (RE) en el dominio médico. En este artículo, exploramos cómo incorporar el conocimiento del dominio, disponible en forma de estructura molecular de los fármacos, para predecir la interacción entre fármacos a partir de un corpus textual. Proponemos un método, Bertchem-DDI, para combinar eficazmente las incrustaciones de fármacos obtenidas de la rica estructura química de los fármacos (codificados en SMILES) junto con la arquitectura de RE basada en la incrustación de BioBert específica del dominio disponible. Los experimentos realizados en el corpus DDIExtraction 2013 indican claramente que esta estrategia mejora otras arquitecturas de líneas de base sólidas en un 3,4% de puntuación de F1 macro.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>事前にトレーニングされた言語モデルから得られた埋め込みの従来の生物医学的バージョンは、最近、医療領域における関係抽出（ RE ）タスクの最先端の結果を示しています。この論文では、テキストコーパスから薬物-薬物相互作用を予測するために、薬物の分子構造の形で利用可能なドメイン知識を組み込む方法を探求する。医薬品の豊富な化学構造（ SMILESでコード化）から得られた医薬品埋め込みと、既製のドメイン固有のBioBERT埋め込みベースのREアーキテクチャを効率的に組み合わせる方法、BERTChem - DDIを提案します。DDIExtraction 2013コーパスで実施された実験は、この戦略が他の強力なベースラインアーキテクチャを3.4 ％のマクロF 1スコアで改善することを明確に示しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>先训语模生物医学版本近见医学领域取(RE)之最新。 论药分子结构域,占药于文本语料库 - 药之用也。 立一法,BERTChem-DDI,以效合化学结构(编码)嵌于SMILES中,嵌于成者基于BioBERT嵌之RE。 DDIExtraction 2013 语料库上实验明白,该策将他强基线体系结构增 3.4% 宏观 F1 分数。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>पूर्व-प्रशिक्षित भाषा मॉडल से प्राप्त एम्बेडिंग के पारंपरिक बायोमेडिकल संस्करण ने हाल ही में चिकित्सा डोमेन में संबंध निष्कर्षण (आरई) कार्यों के लिए अत्याधुनिक परिणाम दिखाए हैं। इस पेपर में, हम यह पता लगाते हैं कि डोमेन ज्ञान को कैसे शामिल किया जाए, जो दवाओं की आणविक संरचना के रूप में उपलब्ध है, जो पाठ्य कॉर्पस से ड्रग-ड्रग इंटरैक्शन की भविष्यवाणी करने के लिए है। हम एक विधि, BERTChem-DDI का प्रस्ताव करते हैं, जो दवाओं की समृद्ध रासायनिक संरचना (SMILES में एन्कोडेड) से प्राप्त दवा एम्बेडिंग को कुशलतापूर्वक संयोजित करने के साथ-साथ ऑफ-द-शेल्फ डोमेन-विशिष्ट BioBERT एम्बेडिंग-आधारित आरई आर्किटेक्चर के साथ है। DDIExtraction 2013 कॉर्पस पर किए गए प्रयोगस्पष्ट रूप से इंगित करते हैं कि यह रणनीति 3.4% मैक्रो F1-स्कोर द्वारा अन्य मजबूत बेसलाइन आर्किटेक्चर में सुधार करती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Léirigh leagan bithleighis thraidisiúnta de leabú a fuarthas ó mhúnlaí teanga réamhoilte torthaí úrscothacha le déanaí maidir le tascanna asbhainte caidrimh (RE) sa réimse leighis. Sa pháipéar seo, déanaimid iniúchadh ar conas eolas fearainn, atá ar fáil i bhfoirm struchtúr móilíneach drugaí, a ionchorprú chun Idirghníomhaíocht Drugaí-Drugaí a thuar ó chorpas téacsúil. Molaimid modh, BERTChem-DDI, chun leabú drugaí a fhaightear ó struchtúr saibhir ceimiceach na ndrugaí (atá ionchódaithe i SMILES) a chomhcheangal go héifeachtach in éineacht le hailtireacht RE atá bunaithe ar leabú BioBERT atá bunaithe ar an bhfearann go sonrach agus lasmuigh den tseilf. Léiríonn turgnaimh a rinneadh ar chorpas DDIExtraction 2013 go soiléir go bhfeabhsaítear leis an straitéis seo ailtireachtaí bonnlínte láidre eile faoi 3.4% macra-scór F1.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ტრადიციონალური ბიომედიციური ვერსია, რომელიც წინაშემოწმებული ენის მოდელებიდან მიღებულია, უკვე შემდეგ ჩვენება მედიციონალური დიომინში შესახებ შესახებ შესახებ შესახებ შესახე ამ დოკუმენში, ჩვენ განსხვავებთ როგორ დავყენებთ დემონიური ცოდნა, როგორც მოლეკუალური სტრუქტურაციის ფორმაში, პროგრამის შესახებ ექსპერქტურის ინტერქექციის შესა ჩვენ გვეყველა მეტი, BERTChem-DDI, რომელიც ექსპექტიკური კონფიგურაციას გამოიყენებს, რომელიც ბეჭდვი ჰიმიკური სტრუქტურაციას (SMILES-ში კონფიგურაცია) მიღებულია პროფიქტიკური პროფიქტიკურ DDIExtraction 2013 კოპპუსში გამოყენებული ექსპერიმენტები წარმოდგენია, რომ ეს სტრატიგია სხვა ძალიან ბაზის აქტიქტიქტურება 3,4% მაკრო F1- სოფლიოში.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Az előképzett nyelvi modellekből származó beágyazások hagyományos orvosbiológiai változata a közelmúltban korszerű eredményeket mutatott az orvosi területen végzett kapcsolatextrakciós (RE) feladatok tekintetében. Ebben a tanulmányban azt vizsgáljuk, hogyan lehet beépíteni a gyógyszerek molekuláris struktúrájában elérhető domain ismereteket a gyógyszer-gyógyszer interakció előrejelzéséhez szöveges korpuszból. Javasoljuk a BERTChem-DDI módszert, amely hatékonyan kombinálja a gyógyszerek gazdag kémiai struktúrájából (SMILES-ben kódolt) nyert gyógyszerek beágyazását, valamint az elérhető domain specifikus BioBERT beágyazási alapú RE architektúrát. A DDIExtraction 2013 korpuszon végzett kísérletek egyértelműen azt mutatják, hogy ez a stratégia 3,4%-kal javítja a többi erős alapvonalas architektúrát.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Η παραδοσιακή βιοϊατρική έκδοση των ενσωματώσεων που λαμβάνονται από προ-εκπαιδευμένα γλωσσικά μοντέλα έδειξε πρόσφατα αποτελέσματα τελευταίας τεχνολογίας για εργασίες εξαγωγής σχέσεων στον ιατρικό τομέα. Στην παρούσα εργασία, διερευνούμε πώς να ενσωματώσουμε τη γνώση του τομέα, διαθέσιμη με τη μορφή μοριακής δομής των φαρμάκων, για την πρόβλεψη της αλληλεπίδρασης φαρμάκων-φαρμάκων από το κειμενικό σώμα. Προτείνουμε μια μέθοδο, για να συνδυάσουμε αποτελεσματικά τις ενσωματώσεις φαρμάκων που λαμβάνονται από την πλούσια χημική δομή των φαρμάκων (κωδικοποιημένες σε SMILES) μαζί με την τυποποιημένη αρχιτεκτονική βασισμένη στην ενσωμάτωση τομέα. Τα πειράματα που διεξήχθησαν στο σώμα δείχνουν σαφώς ότι αυτή η στρατηγική βελτιώνει άλλες ισχυρές αρχιτεκτονικές γραμμών βάσης κατά 3,4% μακρο-βαθμολογία F1.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>La versione biomedica tradizionale degli embedding ottenuti da modelli linguistici pre-formati ha recentemente mostrato risultati all'avanguardia per le attività di estrazione delle relazioni (RE) in ambito medico. In questo articolo, esploriamo come incorporare la conoscenza del dominio, disponibile sotto forma di struttura molecolare dei farmaci, per predire l'interazione farmaco-farmaco dal corpus testuale. Proponiamo un metodo, BERTChem-DDI, per combinare in modo efficiente gli embedding di farmaci ottenuti dalla ricca struttura chimica dei farmaci (codificati in SMILES) insieme all'architettura RE basata su embedding BioBERT. Gli esperimenti condotti sul corpus DDIExtraction 2013 indicano chiaramente che questa strategia migliora altre architetture di base forti del 3,4% macro F1-score.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Tradicinė biomedicinė įrangos versija, gauta naudojant iš anksto parengtus kalbų modelius, neseniai parodė naujausius santykių ekstrahavimo (RE) užduočių medicinos srityje rezultatus. Šiame dokumente mes tiriame, kaip įtraukti srities žinias, kurios yra prieinamos kaip molekulinė narkotikų struktūra, narkotikų ir narkotikų sąveikai iš tekstinio korpuso prognozuoti. Siūlome metodą, BERTChem-DDI, veiksmingai derinti narkotikų įterpimą, gautą iš turtingos cheminės narkotikų struktūros (koduota SMILES), kartu su bioBERT įterpimo į rinką srities specifine RE architektūra. Iš DDIExtraction 2013 korpuso atliktų eksperimentų aiškiai matyti, kad šia strategija 3,4 % makroekonominiu F1 rezultatu pagerinamos kitos tvirtos bazinės architektūros.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Алдын- оқылған тіл үлгілерінен алған ендірудің традиционалдық биомедикалық нұсқасы медицина доменінде қатынау (RE) тапсырмаларының күй- жайында көрсетілді. Бұл қағазда, біз домен білімін қалай біріктіру керектігін текстуалды корпустың молекулялдық құрылымының түрінде қолданылатын, наркот-наркот интерактивін бақылау үшін іздейміз. Біз BERTChem-DDI әдісін таңдаймыз, наркотикалық құрылғылардың бағасы химиялық құрылғысынан (SMILES дегенде кодталған) құрылғылардың біріктіру үшін қолданатын наркотикалық құрылғыларды біріктіруге мүмкіндік береді. DDIExtraction 2013 корпус тәжірибесінде істеген тәжірибелер бұл стратегия басқа күшті негізгі сызықтардың архитектураларын 3,4% F1- нұсқасы архитектураларды жақсартады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Традиционалната биомедициска верзија на вградувањата добиени од предобучените јазички модели неодамна покажа најсовремени резултати за задачите за извлекување врски (РЕ) во медицинскиот домен. Во овој весник, истражуваме како да го вклучиме знаењето на доменот, достапно во форма на молекуларна структура на дрогата, за предвидување на интеракција дрога-дрога од текстуалниот корпус. Предложуваме метод, БЕРТКЕМ-ДДИ, за ефикасна комбинација на вградувања на дрога добиени од богатата хемиска структура на дрога (кодирана во СМИЛЕС) заедно со архитектурата на БИОБЕРТ базирана на вградуваое на дрога, специфична за доменот надвор од Експериментите спроведени на корпусот ДДИЕкстракција 2013 јасно покажуваат дека оваа стратегија ги подобрува другите силни основни архитектури за 3,4 отсто од макро-оценката Ф1.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Versi biomedikal tradisional penyembedding yang diperoleh dari model bahasa terlatih telah baru-baru ini menunjukkan keputusan state-of-the-art untuk tugas ekstraksi hubungan (RE) dalam domain perubatan. Dalam kertas ini, kami mengeksplorasi bagaimana untuk memasukkan pengetahuan domain, tersedia dalam bentuk struktur molekul dadah, untuk meramalkan interaksi dadah-dadah dari korpus teks. Kami mengusulkan kaedah, BERTChem-DDI, untuk menggabungkan dengan efektif penyembedding dadah yang diperoleh dari struktur kimia kaya dadah (dikodifikasikan dalam SMILES) bersama dengan arkitektur RE berbasis BioBERT yang spesifik domain off-the-shelf. Eksperimen yang dilakukan pada korpus DDIExtraction 2013 jelas menunjukkan bahawa strategi ini memperbaiki arkitektur garis dasar kuat lain dengan 3.4% makro-skor F1.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>പഠിപ്പിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഭാഷ മോഡലുകളില്‍ നിന്നും ലഭിക്കുന്ന പാഠമായ ജീവിയോമിക്കല്‍ പതിപ്പുകള്‍ മുമ്പ് പരിശീലന മാതൃകങ്ങളില്‍ നിന്നും കിട്ടിയ ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ കണ്ടെത്തുന്നത് എങ്ങനെയാണ് ഡൊമെയിനിലെ അറിവ് ഉള്‍പ്പെടുത്തേണ്ടതെന്ന്, മയക്കുമരുന്നുകളുടെ രൂപത്തില്‍ ലഭ്യമാക്കുന്നത്,  ബെര്‍ട്ടിചെമ്-ഡിഡിഐ നമ്മള്‍ ഒരു രീതിയില്‍ നിര്‍ദ്ദേശിക്കുന്നു, സമ്പന്നതയുള്ള മരുന്നുകൊണ്ടുള്ള അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ നിന്നും സാധാരണമായി കൂട്ടിക്കൊണ്ടുവരാന്‍ മരുന്നുകളുടെ സ DDIExtraction 2013 കോര്‍പ്പുസില്‍ നടത്തിയ പരീക്ഷണങ്ങള്‍ വ്യക്തമായി തെളിയിക്കുന്നു ഈ strategy മറ്റു ശക്തിയുള്ള ബെസ്റ്റേലൈന്‍ ആര്‍ക്കിട്ടുകള്‍ മുന്‍ക</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Эхлээд сургалтын хэл загвараас авсан уламжлалтын биологийн эмнэлгийн хувилбар нь саяхан эмнэлгийн хэл загвараас хамтын үр дүнг харуулсан. Энэ цаасан дээр бид нарийн молекулын бүтээгдэхүүний хувьд хэрхэн хамтын мэдлэг бүрдүүлэхийг судалж байна. Мэдээж нарийн нарийн харилцааны харилцааныг textual corpus-аас таамаглах боломжтой. Бид, BERTChem-DDI-ын арга загвар, эмийн баян химийн бүтээгдэхүүнээс (SMILES-д кодлогдсон) бүтээгдэхүүнтэй хамтдаа эмийн бүтээгдэхүүнийг үр дүнтэй нэгтгэх гэсэн санал өгдөг. DDIExtraction 2013 корпус дахь туршилтын туршилт нь энэ стратеги нь бусад хүчтэй суурь шугамын архитектуруудыг 3.4% F1-н хэмжээнд сайжруулдаг гэдгийг тодорхой харуулж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mt>Verżjoni bijomedika tradizzjonali ta’ inkorporazzjonijiet miksuba minn mudelli lingwistiċi mħarrġa minn qabel dan l-aħħar uriet riżultati l-aktar avvanzati għall-kompiti ta’ estrazzjoni ta’ relazzjonijiet (RE) fil-qasam mediku. F’dan id-dokument, nistudjaw kif inkorporaw l-għarfien tad-dominju, disponibbli fil-forma ta’ struttura molekulari tad-drogi, għat-tbassir tal-Interazzjoni bejn id-Drogi u d-Drogi minn korpus testwali. We propose a method, BERTChem-DDI, to efficiently combine drug embeddings obtained from the rich chemical structure of drugs (encoded in SMILES) along with off-the-shelf domain-specific BioBERT embedding-based RE architecture.  L-esperimenti mwettqa fuq id-DDIExtraction 2013 corpus jindikaw b’mod ċar li din l-istrateġija ttejjeb arkitetturi oħra b’linji bażi b’3.4% makro-punteġġ F1.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ro>Versiunea biomedicală tradițională a încorporărilor obținute din modele lingvistice pre-instruite a arătat recent rezultate de ultimă oră pentru sarcinile de extragere a relațiilor (RE) în domeniul medical. În această lucrare, explorăm cum să încorporăm cunoștințele de domeniu, disponibile sub forma structurii moleculare a medicamentelor, pentru predicția interacțiunii medicament-medicament din corpul textual. Propunem o metodă, BERTChem-DDI, pentru a combina eficient încorporarea medicamentelor obținute din structura chimică bogată a medicamentelor (codificată în SMILES) împreună cu arhitectura RE bazată pe încorporarea domeniului specific BioBERT. Experimentele efectuate pe corpul DDIExtraction 2013 indică clar faptul că această strategie îmbunătățește alte arhitecturi puternice de bază cu 3,4% scor macro F1.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>Tradycyjna biomedyczna wersja osadzeń uzyskana na podstawie wstępnie przeszkolonych modeli językowych pokazała ostatnio najnowocześniejsze wyniki dla zadań ekstrakcji relacji (RE) w dziedzinie medycznej. W artykule badamy, jak włączyć wiedzę domenową dostępną w postaci struktury molekularnej leków do przewidywania interakcji lekowo-lekowych z korpusu tekstowego. Proponujemy metodę BERTChem-DDI, aby skutecznie łączyć osadzenia leków uzyskane z bogatej struktury chemicznej leków (kodowane w SMILES) z gotową architekturą RE opartą na osadzeniu BioBERT. Eksperymenty przeprowadzone na korpusie DDIExtraction 2013 wyraźnie wskazują, że strategia ta poprawia inne silne architektury bazowe o 3,4% makro F1-score.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Tradisjonale biomedisinsk versjon av innbyggingar som er fått frå føretrainerte språk-modeller har nyleg vist tilstand-of-the-art-resultat for relasjonspakking (RE) oppgåver i medisinsk domenet. I denne papiret utforskar vi korleis domenekunnskap skal inkluderast, tilgjengeleg i form av molekylt struktur av narkotika, for å foregå narkotika-interaksjon frå tekstkorpus. Vi foreslår ein metode, BERTChem-DDI, for å effektivt kombinere innbygging av narkotika som er henta frå den rike kjemiske strukturen av narkotika (koda i SMILES) saman med off the-shelf-domenespesifikke bioBERT-basert RE-arkitektur. Eksperiment gjennomført på DDIExtraction 2013 corpus tyder klart på at denne strategien forbedrar andre sterke baselinjer med 3,4% makro F1- poeng.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Tradicionalna biomedicinska verzija uključenih iz predobučenih jezičkih modela nedavno su pokazala rezultate stanja umjetnosti za izvlačenje odnosa (RE) zadataka u medicinskoj domenu. U ovom papiru istražujemo kako da uključimo znanje domena, dostupno u obliku molekularne strukture droge, za predviđanje interakcije droge iz tekstualnog korpusa. Predlažemo metodu, BERTChem-DDI, da efikasno kombinujemo integracije droge koje su dobile od bogate kemijske strukture droge (kodirane u SMILES) zajedno sa arhitekturom bioBERT-a na osnovu bioBERT-a, specifičnom domenu. Eksperimenti provedeni na korpusu DDIExtraction 2013 jasno ukazuju na to da ova strategija poboljšava druge jake osnovne arhitekture za 3,4% makro F1 rezultata.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>Name මේ පත්තරේ අපි පරීක්ෂණය කරනවා කොහොමද දේමින් දන්නවත් සම්බන්ධ කරන්නේ, විද්‍යාවයේ මනුෂ්‍ය සංවිධානයෙන් පුළුවන් විද්‍ අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක්, BERTChem-DDI, විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් සම්බන්ධ විද්‍යාවක් සම්බන්ධ විද්‍යාවක් සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න පුළුවන් විශේෂයෙන් ව DDIExtraction 2013 කොර්පුස් වල පරීක්ෂණාවල් පැහැදිලිවම ප්‍රකාශයෙන් පෙන්වන්නේ මේ සංයෝජනය විශ්වාස කරනවා අනිත් ශක්තිමත් ප</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Dalka caadiga ah ee warqadaha dhakhaatiirta ah ee noocyada afka hore laga helay waxay ugu dhowaad muuqatay arimaha la soo saaro (RE) shaqooyinka caafimaadka. Warqaddan waxaynu ka baaraannaa sida loo soo koobi karo aqoonta deegaanka, kaas oo loo heli karo qaabka dhakhaatiirta daawooyinka, si loo sii sheegayo Interugga Drugga ee dhakhtarka. Waxaynu soo jeedaynaa qaab, BERTChem-DDI, si fiican loogu soo wada ururiyo dawooyinka laga helay dhismaha hodantinimada kjemikamka ee dawooyinka (ku qoran SMILES) iyo qori-shelf domain-specific BioBERT oo ku saleysan RE-based architecture. Imtixaanka lagu sameeyay DDIExtraction 2013 corpus bayaan u muuqata in strategiyadu uu kordhiyo dhismaha kale oo xoogga leh ee qoriga hoose lagu sameeyo 3.4% macro F1 score.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Traditionell biomedicinsk version av inbäddningar som erhållits från färdigutbildade språkmodeller har nyligen visat på state-of-the-art resultat för relationsextraktion (RE) uppgifter inom det medicinska området. I denna uppsats undersöker vi hur man kan införliva domänkunskap, tillgänglig i form av molekylär struktur av läkemedel, för att förutsäga Drug-Drug Interaction från textkorpus. Vi föreslår en metod, BERTChem-DDI, för att effektivt kombinera läkemedelsinbäddningar som erhållits från den rika kemiska strukturen hos läkemedel (kodade i SMILES) tillsammans med domänspecifik BioBERT inbäddningsbaserad RE-arkitektur. Experiment utförda på DDIExtraction 2013 corpus tyder tydligt på att denna strategi förbättrar andra starka baslinjearkitekturer med 3,4% makro F1-poäng.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>முன் பயிற்சிக்கப்பட்ட மொழி மாதிரிகளிலிருந்து பெற்ற பாரம்பரிய ஜியோமரிக்க வெளியீடுகளின் பதிப்பு இந்த காகிதத்தில், நாம் எவ்வாறு களம் அறிவை சேர்க்க வேண்டும் என்று கண்டறிக்கிறோம், மருந்துகள் வடிவத்தில் கிடைக்கும் வடிவமைப்பில், மருந்து இட We propose a method, BERTChem-DDI, to efficiently combine drug embeddings obtained from the rich chemical structure of drugs (encoded in SMILES) along with off-the-shelf domain-specific BioBERT embedding-based RE architecture.  DDIExtraction 2013 குறும்பத்தில் செயல்படுத்தப்பட்ட சோதனைகள் தெளிவாக இந்த திட்டம் 3. 4% மேக்ரோ F1- score மூலம் மேம்படுத்துகிறது என்பதை குறிக்கிறது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>پہلے تدریس کی زبان مدلکوں سے حاصل ہونے والی ایمبڈینگ کی پیدائمی بیوڈینگ کی نسخہ اٹھانے کے لئے اٹھانے کے (RE) کاموں کے لئے اٹھانے کی حالت-of-the-art نتائج دکھائے گئے ہیں۔ اس کاغذ میں ہم دیکھتے ہیں کہ ڈومین علم کو کس طرح شامل کرنا ہے، مواد کی مولکولی ساختاری کے شکل میں موجود ہے، ڈروگ-ڈروگ اٹراکسٹیکशन کی پیش بینی کے لئے تفصیل کورپوس سے۔ ہم ایک طریقہ، BERTChem-DDI کی پیشنهاد کرتے ہیں، مواد کے مطابق مخلوقات کے مطابق مخلوقات کے مطابق مخلوقات کی رومیایی ساختار سے (SMILES میں کدھی گیا) حاصل کرنے کے لئے مخلوقات کے مطابق مخلوقات کو ترکیب کرنے کے لئے۔ DDIExtraction 2013 کورپوس کی تجربیات صریح دکھاتی ہے کہ یہ استراتژی دوسری قوی بنسس لین معماری 3.4% مکرو F1-اسکور سے بہتر ہوتی ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Bu qogʻozda, biz narsalarning molekyl tuzuvlari shaklida qo'yishni qanday o'rganishni o'rganamiz, va texnologiya qo'llanmalarni kutib chiqarish uchun. Biz BERTChem-DDI, narsalarning hosil kemikali tuzuvlaridan (SMILES'da kodlash) qo'shilgan narsalarni ishlab chiqarish usuli bilan boshlanamiz. Name</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Truyền sinh sản của sự nhúng tay từ những mẫu ngôn ngữ được đào tạo trước đây đã cho thấy kết quả hiện đại nhất trong lĩnh vực y học về việc trích dẫn các mối quan hệ (R). Trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi tìm hiểu làm thế nào để kết hợp kiến thức miền, có thể cung cấp trong cấu trúc phân tử của thuốc, để dự đoán giao thức ma túy từ tập thể hình. Chúng tôi đề xuất một phương pháp, BERTChem-DDI, để kết hợp các loại ma túy được lấy từ cấu trúc hóa chất giàu có của ma túy (mã hóa trong SMILS) cùng với các công trình nền kinh ngạc đặc trưng của BioBERT tái ghép lại dựa trên kiến trúc R. Các thí nghiệm về tập đoàn DDIExtvợ được thực thể rõ ràng cho thấy rằng chiến lược này cải thiện các cấu trúc cơ bản vững chắc khác bằng 3.4)</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>Tradicionalna biomedicinska verzija uključenih iz predobučenih jezičkih modela nedavno je pokazala rezultate stanja umjetnosti za zadatke izvlačenja odnosa (RE) u medicinskoj domenu. U ovom papiru istražujemo kako uključiti znanje domena, dostupno u obliku molekularne strukture droge, za predviđanje interakcije droge i droge iz tekstualnog korpusa. Predlažemo metodu, BERTChem-DDI, kako bi učinkovito kombinirali ugrađenje lijekova koji su dobili od bogate kemijske strukture lijekova (kodirane u SMILES) zajedno s arhitekturom na temelju bioBERT-a na temelju izvan granice. Iskusi provedeni na korpusu DDIExtraction 2013 jasno ukazuju na to da ta strategija poboljšava druge jake osnovne arhitekture za 3,4% makro F1 rezultata.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Традиционната биомедицинска версия на вграждания, получена от предварително обучени езикови модели, наскоро показа най-съвременни резултати за задачи за извличане на релации (РЕ) в областта на медицината. В тази статия изследваме как да включим домейна знания, налични под формата на молекулярна структура на лекарствата, за прогнозиране на взаимодействието лекарство-лекарство от текстов корпус. Предлагаме метод за ефективно комбиниране на вграждането на наркотици, получени от богатата химична структура на лекарствата (кодирани в SMILES), заедно с специфичната за домейна архитектура на базата на вграждането биоBERT архитектура. Експериментите, проведени върху корпуса на DDIExtraction 2013 ясно показват, че тази стратегия подобрява други силни базови архитектури с 3,4% макрос F1-резултат.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Traditionele biomedische versies van embeddings verkregen uit voorgetrainde taalmodellen hebben recentelijk state-of-the-art resultaten getoond voor relationextractie (RE) taken in het medische domein. In dit artikel onderzoeken we hoe domeinkennis, beschikbaar in de vorm van moleculaire structuur van geneesmiddelen, kan worden geïntegreerd voor het voorspellen van Drug-Drug Interactie vanuit tekstueel corpus. We stellen een methode voor, BERTChem-DDI, om medicijnembeddingen verkregen uit de rijke chemische structuur van geneesmiddelen (gecodeerd in SMILES) efficiënt te combineren met standaard domeinspecifieke BioBERT embedding-based RE architectuur. Experimenten uitgevoerd op het DDIExtraction 2013 corpus geven duidelijk aan dat deze strategie andere sterke baselinearchitecturen verbetert met 3,4% macro F1-score.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Traditionel biomedicinsk version af embeddings opnået fra præuddannede sprogmodeller har for nylig vist state-of-the-art resultater for relationsudvinding (RE) opgaver på det medicinske område. I denne artikel undersøger vi, hvordan man indarbejder domæne viden, der er tilgængelig i form af molekylær struktur af lægemidler, til at forudsige Drug-Drug Interaction fra tekstkorpus. Vi foreslår en metode, BERTChem-DDI, til effektivt at kombinere lægemiddelindlejringer opnået fra den rige kemiske struktur af lægemidler (kodet i SMILES) sammen med off-the-shelf domænespecifikke BioBERT indlejringsbaseret RE arkitektur. Eksperimenter udført på DDIExtraction 2013 corpus tyder klart på, at denne strategi forbedrer andre stærke basisarkitekturer med 3,4% makro F1-score.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Traditionelle biomedizinische Einbettungen, die aus vortrainierten Sprachmodellen gewonnen wurden, haben kürzlich State-of-the-Art Ergebnisse für Relation Extraction (RE) Aufgaben im medizinischen Bereich gezeigt. In diesem Beitrag untersuchen wir, wie Domänenwissen, das in Form der molekularen Struktur von Medikamenten verfügbar ist, zur Vorhersage von Drug-Drug-Interaktionen aus textuellem Korpus einfließen kann. Wir schlagen eine Methode vor, BERTChem-DDI, um Wirkstoffeinbettungen, die aus der reichen chemischen Struktur von Medikamenten (kodiert in SMILES) gewonnen werden, effizient mit einer domänenspezifischen BioBERT-Einbettungsarchitektur zu kombinieren. Experimente am Korpus DDIExtraction 2013 zeigen deutlich, dass diese Strategie andere starke Baselinearchitekturen um 3,4% Makro F1-Score verbessert.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>미리 훈련된 언어 모델에서 얻은 전통 생물의학 버전의 삽입은 최근 의학 분야의 관계추출(RE) 임무에서 가장 선진적인 결과를 보였다.본고에서 우리는 약물 분자 구조로 제공된 분야 지식을 어떻게 결합시켜 텍스트 자료 라이브러리에서 약물의 상호작용을 예측하는지를 연구했다.약물이 풍부한 화학구조(스마일코드)에서 얻은 약물 파묻기와 기존의 특정 분야 기반 바이오비트의 파묻기 재건구조를 효과적으로 결합하는 BERTChem DDI 방법을 제시했다.DDI 2013 어료 라이브러리에서 진행된 실험은 이 전략이 다른 강기선 체계 구조의宏F1 점수를 3.4% 높였다는 것을 분명히 나타냈다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_id>Versi biomedis tradisional dari embedding yang diperoleh dari model bahasa yang terlatih baru-baru ini menunjukkan hasil state-of-the-art untuk tugas ekstraksi hubungan (RE) di daerah medis. Dalam kertas ini, kami mengeksplorasi bagaimana untuk memasukkan pengetahuan domain, tersedia dalam bentuk struktur molekuler obat, untuk memprediksi interaksi obat-obat dari tubuh teks. Kami mengusulkan metode, BERTChem-DDI, untuk menggabungkan efisien penyembedding narkoba yang diperoleh dari struktur kimia kaya narkoba (terkodifikasi dalam SMILES) bersama dengan arsitektur RE berbasis BioBERT domain-spesifik off-the-shelf. Eksperimen yang dilakukan pada korpus DDIExtraction 2013 jelas menunjukkan bahwa strategi ini memperbaiki arsitektur garis dasar yang kuat lainnya dengan 3,4% makro-skor F1.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>نسخه‌ی زیست‌پزشکی سنتی از مطالعه‌های پیش آموزش یافته از مدل‌های زبانی اخیرا نتیجه‌های وضعیت-هنری برای اخراج (RE) وضعیت‌های ارتباطی در دامنۀ پزشکی نشان داده‌اند. در این کاغذ، ما کشف می‌کنیم که چگونه علم دامنی را جمع کنیم، که در شکل ساختار مولکولی مولکولی مواد است، برای پیش‌بینی از تفاوت مواد مواد مخدر و مواد مخدر از جسد متن است. ما یک روش، BERTChem-DDI را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم تا موثرت‌آفرینش داروها را از ساختار شیمیایی ثروتمند داروها (که در SMILES kodیده شده) همراه با ساختار آفرینش آفرینش‌های مخصوص بیوBERT که بر پایه‌ی ساختار آفرینش‌های آفرینش‌های بیوBERT متصل شده، به طور مو تجربه‌های DDIExtraction Corpus ۲۰۰۳ روشن نشان می‌دهد که این استراتژی باقی‌مانده‌های پایه‌خط‌های قوی با نمونه‌های ۳.۴ درصد Makro F1 بهتر می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Edilmiş dil nusgalaryndan alınan däpli biomedical versiýasy medical domynda näme üçin state-of-the-art netijesi görkezildi. Bu kağıtda, sanat korpusundan uyuşturucu-uyuşturucu etkinleşimi şeklinde nähili domena bilgileri içereni keşfetýäris. BERTChem DDIExtraction 2013-nji korpusyň bardygyny öränler bu stratejiýanyň beýleki güýçli baz hatlary arhitekturmalaryny 3.4% makro F1-score bilen gowurandyrýandygyny belli edip bilýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Toleo la kitamaduni la kitabibu la vifaa vinavyopatikana kutoka kwenye mitindo ya lugha zilizofunzwa kabla imeonyesha matokeo ya sanaa ya utekelezaji wa mazingira (RE) katika maeneo ya matibabu. Katika karatasi hii, tunachunguza jinsi ya kuingiza maarifa ya ndani, inayopatikana katika muundo wa molekylia wa dawa, kwa kutabiri namna ya kuingiza huduma ya dawa za madawa kutoka kwenye makampuni ya msingi. Tunazipendekeza njia, BERTChem-DDI, kuunganisha vifaa vya dawa vilivyopatikana kwa ufanisi kutoka kwenye muundo tajiri wa kemikali wa madawa (iliyoandikwa kwa SMILES) pamoja na ujenzi maalum wa BioBERT unaoandaliwa na viwanda vya RE. Experiments conducted on the DDIExtraction 2013 corpus clearly indicate that this strategy improves other strong baselines architectures by 3.4% macro F1-score.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Tradisjoneel biomediese weergawe van inbêdings wat vanaf voorafgevorderde taal modele ontvang het onlangs vertoon state-of-the-art resultate vir verwanting uitpakking (RE) opdragte in die mediese domein. In hierdie papier, ondersoek ons hoe om domein kennis te inkorporeer, beskikbaar in die vorm van molekuleer struktuur van drogs, vir voorskou van Drug-Drug Interaksie van tekstuurlike korpus. Ons voorstel 'n metode, BERTChem-DDI, om effektief narkotika inbettings te kombinerer wat van die ryk kemikatiese struktuur van narkotike ontvang word (in SMILES kodeerd) saam met af-die-shelf domein-spesifieke BioBERT-inbetering-gebaseerde RE-arkitektuur te kombinerer. Experiments conducted on the DDIExtraction 2013 corpus clearly indicate that this strategy improves other strong baseline architectures by 3.4% macro F1-score.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>የባሕላዊው የባሕላዊ መሠረት ድምፅ ከቀድሞ ተማሪ ቋንቋ ሞዴል የተገኘውን የድረአምባዊ የባሕላዊ ድምፅ በጥምቀት አካባቢ (RE) ስራዎችን ለመውጣት አግኝቷል፡፡ በዚህ ፕሮግራም፣ የዶሜን እውቀት እንዴት እንደሚያሳስብ እናደርጋለን፡፡ BERTChem-DDI (BERTChem-DDI) የሀብታም የኪሞክሪካ አካውንት (SMILES) በተለየ የዶሜይን ዶሜይን-ፍጥረት BioBERT በተመሳሳይ RE መሠረት እናሳስባታለን፡፡ በDDIExtraction 2013 ካርፓስ ላይ የተደረገውን ፈተና ይህ strategy ሌሎችን ብርቱ መሠረት መሠረቶች በ3.4 በመቶ ማክሮው F1-score እንዲያሳድግ ይገልጣል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>∆Źvv…ôlc…ô t…ôhsil edilmiŇü dil modellerind…ôn alńĪnan n…ôtic…ô biomedical versiyonu t…ôhsil edil…ôn m…ôlumatlarńĪn m…ôlumatlarńĪnńĪn …ôlaq…ôsi (RE) m…ôlumatlarńĪna son zamanlarda g√∂st…ôrmiŇüdir. Bu kańüńĪzda, m…ôktub korpusundan uyuŇüturucu-uyuŇüturucu interaksiyasńĪnńĪ √∂yr…ônm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn, m…ôlumatlarńĪn m…ôlumatlarńĪnńĪ nec…ô inkiŇüaf ed…ôc…ôyini keŇüfetmiŇüik. Bel…ôlikl…ô, BERTChem-DDI metodlarńĪnńĪ t…ôklif edirik ki, UyuŇüturuqlarńĪn z…ôngin kimyasal quruluŇüundan (SMILES-d…ô kodlanmńĪŇü) √ľr…ôkl…ôrl…ô birl…ôŇüdirilmiŇü uyuŇüturucu in ŇüallarńĪnńĪ birl…ôŇüdirsin. DDIExtraction 2013 korpusu t…ôcr√ľb…ôl…ôrind…ô etdiyi t…ôcr√ľb…ôl…ôr bu strateji baŇüqa q√ľvv…ôtli s…ôhif…ôl…ôrin arhitektarńĪnńĪ 3,4% makro F1-score il…ô yaxŇüńĪlaŇüdńĪrńĪr.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>প্রথম প্রশিক্ষিত ভাষা মডেল থেকে পাওয়া প্রচলিত বায়োমেডিকেল সংস্করণ সম্প্রতি চিকিৎসার ডোমেইনে সম্পর্ক বের করার (RE) কাজের জন্য প্রতিষ্ঠানের এই কাগজটিতে আমরা খুঁজে বের করি কিভাবে ডোমেইনের জ্ঞান যুক্ত করতে পারি, যা মাদকের কাঠামোর আকারে পাওয়া যায়, যা কিভাবে পাওয়া যায়, টেক্সটুয়াল কো আমরা একটি পদ্ধতি প্রস্তাব করছি, বের্টিচেম-ডিডিআই, যাতে সমৃদ্ধ রাসায়নিক কাঠামো থেকে পেয়েছে (এসমিলিএস-এ এনকোড করা হয়েছে) যার সাথে শেল্ফ ডোমেইন-নির্দিষ্ট বিয়োবের্ট বিভিন্ন ভি ডিডিআইএক্সট্র্যাক্ট্র্যাকশন ২০১৩ কোর্পাসে অনুষ্ঠিত পরীক্ষার পরীক্ষা পরিষ্কার প্রমাণ করেছে যে এই কৌশল ৩. ৪% ম্যাক্রো এফ১ স্কো</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Tradicionalna biomedicinska verzija uključenih iz predobučenih jezičkih modela nedavno su pokazala rezultate stanja umjetnosti za izvlačenje odnosa (RE) zadataka u medicinskoj domenu. U ovom papiru istražujemo kako uključiti znanje domena, dostupno u obliku molekularne strukture droge, za predviđanje interakcije droge iz tekstualnog korpusa. Predlažemo metodu, BERTChem-DDI, kako bi efikasno kombinirali ugrađenje droge iz bogate kemijske strukture droge (kodirane u SMILES) zajedno s arhitekturom na osnovu bioBERT-a na osnovu bioBERT-a. Eksperimenti provedeni na korpusu DDIExtraction 2013 jasno ukazuju na to da ova strategija poboljšava druge jake osnovne arhitekture za 3,4% makro F1 rezultata.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Tradiční biomedicínská verze vložení získaná z předškolených jazykových modelů v poslední době ukázala nejmodernější výsledky pro úlohy extrakce vztahů (RE) v lékařské oblasti. V tomto článku zkoumáme, jak začlenit doménové znalosti dostupné ve formě molekulární struktury léčiv pro predikci interakce léčiv-léčiv z textového korpusu. Navrhujeme metodu BERTChem-DDI, která efektivně kombinuje vložení léků získané z bohaté chemické struktury léků (kódované v SMILES) s standardní doménově specifickou architekturou BioBERT založenou na vložení RE. Experimenty provedené na korpusu DDIExtraction 2013 jasně ukazují, že tato strategie zlepšuje ostatní silné architektury základních linek o 3,4% makro F1 skóre.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_sq>Versioni tradicional biomedikal i përfshirjeve të përfshira nga modelet e gjuhës së paratrajnuar kanë treguar kohët e fundit rezultate më të larta për detyrat e nxjerrjes së marrëdhënieve (RE) në fushën mjekësore. Në këtë letër, ne eksplorojmë si të përfshijmë njohuritë e domenit, të disponueshme në form ën e strukturës molekulare të drogës, për parashikimin e ndërveprimit të drogës-drogës nga korpusi tekstual. Ne propozojmë një metodë, BERTChem-DDI, për të kombinuar me efektshmëri përfshirjet e drogës të përfshira nga struktura kimike e pasur e drogave (të koduar në SMILES) së bashku me arkitekturën e BE-së bazuar në përfshirjen e domenit të jashtëm shelf BioBERT. Experiments conducted on the DDIExtraction 2013 corpus clearly indicate that this strategy improves other strong baselines architectures by 3.4% macro F1-score.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_et>Traditsioonilised biomeditsiinilised versioonid eelkoolitud keelemudelitest on hiljuti näidanud kaasaegseid tulemusi seoste ekstraheerimise (RE) ülesannete jaoks meditsiini valdkonnas. Käesolevas töös uurime, kuidas kasutada ravimite molekulaarse struktuuri kujul kättesaadavaid domeeniteadmisi ravimite ja ravimite koostoime prognoosimiseks tekstikorpusest. Pakume välja meetodi, BERTChem-DDI, et tõhusalt kombineerida ravimite rikkalikust keemilisest struktuurist saadud ravimite manustamist (kodeeritud SMILES-is) koos bioBERT manustamispõhise taastuvenergia arhitektuuriga. DDIExtraction 2013 korpusega läbi viidud katsed näitavad selgelt, et see strateegia parandab muid tugevaid baasarhitektuure 3,4% võrra F1 makroskoori võrra.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esikoulutetuista kielimalleista saadut perinteiset biol瓣瓣ketieteelliset versiot ovat viime aikoina osoittaneet viimeisimpi瓣 tuloksia relaatioekstraktioteht瓣viss瓣 l瓣瓣ketieteen alalla. T瓣ss瓣 artikkelissa selvit瓣mme, miten l瓣瓣keaineiden molekyylirakenteen muodossa saatavaa verkkotietoa voidaan hy繹dynt瓣瓣 l瓣瓣keaineiden yhteisvaikutuksen ennustamiseen tekstikorpusesta. Ehdotamme BERTChem-DDI-menetelm瓣瓣, jolla yhdistet瓣瓣n tehokkaasti l瓣瓣kkeiden rikkaasta kemiallisesta rakenteesta saadut upotukset (SMILES-koodattu) ja off-the-shelf-domain-spesifinen BioBERT upotuspohjainen RE-arkkitehtuuri. DDIExtraction 2013 -korpusella tehdyt kokeet osoittavat selv瓣sti, ett瓣 t瓣m瓣 strategia parantaa muita vahvoja perusrakenteita 3,4% F1-makropisteell瓣.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_hy>Բիոբժշկական ներդրումների ավանդական բիոբժշկական տարբերակը, որը ստացվել է նախապատրաստված լեզվի մոդելներից, վերջերս ցույց են տվել վերջին արդյունքները բժշկական ոլորտում հարաբերությունների վերացման (ՌԵ) խնդիրների համար: Այս թղթի մեջ մենք ուսումնասիրում ենք, թե ինչպես ներառել տիեզերական գիտելիքներ, որոնք հասանելի են թմրադեղերի մոլեկուլային կառուցվածքի ձևով, թմրադեղերի և թմրադեղերի ինտերակցիայի կանխատեսման համար տեքստալ մարմնից: Մենք առաջարկում ենք մի մեթոդ, Բերթքիմ-ԴԻ, որպեսզի արդյունավետ համադրենք դեղամիջոցների ներդրումները, որոնք ստացվում են դեղամիջոցների հարուստ քիմիական կառուցվածքից (կոդավորված SMILes-ում) միասին բիոբերթ ներդրման կոնկրետ բիոբերթ ոլորտի ներդրման կոն 2013 թվականի DDiextraction կորպուսի վրա կատարված փորձարկումները ակնհայտորեն ցույց են տալիս, որ այս ռազմավարությունը բարելավում է այլ ուժեղ հիմնական ճարտարապետությունները 3.4 տոկոսով մակրո F1-ի գնահատականով:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ca>La versió biomèdica tradicional d'incorporacions obtenides a partir de models de llenguatge pré-entrenats ha mostrat recentment resultats d'última generació per a les tasques d'extracció de relacions (RE) en el domini mèdic. En aquest paper, explorem com incorporar coneixements de domini, disponibles en forma d'estructura molecular de medicaments, per predir l'interacció entre medicaments del cos textual. Proposem un mètode, BERTChem-DDI, per combinar eficientment les incorporacions de medicaments obtenides de l'estructura química rica de medicaments (codificada en SMILES) juntament amb l'arquitectura RE basada en incorporació bioBERT específica en el domini off-shelf. Experiments conducted on the DDIExtraction 2013 corpus clearly indicate that this strategy improves other strong baselines architectures by 3.4% macro F1-score.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_jv>Name In this paper, we find out about the design of domain knowingthat, available in the format of individual structural of narkoties, for preview Drog-Drog interaction from textual Body. We proposal a method, BERT Kemik-DDN, to effectly combine narkotic embedding from the wealth Chinese structural of narkoties (kodkoded in SMIBESS) together with off-the-shell domain-special BIBERT embedding-supported RE architecture. The software is not installable and software can be accessable. Gebudhakan langkung barang nggawe DDEextration 2013 babagan kelas ngomongke ngerasahan punika ingkang dianggawe barang nggawe dolanan sing wis ambang barang 3.4% macro F1-punika.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Tradicionalna biomedicinska različica vdelav, pridobljenih iz predhodno usposobljenih jezikovnih modelov, je nedavno pokazala najsodobnejše rezultate za naloge ekstrakcije relacij (RE) na medicinskem področju. V prispevku raziskujemo, kako vključiti domensko znanje, ki je na voljo v obliki molekularne strukture zdravil, za napovedovanje interakcije med zdravili iz besedilnega korpusa. Predlagamo metodo BERTChem-DDI za učinkovito kombiniranje vdelanih zdravil, pridobljenih iz bogate kemijske strukture zdravil (kodiranih v SMILES), skupaj z bioBERT vdelano arhitekturo, ki temelji na vdelanju, specifično za domeno. Eksperimenti, opravljeni na korpusu DDIExtraction 2013, jasno kažejo, da ta strategija izboljšuje druge močne osnovne arhitekture za 3,4% makro ocene F1.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>@ info: status Ga wannan takardan, Munã yin amfani da yadda za mu shigar da ilmi a cikin wurãre, wanda ke da shi a cikin tsarin kullum na madawara, kuma don ka yi bayani ga aikin Nafi-Nafi daga nau'in rubutu. Tuna buɗar da wata hanyor, BERTchem-DDi, ta koma da amfani da dawwamamman da aka sãmu daga rikin matsayin chemical na narkoki (kodi cikin SMILES) sami da bayan-shelf-Domen-Specific BioBERT embedding-based re-architecture. Tajarakin da aka aikata a kan DDiExtration 2013, na bayyana bayan bayani, wannan zanyarci yana ƙara wasu matsakan masu ƙarfi da 3.4% macro F1-score.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>גרסה ביו-רפואית מסורתית של תוכניות שנקבלו מדוגמנים לשפה מאומנים מראש הראה לאחרונה תוצאות חדשות למשימות חיפוש יחסים (RE) בתחום הרפואי. בעיתון הזה, אנו חוקרים כיצד להכיל ידע שטח, זמין בצורה של מבנה מולקולרי של תרופות, לחזות אינטראקציה סמים-סמים מהקורפוס טקסטולי. אנו מציעים שיטה, BERTChem-DDI, שילוב יעיל תוספות סמים שנוצאות מהמבנה הכימי העשיר של סמים (מוצפנים בסמיילס) יחד עם ארכיטקטורה המבוססת על תוספת ביוברט מחוץ למדף. ניסויים על הקורפוס של DDIExtraction 2013 מצביעים בבירור כי אסטרטגיה זו משפר ארכיטקטורות בסיסיות חזקות אחרות על ידי 3.4% נקודת מקרו F1.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>Traditional biomedical version of embeddings obtained from pre-trained language models have recently shown state-of-the-art results for relation extraction (RE) tasks in the medical domain. འོག་གི་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོས་ཁྱད་པར་དུ་གླེང་སྒྲའི་གནས་ཚུལ་འདྲ་ཞིག་དང་། We propose a method, BERTChem-DDI, to efficiently combine drug embeddings obtained from the rich chemical structure of drugs (encoded in SMILES) along with off-the-shelf domain-specific BioBERT embedding-based RE architecture. Experiments conducted on the DDIExtraction 2013 corpus clearly indicate that this strategy improves other strong baselines architectures by 3.4% macro F1-score.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>