<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.msr">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Multilingual Surface Realisation</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Anya</first><last>Belz</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Bernd</first><last>Bohnet</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Thiago Castro</first><last>Ferreira</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yvette</first><last>Graham</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Simon</first><last>Mille</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Leo</first><last>Wanner</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="2a8fdccc">2020.msr-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>msr-2020-multilingual</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>The Third Multilingual Surface Realisation Shared Task (SR’20): Overview and Evaluation Results<fixed-case>SR</fixed-case>’20): Overview and Evaluation Results</title>
      <author><first>Simon</first><last>Mille</last></author>
      <author><first>Anya</first><last>Belz</last></author>
      <author><first>Bernd</first><last>Bohnet</last></author>
      <author><first>Thiago</first><last>Castro Ferreira</last></author>
      <author><first>Yvette</first><last>Graham</last></author>
      <author><first>Leo</first><last>Wanner</last></author>
      <pages>1–20</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents results from the Third Shared Task on Multilingual Surface Realisation (SR’20) which was organised as part of the COLING’20 Workshop on Multilingual Surface Realisation. As in SR’18 and SR’19, the shared task comprised two tracks : (1) a Shallow Track where the inputs were full UD structures with word order information removed and tokens lemmatised ; and (2) a Deep Track where additionally, functional words and morphological information were removed. Moreover, each <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Track_(navigation)">track</a> had two subtracks : (a) restricted-resource, where only the data provided or approved as part of a track could be used for training models, and (b) open-resource, where any data could be used. The Shallow Track was offered in 11 languages, whereas the Deep Track in 3 ones. Systems were evaluated using both automatic metrics and direct assessment by human evaluators in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readability">Readability</a> and Meaning Similarity to reference outputs. We present the evaluation results, along with descriptions of the SR’19 tracks, data and evaluation methods, as well as brief summaries of the participating systems. For full descriptions of the participating systems, please see the separate system reports elsewhere in this volume.</abstract>
      <url hash="dbf411db">2020.msr-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>mille-etal-2020-third</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://gitlab.com/talnupf/ud2deep" additional="false">talnupf/ud2deep</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wikitext-103">WikiText-103</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>BME-TUW at SR’20 : Lexical grammar induction for surface realization<fixed-case>BME</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>TUW</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>SR</fixed-case>’20: Lexical grammar induction for surface realization</title>
      <author><first>Gábor</first><last>Recski</last></author>
      <author><first>Ádám</first><last>Kovács</last></author>
      <author><first>Kinga</first><last>Gémes</last></author>
      <author><first>Judit</first><last>Ács</last></author>
      <author><first>Andras</first><last>Kornai</last></author>
      <pages>21–29</pages>
      <abstract>We present a system for mapping Universal Dependency structures to raw text which learns to restore word order by training an Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG) that establishes a mapping between string and graph operations. The reinflection step is handled by a standard sequence-to-sequence architecture with a biLSTM encoder and an LSTM decoder with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attention">attention</a>. We modify our 2019 system (Kovcs et al., 2019) with a new grammar induction mechanism that allows IRTG rules to operate on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lemma_(morphology)">lemmata</a> in addition to part-of-speech tags and ensures that each word and its dependents are reordered using the most specific set of learned patterns. We also introduce a hierarchical approach to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_order">word order restoration</a> that independently determines the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_order">word order</a> of each clause in a sentence before arranging them with respect to the main clause, thereby improving overall readability and also making the IRTG parsing task tractable. We participated in the 2020 Surface Realization Shared task, subtrack T1a (shallow, closed). Human evaluation shows we achieve significant improvements on two of the three out-of-domain datasets compared to the 2019 system we modified. Both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Component-based_software_engineering">components</a> of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> are available on GitHub under an MIT license.</abstract>
      <url hash="96eab5d3">2020.msr-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>recski-etal-2020-bme</bibkey>
    <title_ar>BME-TUW at SR'20: تحريض نحوي معجمي لإدراك السطح</title_ar>
      <title_pt>BME-TUW em SR'20: Indução gramatical lexical para realização de superfície</title_pt>
      <title_es>BME-TUW en SR'20: Inducción gramatical léxica para la realización de superficies</title_es>
      <title_zh>SR曰:20之BME-TUW,词汇语法归也</title_zh>
      <title_ja>SR '20のBME - TUW ：表面実現のための語彙文法誘導</title_ja>
      <title_hi>SR'20 पर BME-TUW: सतह प्राप्ति के लिए लेक्सिकल व्याकरण प्रेरण</title_hi>
      <title_ga>BME-TUW ag SR'20: Ionduchtú gramadaí foclóireachta le haghaidh réadú dromchla</title_ga>
      <title_ka>BME-TUW SR'20: ლექსიკალური გრამიკალური ინდექცია</title_ka>
      <title_el>Β.Μ.Ε. στο SR'20: Λεξική γραμματική επαγωγή για την υλοποίηση επιφάνειας</title_el>
      <title_it>BME-TUW a SR'20: induzione grammaticale lessicale per la realizzazione superficiale</title_it>
      <title_lt>BME-TUW at SR'20: Lexical grammar induction for surface realization</title_lt>
      <title_kk>BME- TUW SR' 20: Жергілікті реализациялау үшін лексикалық грамматикалық индукция</title_kk>
      <title_ms>BME-TUW di SR'20: Induksi grammar leksikal untuk penyelesaian permukaan</title_ms>
      <title_mt>BME-TUW at SR'20: Lexical grammar induction for surface realization</title_mt>
      <title_hu>BME-TUW SR'20: Lexikai nyelvtani indukció a felületi megvalósításhoz</title_hu>
      <title_mk>BME-TUW во SR'20: Лексикална граматска индукција за реализирање на површината</title_mk>
      <title_no>BME-TUW ved SR'20: Leksisk grammatisk induksjon for overflate</title_no>
      <title_ml>BME-TUW at SR'20: Lexical grammar induction for surface realization</title_ml>
      <title_pl>BME-TUW na SR'20: Leksykalna indukcja gramatyki do realizacji powierzchni</title_pl>
      <title_ro>BME-TUW la SR'20: Inducție gramaticală lexicală pentru realizarea suprafeței</title_ro>
      <title_sr>BME-TUW na SR'20: Leksička gramatička indukcija za realizaciju površine</title_sr>
      <title_si>BME-TUW SR'20: පුළුවන් අවස්ථානය සඳහා ලෙක්සිකාල් ග්‍රාමාර්ක්‍රියාව ප්‍රදේශනය</title_si>
      <title_so>BME-TUW at SR'20: Lexical grammar induction for surface realization</title_so>
      <title_ur>BME-TUW SR'20 میں: سطح معلومات کے لئے لکسیکل گراماری انڈاکشن</title_ur>
      <title_sv>BME-TUW på SR'20: Lexisk grammatisk induktion för ytförverkligande</title_sv>
      <title_ta>SR'20-ல் BME- TUW: surface உணர்தலுக்கான Lexical grammar induction</title_ta>
      <title_mn>SR'20-д BME-TUW: гадаргуу ойлгохын тулд лексикийн грамматикийн үйлдвэрлэл</title_mn>
      <title_vi>(BME-TUW) ở SR'20: kiến trúc văn học Y tế để thực hiện bề mặt</title_vi>
      <title_uz>SR'20 bilan BME- TUW: Jarayon aniqlash uchun Leksika grammatika induksiyati</title_uz>
      <title_bg>БМЕ-ТУУ в СР'20: Лексикална граматика за реализация на повърхността</title_bg>
      <title_nl>BME-TUW op SR'20: Lexical grammatica induction voor oppervlakterealisatie</title_nl>
      <title_da>BME-TUW ved SR'20: Lexisk grammatisk induktion til overfladebehandling</title_da>
      <title_hr>BME-TUW na SR'20: Leksička gramatička indukcija za realizaciju površine</title_hr>
      <title_id>BME-TUW at SR'20: Lexical grammar induction for surface realization</title_id>
      <title_ko>SR'20의 BME-TUW: 표면적으로 이루어진 어휘 문법 귀납</title_ko>
      <title_fa>BME-TUW در SR'20: اثبات گرامی لکسیکی برای realization سطح</title_fa>
      <title_de>BME-TUW auf der SR'20: Lexikale Grammatikinduktion zur Oberflächenrealisierung</title_de>
      <title_tr>BME-TUW SR'20:</title_tr>
      <title_sw>BME-TUW kwenye SR'20: Ujenezaji wa grafu za Lexico kwa ajili ya kutambua usoni</title_sw>
      <title_af>BME-TUW by SR'20: Leksiese grammatiese induksie vir oorspronklike realisasie</title_af>
      <title_am>BME-TUW</title_am>
      <title_sq>BME-TUW në SR'20: induksion gramatik leksikal për realizimin e sipërfaqes</title_sq>
      <title_bn>SR'২০-এ বিমি-টুউউ: পৃথিবীর বুঝতে লেক্সিকাল গ্রামার শিল্প</title_bn>
      <title_bs>BME-TUW na SR'20: Leksička gramatička indukcija za realizaciju površine</title_bs>
      <title_cs>BME-TUW na SR'20: Lexická gramatická indukce pro realizaci povrchu</title_cs>
      <title_et>BME-TUW SR'20: Lexikaalse grammatika induktsioon pinna realiseerimiseks</title_et>
      <title_hy>BME-TuW-ը ՍՌ'20-ում. Լեքսիկական գրամագրական ինդուկցիան մակերեսի իրականացման համար</title_hy>
      <title_ca>BME-TUW a SR'20: Inducció gramàtica lèxica per a la concretització de la superfície</title_ca>
      <title_fi>BME-TUW SR'20: Lexical grammatic induction for surface realisation</title_fi>
      <title_az>SR'20'də BME-TUW: Yüzə realizasyonu üçün leksiqli gramatik indukciju</title_az>
      <title_ha>QUnicodeControlCharacterMenu</title_ha>
      <title_jv>paper size</title_jv>
      <title_he>BME-TUW ב SR'20: דליקת גרמטיקה לקסיקה להבינה על פני השטח</title_he>
      <title_sk>BME-TUW na SR'20: indukcija leksične slovnice za uresničitev površine</title_sk>
      <title_bo>BME-TUW at SR'20: Lexical grammar induction for surface realization</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم نظامًا لتعيين هياكل التبعية العالمية إلى النص الخام الذي يتعلم استعادة ترتيب الكلمات من خلال تدريب قواعد الشجرة المنتظمة المفسرة (IRTG) التي تنشئ تعيينًا بين عمليات السلسلة والرسم البياني. تتم معالجة خطوة إعادة الانعكاس من خلال بنية قياسية من التسلسل إلى التسلسل مع مشفر biLSTM وفك تشفير LSTM مع الانتباه. نقوم بتعديل نظام 2019 الخاص بنا (Koväcs et al. ، 2019) بآلية تحريض نحوي جديدة تسمح لقواعد IRTG بالعمل على lemmata بالإضافة إلى علامات جزء من الكلام وتضمن إعادة ترتيب كل كلمة وعائلاتها باستخدام الأكثر تحديدًا مجموعة من الأنماط المكتسبة. نقدم أيضًا نهجًا هرميًا لاستعادة ترتيب الكلمات والذي يحدد بشكل مستقل ترتيب الكلمات لكل جملة في جملة قبل ترتيبها فيما يتعلق بالفقرة الرئيسية ، وبالتالي تحسين قابلية القراءة الشاملة وأيضًا جعل مهمة تحليل IRTG قابلة للتتبع. شاركنا في مهمة 2020 Surface Realization Shared ، والمسار الفرعي T1a (ضحل ، مغلق). يُظهر التقييم البشري أننا نحقق تحسينات كبيرة في اثنتين من مجموعات البيانات الثلاثة خارج المجال مقارنةً بنظام 2019 الذي قمنا بتعديله. يتوفر كلا مكوني نظامنا على GitHub بموجب ترخيص MIT.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos um sistema para mapeamento de estruturas de Dependência Universal para texto bruto que aprende a restaurar a ordem das palavras treinando uma Gramática de Árvore Regular Interpretada (IRTG) que estabelece um mapeamento entre operações de string e gráfico. A etapa de reinflexão é tratada por uma arquitetura padrão de sequência a sequência com um codificador biLSTM e um decodificador LSTM com atenção. Modificamos nosso sistema de 2019 (Koväcs et al., 2019) com um novo mecanismo de indução gramatical que permite que as regras do IRTG operem em lemas, além de tags de parte da fala e garante que cada palavra e seus dependentes sejam reordenados usando o mais específico conjunto de padrões aprendidos. Também introduzimos uma abordagem hierárquica para a restauração da ordem das palavras que determina independentemente a ordem das palavras de cada cláusula em uma frase antes de organizá-las em relação à cláusula principal, melhorando assim a legibilidade geral e também tornando a tarefa de análise do IRTG tratável. Participamos da tarefa 2020 Surface Realization Shared, subpista T1a (raso, fechado). A avaliação humana mostra que alcançamos melhorias significativas em dois dos três conjuntos de dados fora do domínio em comparação com o sistema de 2019 que modificamos. Ambos os componentes do nosso sistema estão disponíveis no GitHub sob uma licença do MIT.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos un sistema para mapear estructuras de dependencia universal al texto sin formato que aprende a restaurar el orden de las palabras mediante el entrenamiento de una gramática de árbol regular interpretada (IRTG) que establece un mapeo entre las operaciones de cadenas y gráficas. La etapa de reinflexión se maneja mediante una arquitectura de secuencia a secuencia estándar con un codificador BilsTM y un decodificador LSTM con atención. Modificamos nuestro sistema de 2019 (Koväcs et al., 2019) con un nuevo mecanismo de inducción gramatical que permite que las reglas del IRTG operen con lemas además de etiquetas de parte del discurso y garantiza que cada palabra y sus dependientes se reordenen utilizando el conjunto más específico de patrones aprendidos. También introducimos un enfoque jerárquico para la restauración del orden de las palabras que determina de forma independiente el orden de las palabras de cada cláusula de una oración antes de organizarlas con respecto a la cláusula principal, mejorando así la legibilidad general y haciendo que la tarea de análisis del IRTG sea manejable. Participamos en la tarea Compartida de Realización de Superficies 2020, subpista T1a (superficial, cerrada). La evaluación humana muestra que logramos mejoras significativas en dos de los tres conjuntos de datos fuera del dominio en comparación con el sistema de 2019 que modificamos. Ambos componentes de nuestro sistema están disponibles en GitHub bajo una licencia MIT.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>ユニバーサル依存構造を生テキストにマッピングするためのシステムを提示し、文字列とグラフ演算の間のマッピングを確立する解釈された正規ツリー文法（ IRTG ）をトレーニングすることで、単語の秩序を回復することを学びます。 再反射ステップは、BiLSTMエンコーダとLSTMデコーダを備えた標準的なシーケンスツーシーケンスアーキテクチャによって処理されます。 私たちは、2019年のシステム（ Koväcs et al., 2019 ）を新しい文法帰納メカニズムで修正し、IRTGルールが音声タグの一部に加えてlemmataで動作することを可能にし、各単語とその依存関係が最も具体的な学習パターンのセットを使用して並べ替えられるようにします。 また、主節に関して各節を配置する前に、文章内の各節の語順を独立して決定し、全体的な可読性を向上させ、IRTG構文解析タスクをトラッキング可能にする、語順復元への階層的アプローチを導入する。 2020 Surface Realization Sharedタスク、サブトラックT 1 a （浅い、閉じている）に参加しました。 ヒトの評価では、修正した2019年のシステムと比較して、3つのドメイン外データセットのうち2つで大幅な改善を達成しています。 当社システムの両方のコンポーネントは、MITライセンスの下でGitHubで利用できます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>建一将通用以结构原始文本之统,当训练解释性常树语法(IRTG)以学复单词序,当语法立映于字符串图形之间。 重度线步由格序至序架构,并 biLSTM 编码器、 LSTM 解码器。 用新语法归机改2019年系统(Koväcs等,2019),宜机制许IRTG则除词性标签外,仍可操作于lemmata,并保每单词及依赖项用最学模式集重行排序。 引入一法以复词序,当于主句之前,独立句之词序,以重其可读性,而使IRTG解析事易处也。 吾侪预2020年,子道T1a(浅)。 人工评明,比我2019年系统,我于三域外数集两上显进。 二组件皆得施于 MIT 许可证下 GitHub 上。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम कच्चे पाठ के लिए यूनिवर्सल निर्भरता संरचनाओं को मैप करने के लिए एक प्रणाली प्रस्तुत करते हैं जो एक व्याख्या की गई नियमित ट्री ग्रामर (आईआरटीजी) को प्रशिक्षित करके शब्द क्रम को बहाल करना सीखता है जो स्ट्रिंग और ग्राफ संचालन के बीच एक मैपिंग स्थापित करता है। reinflection चरण एक मानक अनुक्रम-से-अनुक्रम आर्किटेक्चर द्वारा एक biLSTM एन्कोडर और ध्यान के साथ एक LSTM विकोडक के साथ संभाला जाता है। हम अपने 2019 सिस्टम (Koväcs et al., 2019) को एक नए व्याकरण प्रेरण तंत्र के साथ संशोधित करते हैं जो IRTG नियमों को भाग-भाषण टैग के अलावा लेमाटा पर काम करने की अनुमति देता है और यह सुनिश्चित करता है कि प्रत्येक शब्द और उसके आश्रितों को सीखे गए पैटर्न के सबसे विशिष्ट सेट का उपयोग करके फिर से क्रमबद्ध किया जाए। हम शब्द क्रम बहाली के लिए एक पदानुक्रमित दृष्टिकोण भी पेश करते हैं जो स्वतंत्र रूप से मुख्य खंड के संबंध में उन्हें व्यवस्थित करने से पहले एक वाक्य में प्रत्येक खंड के शब्द क्रम को निर्धारित करता है, जिससे समग्र पठनीयता में सुधार होता है और आईआरटीजी पार्सिंग कार्य को भी असभ्य बनाता है। हमने 2020 सरफेस रिकॉलाइजेशन साझा कार्य, सबट्रैक टी 1 ए (उथले, बंद) में भाग लिया। मानव मूल्यांकन से पता चलता है कि हम 2019 प्रणाली की तुलना में तीन आउट-ऑफ-डोमेन डेटासेट में से दो पर महत्वपूर्ण सुधार प्राप्त करते हैं जिसे हमने संशोधित किया था। हमारे सिस्टम के दोनों घटक एक एमआईटी लाइसेंस के तहत GitHub पर उपलब्ध हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid i láthair córas chun struchtúir Spleáchais Uilíoch a mhapáil chuig amhthéacs a fhoghlaimíonn conas ord focal a athbhunú trí oiliúint a chur ar Ghramadach Chrainn Rialta a Léirmhínithe (IRTG) a bhunaíonn léarscáiliú idir oibríochtaí teaghrán agus graif. Láimhseálann ailtireacht chaighdeánach seicheamh-go-seicheamh an chéim athmhínithe le ionchódóir biLSTM agus díchódóir LSTM ar a bhfuil aird. Déanaimid ár gcóras 2019 (Koväcs et al., 2019) a mhodhnú le meicníocht nua ionduchtaithe gramadaí a ligeann do rialacha IRTG oibriú ar leamaí i dteannta le clibeanna cuid cainte agus a chinntíonn go ndéantar gach focal agus a chleithiúnaithe a athordú ag baint úsáide as na cinn is sainiúla. sraith de phatrúin foghlamtha. Tugaimid isteach freisin cur chuige ordlathach maidir le hathchóiriú ord na bhfocal a chinneann go neamhspleách ord focal gach clásail in abairt sula n-eagrófar iad maidir leis an bpríomhchlásal, rud a fheabhsaíonn inléiteacht iomlán agus a fhágann go mbeidh tasc parsála IRTG inrianaithe. Ghlacamar páirt i dtasc Comhroinnte Réadú Dromchla 2020, fo-rian T1a (éadomhain, dúnta). Léiríonn meastóireacht dhaonna go bhfuil feabhsuithe suntasacha bainte amach againn ar dhá cheann de na trí thacar sonraí lasmuigh den fhearann i gcomparáid le córas 2019 a d’athraíomar. Tá an dá chomhpháirt dár gcóras ar fáil ar GitHub faoi cheadúnas MIT.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Bemutatunk egy olyan rendszert, amely az univerzális függőségi struktúrák nyers szöveghez történő leképezésére szolgál, amely megtanulja visszaállítani a szó sorrendjét egy Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG) képzésével, amely létrehozza a leképezést a karakterlánc és a gráf műveletek között. Az újrafeltükrözési lépést egy szabványos szekvencia-szekvencia architektúra kezeli biLSTM kódolóval és LSTM dekódolóval. 2019-es rendszerünket (Kovacs et al., 2019) egy új nyelvtani indukciós mechanizmussal módosítjuk, amely lehetővé teszi az IRTG szabályok számára, hogy a beszédrész címkék mellett lemmátán működjenek, és biztosítja, hogy minden szó és függője átrendeződjön a legspecifikusabb tanult minták használatával. Bevezetünk egy hierarchikus megközelítést a szósorrend helyreállítására is, amely függetlenül határozza meg az egyes mondatok szósorrendjét, mielőtt azokat a főzáradékhoz viszonyítja, ezáltal javítva az általános olvashatóságot és az IRTG elemzési feladatot is vonhatóvá teszi. Részt vettünk a 2020-as Felületmegvalósítási Megosztott feladatban, a T1a kivonásában (sekély, zárt). Az emberi értékelés azt mutatja, hogy a három domain kívüli adatkészlet közül kettőt jelentős javulást értünk el az általunk módosított 2019-es rendszerhez képest. Rendszerünk mindkét komponense elérhető a GitHub-on MIT licenc alatt.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ ჩვენ უნივერსოლური განსაკუთრებულობის სტრუქტურების მაპოვაციის სისტემის შესახებ, რომელიც ვისწავლის სიტყვების შესაძლებლობა, რომელიც ინტერპრექტირებული რეგრალური ხე გრამარი (IRTG) განა რეფლექციის კოდენტი სტანდარტული კოდენტიკოდენტიკოდენტიკოდენტიკოდენტიკოდენტი და LSTM დეკოდენტიკოდენტიკოდენტი დააყენება. ჩვენ 2019 წლის სისტემის შეცვლა (Kovacs et al., 2019) ახალი გრამატური ინდექციის მექანიზმით, რომელიც IRTG წესების შესაძლებლობა ლემეტაზე მუშაობას და დავხმარებთ, რომ ყოველ სიტყვი და მისი დასაწყვებელი განსხვავებული სიტყვის ჩვენ ასევე იერაქტიკური პროგრამა სიტყვების რესტორიაციის შესახებ, რომელიც განსაკუთრებით განსაკუთრებს ყველა კლასოზის სიტყვების პროგრამა, სანამ ყველა კლასოზის განსაკუთრებისთვის გადავადგინოთ, რადგან ყ ჩვენ 2020 წლის განმავლობა რეალიზაციის გაყოფილი საქმე, T1a წლის გარეშე. ადამიანის განსაზღვრება ჩვენ გავაკეთებთ მნიშვნელოვანი გაუკეთება დომინის სამი დანაშორებულ მონაცემების ორზე, რომელიც ჩვენ შევაკეთებული სისტემაზე შედგენა 201 ეგამარა კომპონენტები ჩვენი სისტემის შესაძლებელია GitHub-ზე, რომელიც MIT ლიცენსია.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_lt>We present a system for mapping Universal Dependency structures to raw text which learns to restore word order by training an Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG) that establishes a mapping between string and graph operations.  Reinfliacijos žingsnis tvarkomas standartine sekos po sekos architektūra su biLSTM kodatoriumi ir LSTM kodatoriumi. Pakeitime savo 2019 m. sistemą (Kovacs et al., 2019 m.), naudojant naują gramatikos indukcijos mechanizmą, kuris leidžia IRTG taisyklėms veikti citrinose, be kalbos dalinių žymenų, ir užtikrina, kad kiekvienas žodis ir jo priklausomi asmenys būtų perskirstyti naudojant konkrečiausius įgytus modelius. Taip pat įvedame hierarchinį požiūrį į žodžių tvarkos atkūrimą, kuris nepriklausomai nustato kiekvienos punkto žodžių tvarką sakinyje, prieš juos nustatydamas pagrindinio punkto atžvilgiu, taip pagerinant bendrą skaitomumą ir taip užtikrinant IRTG analizavimo užduotį. Dalyvavome 2020 m. paviršiaus įgyvendinimo bendroje užduotyje, atėmėme T1a (plokščią, uždarytą). Žmogaus vertinimas rodo, kad mes pasiekėme reikšmingus dviejų iš trijų ne srities duomenų rinkinių patobulinimus, palyginti su mūsų pakeista 2019 m. sistema. Abu mūsų sistemos komponentai yra prieinami GitHub licencijoje MIT.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε ένα σύστημα για την αντιστοίχιση δομών καθολικής εξάρτησης σε ακατέργαστο κείμενο το οποίο μαθαίνει να επαναφέρει τη σειρά λέξεων εκπαιδεύοντας μια ερμηνευμένη τακτική γραμματική δέντρου (που εγκαθιστά μια αντιστοίχιση μεταξύ των λειτουργιών συμβολοσειράς και γραφήματος. Το βήμα επανεμφάνισης χειρίζεται μια τυπική αρχιτεκτονική ακολουθίας-ακολουθίας με έναν κωδικοποιητή και έναν αποκωδικοποιητή LSTM με προσοχή. Τροποποιούμε το σύστημά μας 2019 (κ.α., 2019) με έναν νέο μηχανισμό επαγωγής γραμματικής που επιτρέπει στους κανόνες να λειτουργούν σε λεμώματα εκτός από τις ετικέτες τμήματος ομιλίας και εξασφαλίζει ότι κάθε λέξη και τα εξαρτώμενα της αναδιατάσσονται χρησιμοποιώντας το πιο συγκεκριμένο σύνολο μαθημένων προτύπων. Επίσης, εισάγουμε μια ιεραρχική προσέγγιση στην αποκατάσταση της σειράς λέξεων που καθορίζει ανεξάρτητα τη σειρά λέξεων κάθε ρήτρας σε μια πρόταση πριν την τακτοποιήσει σε σχέση με την κύρια ρήτρα, βελτιώνοντας έτσι τη συνολική αναγνωσιμότητα και καθιστώντας την εργασία ανάλυσης ανιχνεύσιμη. Συμμετείχαμε στην 2020 Κοινή Εργασία Υλοποίησης επιφάνειας, αφαίρεση Τ1α (ρηχή, κλειστή). Η ανθρώπινη αξιολόγηση δείχνει ότι επιτυγχάνουμε σημαντικές βελτιώσεις σε δύο από τα τρία σύνολα δεδομένων εκτός τομέα σε σύγκριση με το σύστημα 2019 που τροποποιήσαμε. Και τα δύο συστατικά του συστήματός μας είναι διαθέσιμα στο υπό άδεια ΜΙΤ.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo un sistema per la mappatura delle strutture di Dipendenza Universale al testo grezzo che impara a ripristinare l'ordine delle parole addestrando una grammatica ad albero regolare interpretata (IRTG) che stabilisce una mappatura tra le operazioni stringhe e grafici. La fase di rifunzione è gestita da un'architettura sequenza-sequenza standard con encoder biLSTM e decoder LSTM con attenzione. Modifichiamo il nostro sistema 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) con un nuovo meccanismo di induzione grammaticale che consente alle regole IRTG di operare sulla lemmata oltre ai tag part-of-speech e garantisce che ogni parola e i suoi dipendenti siano riordinati utilizzando l'insieme più specifico di modelli appresi. Introducemo anche un approccio gerarchico al ripristino dell'ordine delle parole che determina in modo indipendente l'ordine delle parole di ogni frase in una frase prima di organizzarle rispetto alla clausola principale, migliorando così la leggibilità complessiva e rendendo anche tracciabile l'attività di analisi IRTG. Abbiamo partecipato al compito condiviso di realizzazione superficiale 2020, sottrarre T1a (poco profondo, chiuso). La valutazione umana mostra che abbiamo ottenuto miglioramenti significativi su due dei tre set di dati fuori dominio rispetto al sistema 2019 che abbiamo modificato. Entrambi i componenti del nostro sistema sono disponibili su GitHub sotto licenza MIT.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Презентираме систем за мапирање на универзалните структури на зависност на суров текст кој научи да го врати редот на зборовите со обука на Интерпретирана регуларна грама на дрво (IRTG) која поставува мапирање помеѓу редови и графички операции. Крајот на реинфлекција се справува со стандардна архитектура од секвенца до секвенца со biLSTM кодер и LSTM декодер со внимание. Ние го модификуваме нашиот систем 2019 (Kovacs и други, 2019) со новиот механизам за индукција на граматика кој им овозможува на ИРТГ правилата да функционираат на лимата, покрај дел од говорните ознаки и да се осигура дека секој збор и неговите зависни се реординирани со користење на најспецифичните научени шеми We also introduce a hierarchical approach to word order restoration that independently determines the word order of each clause in a sentence before arranging them with respect to the main clause, thereby improving overall readability and also making the IRTG parsing task tractable.  We participated in the 2020 Surface Realization Shared task, subtrack T1a (shallow, closed).  Човечката проценка покажува дека постигнуваме значителни подобрувања на двајца од трите надвор од доменот податоци во споредба со системот 2019 година кој го модификувавме. Двете компоненти од нашиот систем се достапни на Гит Хаб под МИТ лиценца.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Біз әлемдегі тәуелсіздік құрылғыларды сызық мәтінде картаптау жүйесін таңдаймыз. Бұл сөздердің ретін қайталау үшін оқыту үшін, мәтіндегі мәтінде, мәтінді тізім мен график операцияларының арасындағы Қайталау қадамын biLSTM кодері мен LSTM декодері бойынша стандартты қадамдастыру архитектурасы менеджеріледі. Біз 2019 жылы жүйемізді (Kovacs et al., 2019) жаңа грамматикалық индукциялық механизммен өзгертіп, IRTG ережелерін сөйлеу тегтерінің бірнеше бөлігіне қосып, әрбір сөз мен оның тәуелдіктері білім үлгілерін қолдану үшін қайта реттеу ү Біз сондай-ақ әрбір сөздердің тізбегін негізгі клаузға қатынау алдында, әрбір сөздердің тізбегін қайталау ретіне иерархиялық тәртібін келтіреміз. Бұл сөздердің әрбір сөздердің тізбегін өзгерту үшін, оларды негізгі Біз 2020 жылы Жергілікті Реализацияның ортақтастырылған тапсырмасына қатысу үшін T1a көшірмесі (жабылған, жабылған). Адам оқиғасы 2019 жылы өзгертілген жүйесімізге салыстырылған үш домен деректер қорларының екі жақсартылығын көрсетеді. Жүйеміздің екі компоненттері MIT лицензиясы арқылы GitHub- та бар.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ml>വാക്കിന്റെ ഉത്തരവ് വീണ്ടെടുക്കാന്‍ പഠിക്കുന്ന ഒരു സിസ്റ്റം മാപ്പ് ചെയ്യുന്നു. അത് സ്ട്രിങ്ങും ഗ്രാഫ് പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ക്കും ഇടയില്‍ ഒരു മാപ്പ്  പുന്നിയോഗിക്കുന്ന പടി ഒരു സാധാരണ സെക്കന്‍സെക്കന്‍സ് മുതല്‍ സെക്കന്‍സ് സെക്കന്‍സ് സെക്കന്‍സ് ആര്‍ക്ടിക്കറ്റര്‍ കൈകാര്യം ചെയ്യുന്ന ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഞങ്ങളുടെ 2019 സിസ്റ്റത്തെ മാറ്റുന്നു. കോവാക്സ് എറ്റ് അല്‍, 2019, ഒരു പുതിയ ഗ്രാമാര്‍ ഇന്‍സ്റ്റാന്‍ഷന്‍ മെനിസ്റ്റമുണ്ട്. അത് ഇംഗി നിയമങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കാന്‍ അന പ്രധാന വാക്കുകളില്‍ സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യമായി ഓരോ വാക്കിന്റെയും വാക്കുകളുടെയും ഉത്തരവാക്കുകളില്‍ നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കുന്നതിനു മുമ്പായി വാക്കുകളുടെയും വാക്കുകള്‍ പുനര 2020 സര്‍ഫെസ്റ്റ് റിയാജിഷന്‍ പങ്കെടുത്ത ജോലിയില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ പങ്കുചേര്‍ന്നു. ടി1a (തണുത്ത, അടച്ചുപൂട്ടി). മനുഷ്യരുടെ വിലാസങ്ങള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു. ഞങ്ങള്‍ മാറ്റിയിട്ടുള്ള 2019 സിസ്റ്റത്തിനെതിരില്‍ മൂന്ന് ഡേറ്റാറ്സെറ്റില്‍  നമ്മുടെ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ രണ്ടു ഭാഗങ്ങളും ജിറ്റ്ഹുബില്‍ ലഭ്യമാണ് MIT ലൈസന്‍സിന്‍റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്ത്.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Бид универсал хамааралтай байдлын бүтцийг зураг зураг хийх системийг суралцаж өгүүлсэн үг дарааллыг эргүүлэхийг суралцаж, стринг болон график үйл ажиллагааны хоорондын зураг зураг зохион байгуулах боломжтой Интерпретийн Загварын грамматар (IR Дахин гүйцэтгэх алхам нь биLSTM коддогч болон LSTM коддогч, анхаарлаа хангалттай стандарт дарааллаар дарааллаар хангалттай архитектур юм. Бид 2019 оны системийг (Kovacs et al., 2019) шинэ грамматикийн үйлдвэрлэлийн механизмаар өөрчилж байна. Энэ нь IRTG дүрмийг хэсэг хэсэг хэлбэрийн тэмдэгүүд дээр уламт дээр ажиллах боломжтой болгодог бөгөөд үг бүр, хамааралтай нь хамгийн тодорхой сургалтын хэлбэрээр да Мөн бид үгийн дарааллын дахин дахин хэлбэрээр хэлбэрээр үгийн дарааллын дарааллын дарааллыг тодорхойлж өгдөг. Тэдгээрийг гол дарааллаар зохион байгуулахаас өмнө хэлбэрээр илүү унших боломжтой, Мөн IRTG ажлын дарааллын дарааллын дарааллыг хийх Бид 2020 оны гадаргуу реализацийн хуваалтын ажилд оролцсон. T1a-ын гадаргуу (гүн гүнзгий, хоцрогдсон). Хүн төрөлхтний оюутнууд бид 2019 оны өөрчлөгдсөн системтэй харьцуулсан гурван хүн төрөлхтний өгөгдлийн сангийн хоёр дахь чухал сайжруулалт гаргадаг. Бидний системийн хоёр компонент нь MIT лицензийн доор GitHub дээр ашиглаж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Przedstawiamy system mapowania struktur uniwersalnej zależności do tekstu surowego, który uczy się przywracać kolejność słów poprzez trening Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG), który ustanawia mapowanie między operacjami ciągu i wykresu. Krok reinflekcji jest obsługiwany przez standardową architekturę sekwencji-sekwencji z koderem biLSTM i dekoderem LSTM z uwagą. Modyfikujemy nasz system 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) o nowy mechanizm indukcji gramatycznej, który umożliwia działanie reguł IRTG na lemmatach oprócz tagów części mowy i zapewnia, że każde słowo i jego zależne są zmieniane przy użyciu najbardziej konkretnego zestawu nauczonych wzorców. Wprowadzamy również hierarchiczne podejście do przywracania kolejności słów, które niezależnie określa kolejność słów każdej klauzuli w zdaniu przed ułożeniem ich w odniesieniu do klauzuli głównej, poprawiając tym samym ogólną czytelność, a także sprawiając, że zadanie parsowania IRTG jest ściągalne. Uczestniczyliśmy w zadaniu 2020 Realizacja Powierzchni Wspólnym, odejmowaniu T1a (płytkie, zamknięte). Ocena ludzka pokazuje, że osiągamy znaczące ulepszenia dwóch z trzech zbiorów danych poza domeną w porównaniu z modyfikowanym przez nas systemem 2019. Oba komponenty naszego systemu są dostępne na GitHub na licencji MIT.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Vă prezentăm un sistem de cartografiere a structurilor de dependență universală la text brut care învață să restabilească ordinea cuvintelor prin instruirea unei Grammatici Interpretate Regular Tree (IRTG) care stabilește o cartografiere între operațiunile de șir și grafic. Pasul de reinflecție este gestionat de o arhitectură standard secvență-secvență cu un encoder biLSTM și un decoder LSTM cu atenție. Modificăm sistemul nostru 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) cu un nou mecanism de inducție gramaticală care permite regulilor IRTG să funcționeze pe lemmata în plus față de etichetele parțiale de vorbire și asigură că fiecare cuvânt și persoanele dependente sunt reordonate folosind cel mai specific set de modele învățate. Introducem, de asemenea, o abordare ierarhică a restaurării ordinii de cuvinte care determină independent ordinea de cuvinte a fiecărei clauze dintr-o propoziție înainte de a le aranja în raport cu clauza principală, îmbunătățind astfel lizibilitatea generală și, de asemenea, făcând sarcina de analizare IRTG trasabilă. Am participat la sarcina partajată de realizare a suprafeței 2020, subtract T1a (superficial, închis). Evaluarea umană arată că obținem îmbunătățiri semnificative la două dintre cele trei seturi de date din afara domeniului comparativ cu sistemul din 2019 pe care l-am modificat. Ambele componente ale sistemului nostru sunt disponibile pe GitHub sub o licență MIT.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer eit system for mapping av universelle avhengighetsstrukturer til råtekst som lærer å gjenoppretta ordrekkefølgje ved opplæring av eit regulært tregrammar (IRTG) som opprettar ei mapping mellom streng og grafenoperasjonar. Reinfleksjonsstegnet vert handsama av ein standard arkitektur med ein biLSTM-kodar og ein LSTM-dekoder med oppmerksomhet. Vi endrar vår 2019-system et (Kovacs et al., 2019) med ein ny grammatisk induksjonsmekanismen som tillater IRTG-reglar å fungere på lemmatikk i tillegg til delvis taletaggar og sikre at kvar ord og avhengigheten vert rekordert med dei mest spesifikke settet av lærte mønsteret. Vi introduserer også ein hierarkisk tilnærming til ordordrekkefølgje som avhengig bestemmer ordrekkefølgja for kvar klausul i eit setning før du ordna dei med respekt til hovudklausulen, dermed å forbetra overalt lesabilitet og også gjera IRTG-tillesingssportabellen. Vi delta i den delte oppgåva for overflaten Realization 2020, subtrakt T1a (sållog, lukka). Menneske evalueringa viser at vi har nådd signifikante forbedringar på to av dei tre datasetta som ikkje er domenet sammenlignet med systemet 2019 vi endra. Begge komponentar av systemet vårt er tilgjengelege på GitHub under ein MIT- lisens.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo sistem za mapiranje univerzalne nezavisnosti strukture na sirov tekst koji nauči da obnovi red riječi obučavajući preglednu regularnu grammaru drveta (IRTG) koja utvrđuje mapiranje između funkcija žica i grafika. Korak reinflekcije se obrađuje standardna arhitektura sekvence do sekvence sa koderom biLSTM i LSTM dekoderom sa pažnjom. Mi izmijenimo naš sistem 2019. godine (Kovacs et al., 2019) sa novim gramatičkim indukcijskim mehanizam koji omogućava da IRTG pravila funkcioniše na lematici u dodatnom delu govornih etiketa i osiguravaju da se svaka reč i njegovi ovisnici ponovno urede koristeći najspecifičniju skupu naučenih obrazaca. Takođe predstavljamo hijerarhički pristup restauraciji rečenica koja neovisno određuje rečenicu svake klauzule u rečenici pre nego što ih sredimo u pogledu glavne klauzule, tako poboljšavajući ukupnu čitljivost i također činiti praćenje zadataka IRTG-a. Mi smo sudjelovali u zajedničkom zadatku realizacije površine 2020. godine, subtrakt T1a (plitko, zatvoren). Ljudska procjena pokazuje da postignemo značajno poboljšanje na dva od tri podataka iz domena u usporedbi sa sistemom 2019 koji smo modificirali. Obje komponente našeg sistema su dostupne na GitHubu pod MIT dozvolu.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අපි සාමාන්‍ය විශේෂ විශේෂතාව ස්ථාපනය කරන්න පද්ධතියක් පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන් පද්ධතියක් පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන් පද්ධතියක් පෙන්වන්න. ඒක පු ආපහු ප්‍රවේශනය පැත්තක් ප්‍රමාණික පද්ධතියෙන් ප්‍රමාණික පද්ධතියෙන් බිල්ස්ටිම් සංකේතකය සහ LSTM සංකේතකයෙන් අ අපි 2019 පද්ධතිය (KOvacs et al., 2019) වෙනස් කරනවා අළුත් ගර්මාර් සංවේදනය සඳහා IRTG නීතිය ලම්මාතාවට පරීක්ෂණය කරන්න පුළුවන් වෙන්නේ කොටස් කිරීමේ ටැග් සඳහා සඳහා පරී අපි වචන පණිවිධානයක් වචන පණිවිධානය කරනවා කියලා වචන පණිවිධානය කරනවා වචන පණිවිධාන පණිවිධානය සඳහා ඔවුන්ව ප්‍රධාන පණිවිධානය සඳහා සාම අපි 2020යි ප්‍රතිමූණ ප්‍රතිමූණ ක්‍රියාත්මක වැදගත් වැඩේ සම්ප්‍රේක්ට් T1a (අඩුවෙන්, වහලා). මිනිස්සු විශ්ලේෂණය පෙන්වනවා අපි 2019 පද්ධති වෙනස් කරපු පද්ධතියෙන් ප්‍රමාණය කරපු දත්ත තුරු දෙකක් ගැන වැඩ අපේ පද්ධතියේ අංකය දෙන්නම තියෙන්නේ MIT ලායිසන්ස් එකේ GitHub වලින්.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar ett system för att kartlägga Universal Dependency strukturer till råtext som lär sig att återställa ordordningen genom att träna en Tolked Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG) som etablerar en kartläggning mellan sträng och grafoperationer. Återflektionssteget hanteras av en standard sekvens-till-sekvensarkitektur med en biLSTM-kodare och en LSTM-avkodare med uppmärksamhet. Vi modifierar vårt system 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) med en ny grammatisk induktionsmekanism som gör det möjligt för IRTG-regler att arbeta på lemmata förutom delar av tal taggar och ser till att varje ord och dess beroende ordnas om med hjälp av de mest specifika uppsättningen av lärda mönster. Vi introducerar också ett hierarkiskt tillvägagångssätt för ordordning restaurering som självständigt bestämmer ordordningen för varje sats i en mening innan de ordnar dem med avseende på huvudsatsen, vilket förbättrar den övergripande läsbarheten och gör IRTG-tolkningsaktiviteten spårbar. Vi deltog i 2020 Surface Realization Shared uppgift, subtract T1a (grunt, stängt). Mänsklig utvärdering visar att vi uppnår betydande förbättringar på två av de tre datauppsättningarna utanför domänen jämfört med 2019 års system vi modifierade. Båda komponenterna i vårt system är tillgängliga på GitHub under en MIT-licens.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாம் பொதுவான சார்ந்த அமைப்புகளை வரைபடத்திற்கான அமைப்புகளை குறைக்கவும், உரையை மீட்டெடுக்கவும் கற்றுக் கொள்ள முடியும். ஒரு மொழிபெயர்ப்பு வழக்கமா The reinflection step is handled by a standard sequence-to-sequence architecture with a biLSTM encoder and an LSTM decoder with attention.  நாங்கள் எங்கள் 2019 அமைப்பை (Kovacs et al., 2019) மாற்றுகிறோம் ஒரு புதிய குறிப்பிட்ட பேச்சு குறிப்பிட்ட உருவங்களை பயன்படுத்தி IRTG விதிகளை லிம்மாட்டை செயல்படுத்த அனுமதிக்கிறது மற்று நாம் வார்த்தை மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கு ஒரு முன்னிருப்பு முறையான சொல்லை மீட்டெடுப்பு செயலை முன்னால் தீர்மானிக்கும் ஒவ்வொரு குறிப்பின் வரிசையை வாக்கியத் 2020 மேற்கோள்களில் நாங்கள் பங்கிடப்பட்ட பணி நாங்கள் மாற்றியது 2019 முறைமையை ஒப்பிட்ட மூன்று தரவுத்தளங்களில் இரண்டில் முக்கியமான முன்னேற்றங்களை நாம் பெறுகிற எங்கள் கணினியின் இரு பகுதிகளும் MIT அனுமதிக்கு கீழ் GitHub கிடைக்கும்.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_so>Waxaan diyaarinaynaa nidaam u sawira dhismaha ku xirnaanta caalamiga ah si a an u sawiro qoraalka lagu barto ku cusboonaysiinta nidaamka hadalka ee lagu barto qoraal-ku-tababarida Tree Regular Grammar (IRTG) oo sawiraad u dhexeeya sawir iyo waxqabadka graph. Qoraalka dib u soo celinta waxaa lagu maamulaa dhismaha saxda ah ee standard-to-sequence, kaas oo leh biLSTM encoder iyo LSTM coder aad u taxadaraysaa. Waxaynu beddelinaynaa nidaamka 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) iyadoo leh mekani cusub oo lagu sameeyo maamulka IRTG in uu ku shaqeeyo lemmata ka sokow alaabta hadalka, waxaynu hubsanaynaa in eray walba iyo qofka ku xiran lagu amro isticmaalka noocyada ugu wacan waxbarashada. We also introduce a hierarchical approach to word order restoration that independently determines the word order of each clause in a sentence before arranging them with respect to the main clause, thereby improving overall readability and also making the IRTG parsing task tractable.  Waxaannu ka qayb galnay 2020 Surface Realization Shared task, subtract T1a (shallow, closed). Qiimeynta biniaadamka waxaa muuqanaya horumarin aad u weyn labada kooban oo ka mid ah saddexda macluumaadka ee domain-ka-baxsan, barbarka ah nidaamka 2019 ee aan beddelinay. Labada qeybood oo nidaamka ah waxaa lagu heli karaa GitHub sharciga MIT.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ms>Kami perkenalkan sistem untuk memetakan struktur Dependensi Universal ke teks mentah yang belajar untuk memulihkan perintah perkataan dengan melatih Grammar Pohon Regular Terinterpretasi (IRTG) yang menetapkan pemetaan antara operasi rentetan dan graf. Langkah refleksi dikendalikan oleh arkitektur rangkaian-ke-rangkaian piawai dengan pengekod biLSTM dan pengekod LSTM dengan perhatian. Kami mengubahsuai sistem 2019 kami (Kovacs et al., 2019) dengan mekanisme induksi grammar baru yang membolehkan peraturan IRTG untuk beroperasi pada lemma tambahan kepada sebahagian-tag-ucapan dan memastikan bahawa setiap perkataan dan dependennya diubahsuai menggunakan set yang paling spesifik corak belajar. Kami juga memperkenalkan pendekatan hierarkis untuk pemulihan perintah perkataan yang secara independen menentukan perintah perkataan setiap klausul dalam kalimat sebelum mengatur mereka terhadap klausul utama, dengan demikian meningkatkan pembacaan keseluruhan dan juga membuat tugas hurai IRTG boleh ditarik. Kami berpartisipasi dalam tugas Perwujudan Surface 2020 Berkongsi, tolak T1a (rendah, ditutup). Evaluasi manusia menunjukkan kita mencapai peningkatan yang signifikan pada dua dari tiga set data luar domain dibandingkan dengan sistem 2019 yang kita ubahsuaikan. Kedua-dua komponen sistem kita tersedia di GitHub di bawah lesen MIT.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ur>ہم ایک سیسٹم کی مکاپیٹ کرنے کے لئے یونلورٹ ڈیپنڈنسیٹ ساختروں کو روئیں ٹیکسٹ کے لئے پیش کریں جو کلمات کے اوقات کو دوبارہ پلٹانے کی تعلیم کے ذریعہ سکھاتا ہے کہ ایک قانونی تری گرم (IRTG) جو استرینگ اور گراف عملیات کے درمیان دوبارہ تغییر پڑھنے کی سطح ایک استاندارڈ سٹرنڈ-تا-سٹرنڈ آرکیٹ کے ذریعہ ایک بیLSTM اکوڈر اور ایک LSTM ڈیکوڈر کے ذریعہ منظور ہوتی ہے. ہم نے 2019 کی سیستم (Kovacs et al., 2019) کو ایک نئی گرامماری انڈاکس مکانیسم کے ساتھ بدل دیا ہے جو IRTG قوانین کو ایک قسمت کی بات ٹاگ کے ساتھ چلنے کی اجازت دیتا ہے اور اس کا مضبوط ہے کہ ہر کلم اور اس کے اعتباروں کو سب سے زیادہ مشخص طریقوں کے مطابق دوبارہ سمجھا جائے۔ ہم نے کلمات کے ذریعے ایک حکومت طریقے کو بھی پیش کیا ہے جو ہر کلمات کے کلمات کے ذریعے ایک کلمات کے ذریعہ سے پہلے ان کو اصلی کلمات کے معاملہ میں ترکیب کرنے سے پہلے ایک کلمات کے کلمات کے ذریعہ مطابق مقرر کرتا ہے، اس کے ذریعہ سے سب کی پڑھنے کی طاقت اور IRTG کو ترکیب ہم نے ۲۰۰۲ سارے سطح ریلیزانیز شریک کام میں شریک ہوا، ٹی 1ا (گلے، بند ہوا)۔ انسان کا ارزیابی دکھاتا ہے کہ ہم نے 2019 سیستم کے مقابلہ میں بدل دیا تھا کہ ہم نے تین ڈومین کے خارج سے دوسرے سے بہترین سوداگری حاصل کی۔ ہمارے سیسٹم کی دو قسمتیں ایک MIT لائیس کے نیچے GitHub پر موجود ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nippreżentaw sistema għall-immappjar tal-istrutturi tad-Dipendenza Universali għat-test mhux ipproċessat li jitgħallem jirritorna l-ordni tal-kliem permezz tat-taħriġ ta’ Grammar Regolatorju tas-Siġar Interpretat (IRTG) li jistabbilixxi mmappjar bejn operazzjonijiet ta’ strings u grafiċi. The reinflection step is handled by a standard sequence-to-sequence architecture with a biLSTM encoder and an LSTM decoder with attention.  Aħna nimmodifikaw is-sistema tagħna tal-2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) b’mekkaniżmu ġdid ta’ induzzjoni grammarja li jippermetti li r-regoli tal-IRTG joperaw fuq il-limma flimkien ma’ tikketti ta’ parti mid-diskors u jiżguraw li kull kelma u d-dipendenti tagħha jiġu ordnati mill-ġdid bl-użu tal-aktar sett speċifiku ta’ mudelli miksuba. Inintroduċu wkoll approċċ ġerarkiku għar-restawr tal-ordni tal-kelma li jiddetermina b’mod indipendenti l-ordni tal-kelma ta’ kull klawżola f’sentenza qabel ma jorganizzawhom fir-rigward tal-klawżola ewlenija, u b’hekk itejjeb il-leġibbiltà ġenerali u jagħmel il-kompitu tal-analiżi tal-IRTG attrabbli wkoll. Parteċipajna fil-kompitu Kondiviż tar-Realizzazzjoni tas-Suq tal-2020, nieqes it-T1a (baxx, magħluq). L-evalwazzjoni tal-bniedem turi li nkisbu titjib sinifikanti fuq tnejn mit-tliet settijiet tad-dejta barra d-dominju meta mqabbla mas-sistema tal-2019 li mmodifikaw. Iż-żewġ komponenti tas-sistema tagħna huma disponibbli fuq GitHub taħt liċenzja MIT.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_uz>Biz bir tizimni koʻchirish uchun tugmalar tartibi yaratish mumkin. Bu soʻzni qayta taklif qilish mumkin. Name @ info: whatsthis We modify our 2019 system (Kovacs et al., 2019) with a new grammar induction mechanism that allows IRTG rules to operate on lemmata in addition to part-of-speech tags and ensures that each word and its dependents are reordered using the most specific set of learned patterns.  Biz bu so'zni o'zgartirish orqali o'zgartirish imkoniyatini o'rganamiz. Bu so'zlarni asosiy soʻzni boshqarishdan avval bir so'zlarning soʻzni o'zgartirish imkoniyatini o'zgartirish mumkin. Bu yerda umumiy oʻqishni oshirish va IRTG parsing vazifani taʼminlovchiga bajarishi mumkin. Biz 2020 tashkilotni tashkilotga ega bo'lgan vazifani, T1a (yopish, yopilgan). Inson qiymatlari esa biz 2019 tizimga o'zgartirilgan uchta domen maʼlumotlar tarkibidagi uchta ta ta'lim rivojlanishimizni ko'rsatadi. Bizning ikki komponenti MIT litsenziyasi bilan GitHub'da imkoniyatlar mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi giới thiệu một hệ thống để vẽ bản đồ các cấu trúc nắm giữ sự phụ thuộc to àn cầu thành văn bản nguyên bản mà học để phục hồi trật tự bằng cách đào tạo một Grammar (IRTG) cấu hình thành một bản đồ giữa các thao tác dòng và đồ thị. Các bước xây dựng được điều khiển bởi một cấu trúc dãy-tới-dãy tiêu chuẩn có bộ mã hóa bialTM và một bộ giải mã LSTM kèm theo sự chú ý. Chúng tôi sửa đổi hệ thống thẩm tê (Kovacs et al., 99) với một cơ chế cảm ứng từ ngữ pháp mới cho phép các quy tắc IRTG hoạt động trên lemmata, thêm các thẻ phần ngôn ngữ, và đảm bảo rằng mỗi từ và những người thân thuộc của nó được sắp đặt lại bằng các mẫu được học hỏi đặc biệt nhất. Chúng tôi cũng thiết lập lại hệ thống phân cấp các chức vụ phục hồi trật tự từ mà quyết định trật tự của mỗi điều khoản trong một câu, trước khi xử lý các điều khoản về điều khoản chính, để nâng mức độ dễ đọc tổng quát và cũng làm cho bộ phân tích các nhiệm vụ của IRTG. Chúng tôi tham gia vụ thực hiện mặt đất 2020 Phân chia nhiệm vụ, trừ T1a (cạn, đóng). Kết quả đánh giá con người cho thấy ta đạt được những cải tiến đáng kể về hai trong ba bộ dữ liệu ngoài lĩnh vực so với hệ thống tê-99 mà ta đã thay đổi. Cả hai thành phần của hệ thống đều có mặt ở GitHub dưới giấy phép MIT.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме система за картографиране на структурите на универсална зависимост към суров текст, която се научава да възстановява реда на думите чрез обучение на интерпретирана регулярна дървесна граматика (IRTG), която установява картографиране между низови и графични операции. Стъпката за рефлекция се обработва от стандартна архитектура последователност към последователност с кодер и декодер с внимание. Ние модифицираме нашата система за 2019 г. (Ковац и др., 2019 г.) с нов граматически индукционен механизъм, който позволява правилата да работят върху лемата в допълнение към таговете за част от речта и гарантира, че всяка дума и нейните зависими са пренаредени, използвайки най-специфичния набор от научени модели. Също така въвеждаме йерархичен подход към възстановяването на реда на думите, който независимо определя реда на думите на всяка клауза в изречение, преди да ги подреди по отношение на основната клауза, като по този начин подобрява общата четливост и прави задачата за анализ проследима. Участвахме в задачата "Споделена реализация на повърхността 2020", изваждане на Т1а (плитко, затворено). Оценката на хората показва, че постигаме значителни подобрения в два от трите набора от данни извън домейна в сравнение със системата от 2019 г., която модифицирахме. И двата компонента на нашата система са достъпни в ГитХъб под лиценз на МИТ.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren een systeem voor het toewijzen van universele afhankelijkheidsstructuren aan ruwe tekst dat leert om de woordvolgorde te herstellen door een Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG) te trainen die een toewijzing tussen string- en grafiekbewerkingen tot stand brengt. De herflectie stap wordt afgehandeld door een standaard sequence-to-sequence architectuur met een biLSTM encoder en een LSTM decoder met aandacht. We modificeren ons 2019-systeem (Kovacs et al., 2019) met een nieuw grammatica-inductiemechanisme dat IRTG-regels toestaat om te werken op lemmata naast part-of-speech tags en ervoor zorgt dat elk woord en zijn afhankelijke personen opnieuw worden geordend met behulp van de meest specifieke set geleerd patronen. We introduceren ook een hiërarchische benadering van het herstellen van woordvolgorde die onafhankelijk de woordvolgorde van elke zin in een zin bepaalt alvorens deze te rangschikken met betrekking tot de hoofdzin, waardoor de algehele leesbaarheid wordt verbeterd en ook de IRTG parsing taak traceerbaar wordt gemaakt. We namen deel aan de 2020 Surface Realization Shared taak, subtrack T1a (ondiep, gesloten). Menselijke evaluatie toont aan dat we significante verbeteringen bereiken op twee van de drie out-of-domain datasets in vergelijking met het 2019-systeem dat we hebben aangepast. Beide componenten van ons systeem zijn beschikbaar op GitHub onder een MIT licentie.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Predstavljamo sistem za mapiranje struktura univerzalne zavisnosti na sirov tekst koji uči da obnovi red riječi obučavajući protumačeni regularni grammar drveta (IRTG) koji utvrđuje mapiranje između operacija žica i grafa. Korak reinflekcije se rješava standardnim arhitekturom sekvence do sekvence s koderom biLSTM i LSTM dekoderom s pažnjom. Mi izmijenimo naš sistem 2019. godine (Kovacs et al., 2019) s novim gramatičkim indukcijskim mehanizam koji omogućava da se IRTG pravila djeluju na lematici u dodatnom dijelom govornih znakova i osigurava da se svaka riječ i njegova zavisnost ponovno urede koristeći najspecifičniji skup učenih obrazaca. Također predstavljamo hijerarhički pristup restauraciji reda riječi koji neovisno određuje redak riječi svake klauzule u rečenici prije nego što ih sredimo u pogledu glavne klauzule, tako poboljšavajući ukupnu čitljivost i učiniti praćenje zadataka IRTG-a. Učelili smo u zajedničkom zadatku realizacije površine 2020. godine, subtrakt T1a (plitko, zatvoren). Ljudska procjena pokazuje da postignemo značajno poboljšanje na dvije od tri podataka izvan domena u usporedbi s sustavom 2019 koji smo modificirali. Obje komponente našeg sustava su dostupne na GitHub pod MIT dozvolu.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Wir stellen ein System zur Zuordnung universeller Abhängigkeitsstrukturen auf Rohtext vor, das lernt, die Wortreihenfolge wiederherzustellen, indem eine Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG) trainiert wird, die eine Zuordnung zwischen String- und Graphenoperationen herstellt. Der Reinflektionsschritt wird von einer Standard Sequenz-zu-Sequenz Architektur mit einem biLSTM Encoder und einem LSTM Decoder mit Aufmerksamkeit abgewickelt. Wir modifizieren unser 2019-System (Kovacs et al., 2019) mit einem neuen Grammatik-Induktionsmechanismus, der es ermöglicht, IRTG-Regeln auf Lemmata zusätzlich zu Teilen-der-Sprache-Tags zu arbeiten und sicherstellt, dass jedes Wort und seine Abhängigkeiten mit den spezifischsten erlernten Mustern neu geordnet werden. Wir führen auch einen hierarchischen Ansatz zur Wiederherstellung der Wortreihenfolge ein, der unabhängig die Wortreihenfolge jedes Satzes in einem Satz bestimmt, bevor er sie in Bezug auf den Hauptsatz anordnet, wodurch die allgemeine Lesbarkeit verbessert und auch die IRTG Parsing Task nachvollziehbar gemacht wird. Wir haben an der 2020 Surface Realization Shared Task teilgenommen, subtrack T1a (flach, geschlossen). Human Evaluation zeigt, dass wir signifikante Verbesserungen bei zwei der drei Out-of-Domain-Datensätze im Vergleich zum 2019-System erzielen, das wir modifiziert haben. Beide Komponenten unseres Systems sind auf GitHub unter einer MIT-Lizenz verfügbar.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>문자열과 그래픽 작업 사이에 매핑된 해석 규칙 트리 구문(IRTG)을 만드는 훈련을 통해 복구 어순을 학습하는 일반 종속 구조를 원본 텍스트에 매핑하는 시스템을 제안했습니다.재반사 절차는 표준 시퀀스에서 시퀀스 구조로 처리되며, biLSTM 인코더와 LSTM 디코더가 있습니다.새로운 구문 귀납 메커니즘으로 IRTG 규칙이 단어 표기 외에 인용을 조작할 수 있도록 하고 가장 구체적인 학습 모델을 사용하여 단어와 종속어를 순서재정리할 수 있도록 하는 2019 시스템(Kovacs et al., 2019)을 수정했습니다.문장의 각 자구를 주자구에 비해 배열하기 전에 독자적으로 어순을 확정하여 전체적인 가독성을 높이고 IRTG 분석 임무를 처리하기 쉽도록 하는 층별 방법도 도입했다.우리는 2020년 지상 공유 임무, 하위 궤도 T1a(얕은층, 폐쇄)에 참여했다.인류 평가에 따르면 우리가 수정한 2019 시스템에 비해 우리는 세 개의 역외 데이터가 집중된 두 가지 측면에서 현저한 개선을 얻었다.우리 시스템의 두 구성 요소는 모두 GitHub에서 MIT 라이센스를 받을 수 있습니다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaweza kuweka mfumo wa ramani ya muundo wa kutegemea Uhuru ulimwenguni kote ili kuvunja ujumbe ambao unajifunza kurejesha amri ya maneno kwa kufundisha mti wa mara kwa mara (IRTG) unaoanzisha ramani kati ya mfumo na operesheni za ramani. Hatua ya upya ya utafiti inakabiliwa na ujenzi wa kiwango cha kiwango cha mfululizo wa mfululizo wa mfululizo wa mfululizo wa mfululizo wa mfululizo wa mfululizo wa mfululizo wa mfululizo wa mfululizo na mfumo wa LSTM kwa makini. Tunaweza kubadilisha mfumo wetu wa mwaka 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) na mfumo mpya wa viwanda vya grammani ambao unaruhusu sheria za IRTG kufanya kazi kwa ajili ya lemmata pamoja na sehemu ya viungo vya hotuba na kuhakikisha kwamba kila neno na wategemewa wake huamrishwa upya kwa kutumia seti maalum za kujifunza. We also introduce a hierarchical approach to word order restoration that independently determines the word order of each clause in a sentence before arranging them with respect to the main clause, thereby improving overall readability and also making the IRTG parsing task tractable.  Tumeshiriki katika jukumu la Kusambaza Sura 2020, lililoshiriki T1a (kivumbi, kilifungwa). Utafiti wa binadamu unaonyesha kwamba tunapata maendeleo makubwa juu ya seti mbili za takwimu hizi mbili za nje ya ndani ukilinganishwa na mfumo wa 2019 ambao tulibadilisha. Sehemu mbili za mfumo wetu zinapatikana kwenye GitHub chini ya leseni ya MIT.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_id>We present a system for mapping Universal Dependency structures to raw text which learns to restore word order by training an Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG) that establishes a mapping between string and graph operations.  Langkah refleksi ditangani oleh arsitektur rangkaian-ke-rangkaian standar dengan pengekode biLSTM dan pengekode LSTM dengan perhatian. Kami mengubah sistem 2019 kami (Kovacs et al., 2019) dengan mekanisme induksi gramatika baru yang memungkinkan aturan IRTG untuk beroperasi pada lemma tambahan pada bagian dari tags pidato dan memastikan bahwa setiap kata dan dependensinya diubah dengan menggunakan set yang paling spesifik pola belajar. Kami juga memperkenalkan pendekatan hierarkis untuk pemulihan perintah kata yang secara independen menentukan perintah kata setiap klausul dalam kalimat sebelum mengatur mereka terhadap klausul utama, dengan demikian meningkatkan keseluruhan pembacaan dan juga membuat tugas penghuraian IRTG traktable. Kami berpartisipasi di Surface Realization 2020, tugas berbagi, tolak T1a (rendah, tertutup). Evaluasi manusia menunjukkan kita mencapai peningkatan yang signifikan pada dua dari tiga dataset luar domain dibandingkan dengan sistem 2019 yang kita modifikasikan. Kedua komponen sistem kita tersedia di GitHub di bawah lisensi MIT.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_tr>Biz uniwersal Baýumlylik strukturalary setir metine reňdirmek üçin bir sistemi görkezýäris. Bu sistemi sözleriň düzenini ýagdaýa görkezä öwrenip otyr. Bu sistemi string we grafik operasiýasynyň arasynda reňdirme bilen tanyýar. Tekrar fleksiýa adım biLSTM ködleme we üns berilýän bir LSTM ködleme tarapynda süýtgedilýär. Biz 2019-njy ýyldaky sistemimizi (Kovacs et al., 2019) yeni bir gramatik induksyonun mekanizması ile, IRTG kurallaryna limmatik täglerini bir parça söz etiketlerine eklemek üçin mümkin edip, her söz we bağlı tägleriniň iň takyk öğrenýän şartlaryň ullanyşyny garaşýarys. Biz hem sözleriň ýene-täzeliklerini sözleriň sözleriň sırasyny bir sözleriň ýüzünde düzenlemeden önce bir iýerarhiýa ýalaýyşyny tanyşdyrýarys we şonuň üçin hemme okamak mümkinçiligini gelişdirýän we IRTG a ýdyşyny bejermek üçin bir sözleriň sırasyny bejerip barýarys. 2020-nji ýylyň ýüze Gerçekleşme Paýlaşylyş Taýdaly zada goşuldyk. İnsanyň çykyşyklamasynda, 2019-njy üýtgediğimiz sisteme we 2-nji domain veri setlerinde möhüm gelişmeleri ýetip bilýäris. Sistemimiziň ikisi hem parçalary MIT lisansynda GitHub üçin bar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer et system til kortlægning af Universal Dependency strukturer til rå tekst, som lærer at gendanne ordrækkefølge ved at træne en Tolked Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG), der etablerer en kortlægning mellem streng og grafoperationer. Genflektionstrinet håndteres af en standard sekvens-til-sekvens arkitektur med en biLSTM encoder og en LSTM dekoder med opmærksomhed. Vi ændrer vores 2019-system (Kovacs et al., 2019) med en ny grammatisk induktionsmekanisme, der gør det muligt for IRTG regler at fungere på lemmata ud over del-of-tale tags og sikrer, at hvert ord og dets afhængige er omorrangeret ved hjælp af de mest specifikke sæt af lærte mønstre. Vi indfører også en hierarkisk tilgang til gendannelse af ordrækkefølge, der uafhængigt bestemmer ordrækkefølgen af hver sætning i en sætning, før de arrangeres i forhold til hovedsætningen, hvilket forbedrer den generelle læsbarhed og også gør IRTG parsing opgaven tracable. Vi deltog i 2020 Surface Realization Shared opgave, subtrak T1a (lavvandet, lukket). Menneskelige evalueringer viser, at vi opnår betydelige forbedringer på to af de tre datasæt uden for domænet sammenlignet med det system, vi ændrede i 2019. Begge komponenter i vores system er tilgængelige på GitHub under en MIT licens.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_am>የዓለማዊ ግንኙነት ሥርዓት መክፈቻን ለመቀላቀል እናስቀምጣለን፡፡ አዲስ ማስታወቂያው በቢልSTM የኮድ እና የLSTM ዶዶሴ በጥያቄ ይደረጋል፡፡ በ2019 ስርዓታችንን (Kovacs et al., 2019) እና አዲስ የግራማር ጉዳይ አካባቢ እና IRTG ሥርዓቶችን ከንግግር ማዕከል በቀር ሊሞራ እንዲፈቅድ እና ሁሉንም ቃል እና ደጋፊዎቹ በተለይም የተማሩ ዓይነቶች እንዲጠቀም እንዲያረጋግጡ እናረጋግጣለን፡፡ በዋነኛው ክፍል ላይ ከመስጠት በፊት የሁሉን ክፍል ቃላትን ለብልሃት ማሳየት እናደርጋለን፡፡ በ2020 ፊትር አካባቢነት የተሰራጨውን ስራ፣ T1a (ጥቁር፣ ተዘጋጀን) አጋራጠርን፡፡ Human evaluation shows we achieve significant improvements on two of the three out-of-domain datasets compared to the 2019 system we modified.  የስርዓታችን ሁለቱ ክፍሎች ከ MIT ፍቃዱን በታች በGitHub ላይ ይገኛሉ፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_fa>ما یک سیستم برای نقشه‌سازی ساختارهای بستگی جهانی را به متن خاکستری که با آموزش یک گرم درخت معمولی (IRTG) تغییر دادن یک نقشه‌سازی بین تکه‌ها و عملیات گراف یاد می‌گیریم. قدم تغییر تغییر تغییر تغییر تغییر دادن با یک معماری استاندارد به رده با یک رمز‌دهنده biLSTM و یک رمز‌دهنده LSTM با توجه است. ما سیستم ۲۰۱۹ را تغییر می‌دهیم (Kovacs et al., 2019) با یک مکانیسم فعالیت گرامی جدید که اجازه می‌دهد قانون IRTG روی لیماتای در اضافه به برچسب‌های سخنرانی عمل کند و مطمئن می‌شود که هر کلمه و بستگی‌های آن با استفاده از ترین مجموعه‌ای از الگوهای یادآ ما همچنین یک دستور تدریجی برای بازسازی دستور کلمات را معرفی می کنیم که به طور مستقل سفارش کلمات هر کلمات را در یک جمله تصمیم می گیرد قبل از اینکه آنها را با ارتباط به کلمات اصلی تدریجی کنیم، به وسیله آن، توانایی کلمات پذیرش را بهتر می کنیم و همچنین ردیابی کار IR ما در کار مشترک سطح واقعیت ۲۰۰۲ شرکت کردیم، subtrack T1a (گسترده، بسته). ارزیابی انسان نشان می‌دهد که ما در دو از سه مجموعه داده‌های خارج از دومین در مقایسه با سیستم ما تغییر داده‌ایم، بهترین‌های بزرگی را دریافت می‌کنیم. هر دو قسمت از سیستم ما در GitHub تحت اجازه‌ی MIT دسترسی دارند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_az>Biz üniversal bağımlılıq qurularını çizgi metinə maplama sistemini göstəririk ki, sözlərin sıralamasını öyrənir. İşləndirilən düzgün a ğac Grammar (IRTG) təhsil edir ki, ağac və grafik işləri arasında maplama yaradır. Refleksiyon adımı biLSTM kodlayıcısı və LSTM kodlayıcısı ilə standart sequence-to-sequence arhitektura ilə müdafiə edilir. Biz 2019-ci sistemimizi (Kovacs et al., 2019) yeni bir gramatika induksyon mehānismi ilə dəyişdiririk ki, IRTG kurallarının bir qismi sözlərin etiketlərini və hər sözü və bağımlıqlarının ən müəyyən öyrəndiyi modellərdən istifadə etməsinə imkan verir. Biz həmçin in hər clauzun sözlərinin sıralamasını özgürsüz təsdiqləməsindən əvvəl özlərinə təsdiqləməsindən əvvəl onları ana clauzula qarşı düzəltməkdən əvvəl hiyerarşik tərzini təşkil edirik, bununla bütün oxuyabiləcəyi və IRTG öyrənəcəyi işlər tərzini də daha yaxşılaşdırırıq. Biz 2020 Yüzü Realizasyon paylaşılmış iş, T1a subtrack (çəkilmiş, kapalı) ilə iştirak etdik. İnsan değerlendirməsi göstərir ki, 2019 sistemi ilə dəyişdiyimiz üç dəyişiklik veri qurularından iki dəyişiklik düzəltdi. Sistemimizin iki komponenti MIT lisansının altında GitHub'da faydalanır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_af>Ons voorsien 'n stelsel vir kartering van Universele Afhanklikheid strukture na raai teks wat leer om woord volgorde te herstel deur die onderwerp van 'n Gewone Gewone Boom Grammar (IRTG) wat stel 'n kaart tussen string en graaf operasies. Die reinfleksie stap is behandel deur 'n standaard volgorde-na-sekwensies-arkitektuur met 'n biLSTM-enkoder en 'n LSTM-dekoder met aandag. Ons verander ons 2019 stelsel (Kovacs et al., 2019) met 'n nuwe grammatiese induksie mekanisme wat die IRTG reëls laat toe om op lemmatie te werk, in addition to part-of-speech tags and verseker dat elke woord en sy afhanklikhede herordeniseer word deur die mees spesifieke stel van geleerde patrone. Ons introduseer ook 'n hierarkies toegang tot woord volgorde herstelling wat onveilig die woord volgorde van elke klaus in 'n seting bepaal voordat hulle met betrekking tot die hoof klaus aanstel, daarom verbeter die hele leesbaarde en ook die IRTG verwerking opdragtabel. Ons het deel in die 2020 Surface Realization Gedeelde taak, subtrakk T1a (skaal, gesluit). Die menslike evaluering vertoon dat ons betekende verbeteringe op twee van die drie uit-domein datastelle vergelyk het met die 2019 stelsel wat ons verander het. Beide komponente van ons stelsel is beskikbaar op GitHub onder 'n MIT lisensie.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim një sistem për hartimin e strukturave të Varësisë Universale në tekst të papërpunuar që mëson të rikthejë rendin e fjalëve duke stërvitur një Gramë të Interpretuar të Treve Regular (IRTG) që krijon një hartim midis operacioneve të rreshtave dhe grafikëve. Hapi i reflektimit trajtohet nga një arkitekturë standarte sekuencë-në-sekuencë me një kodues biLSTM dhe një dekoder LSTM me vëmendje. Ne modifikojmë sistemin tonë 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) me një mekanizëm të ri induktimi gramatik që lejon rregullat e IRTG të funksionojnë në limanë përveç etiketave pjesë-të-fjalës dhe siguron që çdo fjalë dhe varësit e saj të riorganizohen duke përdorur grupin më specifik të modeleve të mësuara. Ne gjithashtu futim një qasje hierarkike për restaurimin e rendit të fjalës që përcakton në mënyrë të pavarur rendin e fjalës të çdo klauzule në një fjalë përpara se t'i rregullojmë a to lidhur me klauzulën kryesore, duke përmirësuar kështu lexueshmërinë e përgjithshme dhe duke bërë gjithashtu të trajtueshme detyrën e analizimit të IRTG. Ne morëm pjesë në detyrën e përbashkët të realizimit të sipërfaqes për 2020, duke hequr T1a (të sipërfaqen, të mbyllur). Human evaluation shows we achieve significant improvements on two of the three out-of-domain datasets compared to the 2019 system we modified.  Të dy komponentet e sistemit tonë janë në dispozicion në GitHub nën një licencë MIT.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ের নির্ভরশীল কাঠামোর মানচিত্রের জন্য একটি সিস্টেম উপস্থাপন করি যা টেক্সট ভেঙ্গে ফেলার জন্য বাক্যের আদেশ পুনরুদ্ধার করতে শিখে যাচ্ বাইলস্টিএম এনকোডার এবং একটি এলএসএসএমএস ডিকোডার দ্বারা একটি স্ট্যান্ডারেন্ড সেকেন্ড-থেকে সেকেন্ডারের ক্ষেত্রে পুনরায় বিক আমরা ২০১৯ সিস্টেম পরিবর্তন করি (কোভাক্স এবং আল, ২০১৯) একটি নতুন গ্রামার শিল্প প্রতিষ্ঠানের মাধ্যমে একটি নতুন শিক্ষার্থীর মাধ্যমে আইআরটিজি নিয়মের কাজ করার সুযোগ দিয়েছি এবং ভাষণের ট্ We also introduce a hierarchical approach to word order restoration that independently determines the word order of each clause in a sentence before arranging them with respect to the main clause, thereby improving overall readability and also making the IRTG parsing task tractable.  আমরা ২০২০০ সার্ফেস রিয়ালিজেশন শেয়ার করার কাজে অংশগ্রহণ করেছিলাম, সাবট্র্যাক টি১ (ধূল, বন্ধ)। মানুষের মুল্যায়ন দেখাচ্ছে যে ২০১৯ সিস্টেমের তুলনায় আমরা পরিবর্তন করেছি ২০১৯ সালের তুলনায় তিনটি ডাটাসেটের উপর আমরা গুরুত্ব এমআইটি লাইসেন্সের অধীনে আমাদের সিস্টেমের দুটো অংশ গিটহাবে পাওয়া যাচ্ছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք ներկայացնում ենք համաշխարհային կախվածության կառուցվածքների քարտեզագրման համակարգ, որը սովորում է վերականգնել բառի կարգը՝ վարժեցնելով մեկնաբանված կանոնական ծառի գրամար (ԻՏԳ), որը կառուցնում է լարերի և գծագրի գործողությունների միջև քարտեզագրություն: Հետախուզական քայլը վերահսկվում է ստանդարտ հաջորդականության ճարտարապետության միջոցով, որտեղ ներկայացված է բիLSԹՄ կոդեր և LSԹՄ կոդեր: We modify our 2019 system (Kovacs et al., 2019) with a new grammar induction mechanism that allows IRTG rules to operate on lemmata in addition to part-of-speech tags and ensures that each word and its dependents are reordered using the most specific set of learned patterns.  We also introduce a hierarchical approach to word order restoration that independently determines the word order of each clause in a sentence before arranging them with respect to the main clause, thereby improving overall readability and also making the IRTG parsing task tractable.  We participated in the 2020 Surface Realization Shared task, subtrack T1a (shallow, closed).  Մարդկային գնահատումը ցույց է տալիս, որ մենք հասնում ենք նշանակալի բարելավումներին 2019 թվականին փոխված համակարգի հետ համեմատելով 3-ից դուրս գալիս տեղեկատվական համակարգից երկուսին: Մեր համակարգի երկու բաղադրիչները հասանելի են ԳիթՀուբի վրա MIT-ի արտոնագրության տակ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ca>Presentam un sistema de mapeament estructures de Dependencia Universal a text brut que aprenen a restaurar l'ordre de paraules treinant un grama d'arbre regular interpretat (IRTG) que estableix un mapeament entre les operacions de cadenes i gràfics. El pas de reinflexió està gestionat per una arquitectura de seqüència a seqüència estàndard amb un codificador biLSTM i un codificador LSTM amb atenció. Modifiquem el nostre sistema de 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) amb un nou mecanisme d'inducció gramàtica que permet que les normes IRTG operin en limàtes a més d'etiquetes de part de la xerrada i asseguri que cada paraula i les seves dependents es reordenen utilitzant el conjunt més específic de patrons aprenguts. També introduïm un enfocament jeràrquic a la restauració de l'ordre de paraules que determina de manera independent l'ordre de paraules de cada clàusula en una frase abans d'organitzar-los en relació a la clàusula principal, millorant així la llegibilitat global i també tornant tractable la tasca d'analització IRTG. Vam participar en la tasca compartida de la Realització de la Superfície del 2020, subtraccionant T1a (baix, tancat). L'evaluació humana mostra que aconsegueixem millores significatives en dos dels tres conjunts de dades fora de domini comparats amb el sistema del 2019 que vam modificar. Ambdós components del nostre sistema estan disponibles a GitHub amb una llicència MIT.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo sistem za mapiranje struktura univerzalne zavisnosti na sirov tekst koji nauči da obnovi red riječi obučavajući preglednu regularnu granicu drveta (IRTG) koja utvrđuje mapiranje između operacija žica i grafika. Korak reinflekcije se rješava standardnim arhitekturom sekvence do sekvence sa koderom biLSTM i LSTM dekoderom sa pažnjom. Mi izmijenimo naš sistem 2019. godine (Kovacs et al., 2019) sa novim gramatičkim indukcijskim mehanizam koji omogućava da se IRTG pravila funkcioniše na limeti u dodatnom dijelom govornih etiketa i osigurava da se svaka riječ i njegovi ovisnici ponovno urede koristeći najspecifičniji skup učenih obrazaca. Također predstavljamo hijerarhički pristup restauraciji reda riječi koji neovisno određuje redak riječi svake klauzule u rečenici prije nego što ih sredimo u pogledu glavne klauzule, tako poboljšavajući ukupnu čitljivost i čineći i praćenje zadataka IRTG-a. Učelili smo u zajedničkom zadatku realizacije površine 2020. godine, subtrakt T1a (plitko, zatvoren). Ljudska procjena pokazuje da postignemo značajno poboljšanje na dva od tri podataka izvan domena u usporedbi s sistemom 2019 koji smo modificirali. Obje komponente našeg sistema su dostupne na GitHubu pod MIT dozvolu.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme systém mapování struktur univerzální závislosti na surový text, který se naučí obnovit pořadí slov tréninkem Interpretované gramatiky regulárního stromu (IRTG), která vytváří mapování mezi řetězcovými a grafovými operacemi. Krok reinflekce je řešen standardní architekturou sekvence-sekvence s pozorností snímačem biLSTM a dekodérem LSTM. Upravujeme náš 2019 systém (Kovacs et al., 2019) o nový mechanismus gramatické indukce, který umožňuje pravidla IRTG pracovat na lemmatě kromě značek části řeči a zajišťuje, že každé slovo a jeho závislé slovo budou přeorganizovány pomocí nejspecifickější sady naučených vzorců. Představujeme také hierarchický přístup k obnově slovního pořadí, který nezávisle určuje pořadí slov každé věty před jejich uspořádáním s ohledem na hlavní větu, čímž zlepšuje celkovou čitelnost a zároveň umožňuje trasovat IRTG parsing úlohu. Podíleli jsme se na 2020 Surface Realization Shared Task, subtrack T1a (mělký, uzavřený). Lidské hodnocení ukazuje, že ve srovnání se systémem 2019, který jsme upravili, dosahujeme významných zlepšení u dvou ze tří datových sad mimo doménu. Obě komponenty našeho systému jsou dostupné na GitHubu pod licencí MIT.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Esitleme universaalse sõltuvuse struktuuride kaardistamise süsteemi toortekstile, mis õpib taastama sõnade järjestuse, treenides tõlgendatud regulaarset puugrammatikat (IRTG), mis loob stringi ja graafikutoimingute kaardistamise. Taasinflektsiooni etappi käsitletakse standardse järjestuse-järjestuse arhitektuuriga biLSTM kodeerija ja LSTM dekooderiga tähelepanu pöörates. Muudame oma 2019. aasta süsteemi (Kovacs jt., 2019) uue grammatika induktsioonimehhanismiga, mis võimaldab IRTG reeglitel lisaks kõneosalistele siltidele töötada lemmatal ning tagab, et iga sõna ja selle sõltuvad on ümber järjestatud, kasutades kõige spetsiifilisemaid õppitud mustreid. Lisaks võtame kasutusele hierarhilise lähenemisviisi sõnade järjekorra taastamisele, mis määrab sõnade järjekorra sõltumatult kindlaks iga lause sõnade järjekorra enne nende korraldamist põhiklausli suhtes, parandades seeläbi üldist loetavust ja muutes IRTG parsimise ülesande jälgitavaks. Osalesime 2020. aasta pinnarealiseerimise jagatud ülesandes T1a mahaarvamine (madal, suletud). Inimeste hindamine näitab, et oleme saavutanud märkimisväärseid edusamme kolmest domeenivälisest andmekogumist kahes võrreldes 2019. aasta süsteemiga, mida me muutsime. Mõlemad meie süsteemi komponendid on GitHub saadaval MIT litsentsi all.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esittelemme järjestelmän universaalin riippuvuuden rakenteiden kartoittamiseen raakatekstiin, joka oppii palauttamaan sanajärjestyksen harjoittelemalla tulkattua säännöllistä puun kielioppia (IRTG), joka muodostaa merkkijonon ja graafisen toiminnan välisen kartoituksen. Uudelleenkorjausvaihetta käsitellään standardilla sekvenssi-sekvenssi-arkkitehtuurilla biLSTM-kooderilla ja LSTM-dekooderilla tarkkaavaisesti. Muokkaamme vuoden 2019 järjestelmäämme (Kovacs et al., 2019) uudella kieliopin induktiomekanismilla, jonka avulla IRTG-säännöt voivat toimia lemmatalla puhetunnisteiden lisäksi ja varmistaa, että jokainen sana ja sen riippuvaiset järjestellään uudelleen käyttämällä tarkimpia opittuja kuvioita. Toteutamme myös hierarkkisen lähestymistavan sanajärjestyksen palauttamiseen, joka määrittää itsenäisesti jokaisen lauseen sanajärjestyksen ennen niiden järjestämistä päälauseen nähden, mikä parantaa yleistä luettavuutta ja tekee IRTG-jäsennystehtävästä jäljitettävän. Osallistuimme vuoden 2020 Surface Realization Shared -tehtävään, vähentää T1a (matala, suljettu). Ihmisten arviointi osoittaa, että olemme saaneet aikaan merkittäviä parannuksia kahdessa kolmesta verkkotunnuksen ulkopuolisesta aineistosta verrattuna vuoden 2019 järjestelmään, jota muokkasimme. Järjestelmämme molemmat komponentit ovat saatavilla GitHubissa MIT-lisenssillä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>We present a sistem for maping Universal Dehendehensible structural to red text that Learn to restitura word order by tutorial an interprehensible Regular Grimm (IRT G) that setup a maping amongst string and graphoperasi. Laptop" and "Desktop Awak dhéwé ngerti sistem dhéwé (KoVaVas et al, 2011) lan akeh sistem sing berarti perbudhakan winih kanggo nyelarane kapan pangan nggawe sistem dhéwé (KoVas et al), lan akeh sistem anyar tentang kanggo nyelarane kapan IRT kebutuhan lemmatik dadi batir tanggal gawe lan ujaran winih-uwong sing berarti secara word lan dianggap dhéwé bera Awak dhéwé éntuk sistem sistem akeh perusahaan kanggo awak dhéwé ngerasakno dadi, nik awak dhéwé kuwi kesempatan kanggo ngubah dhéwé Awak dhéwé ngejaraké karo Mbak-Ngerawat '2020 Iwatahan Ngawe gerakan karo Mbak-Ngerawat, Tu1a-Ngerawat (tigeh, tigeh). Human measurement Shows we success of a Signual Progress on 2 of the 3 out-of-domain dataset Sampeyan durung sing dibutuhke sistem sing dibutuhke nang GIthub sanes alih MT.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו מציגים מערכת למפות מבנים של תלויות יוניברסליות לטקסט חומר שמלמד לשחזר את סדר המילים על ידי אימון גרמאר עץ רגיל מתפרש שלב ההשתקפות מתמודד על ידי ארכיטקטורה סטנדרטית רצף-רצף עם קודד biLSTM וקודר LSTM עם תשומת לב. אנו משנים את מערכת 2019 שלנו (Kovacs et al., 2019) עם מנגנון ניתוח גרמטיקה חדש שמאפשר לחוקי IRTG לפעול על לימטה בנוסף לחלק של תגים של דיבור ומבטיחים שכל מילה והתלויות שלה מתארגנים מחדש באמצעות קבוצה ספציפית ביותר של דפוסים ללמודים. אנחנו גם מציגים גישה היררכית לשיקום סדר מילים שמקבלת באופן עצמאי את סדר המילים של כל פסק במשפט לפני שהסדרנו אותם בנוגע לחלק העיקרי, כך משפר את הקריאות הכללית וגם הופך את המשימה של בדיקת IRTG למשוך. השתתפנו במשימה המשותפת של השטח של 2020, למשוך T1a (שטח, סגור). הערכה האנושית מראה שאנחנו משיגים שיפורים משמעותיים בשני משלושת קבוצות נתונים מחוץ לתחום בהשוואה למערכת 2019 ששינינו. שני המרכיבים של המערכת שלנו זמינים על GitHub תחת רישיון MIT.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna gabatar da wani na'ura wa yin ramani da matsayin Kyauta Duniyar Duniani dõmin ya yi raw matsayin da za'a sanar da su sake tsari tsarin magana da za'a yi amfani da wani grammar Tree na Kiɗari da aka Fassar (IRTG) wanda ke daidaita wani map a tsakanin jumla da aikin taskõkin grafyutan. Gago na canza da aka yi amfani da matsayin na'urar-duhun-sequence na ɗabi'a mai biLSSM kode da kuma an kode LSSM da aikin. Tuna gyarar tsarin 2019 (Kozaks et al., 2019) da wata na'urar manunufi na grammar wanda ke yarda da iznin IRTG ya yi aiki a kan limmata, da kuma a ƙara rabo-tagogi na magana kuma za'a tabbatar da kowace kalma da kamfaniyarsa a yi amfani da tsarin tsari masu ƙayyade ƙayyadadde. Kayya, Munã ƙãga wani takwara wa rehabilita kalma da aka canza tsari da magana wanda yana yarda da shi kaɗai na ƙayyade tsarin duk jama'a a cikin birane a gabãnin ka haɗa su da sharuya mai girma, kuma da haka, za'a kyautata karatun duk kuma za'a sami aikin IRTG mai parse. Mun yi shirin da shi a 2020 Surface real Shared job, subtract T1a (shallow, rufated). Ana ƙaddara mutum yana ganin mu sami mafiya ƙari ko biyu daga data-waɗanda ba'a-Domen ba sammenliki da na tsarin 2019 wanda muka gyare. Dukiya na'uranmu biyu ana iya sãmun GitHub da wata lissãfi na MIT.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo sistem za mapiranje struktur univerzalne odvisnosti v surovo besedilo, ki se nauči obnoviti vrstni red besed z usposabljanjem Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG), ki vzpostavlja mapiranje med operacijami nizov in grafov. Korak ponovne reflekcije se obravnava s standardno arhitekturo zaporedja do zaporedja s kodirjem biLSTM in sprejemnikom LSTM s pozornostjo. Naš sistem za leto 2019 (Kovacs et al., 2019) spreminjamo z novim mehanizmom za indukcijo slovnice, ki omogoča, da pravila IRTG delujejo na lemmata poleg oznak dela govora in zagotavlja, da se vsaka beseda in njeni odvisni osebi preuredijo z uporabo najbolj specifičnega nabora učenih vzorcev. Uvedli smo tudi hierarhični pristop k obnovi vrstnega reda besed, ki neodvisno določa vrstni red besed vsakega stavka v stavku, preden ga uredi glede na glavno stavko, s čimer izboljša splošno berljivost in omogoča sledenje opravila IRTG razčlenjanja. Sodelovali smo pri deljeni nalogi uresničevanja površin 2020, odštevanje T1a (plitvo, zaprto). Ocena ljudi kaže, da smo dosegli znatne izboljšave pri dveh od treh zunajdomenskih podatkovnih nizov v primerjavi s sistemom za leto 2019, ki smo ga spremenili. Obe komponenti našega sistema sta na voljo na GitHub pod MIT licenco.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>We present a system for mapping Universal Dependency structures to raw text which learns to restore word order by training an Interpreted Regular Tree Grammar (IRTG) that establishes a mapping between string and graph operations. The reinflection step is handled by a standard sequence-to-sequence architecture with a biLSTM encoder and an LSTM decoder with attention. We modify our 2019 system (Kovacs et al., 2019) with a new grammar induction mechanism that allows IRTG rules to operate on lemmata in addition to part-of-speech tags and ensures that each word and its dependents are reordered using the most specific set of learned patterns. ང་ཚོས་ཀྱང་དབུས་འཛིན་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་འཇུག་སྣོད་ཀྱི་གོ་རིམ་སྟོན་པ་དེ་ལས་རང་བཞིན་གྱིས་ཐ་སྙད་ཀྱི་གོ་རིམ་སྟོན་པའི་ཡིག ང་ཚོས་༢༠༠2020་རིང་གདོང་རིས་ལྕགས་རིམ་དང་མཉམ་སྤྱོད་པའི་བྱ་འགུལ་གྱི་ནང་དུ་མཉམ་དུ་འགྲོ། Human evaluation shows we achieve significant improvements on the two of the three out-of-domain datasets compared to the 2019 system we modified. ང་ཚོའི་མ་ལག་གི་ཆ་ཤས་གཉིས་པོ་གཉིས་ཀྱིས་MIT ཆོག་ཐང་ཐོག་ཏུ་GitHub སྤྱོད་ཐུབ་པ</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>NILC at SR’20 : Exploring Pre-Trained Models in Surface Realisation<fixed-case>NILC</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>SR</fixed-case>’20: Exploring Pre-Trained Models in Surface Realisation</title>
      <author><first>Marco Antonio</first><last>Sobrevilla Cabezudo</last></author>
      <author><first>Thiago</first><last>Pardo</last></author>
      <pages>50–56</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the submission by the NILC Computational Linguistics research group of the University of S ao Paulo / Brazil to the English Track 2 (closed sub-track) at the Surface Realisation Shared Task 2020. The success of the current pre-trained models like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BERT">BERT</a> or GPT-2 in several tasks is well-known, however, this is not the case for data-to-text generation tasks and just recently some initiatives focused on it. This way, we explore how a pre-trained model (GPT-2) performs on the UD-to-text generation task. In general, the achieved results were poor, but there are some interesting ideas to explore. Among the learned lessons we may note that it is necessary to study strategies to represent UD inputs and to introduce structural knowledge into these pre-trained models.</abstract>
      <url hash="0f5f5699">2020.msr-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>sobrevilla-cabezudo-pardo-2020-nilc</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>