<collection id="2020.lr4sshoc">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Workshop about Language Resources for the SSH Cloud</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Daan</first><last>Broeder</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Maria</first><last>Eskevich</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Monica</first><last>Monachini</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-43-6</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="acd8a0bf">2020.lr4sshoc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>lr4sshoc-2020-language</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Mining Wages in Nineteenth-Century Job Advertisements. The Application of Language Resources and Language Technology to study Economic and Social Inequality</title>
      <author><first>Ruben</first><last>Ros</last></author>
      <author><first>Marieke</first><last>van Erp</last></author>
      <author><first>Auke</first><last>Rijpma</last></author>
      <author><first>Richard</first><last>Zijdeman</last></author>
      <pages>27&#8211;32</pages>
      <abstract>For the analysis of historical wage development, no structured data is available. Job advertisements, as found in newspapers can provide insights into what different types of jobs paid, but require language technology to structure in a format conducive to quantitative analysis. In this paper, we report on our experiments to mine wages from 19th century newspaper advertisements and detail the challenges that need to be overcome to perform a socio-economic analysis of textual data sources.</abstract>
      <url hash="2d8db593">2020.lr4sshoc-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>ros-etal-2020-mining</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title><fixed-case>EOSC</fixed-case> as a game-changer in the Social Sciences and Humanities research activities</title>
      <author><first>Donatella</first><last>Castelli</last></author>
      <pages>37&#8211;38</pages>
      <abstract>This paper aims to give some insights on how the European Open Science Cloud (EOSC) will be able to influence the Social Sciences and Humanities (SSH) sector, thus paving the way towards innovation. Points of discussion on how the LRs and RIs community can contribute to the revolution in the practice of research areas are provided.</abstract>
      <url hash="de393bfc">2020.lr4sshoc-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>castelli-2020-eosc</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Crossing the <fixed-case>SSH</fixed-case> Bridge with Interview Data</title>
      <author><first>Henk</first><last>van den Heuvel</last></author>
      <pages>42&#8211;44</pages>
      <abstract>Spoken audio data, such as interview data, is a scientific instrument used by researchers in various disciplines crossing the boundaries of social sciences and humanities. In this paper, we will have a closer look at a portal designed to perform speech-to-text conversion on audio recordings through Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) in the CLARIN infrastructure. Within the cluster cross-domain EU project SSHOC the potential value of such a linguistic tool kit for processing spoken language recording has found uptake in a webinar about the topic, and in a task addressing audio analysis of panel survey data. The objective of this contribution is to show that the processing of interviews as a research instrument has opened up a fascinating and fruitful area of collaboration between Social Sciences and Humanities (SSH).</abstract>
      <url hash="ccb18aa6">2020.lr4sshoc-1.9</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>van-den-heuvel-2020-crossing</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>