<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.wanlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Fifth Arabic Natural Language Processing Workshop</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Imed</first><last>Zitouni</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Muhammad</first><last>Abdul-Mageed</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Houda</first><last>Bouamor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Fethi</first><last>Bougares</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mahmoud</first><last>El-Haj</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nadi</first><last>Tomeh</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Wajdi</first><last>Zaghouani</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="2ae5a718">2020.wanlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>wanlp-2020-arabic</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>A Semi-Supervised BERT Approach for Arabic Named Entity Recognition<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> Approach for <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic Named Entity Recognition</title>
      <author><first>Chadi</first><last>Helwe</last></author>
      <author><first>Ghassan</first><last>Dib</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohsen</first><last>Shamas</last></author>
      <author><first>Shady</first><last>Elbassuoni</last></author>
      <pages>49–57</pages>
      <abstract>Named entity recognition (NER) plays a significant role in many applications such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_extraction">information extraction</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">information retrieval</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Question_answering">question answering</a>, and even <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>. Most of the work on NER using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning</a> was done for non-Arabic languages like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>, and only few studies focused on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic">Arabic</a>. This paper proposes a semi-supervised learning approach to train a BERT-based NER model using labeled and semi-labeled datasets. We compared our approach against various baselines, and state-of-the-art Arabic NER tools on three datasets : AQMAR, NEWS, and TWEETS. We report a significant improvement in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-measure">F-measure</a> for the AQMAR and the NEWS datasets, which are written in Modern Standard Arabic (MSA), and competitive results for the TWEETS dataset, which contains tweets that are mostly in the Egyptian dialect and contain many mistakes or misspellings.</abstract>
      <url hash="1a068e1d">2020.wanlp-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>helwe-etal-2020-semi</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>MANorm : A Normalization Dictionary for Moroccan Arabic Dialect Written in Latin Script<fixed-case>MAN</fixed-case>orm: A Normalization Dictionary for <fixed-case>M</fixed-case>oroccan <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic Dialect Written in <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>atin Script</title>
      <author><first>Randa</first><last>Zarnoufi</last></author>
      <author><first>Hamid</first><last>Jaafar</last></author>
      <author><first>Walid</first><last>Bachri</last></author>
      <author><first>Mounia</first><last>Abik</last></author>
      <pages>155–166</pages>
      <abstract>Social media user generated text is actually the main resource for many NLP tasks. This text, however, does not follow the standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writing_system">rules of writing</a>. Moreover, the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">dialect</a> such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moroccan_Arabic">Moroccan Arabic</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writing">written communications</a> increases further NLP tasks complexity. A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">dialect</a> is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spoken_language">verbal language</a> that does not have a standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthography">orthography</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">written dialect</a> is based on the phonetic transliteration of spoken words which leads users to improvise spelling while writing. Thus, for the same word we can find multiple forms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transliteration">transliterations</a>. Subsequently, it is mandatory to normalize these different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transliteration">transliterations</a> to one canonical word form. To reach this goal, we have exploited the powerfulness of word embedding models generated with a corpus of YouTube comments. Besides, using a Moroccan Arabic dialect dictionary that provides the canonical forms, we have built a normalization dictionary that we refer to as MANorm. We have conducted several experiments to demonstrate the efficiency of MANorm, which have shown its usefulness in dialect normalization. We made MANorm freely available online.</abstract>
      <url hash="223258b3">2020.wanlp-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>zarnoufi-etal-2020-manorm</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>AraWEAT : Multidimensional Analysis of Biases in Arabic Word Embeddings<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>ra<fixed-case>WEAT</fixed-case>: Multidimensional Analysis of Biases in <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic Word Embeddings</title>
      <author><first>Anne</first><last>Lauscher</last></author>
      <author><first>Rafik</first><last>Takieddin</last></author>
      <author><first>Simone Paolo</first><last>Ponzetto</last></author>
      <author><first>Goran</first><last>Glavaš</last></author>
      <pages>192–199</pages>
      <abstract>Recent work has shown that distributional word vector spaces often encode <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">human biases</a> like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexism">sexism</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racism">racism</a>. In this work, we conduct an extensive analysis of biases in Arabic word embeddings by applying a range of recently introduced bias tests on a variety of embedding spaces induced from corpora in Arabic. We measure the presence of biases across several dimensions, namely : embedding models (Skip-Gram, CBOW, and FastText) and vector sizes, types of text (encyclopedic text, and news vs. user-generated content), dialects (Egyptian Arabic vs. Modern Standard Arabic), and time (diachronic analyses over corpora from different time periods). Our analysis yields several interesting findings, e.g., that implicit gender bias in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embedding">embeddings</a> trained on Arabic news corpora steadily increases over time (between 2007 and 2017). We make the Arabic bias specifications (AraWEAT) publicly available.</abstract>
      <url hash="190afe95">2020.wanlp-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>lauscher-etal-2020-araweat</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>Parallel resources for Tunisian Arabic Dialect Translation<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>unisian <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic Dialect Translation</title>
      <author><first>Saméh</first><last>Kchaou</last></author>
      <author><first>Rahma</first><last>Boujelbane</last></author>
      <author><first>Lamia</first><last>Hadrich-Belguith</last></author>
      <pages>200–206</pages>
      <abstract>The difficulty of processing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">dialects</a> is clearly observed in the high cost of building <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">representative corpus</a>, in particular for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>. Indeed, all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation systems</a> require a huge amount and good management of training data, which represents a challenge in a low-resource setting such as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tunisian_Arabic">Tunisian Arabic dialect</a>. In this paper, we present a data augmentation technique to create a parallel corpus for Tunisian Arabic dialect written in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> and standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic">Arabic</a> in order to build a Machine Translation (MT) model. The created <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> was used to build a sentence-based translation model. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> reached a BLEU score of 15.03 % on a test set, while it was limited to 13.27 % utilizing the corpus without augmentation.</abstract>
      <url hash="69de3825">2020.wanlp-1.18</url>
      <bibkey>kchaou-etal-2020-parallel</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Improving Arabic Text Categorization Using Transformer Training Diversification<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic Text Categorization Using Transformer Training Diversification</title>
      <author><first>Shammur Absar</first><last>Chowdhury</last></author>
      <author><first>Ahmed</first><last>Abdelali</last></author>
      <author><first>Kareem</first><last>Darwish</last></author>
      <author><first>Jung</first><last>Soon-Gyo</last></author>
      <author><first>Joni</first><last>Salminen</last></author>
      <author><first>Bernard J.</first><last>Jansen</last></author>
      <pages>226–236</pages>
      <abstract>Automatic categorization of short texts, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Headline">news headlines</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media posts</a>, has many applications ranging from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_analysis">content analysis</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recommender_system">recommendation systems</a>. In this paper, we use such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Categorization">text categorization</a> i.e., labeling the social media posts to categories like ‘sports’, ‘politics’, ‘human-rights’ among others, to showcase the efficacy of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> across different sources and varieties of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic">Arabic</a>. In doing so, we show that diversifying the training data, whether by using diverse training data for the specific task (an increase of 21 % macro F1) or using diverse data to pre-train a BERT model (26 % macro F1), leads to overall improvements in classification effectiveness. In our work, we also introduce two new Arabic text categorization datasets, where the first is composed of social media posts from a popular Arabic news channel that cover <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook">Facebook</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube">YouTube</a>, and the second is composed of tweets from popular Arabic accounts. The posts in the former are nearly exclusively authored in modern standard Arabic (MSA), while the tweets in the latter contain both MSA and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varieties_of_Arabic">dialectal Arabic</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="ab2499d3">2020.wanlp-1.21</url>
      <bibkey>chowdhury-etal-2020-improving-arabic</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/shammur/arabic_news_text_classification_datasets" additional="false">shammur/arabic_news_text_classification_datasets</pwccode>
    <title_ar>تحسين تصنيف النص العربي باستخدام تنويع تدريب المحولات</title_ar>
      <title_es>Mejora de la categorización del texto árabe mediante la diversificación de la formación</title_es>
      <title_pt>Aprimorando a categorização de texto em árabe usando a diversificação de treinamento do Transformer</title_pt>
      <title_ja>変圧器トレーニングの多様化を利用したアラビア文字の分類の改善</title_ja>
      <title_zh>用变压器培训多样化改阿拉伯语文本分</title_zh>
      <title_hi>ट्रांसफॉर्मर प्रशिक्षण विविधीकरण का उपयोग कर अरबी पाठ वर्गीकरण में सुधार</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Feabhas a chur ar Chatag처iri첬 T챕acs Araibis ag 횣s찼id 횋ags첬l첬 Oili첬na Trasfhoirmeora</title_ga>
      <title_ka>აპაბური ტექსტის კატეგორიზაციის უფრო მეტირება</title_ka>
      <title_el>Βελτίωση της κατηγοριοποίησης αραβικού κειμένου χρησιμοποιώντας διαφοροποίηση εκπαίδευσης μετασχηματιστών</title_el>
      <title_hu>Az arab szövegkategorizálás javítása transzformátor képzéssel Diversifikálás segítségével</title_hu>
      <title_it>Migliorare la classificazione del testo arabo utilizzando la diversificazione della formazione dei trasformatori</title_it>
      <title_kk>Араб мәтін санаттарын жақсарту</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Arabų tekstų kategorijos gerinimas naudojant keitiklių mokymo diversifikaciją</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Подобрување на арапската категоризација на текст со користење на диверзификација на трансформската обука</title_mk>
      <title_ml>അറബി പദാവലിയുടെ വിഭാഗവിഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതിനാല്‍ മുന്‍കൂട്ടുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Titjib fil-Kategorizzazzjoni tat-Test Għarbi bl-Użu tad-Diversifikazzjoni tat-Taħriġ tat-Trasferiment</title_mt>
      <title_ms>Menembak Kategori Teks Arab Menggunakan Penyebarkan Latihan Transformer</title_ms>
      <title_mn>Араб Текст Категоризацийг сайжруулах</title_mn>
      <title_ro>Îmbunătățirea categorizării textului arab folosind formarea transformatorului Diversificarea</title_ro>
      <title_pl>Poprawa kategorizacji tekstu arabskiego za pomocą dywersyfikacji szkolenia transformatora</title_pl>
      <title_no>Forbetra arabisk tekstkategorisering ved å bruka diversifikasjon av transformeringstrening</title_no>
      <title_sr>Poboljšanje kategorije arapskog teksta korištenje diverzifikacije obuke transformatora</title_sr>
      <title_si>අරාබික් පාළුව ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශකය ප්‍රවේශකය ප්‍රවේශනය කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Improvement text categorization using isticmaalidda iskuul xirfadeedka</title_so>
      <title_sv>Förbättra kategorisering av arabisk text med hjälp av transformatorutbildning Diversifiering</title_sv>
      <title_ta>முன்னோக்கி பயிற்சி பிரிவிப்பை பயன்படுத்தி அரபி உரை வகைப்படுத்தல் மேம்படுத்தல்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>تغییر ترینس ٹرینینگ ڈائوریزی کے استعمال سے عربی متن کاٹیوریزی</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Comment</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Tăng cường độ phân loại văn bản Ả Rập qua chế biến hình</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Подобряване на категоризацията на арабски текст с помощта на диверсификацията на обучението за трансформатори</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Poboljšanje kategorije arapskog teksta korištenje diverzifikacije obuke transformatora</title_hr>
      <title_da>Forbedring af kategorisering af arabisk tekst ved hjælp af transformatortræning Diversificering</title_da>
      <title_nl>Verbeteren van Arabische tekstcategorisering met behulp van Transformer Training Diversificatie</title_nl>
      <title_ko>Transformer 훈련을 사용하여 아랍어 텍스트 분류 개선</title_ko>
      <title_fa>بهترین ترکیب متن عربی با استفاده از تغییرات آموزش تغییردهنده</title_fa>
      <title_id>Menembak Kategori Teks Arab Menggunakan Diversifikasi Latihan Transformer</title_id>
      <title_de>Verbesserung der Kategorisierung arabischer Texte mithilfe von Transformer Training Diversifizierung</title_de>
      <title_sw>Kuboresha Ubaguzi wa Matambo ya Kiarabu kwa kutumia Utafiti wa Tafsiri wa Kiarabu</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Arapça Metin Kategoriýasyny Taýýarlançy Eweziýetlerni ullan</title_tr>
      <title_af>Verbeter Arabiese Teks Kategoriseering deur te gebruik van Transformeerder Oefening Verskeidiseering</title_af>
      <title_sq>Përmirësimi i kategorizimit arab të tekstit duke përdorur diversifikimin e trajnimit të transformuesve</title_sq>
      <title_am>ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_az>Arap칞a Metin Kategoriyas캼n캼 칖nvan T톛r톛fl톛yici T톛r톛fl톛ndirm톛si</title_az>
      <title_bn>ট্রান্সফেন্ডার প্রশিক্ষণ বিভাগ ব্যবহার করে আরবী টেক্সট বিভাগের উন্নতি</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Արաբական տեքստի կատեգորիզացիայի բարելավումը</title_hy>
      <title_bs>Poboljšanje kategorije arapskog teksta korištenje diverzifikacije obuke transformatora</title_bs>
      <title_ca>millorar la categorització del text àrab utilitzant la diversificació de la formació transformadora</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Zlepšení kategorizace arabského textu pomocí diverzifikace školení transformátoru</title_cs>
      <title_et>Araabia teksti kategooriate parandamine transformaatorite koolituse mitmekesistamise abil</title_et>
      <title_fi>Arabian tekstin luokittelun parantaminen muuntajien koulutuksen monipuolistamisen avulla</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Ngawe ngerti kategorisi arap sing digawe Seneng transformer podho</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Izboljšanje kategorizacije arabskega besedila z uporabo diverzifikacije usposabljanja transformatorjev</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>ཨ་རབ་ཀྱི་ཡི་གེའི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་ལ་ཡར་རྒྱས་གཏོང་བྱེད་བཞིན་པའི་སྣ་ཚོགས་འདྲ་བྱེད་བཞིན་པ</title_bo>
      <title_he>שיפור הקטגוריזציה טקסטית ערבית בשימוש בהתגוות אימון מעבר</title_he>
      <abstract_pt>A categorização automática de textos curtos, como manchetes de notícias e postagens em mídias sociais, tem muitas aplicações que vão desde análise de conteúdo até sistemas de recomendação. Neste artigo, usamos essa categorização de texto, ou seja, rotulando as postagens de mídia social em categorias como 'esportes', 'política', 'direitos humanos', entre outras, para mostrar a eficácia dos modelos em diferentes fontes e variedades de árabe. Ao fazer isso, mostramos que diversificar os dados de treinamento, seja usando diversos dados de treinamento para a tarefa específica (um aumento de 21% macro F1) ou usando diversos dados para pré-treinar um modelo BERT (26% macro F1), leva para melhorias gerais na eficácia da classificação. Em nosso trabalho, também apresentamos dois novos conjuntos de dados de categorização de texto em árabe, onde o primeiro é composto por postagens de mídia social de um canal de notícias árabe popular que cobre Twitter, Facebook e YouTube, e o segundo é composto por tweets de contas árabes populares. As postagens no primeiro são quase exclusivamente de autoria em árabe padrão moderno (MSA), enquanto os tweets no último contêm MSA e árabe dialetal.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>يحتوي التصنيف التلقائي للنصوص القصيرة ، مثل عناوين الأخبار ومنشورات الوسائط الاجتماعية ، على العديد من التطبيقات التي تتراوح من تحليل المحتوى إلى أنظمة التوصية. في هذه الورقة ، نستخدم مثل هذا التصنيف للنصوص ، أي تصنيف منشورات وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي إلى فئات مثل "الرياضة" ، و "السياسة" ، و "حقوق الإنسان" من بين فئات أخرى ، لإبراز فعالية النماذج عبر مصادر وأنواع مختلفة من اللغة العربية. عند القيام بذلك ، نظهر أن تنويع بيانات التدريب ، سواء باستخدام بيانات تدريب متنوعة للمهمة المحددة (زيادة 21٪ ماكرو F1) أو استخدام بيانات متنوعة للتدريب المسبق لنموذج BERT (26٪ ماكرو F1) ، يؤدي للتحسينات الشاملة في فعالية التصنيف. في عملنا ، نقدم أيضًا مجموعتين جديدتين من بيانات تصنيف النص العربي ، حيث تتكون الأولى من منشورات على وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي من قناة إخبارية عربية شهيرة تغطي Twitter و Facebook و YouTube ، وتتكون الثانية من تغريدات من حسابات عربية شهيرة. المنشورات في الأول مكتوبة بشكل حصري تقريبًا باللغة العربية الفصحى الحديثة (MSA) ، بينما تحتوي التغريدات في الأخيرة على كل من الفصحى واللغة العربية اللهجة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>La categorización automática de textos cortos, como titulares de noticias y publicaciones en redes sociales, tiene muchas aplicaciones que van desde el análisis de contenido hasta los sistemas de recomendación. En este artículo, utilizamos esta categorización de textos, es decir, etiquetar las publicaciones en las redes sociales en categorías como «deportes», «política», «derechos humanos», entre otras, para mostrar la eficacia de los modelos en diferentes fuentes y variedades de árabe. Al hacerlo, demostramos que diversificar los datos de entrenamiento, ya sea mediante el uso de datos de entrenamiento diversos para la tarea específica (un aumento del 21% macro F1) o el uso de datos diversos para preentrenar un modelo BERT (26% macro F1), conduce a mejoras generales en la eficacia de la clasificación. En nuestro trabajo, también presentamos dos nuevos conjuntos de datos de categorización de textos en árabe, donde el primero se compone de publicaciones en redes sociales de un popular canal de noticias árabe que cubre Twitter, Facebook y YouTube, y el segundo se compone de tuits de cuentas populares en árabe. Las publicaciones de la primera están escritas casi exclusivamente en árabe estándar moderno (MSA), mientras que los tuits de la segunda contienen tanto MSA como árabe dialectal.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>ニュースの見出しやソーシャルメディアの投稿など、短いテキストの自動分類には、コンテンツ分析から推奨システムまで、多くのアプリケーションがあります。 この論文では、ソーシャルメディアの投稿を「スポーツ」、「政治」、「人権」などのカテゴリにラベル付けして、アラビア語のさまざまなソースや品種にわたるモデルの有効性を紹介するなど、このようなテキスト分類を使用しています。 その際、特定のタスクに多様なトレーニングデータ（マクロF 1が21 ％増加）を使用するか、多様なデータを使用してBERTモデルを事前にトレーニングするか（マクロF 1が26 ％増加）、トレーニングデータを多様化することは、分類の有効性の全体的な改善につながることを示しています。 私たちの仕事では、2つの新しいアラビア語のテキスト分類データセットも紹介します。1つ目は、Twitter、Facebook、YouTubeをカバーする人気のあるアラビア語のニュースチャンネルからのソーシャルメディアの投稿で構成され、2つ目は人気のあるアラビア語アカウントからのツイートで構成されています。 前者の投稿はほぼ現代標準アラビア語（ MSA ）で書かれており、後者のツイートにはMSAと方言アラビア語の両方が含まれています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>छोटे ग्रंथों का स्वचालित वर्गीकरण, जैसे कि समाचार सुर्खियों और सोशल मीडिया पोस्ट, में सामग्री विश्लेषण से लेकर सिफारिश प्रणालियों तक कई अनुप्रयोग हैं। इस पेपर में, हम इस तरह के पाठ वर्गीकरण का उपयोग करते हैं यानी, सोशल मीडिया पोस्ट को 'खेल', 'राजनीति', 'मानवाधिकार' जैसी श्रेणियों में लेबल करना, अरबी के विभिन्न स्रोतों और किस्मों में मॉडल की प्रभावकारिता को प्रदर्शित करने के लिए। ऐसा करने में, हम दिखाते हैं कि प्रशिक्षण डेटा में विविधता लाना, चाहे विशिष्ट कार्य के लिए विविध प्रशिक्षण डेटा का उपयोग करके (21% मैक्रो एफ 1 की वृद्धि) या BERT मॉडल (26% मैक्रो F1) को पूर्व-प्रशिक्षित करने के लिए विविध डेटा का उपयोग करके, वर्गीकरण प्रभावशीलता में समग्र सुधार की ओर जाता है। हमारे काम में, हम दो नए अरबी पाठ वर्गीकरण डेटासेट भी पेश करते हैं, जहां पहला एक लोकप्रिय अरबी समाचार चैनल से सोशल मीडिया पोस्ट से बना है जो ट्विटर, फेसबुक और यूट्यूब को कवर करता है, और दूसरा लोकप्रिय अरबी खातों से ट्वीट्स से बना है। पूर्व में पोस्ट लगभग विशेष रूप से आधुनिक मानक अरबी (एमएसए) में लिखे गए हैं, जबकि उत्तरार्द्ध में ट्वीट्स में एमएसए और बोलचाल की अरबी दोनों शामिल हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>短文本自类,如新闻标题与社交媒体帖,多所应用,从内容分析至荐举系统。 其在本文,用此本分类,即将社交媒体帖标记为"体育","政治","人权"之类,以展异端、百阿拉伯语之有效性。 所以然者,吾明特定之所以异数(宏观F1益21%)异数以预BERT(26%之宏观F1),异数之多样化,皆有分类之有效性。 于我事中,引入二新阿拉伯语文本类数集,其一由流行阿拉伯语新闻频道社交媒体帖成,频道涵盖Twitter,FacebookYouTube,次行阿拉伯语帐户推文。 前帖几尽用现代格阿拉伯语(MSA)所撰,而后者推文则包MSA方言阿拉伯语。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Tá go leor feidhmchlár ag baint le catagóiriú uathoibríoch téacsanna gearra, amhail ceannlínte nuachta agus postálacha meán sóisialta, ó anailís inneachair go córais mholtaí. Sa pháipéar seo, bainimid úsáid as a leithéid de chatagóiriú téacs .i., na postálacha meán sóisialta a lipéadú chuig catagóirí mar `spóirt', `polaitíocht', `cearta an duine' i measc eile, chun éifeachtúlacht na múnlaí a thaispeáint thar fhoinsí agus cineálacha éagsúla Araibis. Agus é sin á dhéanamh againn, léirímid go n-eascraíonn éagsúlú na sonraí oiliúna, cibé acu trí shonraí oiliúna éagsúla a úsáid don tasc sonrach (méadú de 21% macrai F1) nó trí úsáid a bhaint as sonraí éagsúla chun samhail BERT (26% macra F1) a réamh-oiliúint. le feabhsuithe foriomlána ar éifeachtacht aicmithe. Inár gcuid oibre, tugaimid isteach freisin dhá thacar sonraí catagóirithe téacs Araibis nua, ina bhfuil an chéad cheann comhdhéanta de phoist meáin shóisialta ó chainéal nuachta Arabach coitianta a chlúdaíonn Twitter, Facebook, agus YouTube, agus tá an dara ceann comhdhéanta de thweets ó chuntais Araibis tóir. Is in Araibis chaighdeánach nua-aimseartha (MSA) a scríobhtar na poist sa chéad cheann beagnach, agus tá MSA agus Araibis chanúinteach araon sna tweets sa dara ceann.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>მარტივი ტექსტის ავტომატიკური კატეგორიზაცია, როგორც ახალგაზრულები და სოციალური მედია პოსტი, აქვს ბევრი პროგრამები, რომლებიც შემდეგ ანალიზა ამ დომენტში, ჩვენ ასეთი ტექსტის კატეგორიზაციაში გამოყენებთ, მაგალითად, სოციალური მედიაზე კატეგორიზაციაში, როგორც `спорт', `პოლიტიკა', `ადამიანის საზოგადოება', სხვადასხვადასხვადასხვადასხვა ფორ ამის გავაკეთებთ, რომ განსხვავებული მონაცემების განსხვავება, თუ განსხვავებული განსხვავებული მონაცემების გამოყენება განსხვავებული მონაცემებისთვის (21% მაკრო F1) ან განსხვავებული მონაცემების გამოყენება BERT მოდელს (26% მაკრო F1) გავაკ ჩვენი სამუშაოში ჩვენ შევცვალოთ ორი ახალი ტექსტის კატეგორიზაციის მონაცემები, სადაც პირველი სოციალური მედია პოსტუალური აპაბური კანალიდან შექმნა, რომელიც Twitter, Facebook, YouTube და მეორე პოლიპური აპაბური წ მხოლოდ მხოლოდ მსოფლიოდ არაბური (MSA) სტანდარტატური (MSA) სტანდარტატირებულია, მაგრამ მხოლოდ მსოფლიოში შვიტები მუშაობს MSA და ეთალექტური არა</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η αυτόματη κατηγοριοποίηση σύντομων κειμένων, όπως πρωτοσέλιδοι ειδήσεων και δημοσιεύσεις στα μέσα κοινωνικής δικτύωσης, έχει πολλές εφαρμογές που κυμαίνονται από την ανάλυση περιεχομένου έως τα συστήματα συστάσεων. Σε αυτή την εργασία, χρησιμοποιούμε μια τέτοια κατηγοριοποίηση κειμένου, δηλ. την επισήμανση των δημοσιεύσεων στα μέσα κοινωνικής δικτύωσης σε κατηγορίες όπως "αθλητισμός", "πολιτική", "ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα" μεταξύ άλλων, για να επιδείξουμε την αποτελεσματικότητα των μοντέλων σε διαφορετικές πηγές και ποικιλίες αραβικών. Με τον τρόπο αυτό, καταδεικνύουμε ότι η διαφοροποίηση των δεδομένων εκπαίδευσης, είτε με τη χρήση διαφορετικών δεδομένων κατάρτισης για τη συγκεκριμένη εργασία (αύξηση 21% μακροεντολής F1) είτε με τη χρήση διαφορετικών δεδομένων για την προεκπαίδευση ενός μοντέλου BERT (26% μακροεντολής F1), οδηγεί σε γενικές βελτιώσεις στην αποτελεσματικότητα της ταξινόμησης. Στην εργασία μας, εισάγουμε επίσης δύο νέα σύνολα δεδομένων κατηγοριοποίησης αραβικών κειμένων, όπου το πρώτο αποτελείται από δημοσιεύσεις στα μέσα κοινωνικής δικτύωσης από ένα δημοφιλές αραβικό κανάλι ειδήσεων που καλύπτουν το Twitter, το Facebook και το YouTube, και το δεύτερο αποτελείται από tweets από δημοφιλείς αραβικούς λογαριασμούς. Οι δημοσιεύσεις στο πρώτο είναι σχεδόν αποκλειστικά γραμμένες στα σύγχρονα τυπικά αραβικά (MSA), ενώ τα tweets στα τελευταία περιέχουν τόσο MSA όσο και διαλεκτικά αραβικά.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A rövid szövegek automatikus kategorizálása, mint például a hírcímek és a közösségi média bejegyzések, számos alkalmazást tartalmaz, a tartalom elemzésétől az ajánlási rendszerekig. Ebben a tanulmányban ilyen szövegkategorizálást használunk, azaz a közösségi média bejegyzéseket olyan kategóriákra címkézzük, mint például "sport", "politika", "emberi jogok", hogy bemutassuk a modellek hatékonyságát különböző arab forrásokban és fajtákban. Ennek során megmutatjuk, hogy az edzési adatok diverzifikálása – legyen szó különböző edzési adatok felhasználásáról az adott feladatra (21%-os makro F1 növekedésről), vagy különböző adatok felhasználásáról egy BERT modell előkészítésére (26%-os makro F1) vezet az osztályozás hatékonyságának általános javulásához. Munkánkban két új arab szövegkategorizálási adatkészletet is bemutatunk, amelyek közül az első egy népszerű arab hírcsatorna közösségi média bejegyzéseiből áll, amelyek lefedik a Twitteret, a Facebookot és a YouTube-ot, a második pedig népszerű arab fiókok tweetjeit. Az előbbi bejegyzések szinte kizárólag modern szabványos arab nyelven (MSA), míg az utóbbi tweetjei MSA és dialektális arab nyelvet is tartalmaznak.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>La categorizzazione automatica di testi brevi, come titoli di notizie e post sui social media, ha molte applicazioni che vanno dall'analisi dei contenuti ai sistemi di raccomandazione. In questo articolo, utilizziamo tale categorizzazione testuale, cioè etichettando i post sui social media a categorie come `sport', `politica', `diritti umani' tra gli altri, per mostrare l'efficacia dei modelli attraverso diverse fonti e varietà di arabo. In questo modo, mostriamo che diversificare i dati di allenamento, sia utilizzando diversi dati di allenamento per l'attività specifica (un aumento del 21% macro F1) o utilizzando dati diversi per pre-formare un modello BERT (26% macro F1), porta a miglioramenti globali nell'efficacia della classificazione. Nel nostro lavoro, introduciamo anche due nuovi dataset di categorizzazione dei testi arabi, dove il primo è composto da post sui social media provenienti da un popolare canale di notizie arabo che copre Twitter, Facebook e YouTube, e il secondo è composto da tweet provenienti da popolari account arabi. I post nel primo sono quasi esclusivamente scritti in arabo standard moderno (MSA), mentre i tweet nel secondo contengono sia MSA che arabo dialettale.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Қысқа мәтіндердің автоматты түрде, мысалы, жаңалық айдарлар мен социаллық медиа пошталары, мазмұның анализациясынан бастап, рекомендациялау жүйелеріне қарай көптеген Бұл қағазда, біз бұл мәтін санаттарын қолданып, мысалы, әлемдік медиақтардың орналасуын басқалардың араб көзі мен түрлі түрлі түрлерінде «спорт», «саясаты», «адамдар құқықтары» деп аталамыз. Бұл істеу үшін біз оқыту деректерін түрлі түрлі түрлендіруді көрсетедік, нақты тапсырма үшін әртүрлі оқыту деректерін (21% макро F1 көтерілген) немесе BERT моделін (26% макро F1) алдын- ала оқыту үшін әртүрлі деректерді қолдану үші Біздің жұмысамызда сондай-ақ екі жаңа араб мәтін категориясының деректер қорларын таңдаймыз. Біріншісі Твиттер, Фейсбук, YouTube және YouTube тіркелген араб тіркелгілерінен жалғастырылған әлемдік медиақшалардың жа Бұрынғылардың жіберілген пошталары әзірше әзіргі Араб стандартты (MSA) тізімінде орындалады. Соңғылардың tweets - MSA және диалекталық араб тізімінде де орындалады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Automatinis trumpų tekstų, pavyzdžiui, naujienų pavadinimų ir socialinių žiniasklaidos postų, klasifikavimas apima daugelį programų, nuo turinio analizės iki rekomendacijų sistemų. Šiame dokumente naudojame tokią tekstų klasifikaciją, t. y. ženklinant socialinės žiniasklaidos postus tokioms kategorijoms kaip "sportas", "politika", "žmogaus teisės", be kita ko, siekiant parodyti modelių veiksmingumą įvairiuose arabų šaltiniuose ir veislėse. Taigi parodome, kad mokymo duomenų įvairovė naudojant įvairius mokymo duomenis konkrečiai užduotims atlikti (21 proc. padidinus makro F1 skaičių) arba naudojant įvairius duomenis BERT modeliui parengti (26 proc. makro F1 skaičių), lemia bendrą klasifikacijos veiksmingumo gerinimą. Mūsų darbe taip pat pristatome du naujus arabų tekstų kategorijų duomenų rinkinius, kuriuose pirmąjį sudaro socialinių žiniasklaidos postai iš populiaraus arabų žiniasklaidos kanalo, kuris apima Twitter, Facebook ir YouTube, o antrąjį sudaro tweetai iš populiarių arabų sąskaitų. Pirmosios redakcijos biurai beveik išskirtinai rašomi šiuolaikiškai standartine arabų kalba (MSA), o antrosios redakcijos biuruose yra tiek MSA, tiek dialektinė arabų kalba.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Automatic categorization of short texts, such as news headlines and social media posts, has many applications ranging from content analysis to recommendation systems.  Во овој весник, користиме ваква категоризација на текстот, т.е., означувајќи ги постовите на социјалните медиуми на категории како „спорт“, „политика“, „човекови права“ меѓу другите, за да ја покажеме ефикасноста на моделите меѓу различни извори и разнови на арапски јазик. Со тоа покажуваме дека диверзификацијата на податоците за обука, без разлика дали со користење на различни податоци за обука за специфичната задача (зголемување од 21 отсто на макро Ф1) или со користење на различни податоци за преобука на модел BERT (26 отсто макро Ф1), води до целокупни подобрувања во Во нашата работа, исто така, воведуваме два нови набори податоци за категоризација на арапски текст, каде што првиот е составен од постови на социјалните медиуми од популарен арапски новински канал кој покрива Твитер, Фејсбук и Јутјуб, а вториот е составен од твитови од популарни арапски сметки. Постовите во првите се речиси исклучително авторирани на модерниот стандарден арапски (МСА), додека твитовите во вториот содржат и МСА, и дијалектален арапски.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Pengkategorisasi automatik teks pendek, seperti tajuk berita dan pos media sosial, mempunyai banyak aplikasi yang berlainan dari analisis kandungan ke sistem rekomendasi. Dalam kertas ini, kami menggunakan kategorisasi teks seperti ini, iaitu, mengetikkan pos media sosial kepada kategori seperti `sukan', `politik', `hak-manusia' diantara yang lain, untuk menunjukkan kegunaan model melalui sumber dan jenis-jenis Arab yang berbeza. Dalam melakukan itu, kami menunjukkan bahawa pelbagai pelbagai data latihan, sama ada dengan menggunakan data latihan berbeza untuk tugas khusus (meningkatkan 21% makro F1) atau menggunakan data berbeza untuk melatih model BERT (26% makro F1), mengarah kepada peningkatan keseluruhan dalam keefektivitas klasifikasi. Dalam kerja kami, kami juga memperkenalkan dua set data kategorisasi teks bahasa Arab yang baru, di mana yang pertama terdiri dari pos media sosial dari saluran berita Arab terkenal yang meliputi Twitter, Facebook, dan YouTube, dan yang kedua terdiri dari tweet dari akaun Arab terkenal. Posts di sebelumnya hampir hanya ditulis dalam bahasa Arab standar modern (MSA), sementara tweet di sebelumnya mengandungi MSA dan bahasa Arab dialektal.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>വാര്‍ത്ത തലക്കെട്ടുകളും സാമൂഹ്യ മീഡിയ പോസ്റ്റുകളും പോലുള്ള ചെറിയ പദാവലികളുടെ സ്വയം വിഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ In this paper, we use such text categorization i.e., labeling the social media posts to categories like `sports', `politics', `human-rights' among others, to showcase the efficacy of models across different sources and varieties of Arabic.  അങ്ങനെ ചെയ്യുന്നതിനാല്‍, ട്രെയിനിങ്ങളുടെ ഡേറ്റാ വ്യത്യസ്തമാക്കുന്നത്, പ്രത്യേക ജോലിക്കുള്ള വ്യത്യസ്ത പരിശീല വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത്, വ്യത്യസ്ത വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക് ഞങ്ങളുടെ ജോലിയില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ രണ്ടു പുതിയ അറബി വിഭാഗങ്ങളുടെ ഡാറ്റാസറ്റുകള്‍ പരിചയപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു. അവിടെ ആദ്യം സാമൂഹ്യ മെഡിയാ പോസ്റ്റുകള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയിരിക്ക മുമ്പുള്ള പോസ്റ്റുകള്‍ ആധുനിക സാധാരണ അറബിയില്‍ മാത്രം അധികാരത്തിലായിരുന്നു. അവസാനത്തെ ടൂട്ടുകളില്‍ എസ്എസ്എംഎം എ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-kategorizzazzjoni awtomatika ta’ testi qosra, bħall-headlines tal-aħbarijiet u l-postijiet tal-midja soċjali, għandha ħafna applikazzjonijiet li jvarjaw minn analiżi tal-kontenut sa sistemi ta’ rakkomandazzjoni. F'dan id-dokument, aħna nużaw tali kategorizzazzjoni tat-testi jiġifieri, it-tikkettar tal-postijiet tal-midja soċjali għal kategoriji bħall-'isport', 'politika', 'drittijiet tal-bniedem' fost oħrajn, biex juru l-effikaċja tal-mudelli f'sorsi u varjetajiet different i tal-Għarab. Meta nagħmlu dan, naraw li d-diversifikazzjoni tad-dejta tat-taħriġ, kemm jekk bl-użu ta’ dejta ta’ taħriġ diversifikata għall-kompitu speċifiku (żieda ta’ 21% makro F1) jew bl-użu ta’ dejta diversifikata biex jitħarreġ minn qabel mudell BERT (26% makro F1), twassal għal titjib ġenerali fl-effettività tal-klassifikazzjoni. Fil-ħidma tagħna, a ħna nintroduċu wkoll żewġ settijiet ta’ dejta ġodda dwar il-kategorizzazzjoni tat-testi Għarab, fejn l-ewwel wieħed huwa magħmul minn postijiet tal-midja soċjali minn kanal popolari tal-aħbarijiet Għarab li jkopri Twitter, Facebook, u YouTube, u t-tieni wieħed huwa magħmul minn tweets minn kontijiet Għarab popolari. The posts in the former are nearly exclusively authored in modern standard Arabic (MSA), while the tweets in the latter contain both MSA and dialectal Arabic.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Жишээ нь мэдээллийн толгой, нийгмийн мэдээллийн захиралтуудыг автоматтыг хуваалцах нь олон програм байдаг. Энэ цаасанд бид нийгмийн мэдээллийн хувилбаруудыг өөр өөр эх үүсвэр болон төрлийн Араб хэлбэрүүдийн үр дүнг харуулахын тулд, нийгмийн мэдээллийн хувилбаруудыг "спорт", "улс төр", "хүн төрөлхтний эрхийн" хувилбарт ашигладаг. Иймээс бид сургалтын өгөгдлийг өөрчлөх нь тодорхой ажил дээр олон сургалтын өгөгдлийг ашиглан (21% макро F1-ийн нэмэлт) эсвэл BERT загварын өмнө сургалтын тулд олон төрлийн өгөгдлийг ашиглан (26% макро F1) хуваалтын үр дүнд нийтлэг сайжруул Бидний ажлын хувьд мөн бид хоёр шинэ Араб текст категорийн өгөгдлийн сангуудыг танилцуулдаг. Эхнийх нийгмийн мэдээллийн сангууд нь хамгийн алдартай Араб мэдээллийн хуудас Twitter, Facebook, YouTube, хоёр дахь нь алдартай Араб хуудас бий болсон Эхний бичсэн захидал нь ойролцоогоор орчин үеийн Араб стандарт (MSA) дээр зөвхөн зөвхөн зохион байдаг. Эхний бичсэн tweets нь MSA болон диалектик Араб хоёуланг агуулдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Automatisk kategorisering av korte tekstar, slik som nyhetskoptekstar og sosiale mediepost, har mange program som varierer frå innhaldsanalysen til anbefalingssystemar. I denne papiret bruker vi slike tekstkategorisering, t.d. å merke sosiale mediepost til kategoriar som «sport», «politikk», «menneskehøyr» blant andre, for å visa effektiviteten av modeller på ulike kilder og ulike arabiske forskjeller. Ved å gjera det, viser vi at diversifikasjonen av treningsdata, om ved å bruka diverse treningsdata for den spesifikke oppgåva (eit økning av 21% makro F1) eller bruka diverse data for å føretrenga ein BERT- modell (26% makro F1) fører til overalt forbetringar i klassifikasjonsfeilighet. I arbeidet vårt introduserer vi også to nye arabiske tekstkategoriseringsdatasett, der den første er lagt av sosiale media-post frå ein populært arabisk nyhetskanal som dekkar Twitter, Facebook og YouTube, og den andre er lagt av tweets frå populære arabiske kontoar. Postane i tidlegare er nesten eksklusivt autorisert i moderne arabiske (MSA), mens tweetene i dei siste inneheld både MSA og dialektiske arabiske.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Automatyczna kategoryzacja krótkich tekstów, takich jak nagłówki wiadomości i posty w mediach społecznościowych, ma wiele zastosowań, od analizy treści po systemy rekomendacji. W niniejszym artykule wykorzystujemy taką kategoryzację tekstową tj. oznaczanie postów w mediach społecznościowych do kategorii między innymi "sport", "polityka", "prawa człowieka", aby pokazać skuteczność modeli z różnych źródeł i odmian języka arabskiego. W ten sposób pokazujemy, że dywersyfikacja danych treningowych, czy to poprzez wykorzystanie różnorodnych danych treningowych dla konkretnego zadania (wzrost makra 21% F1) czy wykorzystanie różnorodnych danych do wstępnego treningu modelu BERT (makro 26% F1), prowadzi do ogólnej poprawy skuteczności klasyfikacji. W naszej pracy wprowadzamy również dwa nowe arabskie zestawy danych kategoryzacji tekstów, z których pierwszy składa się z postów w mediach społecznościowych popularnego arabskiego kanału informacyjnego obejmującego Twitter, Facebook i YouTube, a drugi składa się z tweetów z popularnych arabskich kont. Posty w pierwszym są prawie wyłącznie autorskie w języku współczesnego standardowego arabskiego (MSA), natomiast tweety w tym drugim zawierają zarówno MSA, jak i dialektalnego arabskiego.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Categorizarea automată a textelor scurte, cum ar fi titlurile de știri și postările pe rețelele de socializare, are multe aplicații, de la analiza conținutului la sistemele de recomandare. În această lucrare, folosim o astfel de categorizare a textelor, adică etichetarea postărilor de pe rețelele de socializare în categorii precum `sport', `politică', `drepturile omului' printre altele, pentru a demonstra eficacitatea modelelor în diferite surse și varietăți de limbă arabă. Astfel, demonstrăm că diversificarea datelor de antrenament, fie prin utilizarea diverselor date de antrenament pentru sarcina specifică (o creștere de 21% macro F1) sau prin utilizarea diverselor date pentru pregătirea unui model BERT (26% macro F1), duce la îmbunătățiri globale în eficiența clasificării. În lucrarea noastră, introducem, de asemenea, două noi seturi de date de categorizare a textelor arabe, în care primul este compus din posturi de socializare de pe un canal popular de știri arabe care acoperă Twitter, Facebook și YouTube, iar al doilea este compus din tweet-uri din conturi arabe populare. Postările din prima sunt aproape exclusiv scrise în arabă standard modernă (MSA), în timp ce tweeturile din ultima conțin atât MSA, cât și arabă dialectală.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Automatska kategorija kratkih tekstova, poput novinskih naslova i postova društvenih medija, ima mnoge aplikacije od analize sadržaja do sustava preporuke. U ovom papiru koristimo takvu kategoriju teksta, tj. označavamo postove društvenih medija u kategorije poput "sporta", "politike", "ljudska prava" među drugima, kako bi pokazali efikasnost modela u različitim izvorima i raznolikovima arapskih. Tako ćemo pokazati da diversifikacija podataka o obuci, da li koristeći različite podatke o obuci za određeni zadatak (povećanje od 21% makro F1) ili koristeći različite podatke za predobuku model BERT (26% makro F1), dovede do ukupnog poboljšanja u klasifikaciji efikasnosti. U našem poslu, predstavljamo i dve nove grupe podataka za kategoriju arapskih tekstova, gde je prvi sastavljen od postova društvenih medija iz popularnog arapskog novinskog kanala koji pokrivaju Twitter, Facebook i YouTube, a drugi se sastavljaju od tweets iz popularnih arapskih računa. Poslovi u bivšem su skoro isključivo autorisani na modernom standardnom arapskom (MSA), dok tweets u poslednjem sadrže i MSA i dijalektno arapsko.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>ස්වයංක්‍රිය පාළුවන්ගේ ස්වයංක්‍රිය පාළුවන් ස්වයංක්‍රිය විශ්ලේෂණය සහ සාමාජික මිඩියාව පොස්ටල්  මේ පත්තරේ අපි අනිත් පත්තර වර්ගයක් භාවිත කරනවා, ඉතින්, සාමාජික මාධ්‍යම පොස්ටල් ලබා කරනවා, `ස්පෝර්ට්', `රාජිකාර', `මිනිස් අයිතිය' වගේ අ එහෙම කරන්න, අපි පෙන්වන්නේ විවිදිහට ප්‍රධාන දත්ත විවිදිහට, විවිදිහට ප්‍රධාන දත්ත භාවිත කරනවා නැත්නම් (21% මැක්රෝ F1 විශේෂයෙන්) නැත්නම් විවිදිහට දත අපේ වැඩේ අපි අළුත් අරාබික් පැත්තක් පණිවිධානය දත්ත සටහන් දෙකක් තියෙනවා, මුලින්ම සාමාජික මාධ්‍යමය පොස්ටල් වල සංවිධානය කරලා තියෙ මුලින්ගේ පොස්ට්ස් තියෙන්නේ අධ්‍යාතික අරාබිකාව (MSA) වලින් ප්‍රතිකාරයෙන් අධ්‍යාත්මක අරාබිකාව (MSA) වලින්, අන්</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Sida bilowga loo qeybiyaayo qoraal gaaban, tusaale ahaan warqadaha warqadda iyo bandhigyada shabakadda bulshada, waxay leedahay codsiyo badan oo ka mid ah baaritaanka wax-taranka iyo nidaamka la talinayo. Qoraalkan waxaynu ku isticmaalnaa kooxaha qoraalka, tusaale ahaan warqadaha bulshada e e kooxaha u qoran sida `jimicsiga', `siyaasada', `xuquuqda', `xuquuqda dadka kale, si aan u muujinno faa’iidada modellada dhinacyada kala duduwan iyo noocyo kala duduwan oo Carabi ah. Markaas waxaynu tusnaa in kala duwanaanshaha macro-waxbarashada, in lagu isticmaalo macro kala duduwan oo shaqo gaar ah (korodha 21% macro F1) ama isticmaalo macro kala duduwan si loo horumariyo model BERT (26% macro F1), wuxuu keenaa horumarinta faa'iidada fasalka. Sidoo kale waxaynu shaqadeenna ku soo bandhignaa laba macluumaad oo cusub ee qoraalka afka Carabiga ah, meesha ugu horeysa waxaa ka kooban warqadaha shabakadda bulshada ah oo ka mid ah kanal warqada Carabi oo maaruf ah oo ku daboola Twitterka, Facebook, iyo YouTube, labaadna waxaa ka mid ah twitter-yo oo ka yimaada akaunta afka caalamiga ah. Warqadaha hore waxaa si gaar ah looga qoray afka Carabiga oo asalka ah (MSA), marka ugu dambeeya tweetka waxaa ku jira MSA iyo afka Carabiga.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Automatisk kategorisering av korta texter, såsom nyhetsrubriker och inlägg i sociala medier, har många applikationer som sträcker sig från innehållsanalys till rekommendationssystem. I denna uppsats använder vi en sådan textkategorisering, dvs. att märka inlägg i sociala medier till kategorier som `sport', `politik', `mänskliga rättigheter' bland andra, för att visa upp effektiviteten av modeller över olika källor och sorter av arabiska. Genom att göra det visar vi att diversifiering av träningsdata, antingen genom att använda olika träningsdata för den specifika uppgiften (en ökning på 21% makro F1) eller genom att använda olika data för att förbereda en BERT-modell (26% makro F1), leder till övergripande förbättringar av klassificeringens effektivitet. I vårt arbete introducerar vi också två nya arabiska textkategoriseringsdata, där den första består av inlägg i sociala medier från en populär arabisk nyhetskanal som täcker Twitter, Facebook och YouTube, och den andra består av tweets från populära arabiska konton. Inläggen i det förra är nästan uteslutande skrivna på modern standard arabiska (MSA), medan tweeten i det senare innehåller både MSA och dialektisk arabiska.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>செய்தி தலைப்புகள் மற்றும் சமூக ஊடக அஞ்சல்கள் போன்ற சிறிய உரைகளின் தன்னியக்கமாக வகுத்தல், பரிந்துரைப்புகள் முறைமைகளில் இருந்து உள In this paper, we use such text categorization i.e., labeling the social media posts to categories like `sports', `politics', `human-rights' among others, to showcase the efficacy of models across different sources and varieties of Arabic.  இதைச் செய்தால், பயிற்சி தரவை வெவ்வேறுபடுத்துவதை காட்டுகிறோம், குறிப்பிட்ட பணிக்கு பல பயிற்சி தகவல்களை பயன்படுத்தினாலும் (21% மாக்ரோ F1 அதிகரிக்க) அல்லது பல தரவுகளை பயன்படுத் எங்கள் வேலையில், நாம் இரண்டு புதிய அரபி உரை வகைப்படுத்தல் தரவுத்தளங்களையும் குறிப்பிடுகிறோம். முதலில் ஒரு பிரபலமான அரபி செய்திகளில் இருந்து சமூகத்தின் பதிவுகள்  முன்னால் உள்ள குறிப்பில் மட்டுமே தற்போதைய நிலையான அரபி மொழியில் ஆசிரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, மற்றும் இறுதியில் இருந்துள்ள twitter</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>چھوٹے ٹیکسٹوں کی آٹوٹی ٹیکٹریزی، جیسے نیویس ہڈلائین اور سوسیال میڈیا پوسٹ، بہت سی کاربرد ہیں جو منزل تحلیل سے توفیق سیستموں تک پہنچ رہے ہیں. اس کاغذ میں ہم ایسی لکھی کاٹی کاٹی کاٹی کا استعمال کرتے ہیں، یعنی سوسیل میڈیا پوسٹ کو ایک دوسرے کے درمیان کاٹیوں پر لکھتے ہیں جیسے "کھیل"، "سیاسی"، "انسان حقوق"، اور ان کے درمیان مختلف سراسروں اور مختلف مختلف عربی کی موجودات کے مطابق دکھ ہم اس طرح دکھاتے ہیں کہ ٹرینگ ڈیٹوں کو مختلف طریقے سے تدریس ڈیٹوں کو دکھاتے ہیں، خواہ مختلف طریقے ٹرینگ ڈیٹوں کو استعمال کرتے ہیں (21% مکرو F1 کی زیادتی) یا مختلف ڈیٹوں کو BERT موڈل (26% مکرو F1) کی پیش ترینس کے لئے استعمال کرتے ہیں۔ ہمارے کام میں ہم نے دو نو عربی ٹیکسٹ کاٹی سیٹ ڈیٹ سٹ پیش کیے ہیں، جہاں پہلی صومعی میڈیا پوسٹ سے ایک محبوب عربی نیویس چانال سے پیدا کیے جاتے ہیں جو ٹویٹر, فیسبوک اور یوٹیوب کو پورا کرتا ہے، اور دوسری جماعت عربی حساب سے ٹویٹ اگلوں کی پوسٹ تقریباً صرف آزمائش عربی (MSA) میں لکھی جاتی ہیں، حالانکہ پچھلوں کی ٹویٹوں میں MSA اور dialectal عربی ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Automatic categorization of short texts, such as news headlines and social media posts, has many applications ranging from content analysis to recommendation systems.  Bu qogʻozda, bu matn turlarini, balki jamiyat media postlarini `sport', `politikk', `human rights' kabi guruhlarga ishlatish mumkin, boshqalarga boshqa manbalar va arabdagi turli modellarning effektini ko'rsatish uchun. Shunday qilib, biz taʼminlovchi maʼlumotni ajratishni ko'rsamiz, xusus vazifaning turli taʼminlov maʼlumotlarini (21% makro F1 yordamida ko'p maʼlumot yordamida yoki BERT modelini oldin foydalanish (26% makro F1) uchun bir necha maʼlumot yordamida ko'proq taʼminlovchi maʼlumotni bajarish natijasida bajariladiga Biz ishimizda, biz ikkita yangi arab matnning kategori tarjimalarini ko'rganamiz. Bu yerda birinchi muammoni arab tarkibidagi jamiyat media postlaridan qo'llangan, Twitter, Facebook, YouTube va ikkinchi marta umuman arab hisoblaridan foydalanadi. Oldingi postlar esa faqat yangi standard arab (MSA) tilida yetarli huquqlar yaratadi, va keyingi xabarlar MSA va dialek arabda mavjud.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tự động phân loại các văn bản ngắn, như các tin nóng và các bài báo truyền thông xã hội, có rất nhiều ứng dụng, từ phân tích nội dung đến các hệ thống đề nghị. Trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi dùng loại văn bản này, ví dụ, đánh dấu các bài đăng truyền thông xã hội cho các loại như'thể thao','chính trị', và'nhân quyền'trong số các loại khác nhau, để trưng bày hiệu quả của các mô hình từ các nguồn khác nhau và các loại của chữ Ả Rập. Trong việc đó, chúng tôi cho thấy sự phân tán dữ liệu đào tạo, bằng cách sử dụng các dữ liệu đào tạo khác nhau cho nhiệm vụ đặc biệt (tăng cường độ mô- 21=-macro F1) hay sử dụng các dữ liệu khác nhau để khởi tạo mô hình thực phẩm thiếu sót sót sót cho mô hình (26=$macro F1) dẫn đến một cải tiến tổng thể về hiệu quả phân loại. Trong công việc của chúng tôi, chúng tôi cũng giới thiệu hai tập tin về phân loại văn bản Á Rập mới, nơi thứ nhất được viết bởi các bài báo mạng xã hội từ một kênh tin tức tiếng Ả Rập nổi tiếng bao gồm Twitter, Facebook, và YouTube, và phần thứ hai là những dòng tweet từ các tài khoản Ả Rập nổi tiếng. The posts in the previous are almost entirely authorsed in modern chuẩn Ả Rập (MSA), and the tweets in the latter included both MSA and phương tiện Ả Rập.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Автоматичното категоризиране на кратки текстове, като заглавия на новини и публикации в социалните медии, има много приложения, вариращи от анализ на съдържанието до системи за препоръки. В тази статия използваме такава текстова категоризация, т.е. етикетиране на публикациите в социалните медии в категории като "спорт", "политика", "човешки права" и др., за да покажем ефективността на моделите в различни източници и разновидности на арабския език. По този начин показваме, че диверсифицирането на данните за обучението, независимо дали чрез използването на разнообразни данни за обучение за конкретната задача (увеличение с 21% макроF1) или използването на разнообразни данни за предварително обучение на модел води до цялостни подобрения в ефективността на класификацията. В нашата работа въвеждаме и два нови набора от данни за категоризация на арабски текстове, като първият е съставен от публикации в социалните медии от популярен арабски новинарски канал, който покрива Туитър, Фейсбук и Ютюб, а вторият е съставен от туитове от популярни арабски акаунти. Публикациите в първите са почти изключително автори на съвременен стандартен арабски (МСА), докато туитовете във втория съдържат както МСА, така и диалектален арабски.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Automatska kategorija kratkih tekstova, poput novinskih naslova i postova društvenih medija, ima mnoge aplikacije od analize sadržaja do sustava preporuke. U ovom papiru koristimo takvu kategoriju teksta, tj. označavamo postove društvenih medija u kategorije poput "sporta", "politike", "ljudska prava" među drugima kako bi pokazali učinkovitost modela u različitim izvorima i raznim raznim arapskim izvorima. Učineći to, pokazujemo da diversifikacija podataka o obuci, da li koristeći različite podatke o obuci za određeni zadatak (povećanje od 21% makro F1) ili koristeći različite podatke za predobuku model BERT (26% makro F1), dovede do ukupnog poboljšanja učinkovitosti klasifikacije. U našem poslu, također predstavljamo dvije nove grupe podataka za kategoriju arapskih tekstova, gdje je prvi sastavljen od postova društvenih medija iz popularnog arapskog novinskog kanala koji pokrivaju Twitter, Facebook i YouTube, a drugi se sastavljaju od tweets iz popularnih arapskih računa. Postavi u bivšem su skoro isključivo ovlašteni na modernom standardnom arapskom (MSA), dok tweets u posljednjem sadrže i MSA i dijalektno arapsko.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Automatisk kategorisering af korte tekster, såsom nyhedsoverskrifter og indlæg på sociale medier, har mange applikationer, der spænder fra indholdsanalyse til anbefalingssystemer. I denne artikel bruger vi en sådan tekstkategorisering, dvs. at mærke indlæggene på sociale medier til kategorier som `sport', `politik', `menneskerettigheder' blandt andre, for at vise effektiviteten af modeller på tværs af forskellige kilder og sorter af arabisk. Ved at gøre dette viser vi, at diversificering af træningsdata, enten ved at bruge forskellige træningsdata til den specifikke opgave (en stigning på 21% makro F1) eller ved at bruge forskellige data til forudtræning af en BERT-model (26% makro F1), fører til generelle forbedringer i klassificeringseffektiviteten. I vores arbejde introducerer vi også to nye arabiske tekst kategorisering datasæt, hvor det første består af sociale medier indlæg fra en populær arabisk nyhedskanal, der dækker Twitter, Facebook og YouTube, og det andet består af tweets fra populære arabiske konti. Indlæggene i førstnævnte er næsten udelukkende forfattet på moderne standard arabisk (MSA), mens tweets i sidstnævnte indeholder både MSA og dialektisk arabisk.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Automatische categorisering van korte teksten, zoals nieuwsberichten en social media posts, heeft veel toepassingen variërend van contentanalyse tot aanbevelingssystemen. In dit artikel gebruiken we een dergelijke tekstcategorisering, d.w.z. het labelen van de social media posts naar categorieën als 'sport', 'politiek', 'mensenrechten' onder andere, om de effectiviteit van modellen in verschillende bronnen en variëteiten van Arabisch te tonen. Hiermee laten we zien dat diversifiëring van de trainingsgegevens, hetzij door gebruik te maken van diverse trainingsgegevens voor de specifieke taak (toename van 21% macro F1) of door gebruik te maken van diverse gegevens om een BERT-model vooraf te trainen (26% macro F1), leidt tot algemene verbeteringen in de effectiviteit van de classificatie. In ons werk introduceren we ook twee nieuwe Arabische tekstcategoriseringsdatasets, waarbij de eerste bestaat uit social media posts van een populair Arabisch nieuwskanaal dat betrekking heeft op Twitter, Facebook en YouTube, en de tweede bestaat uit tweets van populaire Arabische accounts. De berichten in het eerste zijn bijna uitsluitend geschreven in het moderne standaard Arabisch (MSA), terwijl de tweets in het laatste zowel MSA als dialectaal Arabisch bevatten.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Die automatische Kategorisierung von Kurztexten, wie Nachrichtenﾃｼberschriften und Social-Media-Posts, hat viele Anwendungen von der Inhaltsanalyse bis hin zu Empfehlungssystemen. In diesem Beitrag verwenden wir eine solche Textkategorisierung, d.h. die Beschriftung der Social-Media-Beitrﾃ､ge zu Kategorien wie "Sport", "Politik", "Menschenrechte" u.a., um die Wirksamkeit von Modellen ﾃｼber verschiedene Quellen und Varietﾃ､ten des Arabischen zu demonstrieren. Dabei zeigen wir, dass die Diversifizierung der Trainingsdaten, sei es durch die Verwendung diverser Trainingsdaten fﾃｼr die spezifische Aufgabe (Erhﾃｶhung um 21% Makro F1) oder die Verwendung diverser Daten fﾃｼr das Vortraining eines BERT-Modells (26% Makro F1), zu einer allgemeinen Verbesserung der Klassifizierungseffizienz fﾃｼhrt. In unserer Arbeit stellen wir auch zwei neue arabische Textkategorisierungsdatensﾃ､tze vor, bei denen der erste aus Social-Media-Posts eines beliebten arabischen Nachrichtenkanals besteht, der Twitter, Facebook und YouTube abdeckt, und der zweite aus Tweets von populﾃ､ren arabischen Konten. Die Beitrﾃ､ge in ersterem sind fast ausschlieﾃ殕ich in modernem Standardarabisch (MSA) verfasst, wﾃ､hrend die Tweets in letzterem sowohl MSA als auch dialektales Arabisch enthalten.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>تقسیم خودکار از متن‌های کوتاه، مثل عنوان‌های اخبار و پست رسانه‌های اجتماعی، کاربردهای زیادی دارند که از تحلیل محتویات به سیستم‌های توصیف می‌کنند. در این کاغذ، ما از چنین دسته‌های متن استفاده می‌کنیم، یعنی نقطه‌های رسانه‌های اجتماعی به دسته‌هایی مثل «ورزش», «سیاست», «حقوق بشر» بین دیگر، برای نشان دادن اثبات مدل‌ها در منابع مختلف و مختلف عربی. در این صورت، نشان می دهیم که تغییر داده های آموزش، با استفاده از داده های آموزش مختلف برای کار خاص (افزایش 21% ماکرو F1) یا استفاده از داده های مختلف برای پیشآموزش مدل BERT (26% ماکرو F1) باعث می شود که به عمومی تغییرات در فعالیت گروه برقرار شود. در کارمون، ما همچنین دو مجموعه داده‌های جدیدی جدیدی از مجموعه‌های متن عربی را معرفی می‌کنیم، جایی اول از مجموعه‌های رسانه‌های اجتماعی از یک کانال اخبار عربی مشهور ساخته شده است که توئیتر، فیسبوک و یوتیوب را پوشانده می‌شود، و دوم از Posts in the former are almost exclusively authorized in modern Arabic (MSA) while the tweets in the latter contain both MSA and dialectal Arabic.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Kategorisasi otomatis teks pendek, seperti berita utama dan pos media sosial, memiliki banyak aplikasi yang berasal dari analisis isi ke sistem rekomendasi. Dalam kertas ini, kami menggunakan kategorisasi teks seperti ini, yaitu, menandai pos media sosial ke kategori seperti `olahraga', `politik', `hak manusia' diantara yang lain, untuk menunjukkan efektivitas model di berbagai sumber dan varietas Arab. Dalam melakukan itu, kami menunjukkan bahwa diversifikasi data pelatihan, baik dengan menggunakan data pelatihan berbeda untuk tugas spesifik (meningkat 21% makro F1) atau menggunakan data berbeda untuk melatih model BERT (26% makro F1), menyebabkan keseluruhan peningkatan efektivitas klasifikasi. Dalam pekerjaan kami, kami juga memperkenalkan dua set data kategorisasi teks bahasa Arab baru, di mana yang pertama terdiri dari pos media sosial dari saluran berita Arab populer yang menutupi Twitter, Facebook, dan YouTube, dan yang kedua terdiri dari tweet dari rekening Arab populer. Posts di sebelumnya hampir eksklusif ditulis dalam bahasa Arab standar modern (MSA), sementara tweet di sebelumnya mengandung MSA dan bahasa Arab dialektal.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>뉴스 제목과 소셜 미디어 게시물 등 짧은 텍스트를 자동으로 분류하는 데 많은 응용 프로그램이 있는데 내용 분석부터 추천 시스템까지 다양하다.본고에서 우리는 이러한 텍스트 분류를 이용하여 소셜 미디어 게시물을'스포츠','정치','인권'등 유형으로 표시함으로써 서로 다른 출처와 서로 다른 아랍어 버전의 모델의 유효성을 보여준다.이렇게 하는 과정에서 우리는 훈련 데이터를 다양하게 하는 것은 특정 임무를 위해 서로 다른 훈련 데이터(21%의 매크로F1 증가)를 사용하든 서로 다른 데이터를 사용하여 BERT모델을 미리 훈련하는 것(26%의 매크로F1)을 사용하든 분류 유효성을 전체적으로 높일 수 있음을 나타냈다.우리의 업무에서 우리는 두 개의 새로운 아랍어 텍스트 분류 데이터 집합을 도입했다. 그 중에서 첫 번째는 유행하는 아랍어 뉴스 채널(트위터, 페이스북, 유튜브 포함)의 소셜 미디어 게시물로 구성되고, 두 번째는 유행하는 아라비아어 계정의 트위터로 구성된다.전자의 게시물은 거의 완전히 현대 표준 아랍어(MSA)로 작성된 것이고, 후자의 추문은 MSA와 아랍어 사투리를 포함하고 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_tr>Täzelikler we sosial medýdançalaryň ýerleri ýaly gysga metinlerin otomatik kategoriýasyýasy, meslekat analýşinden täze maslahat sistemlerine çenli köp uygulamalar bar. Bu kagyzda, biz şol ýaly metin kategoriýasyny ulanýarys, meselâ, sosyal medialaryň ýerlerini 'sport', 'syýasaty', 'adamlaryň haklary' ýaly kategoriýasyna etiket etmek üçin, nusgalaryň etkinleşigini farklı çe şmelerde we Arapça çeşitliklerde görkezmek üçin. Bu şekilde biz okuwçylyk maglumatyny üýtgetmegimizi görkezýäris, näçe görnüş görevi üçin üýtgeşik maglumatyny üýtgetmek üçin (21% makro F1 üýtgetmek üçin) ýa-da BERT modelini öň-täzeden üýtgetmek üçin dürli maglumaty ulanarak görkezýäris. Biziň işimizde hem iki täze arapça metin kategoriýasynyň daşarylýarys. Ilkinji gezek Twitter, Facebook we YouTube-dan örän meşhur arapça hasaplanýan sosial mediýalaryň poýatlaryny ýazylýar. Öňki sahypalarda modern arabça (MSA) sahypa ýazylýar, soňki tweetlerde hem MSA we dialektal arapça ýazylýar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Kugawanywa kwa uhuru wa maandishi fupi, kama vile vichwa vya habari na makala za mitandao ya kijamii, ina matumizi mengi yanayotoka katika uchambuzi wa maudhui kwenda kwenye mfumo wa mapendekezo. Katika karatasi hii, tunatumia makundi kama haya, kama vile makala za mitandao ya kijamii kwa makundi kama ‘michezo’, ‘siasa’, ‘haki za binadamu’ miongoni mwa wengine, ili kuonyesha ufanisi wa mifano katika vyanzo mbalimbali vya Kiarabu. Kwa kufanya hivyo, tunaonyesha kwamba kubadilishana na takwimu za mafunzo, ikiwa kwa kutumia taarifa mbalimbali za mafunzo kwa kazi maalum (kuongezeka kwa asilimia 21 ya Makro F1) au kwa kutumia taarifa mbalimbali za kupandisha mtindo wa zamani wa BERT (asilimia 26 ya Makro F1), unapelekea kuboresha kwa ujumla katika ufanisi wa kutangaza. Katika kazi yetu, pia tunaanzisha taarifa mbili mpya za makundi ya maandishi ya Kiarabu, ambapo kwanza inajumuisha makala za mitandao ya kijamii kutoka kituo maarufu cha habari cha Kiarabu kinachoandika Twita, Facebook, na YouTube, na pili inajumuisha twiti kutoka akaunti maarufu za Kiarabu. Makala ya zamani yanakaribia kuandikwa kwa kiarabu cha kisasa (MSA), wakati twiti za mwisho zina jumbe za MSA na lugha za Kiarabu.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Outomatiese kategoriseering van kort teks, soos nuuskoplyne en sosiale media-pos, het baie toepassings wat van inhoud analiseer tot aanbevelingsstelsels af vanaf aanbeveling. In hierdie papier gebruik ons sodanige teks kategoriseering, t.d. die sosiale media-pos na kategorie soos 'sport', 'politiek', 'menseregte' onder ander, om die effektiviteit van modele te wys oor verskillende bronne en verskillende Arabske. Om dit te doen, wys ons dat die onderwerp data diversifiseer, of deur verskeie onderwerp data vir die spesifieke taak gebruik word ( 'n vergroot van 21% makro F1) of verskeie data gebruik word om 'n BERT model (26% makro F1) voor te trein, lei na alle verbeteringe in klasifikasie effektief. In ons werk, introduseer ons ook twee nuwe arabiese teks kategoriseeringsdatasete, waar die eerste is van sosiale media-pos geskap van 'n populêre arabiese nuuskanaal wat Twitter, Facebook en YouTube oordek, en die tweede is van tweete van populêre arabiese rekeninge geskap. Die pos in die vorige is byna eksklusief oorgeskryf in moderne standaard Arabiese (MSA), terwyl die tweete in die laaste bevat beide MSA en dialektiese Arabiese.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Kategorizimi automatik i teksteve të shkurtra, të tilla si titujt e lajmeve dhe postimet e medias sociale, ka shumë aplikacione që shkojnë nga analiza e përmbajtjes deri në sistemet rekomandimi. In this paper, we use such text categorization i.e., labeling the social media posts to categories like `sports', `politics', `human-rights' among others, to showcase the efficacy of models across different sources and varieties of Arabic.  Duke bërë këtë, ne tregojmë se diversifikimi i të dhënave të trainimit, qoftë duke përdorur të dhëna të ndryshme të trainimit për detyrën specifike (një rritje prej 21% makro F1) apo duke përdorur të dhëna të ndryshme për të paratrainuar një model BERT (26% makro F1), çon në përmirësime të përgjithshme në efektshmërinë e klasifikimit. Në punën tonë, ne gjithashtu futim dy grupe të dhënash të reja për kategorizimin e tekstit arab, ku e para përbëhet nga postet e medias sociale nga një kanal popullor i lajmeve arabe që mbulon Twitter, Facebook dhe YouTube dhe e dyta përbëhet nga tweetet nga llogaritë popullore arabe. Postat në të mëparshmen janë pothuajse ekskluzivisht të shkruara në gjuhën arabe moderne standard (MSA), ndërsa tweetet në të mëparshmen përmbajnë si MSA ashtu edhe në gjuhën arabe dialektale.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>የዜና አናቶች እና የማኅበራዊ አውታር ድምጾች የቅርጽ ጽሑፎች አካባቢነት፣ የጥቅረት መረጃ እና የመታሰቢያ ስርዓት ሲስተካከል ብዙ ፕሮግራሞች አላቸው፡፡ በዚህ ገጽ፣ እንደዚህ የጽሑፍ ክፍተት፣ ማኅበራዊ ሚዲያዎች የፖለቲካ፣ ‘ፖለቲካ’፣ ‘የሰብዓዊ መብቶች’ በተለያዩ የዐረብኛ ምንጮች እና በተለያዩ ቋንቋዎች ያሉትን ምሳሌዎችን ለማሳየት ነው፡፡ እንደዚሁም እናሳየዋለን የቴርቨርሲቲ ዳታዎችን በመለየት፣ በተለያዩ ስራ (መካሪው የ21% ማክሮ F1) ወይም የBERT ሞዴል (26% ማክሮ F1) በመጠቀም የልዩ ዳታዎችን በመጠቀም በመጠቀም ማሳየትን እናሳየዋለን፡፡ በሥራችን ሁለት አዲስ የዐረብኛ ጽሑፍ አካባቢ ጽሑፎችን አካባቢ ማኅበራዊ አውታር ሚዲያ ጽሑፎች ላይ እናስጠጋለን፤ መጀመሪያው ትዊተር፣ ፌስቡክ እና ዩቱዩብ ከታወቀ አረቢያ አረቢያ አካባቢ ቋንቋ የተደረገ እና ሁለተኛይቱ ትዊተሮችን ትዊተሮች ተካፈለ። የቀድሞው የጦማሪያዎቹ ጽሑፎች በአዲስ ዓረባዊ ዓረባዊ (MSA) ተሟጋቾች ብቻ ናቸው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Կարճ տեքստների, ինչպիսիք են նորությունների գլխարկները և սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցները, ավտոմատիկ դասակարգումը ունի շատ ծրագրեր՝ սկսած պարունակության վերլուծումից մինչև խորհուրդների համակարգերը: Այս թղթի մեջ մենք օգտագործում ենք այնպիսի տեքստի կատեգորիզացիա, այսինքն, սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցների դիրքերը նման կատեգորիաների, ինչպիսիք են «սպորտը», «քաղաքականությունը», «մարդու իրավունքները», մյուսների միջև, ցույց տալու մոդելների արդյունավետությունը արա Այդպես անելով, մենք ցույց ենք տալիս, որ կրթության տվյալների բազմազանությունը, անկախ նրանից, թե օգտագործելով բազմազան կրթության տվյալներ կոնկրետ խնդրի համար (21 տոկոսով աճ մակրո F1), թե օգտագործելով բազմազան տվյալներ BER մոդելի (26 տոկոսով մակրո F1) նախապատ Մեր աշխատանքում մենք ներկայացնում ենք նաև երկու նոր արաբական տեքստի կատեգորիզացիայի տվյալներ, որոնց առաջինը կազմված է սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցներից մի հայտնի արաբական լրատվամիջոցներից, որոնք ծածկում են Թվիթեր, Ֆեյսբուք և YouTube, և երկրորդը կազմված է հանրային արաբա Առաջինում տեղադրված տեղադրությունները գրեթե միայն գրված են ժամանակակից ստանդարտ արաբերենով (MSA), մինչդեռ վերջինում տեղադրված թվիթերը պարունակում են MSA-ն և դիալեկտալ արաբերենը:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>YazńĪlńĪm baŇülńĪqlarńĪ v…ô sosyal media po√ßtalarńĪ kimi qńĪsa m…ôtnl…ôrin avtomatik kategoriyasiyasńĪ, m…ôlumat analizind…ôn t…ôsirl…ôrin…ô q…ôd…ôr √ßox proqramlar vardńĪr. Bu kańüńĪzda, biz bu m…ôtn kategoriyasńĪnńĪ istifad…ô edirik, m…ôs…ôl…ôn, sosyal mediyalarńĪn m…ôtnl…ôrini baŇüqalarńĪnńĪn arasńĪnda "sport", "siyasi", "insan haqlarńĪ" kimi kategoriyalara etiketl…ôndirdik v…ô modell…ôrin etkinlińüini farklńĪ m…ônb…ôl…ôri v…ô …ôr…ôbc…ô m√ľxt…ôlif √ße Ňüitl…ôrd…ô g√∂st…ôr…ôk. Bel…ôlikl…ô, biz t…ôhsil m…ôlumatlarńĪnńĪ m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôhsil etm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôhsil m…ôlumatlarńĪnńĪ (21% makro F1 artńĪrmaq √ľ√ß√ľn) v…ô ya BERT modelini √∂n t…ôhsil etm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn m√ľxt…ôlif m…ôlumatlarńĪ istifad…ô etm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn (26% makro F1) m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôhsil m…ôlumatlarńĪnńĪ m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôhsil m…ôlumatlarńĪnńĪ istifad…ô ed…ôr…ôk g√∂st…ôririk. Bizim iŇüimizd…ô d…ô iki yeni …ôr…ôb m…ôtn kategoriyasiyasńĪ veri setl…ôrini tanńĪdńĪrńĪrńĪq. ńįlki is …ô Twitter, Facebook v…ô YouTube'u √∂rt√ľy…ôn m…ôŇühur …ôr…ôb hesablarńĪndan sosyal media po√ßtalarńĪndan oluŇüur. ∆Źvv…ôlkil…ôrin m…ôktublarńĪ az qala m√ľ…ôyy…ôn …ôr…ôb dilind…ô yazńĪlmńĪŇü halda, sonrakńĪlardakńĪ twetl…ôr d…ô MSA v…ô dialektal …ôr…ôb dilind…ô yazńĪlmńĪŇüdńĪr.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>স্বয়ংক্রিয় টেক্সটের স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে বিভাগ, যেমন সংবাদ শিরোনাম এবং সামাজিক মিডিয়া পোস্ট, অনেক অ্যাপলিকেশন আছে যা বি এই কাগজটিতে আমরা এই ধরনের টেক্সট বিভাগ বিভাগ ব্যবহার করি, যেমন সামাজিক মিডিয়া পোস্টগুলোকে ‘ক্রীড়া’, ‘রাজনীতি’, ‘মানবাধিকার’ বিভিন্ন সূত্র এবং আরবীর বিভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভ এভাবে আমরা দেখাচ্ছি যে প্রশিক্ষণের তথ্য বৈচিত্র্যকরণ করা, বিশেষ কাজের জন্য বিভিন্ন প্রশিক্ষণের তথ্য ব্যবহার করে (২১% ম্যাক্রো এফ১) বা বিভিন্ন তথ্য ব্যবহার করে বিবেরেট আমাদের কাজে আমরা দুটি নতুন আরবী টেক্সট বিভাগের ডাটাটা সংক্রান্ত করেছি, যেখানে প্রথম সামাজিক মিডিয়া পোস্টগুলো তৈরি করা হয়েছে জনপ্রিয় আরবী সংবাদ চ্যানেল থে প্রাক্তন পোস্টের প্রায় শুধুমাত্র আধুনিক স্ট্যান্ডার আরবি (এমএসএ) নামে লেখা প্রায় লেখা হয়েছে, আর পরবর্তী টুইটারের মধ্যে এ</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Automatska kategorija kratkih tekstova, poput naslova novina i postova društvenih medija, ima mnoge aplikacije od analize sadržaja do sustava preporuke. U ovom papiru koristimo takvu kategoriju teksta, tj. označavamo postove društvenih medija u kategorije poput "sporta", "politike", "ljudska prava" među drugima, kako bi pokazali učinkovitost modela u različitim izvorima i raznim raznim arapskim izvorima. Učineći to, pokazujemo da diversifikacija podataka o obuci, da li koristeći različite podatke o obuci za određeni zadatak (povećanje od 21% makro F1) ili koristeći različite podatke za predobuku BERT model (26% makro F1), dovede do ukupnog poboljšanja u učinkovitosti klasifikacije. U našem poslu, također predstavljamo dvije nove grupe podataka za kategoriju arapskih tekstova, gdje je prvi sastavljen od postova socijalnih medija iz popularnog arapskog novinskog kanala koji pokrivaju Twitter, Facebook i YouTube, a drugi se sastavljaju od tweets iz popularnih arapskih računa. Postavi na bivšem su skoro isključivo ovlašteni na modernom standardnom arapskom (MSA), dok tweet u posljednjem sadrži i MSA i dijalektno arapsko.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>La categorització automàtica de textos curts, com els titulars de notícies i publicacions dels mitjans socials, té moltes aplicacions que van des de l'anàlisi del contingut fins als sistemes de recomanació. En aquest article utilitzem aquesta categorització de textos, és a dir, etiquetant les publicacions dels mitjans socials en categories com 'esport', 'política', 'drets humans', entre altres, per mostrar l'eficacia dels models a diverses fonts i varietats d'àrab. En fer-ho, demostram que diversificar les dades de capacitació, tant si utilitzant diverses dades de capacitació per a la tasca específica (un augment del 21% de macro F1) com si utilitzant diverses dades per a preparar un model BERT (26% de macroF1), porta a millores globals en l'eficiència de la classificació. In our work, we also introduce two new Arabic text categorization datasets, where the first is composed of social media posts from a popular Arabic news channel that cover Twitter, Facebook, and YouTube, and the second is composed of tweets from popular Arabic accounts.  Les publicacions de la primera són gairebé exclusivament autoritzades en àrab modern estàndard (MSA), mentre que les tweets d'aquesta última contén tant MSA com àrab dialectal.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Automatická kategorizace krátkých textů, jako jsou titulky zpráv a příspěvky na sociálních médiích, má mnoho aplikací od analýzy obsahu až po systémy doporučení. V tomto článku používáme takovou kategorizaci textů, tj. označení příspěvků na sociálních médiích do kategorií jako například "sport", "politika", "lidská práva", abychom ukázali efektivitu modelů napříč různými zdroji a odrůdami arabštiny. Přitom ukazujeme, že diverzifikace tréninkových dat, ať už použitím různých tréninkových dat pro konkrétní úkol (zvýšení 21% makra F1) nebo použitím různých dat k předtréninku modelu BERT (26% makro F1), vede k celkovému zlepšení efektivity klasifikace. V naší práci také představujeme dva nové datové sady pro kategorizaci arabských textů, kde první je složena z příspěvků na sociálních médiích z populárního arabského zpravodajského kanálu, který pokrývá Twitter, Facebook a YouTube, a druhá je složena z tweetů z populárních arabských účtů. Příspěvky v prvním jsou napsány téměř výhradně v moderní standardní arabštině (MSA), zatímco tweety v druhém obsahují jak MSA, tak dialektální arabštinu.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Lühikeste tekstide automaatne kategoriseerimine, näiteks uudiste pealkirjad ja sotsiaalmeedia postitused, sisaldab palju rakendusi alates sisuanalüüsist kuni soovitussüsteemideni. Käesolevas artiklis kasutame sellist tekstikategooriat ehk sotsiaalmeedia postituste märgistamist kategooriatesse nagu spordi, poliitika ja inimõigused, et näidata mudelite efektiivsust eri araabia allikates ja sortides. Seda tehes näitame, et koolitusandmete mitmekesistamine, kas kasutades erinevaid koolitusandmeid konkreetse ülesande jaoks (21% makro F1 suurenemine) või kasutades erinevaid andmeid BERT mudeli eeltreenimiseks (26% makro F1), toob kaasa klassifitseerimise efektiivsuse üldise paranemise. Oma töös tutvustame ka kahte uut araabia teksti kategooriate andmekogumit, kus esimene koosneb populaarse araabia uudistekanali sotsiaalmeedia postitustest, mis katavad Twitter, Facebook ja YouTube, ning teine koosneb populaarsete araabia kontode säutsudest. Esimese postitused on peaaegu eranditult autorid kaasaegse araabia keeles (MSA), teise säutsud sisaldavad nii MSA kui dialektilist araabia keelt.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Lyhyiden tekstien automaattinen luokittelu, kuten uutisotsikot ja sosiaalisen median viestit, sisältää monia sovelluksia sisällönanalyysistä suositusjärjestelmiin. Tässä artikkelissa käytämme tällaista tekstiluokittelua eli sosiaalisen median julkaisujen merkitsemistä luokkiin, kuten urheilu, `politiikka', `ihmisoikeudet', tuodaksemme esiin mallien tehokkuuden eri lähteissä ja lajikkeissa arabiaa. Tällä tavoin osoitamme, että koulutustietojen monipuolistaminen, joko käyttämällä monipuolisia koulutustietoja tiettyyn tehtävään (21% makro F1) tai käyttämällä monipuolisia tietoja BERT-mallin esikoulutukseen (26% makro F1), johtaa luokituksen tehokkuuteen. Työssämme esitellään myös kaksi uutta arabiankielistä tekstiluokitteluaineistoa, joista ensimmäinen koostuu suositun arabiankielisen uutiskanavan sosiaalisen median viesteistä, jotka kattavat Twitter, Facebook ja YouTube, ja toinen koostuu suosituista arabiankielisistä tileistä. Ensimmäisessä kirjoituksissa kirjoitetaan lähes yksinomaan modernin standardin arabiaksi (MSA), kun taas jälkimmäisessä twiitit sisältävät sekä MSA:ta että dialektista arabiaa.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Menu item Nang peurén iki, kita ngubah kategorisi kanggo teks, dadi, sing ngomong kategori media sothik kanggo kategori sing dikarolan 'olèhku', 'politik', 'hak-perbudhakan' sing wis ngerasakno, iso nggarap akeh model sing ngejaraké mroleh gambaran karo cah samihan karo akeh lan kabèh liyane Ngawe ngilanggar soalé, ingkang dipileksi dadi ngwehendepan ampungan, koyo ngono perusahaan data yang dipileksi kanggo nggawe kesempak nggawe Nang dhéwé éntuk, awak dhéwé nambah data sing gawe kategorise arap sing nganggo, nêkaro kamèh sing bersatu basa media sotiki nang chanal sing popular kanggo awak dhéwé YouTube, Google lan YouTube, lan saiki bersatu bakal kelompok tuytis menyang kontu arap. Ndoleh sing nang sabanjuré, kuwi mesthi kabèh autor tentang karo bentuan arab sing dumadhi (SMA), terus kuwi tuwitan sing dumadhi mrA karo dialectal arab sing sampek.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>categorization farat ɗaya na rubutu masu nau'in rubutu kamar sunayen na lãbãri da posten mita da jamii, yana da wasu shiryoyin ayuka mãsu tsawo daga analyn maɓalli zuwa na'urar shawara. Daga wannan takardan, Munã yin amfani da category-matsayin, misali, makala na mitandai da jamii zuwa categories kamar `idãnun-idãnun', `siyasar', `masu haki', `a cikin wasu mutane, dõmin ya nuna fasalin misalin misalin misalin misalin dukkan sourcen nan dabam na Larabci. Idan za mu aikata haka, za mu nũna wa, yin diffdi da data na tsari, ko da za'a yi amfani da data masu tsari wa aikin ƙayyadadde (ƙaranci wa 21% macro F1) ko kuma Mu yi amfani da wasu data ko da za'a yi amfani da shi ga tunkuɗe misalin BERT (26% macro F1), zai ƙara ƙarami cikin fikarin fasalin. Daga aikinmu, tuna kofi biyu na takarda matsayin littafin Larabci, inda na samu ta farko daga makala na mitanda da jamii daga wani kanal na Larabci wanda ke rufe Twitter, Facebook, da YouTube, kuma na samu ta koma na biyu daga akan arabu. Makala na farko na kusa kawai ana karatun su cikin littafan arabu na taƙaita (M A), kuma a lokacin da wato biyu na ƙarshen su ƙunsa da dukansu masu M A da harshen Larabci.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Avtomatska kategorizacija kratkih besedil, kot so naslovi novic in objave v družbenih omrežjih, ima številne aplikacije, od analize vsebine do sistemov priporočil. V tem prispevku uporabljamo takšno kategorizacijo besedil, tj. označevanje objav v družbenih medijih v kategorije, kot so ‚šport', ‚politika', ‚človekove pravice', med drugim, da bi predstavili učinkovitost modelov v različnih virih in sortah arabščine. S tem pokažemo, da diverzifikacija podatkov o usposabljanju, bodisi z uporabo različnih podatkov o usposabljanju za določeno nalogo (21-odstotno povečanje makro F1) bodisi z uporabo različnih podatkov za predusposabljanje modela BERT (26-odstotno makro F1), vodi do splošnega izboljšanja učinkovitosti klasifikacije. V našem delu predstavljamo tudi dva nova nabora podatkov za kategorizacijo arabskih besedil, kjer je prvi sestavljen iz objav na družbenih omrežjih iz priljubljenega arabskega novičarskega kanala, ki pokriva Twitter, Facebook in YouTube, drugi pa je sestavljen iz tweetov iz priljubljenih arabskih računov. Objave v prvem so skoraj izključno avtorske v sodobni standardni arabščini (MSA), medtem ko tweeti v drugem vsebujejo tako MSA kot narečno arabščino.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>לקטגוריזציה אוטומטית של טקסטים קצרים, כמו כותרי חדשות ופרסומות תקשורת חברתית, יש שימושים רבים שמגיעים מניתוח תוכן למערכות המלצות. In this paper, we use such text categorization i.e., labeling the social media posts to categories like `sports', `politics', `human-rights' among others, to showcase the efficacy of models across different sources and varieties of Arabic.  בכך, אנו מראים שהסיווג של נתוני האימונים, בין אם משתמש בנתונים אימונים מגוונים למשימה המסופרת (גיבוי של 21% מקרו F1) או בשימוש בנתונים מגוונים כדי לאימון מודל BERT (26% מקרו F1), מוביל לשיפורים כלליים ביעילות הסווג. בעבודתנו, אנחנו גם מציגים שני קבוצות נתונים חדשות על הקטגוריזציה טקסטית ערבית, שבהן הראשונה מורכבת משלוחי תקשורת חברתית מערוץ חדשות ערבית פופולרי שכסה את טוויטר, פייסבוק, ויוטוב, ושנייה מורכבת מטוויטרים מחשבונות ערביים פופולריים. The posts in the former are nearly exclusively authored in modern standard Arabic (MSA), while the tweets in the latter contain both MSA and dialectal Arabic.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>རང་འགུལ་གྱིས་ཡི་གེའི་དབྱེ་རིགས་དག་པ། དཔེར་ན་གསར་འགུལ་གྱི་མགོ་ཡིག་དང་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་གནས་ཡུལ་ལ་ཁྱད་པར་ཉེར་ས In this paper, we use such text categorization i.e. labeling the social media posts to categories like `sports', `politics', `human-rights' among others, to show the efficacy of models across different sources and varieties of Arabic. བྱས་ཙང་མིན་འཐབ་ཚུལ་གྱིས་གོ་སྐབས་གཙོ་རིམ་གྱི་གནས་ཚུལ་གསལ་བཀལ་བ་མིན་ན། ང་ཚོའི་ལས་ཀ་ལྟར་ངེད་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་ཨ་རབ་གི་ཡིག་གེ་དབྱེ་བ་གྲངས་ཆ་འཕྲིན་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་གསར་བསྐྲུན་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། The posts in the former are nearly exclusively authored in modern standard Arabic (MSA), while the tweets in the latter contain both MSA and dialectal Arabic.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Team Alexa at NADI Shared Task<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>lexa at <fixed-case>NADI</fixed-case> Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Mutaz</first><last>Younes</last></author>
      <author><first>Nour</first><last>Al-khdour</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammad</first><last>AL-Smadi</last></author>
      <pages>237–242</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we discuss our team’s work on the NADI Shared Task. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> requires classifying Arabic tweets among 21 dialects. We tested out different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">approaches</a>, and the best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One_(pronoun)">one</a> was the simplest one. Our best submission was using Multinational Naive Bayes (MNB) classifier (Small and Hsiao, 1985) with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N-gram">n-grams</a> as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a>. Despite its simplicity, this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> shows better results than complicated <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> such as BERT. Our best submitted score was 17 % <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F1_score">F1-score</a> and 35 % <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="4568a554">2020.wanlp-1.22</url>
      <bibkey>younes-etal-2020-team</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Weighted combination of BERT and N-GRAM features for Nuanced Arabic Dialect Identification<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> and N-<fixed-case>GRAM</fixed-case> features for Nuanced <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic Dialect Identification</title>
      <author><first>Abdellah</first><last>El Mekki</last></author>
      <author><first>Ahmed</first><last>Alami</last></author>
      <author><first>Hamza</first><last>Alami</last></author>
      <author><first>Ahmed</first><last>Khoumsi</last></author>
      <author><first>Ismail</first><last>Berrada</last></author>
      <pages>268–274</pages>
      <abstract>Around the Arab world, different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varieties_of_Arabic">Arabic dialects</a> are spoken by more than 300 M persons, and are increasingly popular in social media texts. However, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varieties_of_Arabic">Arabic dialects</a> are considered to be low-resource languages, limiting the development of machine-learning based systems for these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">dialects</a>. In this paper, we investigate the Arabic dialect identification task, from two perspectives : country-level dialect identification from 21 Arab countries, and province-level dialect identification from 100 provinces. We introduce an unified pipeline of state-of-the-art models, that can handle the two subtasks. Our experimental studies applied to the NADI shared task, show promising results both at the country-level (F1-score of 25.99 %) and the province-level (F1-score of 6.39 %), and thus allow us to be ranked 2nd for the country-level subtask, and 1st in the province-level subtask.</abstract>
      <url hash="519b307c">2020.wanlp-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>el-mekki-etal-2020-weighted</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="29">
      <title>Faheem at NADI shared task : Identifying the dialect of Arabic tweet<fixed-case>NADI</fixed-case> shared task: Identifying the dialect of <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic tweet</title>
      <author><first>Nouf</first><last>AlShenaifi</last></author>
      <author><first>Aqil</first><last>Azmi</last></author>
      <pages>282–287</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes Faheem (adj. of understand), our submission to NADI (Nuanced Arabic Dialect Identification) shared task. With so many <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varieties_of_Arabic">Arabic dialects</a> being under-studied due to the scarcity of the resources, the objective is to identify the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varieties_of_Arabic">Arabic dialect</a> used in the tweet, country wise. We propose a machine learning approach where we utilize word-level n-gram (n = 1 to 3) and tf-idf features and feed them to six different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifiers</a>. We train the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">data set</a> of 21,000 tweetsprovided by the organizerscovering twenty-one Arab countries. Our top performing classifiers are : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_regression">Logistic Regression</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Support_vector_machine">Support Vector Machines</a>, and Multinomial Na ve Bayes.</abstract>
      <url hash="d83329d1">2020.wanlp-1.29</url>
      <bibkey>alshenaifi-azmi-2020-faheem</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="31">
      <title>The QMUL / HRBDT contribution to the NADI Arabic Dialect Identification Shared Task<fixed-case>QMUL</fixed-case>/<fixed-case>HRBDT</fixed-case> contribution to the <fixed-case>NADI</fixed-case> <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rabic Dialect Identification Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Abdulrahman</first><last>Aloraini</last></author>
      <author><first>Massimo</first><last>Poesio</last></author>
      <author><first>Ayman</first><last>Alhelbawy</last></author>
      <pages>295–301</pages>
      <abstract>We present the Arabic dialect identification system that we used for the country-level subtask of the NADI challenge. Our model consists of three components : BiLSTM-CNN, character-level TF-IDF, and topic modeling features. We represent each tweet using these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> and feed them into a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep neural network</a>. We then add an effective <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuristic_(computer_science)">heuristic</a> that improves the overall performance. We achieved an F1-Macro score of 20.77 % and an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of 34.32 % on the test set. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> was also evaluated on the Arabic Online Commentary dataset, achieving results better than the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_of_the_art">state-of-the-art</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="fa2a8391">2020.wanlp-1.31</url>
      <bibkey>aloraini-etal-2020-qmul</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>