<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.smm4h">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Fifth Social Media Mining for Health Applications Workshop &amp; Shared Task</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Graciela</first><last>Gonzalez-Hernandez</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ari Z.</first><last>Klein</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ivan</first><last>Flores</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Davy</first><last>Weissenbacher</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Arjun</first><last>Magge</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Karen</first><last>O'Connor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Abeed</first><last>Sarker</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anne-Lyse</first><last>Minard</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elena</first><last>Tutubalina</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Zulfat</first><last>Miftahutdinov</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ilseyar</first><last>Alimova</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="d0fb857f">2020.smm4h-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>smm4h-2020-social</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Conversation-Aware Filtering of Online Patient Forum Messages</title>
      <author><first>Anne</first><last>Dirkson</last></author>
      <author><first>Suzan</first><last>Verberne</last></author>
      <author><first>Wessel</first><last>Kraaij</last></author>
      <pages>11–18</pages>
      <abstract>Previous approaches to NLP tasks on online patient forums have been limited to single posts as units, thereby neglecting the overarching conversational structure. In this paper we explore the benefit of exploiting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context_(language_use)">conversational context</a> for filtering posts relevant to a specific <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medicine">medical topic</a>. We experiment with two approaches to add conversational context to a BERT model : a sequential CRF layer and manually engineered features. Although neither approach can outperform the F1 score of the BERT baseline, we find that adding a sequential layer improves <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">precision</a> for all target classes whereas adding a non-sequential layer with manually engineered features leads to a higher <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">recall</a> for two out of three target classes. Thus, depending on the end goal, conversation-aware modelling may be beneficial for identifying relevant messages. We hope our findings encourage other researchers in this domain to move beyond studying messages in isolation towards more discourse-based data collection and classification. We release our code for the purpose of follow-up research.</abstract>
      <url hash="dfb0c9ed">2020.smm4h-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>dirkson-etal-2020-conversation</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Overview of the Fifth <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media_mining">Social Media Mining</a> for Health Applications (# SMM4H) Shared Tasks at COLING 2020<fixed-case>SMM</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>) Shared Tasks at <fixed-case>COLING</fixed-case> 2020</title>
      <author><first>Ari</first><last>Klein</last></author>
      <author><first>Ilseyar</first><last>Alimova</last></author>
      <author><first>Ivan</first><last>Flores</last></author>
      <author><first>Arjun</first><last>Magge</last></author>
      <author><first>Zulfat</first><last>Miftahutdinov</last></author>
      <author><first>Anne-Lyse</first><last>Minard</last></author>
      <author><first>Karen</first><last>O’Connor</last></author>
      <author><first>Abeed</first><last>Sarker</last></author>
      <author><first>Elena</first><last>Tutubalina</last></author>
      <author><first>Davy</first><last>Weissenbacher</last></author>
      <author><first>Graciela</first><last>Gonzalez-Hernandez</last></author>
      <pages>27–36</pages>
      <abstract>The vast amount of data on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> presents significant opportunities and challenges for utilizing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_technology">it</a> as a resource for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Health_informatics">health informatics</a>. The fifth iteration of the Social Media Mining for Health Applications (# SMM4H) shared tasks sought to advance the use of Twitter data (tweets) for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pharmacovigilance">pharmacovigilance</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toxicovigilance">toxicovigilance</a>, and epidemiology of birth defects. In addition to re-runs of three tasks, # SMM4H 2020 included new tasks for detecting adverse effects of medications in French and Russian tweets, characterizing chatter related to prescription medication abuse, and detecting self reports of birth defect pregnancy outcomes. The five tasks required methods for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_classification">binary classification</a>, multi-class classification, and named entity recognition (NER). With 29 teams and a total of 130 system submissions, participation in the # SMM4H shared tasks continues to grow.</abstract>
      <url hash="d466597e">2020.smm4h-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>klein-etal-2020-overview</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Ensemble BERT for Classifying Medication-mentioning Tweets<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> for Classifying Medication-mentioning Tweets</title>
      <author><first>Huong</first><last>Dang</last></author>
      <author><first>Kahyun</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Sam</first><last>Henry</last></author>
      <author><first>Özlem</first><last>Uzuner</last></author>
      <pages>37–41</pages>
      <abstract>Twitter is a valuable source of patient-generated data that has been used in various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Population_study">population health studies</a>. The first step in many of these studies is to identify and capture Twitter messages (tweets) containing medication mentions. In this article, we describe our submission to Task 1 of the Social Media Mining for Health Applications (SMM4H) Shared Task 2020. This task challenged participants to detect tweets that mention <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medication">medications</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dietary_supplement">dietary supplements</a> in a natural, highly imbalance dataset. Our system combined a handcrafted preprocessing step with an ensemble of 20 BERT-based classifiers generated by dividing the training dataset into subsets using 10-fold cross validation and exploiting two BERT embedding models. Our system ranked first in this task, and improved the average F1 score across all participating teams by 19.07 % with a precision, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-number">F1</a> on the test set of 83.75 %, 87.01 %, and 85.35 % respectively.</abstract>
      <url hash="9ec7fef8">2020.smm4h-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>dang-etal-2020-ensemble</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/smm4h">SMM4H</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>SMM4H Shared Task 2020-A Hybrid Pipeline for Identifying Prescription Drug Abuse from Twitter : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">Machine Learning</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">Deep Learning</a>, and Post-Processing<fixed-case>SMM</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>H</fixed-case> Shared Task 2020 - A Hybrid Pipeline for Identifying Prescription Drug Abuse from <fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Post-Processing</title>
      <author><first>Isabel</first><last>Metzger</last></author>
      <author><first>Emir Y.</first><last>Haskovic</last></author>
      <author><first>Allison</first><last>Black</last></author>
      <author><first>Whitley M.</first><last>Yi</last></author>
      <author><first>Rajat S.</first><last>Chandra</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark T.</first><last>Rutledge</last></author>
      <author><first>William</first><last>McMahon</last></author>
      <author><first>Yindalon</first><last>Aphinyanaphongs</last></author>
      <pages>57–62</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents our approach to multi-class text categorization of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">tweets</a> mentioning prescription medications as being indicative of potential abuse / misuse (A), consumption / non-abuse (C), mention-only (M), or an unrelated reference (U) using natural language processing techniques. Data augmentation increased our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training and validation corpora</a> from 13,172 tweets to 28,094 tweets. We also created word-embeddings on domain-specific social media and medical corpora. Our hybrid pipeline of an attention-based CNN with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Post-processing">post-processing</a> was the best performing system in task 4 of SMM4H 2020, with an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-number">F1 score</a> of 0.51 for class A.</abstract>
      <url hash="4146f152">2020.smm4h-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>metzger-etal-2020-smm4h</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>How Far Can We Go with Just Out-of-the-box BERT Models?<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> Models?</title>
      <author><first>Lucie</first><last>Gattepaille</last></author>
      <pages>95–100</pages>
      <abstract>Social media have been seen as a promising data source for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pharmacovigilance">pharmacovigilance</a>. Howev-er, methods for automatic extraction of Adverse Drug Reactions from social media plat-forms such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a> still need further development before they can be included reliably in routine pharmacovigilance practices. As the Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformer (BERT) models have shown great performance in many major NLP tasks recently, we decided to test its performance on the SMM4H Shared Tasks 1 to 3, by submitting results of pretrained and fine-tuned BERT models without more added knowledge than the one carried in the training datasets and additional datasets. Our three submissions all ended up above average over all teams’ submissions : 0.766 F1 for task 1 (15 % above the average of 0.665), 0.47 F1 for task 2 (2 % above the average of 0.46) and 0.380 F1 score for task 3 (30 % above the average of 0.292). Used in many of the high-ranking submission in the 2019 edition of the SMM4H Shared Task, BERT contin-ues to be state-of-the-art in ADR extraction for Twitter data.</abstract>
      <url hash="40170bbc">2020.smm4h-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>gattepaille-2020-far</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/smm4h">SMM4H</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>FBK@SMM4H2020 : RoBERTa for Detecting Medications on Twitter<fixed-case>FBK</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>SMM</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>2020: <fixed-case>R</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>a for Detecting Medications on <fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter</title>
      <author><first>Silvia</first><last>Casola</last></author>
      <author><first>Alberto</first><last>Lavelli</last></author>
      <pages>101–103</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes a classifier for tweets that mention medications or supplements, based on a pretrained transformer. We developed such a system for our participation in Subtask 1 of the Social Media Mining for Health Application workshop, which featured an extremely unbalanced dataset. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> showed promising results, with an F1 of 0.8 (task mean : 0.66).</abstract>
      <url hash="72711b9e">2020.smm4h-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>casola-lavelli-2020-fbk</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Autobots Ensemble : Identifying and Extracting Adverse Drug Reaction from Tweets Using Transformer Based Pipelines</title>
      <author><first>Sougata</first><last>Saha</last></author>
      <author><first>Souvik</first><last>Das</last></author>
      <author><first>Prashi</first><last>Khurana</last></author>
      <author><first>Rohini</first><last>Srihari</last></author>
      <pages>104–109</pages>
      <abstract>This paper details a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> designed for Social Media Mining for Health Applications (SMM4H) Shared Task 2020. We specifically describe the systems designed to solve task 2 : Automatic classification of multilingual tweets that report adverse effects, and task 3 : Automatic extraction and normalization of adverse effects in English tweets. Fine tuning RoBERTa large for classifying English tweets enables us to achieve a F1 score of 56 %, which is an increase of +10 % compared to the average F1 score for all the submissions. Using BERT based NER and question answering, we are able to achieve a F1 score of 57.6 % for extracting adverse reaction mentions from tweets, which is an increase of +1.2 % compared to the average F1 score for all the submissions.</abstract>
      <url hash="381beedf">2020.smm4h-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>saha-etal-2020-autobots</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>SpeechTrans@SMM4H’20 : Impact of Preprocessing and N-grams on Automatic Classification of Tweets That Mention Medications<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>peech<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>rans@<fixed-case>SMM</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>’20: Impact of Preprocessing and N-grams on Automatic Classification of Tweets That Mention Medications</title>
      <author><first>Mohamed</first><last>Lichouri</last></author>
      <author><first>Mourad</first><last>Abbas</last></author>
      <pages>118–120</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> developed for automatically classifying tweets that mention medications. We used the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_tree_learning">Decision Tree classifier</a> for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(computing)">task</a>. We have shown that using some elementary preprocessing steps and TF-IDF n-grams led to acceptable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> performance. Indeed, the F1-score recorded was 74.58 % in the development phase and 63.70 % in the test phase.</abstract>
      <url hash="de11e720">2020.smm4h-1.19</url>
      <bibkey>lichouri-abbas-2020-speechtrans</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Want to Identify, Extract and Normalize Adverse Drug Reactions in Tweets? Use RoBERTa<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>a</title>
      <author><first>Katikapalli Subramanyam</first><last>Kalyan</last></author>
      <author><first>Sivanesan</first><last>Sangeetha</last></author>
      <pages>121–124</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents our approach for task 2 and task 3 of Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 shared tasks. In task 2, we have to differentiate adverse drug reaction (ADR) tweets from nonADR tweets and is treated as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_classification">binary classification</a>. Task 3 involves extracting ADR mentions and then mapping them to MedDRA codes. Extracting ADR mentions is treated as sequence labeling and normalizing ADR mentions is treated as multi-class classification. Our system is based on pre-trained language model RoBERTa and it achieves a) F1-score of 58 % in task 2 which is 12 % more than the average score b) relaxed F1-score of 70.1 % in ADR extraction of task 3 which is 13.7 % more than the average score and relaxed F1-score of 35 % in ADR extraction + normalization of task 3 which is 5.8 % more than the average score. Overall, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> achieve promising results in both the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a> with significant improvements over average scores.</abstract>
      <url hash="d62e8cc7">2020.smm4h-1.20</url>
      <bibkey>kalyan-sangeetha-2020-want</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/smm4h">SMM4H</pwcdataset>
    <title_es>¿Quiere identificar, extraer y normalizar las reacciones adversas a los medicamentos en los tuits? Usar RoBerta</title_es>
      <title_hi>Tweets में प्रतिकूल दवा प्रतिक्रियाओं की पहचान, निकालें और सामान्य करना चाहते हैं? RoBERTa का उपयोग करें</title_hi>
      <title_ar>هل تريد تحديد التفاعلات الضارة مع الأدوية واستخراجها وتطبيعها في التغريدات؟ استخدم RoBERTa</title_ar>
      <title_zh>欲知取法推文中药不良反应? 用罗伯塔</title_zh>
      <title_pt>Quer identificar, extrair e normalizar reações adversas a medicamentos em tweets? Usar RoBERTa</title_pt>
      <title_ja>ツイートで薬物の有害反応を特定し、抽出し、正常化したいですか？ RoBERTaを使用してください</title_ja>
      <title_ga>Ar mhaith leat Frithghníomhartha díobhálacha Drugaí in Tweetanna a Aithint, a Bhaint agus a Normalú? Úsáid RoBERTa</title_ga>
      <title_el>Θέλετε να εντοπίσετε, να εξαγάγετε και να κανονικοποιήσετε τις ανεπιθύμητες αντιδράσεις φαρμάκων στα tweets; Χρήση RoBERTa</title_el>
      <title_hu>Szeretné azonosítani, kivonni és normalizálni a mellékhatásokat Tweetekben? A RoBERTa alkalmazása</title_hu>
      <title_kk>Твиттерде қарсы наркот реакцияларын анықтау, тарқату және нормализациялау керек пе? RoBERTa қолданылсын</title_kk>
      <title_it>Vuoi identificare, estrarre e normalizzare le reazioni avverse alla droga nei tweet? Usa RoBERTa</title_it>
      <title_lt>Ar norite nustatyti, ištraukti ir normalizuoti nepageidaujamas vaisto reakcijas Tweetuose? Vartoti RoBERTa</title_lt>
      <title_ka>გსურთ იდენტიფიკაცია, ექსტრაქტირება და ნორმალიზაცია შესაძლებელი პროგრამების რეაქციაში? RoBERTa- ს გამოყენება</title_ka>
      <title_ms>Ingin Mengenalpasti, Ekstrak dan Normalkan Reaksi Darah dadah dalam Tweet? Guna RoBERTa</title_ms>
      <title_mk>Want to Identify, Extract and Normalize Adverse Drug Reactions in Tweets?  Користи RoBERTa</title_mk>
      <title_no>Vil du identifisera, pakka ut og normalisera motsetjingar i Tweets? Bruk RoBERTa</title_no>
      <title_mn>Твитт дээр эсрэг нарийн урвалыг тайлбарлах, татаж, нормализах уу? RoBERTa хэрэглэх</title_mn>
      <title_ro>Doriți să identificați, extrageți și normalizați reacțiile adverse la medicamente în Tweets? Utilizați RoBERTa</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Želite li identifikovati, izvaditi i normalizirati nuspojavne reakcije droge u Tweets-u? Koristi RoBERTa</title_sr>
      <title_ml>ടൂട്ടുകളില്‍ മയക്കുമരുന്നുള്ള പ്രതികരണങ്ങള്‍ തിരിച്ചറിയാന്‍, പുറത്താക്കി നോര്‍മാലിസ് ചെയ്യണമോ? റോബെര്‍ട്ട ഉപയോഗിക്കുക</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Tixtieq tidentifika, Estratta u Normalizza Reazzjonijiet Avversi tal-Mediċina fit-Tweets? Uża RoBERTa</title_mt>
      <title_si>ට්විට්ස් වල ප්‍රතික්‍රියාව අඳිශ්නය, නික්‍රියාත්මක සහ සාමාන්‍යය කරන්න ඕනද? RoBERTa භාවිතා කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_sv>Vill du identifiera, extrahera och normalisera biverkningar i Tweets? Använd RoBERTa</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Want to Identify, Extract and Normalize Adverse Drug Reactions in Tweets?  RoBERTAயை பயன்படுத்து</title_ta>
      <title_pl>Chcesz zidentyfikować, wyciągnąć i normalizować działania niepożądane w tweetach? Użyj RoBERTa</title_pl>
      <title_so>Ma rabtid in aad Tweet ka aqoonsato, soo saaro iyo Normalize jawaabayaasha dawooyinka? Isticmaal RoBERta</title_so>
      <title_ur>کیا ٹویٹوں میں مخالف ڈراگ رکنٹیوں کو پہچان کرنا، نکالنا اور عامل کرنا چاہتے ہیں؟ روبرٹا استعمال کریں</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Có muốn xác định phản ứng phản ứng phản ứng phản ứng phản ứng đỏ trong Tweet không? Dùng RoBERTa</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Twitterda davom etishni aniqlashni istaysizmi, olib tashlashni istaysizmi? RoBERTAdan foydalanish</title_uz>
      <title_hr>Želite li identificirati, izvući i normalizirati nuspojavne reakcije droge u Tweets-u? Koristi RoBERTa</title_hr>
      <title_da>Vil du identificere, udtrække og normalisere bivirkninger i Tweets? Brug RoBERTa</title_da>
      <title_nl>Wil je bijwerkingen in Tweets identificeren, extraheren en normaliseren? RoBERTa gebruiken</title_nl>
      <title_ko>추문에서 약물의 불량 반응을 식별하고 추출하며 규범화하고 싶습니까?로베르타 사용하기</title_ko>
      <title_bg>Искате ли да идентифицирате, извлечете и нормализирате нежеланите лекарствени реакции в Туитс? Използване на RoBERTa</title_bg>
      <title_sw>Je, unataka kutambua, kutengeneza na kuzuia maoni yanayotokea madawa katika twita? Tumia RoBERTa</title_sw>
      <title_de>Möchten Sie unerwünschte Arzneimittelwirkungen in Tweets identifizieren, extrahieren und normalisieren? RoBERTa verwenden</title_de>
      <title_id>Want to Identify, Extract and Normalize Adverse Drug Reactions in Tweets?  Use RoBERTa</title_id>
      <title_sq>Want to Identify, Extract and Normalize Adverse Drug Reactions in Tweets?  Use RoBERTa</title_sq>
      <title_fa>می‌خواهید واکنش‌های مخالف مواد توئیت‌ها را شناسایی، خارج و عامل کنید؟ استفاده از RoBERTa</title_fa>
      <title_hy>Want to Identify, Extract and Normalize Adverse Drug Reactions in Tweets?  Օգտագործել</title_hy>
      <title_az>Tweets i√ßind…ô t…ôdbir uyuŇüturucu reaksiyonlarńĪnńĪ tanńĪtmaq, √ßńĪxartmaq v…ô normal etm…ôk ist…ôyirsiniz? RoBERTa qullan</title_az>
      <title_tr>Tweets içinde naçan narkotik reaksiyonlary tanap, açmak we düzenlemek isleýärmi? RoBERTa ullan</title_tr>
      <title_bn>Want to Identify, Extract and Normalize Adverse Drug Reactions in Tweets?  RoBERTA ব্যবহার করো</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Want to Identify, Extract and Normalize Adverse Drug Reactions in Tweets?  Use RoBERTa</title_ca>
      <title_af>Wil jy identifiseer, uitpak en Normaliseer Adverse Drugsreaksies in Tweets? Gebruik RoBERTa</title_af>
      <title_cs>Chcete identifikovat, extrahovat a normalizovat nežádoucí léčivé účinky ve tweetech? Použít RoBERTa</title_cs>
      <title_am>በTweet መግለጫ፣ ማውጣት እና ማውጣት ይፈልጋሉ? RoBERTAን ተጠቀም</title_am>
      <title_fi>Haluatko tunnistaa, purkaa ja normalisoida haittavaikutukset Tweets? Käytä RoBERTaa</title_fi>
      <title_bs>Želite li identificirati, izvući i normalizirati nuspojavne reakcije droge u Tweets-u? Koristi RoBERTa</title_bs>
      <title_et>Soovite tuvastada, ekstraheerida ja normaliseerida kõrvaltoimeid Tweets? RoBERTa kasutamine</title_et>
      <title_jv>Opo kowe gelem menehi, dibujuhi lan njujuhi Keterarangke Nari Rasane Nang Tuwit ? Ngawe RBERT</title_jv>
      <title_ha>Yana son ka gane, ka fita kuma ka ƙayyade Ciki-Madaidaici na Kwamfyuta? Yi amfani da RoBERTA</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Želite prepoznati, izvleči in normalizirati neželene učinke zdravil v Tweets? Uporabi RoBERTa</title_sk>
      <title_he>רוצה לזהות, להוציא ולנורמליז תגובות תרופות לא רצויות בטוויטים? השתמש ברוברטה</title_he>
      <title_bo>Tweets་ནང་དུ་འཕགས་རིས་མཐུན་བཟོ་བྱེད་མི་འདུག་གམ RoBERTa སྤྱོད་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_es>Este documento presenta nuestro enfoque para las tareas 2 y 3 de las tareas compartidas de Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020. En la tarea 2, tenemos que diferenciar los tuits de reacciones adversas a medicamentos (ADR) de los tuits que no son ADR y se trata como clasificación binaria. La tarea 3 consiste en extraer menciones de ADR y luego asignarlas a los códigos de MedDRA. La extracción de menciones de ADR se trata como un marcaje de secuencia y la normalización de las menciones de ADR se trata como Nuestro sistema se basa en el modelo lingüístico RoBerta previamente entrenado y logra a) una puntuación F1 del 58% en la tarea 2, que es un 12% más que la puntuación media b) una puntuación F1 relajada del 70,1% en la extracción ADR de la tarea 3, que es un 13,7% más que la puntuación media y una puntuación F1 relajada del 35% en la extracción ADR + normalización de la tarea 3, lo que supone un 5,8% más que la puntuación media. En general, nuestros modelos logran resultados prometedores en ambas tareas con mejoras significativas con respecto a los puntajes promedio.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ar>تقدم هذه الورقة نهجنا للمهمة 2 والمهمة 3 الخاصة بالتعدين على وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي من أجل الصحة (SMM4H) 2020 المهام المشتركة. في المهمة 2 ، يتعين علينا التفريق بين تغريدات التفاعلات العكسية للأدوية (ADR) والتغريدات التي لا تحتوي على نتائج (nonADR) ويتم التعامل معها على أنها تصنيف ثنائي. تتضمن المهمة 3 استخراج إشارات ADR ثم تعيينها إلى رموز MedDRA. يتم التعامل مع استخلاص إشارات ADR على أنها تصنيف تسلسل ويتم التعامل مع تسوية إشارات ADR على أنها تصنيف متعدد الفئات. يعتمد نظامنا على نموذج اللغة RoBERTa الذي تم تدريبه مسبقًا ويحقق أ) درجة F1 بنسبة 58٪ في المهمة 2 والتي تزيد بنسبة 12٪ عن متوسط الدرجة ب) درجة F1 المريحة بنسبة 70.1٪ في استخلاص ADR للمهمة 3 والتي هي 13.7٪ أكثر من متوسط الدرجات ودرجة F1 المخففة بنسبة 35٪ في استخراج ADR + تطبيع المهمة 3 وهو 5.8٪ أكثر من متوسط الدرجة. بشكل عام ، تحقق نماذجنا نتائج واعدة في كلتا المهمتين مع تحسينات كبيرة على متوسط الدرجات.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo apresenta nossa abordagem para as tarefas 2 e 3 das tarefas compartilhadas de Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020. Na tarefa 2, temos que diferenciar tweets de reação adversa a medicamentos (RAM) de tweets sem RAM e é tratado como classificação binária. A tarefa 3 envolve extrair menções de ADR e depois mapeá-las para códigos MedDRA. A extração de menções de ADR é tratada como rotulagem de sequência e a normalização de menções de ADR é tratada como classificação multiclasse. Nosso sistema é baseado no modelo de linguagem pré-treinado RoBERTa e atinge a) F1-score de 58% na tarefa 2, que é 12% a mais que a pontuação média b) F1-score relaxado de 70,1% na extração de ADR da tarefa 3, que é 13,7% a mais que a pontuação média e F1-score relaxado de 35% na extração de RAM + normalização da tarefa 3 que é 5,8% a mais que a pontuação média. No geral, nossos modelos alcançam resultados promissores em ambas as tarefas com melhorias significativas em relação às pontuações médias.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、2020年のソーシャルメディアマイニング・フォー・ヘルス（ SMM 4 H ）の共有タスクのタスク2とタスク3に対する当社のアプローチを紹介します。タスク2では、有害薬物反応（ ADR ）ツイートを非ADRツイートと区別する必要があり、バイナリ分類として扱われます。タスク3では、ADRの言及を抽出し、それをMedDRAコードにマッピングします。ADR言及の抽出は配列標識として扱われ、ADR言及の正規化はマルチクラス分類として扱われる。私たちのシステムは、事前にトレーニングされた言語モデルRoBERTaに基づいており、a ）タスク2のF 1スコアは、平均スコアよりも12 ％高い58 ％、b ）タスク3のADR抽出の緩和されたF 1スコアは、平均スコアよりも13.7 ％高い70.1 ％、ADR抽出の緩和されたF 1スコアは、平均スコアよりも5.8 ％高い35 ％+タスク3の正規化を達成します。全体として、当社のモデルは、平均スコアよりも大幅に改善された両方のタスクで有望な結果を達成します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>本文言吾法,施于2020年社交媒体康发掘(SMM4H)共享其任2与任3。 务2之中,必别药物不良反应(ADR)推文非ADR推文,视为二元。 任 3 及取 ADR ,然后射于 MedDRA 代码。 提ADR提及为序标记,归一化ADR提及为多类。 臣等之统,先训之RoBERTa,其成a)务2中F1分为58%,高于均分12% b)于任3者ADR取中放F1分为70.1%,高于均分13.7%,于ADR取中放F1分为35%+务3之标准化,高于均分数5.8%。 总体而言,吾两务皆有所欲,而显于均分矣。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर स्वास्थ्य के लिए सोशल मीडिया माइनिंग (SMM4H) 2020 साझा कार्यों के कार्य 2 और कार्य 3 के लिए हमारे दृष्टिकोण को प्रस्तुत करता है। कार्य 2 में, हमें गैर-एडीआर ट्वीट्स से प्रतिकूल दवा प्रतिक्रिया (एडीआर) ट्वीट्स को अलग करना होगा और इसे बाइनरी वर्गीकरण के रूप में माना जाता है। कार्य 3 में एडीआर का उल्लेख निकालना और फिर उन्हें मेडड्रा कोड में मैप करना शामिल है। एडीआर उल्लेखों को निकालने को अनुक्रम लेबलिंग के रूप में माना जाता है और एडीआर उल्लेखों को सामान्य करने को बहु-वर्ग वर्गीकरण के रूप में माना जाता है। हमारी प्रणाली पूर्व प्रशिक्षित भाषा मॉडल RoBERTa पर आधारित है और यह एक) कार्य 2 में 58% का F1-स्कोर प्राप्त करता है जो औसत स्कोर से 12% अधिक है b) कार्य 3 के एडीआर निष्कर्षण में 70.1% का आराम से F1-स्कोर जो औसत स्कोर से 13.7% अधिक है और एडीआर निष्कर्षण में 35% का आराम से F1-स्कोर + कार्य 3 का सामान्यीकरण जो औसत स्कोर से 5.8% अधिक है। कुल मिलाकर, हमारे मॉडल औसत स्कोर पर महत्वपूर्ण सुधार के साथ दोनों कार्यों में आशाजनक परिणाम प्राप्त करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cuireann an páipéar seo i láthair ár gcur chuige do thasc 2 agus tasc 3 de thascanna comhroinnte Mianadóireacht ar na Meáin Shóisialta le haghaidh Sláinte (SMM4H) 2020. I dtasc 2, ní mór dúinn tvuíteanna frithghníomhartha díobhálacha drugaí (ADR) a idirdhealú ó thíogaireachtaí nonADR agus láimhseáiltear é mar aicmiú dénártha. Baineann Tasc 3 le tagairtí ADR a bhaint amach agus ansin iad a mhapáil chuig cóid MedDRA. Déileáiltear le hasbhaint tagairtí ADR mar lipéadú seichimh agus caitear le normalú tagairtí ADR mar aicmiú ilaicme. Tá ár gcóras bunaithe ar mhúnla teanga réamh-oilte RoBERTa agus éiríonn leis a) scór F1 de 58% i dtasc 2 atá 12% níos mó ná an meánscór b) scór F1 réchúiseach de 70.1% in eastóscadh ADR de thasc 3 a 13.7% níos mó ná an meánscór agus scór F1 réchúiseach de 35% in eastóscadh ADR + normalú thasc 3 atá 5.8% níos mó ná an meánscór. Tríd is tríd, baineann ár múnlaí torthaí dóchais amach sa dá thasc agus feabhsuithe suntasacha thar na meánscóir.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დოკუმენტი ჩვენი მოხმარება სოციალური მედიახის გარეშე (SMM4H) 2020-ის გარეშე საზოგადო დავალებისთვის და სამუშაო დავალებისთვის. მეორე დავალებში, ჩვენ უნდა განსხვავება განსაკუთრებული ნაპირო რექიცია (ADR) ტივიტებით nonADR ტივიტებით და უნდა იყოს ბინერი კლასიფიკაცია. სამუშაო სამუშაო შესახებ ADR შესახებ გამოყენება და შემდეგ შესახებ MedDRA კოდეების შესახებ. ADR ამოსახულებების გამოყენება როგორც წერტილის ამოსახულება და ADR ამოსახულებების ნორმალიზება მრავალკლასის კლასიფიკაციაში გამოყენება. ჩვენი სისტემა პროBERTa-ის წინასწარმოადგენული ენის მოდელზე დაბაზიან და ეს მიიღება a) პროცენტში 58% F1- score, რომელიც 12% უფრო მეტია პროცენტში b) პროცენტულია პროცენტში 70 ჩვენი მოდელები გავაკეთებენ, რომელიც ჩვენი მოდელები გავაკეთებენ საუკეთესო შესაძლებლობებით, რომლებიც საუკეთესო შესაძლებლობებით საშუალო</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία παρουσιάζει την προσέγγισή μας για το έργο 2 και το έργο 3 της εξόρυξης κοινωνικών μέσων για την υγεία (ΜΜΧ) 2020 κοινών εργασιών. Στο έργο 2, πρέπει να διαφοροποιήσουμε τα tweets ανεπιθύμητων αντιδράσεων (ADR) από τα tweets μη ADR και αντιμετωπίζεται ως δυαδική ταξινόμηση. Η εργασία 3 περιλαμβάνει την εξαγωγή αναφορών ADR και στη συνέχεια την αντιστοίχισή τους στους κωδικούς MedDRA. Η εξαγωγή αναφορών ADR αντιμετωπίζεται ως σήμανση ακολουθίας και η ομαλοποίηση αναφορών ADR αντιμετωπίζεται ως ταξινόμηση πολλαπλών κατηγοριών. Το σύστημά μας βασίζεται στο προ-εκπαιδευμένο γλωσσικό μοντέλο και επιτυγχάνει α) βαθμολογία 58% στην εργασία 2 το οποίο είναι 12% μεγαλύτερο από το μέσο σκορ β) χαλαρή βαθμολογία F1 70,1% στην εξαγωγή εργασίας 3 η οποία είναι 13,7% μεγαλύτερη από το μέσο σκορ και χαλαρή βαθμολογία F1 35% στην εξαγωγή και ομαλοποίηση της εργασίας 3 η οποία είναι 5,8% μεγαλύτερη από το μέσο σκορ. Συνολικά, τα μοντέλα μας επιτυγχάνουν πολλά υποσχόμενα αποτελέσματα και στις δύο εργασίες με σημαντικές βελτιώσεις σε σχέση με τις μέσες βαθμολογίες.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a tanulmány bemutatja a Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 megosztott feladatainak 2. és 3. feladatát. A második feladatban meg kell különböztetnünk a mellékhatások (ADR) tweetjeit a nem ADR tweetektől, és ezeket bináris osztályozásként kezeljük. A harmadik feladat az ADR-említések kivonása, majd a MedDRA-kódokhoz történő leképezése. Az ADR említések kivonása sorozatcímkézésként kezelhető, az ADR említések normalizálását pedig többosztályos osztályozásként kezelik. Rendszerünk a RoBERTa előre képzett nyelvi modellre épül, és a) F1 pontszámot 58%-kal ér el a 2. feladatban, ami 12%-kal több, mint az átlagos pontszám b) lazított F1 pontszámot 70,1%-kal a 3. feladat ADR kivonása során, ami 13,7%-kal több, mint az átlagos pontszám és lazított F1 pontszámot 35%-kal az ADR kivonás során + a 3. feladat normalizálása során, ami 5,8%-kal több, mint az átlagos pontszám. Összességében modelleink ígéretes eredményeket érnek el mindkét feladatban, jelentős javulással az átlagos pontszámokhoz képest.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_mk>Овој документ го претставува нашиот пристап за задачата 2 и задачата 3 на Социјалната медиумска минирање за здравје (СММ4Х) 2020 заеднички задачи. Во задачата 2, ние мораме да разликуваме негативни реакции на лековите (АДР) твитови од твитови без АДР и се третира како бинарна класификација. Работата 3 вклучува извлекување на спомените на АДР и потоа мапирање на кодовите на MedDRA. Екстрактирањето на спомените на АДР се третира како означување на секвенца и нормализацијата на спомените на АДР се третира како мултикласификација. Нашиот систем се базира на предобучен јазички модел RoBERTa и постигнува a) F1-оценка од 58% во задачата 2 што е 12% повеќе од просечната оценка b) релаксиран F1-оценка од 70,1% во АДР-екстракција на задачата 3 што е 13,7% повеќе од просечната оценка и релаксиран F1-оценка од 35% во АДР екстракција + нормализација на задачата 3 што е 5,8% повеќе од просечната оценка. Вкупно, нашите модели постигнуваат ветувачки резултати во двете задачи со значителни подобрувања во однос на просечните резултати.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>This paper presents our approach for task 2 and task 3 of Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 shared tasks.  Dalam tugas 2, kita perlu membezakan reaksi dadah negatif (ADR) tweet dari tweet bukan ADR dan dianggap sebagai klasifikasi binari. Task 3 involves extracting ADR mentions and then mapping them to MedDRA codes.  Mengekstrak sebutan ADR dianggap sebagai label urutan dan normalisasi sebutan ADR dianggap sebagai klasifikasi kelas berbilang. Sistem kita berdasarkan model bahasa yang dilatih-dilatih RoBERTa dan ia mencapai a) skor-F1 58% dalam tugas 2 yang 12% lebih daripada skor rata-rata b) skor-F1 relaxed 70.1% dalam ekstraksi ADR tugas 3 yang 13.7% lebih daripada skor rata-rata dan skor-F1 relaxed 35% dalam ekstraksi ADR + normalisasi tugas 3 yang 5.8% lebih daripada skor rata-rata. Secara keseluruhan, model kita mencapai keputusan yang berjanji dalam kedua-dua tugas dengan peningkatan yang signifikan atas skor rata-rata.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ സോഷ്യല്‍ മീഡിയ മിനിങ്ങ് വേണ്ടി മൂന്ന് ജോലിക്കും നമ്മുടെ പ്രായോഗ്യം കാണിച്ചുകൊടുക്കുന്നു. 2020 പങ് ജോലി 2-ല്‍, നമുക്ക് വ്യത്യാസകരമായ മയക്കുമരുന്നുള്ള പ്രതികാരം വ്യത്യസ്തമാക്കേണ്ടതുണ്ട്, അഡേആര്‍ ട്ടീറ്റുകളില്‍ നിന്നും  ടാസ്ക് 3 എഡിആര്‍ മെന്നറിയിപ്പുകള്‍ പുറത്തെടുക്കുകയും പിന്നെ മെഡ്ഡിRA കോഡുകളിലേക്ക് മാപ്പ് ചെയ്യു ADR മെന്‍ഷനുകള്‍ പുറത്തെടുക്കുന്നത് സെക്കന്റ് ലേബിള്‍ എന്നും സാധാരണമാക്കുന്ന ADR മെന്‍ഷനുകള്‍ പല-ക്ലാസ് ക്ലാസിഫിക് ഞങ്ങളുടെ സിസ്റ്റം മുന്‍പരിശീലന ഭാഷ മോഡല്‍ റോബെര്‍ട്ടാ അടിസ്ഥാനത്താണ്. ജോലിയില്‍ 58% നേടുന്ന F1- സ്കോര്‍ എത്തുന്നു. അത് 12% കൂടുതല്‍ സാധാരണ സ്കോര്‍ b നേടുന്നു) എഡ്ആര്‍ പുറത്തെടുക്കുന്നതില്‍ എഫ്1% സ്കോര്‍ വിശാലമായിരുന്നു. അത് എഡി മൊത്തം, നമ്മുടെ മോഡലുകള്‍ വാഗ്ദാനം ചെയ്യുന്ന രണ്ട് ജോലികള്‍ക്കും നല്ല മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്തുന്നതാണ്.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo presenta il nostro approccio per il compito 2 e il compito 3 dei compiti condivisi Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020. Nel compito 2, dobbiamo distinguere i tweet sulle reazioni avverse al farmaco (ADR) dai tweet non ADR ed è trattato come classificazione binaria. Il compito 3 consiste nell'estrarre le menzioni ADR e quindi mapparle ai codici MedDRA. Estrarre le menzioni ADR è trattata come etichettatura di sequenza e normalizzare le menzioni ADR è trattata come classificazione multi-classe. Il nostro sistema si basa sul modello linguistico pre-addestrato RoBERTa e raggiunge a) F1-score del 58% nel task 2 che è il 12% in più del punteggio medio b) F1-score rilassato del 70,1% nell'estrazione ADR del task 3 che è il 13,7% in più del punteggio medio e F1-score rilassato del 35% nell'estrazione ADR + normalizzazione del task 3 che è il 5,8% in più del punteggio medio. Nel complesso, i nostri modelli raggiungono risultati promettenti in entrambi i compiti con miglioramenti significativi rispetto ai punteggi medi.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас нийгмийн Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 оны хуваалцааны ажил 2 дахь ажил болон 3 даалгаварын талаар биднийг харуулдаг. 2-р ажил дээр бид эсрэг эм урвалыг (АДР) нь ДОХР биш tweets-ээс ялгаалж, хоёр дахь хуваалтын хуваалтыг харьцуулах хэрэгтэй. 3 даалгавар нь ДОХ-ын хэлэлцээг гаргаж, дараа нь MedDRA кодын зурагт зурагтай. ДОХ-ын нэр тодорхойлолтуудыг дарааллын тэмдэглэл гэж үздэг ба ДОХ-ын нэр тодорхойлолтуудыг олон ангид хэлбэртэй гэж үздэг. Бидний систем RoBERTa-ын өмнө сургалтын хэл загвар дээр суурилсан бөгөөд энэ нь a) 2 даалгаварын F1-тоо 58%-той байдаг бөгөөд энэ нь дундаж оноос 12%-аас илүү b) даалгавартай F1-тоо 70.1% байдаг бөгөөд энэ нь дундаж оноос 13.7% байдаг бөгөөд ADR 3 дахь даалгавартай F1-тоо 35%-аас илүү байдаг бөгөөд энэ нь дундаж оноос 5.8% байдаг бөгөөд Ихэнхдээ бидний загварууд дундаж оноо дээр маш чухал сайжруулах үйл ажиллагаанд амлалтай үр дүнг гаргадаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret viser tilnærminga vårt for oppgåve 2 og oppgåve 3 på den delte oppgåva i sosiale mediaminering for helse (SMM4H) 2020. I oppgåve 2 må vi forskjellere negativt narkotikarelateksjon (ADR) frå nonADR-tweets og behandla som binærklassifikasjon. Oppgåve 3 inneheld å pakka ut ADR-mengdar og så kartera dei til MedDRA-kodar. Då pakka ut ADR- omsetjingar vert behandlet som sekvensmerkelapp og normaliserer ADR- omsetjingar vert behandlet som multiklassesklassifikasjon. Sistemet vårt er basert på føretrained språk- modellen RoBERTa, og det oppnår a) F1- poeng med 58% i oppgåve 2, som er 12% meir enn gjennomsnittlig poeng b) relaksert F1- poeng med 70, 1% i ADR- utpakking av oppgåve 3, som er 13, 7% meir enn gjennomsnittlig poeng og relaksert F1- poeng med 35% i ADR- utpakking + normalisering av oppgåve 3 som er 5, 8% meir enn gjennomsnittlig poeng. Generelt, våre modeller når det gjelder alvorleg resultatet i begge oppgåver med betydelige forbedringar over gjennomsnittsverdiar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente pristatomas mūsų požiūris į 2 užduotį ir 3 užduotį „Socialinės žiniasklaidos kasyba sveikatos labui“ (SMM4H) 2020 m. bendras užduotis. 2 užduotyje turime atskirti nepageidaujamą vaisto reakciją (ADR) nuo ne ADR tweetų ir ją vertinti kaip dvigubą klasifikaciją. 3 užduotis apima ADR paminėjimų ištraukimą, o vėliau jų mapavimą pagal MedDRA kodus. Extracting ADR mentions is treated as sequence labeling and normalizing ADR mentions is treated as multi-class classification.  Mūsų sistema grindžiama iš anksto parengtu kalbos modeliu RoBERTa ir ji pasiekia a) F1 tašką 58% 2 užduotyje, kuris yra 12% didesnis už vidutinį tašką b) atpalaiduotą F1 tašką 70,1% 3 užduoties ADR ekstrakcijoje, kuris yra 13,7% didesnis už vidutinį tašką ir atpalaiduotą F1 tašką 35% ADR ekstrakcijoje + 3 užduoties normalizavimą, kuris yra 5,8% didesnis už vidutinį tašką. Apskritai mūsų modeliai pasiekia pažadėtinų rezultatų abiejose užduotyse, o vidutiniai rezultatai gerokai pagerėja.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз 2020 жылы ортақ тапсырмалар үшін 2- тапсырма және 3- тапсырманың социалдық медиа балау баласы (SMM4H) балаларының тәсілімізді көрсетеді. 2- тапсырмасында қарсы наркотикалық реакциясын (ADR) бақылау керек. ДОПР-тың tweets- тізбектерінен түрлену керек және бинарлық классификациясы ретінде қатынау керек. 3- тапсырма ADR мәліметтерді тарқату және оны MedDRA кодтарына картап беру үшін болады. ADR мәліметтерді тарқату реттеу жарлығы ретінде қалады және ADR мәліметтерді көп класс классификациясы ретінде қалады. Біздің жүйеміз RoBERTa тіл моделіне негізделген, 2- тапсырмада 58% деген F1- нүктесі, бұл 12% деген орташа нүктесінен артық b) 3- тапсырманың ADR тарқатуында 70, 1% деген F1- нүктесі, ол орташа нүктесінен артық 13, 7% деген және 35% деген F1- нүктесі, ADR тарқатуында + 3- тапсырманың нормализациясы Біздің үлгілеріміз орташа нәтижелерден артық жақсарту үшін әлемді тапсырмалардың екеуінде болатын нәтижелерін жеткізеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł przedstawia nasze podejście do zadań wspólnych zadań 2 i zadań 3 Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020. W zadaniu 2 musimy odróżnić tweety dotyczące reakcji niepożądanych leków (ADR) od tweetów nieADR i jest traktowane jako klasyfikacja binarna. Zadanie 3 polega na wyodrębnieniu wzmianek ADR, a następnie na mapowaniu ich do kodów MedDRA. Wyciąganie wzmianek ADR traktowane jest jako etykietowanie sekwencji, a normalizacja wzmianek ADR traktowana jest jako klasyfikacja wieloklasowa. Nasz system oparty jest na wstępnie przeszkolonym modelu językowym RoBERTa i osiąga a) wynik F1 58% w zadaniu 2 który jest 12% większy niż średni wynik b) złagodzony wynik F1 70,1% w ekstrakcji ADR zadania 3 który jest 13,7% większy niż średni wynik i złagodzony wynik F1 35% w ekstrakcji ADR oraz normalizację zadania 3, który jest 5,8% większy niż średni wynik. Ogólnie rzecz biorąc, nasze modele osiągają obiecujące rezultaty w obu zadaniach ze znaczną poprawą nad średnimi wynikami.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_si>මේ පත්තුවේ අපේ වැඩේ දෙවෙනි වැඩේ සමාජික මිඩියාව ස්වාස්ථ්‍ය විධානය (SMM4H) 2020ක් වැඩි වැඩේ තියෙනවා. 2 වැඩේ අපිට විරුද්ධ ව්‍යාප්‍තික ප්‍රතික්‍රියාව (ADR) නොADR ටුයිට් වලින් වෙනස් කරන්න වෙනවා ඒ වගේම බායිනාර් විශේෂණ වැඩ 3යි ADR කිරීම් නිර්මාණය කරලා ඒවා MedDRA කෝඩ් වලට සැකසුම් කරලා තියෙනවා. Name අපේ පද්ධතිය ප්‍රීක්ෂණිත භාෂාව ප්‍රමාණය RoBERTa වලට අධිරූපය වෙලා තියෙන්නේ. ඒ වගේම ඒක සාමාන්‍ය ස්කෝර් 2 වල F1- ස්කෝර් 58% තියෙන්නේ. ඒක 12% වඩා සාමාන්‍ය ස්කෝර් b) සාමාන්‍ය ස්කෝර් 3 වල F1- ස්කෝර් 70.1% ත සාමාන්‍යයෙන්, අපේ මොඩල් එක්ක පොරොන්දු වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රතිචාර ප්‍රතිචාර ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලැබෙනවා සාම</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalkan wuxuu soo saaraa qaabilaada shaqada 2 iyo shaqada 3 ee maareynta caafimaadka sooshalka (SMM4H) 2020 oo shaqada la qaybsaday. Shaqada 2 waa in aan ka kala soocno dib u yeelashada daawooyinka (ADR) tweetka oo aan aheyn adigoo isticmaalaya labaad. Task 3 involves extracting ADR mentions and then mapping them to MedDRA codes.  Macluumaadka ka soo bixinta ADR waxaa loola dhaqdhaqaaqaaqaa sida tababarida iyo si caadi ah oo lagu qorayo macluumaadka ADR lagu qoro fasalka kala duduwan. Sirkayada waxaa ku saleysan qaababka afka hore ee RoBERta, waxayna gaadhaa (a) Shaqo-F1-score 58 oo ka badan 12% oo qiimaha dhexe b) waxay qabsatay F1-score 70.1% oo ka badnaan iskuulka shaqada 3, taasoo ah 13.7 % oo ka badnaan kooxda ugu dhexeeya 35% ee ADR extraction + normalization shaqo 3 oo ka badan 5.8% qiimaha ugu dhexeeya. Sida caadiga ah modelalkayagu waxay heli karaan sabab ballan ah labadooda shaqaalaha lagu sameeyo horumar badan oo ka kordhiya qiimaha guud.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jippreżenta l-approċċ tagħna għall-kompitu 2 u l-kompitu 3 tal-Minjieri tal-Midja Soċjali għas-Saħħa (SMM4H) 2020. Fit-tieni kompitu, irridu niddifferenzjaw it-tweets tar-reazzjoni avversa tal-mediċina (ADR) minn tweets mhux ADR u huwa ttrattat bħala klassifikazzjoni binarja. Il-kompitu 3 jinvolvi l-estrazzjoni tas-semmijiet tal-ADR u mbagħad l-immappjar tagħhom għall-kodiċijiet MedDRA. L-estrazzjoni tas-semmijiet tal-ADR hija ttrattata bħala tikkettar tas-sekwenza u s-semmijiet normalizzanti tal-ADR huma ttrattati bħala klassifikazzjoni ta’ diversi klassijiet. Is-sistema tagħna hija b b a żata fuq mudell lingwistiku mħarreġ minn qabel RoBERTa u tilħaq a) punteġġ F1 ta’ 58% fil-kompitu 2 li huwa 12% aktar mill-punteġġ medju b) punteġġ F1 rilassat ta’ 70.1% fl-estrazzjoni ADR tal-kompitu 3 li huwa 13.7% aktar mill-punteġġ medju u punteġġ F1 rilassat ta’ 35% fl-estrazzjoni ADR + normalizzazzjoni tal-kompitu 3 li huwa 5.8% aktar mill-punteġġ medju. Overall, our models achieve promising results in both the tasks with significant improvements over average scores.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir predstavlja naš pristup zadatku 2 i zadatku 3 delovanja rudarstva socijalnih medija za zdravlje (SMM4H) 2020. U zadatku 2, moramo diferencirati tujtove protiv nuspojave (ADR) od tweets bez ADR-a i tretirati se kao binarna klasifikacija. Task 3 uključuje izvlačenje spomena ADR-a i mapiranje ih na MedDRA kodove. Ekstrakcija spomena ADR-a se tretira kao etiketiranje sekvencija i normalizacija spomena ADR-a se tretira kao klasifikacija multiklasa. Naš sistem je baziran na predobučenom jezičkom modelu RoBERTa i postiže a) F1 rezultat od 58% u zadatku 2 koji je 12% više od prosječnog rezultata b) opušteni F1 rezultat od 70,1% u izvlačenju zadatka 3 ADR koji je 13,7% više od prosječnog rezultata i opuštenog F1 rezultata od 35% u izvlačenju ADR + normalizaciju zadatka 3 koji je 5,8% više od prosječnog rezultata. U svemu, naši modeli postignu obećavajuće rezultate u oba zadatka sa značajnim poboljšanjem preko prosječnih rezultata.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ur>This paper presents our approach for task 2 and task 3 of Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 shared tasks. ٹوئیٹ 2 میں ہم کو مخالف مخالف ڈراگر واکنش (ADR) ٹویٹوں سے متفرق کرنا ضروری ہے اور ان کو دوبارہ کلاسیفوں کے طور پر سمجھا جاتا ہے۔ Task 3 includes extracting ADR mentions and then mapping them to MedDRA codes. ADR مذہروں کو اٹھانے کا ذریعہ سطح لیبلینگ اور ADR مذہروں کو عامل کرنا multi-class classification کے طور پر سمجھا جاتا ہے. ہماری سیستم پہلے تدریس کی زبان موڈل RoBERTa پر بنیاد ہے اور یہ کام 2 میں 58% کی F1-score پہنچتی ہے جو عمومی اسکور (b) سے 12% زیادہ ہے۔ اور ہمارے مدلکوں کو دوسرے کاموں میں وعدہ دینے والی نتیجے پہنچ رہے ہیں جن کے ذریعہ عمدہ اسکور پر اضافہ ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare prezintă abordarea noastră pentru sarcinile 2 și 3 ale Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020. În sarcina 2, trebuie să diferențiem tweeturile reacțiilor adverse la medicament (ADR) de tweeturile non-ADR și sunt tratate ca clasificare binară. Sarcina 3 implică extragerea mențiunilor ADR și apoi maparea lor la codurile MedDRA. Extragerea mențiunilor ADR este tratată ca etichetare secvențială și normalizarea mențiunilor ADR este tratată ca clasificare multiclasă. Sistemul nostru se bazează pe modelul lingvistic pre-instruit RoBERTa și obține a) scorul F1 de 58% în sarcina 2, care este cu 12% mai mult decât scorul mediu b) scorul F1 relaxat de 70,1% în extracția ADR a sarcinii 3, care este cu 13,7% mai mult decât scorul mediu și scorul F1 relaxat de 35% în extracția ADR + normalizarea sarcinii 3, care este cu 5,8% mai mult decât scorul mediu. În general, modelele noastre obțin rezultate promițătoare în ambele sarcini, cu îmbunătățiri semnificative față de scorurile medii.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats presenterar vårt tillvägagångssätt för uppgift 2 och uppgift 3 i Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 delade uppgifter. I uppgift 2 måste vi skilja på ADR-tweets från icke-ADR-tweets och behandlas som binär klassificering. Uppgift 3 innebär att extrahera ADR-omnämnanden och sedan kartlägga dem till MedDRA-koder. Uttagning av ADR-omnämnanden behandlas som sekvensmärkning och normalisering av ADR-omnämnanden behandlas som flerklassklassificering. Vårt system är baserat på färdigutbildad språkmodell RoBERTa och uppnår a) F1-poäng på 58% i uppgift 2 vilket är 12% mer än genomsnittspoängen b) avslappnad F1-poäng på 70,1% i ADR extraktion av uppgift 3 vilket är 13,7% mer än genomsnittspoängen och avslappnad F1-poäng på 35% i ADR extraktion + normalisering av uppgift 3 som är 5,8% mer än genomsnittspoängen. Sammantaget uppnår våra modeller lovande resultat i båda uppgifterna med betydande förbättringar jämfört med genomsnittet.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த தாள் எங்கள் செயல் 2 மற்றும் செயல் 3 என்று கூறுகிறது சாலிக ஊடகங்களின் சிகிச்சையை (SMM4H) 2020 பகிர்ந்த பணிகள். செயல் 2, நாம் வேறுபடுத்த வேண்டும் எதிர்மறை மருந்து விகிதத்தை (ADR) தொடர்புகளிலிருந்து வித்தியாசமாக்க வேண்டும் மற்று செயல் 3 ADR குறிப்புகளை வெளியேற்றுதல் மற்றும் மேட்டிரா குறியீடுகளுக்கு வரைபடம் செய்யும். ADR குறிப்புகளை வெளியேற்றுதல் மற்றும் ADR குறிப்புகளை இயல்பாக்குதல் மற்றும் பல வகுப்பு வகுப்பாக கருதப்படுகிறது. எங்கள் அமைப்பு முன்பயிற்சி மொழி மாதிரி ரோபெர்டா அடிப்படையில் உள்ளது இது செயலில் 58% புள்ளியை அடைக்கும், அது 12% அதிகமாகும் சராசரி புள்ளியை விட b அதிகமாக இருக்கும்) ADR செயலை வெளியேற்றத்தில் F1- புள்ளியை விட 13.7% அதிகமாக இருக்கும் சரா மொத்தமாக, எங்கள் மாதிரிகள் வாக்களிக்கப்படும் விளைவுகள் இருவரும் செயல்களுக்கும் முன்னேற்றங்கள் சராசரி மதிப்ப</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này giới thiệu phương pháp của chúng ta cho nhiệm vụ 2 và nhiệm vụ 3 của Phòng chống truyền thông Xã hội (SMS4H) 2020 đã chia sẻ nhiệm vụ. Trong nhiệm vụ 2, chúng ta phải phân biệt các phản ứng gây hại (giải phóng) trên Twitter và được xem như phân loại nhị phân. Nhiệm vụ thứ ba gồm rút các chỉ thị dị ứng và rồi chuyển chúng sang mã Meddra. Việc trích dẫn dị tố được xem như chỉ thị dãy số và giải pháp định hình thường được coi là phân cấp nhiều lớp. Hệ thống của chúng ta dựa trên một mô hình ngôn ngữ đã được đào tạo trước Roeta và nó đạt được a) F1-số 58=.* trong nhiệm vụ 2 mà là 12=. nhiều hơn so với tỉ số trung b ình b) thư giãn F1-số 701.1=. trong giải cứu nhiệm vụ 3 là 13.7=. nhiều hơn so với tỉ số trung bình và thư giãn F1-điểm của 35=. trong giải cứu cộng hưởng cộng hưởng cộng hưởng cám cám cám cám cám cám cám cám cám trợ Trên hết, mẫu của chúng ta đạt được kết quả hứa hẹn về cả hai nhiệm vụ với cải tiến đáng kể trên điểm trung bình.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Bu qogʻoz 2020 bo'lgan vazifalarning 2 va Social Media Mind (SMM4H) vazifasi 3 ta vazifasini beradi. 2 vazifasida biz dop raqamli xabarlarni o'zgartirishimiz kerak va biz ikkita sinf sifatida boshlanamiz kerak. Vazifa 3 uchun ADR hisoblarini olib tashlash va keyin ularni MedDRA kodlarga diagramma qiladi. ADR hisobotini ajratish uchun sequence lab chiqarish va oddiy ADR hisoblarini bir necha klassifning sifatida qoʻllaniladi. Biz tizimmiz oldin o'rganilgan til modeli RoBERTa asosida, u vazifani 2 bilan 58% bajaradi, u 12% dan ortiq scori b bo'lgan F1 scori, ADR vazifani ajratish 3% dan 13.7% dan ortiq boʻlgan, ADR soni ajratish va vazifa 3 dan 5.8% dan ortiq boʻlgan. Umumiy, bizning modellarimiz eng yaxshi ishlarni bajaradi va ikkita vazifalar o'zgartiradi, o'rtacha darajada katta yaxshi o'zgarishlar bilan bajaradi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir predstavlja naš pristup zadatku 2 i zadatku 3 zajedničkih zadataka za rudarstvo socijalnih medija za zdravlje (SMM4H) 2020. U zadatku 2, moramo razlikovati nuspojavne reakcije na lijekove (ADR) tweets od tweets non ADR-a i tretirati se kao binarnu klasifikaciju. Treći zadatak uključuje izvlačenje spomena ADR-a i onda ih mapirati na MedDRA kodove. Izvlačenje spomena ADR-a liječeno je kao etiketiranje sekvence i normaliziranje spomena ADR-a liječeno je kao multiklasična klasična klasifikacija. Naš sustav se temelji na predobučenom jezičkom modelu RoBERTa i postiže a) F1 rezultat od 58% u zadatku 2 koji je 12% više od prosječnog rezultata b) opušteni F1 rezultat od 70,1% u izvlačenju zadatka 3 ADR-a koji je 13,7% više od prosječnog rezultata i opuštenog F1 rezultata od 35% u izvlačenju ADR-a + normalizaciju zadatka 3 koji je 5,8% više od prosječnog rezultata. Općenito, naši modeli postignu obećavajuće rezultate u oba zadatka s značajnim poboljšanjem u prosječnim rezultatima.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Deze paper presenteert onze aanpak voor taak 2 en taak 3 van Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 gedeelde taken. In taak 2 moeten we tweets van ongewenste drugsreacties (ADR) onderscheiden van tweets die niet-ADR zijn en worden we behandeld als binaire classificatie. Taak 3 omvat het extraheren van ADR-vermeldingen en vervolgens toewijzen aan MedDRA-codes. Het extraheren van ADR vermeldingen wordt behandeld als sequentie labeling en het normaliseren van ADR vermeldingen wordt behandeld als multi-class classificatie. Ons systeem is gebaseerd op voorgetrainde taalmodel RoBERTa en het bereikt a) F1-score van 58% in taak 2 die 12% meer is dan de gemiddelde score b) ontspannen F1-score van 70,1% in ADR extractie van taak 3 die 13,7% meer is dan de gemiddelde score en ontspannen F1-score van 35% in ADR extractie en normalisatie van taak 3 die 5,8% meer is dan de gemiddelde score. Over het algemeen bereiken onze modellen veelbelovende resultaten in beide taken met significante verbeteringen ten opzichte van gemiddelde scores.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel præsenterer vores tilgang til opgave 2 og opgave 3 i Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 delte opgaver. I opgave 2 skal vi skelne mellem bivirkninger (ADR) tweets og ikke-ADR tweets og behandles som binær klassificering. Opgave 3 indebærer at udtrække ADR-omtaler og derefter kortlægge dem til MedDRA-koder. Udtrækning af ADR omtaler behandles som sekvensmærkning og normalisering af ADR omtaler behandles som multi-class klassificering. Vores system er baseret på prætrænet sprogmodel RoBERTa og det opnår a) F1-score på 58% i opgave 2, som er 12% mere end gennemsnitsscoren b) afslappet F1-score på 70,1% i ADR udtrækning af opgave 3, som er 13,7% mere end gennemsnitsscoren og afslappet F1-score på 35% i ADR udtrækning + normalisering af opgave 3, som er 5,8% mere end gennemsnitsscoren. Samlet set opnår vores modeller lovende resultater i begge opgaver med betydelige forbedringer i forhold til gennemsnitsscorer.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия представя нашия подход към задача 2 и задача 3 на споделените задачи на Социалните медии Минно дело за здраве (СММ4Х) 2020. В задача 2 трябва да разграничим туитовете на нежеланите лекарствени реакции (АРР) от туитовете, които не са АРР и се третират като двоична класификация. Задача 3 включва извличане на споменатите АРС и след това свързване с кодовете на MedDRA. Извличането на споменатите АРС се третира като последователно етикетиране, а нормализирането на споменатите АРС се третира като многокласна класификация. Системата ни е базирана на предварително обучен езиков модел и постига а) оценка от 58% при задача 2, което е 12% повече от средния резултат б) отпуснат резултат от 70,1% при екстракция на задача 3, което е 13,7% повече от средния резултат и отпуснат резултат от 35% при екстракция на АРР + нормализация на задача 3, което е 5,8% повече от средния резултат. Като цяло нашите модели постигат обещаващи резултати и в двете задачи със значителни подобрения спрямо средните резултати.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag stellt unseren Ansatz für Aufgaben 2 und Aufgabe 3 von Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 gemeinsam genutzten Aufgaben vor. In Aufgabe 2 müssen wir unerwünschte Arzneimittel-Tweets (ADR) von Nicht-ADR-Tweets unterscheiden und werden als binäre Klassifizierung behandelt. Aufgabe 3 besteht darin, ADR-Erwähnungen zu extrahieren und sie dann MedDRA-Codes zuzuordnen. Das Extrahieren von ADR-Erwähnungen wird als Sequenz-Kennzeichnung behandelt und das Normalisieren von ADR-Erwähnungen wird als Mehrklassenklassifizierung behandelt. Unser System basiert auf dem vortrainierten Sprachmodell RoBERTa und erreicht a) F1-Score von 58% in Aufgabe 2, der 12% höher ist als die durchschnittliche Punktzahl b) entspannte F1-Punktzahl von 70,1% in ADR-Extraktion von Aufgabe 3, die 13,7% höher ist als die durchschnittliche Punktzahl und entspannte F1-Punktzahl von 35% in ADR-Extraktion, Normalisierung von Aufgabe 3, die 5,8% höher als die durchschnittliche Punktzahl ist. Insgesamt erzielen unsere Modelle in beiden Aufgabenstellungen vielversprechende Ergebnisse mit deutlichen Verbesserungen gegenüber Durchschnittswerten.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>This paper presents our approach for task 2 and task 3 of Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 shared tasks.  Dalam tugas 2, kita harus membedakan reaksi obat negatif (ADR) tweet dari tweet bukan ADR dan diperlakukan sebagai klasifikasi binari. Tugas 3 melibatkan mengekstrak sebutan ADR dan kemudian memetakannya ke kode MedDRA. Mengekstrak sebutan ADR diperlakukan sebagai label urutan dan normalisasi sebutan ADR diperlakukan sebagai klasifikasi multikelas. Sistem kita berdasarkan model bahasa terlatih sebelum RoBERTa dan ia mencapai a) F1-skor 58% dalam tugas 2 yang 12% lebih dari nilai rata-rata b) relaxed F1-skor 70.1% dalam ADR ekstraksi tugas 3 yang 13.7% lebih dari nilai rata-rata dan relaxed F1-skor 35% dalam ADR ekstraksi + normalisasi tugas 3 yang 5.8% lebih dari nilai rata-rata. Overall, our models achieve promising results in both the tasks with significant improvements over average scores.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 소셜미디어 건강발굴(SMM4H) 2020에서 임무를 공유하는 임무 2와 임무 3의 방법을 소개한다.임무 2에서는 약물불량반응(ADR) 트윗과 비 ADR 트윗을 구분해 이원적으로 분류해야 한다.작업 3은 ADR 언급을 추출한 다음 MedDRA 코드에 매핑합니다.추출된 ADR 언급은 시퀀스 태그로, 표준화된 ADR 언급은 여러 범주로 분류됩니다.우리 시스템은 사전 훈련된 언어 모델인 로베르타를 바탕으로 a)퀘스트 2의 F1 점수는 58%로 평균 점수보다 12% 높았고 b)퀘스트 3의 ADR에서 추출한 이완 F1 점수는 70.1%로 평균 점수보다 13.7% 높았으며 퀘스트 3의 ADR에서 추출한 이완 F1 점수는 35%로 평균 점수보다 5.8% 높았다.전반적으로 말하자면, 우리의 모델은 이 두 가지 임무에서 모두 만족스러운 결과를 얻었고, 평균 점수보다 현저하게 높아졌다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ روش ما را برای وظیفه ۲ و وظیفه ۳ از وظیفه‌های مشترک سرمایه‌گذاری رسانه‌های اجتماعی برای سلامت (SMM4H) نشان می‌دهد. در وظیفه ۲، ما باید واکنش مختلف مواد مختلف (ADR) را از تویت های غیر ADR جدا کنیم و به عنوان classification binary treated می‌شود. وظیفه ۳ شامل استخراج یادآوری ADR و سپس نقشه‌بندی آن‌ها به کدهای MedDRA است. اخراج کردن اشاره‌های ADR به عنوان برچسب برچسب‌های برچسب‌ها درمان می‌شود و عادی کردن اشاره‌های ADR به عنوان برچسب‌های برچسب‌های بیشتر کلاس درمان می‌شود. سیستم ما بر روی مدل زبان پیش آموزش شده RoBERTa بنیاد می‌رسد و آن به (a) نقاط F1 58% در کار ۲ رسیده است که 12% بیشتر از نقاط متوسط b) نقاط F1 متوسط 70.1% در استخراج ADR از کار ۳ است که 13.7% بیشتر از نقاط متوسط و نقاط F1 متوسط از 35% در استخراج ADR + نقاط کاری ۳ است که 5.8% بیشتر از نقاط متوسط است. در کل، مدل‌های ما نتیجه‌ی قول‌دهنده در هر دو وظیفه‌ای با بهترین شدید بیش از امتیاز متوسط رسیده‌اند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier stel ons toegang vir taak 2 en taak 3 van sosiale media-mining vir gesondheid (SMM4H) 2020 gedeelde taak voorsien. In taak 2, moet ons neerdaagde narkotika reaksie (ADR) tweets van nonADR tweets verskillig en as binêre klasifikasie behandel word. Opdrag 3 involves extracting ADR mentions and then mapping them to MedDRA codes. Uitpakking van ADR-nommers is behandel as sekwensieetiketting en normalisering van ADR-nommers is behandel as multiklas klasifikasie. Ons stelsel is gebaseer op voor- opgelei taal model RoBERTa en dit bereik 'n) F1- telling van 58% in taak 2 wat is 12% meer as die gemiddelde telling b) opgelaai F1- telling van 70. 1% in ADR uittrek van taak 3 wat is 13. 7% meer as die gemiddelde telling en opgelaai F1- telling van 35% in ADR uittrek + normalisering van taak 3 wat is 5. 8% meer as die gemiddelde telling. Op die hele manier, ons modele het beloftende resultate bereik in beide die opdragte met betekende verbeteringe oor gemiddelde punte.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz biziň 2-nji görevimiz we 3-nji görevimiz üçin sosyal medýýallaryň saglygyň taýýarlanmagynyň (SMM4H) 2020-nji beýleki zadlary paýlaşýar. 2-nji täblikde, nusgalan ilat täsirini (ADR) nonADR tweetlerinden çykarmalydyr we ikinji klasifikasy hökmünde duýmalydyrys. 3-nji Görev ADR agzalaryny açmak we soňra ony MedDRA kodlara görkezmek bilen meýilleşdirýär. ADR agzalary açylmak üçin sıralan etiketlemek üçin gözlenýär we ADR agzalaryny düzenlemek üçin bir çoklu klasifikasyon diýip gözlenýär. Biziň sistemimiz RoBERTa öňünden eğlenen dil nusgasyna daýanýar we bu 2-nji işde 58% F1-score daýanýar. Bu 2-nji işinde orta sanatdan 12% köp b) süýtgeli F1-score da 70.1% ADR 3-nji işiň çekmesinde rahatlandyrylýar. Bu 3-nji işiň orta sanatyndan 13.7% we rahatlandyrylýan F1-score da 35% ADR çekmesinde + taýýarlyk 3-nji işiň normalizasynda 5.8% kö Her zamanki modellerimiz ortalama noktaları üzerinde önemli gelişmeler için söz verilen sonuçlarına ulaştı.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_hy>Այս աշխատանքը ներկայացնում է մեր մոտեցումը 2-րդ և 3-րդ հանձնարարության համար, որը հանդիսանում է 2020-ի սոցիալական մեդիայի առողջության (SMM4H) հանրային հանձնարարությունները: Երկրորդ խնդրում մենք պետք է տարբերենք դեղամիջոցների բացասական արձագանքը (ADR) թվիթերից ոչ ADR թվիթերից և վերաբերվում է որպես երկու դասակարգման: Երրորդ խնդիրը ներառում է ԱԴՌ-ի նշանները վերցնելը և հետո դրանք քարտեզագրել ՄԵԴՌ-ի կոդների վրա: ԱԴՌ-ի մեջբերումները վերաբերվում են որպես հաջորդականության պիտակ և նորմալ ԱԴՌ-ի մեջբերումները վերաբերվում են որպես բազմադասական դասակարգում: Մեր համակարգը հիմնված է նախապատրաստված լեզվի մոդելի ՌոBERտայի վրա և այն հասնում է a) F1-գնահատականի 58 տոկոսին 2-ի դեպքում, որը 12 տոկոսից ավելին է, քան միջին գնահատականը b) հանգստացած F1-գնահատականը 70.1 տոկոսից ADR-ի վերացման դեպքում 3-ի դեպքում, որը 13.7 տոկոսից ավելին է, քան միջին գնահատականը, և հանգստացած F1-գնահատականը 35 տոկոսից ADR Ընդհանուր առմամբ, մեր մոդելները հասնում են խոստացնող արդյունքներ երկու խնդիրներում, որոնք մեծ բարելավում են միջին գնահատականների համեմատ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt bizim 2. və 3. işimizin sosial Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 paylaşılan işlərimizin tərzimi göstərir. İkinci görevdə, neçə-neçə uyuşturucu reaksiyonu (ADR) bitlərindən ayırmalıyıq və ikili klasifikasyon olaraq davranmalıyıq. Üçüncü görev ADR yaddaşlarını çıxartmaq və sonra onları MedDRA kodlarına mapa etmək istəyir. ADR yaddaşlarını çıxartmaq seçmə etiketi kimi görünür və ADR yaddaşlarını normalizləmək çoxlu sınıf klasifikasyonu kimi görünür. Bizim sistemimiz əvvəl təhsil edilmiş dil modeli RoBERTa'ya dayandırılmış və bu 2'nin f1-score 58%-dən artır, bu da orta nöqtədən 12%-dən artır b) 3'nin ADR çıxarılmasından 70.1%-dən rahatlı F1 nöqtəsidir, bu da orta nöqtəsindən 13.7%-dən artır və 3'nin ADR çıxarılmasında rahatlı F1-score 35%-dən artır və bu da 5.8% orta nöqtəsindən artır. Əlbəttə, modellərimiz orta nöqtələrin üstündə möhkəm düzəltməsi ilə hər ikisinin və ’ d verən sonuçlarına nail olur.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_sw>Makala hii inaonyesha mbinu yetu ya kazi ya 2 na kazi 3 ya Mitandao ya kijamii ya Kumbukumbu ya Afya (SMM4H) 2020 zilizoshirikiana na kazi zetu. Katika kazi ya 2, tunatakiwa kutofautisha mwitikio mbaya wa madawa (ADR) kwenye twiti za twiti zisizo na ADR na hutumiwa kama sifa binafsi. Kazi 3 inahusisha kuondoa tahadhari za ADR na kisha kutengeneza ramani kwenye sheria za MedDRA. Kutokana na matamko ya ADR yanachukuliwa kama maarifa yanayoelezea na kuharimisha maneno ya ADR yanachukuliwa kama sifa za darasa nyingi. Mfumo wetu umejikita na muundo wa lugha iliyoendelea RoBERTa na inafikia) score ya F1 ya asilimia 58 katika kazi 2 ambayo ni zaidi ya asilimia 12 ya kiwango cha wastani b) ilifukuza score ya F1 ya asilimia 70.1 katika kazi ya ADR kuondolewa kwa kiwango cha wastani 3 ambacho ni asilimia 13.7 zaidi ya score ya wastani na kupumzika score ya F1 kwa asilimia 35 katika uteuzi wa ADR + utaratibu wa kazi 3 ambayo ni asilimia 5.8 zaidi ya score ya wastani. Kwa ujumla, mifano yetu hupata matokeo ya kuahidini yanasababisha kazi zote zenye maboresho makubwa zaidi ya vipindi vya wastani.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_am>ይህም ገጽ ለስራ 2 እና ለስራ 3 የማኅበራዊ ሚዲያ አሳብ ለጤና አሳብ (SMM4H) 2020 የተካፈሉት ስራዎችን ያቀርባል፡፡ በስራ 2፣ የተቃወመ የረኀብ ጥያቄ (ADR) ትዊተሮችን ከኤድአር ትዊተር እና የሀብት መግለጫ እንዲሆን ያስፈልጋል፡፡ ስራ 3 የADR ማስታወሻ ማውጣት እና ከዚያም ወደ ሜድDRA ኮድ ማህበረሰብ ነው። ADR ማስታወቂያውን ለማውጣት በቁጥጥር ማሳየት እና የADR ማስታወቂያውን በማስተካከል በብዙ-ክፍል መግለጫ ሆኖ ይጠቀማል፡፡ የድምፅ ቋንቋ ምሳሌ RoBERta የተመሠረተ ነው፡፡ በጠቅላላላ፣ ሞዴላዎቻችን በተስፋ የሚደርሱትን ፍሬዎች በሁለታቸው ትልቅ ድምፅ የሚያደርጉትን አግኝተዋል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument paraqet qasjen tonë për detyrën 2 dhe detyrën 3 të Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020. Në detyrën e dytë, ne duhet të diferencojmë reaksionin e keq të drogës (ADR) tweetet nga tweetet jo ADR dhe trajtohet si klasifikim binar. Detyra 3 përfshin nxjerrjen e përmendimeve të ADR dhe pastaj hartimin e tyre në kodet e MedDRA. Ekstraktimi i përmendimeve ADR trajtohet si etiketat e sekuencës dhe normalizimi i përmendimeve ADR trajtohet si klasifikim shumë-klasësh. Sistemi ynë është bazuar në model in e gjuhës së paratrajnuar RoBERTa dhe arrin a) rezultat F1 prej 58% në detyrën 2 që është 12% më shumë se rezultati mesatar b) rezultat F1 të relaksuar prej 70.1% në ADR ekstrahimin e detyrës 3 që është 13.7% më shumë se rezultati mesatar dhe rezultat F1 të relaksuar prej 35% në ADR ekstrahimin + normalizimin e detyrës 3 që është 5.8% më shumë se rezultati mesatar. Në përgjithësi, modelet tona arrijnë rezultate premtuese në të dy detyrat me përmirësime të rëndësishme mbi rezultatet mesatare.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek představuje náš přístup k úkolům 2 a úkolům 3 Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020 sdíleným úkolům. V úkolu 2 musíme odlišit tweety nežádoucí léčivé reakce (ADR) od tweetů jiných nežádoucích léčiv a je považováno za binární klasifikaci. Úkol 3 zahrnuje extrahování zmínek ADR a následné mapování jejich na kódy MedDRA. Extrakce ADR zmínek je považována za sekvenční označení a normalizace ADR zmínek je považována za vícetřídní klasifikaci. Náš systém je založen na předcvičeném jazykovém modelu RoBERTa a dosahuje a) F1 skóre 58% v úkolu 2, což je 12% větší než průměrné skóre b) uvolněné F1 skóre 70,1% v ADR extrakci úkolu 3, což je 13,7% větší než průměrné skóre a uvolněné F1 skóre 35% v ADR extrakci, normalizace úkolu 3, která je 5,8% větší než průměrné skóre. Celkově dosahují naše modely slibných výsledků v obou úkolech s výrazným zlepšením nad průměrným skórem.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest paper presenta el nostre enfocament per a la tasca 2 i la tasca 3 de Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2020. In task 2, we have to differentiate adverse drug reaction (ADR) tweets from nonADR tweets and is treated as binary classification.  La tasca 3 consisteix en extrair les mencions de l'ADR i després en mapejar-les a codis MedDRA. L'extracció de les mencions ADR es tracta com etiquetar seqüències i normalitzar les mencions ADR es tracta com una classificació multiclasse. El nostre sistema es basa en el model de llenguatge pre-entrenat RoBERTa i aconsegueix a) puntuació F1 del 58% en la tasca 2, que és el 12% més que la mitjana puntuació b) puntuació F1 relaxada del 70,1% en l'extracció ADR de la tasca 3, que és el 13,7% més que la mitjana puntuació i puntuació F1 relaxada del 35% en l'extracció ADR + normalització de la tasca 3, que és el 5,8% més que la mitjana puntuació. En general, els nostres models aconsegueixen resultats prometedors en les dues tasques amb millores significatives sobre les puntuacions mitjanes.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa esitellään lähestymistapamme sosiaalisen median kaivostoiminnan (SMM4H) 2020 jaettuihin tehtäviin 2 ja 3. Tehtävässä 2 meidän on erotettava haittavaikutusten (ADR) tweetit muista kuin ADR tweeteistä ja niitä käsitellään binääriluokitteluna. Tehtävään 3 kuuluu ADR-mainintojen poimiminen ja niiden yhdistäminen MedDRA-koodeihin. ADR-mainintojen purkamista käsitellään sekvenssimerkinnöinä ja ADR-mainintojen normalisointia moniluokkaisena luokitteluna. Järjestelmämme perustuu ennalta koulutettuun kielimalliin RoBERTa ja se saavuttaa a) F1-pisteen 58% tehtävässä 2, mikä on 12% enemmän kuin keskiarvo b) rennon F1-pisteen 70,1% ADR-ekstraktiossa tehtävästä 3, mikä on 13,7% enemmän kuin keskiarvo ja rennon F1-pisteen 35% ADR-ekstraktiossa + normalisoitumisen tehtävän 3, joka on 5,8% enemmän kuin keskiarvo. Kaiken kaikkiaan malleillamme saavutetaan lupaavia tuloksia molemmissa tehtävissä ja parannuksia keskimääräisiin tuloksiin verrattuna.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas artiklis tutvustatakse meie lähenemisviisi sotsiaalmeedia tervishoiu kaevandamise (SMM4H) 2020. aasta jagatud ülesannete 2. ja 3. ülesandele. Ülesandes 2 tuleb eristada kõrvaltoimete (ADR) säutseid mitteADR säutseid ja neid käsitletakse kahekordse klassifikatsioonina. Ülesanne 3 hõlmab vaidluste kohtuvälise lahendamise märgete väljavõtmist ja seejärel nende kaardistamist MedDRA koodidega. ADR-märgete ekstraheerimist käsitletakse järjestuse märgistusena ja ADR-märgete normaliseerimist käsitletakse mitmeklassilise klassifikatsioonina. Meie süsteem põhineb eelõpetatud keelemudelil RoBERTa ja see saavutab a) F1-skoori 58% ülesandes 2, mis on 12% rohkem kui keskmine skoor b) lõdvestunud F1-skoori 70,1% ADR ekstraheerimisel ülesandes 3, mis on 13,7% rohkem kui keskmine skoor ja lõdvestunud F1-skoori 35% ADR ekstraheerimisel + ülesande 3 normaliseerimine, mis on 5,8% rohkem kui keskmine skoor. Kokkuvõttes saavutavad meie mudelid mõlemas ülesandes paljulubavaid tulemusi, mis on oluliselt paranenud keskmisest tulemusest.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটি স্বাস্থ্যের জন্য সামাজিক মিডিয়া মিনিং এর ২ এবং তিন কাজের জন্য আমাদের প্রতিক্রিয়া উপস্থাপন করেছে ২০২০ টি শে দ্বিতীয় কাজে আমাদের অএডিআর টুইট থেকে বিভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন মাদক প্রতিক্রিয়া (এডিআর) টুইট বিভিন্ন করা দরকার এবং বাইন কাজ ৩ এর মধ্যে এডিআরের মন্তব্য বের করে মেডিড্রা কোডে ম্যাপ করা হয়। এডিআর উল্লেখযোগ্য উল্লেখ করা হচ্ছে সেকেন্ড লেবেলিং এবং স্বাভাবিকভাবে এডিআর মেনেন্টগুলো বহুশ্রেণীর বিভাগ হিস আমাদের সিস্টেম রোবের্তার পূর্ব প্রশিক্ষিত ভাষার মডেলের উপর ভিত্তিতে রয়েছে এবং এটি কাজের দ্বারা ৫৮% ফেসবুকের স্কোর অর্জন করা হয়েছে যা সাধারণ স্কোর bের চেয়ে ১২% বেশী) এডিআর কাজের বের করার ৩০. সাধারণত, আমাদের মডেলগুলো প্রতিশ্রুতিশীল ফলাফল অর্জন করেছে যার ফলে সাধারণত স্কোরের বেশী বিশাল উন্নতি পায়।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir predstavlja naš pristup zadatku 2 i zadatku 3 zajedničkih zadataka za rudarstvo socijalnih medija za zdravlje (SMM4H) 2020. U zadatku 2, moramo diferencirati nuspojavne reakcije na drogu (ADR) tweets od non ADR tweets i tretirati se kao binarnu klasifikaciju. Task 3 uključuje izvlačenje spomena ADR-a i onda ih mapiranje na MedDRA kodove. Izvlačenje spomena ADR-a tretira se kao etiketiranje sekvence i normaliziranje spomena ADR-a tretira se kao klasifikacija multiklasa. Naš sistem je baziran na predobučenom jezičkom modelu RoBERTa i postiže a) F1 rezultat od 58% u zadatku 2 koji je 12% više od prosječnog rezultata b) opušteni F1 rezultat od 70,1% u izvlačenju zadatka 3 ADR-a koji je 13,7% više od prosječnog rezultata i opuštenog F1 rezultata od 35% u izvlačenju ADR-a + normalizaciju zadatka 3 koji je 5,8% više od prosječnog rezultata. Općenito, naši modeli postignu obećavajuće rezultate u obje zadatke sa značajnim poboljšanjem preko prosječnih rezultata.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku je predstavljen naš pristop k nalogi 2 in 3 skupnih nalog socialnih medijev rudarjenje za zdravje (SMM4H) 2020. V nalogi 2 moramo razlikovati neželene učinke na zdravilo (ADR) tweets od non ADR tweets in se obravnavamo kot binarno klasifikacijo. Naloga 3 vključuje pridobivanje omenitev ARS in njihovo preslikavo v kode MedDRA. Izvlečevanje omemb ADR se obravnava kot označevanje zaporedja, normalizacija omemb ADR pa se obravnava kot razvrstitev več razredov. Naš sistem temelji na vnaprej usposobljenem jezikovnem modelu RoBERTa in dosega a) rezultat F1 58% v nalogi 2, kar je 12% več od povprečne rezultate b) sproščeno rezultat F1 70,1% pri ekstrakciji ADR 3, kar je 13,7% več od povprečne rezultate in sproščeno rezultat F1 35% pri ekstrakciji ADR + normalizacija naloge 3, kar je 5,8% več od povprečne rezultate. Na splošno naši modeli dosegajo obetavne rezultate pri obeh nalogah z znatnimi izboljšavami v primerjavi s povprečnimi rezultati.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Perintah iki dadi nggawe perintah dumadhi kanggo nggawe 2 nggo 3 nggawe barang Media Minng kanggo Kemerdekaan Sak Jaakan (SMM4H) 2020 ngerasakno 1=task 2 3 Name Kita sistem wis basa oleh-cara perusahaan anyar luwih model Punika, maneh sing paling nggawe model sing rumangsa akeh lan sawalik iki dadi sing luwih dumadhi kanggo kalagayan sing luwih dumadhi</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Bu takardan na gaurar da aikin mu wa aikin 2 and aikin 3 of society Media Mining for Heatherhood (SMM4H) 2020 Shared tasks. Kayyan aikin 2, ana hana mu rarrabe masu iya motsi ga aikin madawara (ADR) daga Twitter na nonADR kuma ana yi amfani da shi kamar fassar labari. Tafiyar 3 na ƙunsa da mai fitarwa na ADR kuma ka sami su zuwa kodin MedDR. Extracting ADR mentions is treated as sequence labeling and normalizing ADR mentions is treated as multi-class classification.  Ana kasar da tsarin mu a kan misalin harshen RoBERTa a gabãnin an yi amfani da shi, kuma yana sãmu a) F1-score na 58 cikin aikin 2 wanda ke da 12% ko kuma mafi ƙaranci score b) ya saka F1-score na 70.1% cikin rabon aikin ADR 3 da ke ƙara 13.7% da ke ƙaranci F1-score na halartar nau'i na 35% a ADR Extractin+na normal aikin aikin 3 wanda ke kasa 5.8%. Gansa, misãlai masu sami matsayin da ake yi wa'adi da su sami aikin dukansu da suka kyautata mafiya kyauta kan nauyi.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>העיתון הזה מציג את הגישה שלנו למשימה 2 ומשימה 3 של מחקר מדיה חברתית לבריאות (SMM4H) 2020 משותפים משותפים. במשימה 2, אנחנו צריכים להפריד את תגובת התרופות הלא רצינית (ADR) טוויטים מתוך טוויטים ללא ADR ומטפלים בתור מסווג בינרי. Task 3 involves extracting ADR mentions and then mapping them to MedDRA codes.  הוצאת הזכרונות של ADR מתייחסת כתווית רצף והזכרונות של ADR נורמלי מתייחסת כקליזציה רבה-מעמד. המערכת שלנו מבוססת על מודל שפה מאומן מראש RoBERTa והיא משיגה a) נקודת F1 של 58% במשימה 2 שהיא 12% יותר מהנקודת הממוצעת b) נקודת F1 מרגיעה של 70.1% בהוצאה ADR של משימה 3 שהיא 13.7% יותר מהנקודת הממוצעת והנקודת F1 מרגיעה של 35% בהוצאה ADR + נורמליזציה של משימה 3 שהיא 5.8% יותר מהנקודה הממוצעת. באופן כללי, הדוגמנים שלנו מגיעים לתוצאות מבטיחות בשני המשימות עם שיפורים משמעותיים מעל נקודות ממוצעים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་ང་ཚོའི་གཟུགས་སྐོར་ལ་བྱ་རིམ་དང་། སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་དྲ་སྤྲོད་ཀྱི་ཞབས་ཞུ་གཏོང་(SMM4H)སྤྱི་ཚ In task 2, we have to differentiate adverse drug reaction (ADR) tweets from nonADR tweets and is treated as binary classification. Task 3 involves extracting ADR mentions and then mapping them to MedDRA codes. Extracting ADR mentions is treated as sequence labeling and normalizing ADR mentions is treated as multi-class classification. Our system is based on pre-trained language model RoBERTa and it achieves a) F1-score of 58% in task 2 which is 12% more than the average score b) relaxed F1-score of 70.1% in ADR extraction of task 3 which is 13.7% more than the average score and relaxed F1-score of 35% in ADR extraction + normalization of task 3 which is 5.8% more than the average score. འཇུག་བརྡན་ན། མིག་དཔེ་དབྱིབས་མ་ཚད་རྒྱ་ནག་གི་ཚད་ལྟར་འགྱུར་རྐྱེན་པའི་ཁས་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་ཐུབ་པ་ཡིན།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Detecting Tweets Reporting Birth Defect Pregnancy Outcome Using Two-View CNN RNN Based Architecture<fixed-case>CNN</fixed-case> <fixed-case>RNN</fixed-case> Based Architecture</title>
      <author><first>Saichethan</first><last>Reddy</last></author>
      <pages>125–127</pages>
      <abstract>This research work addresses a new multi-class classification task (fifth task) provided at the fifth Social Media Mining for Health Applications (SMM4H) workshop. This automatic tweet classification task involves distinguishing three classes of tweets that mention <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birth_defect">birth defects</a>. We propose a novel two view based CNN-BiGRU based architectures for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(computing)">task</a>. Experimental evaluation of our proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_architecture">architecture</a> over the validation set gives encouraging results as it improves by approximately 7 % over our single view model for the fifth task. Code of our proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_framework">framework</a> is made available on Github</abstract>
      <url hash="69d81814">2020.smm4h-1.21</url>
      <bibkey>reddy-2020-detecting</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/smm4h">SMM4H</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>LITL at SMM4H : An Old-school Feature-based Classifier for Identifying Adverse Effects in Tweets<fixed-case>LITL</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>SMM</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>: An Old-school Feature-based Classifier for Identifying Adverse Effects in Tweets</title>
      <author><first>Ludovic</first><last>Tanguy</last></author>
      <author><first>Lydia-Mai</first><last>Ho-Dac</last></author>
      <author><first>Cécile</first><last>Fabre</last></author>
      <author><first>Roxane</first><last>Bois</last></author>
      <author><first>Touati Mohamed Yacine</first><last>Haddad</last></author>
      <author><first>Claire</first><last>Ibarboure</last></author>
      <author><first>Marie</first><last>Joyau</last></author>
      <author><first>François</first><last>Le moal</last></author>
      <author><first>Jade</first><last>Moiilic</last></author>
      <author><first>Laura</first><last>Roudaut</last></author>
      <author><first>Mathilde</first><last>Simounet</last></author>
      <author><first>Irena</first><last>Stankovic</last></author>
      <author><first>Mickaela</first><last>Vandewaetere</last></author>
      <pages>134–137</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our participation to the SMM4H shared task 2. We designed a rule-based classifier that estimates whether a tweet mentions an adverse effect associated to a medication. Our system addresses <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>, and is based on a number of specific word lists and features. These cues were mostly obtained through an extensive corpus analysis of the provided training data. Different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weighting">weighting schemes</a> were tested (manually tuned or based on a logistic regression), the best one achieving a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-number">F1 score</a> of 0.31 for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and 0.15 for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="8776f27d">2020.smm4h-1.24</url>
      <bibkey>tanguy-etal-2020-litl</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/smm4h">SMM4H</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="25">
      <title>Sentence Classification with Imbalanced Data for Health Applications</title>
      <author><first>Farhana Ferdousi</first><last>Liza</last></author>
      <pages>138–145</pages>
      <abstract>Identifying and extracting reports of medications, their abuse or adverse effects from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> is a challenging task. In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>, relevant reports are very infrequent, causes imbalanced class distribution for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning algorithms</a>. Learning algorithms typically designed to optimize the overall accuracy without considering the relative distribution of each class. Thus, imbalanced class distribution is problematic as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">learning algorithms</a> have low predictive accuracy for the infrequent class. Moreover, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> represents natural linguistic variation in creative language expressions. In this paper, we have used a combination of data balancing and neural language representation techniques to address the challenges. Specifically, we participated the shared tasks 1, 2 (all languages), 4, and 3 (only the span detection, no normalization was attempted) in Social Media Mining for Health applications (SMM4H) 2020 (Klein et al., 2020). The results show that with the proposed methodology <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall scores</a> are better than the precision scores for the shared tasks. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall score</a> is also better compared to the mean score of the total submissions. However, the F1-score is worse than the mean score except for task 2 (French).</abstract>
      <url hash="5f506409">2020.smm4h-1.25</url>
      <bibkey>liza-2020-sentence</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/smm4h">SMM4H</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="31">
      <title>Sentence Contextual Encoder with BERT and BiLSTM for Automatic Classification with Imbalanced Medication Tweets<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> and <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>i<fixed-case>LSTM</fixed-case> for Automatic Classification with Imbalanced Medication Tweets</title>
      <author><first>Olanrewaju Tahir</first><last>Aduragba</last></author>
      <author><first>Jialin</first><last>Yu</last></author>
      <author><first>Gautham</first><last>Senthilnathan</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexandra</first><last>Crsitea</last></author>
      <pages>165–167</pages>
      <abstract>This paper details the system description and approach used by our team for the SMM4H 2020 competition, Task 1. Task 1 targets the automatic classification of tweets that mention medication. We adapted the standard BERT pretrain-then-fine-tune approach to include an intermediate training stage with a biLSTM architecture neural network acting as a further fine-tuning stage. We were inspired by the effectiveness of within-task further pre-training and sentence encoders. We show that this approach works well for a highly imbalanced dataset. In this case, the positive class is only 0.2 % of the entire dataset. Our model performed better in both F1 and precision scores compared to the mean score for all participants in the competition and had a competitive recall score.</abstract>
      <url hash="fd8de0a9">2020.smm4h-1.31</url>
      <bibkey>aduragba-etal-2020-sentence</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>