<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.udw">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on Universal Dependencies (UDW 2020)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Marie-Catherine</first><last>de Marneffe</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Miryam</first><last>de Lhoneux</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Joakim</first><last>Nivre</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sebastian</first><last>Schuster</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="6d1f74e6">2020.udw-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>udw-2020-universal</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Verification, Reproduction and Replication of NLP Experiments : a Case Study on Parsing Universal Dependencies<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Experiments: a Case Study on Parsing <fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependencies</title>
      <author><first>Çağrı</first><last>Çöltekin</last></author>
      <pages>46–56</pages>
      <abstract>As in any field of inquiry that depends on experiments, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verifiability">verifiability</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Experiment">experimental studies</a> is important in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">computational linguistics</a>. Despite increased attention to verification of empirical results, the practices in the field are unclear. Furthermore, we argue, certain traditions and practices that are seemingly useful for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verificationism">verification</a> may in fact be counterproductive. We demonstrate this through a set of multi-lingual experiments on parsing Universal Dependencies treebanks. In particular, we show that emphasis on exact replication leads to practices (some of which are now well established) that hide the variation in experimental results, effectively hindering verifiability with a false sense of certainty. The purpose of the present paper is to highlight the magnitude of the issues resulting from these common practices with the hope of instigating further discussion. Once we, as a community, are convinced about the importance of the problems, the solutions are rather obvious, although not necessarily easy to implement.</abstract>
      <url hash="60b6e037">2020.udw-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>coltekin-2020-verification</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Land_mine">LFG</a> To <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urban_exploration">UD</a> : A Combined Approach<fixed-case>LFG</fixed-case> To <fixed-case>UD</fixed-case>: A Combined Approach</title>
      <author><first>Cheikh M. Bamba</first><last>Dione</last></author>
      <pages>57–66</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports on a systematic approach for deriving Universal Dependencies from LFG structures. The conversion starts with a step-wise transformation of the c-structure, combining part-of-speech (POS) information and the embedding path to determine the true head of dependency structures. The paper discusses several issues faced by existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithms</a> when applied on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolof_language">Wolof</a> and presents the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy">strategies</a> used to account for these issues. An experimental evaluation indicated that our approach was able to generate the correct output in more than 90 % of the cases, leading to a substantial improvement in conversion accuracy compared to the previous models.</abstract>
      <url hash="84d19d0f">2020.udw-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>dione-2020-lfg</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Configurable Dependency Tree Extraction from CCG Derivations<fixed-case>CCG</fixed-case> Derivations</title>
      <author><first>Kilian</first><last>Evang</last></author>
      <pages>87–93</pages>
      <abstract>We revisit the problem of extracting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependency_grammar">dependency structures</a> from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependency_grammar">derivation structures</a> of Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG). Previous approaches are often restricted to a narrow subset of CCG or support only one flavor of dependency tree. Our approach is more general and easily configurable, so that multiple styles of dependency tree can be obtained. In an initial case study, we show promising results for converting English, German, Italian, and Dutch CCG derivations from the Parallel Meaning Bank into (unlabeled) UD-style dependency trees.</abstract>
      <url hash="952e71bd">2020.udw-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>evang-2020-configurable</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    <title_es>Extracción de árbol de dependencias configurable de derivaciones de CCG</title_es>
      <title_pt>Extração de árvore de dependência configurável de derivações CCG</title_pt>
      <title_ar>استخلاص شجرة تبعية قابل للتكوين من اشتقاقات CCG</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Extraction de l'arbre de dépendance configurable à partir des dérivations</title_fr>
      <title_zh>取 CCG 生可配者</title_zh>
      <title_ru>Настраиваемое извлечение дерева зависимостей из производных CCG</title_ru>
      <title_ja>CCG派生からの構成可能な依存関係ツリー抽出</title_ja>
      <title_hi>CCG व्युत्पत्ति से विन्यास निर्भरता ट्री निष्कर्षण</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Sliocht Crann Spleáchais Inchumraithe ó Dhíorthaigh CCG</title_ga>
      <title_ka>CCG დერივიაციებიდან დარწმუნებელი გადარწმუნებელი ხე ექსტრექცია</title_ka>
      <title_el>Διαμορφώσιμη εξαγωγή δέντρου εξάρτησης από παράγωγα CCG</title_el>
      <title_hu>Konfigurálható függőségfa kivonás CCG származékokból</title_hu>
      <title_it>Estrazione configurabile dell'albero di dipendenza da derivati CCG</title_it>
      <title_kk>CCG түрлендіруден баптаулық Тәуелдік Бұтақты тарқату</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Konfigūruojamas priklausomybės medžio ekstrahavimas iš pagrindinės sandorio šalies išvestinių lėšų</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Name</title_mk>
      <title_mt>Estrazzjoni ta’ Siġar ta’ Dipendenza Konfigurabbli mid-Derivattivi tas-CCG</title_mt>
      <title_ml>CCG ഡെറിവേഷനുകളില്‍ നിന്നും ആശ്രയിക്കുന്ന വൃക്ഷത്തെ ക്രമീകരിക്കുക</title_ml>
      <title_mn>ЦХГ-ын хамгаалалтаас итгэлтэй хамааралтай мод</title_mn>
      <title_no>Set opp avhengighetstre-utpakking frå CCG-avhengighet</title_no>
      <title_pl>Konfigurowalna ekstrakcja drzewa zależności z pochodnych CCG</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Extragerea copacului de dependență configurabilă din derivații CCG</title_ro>
      <title_ms>Ekstraksi Pohon Dependensi Boleh Konfigur Dari Derivation CCG</title_ms>
      <title_sr>Povjerljivo izvlačenje drveta zavisnosti iz CCG odvajanja</title_sr>
      <title_si>CCG නිරීක්ෂණයෙන් විශ්වාස කරන්න පුළුවන් විශ්වාස විශේෂතාවක් ගස් බිඳින්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Configurable Dependency Tree Extraction from CCG Derivations</title_so>
      <title_sv>Konfigurerbar beroendeträdextraktion från CCG-derivat</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>سی سی جی ڈریویٹ سے قائم رکھنے والی اعتمادی تری نکالی</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Cấu hình độ phụ thuộc cây</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Configureerbare afhankelijkheidsboomextractie uit CCG-derivaten</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Конфигурируемо извличане на дървото на зависимостта от производни на CCG</title_bg>
      <title_da>Konfigurerbar afhængighedstræekstraktion fra CCG-derivater</title_da>
      <title_hr>Povjerljivo izvlačenje drveta ovisnosti iz odvajanja CCG-a</title_hr>
      <title_de>Konfigurierbare AbhĂ¤ngigkeitsbaumextraktion aus CCG-Ableitungen</title_de>
      <title_id>Ekstraksi Pohon Dependensi Konfigurabel dari Derivasi CCG</title_id>
      <title_ko>CCG 파생에서 구성 가능 종속 트리 추출</title_ko>
      <title_fa>استخراج از درخت بستگی قابل تأیید از دزدی CCG</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Utoa wa Mti wa Kutegemea Kutokana na CCG</title_sw>
      <title_tr>CCG Kiçilikden ynamlyk Treei Açmak</title_tr>
      <title_af>Konfiguraabele Afhanklikheid Boom Uitpakking van CCG Afwyking</title_af>
      <title_sq>Ekstraksioni i konfigurueshëm i drurit të varësisë nga derivatat CCG</title_sq>
      <title_am>ዶሴ `%s'ን ማስፈጠር አልተቻለም፦ %s</title_am>
      <title_hy>Comment</title_hy>
      <title_az>CCG Derivasyonlarƒ±ndan t…ôsdiql…ônil…ôn baƒüƒ±mlƒ±lƒ±q aƒüacƒ± A√ßƒ±rmasƒ±</title_az>
      <title_bn>CCG ডেরিভেশন থেকে নির্ভরিত বৃক্ষ কনফিগার করুন</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Povjerljivo izvlačenje drveta ovisnosti iz odvajanja CCG-a</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Configurable Dependency Tree Extraction from CCG Derivations</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Konfigurovatelná extrakce stromu závislosti z CCG derivátů</title_cs>
      <title_et>Seadistatav sõltuvuspuu ekstraheerimine CCG tuletistest</title_et>
      <title_fi>Määritettävän riippuvuuspuun poiminta CCG-johdannaisista</title_fi>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_jv>Tatanan Sampeyan Jaringan</title_jv>
      <title_bo>CCG Derivations ཐོག་ནས་རིམ་སྒྲིག་རུང་བའི་རྟེན་འབྲེལ་བ་སྡོང་ཕྱིར་འདུག</title_bo>
      <title_sk>Nastavljivo ekstrakcijo drevesa odvisnosti iz izpeljanih CCG</title_sk>
      <title_he>Configurable Dependency Tree Extraction from CCG Derivations</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>نعيد النظر في مشكلة استخراج هياكل التبعية من هياكل اشتقاق القواعد الفئوية التجميعية (CCG). غالبًا ما تقتصر الأساليب السابقة على مجموعة فرعية ضيقة من CCG أو تدعم نكهة واحدة فقط من شجرة التبعية. نهجنا أكثر عمومية وقابل للتكوين بسهولة ، بحيث يمكن الحصول على أنماط متعددة من شجرة التبعية. في دراسة حالة أولية ، نعرض نتائج واعدة لتحويل مشتقات CCG الإنجليزية والألمانية والإيطالية والهولندية من بنك المعنى الموازي إلى أشجار تبعية على غرار UD (غير مسماة).</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_fr>Nous revoyons le problème de l'extraction des structures de dépendance à partir des structures de dérivation de la grammaire catégorielle combinatoire (CCG). Les approches précédentes sont souvent limitées à un sous-ensemble restreint de CCG ou ne prennent en charge qu'un seul type d'arbre de dépendance. Notre approche est plus générale et facilement configurable, de sorte que plusieurs styles d'arbre de dépendance peuvent être obtenus. Dans une première étude de cas, nous montrons des résultats prometteurs pour la conversion des dérivations CCG en anglais, allemand, italien et néerlandais de la Banque de significations parallèles en arbres de dépendance de style UD (non étiquetés).</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_pt>Revisitamos o problema de extrair estruturas de dependência das estruturas de derivação da Gramática Categorial Combinatória (CCG). As abordagens anteriores geralmente são restritas a um subconjunto estreito de CCG ou suportam apenas um tipo de árvore de dependência. Nossa abordagem é mais geral e facilmente configurável, de modo que vários estilos de árvore de dependência podem ser obtidos. Em um estudo de caso inicial, mostramos resultados promissores para a conversão de derivações de CCG em inglês, alemão, italiano e holandês do Parallel Meaning Bank em árvores de dependência (não rotuladas) no estilo UD.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Revisamos el problema de extraer estructuras de dependencia de las estructuras de derivación de la gramática categorial combinatoria (CCG). Los enfoques anteriores a menudo se restringen a un subconjunto estrecho de CCG o admiten solo una variante de árbol de dependencias. Nuestro enfoque es más general y fácilmente configurable, de modo que se pueden obtener múltiples estilos de árbol de dependencias. En un estudio de caso inicial, mostramos resultados prometedores para convertir las derivaciones de CCG en inglés, alemán, italiano y holandés del banco de significados paralelos en árboles de dependencias al estilo UD (sin etiqueta).</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>複合カテゴリアル文法（ CCG ）の導出構造から依存構造を抽出する問題を再検討する。以前のアプローチは、多くの場合、CCGの狭いサブセットに制限されているか、依存関係ツリーの1つのフレーバーのみをサポートしています。当社のアプローチはより一般的で、簡単に構成可能であるため、複数のスタイルの依存関係ツリーを取得できます。初期のケーススタディでは、Parallel Meaning Bankからの英語、ドイツ語、イタリア語、オランダ語のCCG派生を（ラベル付けされていない） UDスタイルの依存関係ツリーに変換するための有望な結果を示しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>हम Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG) की व्युत्पत्ति संरचनाओं से निर्भरता संरचनाओं को निकालने की समस्या को फिर से देखते हैं। पिछले दृष्टिकोण अक्सर सीसीजी के एक संकीर्ण सबसेट तक सीमित होते हैं या निर्भरता पेड़ के केवल एक स्वाद का समर्थन करते हैं। हमारा दृष्टिकोण अधिक सामान्य और आसानी से कॉन्फ़िगर करने योग्य है, ताकि निर्भरता पेड़ की कई शैलियों को प्राप्त किया जा सके। एक प्रारंभिक मामले के अध्ययन में, हम समानांतर अर्थ बैंक से अंग्रेजी, जर्मन, इतालवी और डच सीसीजी व्युत्पत्ति को (बिना लेबल के) यूडी-शैली निर्भरता पेड़ों में परिवर्तित करने के लिए आशाजनक परिणाम दिखाते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>重审分类语法(CCG)生结构。 前法常限 CCG 一狭子集,或止支一依树。 吾法更通用而易配,故可得多方。 于初例研究,展将英语、德语、意大利语、荷兰语 CCG 遣生从平行含义库转换为(未标者)UD 式依树之望。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>Мы вернемся к проблеме извлечения структур зависимостей из производных структур комбинированной грамматики категорий (CCG). Предыдущие подходы часто ограничиваются узким подмножеством CCG или поддерживают только один аромат дерева зависимостей. Наш подход является более общим и легко настраиваемым, так что можно получить несколько стилей дерева зависимостей. В первоначальном тематическом исследовании мы показываем многообещающие результаты преобразования производных CCG на английском, немецком, итальянском и голландском языках из банка параллельных значений в (немеченные) деревья зависимостей в стиле UD.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Breathnaímid arís ar an bhfadhb a bhaineann le struchtúir spleáchais a bhaint as struchtúir díorthaithe na Gramadaí Catagóire Comhcheangailte (CCG). Is minic go mbíonn cineálacha cur chuige roimhe seo teoranta d’fhothacar caol CCG nó ní thacaíonn siad ach le blas amháin de chrann spleáchais. Tá ár gcur chuige níos ginearálta agus is furasta é a chumrú, ionas gur féidir cineálacha éagsúla crann spleáchais a fháil. I gcás-staidéar tosaigh, léirímid torthaí geallta maidir le díorthaigh CCG Béarla, Gearmáinis, Iodáilis agus Ollainnis ón mBanc Brí Comhthreomhar a thiontú ina gcrainn spleáchais (neamhlipéadaithe) ar stíl UD.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ გავაკეთებთ პრობლემა, რომელიც დამხოლოდ სტრუქტურების გამოყენების სტრუქტურების გამოყენების სტრუქტურებიდან. პირველი დახმარება უფრო განსაზღვრებულია CCG-ის ზუსტად სუბსეტისთვის, ან მხოლოდ ერთი სამყარო დამხმარებულობის ხელისთვის. ჩვენი პროგორმაცია უფრო სხვადასხვა და ადვილურად კონფიგურაციელია, რადგან უფრო მეტი სტილი დამხმარებული ხე იქნება. პირველი შემთხვევაში, ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ გვეჩვენებთ გავაკეთებული წარმოდგენება ინგლისური, გერმანური, თრალური და დონდენური CCG-ის განსხვავებების პარალელური Meaning Bank-ის</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A Kombinált Kategorial Grammar (CCG) származási struktúráiból való függőségi struktúrák kivonásának problémáját vizsgáljuk újra. A korábbi megközelítések gyakran a CCG szűk részhalmazára korlátozódnak, vagy csak egy ízű függőségi fát támogatnak. Megközelítésünk általánosabb és könnyen konfigurálható, így többféle függőségi stílus is elérhető. Egy első esettanulmányban ígéretes eredményeket mutatunk a Parallel Meaning Bank angol, német, olasz és holland CCG származékainak konvertálására (címke nélküli) UD-stílusú függőségi fákká.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Εξετάζουμε ξανά το πρόβλημα της εξαγωγής δομών εξάρτησης από τις δομές παραγώγησης της Συνδυαστικής Κατηγορικής Γραμματικής. Οι προηγούμενες προσεγγίσεις συχνά περιορίζονται σε ένα στενό υποσύνολο του ή υποστηρίζουν μόνο μία γεύση δέντρου εξάρτησης. Η προσέγγισή μας είναι πιο γενική και εύκολα διαμορφώσιμη, έτσι ώστε να μπορούν να ληφθούν πολλαπλά στυλ δέντρου εξάρτησης. Σε μια αρχική μελέτη περίπτωσης, παρουσιάζουμε ελπιδοφόρα αποτελέσματα για τη μετατροπή των παραγώγων της Αγγλικής, Γερμανικής, Ιταλικής και Ολλανδικής Τράπεζας Παράλληλης Σημαίας σε δέντρα εξάρτησης τύπου UD.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Riassumiamo il problema dell'estrazione delle strutture di dipendenza dalle strutture di derivazione della Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG). Gli approcci precedenti sono spesso limitati a un sottoinsieme ristretto di CCG o supportano solo un sapore di albero delle dipendenze. Il nostro approccio è più generale e facilmente configurabile, in modo che si possano ottenere più stili di albero delle dipendenze. In un primo caso di studio, abbiamo mostrato risultati promettenti per la conversione di derivazioni CCG inglesi, tedesche, italiane e olandesi dalla Parallel Meaning Bank in alberi di dipendenza in stile UD (senza etichetta).</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Persvarstome priklausomybės struktūrų gavimo iš Kombinuotosios kategorijos gramos (CCG) išvestinių struktūrų problem ą. Ankstesni metodai dažnai taikomi tik siauram CCG pogrupiui arba remia tik vieną priklausomybės medžio skonį. Mūsų požiūris yra bendresnis ir lengviau konfigūruoti, kad būtų galima gauti įvairius priklausomybės medžio stilius. Pradiniame atvejo tyrime parodome pažadėtinus rezultatus, kad anglų, vokiečių, Italijos ir Nyderlandų pagrindinės sandorio šalies išvestinės finansinės priemonės iš Parallel Meaning Bank konvertuojamos į UD tipo priklausomybės medžius.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Біз Тәуелсіздік құрылғыларды Комбинациялық санаттық грамма (CCG) құрылғыларынан шығару мәселесін қайта қайта жасадық. Алдыңғы жағдайлары көбінесе CCG астының қысқа бөлігіне шектелген немесе тек бір тәуелдік ағашының жарықтығын қолдауға болады. Біздің қасиетіміз жалпы және оңай баптаулық, сондықтан бірнеше тәуелдік ағашының стилі алу мүмкін. Бастапқы жағдайда, біз ағылшын, неміс, итальян және голландша CCG параллел Meaning Bank-ден UD стилінің тәуелсіздік ағаштарына аудару үшін үлкен нәтижелерді көрсетедік.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Го прегледаме проблемот со извлекувањето на структурите на зависност од структурите на дериминација на комбинаторната категоријална грама (CCG). Претходните пристапи честопати се ограничени на тесен подгруп на CCG или поддржуваат само еден вкус на дрво на зависност. Our approach is more general and easily configurable, so that multiple styles of dependency tree can be obtained.  Во првичната студија на случаите, покажуваме ветувачки резултати за претворање на англиски, германски, италијански и холандски деринации од ЦЦГ од паралелната банка на значење во дрвја на (неозначени) зависности во стил УД.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami mengulang semula masalah mengekstrak struktur dependensi dari struktur derivasi Grammar Kategori Kombinator (CCG). pendekatan terdahulu sering diharamkan kepada subset sempit CCG atau menyokong hanya satu rasa pokok dependensi. pendekatan kita adalah lebih umum dan mudah konfigurasi, sehingga gaya berbilang pokok dependensi boleh dicapai. Dalam kajian kes awal, kami menunjukkan keputusan yang berjanji untuk mengubah aliran CCG Inggeris, Jerman, Itali, dan Belanda dari Bank Maksud Paralel ke pokok dependensi gaya UD (tanpa label).</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ആശ്രയിക്കുന്ന സ്ഥാനങ്ങള്‍ പുറത്തെടുക്കുന്നതിന്‍റെ പ്രശ്നം നമ്മള്‍ വീണ്ടും വീണ്ടും വീണ്ടും വീണ്ടും വീണ്ടും വീണ്ടും വീ മുമ്പുള്ള പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ സിസിജിയിലെ ചെറുതായ പബ്ബട്ടിലേക്ക് നിര്‍ബന്ധിതരാകുന്നു. അല്ലെങ്കില്‍ ആശ്രയിക് നമ്മുടെ അടുത്തേക്ക് വളരെ സാധാരണ ക്രമീകരിക്കുന്നതും എളുപ്പമുള്ളതുമാണ്. അതുകൊണ്ട് ആശ്രയിക്കുന്ന വൃക്ഷത് ആദ്യമായ ഒരു കേസ് പഠനത്തില്‍, ഇംഗ്ലീഷ്, ജര്‍മ്മന്‍, ഇറ്റലിയന്‍, ഡാച്ച് സിസിജിയെ മാറ്റുന്നതിനുള്ള പ്രത്യേക ഫലങ്ങള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു. പാരാളല്‍ ബാങ്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nirrevedu l-problema tal-estrazzjoni tal-istrutturi tad-dipendenza mill-istrutturi tad-derivazzjoni tal-Gramma Kategorjali Kombinatorja (CCG). L-approċċi preċedenti ta’ spiss huma ristretti għal sottosett dejjaq ta’ CCG jew jappoġġjaw biss togħma waħda ta’ siġar ta’ dipendenza. L-approċċ tagħna huwa aktar ġenerali u faċilment konfigurabbli, sabiex jinkisbu diversi stili ta’ siġar ta’ dipendenza. Fi studju inizjali ta’ każ, qed nuru riżultati promettenti għall-konverżjoni tad-derivazzjonijiet tas-CCG Ingliż, Ġermaniż, Taljan u Olandiż mill-Bank Parallel Meaning f’siġar ta’ dipendenza (mingħajr tikketta) tal-istil UD.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Бид хамааралтай байгууллагын бүтцийг Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG) болон хамааралтай байгууллагын бүтцийг авах асуудлыг дахин шинэчлэх болно. Өмнөх арга баримтууд CCG-ын бага хэсэгт хязгаарлагддаг эсвэл хамааралтай модын амттай ганц амттай байдаг. Бидний арга зам илүү ерөнхий болон амархан загварчлах боломжтой. Тиймээс олон төрлийн хамааралтай мод гаргаж болно. Эхлээд судалгаанд бид Англи, Герман, Итали, Далландын CCG-ын параллел Meaning Bank-ээс UD хэлбэрээр хамааралтай модыг шилжүүлэх амлалтай үр дүнг харуулж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Vi gjenoppretter problemet med å pakka ut avhengighetsstrukturene frå avhengighetsstrukturene av kombinert kategorigrafisk Grammar (CCG). Førre tilnærmingar er ofte begrenset til ein liten underdelen av CCG eller støtta berre ein flavor av avhengighetstrået. Tilnærminga vårt er mer generell og lett oppsettbar, slik at fleire stilar av avhengighetstreet kan få fram. I eit opprinnelig studie viser vi promiserende resultat for konvertering av anglesk, tysk, italiensk og nederlandsk CCG-derivasjonar frå Parallel Meaning Bank til UD-stilavhengighetstre.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Ponownie podejmujemy problem wyodrębniania struktur zależności ze struktur pochodnych Gramatyki Kategorialnej (CCG). Poprzednie podejścia są często ograniczone do wąskiego podzbioru CCG lub obsługują tylko jeden smak drzewa zależności. Nasze podejście jest bardziej ogólne i łatwe do konfiguracji, dzięki czemu można uzyskać wiele stylów drzewa zależności. W pierwszym studium przypadku pokazano obiecujące wyniki konwersji angielskich, niemieckich, włoskich i holenderskich pochodnych CCG z banku równoległego znaczenia na (nieoznakowane) drzewa zależności w stylu UD.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Revizuim problema extragerii structurilor de dependenţă din structurile de derivaţie ale Grammaticii Combinative Categoriale (CCG). Abordările anterioare sunt adesea limitate la un subset îngust de CCG sau susțin doar o singură aromă de arbore de dependență. Abordarea noastră este mai generală și ușor configurabilă, astfel încât să se poată obține mai multe stiluri de arbore de dependență. Într-un studiu de caz inițial, prezentăm rezultate promițătoare pentru convertirea derivatelor CCG din limba engleză, germană, italiană și olandeză de la Banca de înțelegere paralelă în arbori de dependență (fără etichete) în stil UD.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Pregledali smo problem izvlačenja struktura zavisnosti iz struktura derivacije kombinacije kategorije Grammara (CCG). Prethodni pristupi su često ograničeni na usku podskupinu CCG-a ili podržavaju samo jednu ukus drveta zavisnosti. Naš pristup je općenitiji i lako konfigurabilniji, tako da se može dobiti višestruki stil drveta zavisnosti. U početnoj studiji slučajeva pokazujemo obećavajuće rezultate za preobraćanje proizvoda engleskog, nemačkog, italijanskog i holandskog CCG iz Parallel Meaning Banke u drveće zavisnosti UD-stila.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නය කරනවා විශේෂතාවක් නිර්මාණය කරන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් සම්බන්ධ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ පසුගින් ප්‍රවේශනය සාමාන්‍ය වෙනුවෙන් CCG සම්බන්ධයක් නැති වෙනුවෙන් සම්බන්ධතාවක් නැති වෙනුවෙන් සම්බන අපේ ප්‍රවේශනය තරම් සාමාන්‍ය සහ ලේසියෙන් සැකසුම් වෙන්න පුළුවන්, ඉතින් විශේෂතාවක් විශේෂ ගස්ස පටන් ගත්ත විදියට, අපි ඉංග්‍රීසි, ජර්මන්, ඉතාලියාන් සහ ඩච්ච් CCG ප්‍රශ්නයක් පෙන්වන්න පොරොන්දු වාර්තාවක් පෙන්වන්නේ, UD</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Vi återkommer till problemet med att extrahera beroendestrukturer från härledningsstrukturerna i Kombinatorisk Kategorisk Grammatik (CCG). Tidigare tillvägagångssätt begränsas ofta till en smal delmängd av CCG eller stöder endast en smak av beroendeträd. Vårt tillvägagångssätt är mer generellt och enkelt konfigurerbart, så att flera stilar av beroendeträd kan erhållas. I en inledande fallstudie visar vi lovande resultat för att konvertera engelska, tyska, italienska och holländska CCG-derivat från Parallell Meaning Bank till (omärkta) beroendeträd i UD-stil.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Dhibaatada ka soo saarashada dhismaha ay ku xiran tahay waxaan ka soo celinaynaa dhismaha dhaqanka kambinarka (CCG). Dhaqdooyinkii hore waa inta badan ay ku xadgudbaan qeyb fudud CCG ama ay kaalmeeyaan geed kaliya oo ku xiran. Dhaqdhaqaalahayagu waa mid ka caadi ah oo si fudud u sameyn karo, si aad u heli karto noocyo badan oo geed ku xiran. Waxbarashada bilowga ah waxaynu tusnaynaa resultooyin ballan ah oo laga beddelo Ingiriis, Jarmal, Talyaani iyo CCG oo ka soo wareegsan jardiinada baarlamaanka ee u jeeda (aan labeled) geedaha ku xiran UD-style.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>சார்பு அமைப்புகளை வெளியேற்றும் பிரச்சனை முந்தைய செயல்பாடுகள் எப்பொழுதும் சிசிஜியின் சிறிய கட்டுப்பொருளுக்கு வரையறுக்கப்படுகிறது அல்லது சார்ந்த ச நம்முடைய செயல்பாடு மிகவும் பொதுவான மற்றும் எளிதாக வடிவமைக்கும், அதனால் பல வகைகள் சார்ந்த சார்பு மரத்தின்  ஒரு ஆரம்ப விஷயத்தில், நாம் வாக்குறுதியான முடிவுகளை காட்டுகிறோம் ஆங்கிலத்தில், ஜெர்மன், இத்தாலியன் மற்றும் டாச்ச் சிசிஜி பிரிவுகளை பார்த்துக</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم نے مسئلہ کو دوبارہ تخلیق کرنا کی مسئلہ کی تخلیق کرنا (CCG) کی کمbinatory Categorial Grammar کی طرح سے۔ اگلوں کی طریقے اکثر CCG کے تنگ سپس سے محدود ہوتے ہیں یا صرف ایک وابستگی درخت کی مزہ مدد کرتے ہیں. ہمارا طریقہ بہت ساده اور آسان طریقہ پر قائم ہوتا ہے، تاکہ تعلق درخت کے بہت سے طریقے حاصل کئے جائیں۔ ہم انگلیسی، جرمانی، ایتالیایی اور ڈرچ سی جی کے پیدا کرنے کے لئے وعدہ دینے والے نتیجے دکھاتے ہیں کہ پارالل منظور بانک سے (غیر نامیدہ) UD-style dependency درختوں کے درختوں میں اخلائے جاتے ہیں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Biz Kombinator kategorial grammatikal (CCG) tuzuvchidagi ishlatuvchi ishlatuvchi muammolarni qaytadan qayta yuboramiz. @ info Bizning usuli umumiy va oddiy moslab bo'ladi, shunday qilib qo'shimcha daraxtning ko'pchilik uslublari topish mumkin. Birinchi marta o'rganishda, biz Inglizcha, Olmoncha, Italyani va Dutch CCG tashkilotlarini Parallel Bank (notoʻgʻri) tarkibini UD uslubga ishlatuvchi daraxtlarga aytib ko'rsamiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng ta thăm lại vấn đề về việc khai thác các cấu trúc phụ thuộc từ các cấu trúc phân biệt của Grammar (CCG). Những phương pháp trước thường bị giới hạn bởi một nhóm nhỏ của CCG hoặc hỗ trợ chỉ một loại hương vị của cây phụ thuộc. Cách tiếp cận của chúng tôi là chung và dễ cấu hình hơn, để có thể kiếm được nhiều kiểu cây phụ thuộc. Trong một nghiên cứu đầu tiên, chúng tôi cho thấy kết quả hứa hẹn trong việc chuyển đổi sản phẩm theo kiểu Anh, Đức, Ý, và Trung tâm Cộng Hòa từ the Parallel meaning Bank thành (đã không được bảo vệ) UD phụ thuộc.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Преразглеждаме проблема с извличането на зависими структури от производните структури на Комбинаторната категорична граматика. Предишните подходи често са ограничени до тясна подгрупа или поддържат само един вкус на дърво на зависимост. Нашият подход е по-общ и лесно конфигурируем, така че да могат да бъдат получени множество стилове на дървото на зависимостта. В първоначално проучване на казуса показваме обещаващи резултати за преобразуване на английски, немски, италиански и холандски производни от Паралелната банка на значението в (немаркирани) дървета на зависимост в стил UD.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We bespreken het probleem van het extraheren van afhankelijkheidsstructuren uit de afgeleide structuren van Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG). Eerdere benaderingen zijn vaak beperkt tot een smalle subset van CCG of ondersteunen slechts één smaak van afhankelijkheidsboom. Onze aanpak is meer algemeen en gemakkelijk te configureren, zodat meerdere stijlen van afhankelijkheidsboom kunnen worden verkregen. In een eerste casestudy tonen we veelbelovende resultaten voor het omzetten van Engelse, Duitse, Italiaanse en Nederlandse CCG-afgeleiden van de Parallel Meaning Bank in (niet-gelabelde) UD-stijl afhankelijkheidsbomen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Vi gennemgår problemet med at udvinde afhængighedsstrukturer fra afledningsstrukturerne i Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG). Tidligere tilgange er ofte begrænset til en smal delmængde af CCG eller understøtter kun én smag af afhængighedstræ. Vores tilgang er mere generel og let konfigurerbar, så flere stilarter af afhængighedstræ kan opnås. I et første casestudie viser vi lovende resultater for at konvertere engelske, tyske, italienske og hollandske CCG-derivater fra Parallel Meaning Bank til afhængighedstræer i UD-stil.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Pregledali smo problem izvlačenja struktura zavisnosti iz struktura derivacije kombiniranih kategorijskih grammara (CCG). Prethodni pristupi često ograničeni su na usku podskupinu CCG-a ili podržavaju samo jednu ukus drveta ovisnosti. Naš pristup je općeniji i lako konfiguriraniji, tako da se može dobiti višestruki stil drveta zavisnosti. U početnom istraživanju slučajeva pokazujemo obećavajuće rezultate za preobraćanje proizvoda engleskog, njemačkog, italijanskog i holandskog CCG iz Parallel Meaning Banke u drveće ovisnosti UD-stila.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Wir beschäftigen uns mit dem Problem der Extraktion von Abhängigkeitsstrukturen aus den Ableitungsstrukturen der Kombinatorischen Kategorischen Grammatik (CCG). Bisherige Ansätze beschränken sich oft auf eine enge Teilmenge von CCG oder unterstützen nur eine Variante des Abhängigkeitsbaums. Unser Ansatz ist allgemeiner und einfach konfigurierbar, so dass mehrere Arten von Abhängigkeitsbaum erhalten werden können. In einer ersten Fallstudie zeigen wir vielversprechende Ergebnisse für die Umwandlung englischer, deutscher, italienischer und niederländischer CCG-Ableitungen aus der Parallel Meaning Bank in (nicht gekennzeichnete) UD-artige Abhängigkeitsbäume.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 조합범주문법(CCG)의 파생구조에서 의존구조를 추출하는 문제를 재검토했다.이전의 방법은 일반적으로 CCG의 좁은 서브집합에 국한되거나 하나의 유형의 의존 트리만 지원했다.우리의 방법은 더욱 통용되고 배치하기 쉬우므로 다양한 스타일의 의존 트리를 얻을 수 있다.최초의 사례 연구에서 우리는 영어, 독일어, 이탈리아어, 네덜란드어 CCG 파생어를 평행 의미 라이브러리에서 (표기되지 않은) UD 스타일 의존 트리로 전환한 유망한 결과를 보여 주었다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Tunapitia tena tatizo la kutengeneza miundombinu ya kutegemea na muundo wa Kikatuni cha Kombination (CCG). Matokeo yaliyopita mara nyingi yanazuiwa kwenye mfumo mfupi wa CCG au kuunga mkono mti mmoja tu wa kutegemea. Hatua yetu ni jumla zaidi na kwa urahisi, ili uwezekano wa aina mbalimbali za mti wa kutegemea. In an initial case study, we show promising results for converting English, German, Italian, and Dutch CCG derivations from the Parallel Meaning Bank into (unlabeled) UD-style dependency trees.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_id>Kami mengulangi masalah ekstraksi struktur dependensi dari struktur derivasi dari Kombinator Categorial Grammar (CCG). Pendekatan sebelumnya sering dibatasi ke subset sempit CCG atau mendukung hanya satu rasa pohon dependensi. pendekatan kita lebih umum dan mudah konfigurasi, sehingga gaya berbilang pohon dependensi dapat diperoleh. Dalam studi kasus awal, kami menunjukkan hasil yang berjanji untuk mengubah derivasi CCG Inggris, Jerman, Italia, dan Belanda dari Bank Maksudnya Paralel ke pohon dependensi gaya UD (tanpa label).</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>ما مشکل استخراج ساختارهای بستگی از ساختارهای استخراج از گرم‌گرم‌گر‌گر‌گر‌گر‌گر (CCG) را تغییر می‌دهیم. دسترسی قبلی اغلب به یک زیر کم از CCG محدود می‌شوند یا فقط یک بوی درخت بستگی حمایت می‌کنند. دستور ما ژنرال‌تر و آسان‌تر قابل پیکربندی است، تا بسیاری از طرح‌های درخت بستگی به دست آورده شود. در یک مطالعه پرونده اول، نتیجه‌های قول‌دهنده برای تغییر تولید انگلیسی، آلمانی، ایتالیایی و هلندی CCG از بانک معنی پارالل به درختان بستگی UD (نامیده شده) نشان می‌دهیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Vasitet döredilmelerini Combinative Categorial Grammar (CCG) döredilişinden çykarmak kynçylygynyň ýüklemegini üýtgedik. Öňki gollanmalar köplenç CCG'iň gysgy toparyna mümkin edýär ýada diňe bir bagly agajyň lezzetlerini destekleýär. Biziň ýaryşymyz has ukyply we aňsatlyk bilen döredilebilir, şonuň üçin birnäçe stili bagly agajyň içine alyp biler. Başga bir ýagdaýda, biz iňlisçe, nemes, italiýa we holandiýa CCG-iň Parallel Meaning Bank'dan UD stilinde baglary üýtgetmek üçin söz berýän netijeleri görkeýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>የካምቦራዊ ኮምቦርቲካዊ ግራማር (CCG) አካባቢ ግንኙነቶችን ለመውጣት ጉዳይ እንደገና እንመለሳለን፡፡ የቀድሞው ደረጃዎች የCCG አካባቢ አካባቢ ይደረጋሉ ወይም አንዲት ጣፋጭ የታመነች ዛፍ ብቻ ይደግፋሉ፡፡ ልግስናችን የጠቅላላ እና ቀላል ማግኘት ይችላል፡፡ በመጀመሪያው ጉዳይ ትምህርት፣ እንግሊዝኛ፣ ጀርመን፣ ኢጣሊያዊ እና የኬልክ CG ውጤቶች ከፓርላሌል ባንክ ወደ (ያልተፈቀደ) የUD-style የታመነ ዛፎች ለመለወጥ የተስፋ ፍሬ እናሳየዋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Ne përsërisim problemin e nxjerrjes së strukturave të varësisë nga strukturat e derivatave të Gramës Kombinatore Kategorore (CCG). Përqasjet e mëparshme shpesh janë të kufizuara në një nëngrup të ngushtë të CCG apo mbështesin vetëm një shije të drurit të varësisë. Përqafimi ynë është më i përgjithshëm dhe i konfigurueshëm lehtë, kështu që mund të arrihet stili i shumëfishtë i drurit të varësisë. Në një studim fillestar rasti, ne tregojmë rezultate premtuese për konvertimin e derivatave angleze, gjermane, italiane dhe hollandeze të CCG-së nga Banka Paralele e Ndërkuptimit në pemë të varura në stil UD.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_af>Ons hersien die probleem van uitpakking van afhanklikheid strukture van die afgeleide strukture van Kombineerlike Kategorie Grammar (CCG). Vorige toegang is dikwels beperk na 'n sterk subartikel van CCG of ondersteun slegs een vlak van afhanklikheid boom. Ons toegang is meer algemeen en maklik konfigureer, sodat veelvuldige style van afhanklikheidsboom kan verkry word. In 'n aanvanklike geval studie, vertoon ons beloftende resultate vir omskakeling van Engels, Duits, Italiese, en Nederlandse CCG afgeleide van die Parallel Meaning Bank na (ongeabelde) UD-styl afhanklikheidbome.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք կրկին քննարկում ենք կախվածության կառուցվածքների վերացման խնդիրը համակցառված կատեգորիալ գրամամայի կառուցվածքներից: Նախորդ մոտեցումները հաճախ սահմանափակվում են ընդհանուր կենտրոնային հատվածի սահմանափակ ենթախումբ կամ աջակցում են միայն մեկ կախվածության ծառի համ: Մեր մոտեցումը ավելի ընդհանուր է և հեշտությամբ կարելի է կազմել, որպեսզի կարելի է ստանալ կախվածության ծառի բազմաթիվ ոճեր: Սկզբնական դեպքերի ուսումնասիրության մեջ մենք ցույց ենք տալիս խոստացնող արդյունքներ անգլերեն, գերմաներեն, իտալանդական և հոլանդական համակարգչային հատվածային գաղափարների փոխարինելու համար զուգահեռ նշանակության բանկից UD-ի ոճի կախվածության ծառ</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Kombinativ Kategoriyal Grammar (CCG) qurularından bağımlılıq qurularını çıxartmaq problemini yenidən dəyişdiririk. Əvvəlki tərzimlər çox sıxıntılı CCG-nin qısa bir subgrupuna bağlı və ya yalnız bir təvəkküllük a ğacının təsirini dəstəkləyir. Bizim yaxınlığımız daha genel və asanlıqla konfigurasiyadır, böylece çoxlu təvəkküllük ağacının istifadəsi alınabilir. Əvvəlki məsələdə, İngilizce, Almanca, İtalyan və Hollandica CCG'nin Parallel Meaning Bank'dan UD-stil bağımlılıq ağaclarına dönüşdürməsi üçün vəd verici sonuçlarını göstəririk.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা কোম্বানিয়ন্ত্রিক ক্যাটারিয়াল গ্রামার (সিসিজি) থেকে নির্ভরিত কাঠামো বের করার সমস্যার পুনরায় পুনরায় বিবেচনা করি। পূর্ববর্তী পদক্ষেপ প্রায়শই সিসিজির একটি সংকীর্ণ বিভাগে সীমাবদ্ধ হয়ে যায় অথবা শুধুমাত্র একটি নির্ভরশীল গাছের আমাদের প্রতিযোগিতা বেশী সাধারণ এবং সহজে কনফিগার করা যায়, যাতে বেশ কয়েকটি নির্ভরশীল গাছ পাওয়া যায়। In an initial case study, we show promising results for converting English, German, Italian, and Dutch CCG derivations from the Parallel Meaning Bank into (unlabeled) UD-style dependency trees.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Pregledali smo problem izvlačenja struktura zavisnosti iz struktura derivacije kombinacije kategorije Grammara (CCG). Prethodni pristupi su često ograničeni na usku podskupinu CCG-a ili podržavaju samo jednu ukus drveta zavisnosti. Naš pristup je općeniji i lako konfigurativniji, tako da se može dobiti višestruki stil drveta zavisnosti. U početnoj studiji slučajeva, pokazujemo obećavajuće rezultate za preobraćanje proizvoda engleskog, njemačkog, italijanskog i holandskog CCG iz Parallel Meaning Banke u drveće ovisnosti UD-stila.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Revistim el problema de l'extracció d'estructures de dependencia de les estructures de derivació de la grama categoria combinadora (CCG). Els enfocaments anteriors sovint estan restringits a un petit subconjunt de GCC o només suporten un sabor d'arbre de dependencia. El nostre enfocament és més general i fàcil de configurar, de manera que es poden obtenir múltiples estils d'arbre de dependencia. En un primer estudi de cas, demostram resultats prometedors per convertir derivacions angleses, alemanes, italianes i holandeses de GCC del Banc Parallel Meaning en arbres de dependencia (sense etiqueta) d'estil UD.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Tarkastelemme uudelleen riippuvuusrakenteiden poimimista kombinaatioluokkaisen kieliopin (CCG) johdannaisrakenteista. Aiemmat lähestymistavat rajoittuvat usein kapeaan CCG:n osajoukkoon tai tukevat vain yhtä riippuvuuspuun makua. Lähestymistapamme on yleisempi ja helposti konfiguroitavissa, jotta voidaan saada useita riippuvuuspuun tyylejä. Ensimmäisessä tapaustutkimuksessa näytämme lupaavia tuloksia englannin, saksan, italian ja hollannin CCG-johdannaisten muuntamisessa Parallel Meaning Bankista (merkitsemättömiksi) UD-tyylisiksi riippuvuuspuiksi.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_cs>Opět se zabýváme problematikou extrakce závislostních struktur z odvozených struktur kombinované kategoriální gramatiky (CCG). Předchozí přístupy jsou často omezeny na úzkou podmnožinu CCG nebo podporují pouze jednu příchuť stromu závislosti. Náš přístup je obecnější a snadno konfigurovatelný, takže lze získat více stylů závislostního stromu. V první případové studii ukazujeme slibné výsledky pro konverzi anglických, německých, italských a nizozemských CCG odvození z banky paralelního významu do (neznačených) UD závislostních stromů.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Uurime sõltuvusstruktuuride eraldamise probleemi kombineeritud kategooriagrammatika (CCG) tuletamisstruktuuridest. Varasemad lähenemised on sageli piiratud CCG kitsa alamhulgaga või toetavad ainult ühte sõltuvuspuu maitset. Meie lähenemine on üldisem ja kergesti konfigureeritav, nii et saab hankida mitmeid sõltuvuspuu stiile. Esialgses juhtumiuuringus näitame paljutõotavaid tulemusi inglise, saksa, itaalia ja hollandi CCG tuletiste teisendamiseks paralleelse tähenduspangast (märgistamata) UD-stiilis sõltuvuspuudeks.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_sk>Ponovno obravnavamo problem ekstrakcije struktur odvisnosti iz struktur izpeljanja kombinacijske kategorijske slovnice (CCG). Prejšnji pristopi so pogosto omejeni na ozko podskupino CCG ali podpirajo samo en okus drevesa odvisnosti. Naš pristop je splošnejši in enostavno nastavljiv, tako da je mogoče pridobiti več slogov drevesa odvisnosti. V začetni študiji primera smo prikazali obetavne rezultate za pretvorbo angleških, nemških, italijanskih in nizozemskih derivatov CCG iz vzporedne banke pomena v (neoznačena) drevesa odvisnosti v slogu UD.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Za kure musamman ta fita masu inganci daga matsayin kombinorial Grammar (CCG). Tsarin da ya gabãta ana ƙayyade zuwa wani ƙarƙashin CCG mai ƙaranci ko kuma an ƙarfafa kowace wata itãce ta baka ɗabi'a. Mataimakinmu yana da mafiya jumla kuma mai sauƙi, dõmin a iya sãmu misãlai masu yawa na itãcen dependanci. Daga wani jarrabi na farko, Munã nũna fassarar da ake yi wa'adi da za'a mayar da mataimaki na Ingiriya, Jarman, Italian da kuma sauran CCG daga Parallel ɗin muhimmin Bank zuwa (ba da labels) mitin rubutu na UD.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>We resumed the question of extrapolation of diphenditor structural navigation from the Digawe sing oleh sing ditambah nyimpen nggo mbengok ujug-ujug kanggo ngetok ning acara cara sing ditambah panelok. Awak dhéwé ngerti luwih akeh lan akeh susahe sak ditambah, dadi sak kudu milih lan susahe panelak. Nang alih sing mulai, kita sembarang langkung pawaran kanggo nggawe layang tanggal Inggris, German, italian, lan kelas kaman kelas nggawe barang nggo Kemerdekaan Paralell means Banque nganggo perusahaan (gak nggawe sawaran) sedhayang kuwi mau.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་མཐུན་སྒྲིག་ཆ་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་རྩིས་འབྲེལ་ནས་ཕྱིར་བསྐྲད་གཏོང་ནུས་ཀྱི་དཀའ་ངལ་འདོན་དགོས་པ། སྔོན་མི་གཟུགས་འགྲོ་བ་དག་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་CCG ཚོའི་ཆེ་མཐོང་ཚད་གཅིག་ལས་རྒྱབ་སྐྱོར་མེད་པ། ང་ཚོའི་ཐབས་ལམ་དེ་སྤྱིར་བཏང་ནུས་མེད་པར་བཟོ་བཏང་བ་ཡིན། སྔོན་གྱི་གནད་དོན་ལྡན་ཞིག་གིས་ང་ཚོར་དབྱིན་ཡིག་དང་། སྐད་རིགས། ཨིན་ཇུས་དང་། ཨིན་ཊ་ལི་ཡཱན།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>We revisit the problem of extracting dependency structures from the derivation structures of Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG).  גישות קודמות מוגבלות לעתים קרובות לתחתית צרה של CCG או לתמוך רק טעם אחד של עץ תלויות. הגישה שלנו היא גנרלית יותר וקל להתייצב, כך שאפשר להשיג סגנונים רבים של עץ התלויות. In an initial case study, we show promising results for converting English, German, Italian, and Dutch CCG derivations from the Parallel Meaning Bank into (unlabeled) UD-style dependency trees.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>First Steps towards Universal Dependencies for Laz<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependencies for <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>az</title>
      <author><first>Utku</first><last>Türk</last></author>
      <author><first>Kaan</first><last>Bayar</last></author>
      <author><first>Ayşegül Dilara</first><last>Özercan</last></author>
      <author><first>Görkem Yiğit</first><last>Öztürk</last></author>
      <author><first>Şaziye Betül</first><last>Özateş</last></author>
      <pages>189–194</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laz_language">Laz language</a>, which is also the first Universal Dependencies Treebank for a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_the_Caucasus">South Caucasian language</a>. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> aims to create a syntactically and morphologically annotated resource for further research. We also aim to document an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">endangered language</a> in a systematic fashion within an inherently cross-linguistic framework : the Universal Dependencies Project (UD). As of now, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> consists of 576 sentences and 2,306 tokens annotated in light with the UD guidelines. We evaluated the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> on the dependency parsing task using a pretrained multilingual parsing model, and the results are comparable with other low-resourced treebanks with no <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training set</a>. We aim to expand our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> in the near future to include 1,500 sentences. The bigger goal for our project is to create a set of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebanks</a> for minority languages in Anatolia.</abstract>
      <url hash="f2b6354f">2020.udw-1.21</url>
      <bibkey>turk-etal-2020-first</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Dependency annotation of noun incorporation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polysynthetic_language">polysynthetic languages</a></title>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Tyers</last></author>
      <author><first>Karina</first><last>Mishchenkova</last></author>
      <pages>195–204</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes an approach to annotating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incorporation_(linguistics)">noun incorporation</a> in Universal Dependencies. It motivates the need to annotate this particular morphosyntactic phenomenon and justifies it with respect to frequency of the construction. A case study is presented in which the proposed annotation scheme is applied to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chukchi_language">Chukchi</a>, a language that exhibits <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incorporation_(linguistics)">noun incorporation</a>. We compare argument encoding in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chukchi_language">Chukchi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_language">Russian</a> and find that while in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and Russian discourse elements are primarily tracked through noun phrases and pronouns, in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chukchi_language">Chukchi</a> they are tracked through agreement marking and incorporation, with a lesser role for noun phrases.</abstract>
      <url hash="7494e366">2020.udw-1.22</url>
      <revision id="1" href="2020.udw-1.22v1" hash="8261a1c9" />
      <revision id="2" href="2020.udw-1.22v2" hash="7494e366" date="2020-12-11">Corrected author affiliations</revision>
      <bibkey>tyers-mishchenkova-2020-dependency</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>Universal Dependency Treebank for Xibe<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependency Treebank for <fixed-case>X</fixed-case>ibe</title>
      <author><first>He</first><last>Zhou</last></author>
      <author><first>Juyeon</first><last>Chung</last></author>
      <author><first>Sandra</first><last>Kübler</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Tyers</last></author>
      <pages>205–215</pages>
      <abstract>We present our work of constructing the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xibe">Xibe language</a> following the Universal Dependencies (UD) annotation scheme. Xibe is a low-resourced and severely endangered Tungusic language spoken by the Xibe minority living in the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region of China. We collected 810 sentences so far, including 544 sentences from a grammar book on written Xibe and 266 sentences from Cabcal News. We annotated those sentences manually from scratch. In this paper, we report the procedure of building this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a> and analyze several important annotation issues of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebank</a>. Finally, we propose our plans for future work.</abstract>
      <url hash="a358086c">2020.udw-1.23</url>
      <bibkey>zhou-etal-2020-universal</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>