<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.fnp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Dr Mahmoud</first><last>El-Haj</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dr Vasiliki</first><last>Athanasakou</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dr Sira</first><last>Ferradans</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dr Catherine</first><last>Salzedo</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dr Ans</first><last>Elhag</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dr Houda</first><last>Bouamor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dr Marina</first><last>Litvak</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dr Paul</first><last>Rayson</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dr George</first><last>Giannakopoulos</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nikiforos</first><last>Pittaras</last></editor>
      <publisher>COLING</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain (Online)</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="e65cdc18">2020.fnp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>fnp-2020-joint</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>The Financial Document Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ausal 2020)</title>
      <author><first>Dominique</first><last>Mariko</last></author>
      <author><first>Hanna</first><last>Abi-Akl</last></author>
      <author><first>Estelle</first><last>Labidurie</last></author>
      <author><first>Stephane</first><last>Durfort</last></author>
      <author><first>Hugues</first><last>De Mazancourt</last></author>
      <author><first>Mahmoud</first><last>El-Haj</last></author>
      <pages>23–32</pages>
      <abstract>We present the FinCausal 2020 Shared Task on Causality Detection in Financial Documents and the associated FinCausal dataset, and discuss the participating systems and results. Two sub-tasks are proposed : a binary classification task (Task 1) and a relation extraction task (Task 2). A total of 16 teams submitted runs across the two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">Tasks</a> and 13 of them contributed with a system description paper. This workshop is associated to the Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), held at The 28th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING’2020), Barcelona, Spain on September 12, 2020.</abstract>
      <url hash="08403b89">2020.fnp-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>mariko-etal-2020-financial</bibkey>
    <title_ar>المهمة المشتركة للكشف عن السببية للوثيقة المالية (المالية 2020)</title_ar>
      <title_pt>A Tarefa Compartilhada de Detecção de Causalidade de Documentos Financeiros (FinCausal 2020)</title_pt>
      <title_es>La tarea compartida de detección de causalidad de documentos financieros (FinCausal 2020)</title_es>
      <title_ja>財務文書の因果関係検出共有タスク(FinCausal 2020)</title_ja>
      <title_zh>财务文因果关系检测共享(FinCausal 2020)</title_zh>
      <title_hi>वित्तीय दस्तावेज़ कार्यक्षमता का पता लगाना साझा कार्य (FinCausal 2020)</title_hi>
      <title_ga>An Tasc Comhroinnte um Bhrath Cúisíochta an Doiciméid Airgeadais (FiCause 2020)</title_ga>
      <title_hu>A pénzügyi dokumentum okság észlelése megosztott feladat (FinCausal 2020)</title_hu>
      <title_el>Το Χρηματοδοτικό Έγγραφο Κοινή Εργασία Ανίχνευσης Αιτιολογίας (FinCausal 2020)</title_el>
      <title_ka>ფინანსტური დოკუმენტის განსაზღვრების გარეშე საზოგადოება (FinCausal 2020)</title_ka>
      <title_it>Compito condiviso di rilevamento delle cause del documento finanziario (FinCausal 2020)</title_it>
      <title_kk>Қаржылы құжаттың қауіпсіздігін табу ортақ тапсырмасы (FinCausal 2020)</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Соделена задача за детектирање на причината на финансискиот документ (FinCausal 2020)</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Finansinio dokumento priežastinio nustatymo bendra užduotis (iki 2020 m. pabaigos)</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Tugas Berkongsi Pengesanan Kesebatan Dokumen Kewangan (FinCausal 2020)</title_ms>
      <title_ml>Financial Document Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Id-Dokument Finanzjarju Kompitu Konġunt għall-Iskopru tal-Kawżalità (FinCausal 2020)</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Санхүүгийн бичиг баримтуудын хамааралтай ажил (FinCausal 2020)</title_mn>
      <title_no>The Financial Document Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_no>
      <title_pl>Dokument finansowy Wspólne zadanie wykrywania przyczyn (FinCausal 2020)</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Activitatea comună de detectare a cauzelor documentului financiar (FinCausal 2020)</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Finansijski dokument za otkrivanje optužnice zajedničkog zadatka (FinCausal 2020)</title_sr>
      <title_si>විත්‍යාත්මක ලිපින්ත අවස්ථාවක් හොයාගන්න සාමාන්‍ය වැඩ (FinCause 2020යි)</title_si>
      <title_so>The Financial Document Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_so>
      <title_sv>Den gemensamma uppgiften för att upptäcka orsak i det finansiella dokumentet (FinCausal 2020)</title_sv>
      <title_ta>தொழில்நுட்ப ஆவணத்தின் பயன்பாடு கண்டுபிடிப்பு பகிர்ந்த பணி</title_ta>
      <title_ur>فینٹنسیل ڈوکینسٹ کائذلیٹ ڈیکسٹ شناسایی شریک ٹاکس (فینٹنسیل 2020)</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Comment</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Tài liệu Tài chính Điều tra nhân dạng chia sẻ (Fincause 2020)</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Споделена задача за откриване на причинно-следствена връзка във финансовия документ (окончателна кауза 2020 г.)</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Dijeljeni zadatak za otkrivanje opasnosti financijskog dokumenta (FinCausal 2020)</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Het Financieel Document Causality Detection Gedeelde Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_nl>
      <title_da>Delt opgave til opdagelse af årsagspåvisning i det finansielle dokument (FinCausal 2020)</title_da>
      <title_de>Das Finanzdokument Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_de>
      <title_id>Dokumen keuangan Deteksi Kesebatan Tugas Bersama (FinCausal 2020)</title_id>
      <title_ko>금융 문서 인과관계 검사 공유 임무(FinCausive 2020)</title_ko>
      <title_fa>کاری مشترک بازرسی سند مالی (FinCausal 2020)</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Utafiti wa Matukio ya Huduma za Kifedha (FinCausal 2020)</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Maliýe Sened Mazmunyň Aňlamak Mazmuny (FinCausal 2020)</title_tr>
      <title_af>Die Finansie Dokument Opkyk Gedeelde Opdrag (FinCausal 2020)</title_af>
      <title_sq>Detyra e përbashkët e zbulimit të shkakut të dokumentit financiar (FinCausal 2020)</title_sq>
      <title_am>ሰነዱን እንዳለ ምረጡ</title_am>
      <title_hy>The Financial Document Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_hy>
      <title_az>Financial Document Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_az>
      <title_bn>অর্থনৈতিক ডকুমেন্ট ক্যাসেলিটি ডিটেক্টরেশন শেয়ার করা কাজ (ফিনাসাল ২০২০)</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Zajednički zadatak za otkrivanje optužnice financijskog dokumenta (FinCausal 2020)</title_bs>
      <title_ca>La tasca compartida de detecció de causalitat dels documents financers (FinCausal 2020)</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Finanční dokument Detekce kausality Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_cs>
      <title_et>Finantsdokumendi põhjuslikkuse tuvastamise jagatud ülesanne (FinCausal 2020)</title_et>
      <title_fi>Taloudellinen asiakirja Syyllisyyden havaitsemisen yhteinen tehtävä (FinCausal 2020)</title_fi>
      <title_he>The Financial Document Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal 2020)</title_he>
      <title_jv>FinCause 2020</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Skupna naloga odkrivanja vzročnosti finančnega dokumenta (FinCausal 2020)</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>དངུལ་འབྲེལ་ཡིག་ཆ་སྤྲོ་བ་དང་མཉམ་དུ་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་དང་།</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم مهمة FinCausal 2020 المشتركة حول اكتشاف السببية في المستندات المالية ومجموعة البيانات المالية المرتبطة بها ، ونناقش الأنظمة والنتائج المشاركة. تم اقتراح مهمتين فرعيتين: مهمة التصنيف الثنائي (المهمة 1) ومهمة استخراج العلاقة (المهمة 2). تم إرسال إجمالي 16 فريقًا عبر المهمتين وساهم 13 منهم بورقة وصف النظام. ترتبط ورشة العمل هذه بورشة العمل المشتركة حول معالجة السرد المالي والتلخيص المالي متعدد اللغات (FNP-FNS 2020) ، التي عقدت في المؤتمر الدولي الثامن والعشرين حول اللغويات الحاسوبية (COLING'2020) ، برشلونة ، إسبانيا في 12 سبتمبر 2020.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos a Tarefa Compartilhada FinCausal 2020 sobre Detecção de Causalidade em Documentos Financeiros e o conjunto de dados FinCausal associado e discutimos os sistemas e resultados participantes. Duas subtarefas são propostas: uma tarefa de classificação binária (Tarefa 1) e uma tarefa de extração de relações (Tarefa 2). Um total de 16 equipes enviaram corridas nas duas Tarefas e 13 delas contribuíram com um documento de descrição do sistema. Este workshop está associado ao Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), realizado na 28ª Conferência Internacional de Linguística Computacional (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Espanha, em 12 de setembro de 2020.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos la tarea compartida FinCausal 2020 sobre detección de causalidad en documentos financieros y el conjunto de datos FinCausal asociado, y discutimos los sistemas participantes y los resultados. Se proponen dos subtareas: una tarea de clasificación binaria (Tarea 1) y una tarea de extracción de relaciones (Tarea 2). Un total de 16 equipos enviaron corridas en las dos Tareas y 13 de ellos contribuyeron con un documento de descripción del sistema. Este taller está asociado al Taller Conjunto sobre Procesamiento de Narrativas Financieras y Resumen Financiero MultiLing (FNP-FNS 2020), celebrado en la 28ª Conferencia Internacional de Lingüística Computacional (COLING'2020), Barcelona, España, el 12 de septiembre de 2020.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>財務文書の原因検知に関するFinCausal 2020共有タスクと関連するFinCausalデータセットを提示し、参加システムと結果について説明します。バイナリ分類タスク（タスク1 ）とリレーション抽出タスク（タスク2 ）の2つのサブタスクが提案されています。合計16チームが2つのタスクにわたって実行を提出し、そのうち13チームがシステム説明論文を寄稿しました。このワークショップは、2020年9月12日にスペインのバルセロナで開催された第28回計算言語学国際会議（ COLING '2020 ）で開催された金融物語処理とマルチリング金融要約に関する共同ワークショップ（ FNP - FNS 2020 ）に関連しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>हम वित्तीय दस्तावेजों और संबंधित FinCausal डेटासेट में कार्यकारणता का पता लगाने पर FinCausal 2020 साझा कार्य प्रस्तुत करते हैं, और भाग लेने वाले सिस्टम और परिणामों पर चर्चा करते हैं। दो उप-कार्य प्रस्तावित हैं: एक बाइनरी वर्गीकरण कार्य (कार्य 1) और एक संबंध निष्कर्षण कार्य (कार्य 2)। कुल 16 टीमों ने दो कार्यों में रन प्रस्तुत किए और उनमें से 13 ने सिस्टम विवरण पेपर के साथ योगदान दिया। यह कार्यशाला वित्तीय कथा प्रसंस्करण और मल्टीलिंग वित्तीय सारांशीकरण (एफएनपी-एफएनएस 2020) पर संयुक्त कार्यशाला से जुड़ी हुई है, जो 12 सितंबर, 2020 को कम्प्यूटेशनल भाषाविज्ञान (COLING'2020), बार्सिलोना, स्पेन पर 28 वें अंतर्राष्ट्रीय सम्मेलन में आयोजित की गई थी।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>因金融文因果关系检测之FinCausal 2020,及关FinCausal数集,并讨论其统实。 举二子:二元类(任 1)与事(2)。 凡16一团队交横两任,其13团队供系统述文。 是研讨会与2020岁9月12日于西班牙巴塞罗那第28届计语言学国际会议(COLING'2020)上行金融叙事处理与多元金融摘要合研讨会(FNP-FNS 2020)。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid i láthair Tasc Comhroinnte FinCausal 2020 ar Bhrath Cúisíochta i nDoiciméid Airgeadais agus an tacar sonraí Cúiseanna Airgeadais lena mbaineann, agus pléimid na córais agus na torthaí rannpháirteacha. Moltar dhá fhothasc: tasc aicmithe dhénártha (Tasc 1) agus tasc astarraingthe gaol (Tasc 2). Ritheann 16 fhoireann san iomlán a cuireadh isteach ar fud an dá Thasc agus chuir 13 acu le páipéar cur síos ar an gcóras. Baineann an cheardlann seo leis an gCeardlann Chomhpháirteach ar Phróiseáil Inste Airgeadais agus Achoimre Airgeadais Ilteangach (FNP-FNS 2020), a tionóladh ag an 28ú Comhdháil Idirnáisiúnta ar Theangeolaíocht Ríomhaireachtúil (COLING'2020), Barcelona, an Spáinn an 12 Meán Fómhair, 2020.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Bemutatjuk a FinCausal 2020 megosztott feladatot a pénzügyi dokumentumokban és a kapcsolódó FinCausal adatkészletet, valamint megvitatjuk a résztvevő rendszereket és eredményeket. Két alcsoport javasolt: egy bináris osztályozási feladat (1. feladat) és egy kapcsolatkivonási feladat (2. feladat). Összesen 16 csapat jelentkezett a két feladaton keresztül, és 13 közülük járult hozzá egy rendszerleíró dokumentummal. Ez a workshop a pénzügyi narrációs feldolgozás és a multilingi pénzügyi összefoglalás (FNP-FNS 2020) közös workshopjához kapcsolódik, amelyet 2020. szeptember 12-én tartottak Barcelonában, Spanyolországban.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ ფინქანციური დოკუმენტებში და დაკავშირებული ფინქანციური მონაცემების საზოგადოება 2020-ში ჩვენ აღმოჩნეთ საზოგადოებული დავაკეთებული დავაკეთებული დავაკეთებული დავაკეთებული ორი სამუშაო დავალება იყენება: ბიუნარი კლასიფიკაციის დავალება (დავალება 1) და დაკავშირებული ექსტრექციის დავალება (დავალება 2). საერთო 16 ჯგუფი, რომელიც ორი დავალება და 13 იყოს სისტემის გამოსახულების დამატებით. ეს სამუშაო დააყენებულია ერთადერთი სამუშაო სამუშაო პროცესის და მრალური ფინანციური კონფინციური კონფინციური კონფინციური კონფინციური კონფინციური კონფინციური კონფინციური კონფინციური კონფინცი</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε την Κοινή Εργασία για την Ανίχνευση Αιτιολογίας στα Χρηματοοικονομικά Έγγραφα και το σχετικό σύνολο δεδομένων και συζητάμε τα συμμετέχοντα συστήματα και αποτελέσματα. Προτείνονται δύο δευτερεύουσες εργασίες: μια εργασία δυαδικής ταξινόμησης (εργασία 1) και μια εργασία εξαγωγής σχέσεων (εργασία 2). Συνολικά δεκαέξι ομάδες που υποβλήθηκαν εκτελούνται στις δύο εργασίες και 13 από αυτές συνέβαλαν με ένα έγγραφο περιγραφής του συστήματος. Το εργαστήρι αυτό συνδέεται με το Κοινό Εργαστήρι για την Επεξεργασία Χρηματοοικονομικής Αφηγητικής και την Οικονομική Σύνοψη (FNP-FNS 2020), που πραγματοποιήθηκε στο 28ο Διεθνές Συνέδριο Υπολογιστικής Γλωσσολογίας (COLING'2020), Βαρκελώνη, Ισπανία τον 12ο Σεπτέμβριο.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo il compito condiviso FinCausal 2020 sulla rilevazione della causalità nei documenti finanziari e il dataset FinCausal associato, e discutiamo i sistemi e i risultati partecipanti. Vengono proposti due sottocompiti: un'attività di classificazione binaria (Task 1) e un'attività di estrazione delle relazioni (Task 2). Un totale di 16 squadre presentate corre attraverso le due Task e 13 di loro hanno contribuito con un documento di descrizione del sistema. Questo workshop è associato al Workshop congiunto sull'elaborazione narrativa finanziaria e la sintesi finanziaria multilinga (FNP-FNS 2020), tenutosi alla 28a Conferenza internazionale sulla linguistica computazionale (COLING'2020), Barcellona, Spagna il 12 settembre 2020.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Біз "FinCausal 2020" бағдарламалық құжаттардың қауіпсіздік тапсырмаларын анықтау және қатынастық FinCausal деректер жиынын таңдап, қатынастық жүйелерді және нәтижелерді талқылаймыз. Екі ішкі тапсырмалар қолданылады: бинарлық тапсырма (1- тапсырма) және қатынасы тарқату тапсырмасы (2- тапсырма). Екі тапсырма арасында 16 топ жіберілген жүйелік сипаттамасын қолдану жүйесінің түсініктеме қағазымен жалғастырды. Бұл жұмыс істеу қаржылық нарративті процесс және көптеген қаржылық тұжырымдамасы (FNP-FNS 2020) туралы 28- ші халықаралық конференция Компьютерлік лингвистикалық конференциясы (COLING'2020), Барселона, Испания 12- қаршамасында.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Ние ја претставуваме заедничката задача „FinCausal 2020“ за детекција на причината во финансиските документи и поврзаниот набор на податоци „FinCausal“, и разговараме за учествувачките системи и резултати. Предложени се две подзадачи: бинарна задача за класификација (задача 1) и задача за извлекување односи (задача 2). Вкупно 16 испратени тимови ги поминуваат двете задачи и 13 од нив придонесоа со документ за опис на системот. This workshop is associated to the Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), held at The 28th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spain on September 12, 2020.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Finansiniuose dokumentuose ir susijusiame duomenų rinkinyje „FinCausal 2020“ pristatoma bendra užduotis nustatyti priežastinius veiksnius ir aptariamos dalyvaujančios sistemos bei rezultatai. Siūlomos dviejų dalių užduotys: dviguba klasifikavimo užduotis (1 užduotis) ir santykių išgavimo užduotis (2 užduotis). A total of 16 teams submitted runs across the two Tasks and 13 of them contributed with a system description paper.  Šis seminaras yra susijęs su 28-ojoje tarptautinėje kompiuterinės kalbos konferencijoje (COLING'2020), Barselonoje (Ispanija), įvykusioje 2020 m. rugsėjo 12 d., surengtu Jungtiniu seminaru dėl finansinio siauraus apdorojimo ir daugialypės finansinės santraukos (FNP-FNS 2020).</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Kami memperkenalkan Tugas Berkongsi FinCausal 2020 mengenai pengesan Causality dalam Dokumen Kewangan dan set data FinCausal yang berkaitan, dan membincangkan sistem dan keputusan yang berpartisipasi. Dua sub-tugas dicadangkan: tugas klasifikasi binari (Tugas 1) dan tugas ekstraksi hubungan (Tugas 2). Jumlah 16 pasukan yang dihantar berjalan melalui dua Tugas dan 13 daripada mereka berkontribusi dengan kertas keterangan sistem. Pejabat ini berkaitan dengan Pejabat Perkongsian mengenai Pemprosesan Kewangan Narratif dan Penapisan Kewangan MultiLing (FNP-FNS 2020), yang dilakukan pada Perkonferensi Antarabangsa ke-28 tentang Bahasa Komputasi (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spanyol pada 12 September 2020.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഫിന്‍കാസാല്‍ 2020 സംഘടിപ്പിക്കുന്ന പണിയായ രേഖകളില്‍ സഹകരിക്കുന്നതിനെക്കുറിച്ചും ഫിന്‍കാസല്‍ ഡാറ്റാസറ്റെറ്റിനെയും കാണിച രണ്ടു സബ് ജോലികള്‍ പ്രൊദ്ദേശിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു: ഒരു ബൈനര്‍ ക്ലാസ്ഫിക്കല്‍ ജോലി (ടാസ്ക് 1) ഒരു ബന്ധപ്പെടുത്തുന് മൊത്തം 16 ടീം മൊത്തം സമര്‍പ്പിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. രണ്ട് ജോലികള്‍ മുഴുവന്‍ ഓടിക്കൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. അവയില്‍ 13 ഈ പണിയാര്‍ക്ക് ഫാന്‍സിക്കല്‍ നാരാജിവ് പ്രവര്‍ത്തിക്കുന്നതിന്‍റെയും മള്‍ലിങ്ങിന്‍റെയും ഫാന്‍സിക്കല്‍ ചുരുക്കത്തിന്‍റെയും യൂണ്ട് വര്‍ക്കാര്‍ക്ക് ഷോപ്പില്‍ ബന്ധപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nippreżentaw il-Kompitu Konġunt FinCausal 2020 dwar id-Detezzjoni tal-Kawżalità fid-Dokumenti Finanzjarji u s-sett ta’ dejta assoċjat FinCausal, u niddiskutu s-sistemi u r-riżultati parteċipanti. Huma proposti żewġ sottokompiti: kompitu ta’ klassifikazzjoni binarja (Kompitu 1) u kompitu ta’ estrazzjoni ta’ relazzjonijiet (Kompitu 2). Total ta’ 16-il tim sottomess jaqa’ tul iż-żewġ Kompiti u 13 minnhom ikkontribwixxew b’dokument ta’ deskrizzjoni tas-sistema. Dan il-workshop huwa assoċjat mal-Workshop Konġunt dwar l-Ipproċessar Narrattiv Finanzjarju u s-Sommarju Finanzjarju Multilingwi (FNP-FNS 2020), li sar fit-28 Konferenza Internazzjonali dwar il-Lingwistika Komputazzjonali (COLING'2020), Barċellona, Spanja fit-12 ta' Settembru 2020.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Бид "FinCausal 2020" гэх санхүүгийн баримт болон хамааралтай Финкауслын өгөгдлийн сангуудын хамтын хамтын ажиллагааг тайлбарлаж, оролцох систем болон үр дүн дээр ярилцаж байна. Хоёр суб-задалга санал болгож байна: хоёр давхар хуваалтын ажил (Task 1) болон хамааралтай хайлтын ажил (Task 2). Хоёр ажил дээр 16 баг дамжуулагдсан бөгөөд 13 нь системийн тодорхойлолтын цаастай тусламжтай. Энэ үйл ажиллагаа санхүүгийн нийгмийн үйлдвэрлэл болон олон холбоотой санхүүгийн нийгмийн нийлүүлэлт (FNP-FNS 2020) дээр холбогдсон 28-р Олон улсын Конференцийн Компьютерийн Linguistics (COLING'2020), Барселона, Испания, 2020 оны 9-р сарын 12-нд.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer FinCausal 2020 delt oppgåve om avbryting i finansielle dokument og den tilknytte datasettet for FinCausal, og diskuterer deltar systemet og resultatet. To underoppgåver er foreslått: ein binærklassifikasjonsverkt (oppgåve 1) og ei relasjonsutpakkingsverkt (oppgåve 2). Eit totalt 16 grupper sendt køyrer over to oppgåver og 13 av dei bidra med eit systembeskriveljarpapir. Dette arbeidsområdet er tilknyttet til den samanlige arbeidsområdet om finansielle narrative prosessering og multiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), som held på den 28. internasjonale konferansen om datamaskinske lingvistikk (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spania 12. september 2020.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Prezentăm sarcina partajată FinCausal 2020 privind detectarea cauzalității în documentele financiare și setul de date FinCausal asociat și discutăm sistemele și rezultatele participante. Sunt propuse două subsarcini: o sarcină de clasificare binară (Activitatea 1) și o sarcină de extragere a relațiilor (Activitatea 2). Un total de 16 echipe depuse rulează în cele două sarcini și 13 dintre ele au contribuit cu un document de descriere a sistemului. Acest atelier este asociat cu Workshop-ul comun privind procesarea narativă financiară și rezumarea financiară multilingă (FNP-FNS 2020), organizat în cadrul celei de-a 28-a Conferințe internaționale de lingvistică computațională (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spania, pe 12 septembrie 2020.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>Przedstawiamy wspólne zadanie FinCausal 2020 dotyczące wykrywania przyczyn w dokumentach finansowych oraz powiązany zestaw danych FinCausal oraz omówimy uczestniczące systemy i wyniki. Proponowane są dwa podzadania: zadanie klasyfikacji binarnej (zadanie 1) i zadanie ekstrakcji relacji (zadanie 2). W sumie szesnastu zespołów zgłoszonych przez dwa zadania, a trzynaście z nich przyczyniło się do opisu systemu. Warsztaty te są związane z Wspólnymi Warsztatami na temat Przetwarzania Narracji Finansowej i Podsumowania Finansowego MultiLing (FNP-FNS 2020), które odbyły się na 28-tej Międzynarodowej Konferencji Językoznawstwa Komputerowego (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Hiszpania we wrześniu 12,2020.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo zajednički zadatak o otkrivanju optužnice u financijskim dokumentima i povezanom kompletu podataka o finkaziji 2020. i razgovaramo o sustavima i rezultatima sudjelovanja. Предлагају се два подзадача: бинарна класификационна задача (задач 1) и задача извеђења относије (задач 2). Ukupno 16 timova koje su podnele trke preko dva zadatka i 13 njih doprinosilo je papirom za opis sistema. Ovaj radionici je povezan sa zajedničkom radionicom o financijskom narativnom procesu i finansijskom samurazu multiLinga (FNP-FNS 2020), održanom na 28. Međunarodnoj konferenciji o kompjutacijskoj lingwistiki (COLING'2020), Barceloni, Španiji 12. septembra 2020.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අපි ෆින්කායුස් ලොකුණු ලොකුණු සහ සම්බන්ධ වැඩසටහන් සම්බන්ධ වැඩසටහන් සම්බන්ධ වැඩසටහන් වෙනුවෙන් සම්බන්ධ ව සබ- වැඩක් දෙකක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා: බායිනාර් විශේෂණ වැඩක් (වැඩක් 1) සහ සම්බන්ධ විශේෂණ වැඩක් (ව සම්පූර්ණයෙන් කණ්ඩායම් 16 කණ්ඩායම් දෙකක් වෙනුවෙන් ක්‍රියාවක් දෙකක් සහ 13 කණ්ඩායම් විස්තර වි මේ වැඩසම්බන්ධය සම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැඩසම්බන්ධ වැ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Waxaannu soo bandhignaynaa Shaqada FinCausal 2020 ee loo sharciyey Shaqooyinka kalsoonka ee dukumentiyada dhaqaalaha iyo sawirka macluumaadka ee la xidhiidha FinCausal, waxaana kala sheekaynaynaa nidaamka qayb-qaadashada iyo resultiyada. Two sub-tasks are proposed: a binary classification task (Task 1) and a relation extraction task (Task 2).  Dhammaan 16 koox oo la soo dhiibay waxay ku gudbaan labada shaqo iyo 13 oo ka mid ah warqad qoraalka nidaamka. Warqaddan waxaa la xiriira ururka Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), held at The 28th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spain, on 12 September 2020.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar FinCausal 2020 Shared Task on Causality Detection i Finansiella dokument och tillhörande FinCausal dataset samt diskuterar deltagande system och resultat. Två underuppgifter föreslås: en binär klassificeringsuppgift (Uppgift 1) och en relationsextraktionsuppgift (Uppgift 2). Totalt 16 inlämnade team löper över de två uppgifterna och 13 av dem bidrog med en systembeskrivning. Denna workshop är kopplad till den gemensamma workshopen om finansiell narrativ bearbetning och multiLing finansiell sammanfattning (FNP-FNS 2020), som hölls vid den 28:e internationella konferensen om datorlingvistik (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spanien den 12 september 2020.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாங்கள் பின்காusal 2020 பகிர்ந்த பணியை நிதி ஆவணங்களில் காப்பாற்றல் கண்டுபிடிப்பு மற்றும் தொடர்புடைய பின்காஸால் தகவல் அமைப்புகள் மற்றும இரண்டு துணை பணிகள் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறது: ஒரு இரு வகைப்படுத்தல் செயல் (பணி 1) மற்றும் ஒரு தொடர்பு பிரிப்பு செயல் (பணி 2). மொத்தமான 16 குழுக்கள் கொடுக்கப்பட்ட இரண்டு பணிகள் முழுவதும் இயங்குகின்றன மற்றும் 13 அவைகள் ஒரு அமைப்பு விவரிப்பு  இந்த workshop is associated with the Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summary (FNP- FNS 2020), held at the 28th International Conference on Computation Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spain, 12 September 2020.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم فینس کائوسل 2020 کے ساتھ فینس کائوسل ڈیٹسٹ کے معاملہ میں فنانسی ڈیٹسٹ کے بارے میں مشترک ٹاکس کو پیش کریں گے اور مشترک سیستم اور نتیجے کے بارے میں مشترک کریں گے۔ دو سوب-ٹاکس پیشنهاد کیے جاتے ہیں: ایک دوسری کلاسیفون ٹاکس (ٹاکس ۱) اور ایک ارتباط اضافہ ٹاکس (ٹاکس ۲). ۱۶ ٹیموں میں سے ایک جمع ہے جو دو ٹاکس پر چلنے والے ہیں اور ان میں سے ۱۳ سیسٹم کا سفارش کاغذ کے ساتھ مدد کیا گیا ہے. This workshop is associated with the Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), held at the 28th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spain on September 12, 2020.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Biz 2020 FinCausal Vazifani Financial hujjatlar va bogʻliq FinCausal maʼlumotlar tarkibini aniqlash va ishlash tizimlarini va natijalarini ajratib turamiz. Name Ushbu ikkita vazifalar bilan joʻnatilgan 16 guruhi ikkita vazifalar bilan ishga tushirilmoqda va 13 kamida tizimning taʼrif qogʻozi bilan ishlatilgan. Name</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi xin giới thiệu Nhiệm vụ được chia sẻ về nhân quả trong các tài liệu tài chính và bộ dữ liệu liên quan Đến vùng Tìm và thảo luận về hệ thống và kết quả. Được đề xuất hai nhiệm vụ phụ: một nhiệm vụ phân loại nhị phân (Task 1) và một nhiệm vụ phân tích liên quan (Task 2). Tổng bộ sáu đội được gửi đi chạy qua hai nhiệm vụ và 13 của chúng được đóng góp bằng một tờ báo mô tả hệ thống. Hội thảo này được tổ chức tại Hội thảo Liên kết Hợp đồng Phát âm tài chính và cho kết luận tài chính đa Linh (FNP-FNS 2020), tổ chức tại Đệ Nhất Hội nghị Quốc Tế về ngôn ngữ học vi tính (COLLING'2020), Barcelona, Tây Ban Nha vào tháng chín 12, 2020.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer FinCausal 2020 Shared Task on Causality Detection i Finansielle Dokumenter og det tilhørende FinCausal datasæt, og diskuterer de deltagende systemer og resultater. Der foreslås to underopgaver: en binær klassificeringsopgave (opgave 1) og en relationsudvindingsopgave (opgave 2). I alt 16 indsendte hold løber på tværs af de to opgaver, og 13 af dem bidrog med en beskrivelse af systemet. Denne workshop er knyttet til den fælles workshop om finansiel fortællingsbehandling og multiLing finansiel opsummering (FNP-FNS 2020), der afholdes på den 28. internationale konference om computerlingvistik (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spanien den 12. september 2020.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме споделената задача за откриване на причинна причина във финансовите документи и свързания с нея набор от данни за причинна причина и обсъждаме участващите системи и резултати. Предлагат се две подзадачи: задача за двоична класификация (задача 1) и задача за извличане на релации (задача 2). Общо 16 екипа представиха проби по двете задачи, като 13 от тях допринесоха за описание на системата. Този семинар е свързан със Съвместната работна среща по обработка на финансови разкази и мултилинг финансово обобщаване (ФНП-ФНС 2020), проведена на 28-та международна конференция по компютърна лингвистика (Барселона, Испания на 12 септември 2020 г.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren de FinCausal 2020 Shared Task on Causality Detection in Financial Documents en de bijbehorende FinCausal dataset, en bespreken de deelnemende systemen en resultaten. Er worden twee subtaken voorgesteld: een binaire classificatietaak (Taak 1) en een Relatie extractie taak (Taak 2). Een totaal van zestien teams heeft de twee taken doorlopen en 13 van hen droegen bij met een systeembeschrijvingspapier. Deze workshop is gekoppeld aan de Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), gehouden tijdens de 28e Internationale Conferentie over Computational Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spanje op september 12, 2020.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Predstavljamo zajednički zadatak FinCausal 2020 o otkrivanju optužnice u financijskim dokumentima i povezanim skupinom podataka o financijskim optužnicama i raspravljamo o sudjelujućim sustavima i rezultatima. Predloženi su dva podzadatka: binarni zadatak klasifikacije (zadatak 1) i zadatak izvlačenja odnosa (zadatak 2). Ukupno 16 timova podanih trčanja preko dva zadatka i 13 njih doprinosilo je papirom opisa sustava. Ovaj radionici je povezan s zajedničkim radionicom o financijskom proizvodnju Narrativnog procesa i financijskom sažetku multiLinga (FNP-FNS 2020), održanom na 28. Međunarodnoj konferenciji o računalnoj lingvistiki (COLING'2020), Barceloni, Španjolskoj 12. rujna 2020. godine.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Wir stellen die FinCausal 2020 Shared Task on Causality Detection in Financial Documents und den zugehörigen FinCausal Datensatz vor und diskutieren die beteiligten Systeme und Ergebnisse. Zwei Unteraufgaben werden vorgeschlagen: eine binäre Klassifikationsaufgabe (Aufgabe 1) und eine Beziehungsextraktionsaufgabe (Aufgabe 2). Insgesamt sechs Teams eingereichte Läufe über die beiden Aufgaben und 13 von ihnen trugen mit einer Systembeschreibung bei. Dieser Workshop ist im Zusammenhang mit dem Gemeinsamen Workshop über Financial Narrative Processing und MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), der auf der 28th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spanien am 12.September, 2020, abgehalten wird.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kami mempersembahkan Tugas Berkongsi FinCausal 2020 pada Deteksi Kesebatan dalam Dokumen Finanzial dan dataset FinCausal yang terkait, dan mendiskusikan sistem dan hasil yang berpartisipasi. Dua sub-tugas diusulkan: tugas klasifikasi binari (Tugas 1) dan tugas ekstraksi hubungan (Tugas 2). Sebuah total 16 tim yang dikirim berjalan melalui dua Tugas dan 13 dari mereka berkontribusi dengan kertas deskripsi sistem. Workshop ini berhubungan dengan Workshop Perkongsian Proses Narratif Finanzial dan Penapisan Finanzial MultiLing (FNP-FNS 2020), yang dilakukan di Konferensi Internasional 28 tentang Linguistik Komputasional (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spanyol pada 12 September 2020.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>금융문서에서 인과관계가 감지되는 핀카우시브 2020 공유 임무와 관련 핀카우시브 데이터 세트를 소개하고 참여 시스템과 결과를 논의했다.두 개의 하위 임무를 제시했다. 이원 분류 임무(임무1)와 관계 추출 임무(임무2)이다.총 16개 팀이 두 가지 임무의 운행 상황을 제출했고 그 중 13개 팀은 시스템 설명 파일을 제출했다.이 세미나는 2020년 9월 12일 스페인 바르셀로나에서 열린 제28회 계산언어학 국제회의(COLING'2020)에서 열린 재무 서술 처리와 다행재무 요약 합동 세미나(FNP-FNS 2020)와 관련이 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>ما وظیفه مشترک فناکسل ۲۰۰۲ را در مورد شناسایی بازداشتنی در مدارک مالی و مجموعه داده‌های فناکسل مرتبط می‌کنیم و در مورد سیستم‌های مشترک و نتیجه‌های مشترک صحبت می‌کنیم. دو کار زیر پیشنهاد می‌شود: یک کار جدا کردن دوگانه (Task 1) و یک کار خارج کردن ارتباط (Task 2). تعداد ۱۶ تیم در طول دو کار ارائه شده و ۱۳ از آنها با کاغذ توصیف سیستم کمک کردند. این کارنامه با کارنامه‌ای که در سال ۲۸م کنفرانس بین المللی رابطه به زبان‌های کامپیوتری (COLING'2020), بارسلونا، اسپانیا در سال ۱۲ سپتامبر ۲۰۰۲ در جریان بین المللی رابطه به پرداخت نژاد مالی و تعداد مالی‌های متعدد لینگ (FNP-FNS 2020) ارتباط</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Tunawasilisha kazi ya FinCausal 2020 Kuhusu Utafiti katika nyaraka za kifedha na seti ya data zinazohusiana na FinCausal, na kujadili mifumo ya kushiriki na matokeo. Kazi mbili za subira zinapendekezwa: kazi ya usambazaji binafsi (Kazi 1) na kazi ya utekelezaji wa mahusiano (Kazi 2). Jumla ya timu 16 zilizowasilishwa huendesha kazi mbili na 13 kati yao ilichangia kwa karatasi ya maelezo ya mfumo. Warsha hii inahusiana na Warsha ya Joint on Processing Narrative and MultiLing Mkutano wa Kifedha (FNP-FNS 2020), uliofanyika katika Mkutano wa Kimataifa wa 28 on Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Hispania mnamo Septemba 12, 2020.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Biz Finkäzlik 2020-nji ýylda Finkäzlik Maglumaty Senedlerinde Mazmunlyk Etmegi we şuňa gerekli Finkäzlik Maglumaty setirini we syýasatlaryň we netijelerinden çykyp barlaýarys. 2 Sub-Task Iki zadyň arasynda 16 topar gönderdi we 13 topar sistem waspy bilen kömekleydi. Bu seminal Maliýe Narratiw işlemleri we MultiLing Maliýe jemgyýetleri (FNP-FNS 2020) bilen, 28-nji Halkara Konferenciýa Kompýuter Lingüstikleri (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Espanyýa 12-nji Senýabrda geçirilýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Ons stel die FinCausal 2020 Gedeelde Opdrag aangaande Opkyk van Opkyk in Finansiedokumente en die geassosieerde FinCausal dataset en bespreek die gedeeltelike stelsels en resultate. Twee subtaak word voorgestel:  'n binêre klassifikasie taak (Taak 1) en 'n verwanting uitpak taak (Taak 2). Name Hierdie werkvoop is geassosieer aan die saamgevoerde werkvoop op Finansielike Narratiewe Prosessering en MultiLing Finansielike Opsomming (FNP-FNS 2020), wat op die 28ste Internasionale Konferensie oor Rekenaasjonale Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spania op 12 September 2020 gehou het.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim punën e përbashkët FinCausal 2020 mbi zbulimin e arsyeshme në dokumentet financiare dhe të dhënat e lidhura FinCausal dhe diskutojmë sistemet dhe rezultatet pjesëmarrëse. Dy nëndetyra propozohen: një detyrë klasifikimi binar (detyra 1) dhe një detyrë ekstrahimi lidhjesh (detyra 2). A total of 16 teams submitted runs across the two Tasks and 13 of them contributed with a system description paper.  Ky seminar është i lidhur me seminarin e përbashkët mbi procesimin financiar narrativ dhe përmbledhjen financiare të shumëgjuhës (FNP-FNS 2020), mbajtur në konferencën e 28-të ndërkombëtare mbi gjuhët kompjuterike (COLING'2020), Barcelonë, Spanja më 12 shtator 2020.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>በሀብት ሰነዶች እና በተገኘው የፊንካusal ዳታ ማዕከላዊ ስራዎችን በጥያቄ ላይ እናሳየዋለን እና ተጋሪዎችን ስርዓቶች እና ፍሬዎችን እናዋጋለን፡፡ ሁኔታ በሁለቱ ስራ እና 13 ተሟጋቾች በሥርዓት ትርጉም ላይ የተሰጡት 16 ተሟጋቾች ይሮጣሉ፡፡ ይህ workshop በ28th International Conference on Computation Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, September 12, 2020, ስፓኒን የተደረገው በርስፓን (FNP-FNS 2020), የተጠቃሚ የሀብት Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summary (FNP-FNS 2020), የተጠቃሚ ነው።</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք ներկայացնում ենք Fin-Պատճառ 2020-ի ընդհանուր խնդիրը ֆինանսական փաստաթղթերում և կապված Fin-Պատճառ տվյալների համակարգը և քննարկում ենք մասնակցում համակարգերը և արդյունքները: Կարելի է առաջարկել երկու ենթախնդիր. երկարային դասակարգման խնդիր (առաջադրանք 1) և հարաբերությունների վերացման խնդիր (առաջադրանք 2): Ընդհանուր առմամբ 16 խումբ, որոնք ներկայացվել են, կատարում են երկու հանձնարարությունները, 13-ը ներդրում են համակարգի նկարագրման հոդվածով: Այս դասընթացը կապված է ֆինանսական փորձարկումների և բազմալեզուների ֆինանսական համառոտագրման համագործակցային աշխատասենյակի հետ (FNC-FNS 2020), որը տեղի էր ունենում 2020 թվականի սեպտեմբերի 12-ին համակարգչային լեզվաբանության 28-րդ միջազգային կոնֆերանսիայում (COLinG'2020), Բարցիլոնա</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>We present the FinCausal 2020 Shared Task on Causality Detection in Financial Documents and the associated FinCausal dataset, and discuss the participating systems and results.  দুটি সাব-কাজ প্রস্তাব করা হয়েছে: একটি বাইনারি শ্রেণীবিভাগ কাজ (কাজ ১) এবং একটি সম্পর্ক বিনিময় কাজ (কাজ ২)। এই দুই কাজ জ জুড়ে ১৬ টি দল জমা দেয়া হয়েছে এবং তাদের মধ্যে ১৩টি টি একটি সিস্টেম বর্ণনা কাগজে অবদান করেছে। এই কর্মশালার সাথে যুক্ত অর্থনৈতিক ন্যারেটিভ প্রক্রিয়া এবং মাল্টিলিঙ্গ অর্থনৈতিক সংক্রান্ত সংক্রান্ত (এফএনপি-এফএনএস ২০০), ২৮তম আন্তর্জাতিক সম্মেলন (কমিউনিটিশনাল ল লিঙ্গিস্টিক</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Biz FinCausal 2020 paylaşılan işləri Finanlı Belgələr və FinCausal veri qurğuları barəsində fərqli keçmə və iştirak sistemləri və sonuçları barəsində mübahisə edirik. İki alt işi təbliğ edilir: ikili klasifikasiya işi (Task 1) və bağlantı çıxarma işi (Task 2). İki Görev arasında 16 dəstə tərəfindən və 13 dəstə tərəfindən sistem tanımlama kağıdı ilə kömək etdi. Bu çalışma Finanlı Narrativ İşlemi və MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020) ilə birləşdirilmişdir. 2020. gada 12. septembrdə İspaniya ilə birləşdirilmişdir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo zajednički zadatak FinCausal 2020 o otkrivanju optužnice u financijskim dokumentima i povezanom kompletu podataka o FinCausal-u i razgovaramo o sudjelujućim sistemima i rezultatima. Predloženi su dva podzadatka: binarni zadatak klasifikacije (zadatak 1) i zadatak izvlačenja odnosa (zadatak 2). Ukupno 16 timova podanih trčanja preko dva zadatka i 13 njih doprinosilo je papirom opisa sistema. Ovaj radionici je povezan sa zajedničkim radionicom o financijskom narativnom procesu i finansijskom sažetku za multiLing (FNP-FNS 2020), održanom na 28. Međunarodnoj konferenciji o računalnoj lingvistiki (COLING'2020), Barceloni, Španiji 12. septembra 2020.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Presentam la tasca compartida FinCausal 2020 sobre la detecció de causalitat en documentos financers i el conjunt de dades FinCausal associat, i discutem els sistemes i resultats participants. Se proponen dues subtasques: una tasca binaria de classificació (tasca 1) i una tasca d'extracció de relacions (tasca 2). Un total de 16 equips presentats corren per les dues tasques i 13 d'ells van contribuir amb un paper de descripció del sistema. This workshop is associated to the Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), held at The 28th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spain on September 12, 2020.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme sdílený úkol FinCausal 2020 na detekci kausality ve finančních dokumentech a související datovou sadu FinCausal a diskutujeme o zúčastněných systémech a výsledcích. Jsou navrženy dva dílčí úkoly: úkol binární klasifikace (úkol 1) a úkol extrakce vztahů (úkol 2). Celkem šestnáct předložených týmů běží napříč dvěma úkoly a třináct z nich přispělo popisem systému. Tento workshop je přidružen ke Společnému workshopu o finančním vyprávění a multilingovém finančním shrnutí (FNP-FNS 2020), který se koná na osmé mezinárodní konferenci o výpočetní lingvistice (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Španělsko, září 12.2020.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Tutvustame finantsdokumentides põhjuslikkuse tuvastamise jagatud ülesannet FinCausal 2020 ja sellega seotud FinCausal andmekogumit ning arutame osalevaid süsteeme ja tulemusi. Pakutakse välja kaks alamülesannet: binaarse klassifitseerimise ülesanne (ülesanne 1) ja seose ekstraheerimise ülesanne (ülesanne 2). Kokku esitas kahe ülesande jooksul 16 meeskonda, neist 13 andsid oma panuse süsteemi kirjeldusega. See töötuba on seotud finantsjuhendite töötlemise ja MultiLing finantskokkuvõtte ühistöötlusega (FNP-FNS 2020), mis toimus 12. septembril 2020 Barcelonas Hispaanias 28. rahvusvahelisel arvutuskeeleteaduskonverentsil (COLING'2020).</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esittelemme FinCausal 2020 Shared Task on Causality Detection in Financial Documents -dokumenttien ja siihen liittyvän FinCausal-aineiston sekä keskustelemme osallistuvista järjestelmistä ja tuloksista. Ehdotetaan kahta osatehtävää: binääriluokitustehtävä (tehtävä 1) ja relaatioiden poistotehtävä (tehtävä 2). Yhteensä 16 tiimiä lähetti juoksuja kahteen tehtävään, joista 13 osallistui järjestelmäkuvaukseen. Tämä työpaja liittyy Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation -seminaariin (FNP-FNS 2020), joka pidettiin 28. kansainvälisessä laskennallisen kielitieteen konferenssissa (COLING'2020), Barcelonassa Espanjassa 12. syyskuuta 2020.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé nggawe Opong FinCause 2020 Kemerdekaan Kemerdekaan Karo Kemerdekaan Dolanan FinCause lan dataset FinCause sing ngewehi nggo nggambar sistem sing beraksi barêng-barêng task total Workspace iki diputasane nggo Joint Workspace nang Progressing Finance Narratve and MultiLing Finance Cumbersation (FNP-FN2020), sane Jejarang tanggal 1-2 Septembar, 2020.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>אנו מציגים את המשימה המשותפת FinCausal 2020 על גילוי סיבה במסמכים פיננסיים והקבוצת הנתונים הקשורה FinCausal, ודיונים על מערכות והתוצאות המשתתפות. שני משימות תת-משימה מוצעות: משימה סיווג בינרית (משימה 1) ומשימת חיתוך יחסים (משימה 2). בסך הכל 16 קבוצות שנשלחו נמצאות בשני המשימות, 13 מהן תורמו עם נייר תיאור מערכת. העבודה הזו קשורה לעבודה המשותפת על תהליך פיננסי נרטטיבי ומספר לינג פיננסי (FNP-FNS 2020), שנערכה במועדון הבינלאומי ה-28 על לינגסטיקה מחשבית (COLING'2020), ברסלונה, ספרד ב-12 בספטמבר 2020.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo skupno nalogo FinCausal 2020 o odkrivanju vzročnosti v finančnih dokumentih in s tem povezan nabor podatkov FinCausal ter razpravljamo o sodelujočih sistemih in rezultatih. Predlagana sta dve podnalogi: opravilo binarne klasifikacije (naloga 1) in opravilo ekstrakcije relacij (naloga 2). Skupaj je 16 ekip predložilo tekme v obeh nalogah, od tega jih je 13 prispevalo k opisu sistema. Delavnica je povezana s Skupno delavnico o obdelavi finančnih pripovedi in MultiLing finančnem povzetku (FNP-FNS 2020), ki je potekala na 28. mednarodni konferenci o računalniškem jezikoslovju (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Španija 12. septembra 2020.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna halatar da Shirin Ayuka na FinCausal 2020 Ana ƙayyade aikin biyu masu shawara: wani aikin mai classified sau biyu (Tafiyar 1) da wani aikin masu husũma (Tafiyar 2). Gamlar jama'a na 16un jama'a da aka jẽfa shi na tafiyar a kan aikin biyu, kuma 13 daga cikinsu suka ƙarfafa da wani takarda fassarar na'ura. Wannan workworkspace is connected to the Johanned workspace on Economic Narrative Performance and multi-Ling Summary (FNP-FNS 2020), organized at the 28th International Conference on Computation Linguistics (COLIN'2020), Barcelona, Isbania, on September 12, 2020.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་དངུལ་ཡིག Sub-tasks are proposed: a binary classification task (Task 1) and a relation extraction task (Task 2). ཡོངས་བསྡོམས་པའི་ཚོགས་ཁང་༡༦་འདི་ལས་ཀ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་འཁོར་སྐྱོད་བྱས་པ This workshop is associated with the Joint Workshop on Financial Narrative Processing and MultiLing Financial Summarisation (FNP-FNS 2020), held at The 28th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING'2020), Barcelona, Spain on September 12, 2020.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>JDD @ FinCausal 2020, Task 2 : Financial Document Causality Detection<fixed-case>JDD</fixed-case> @ <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ausal 2020, Task 2: Financial Document Causality Detection</title>
      <author><first>Toshiya</first><last>Imoto</last></author>
      <author><first>Tomoki</first><last>Ito</last></author>
      <pages>50–54</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the approach we built for the Financial Document Causality Detection Shared Task (FinCausal-2020) Task 2 : Cause and Effect Detection. Our approach is based on a multi-class classifier using BiLSTM with Graph Convolutional Neural Network (GCN) trained by minimizing the binary cross entropy loss. In our approach, we have not used any extra data source apart from combining the trial and practice dataset. We achieve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weighted_arithmetic_mean">weighted F1 score</a> to 75.61 percent and are ranked at 7-th place.</abstract>
      <url hash="fec1db74">2020.fnp-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>imoto-ito-2020-jdd</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>NITK NLP at FinCausal-2020 Task 1 Using BERT and Linear models.<fixed-case>NITK</fixed-case> <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ausal-2020 Task 1 Using <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> and Linear models.</title>
      <author><first>Hariharan</first><last>R L</last></author>
      <author><first>Anand Kumar</first><last>M</last></author>
      <pages>60–63</pages>
      <abstract>FinCausal-2020 is the shared task which focuses on the causality detection of factual data for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_analysis">financial analysis</a>. The financial data facts do n’t provide much explanation on the variability of these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a>. This paper aims to propose an efficient method to classify the data into one which is having any financial cause or not. Many models were used to classify the data, out of which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">SVM model</a> gave an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-score">F-Score</a> of 0.9435, BERT with specific <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fine-tuning">fine-tuning</a> achieved best results with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-score">F-Score</a> of 0.9677.</abstract>
      <url hash="d621f784">2020.fnp-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>r-l-m-2020-nitk</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Fraunhofer IAIS at FinCausal 2020, Tasks 1 &amp; 2 : Using Ensemble Methods and Sequence Tagging to Detect Causality in Financial Documents<fixed-case>IAIS</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ausal 2020, Tasks 1 &amp; 2: Using Ensemble Methods and Sequence Tagging to Detect Causality in Financial Documents</title>
      <author><first>Maren</first><last>Pielka</last></author>
      <author><first>Rajkumar</first><last>Ramamurthy</last></author>
      <author><first>Anna</first><last>Ladi</last></author>
      <author><first>Eduardo</first><last>Brito</last></author>
      <author><first>Clayton</first><last>Chapman</last></author>
      <author><first>Paul</first><last>Mayer</last></author>
      <author><first>Rafet</first><last>Sifa</last></author>
      <pages>64–68</pages>
      <abstract>The FinCausal 2020 shared task aims to detect <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Causality">causality</a> on financial news and identify those parts of the causal sentences related to the underlying cause and effect. We apply ensemble-based and sequence tagging methods for identifying <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Causality">causality</a>, and extracting causal subsequences. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> yield promising results on both sub-tasks, with the prospect of further improvement given more time and computing resources. With respect to task 1, we achieved an F1 score of 0.9429 on the evaluation data, and a corresponding ranking of 12/14. For task 2, we were ranked 6/10, with an F1 score of 0.76 and an ExactMatch score of 0.1912.</abstract>
      <url hash="b612206a">2020.fnp-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>pielka-etal-2020-fraunhofer</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>NTUNLPL at FinCausal 2020, Task 2 : Improving Causality Detection Using Viterbi Decoder<fixed-case>NTUNLPL</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ausal 2020, Task 2:Improving Causality Detection Using <fixed-case>V</fixed-case>iterbi Decoder</title>
      <author><first>Pei-Wei</first><last>Kao</last></author>
      <author><first>Chung-Chi</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <author><first>Hen-Hsen</first><last>Huang</last></author>
      <author><first>Hsin-Hsi</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <pages>69–73</pages>
      <abstract>In order to provide an explanation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning models</a>, causality detection attracts lots of attention in the artificial intelligence research community. In this paper, we explore the cause-effect detection in financial news and propose an approach, which combines the BIO scheme with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viterbi_decoder">Viterbi decoder</a> for addressing this challenge. Our approach is ranked the first in the official run of cause-effect detection (Task 2) of the FinCausal-2020 shared task. We not only report the implementation details and ablation analysis in this paper, but also publish our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Source_code">code</a> for academic usage.</abstract>
      <url hash="8e862016">2020.fnp-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>kao-etal-2020-ntunlpl</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/pxpxkao/fincausal-2020" additional="false">pxpxkao/fincausal-2020</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>FiNLP at FinCausal 2020 Task 1 : Mixture of BERTs for Causal Sentence Identification in Financial Texts<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>i<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ausal 2020 Task 1: Mixture of <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>s for Causal Sentence Identification in Financial Texts</title>
      <author><first>Sarthak</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <pages>74–79</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our system developed for the sub-task 1 of the FinCausal shared task in the FNP-FNS workshop held in conjunction with COLING-2020. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> classifies whether a financial news text segment contains causality or not. To address this task, we fine-tune and ensemble the generic and domain-specific BERT language models pre-trained on financial text corpora. The task data is highly imbalanced with the majority non-causal class ; therefore, we train the models using strategies such as under-sampling, cost-sensitive learning, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_augmentation">data augmentation</a>. Our best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> achieves a weighted F1-score of 96.98 securing 4th position on the evaluation leaderboard. The code is available at https://github.com/sarthakTUM/fincausal</abstract>
      <url hash="60bbeee2">2020.fnp-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>gupta-2020-finlp</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/sarthaktum/fincausal" additional="false">sarthaktum/fincausal</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/semeval-2010-task-8">SemEval-2010 Task 8</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Domino at FinCausal 2020, Task 1 and 2 : Causal Extraction System<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ausal 2020, Task 1 and 2: Causal Extraction System</title>
      <author><first>Sharanya</first><last>Chakravarthy</last></author>
      <author><first>Tushar</first><last>Kanakagiri</last></author>
      <author><first>Karthik</first><last>Radhakrishnan</last></author>
      <author><first>Anjana</first><last>Umapathy</last></author>
      <pages>90–94</pages>
      <abstract>Automatic identification of cause-effect relationships from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a> is a challenging but important problem in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence">artificial intelligence</a>. Identifying semantic relationships has become increasingly important for multiple downstream applications like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Question_answering">Question Answering</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">Information Retrieval</a> and Event Prediction. In this work, we tackle the problem of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Causal_inference">causal relationship extraction</a> from financial news using the FinCausal 2020 dataset. We tackle two tasks-1) Detecting the presence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Causality">causal relationships</a> and 2) Extracting segments corresponding to cause and effect from news snippets. We propose Transformer based sequence and token classification models with post-processing rules which achieve an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-number">F1 score</a> of 96.12 and 79.60 on Tasks 1 and 2 respectively.</abstract>
      <url hash="5960491b">2020.fnp-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>chakravarthy-etal-2020-domino</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/sharanyarc96/domino-fincausal2020" additional="false">sharanyarc96/domino-fincausal2020</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/squad">SQuAD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>IITkgp at FinCausal 2020, Shared Task 1 : Causality Detection using Sentence Embeddings in Financial Reports<fixed-case>IIT</fixed-case>kgp at <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ausal 2020, Shared Task 1: Causality Detection using Sentence Embeddings in Financial Reports</title>
      <author><first>Arka</first><last>Mitra</last></author>
      <author><first>Harshvardhan</first><last>Srivastava</last></author>
      <author><first>Yugam</first><last>Tiwari</last></author>
      <pages>95–99</pages>
      <abstract>The paper describes the work that the team submitted to FinCausal 2020 Shared Task. This work is associated with the first sub-task of identifying causality in sentences. The various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> used in the experiments tried to obtain a latent space representation for each of the sentences. Linear regression was performed on these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representation_(mathematics)">representations</a> to classify whether the sentence is causal or not. The experiments have shown BERT (Large) performed the best, giving a F1 score of 0.958, in the task of detecting the causality of sentences in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_statement">financial texts</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_statement">reports</a>. The class imbalance was dealt with a modified <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loss_function">loss function</a> to give a better metric score for the evaluation.</abstract>
      <url hash="320606fe">2020.fnp-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>mitra-etal-2020-iitkgp</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Extractive Financial Narrative Summarisation based on DPPs<fixed-case>DPP</fixed-case>s</title>
      <author><first>Lei</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <author><first>Yafei</first><last>Jiang</last></author>
      <author><first>Yinan</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <pages>100–104</pages>
      <abstract>We participate in the FNS-Summarisation 2020 shared task to be held at FNP 2020 workshop at COLING 2020. Based on Determinantal Point Processes (DPPs), we build an extractive automatic financial summarisation system for the specific task. In this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>, we first analyze the long report data to select the important narrative parts and generate an intermediate document. Next, we build the kernel Matrix L for the intermediate document, which represents the quality of its sentences. On the basis of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L_(complexity)">L</a>, we then can use the DPPs sampling algorithm to choose those sentences with high quality and diversity as the final summary sentences.</abstract>
      <url hash="30d861d5">2020.fnp-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>li-etal-2020-extractive</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>End-to-end Training For Financial Report Summarization</title>
      <author><first>Moreno</first><last>La Quatra</last></author>
      <author><first>Luca</first><last>Cagliero</last></author>
      <pages>118–123</pages>
      <abstract>Quoted companies are requested to periodically publish <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_statement">financial reports</a> in textual form. The annual financial reports typically include detailed financial and business information, thus giving relevant insights into company outlooks. However, a manual exploration of these financial reports could be very time consuming since most of the available information can be deemed as non-informative or redundant by expert readers. Hence, an increasing research interest has been devoted to automatically extracting domain-specific summaries, which include only the most relevant information. This paper describes the SumTO system architecture, which addresses the Shared Task of the Financial Narrative Summarisation (FNS) 2020 contest. The main task objective is to automatically extract the most informative, domain-specific textual content from financial, English-written documents. The aim is to create a summary of each company report covering all the business-relevant key points. To address the above-mentioned goal, we propose an end-to-end training method relying on Deep NLP techniques. The idea behind the system is to exploit the syntactic overlap between input sentences and ground-truth summaries to fine-tune pre-trained BERT embedding models, thus making such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> tailored to the specific context. The achieved results confirm the effectiveness of the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a>, especially when the goal is to select relatively long text snippets.</abstract>
      <url hash="628f542b">2020.fnp-1.20</url>
      <bibkey>la-quatra-cagliero-2020-end</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/morenolaquatra/sumto_financial_summarization" additional="false">morenolaquatra/sumto_financial_summarization</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>AMEX AI-Labs : An Investigative Study on Extractive Summarization of Financial Documents<fixed-case>AMEX</fixed-case> <fixed-case>AI</fixed-case>-Labs: An Investigative Study on Extractive Summarization of Financial Documents</title>
      <author><first>Piyush</first><last>Arora</last></author>
      <author><first>Priya</first><last>Radhakrishnan</last></author>
      <pages>137–142</pages>
      <abstract>We describe the work carried out by AMEX AI-LABS on an extractive summarization benchmark task focused on Financial Narratives Summarization (FNS). This task focuses on summarizing annual financial reports which poses two main challenges as compared to typical news document summarization tasks : i) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annual_report">annual reports</a> are more lengthier (average length about 80 pages) as compared to typical news documents, and ii) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annual_report">annual reports</a> are more loosely structured e.g. comprising of tables, charts, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_(literary_theory)">textual data</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_image">images</a>, which makes it challenging to effectively summarize. To address this summarization task we investigate a range of unsupervised, supervised and ensemble based techniques. We find that ensemble based techniques perform relatively better as compared to using only the unsupervised and supervised based techniques. Our ensemble based model achieved the highest rank of 9 out of 31 systems submitted for the benchmark task based on Rouge-L evaluation metric.</abstract>
      <url hash="75e35e28">2020.fnp-1.23</url>
      <bibkey>arora-radhakrishnan-2020-amex</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="28">
      <title>Taxy.io@FinTOC-2020 : Multilingual Document Structure Extraction using Transfer Learning<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>TOC</fixed-case>-2020: Multilingual Document Structure Extraction using Transfer Learning</title>
      <author><first>Frederic</first><last>Haase</last></author>
      <author><first>Steffen</first><last>Kirchhoff</last></author>
      <pages>163–168</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we describe our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> submitted to the FinTOC-2020 shared task on financial doc- ument structure extraction. We propose a two-step approach to identify titles in financial docu- ments and to extract their table of contents (TOC). First, we identify text blocks as candidates for titles using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unsupervised_learning">unsupervised learning</a> based on character-level information of each document. Then, we apply <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervised_learning">supervised learning</a> on a self-constructed regression task to predict the depth of each text block in the document structure hierarchy using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">transfer learning</a> combined with document features and layout features. It is noteworthy that our single multilingual model performs well on both tasks and on different languages, which indicates the usefulness of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">transfer learning</a> for title detection and TOC generation. Moreover, our approach is independent of the presence of actual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Table_of_contents">TOC pages</a> in the documents. It is also one of the few submissions to the FinTOC-2020 shared task addressing both subtasks in both languages, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>, with one single <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="65681eb8">2020.fnp-1.28</url>
      <bibkey>haase-kirchhoff-2020-taxy</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="31">
      <title>A Computational Analysis of Financial and Environmental Narratives within <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_statement">Financial Reports</a> and its Value for Investors</title>
      <author><first>Felix</first><last>Armbrust</last></author>
      <author><first>Henry</first><last>Schäfer</last></author>
      <author><first>Roman</first><last>Klinger</last></author>
      <pages>181–194</pages>
      <abstract>Public companies are obliged to include financial and non-financial information within their cor- porate filings under Regulation S-K, in the United States (SEC, 2010). However, the requirements still allow for manager’s discretion. This raises the question to which extent the information is actually included and if this information is at all relevant for investors. We answer this question by training and evaluating an end-to-end deep learning approach (based on BERT and GloVe embeddings) to predict the financial and environmental performance of the company from the Management’s Discussion and Analysis of Financial Conditions and Results of Operations (MD&amp;A) section of 10-K (yearly) and 10-Q (quarterly) filings. We further analyse the mediating effect of the environmental performance on the relationship between the company’s disclosures and financial performance. Hereby, we address the results of previous studies regarding environ- mental performance. We find that the textual information contained within the MD&amp;A section does not allow for conclusions about the future (corporate) financial performance. However, there is evidence that the environmental performance can be extracted by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing methods</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="93580757">2020.fnp-1.31</url>
      <bibkey>armbrust-etal-2020-computational</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/forgefin/fin-env-narrative" additional="false">forgefin/fin-env-narrative</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="33">
      <title>Mitigating Silence in Compliance Terminology during Parsing of Utterances</title>
      <author><first>Esme</first><last>Manandise</last></author>
      <author><first>Conrad</first><last>de Peuter</last></author>
      <pages>204–212</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports on an approach to increase multi-token-term recall in a parsing task. We use a compliance-domain parser to extract, during the process of parsing raw text, terms that are unlisted in the terminology. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a> uses a similarity measure (Generalized Dice Coefficient) between listed terms and unlisted term candidates to (i) determine term status, (ii) serve putative terms to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a>, (iii) decrease parsing complexity by glomming multi-tokens as lexical singletons, and (iv) automatically augment the terminology after parsing of an utterance completes. We illustrate a small experiment with examples from the tax-and-regulations domain. Bootstrapping the parsing process to detect out- of-vocabulary terms at runtime increases parsing accuracy in addition to producing other benefits to a natural-language-processing pipeline, which translates arithmetic calculations written in English into computer-executable operations.</abstract>
      <url hash="fb22bb11">2020.fnp-1.33</url>
      <bibkey>manandise-de-peuter-2020-mitigating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>