<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.trustnlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Trustworthy Natural Language Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Yada</first><last>Pruksachatkun</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anil</first><last>Ramakrishna</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kai-Wei</first><last>Chang</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Satyapriya</first><last>Krishna</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jwala</first><last>Dhamala</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Tanaya</first><last>Guha</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Xiang</first><last>Ren</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.trustnlp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="c36171ab">2021.trustnlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>trustnlp-2021-trustworthy</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Interpretability Rules : Jointly Bootstrapping a Neural Relation Extractorwith an Explanation Decoder</title>
      <author><first>Zheng</first><last>Tang</last></author>
      <author><first>Mihai</first><last>Surdeanu</last></author>
      <pages>1–7</pages>
      <abstract>We introduce a method that transforms a rule-based relation extraction (RE) classifier into a neural one such that both interpretability and performance are achieved. Our approach jointly trains a RE classifier with a decoder that generates explanations for these extractions, using as sole supervision a set of rules that match these relations. Our evaluation on the TACRED dataset shows that our neural RE classifier outperforms the rule-based one we started from by 9 F1 points ; our decoder generates explanations with a high BLEU score of over 90 % ; and, the joint learning improves the performance of both the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> and decoder.</abstract>
      <url hash="06b035ec">2021.trustnlp-1.1</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryData" hash="99d332b6">2021.trustnlp-1.1.OptionalSupplementaryData.tgz</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.trustnlp-1.1</doi>
      <bibkey>tang-surdeanu-2021-interpretability</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Measuring Biases of Word Embeddings : What <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Similarity_measure">Similarity Measures</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Descriptive_statistics">Descriptive Statistics</a> to Use?</title>
      <author><first>Hossein</first><last>Azarpanah</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohsen</first><last>Farhadloo</last></author>
      <pages>8–14</pages>
      <abstract>Word embeddings are widely used in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing (NLP)</a> for a vast range of applications. However, it has been consistently proven that these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embedding">embeddings</a> reflect the same <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">human biases</a> that exist in the data used to train them. Most of the introduced bias indicators to reveal word embeddings’ bias are average-based indicators based on the cosine similarity measure. In this study, we examine the impacts of different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Similarity_measure">similarity measures</a> as well as other descriptive techniques than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Average">averaging</a> in measuring the biases of contextual and non-contextual word embeddings. We show that the extent of revealed biases in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embeddings</a> depends on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Descriptive_statistics">descriptive statistics</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Similarity_measure">similarity measures</a> used to measure the bias. We found that over the ten categories of word embedding association tests, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mahalanobis_distance">Mahalanobis distance</a> reveals the smallest bias, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euclidean_distance">Euclidean distance</a> reveals the largest bias in word embeddings. In addition, the contextual models reveal less severe biases than the non-contextual word embedding models.</abstract>
      <url hash="f76a7135">2021.trustnlp-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.trustnlp-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>azarpanah-farhadloo-2021-measuring</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Private Release of Text Embedding Vectors</title>
      <author><first>Oluwaseyi</first><last>Feyisetan</last></author>
      <author><first>Shiva</first><last>Kasiviswanathan</last></author>
      <pages>15–27</pages>
      <abstract>Ensuring strong theoretical privacy guarantees on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_file">text data</a> is a challenging problem which is usually attained at the expense of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Utility">utility</a>. However, to improve the practicality of privacy preserving text analyses, it is essential to design algorithms that better optimize this tradeoff. To address this challenge, we propose a release mechanism that takes any (text) embedding vector as input and releases a corresponding private vector. The mechanism satisfies an extension of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Differential_privacy">differential privacy</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_space">metric spaces</a>. Our idea based on first randomly projecting the vectors to a lower-dimensional space and then adding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noise_(signal_processing)">noise</a> in this projected space generates private vectors that achieve strong theoretical guarantees on its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Utility">utility</a>. We support our theoretical proofs with empirical experiments on multiple word embedding models and NLP datasets, achieving in some cases more than 10 % gains over the existing state-of-the-art privatization techniques.</abstract>
      <url hash="8e14c23f">2021.trustnlp-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.trustnlp-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>feyisetan-kasiviswanathan-2021-private</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/mpqa-opinion-corpus">MPQA Opinion Corpus</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/sst">SST</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>xER : An Explainable Model for Entity Resolution using an Efficient Solution for the Clique Partitioning Problem<fixed-case>ER</fixed-case>: An Explainable Model for Entity Resolution using an Efficient Solution for the Clique Partitioning Problem</title>
      <author><first>Samhita</first><last>Vadrevu</last></author>
      <author><first>Rakesh</first><last>Nagi</last></author>
      <author><first>JinJun</first><last>Xiong</last></author>
      <author><first>Wen-mei</first><last>Hwu</last></author>
      <pages>34–44</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we propose a global, self- explainable solution to solve a prominent NLP problem : Entity Resolution (ER). We formu- late ER as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_partitioning_problem">graph partitioning problem</a>. Every mention of a real-world entity is represented by a node in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(discrete_mathematics)">graph</a>, and the pairwise sim- ilarity scores between the mentions are used to associate these nodes to exactly one <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clique_(graph_theory)">clique</a>, which represents a real-world entity in the ER domain. In this paper, we use Clique Partition- ing Problem (CPP), which is an Integer Pro- gram (IP) to formulate ER as a graph partition- ing problem and then highlight the explainable nature of this method. Since CPP is NP-Hard, we introduce an efficient solution procedure, the xER algorithm, to solve CPP as a combi- nation of finding maximal cliques in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(discrete_mathematics)">graph</a> and then performing generalized set packing using a novel formulation. We discuss the advantages of using xER over the traditional methods and provide the computational exper- iments and results of applying this method to ER data sets.</abstract>
      <url hash="2c21d97b">2021.trustnlp-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.trustnlp-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>vadrevu-etal-2021-xer</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ecb">ECB+</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Towards Benchmarking the Utility of Explanations for Model Debugging</title>
      <author><first>Maximilian</first><last>Idahl</last></author>
      <author><first>Lijun</first><last>Lyu</last></author>
      <author><first>Ujwal</first><last>Gadiraju</last></author>
      <author><first>Avishek</first><last>Anand</last></author>
      <pages>68–73</pages>
      <abstract>Post-hoc explanation methods are an important class of approaches that help understand the rationale underlying a trained model’s decision. But how useful are they for an end-user towards accomplishing a given task? In this vision paper, we argue the need for a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benchmarking">benchmark</a> to facilitate evaluations of the utility of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Post-hoc_analysis">post-hoc explanation methods</a>. As a first step to this end, we enumerate desirable properties that such a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benchmark_(computing)">benchmark</a> should possess for the task of debugging text classifiers. Additionally, we highlight that such a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benchmarking">benchmark</a> facilitates not only assessing the effectiveness of explanations but also their efficiency.</abstract>
      <url hash="dfa79dcd">2021.trustnlp-1.8</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.trustnlp-1.8</doi>
      <bibkey>idahl-etal-2021-towards</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/sst">SST</pwcdataset>
    <title_es>Hacia una evaluación comparativa de la utilidad de las explicaciones para la depuración de modelos</title_es>
      <title_pt>Para comparar o utilitário de explicações para depuração de modelo</title_pt>
      <title_ar>نحو قياس فائدة التفسيرات لتصحيح الأخطاء في النموذج</title_ar>
      <title_hi>मॉडल डीबगिंग के लिए स्पष्टीकरण की उपयोगिता बेंचमार्किंग की ओर</title_hi>
      <title_ja>モデルデバッグの説明の有用性のベンチマークに向けて</title_ja>
      <title_zh>对模型调试解释之效以准测试</title_zh>
      <title_ga>I dTreo Tagarmharcála ar Fhóntas na Mínithe le haghaidh Dífhabhtaithe Múnla</title_ga>
      <title_ka>მოდელის განბზემის გამოსახულებების გამოყენება</title_ka>
      <title_el>Προς τον συγκριτικό έλεγχο της χρησιμότητας των επεξηγήσεων για τη διόρθωση υποδειγμάτων</title_el>
      <title_hu>A modellhibakeresés magyarázatainak hasznosságának összehasonlítása felé</title_hu>
      <title_it>Verso un benchmarking dell'utilità delle spiegazioni per il debug dei modelli</title_it>
      <title_kk>Үлгі жөндеу үшін түсініктемелер утилитасын белгілеу</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Towards Benchmarking the Utility of Explanations for Model Debugging</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Paaiškinimų dėl atsisakymo modelio naudojimo lyginamojo vertinimo</title_lt>
      <title_ml>മോഡല്‍ പിഴവ് തെറ്റുന്നതിനുള്ള ഉപകരണത്തിനുള്ള ഉപകരണങ്ങള്‍ മുകളിലേക്ക് മാറുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Menuju Benchmarking Utility of Explanations for Model Debugging</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Lejn il-Benchmarking tal-Utilità ta’ Spjegazzjonijiet għal Mudell ta’ Depugging</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Загварын шийдвэрлэлийн хэрэглээ банкмаркинг руу</title_mn>
      <title_no>Gå til benchmarking verktøyet for utklaringar for modellefeilsøking</title_no>
      <title_ro>Către analiza comparativă a utilității explicațiilor pentru depanarea modelelor</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Skrenuo je korisnost objašnjenja modela</title_sr>
      <title_pl>W kierunku analizy porównawczej użyteczności wyjaśnień dla debugowania modeli</title_pl>
      <title_ta>மேல் பென்ச்மெங்குப்பாட்டில் மாதிரி பிழைநீக்கத்திற்கான பயன்பாடு</title_ta>
      <title_so>Towards Benchmarking the Utility of Explanations for Model Debugging</title_so>
      <title_sv>Mot benchmarking av nyttan av förklaringar för modellfelsökning</title_sv>
      <title_ur>Model Debugging کے لئے توضیح کا استعمال بنچم کرنے کی طرف</title_ur>
      <title_si>මොඩේල් විවේදනය සඳහා ප්‍රකාශනය සඳහා බෙන්ච්මාර්ක් කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_uz>@ info</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Để chuẩn bị điểm chính sách Name</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Към сравнителен анализ на полезността на обясненията за отстраняване на грешки в моделите</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Naar benchmarking van het nut van toelichtingen voor model debuggen</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Usmjerenje korisnosti objašnjenja modela</title_hr>
      <title_da>På vej mod benchmarking af nytten af forklaringer til model fejlfinding</title_da>
      <title_de>Auf dem Weg zum Benchmarking des Nutzens von Erläuterungen für Model Debugging</title_de>
      <title_fa>به سمت برچسب استفاده توضیح‌ها برای تبدیل کردن مدل</title_fa>
      <title_ko>기준 테스트 모델 디버깅 해석의 실용성</title_ko>
      <title_id>Menuju Benchmarking Utility of Explanations for Model Debugging</title_id>
      <title_sw>Upande wa benchmarking Utumiaji wa Mazungumzo kwa ajili ya Kupima Ubadilisho wa Model</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Model Arşitleme üçin Aňlamak Aralygyny Çykarmak üçin Ýarda</title_tr>
      <title_af>Na die Benchmarking van die nutsprogramme van Verduidelings vir Model Ontfouting</title_af>
      <title_sq>Për përkrahjen e përdorueshmërisë së shpjegimeve për Debugging Model</title_sq>
      <title_am>Towards Benchmarking the Utility of Explanations for Model Debugging</title_am>
      <title_hy>Մոդելի զարգացման բացատրությունների օգտակարության համեմատության ուղղությամբ</title_hy>
      <title_az>Model Arzulamas캼 칲칞칲n 쿮fsilm톛tl톛rin istifad톛si</title_az>
      <title_bn>মোডেল ডিবাগিং এর জন্য এক্সপ্ল্যানেজের ব্যবহার</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Prema pregledu korisnosti objašnjenja modela</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Vers la comparació de l'utilitat d'explicacions de depuració model</title_ca>
      <title_et>Mudeli silumise selgituste kasulikkuse võrdlusanalüüs</title_et>
      <title_cs>Směrem k srovnávání užitečnosti vysvětlení pro modelové ladění</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Kohti mallien virheenkorjauksen selitysten hyödyllisyyden vertailuanalyysia</title_fi>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>לכיוון סימני השימוש של הסברים לנגירת דוגמנים</title_he>
      <title_sk>Proti primerjalni analizi uporabnosti pojasnil za odpravljanje napak modelov</title_sk>
      <title_jv>Tarjamahan Bench-marking Utubut kanggo Keurahaan kanggo Debug model</title_jv>
      <title_bo>Model Debug་ལ་སྟོན་པར་འཆར་བཤེར་གྱི་ལག་ཆ་སྟངས་བཀལ་བ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تعد طرق التفسير اللاحق فئة مهمة من الأساليب التي تساعد في فهم الأساس المنطقي وراء قرار النموذج المدرب. ولكن ما مدى فائدتها للمستخدم النهائي في إنجاز مهمة معينة؟ في ورقة الرؤية هذه ، نجادل في الحاجة إلى معيار لتسهيل تقييمات فائدة طرق التفسير اللاحقة. كخطوة أولى لتحقيق هذه الغاية ، نقوم بتعداد الخصائص المرغوبة التي يجب أن يمتلكها مثل هذا المعيار لمهمة تصحيح أخطاء مصنفات النص. بالإضافة إلى ذلك ، نسلط الضوء على أن مثل هذا المعيار لا يسهل فقط تقييم فعالية التفسيرات ولكن أيضًا كفاءتها.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Los métodos de explicación post-hoc son una clase importante de enfoques que ayudan a comprender los fundamentos de la decisión de un modelo entrenado. Pero, ¿qué tan útiles son para que un usuario final lleve a cabo una tarea determinada? En este documento de visión, argumentamos la necesidad de un punto de referencia para facilitar las evaluaciones de la utilidad de los métodos de explicación post-hoc. Como primer paso hacia este fin, enumeramos las propiedades deseables que este punto de referencia debe poseer para la tarea de depurar los clasificadores de texto. Además, destacamos que este punto de referencia facilita no solo la evaluación de la eficacia de las explicaciones sino también su eficiencia.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Os métodos de explicação post-hoc são uma classe importante de abordagens que ajudam a entender a lógica subjacente à decisão de um modelo treinado. Mas quão úteis eles são para um usuário final para realizar uma determinada tarefa? Neste documento de visão, argumentamos a necessidade de um benchmark para facilitar as avaliações da utilidade dos métodos de explicação post-hoc. Como primeiro passo para este fim, enumeramos as propriedades desejáveis que tal benchmark deve possuir para a tarefa de depurar classificadores de texto. Além disso, destacamos que tal benchmark facilita não apenas a avaliação da eficácia das explicações, mas também sua eficiência.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>事後的な説明方法は、訓練されたモデルの意思決定の基礎となる根拠を理解するのに役立つ重要なアプローチのクラスです。しかし、それらは与えられたタスクを達成するためのエンドユーザーにとってどの程度有用ですか？このビジョン論文では、事後説明法の有用性の評価を容易にするためのベンチマークの必要性を主張している。そのための最初のステップとして、このようなベンチマークがテキスト分類子のデバッグ作業のために持つべき望ましい特性を列挙する。さらに、このようなベンチマークは、説明の有効性だけでなく、その効率性を評価するのにも役立つことを強調しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>पोस्ट-हॉक स्पष्टीकरण विधियां दृष्टिकोणों का एक महत्वपूर्ण वर्ग हैं जो एक प्रशिक्षित मॉडल के निर्णय के अंतर्निहित तर्क को समझने में मदद करती हैं। लेकिन किसी दिए गए कार्य को पूरा करने की दिशा में अंतिम उपयोगकर्ता के लिए वे कितने उपयोगी हैं? इस दृष्टि पत्र में, हम पोस्ट-हॉक स्पष्टीकरण विधियों की उपयोगिता के मूल्यांकन को सुविधाजनक बनाने के लिए एक बेंचमार्क की आवश्यकता का तर्क देते हैं। इस अंत के लिए पहले कदम के रूप में, हम वांछनीय गुणों की गणना करते हैं जो इस तरह के बेंचमार्क को टेक्स्ट क्लासिफायर्स को डीबग करने के कार्य के लिए होना चाहिए। इसके अतिरिक्त, हम इस बात पर प्रकाश डालते हैं कि इस तरह के बेंचमार्क न केवल स्पष्टीकरण की प्रभावशीलता का आकलन करने की सुविधा प्रदान करते हैं, बल्कि उनकी दक्षता भी।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>其后说法为一要,有助于训练之基本原理。 然其於最终用户成给定任有多大用处哉? 本愿景文中,以为须一准以趣后效。 为此一者,枚举此准,试于调文本分类器之任。 此外我辈强调,不惟有助于评释之有效性,亦有助于估效率。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Is cineál cur chuige tábhachtach iad modhanna mínithe iar-hoc a chabhraíonn le tuiscint a fháil ar an réasúnaíocht atá mar bhonn le cinneadh múnla oilte. Ach cé chomh húsáideach atá siad don úsáideoir deiridh chun tasc ar leith a chur i gcrích? Sa pháipéar físe seo, áitímid go bhfuil gá le tagarmharc chun meastóireachtaí a éascú ar úsáid modhanna mínithe iar-hoc. Mar chéad chéim chuige sin, áirímid na hairíonna inmhianaithe ba cheart a bheith ag tagarmharc den sórt sin chun aicmitheoirí téacs a dhífhabhtú. Ina theannta sin, tugaimid chun suntais go n-éascaíonn tagarmharc den sórt sin ní amháin éifeachtacht na mínithe a mheasúnú ach freisin a n-éifeachtúlacht.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>A poszthoc magyarázat módszerek fontos megközelítési osztálya, amelyek segítenek megérteni a képzett modell döntésének alapjául szolgáló indokokat. De mennyire hasznosak egy végfelhasználó számára egy adott feladat elvégzésében? Ebben az elképzelésben azzal érvelünk, hogy szükség van egy referenciaértékre, amely megkönnyíti a post-hoc magyarázat módszerek hasznosságának értékelését. Első lépésként felsoroljuk azokat a kívánatos tulajdonságokat, amelyekkel egy ilyen referenciaértéknek rendelkeznie kell a szövegosztályozók hibakereséséhez. Emellett kiemeljük, hogy egy ilyen referenciaérték nemcsak a magyarázatok hatékonyságának értékelését, hanem hatékonyságukat is megkönnyíti.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Οι μέθοδοι επεξήγησης είναι μια σημαντική κατηγορία προσεγγίσεων που βοηθούν στην κατανόηση της αιτιολογίας που βασίζεται στην απόφαση ενός εκπαιδευμένου μοντέλου. Αλλά πόσο χρήσιμες είναι για έναν τελικό χρήστη για την εκπλήρωση ενός συγκεκριμένου έργου; Σε αυτό το έγγραφο οραμάτων, υποστηρίζουμε την ανάγκη για ένα σημείο αναφοράς για τη διευκόλυνση των αξιολογήσεων της χρησιμότητας των μεθόδων επεξήγησης μετά-hoc. Ως πρώτο βήμα προς αυτό το σκοπό, απαριθμούμε τις επιθυμητές ιδιότητες που θα πρέπει να κατέχει ένα τέτοιο σημείο αναφοράς για το έργο της αποσφαλμάτωσης ταξινομητών κειμένου. Επιπλέον, επισημαίνουμε ότι ένα τέτοιο σημείο αναφοράς διευκολύνει όχι μόνο την αξιολόγηση της αποτελεσματικότητας των εξηγήσεων αλλά και την αποτελεσματικότητά τους.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>I metodi di spiegazione post-hoc sono una classe importante di approcci che aiutano a comprendere la logica alla base della decisione di un modello addestrato. Ma quanto sono utili per un utente finale nella realizzazione di un determinato compito? In questo documento di visione, sosteniamo la necessità di un benchmark per facilitare la valutazione dell'utilità dei metodi di spiegazione post-hoc. Come primo passo a questo scopo, enumeramo le proprietà desiderabili che un tale benchmark dovrebbe possedere per il compito di debug dei classificatori di testo. Inoltre, sottolineiamo che tale parametro facilita non solo la valutazione dell'efficacia delle spiegazioni, ma anche la loro efficienza.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Соңғы түсініктеме әдістері - оқылған үлгінің шешімін түсініп, түсініктердің маңызды түсініктеме класы. Бірақ олар келтірілген тапсырманы орындау үшін соңғы пайдаланушыға қанша пайдалы? Бұл көрініс қағазында, соңғы түсініс тәсілдерінің утилитациясының бағалауын көмектесу үшін бақылау керектігін айтып тұрмыз. Бұл соңына бірінші қадам ретінде, мәтін жөндеу классификаторларының тапсырмасын қалайтын қасиеттерді есептеп береміз. Сонымен қатар, бұл параметр тек түсініктердің ефективдігін оқу үшін емес, сондай-ақ олардың ефективдігін оқу үшін анықтайды.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Постохок методите на објаснување се важна класа на пристапи кои помагаат да се разбере рационалната основа на одлуката на обучениот модел. Но колку корисни се тие за крајниот корисник за исполнување на одредена задача? Во овој документ за визија, тврдиме дека е потребно benchmark за олеснување на проценките на корисноста на пост-хок методите на објаснување. Како прв чекор кон оваа цел, ги нумираме желбите сопствености кои ваквата референтна значка треба да ги поседува за задачата на распоредување на класификаторите на текст. Покрај тоа, истакнуваме дека ваквата референтна мерка не само што ја олеснува проценката на ефикасноста на објаснувањата, туку и нивната ефикасност.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kaedah penjelasan post-hoc adalah kelas penting pendekatan yang membantu memahami alasan yang mendasarkan keputusan model terlatih. Tetapi bagaimana berguna bagi pengguna akhir untuk menyelesaikan tugas tertentu? Dalam kertas penglihatan ini, kita berdebat perlukan tanda referensi untuk memudahkan penilaian utiliti kaedah penjelasan post-hoc. Sebagai langkah pertama ke hujung ini, kita enumerasikan ciri-ciri yang diinginkan yang tanda rujukan seperti itu sepatutnya mempunyai untuk tugas penyahpepijatan pengeklasifikasi teks. Selain itu, kami menyatakan bahawa tanda referensi seperti itu memudahkan tidak hanya menilai kegunaan penjelasan tetapi juga kegunaan mereka.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ka>ოჲჟჳჲკ ჲბწჟნწგანთწ მვრჲეთ ჟა მნჲდჲ გაზნთ კლაჟა ნა ოპთწრვლთრვ, კჲთრჲ ოჲმჲდნარ ეა პაჱბვპვ პაჱსმვნთვრჲ ნა პაჱსმვნთვრჲ ნა რპვნთპან მჲევლ. მაგრამ რამდენი გამოსაყენებელია დასასრულებელი მომხმარებელისთვის, რომლებიც დასასრულებელი მომხმარებელია? ჩვენ ახალგაზრდებით, რომ ბენქმარკი უნდა გავამუშავოთ პოსჰოკის გამოწვების გამოყენება. როგორც პირველი კონფიგურაციაში, ჩვენ მინდომი განსაზღვრებელი განსაზღვრებების შესახებ, რომელიც ასეთი კონფიგურაცია უნდა იყავს ტექსტის კლასიფიგურაციის დამატებით, ჩვენ აღწერეთ, რომ ასეთი ბანქმერი უფლება არა მხოლოდ განახსნას ეფექტიურობას, მაგრამ ისინი ეფექტიურობას.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_ml>പിന്നീട് ഹോക്ക് വിശദീകരിക്കുന്ന രീതികള്‍ ഒരു പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട പരിശീലന മോഡലിന്‍റെ തീരുമാനം നടത്തുന്നതില്‍ നിന പക്ഷെ അവസാന ഉപയോക്താവിന് അവര്‍ക്ക് എത്ര പ്രയോജനപ്പെടുന്നു? ഈ ദര്‍ശനത്തിന്റെ പത്രത്തില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ വാദിക്കുന്നു, ഒരു ബെന്‍ച്മാര്‍ക്ക് ആവശ്യമുണ്ടെന്ന്, പിന്നെ ഹോക്ക് വിശദീകരിക്ക ഈ അവസാനത്തിന്റെ ആദ്യത്തെ പടിയായി ഞങ്ങള്‍ ആഗ്രഹിക്കുന്ന ഗുണഗണങ്ങള്‍ എണ്ണുന്നു. ഇതുപോലൊരു ബെന്‍ച്മാര്‍ക്ക് പിഴവ് വിവരങ് കൂടാതെ, ഇത്തരം ബെന്‍ച്മാര്‍ക്ക് വിശദീകരണങ്ങളുടെ പ്രഭാവം മാത്രമല്ല, അവരുടെ പ്രഭാവം മാത്രമല്ല.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Сургуулсан загварын шийдвэрийг ойлгоход тусалдаг хамгийн чухал арга зам юм. Гэхдээ эцсийн хэрэглэгчид ямар хэрэгтэй вэ? Энэ харагдаж байгаа цаасан дээр бид дараагийн тайлбарлалтын хэрэглээ үнэлэх хэрэгтэй гэдгийг хэлж байна. Энэ төгсгөлд эхний алхам болгон, бид ийм банкмарк нь текст классификацийн ажлыг шийдвэрлэх шаардлагатай чадварыг тооцож байна. Мөн бид ийм тодорхойлолт нь зөвхөн тодорхойлолтын үр дүнтэй байдлыг, мөн үр дүнтэй байдлыг тодорхойлж чадахгүй гэдгийг тодорхойлдог.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_lt>Po hoc paaiškinimo metodai yra svarbi metodų klasė, padedanti suprasti pagrįstą mokymo modelio sprendimą. Bet kaip naudingos jos galutiniam vartotojui tam tikros užduoties vykdymui? Šiame vizijos dokumente teigiame, kad reikia lyginamojo rodiklio, kuris palengvintų post hoc paaiškinimo metodų naudingumo vertinimą. Pirmuoju žingsniu šiuo tikslu išvardijame pageidaujamas savybes, kurias toks lyginamasis rodiklis turėtų turėti vykdant failavimo teksto klasifikatorių užduotį. Be to, pabrėžiame, kad toks lyginamasis rodiklis padeda ne tik įvertinti paaiškinimų veiksmingumą, bet ir jų veiksmingumą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ro>Metodele de explicare post-hoc reprezintă o clasă importantă de abordări care ajută la înțelegerea rațiunii care stau la baza deciziei unui model instruit. Dar cât de utile sunt acestea pentru un utilizator final în îndeplinirea unei sarcini date? În acest document de viziune, argumentăm necesitatea unui benchmark pentru a facilita evaluarea utilității metodelor de explicare post-hoc. Ca prim pas în acest scop, enumerăm proprietățile dorite pe care un astfel de referință ar trebui să le posede pentru sarcina de depanare a clasificatoarelor de text. În plus, subliniem că un astfel de referință facilitează nu numai evaluarea eficacității explicațiilor, ci și a eficienței acestora.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>Metody wyjaśniania post-hoc są ważną klasą podejść, które pomagają zrozumieć uzasadnienie decyzji przeszkolonego modelu. Ale jak przydatne są dla użytkownika końcowego w realizacji danego zadania? W niniejszym opracowaniu wizji argumentujemy potrzebę ustanowienia referencji ułatwiającej ocenę użyteczności metod wyjaśniania post-hoc. Pierwszym krokiem w tym celu jest wyliczenie pożądanych właściwości, które taki referencyjny powinien posiadać do zadania debugowania klasyfikatorów tekstowych. Dodatkowo podkreślamy, że taki punkt odniesienia ułatwia nie tylko ocenę skuteczności wyjaśnień, ale także ich skuteczności.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mt>Il-metodi ta’ spjegazzjoni post-hoc huma klassi importanti ta’ approċċi li jgħinu biex jifhmu r-raġunament li fuqu hija bbażata d-deċiżjoni ta’ mudell imħarreġ. Iżda kemm huma utli għal utent finali biex iwettaq kompitu partikolari? In this vision paper, we argue the need for a benchmark to facilitate evaluations of the utility of post-hoc explanation methods.  Bħala l-ewwel pass għal dan il-għan, a ħna nilenumeraw il-karatteristiċi mixtieqa li punt ta’ riferiment bħal dan għandu jkollu għall-kompitu ta’ klassifikaturi tat-test tad-depurazzjoni. Barra minn hekk, a ħna tenfasizzaw li tali punt ta’ riferiment jiffaċilita mhux biss il-valutazzjoni tal-effettività tal-ispjegazzjonijiet iżda wkoll l-effiċjenza tagħhom.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_sr>Posthočne metode objašnjenja su važna klasa pristupa koja pomaže da razumeju razlog pod odlukom obučenog model a. Ali koliko su korisni za krajnjeg korisnika za postizanje određenog zadatka? U ovom vizijskom papiru tvrdimo da je potrebna kritika za olakšanje procjene korisnosti posthočnih metoda objašnjavanja. Kao prvi korak do ovog kraja, brojimo poželjne vlasništvo koje bi takva kritika trebala posjedovati za zadatak klasifikatora teksta za debugging. Osim toga, naglašavamo da takva kritika olakšava ne samo procjenu učinkovitosti objašnjenja, nego i njihovu učinkovitost.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalka kala garsoorida dib-hoc waa fasalka muhiim ah, kaas oo caawinaya inuu fahmo go'aanka sameynta modelka la tababaray. Laakin sidee faa'iido bay u leeyihiin in ay dhamaado shaqada la siiyey? Qoraalkan muuqashada waxaynu ka sheekaynaynaa in loo baahan yahay bangiga si loo fududeeyo qiimeynta isticmaalka qaababka kala garsoorida kadib. Marka ugu horeysa halkan, waxaynu xisaabnaynaa hantidii aad u baahan tahay in bookmarkaas caynkaas ah uu u lahaado shaqada ka baaraandegista fasaxyada qoraalka. Sidoo kale waxaynu ku qoraynaa in bangiyadu ay sawiraan faa’iidada fasaxa oo keliya, laakiin sidoo kale waxyaabahooda.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Post-hoc förklaringsmetoder är en viktig klass av tillvägagångssätt som hjälper till att förstå motiven bakom en utbildad modells beslut. Men hur användbara är de för en slutanvändare när det gäller att utföra en viss uppgift? I detta visionsdokument argumenterar vi för behovet av ett riktmärke för att underlätta utvärderingar av nyttan av post-hoc förklaringsmetoder. Som ett första steg i detta syfte räknar vi upp önskvärda egenskaper som ett sådant riktmärke bör ha för uppgiften att felsöka textklassificerare. Dessutom betonar vi att ett sådant riktmärke underlättar inte bara bedömningen av hur effektiva förklaringarna är, utan också hur effektiva de är.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>පස්හෝක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් විදිහට ප්‍රශ්නයක් තමයි වැදගත් ප්‍රශ්නයක් විදිහට ප්‍රශ්නයක් විදිහට ප්‍රශ්නයක්  ඒත් ඔවුන් කොච්චර ප්‍රයෝජනයක් තියෙන්නේ අවසාන ප්‍රයෝජනකයෙක් වෙනුවෙන් වැඩ කරන්න? මේ බලන්න පැත්තේ අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා බෙන්ච්මාර්ක් එකක් විශ්වාස කරන්න පුළුවන් විදිහට පස්සේ හොක් ප්‍රශ්නයක මේ අවසානයට පළමු පැත්තක් විදියට, අපි අවශ්‍ය විශේෂතාවක් ගණන් කරනවා ඒ වගේ බෙන්ච්මාර්ක් වලින් පාළුවන් වි තවත්, අපි පැහැදිලි කරනවා ඒ වගේ බෙන්ච්මාර්ක් එකක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් විතරයි ප්‍රශ්නයක් ගැන විතරයි ඔවුන්ගේ වැඩක</abstract_si>
      <abstract_no>Post hoc-forklaringsmetodar er ein viktig klasse av tilnærmingar som hjelper å forstå rationalen som underligg opplærte modellen. Men kor nyttig er dei for ein sluttbrukar mot å fullføra ei oppgåve? I denne visingspapiret argumenterer vi nødvendighet for ein benchmarkt for å gjere tilgjengeleg evalueringa av verktøyet til post hoc-forklaringsmetodar. Som ein første steg til denne slutten, teller vi desimalar eigenskapar som slike benchmarket skal ha for oppgåva av feilsøkingstekstklassifikatorar. I tillegg markerer vi at slike benchmarket tilgjengeleg ikkje berre å vurdere effektiviteten av forklaringar, men også effektiviteten sine.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ur>پوس-هوک توضیح طریقے ایک اہم طریقے کا کلاس ہے جو ایک تربین مدل کے فیصلہ کے لائق منطقی کو سمجھنے کی مدد کرتی ہے. لیکن یہ آخر کارساز کے لئے کس قدر فائدہ پائیں گے؟ اس دیدھنی کاغذ میں، ہم ایک بنچم مارک کی ضرورت سے جھگڑتے ہیں کہ اس کے بعد اچھی توضیح کے طریقے کے استعمال کو آسان کرے۔ اس کے لئے پہلی قدم کے طور پر ہم چاہتے ہیں کہ اس طرح ایک بنچم مارک کو ٹیکس کلیسٹر کے کام کے لئے ملے۔ اور اس کے علاوہ ہم تفصیل دیتے ہیں کہ اس طرح ایک سنچم مارک صرف تفصیل کے مطابق کا ارزش نہ کرتا ہے بلکہ ان کے مطابق بھی ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>பின் ஹோக் விளக்கம் முறைமைகள் ஒரு முக்கியமான வகுப்பு முறைமைகளாகும். ஒரு பயிற்சி மாதிரியின் தீர்வு அடிப்படையில ஆனால் குறிப்பிட்ட செயலை நிறைவேற்றுவதற்கு அவர்கள் எவ்வளவு பயனுள்ளது? இந்த பார்வை காக்கியத்தில், நாம் ஒரு பெங்க்மார்க் தேவையை விவாதம் செய்ய வேண்டும் பின்பு ஹோக் விளக்கம் முறைமை இந்த முடிவிற்கு முதல் படி என்றால், நாம் கணக்கிட வேண்டிய தன்மைகளை கணக்கிடுகிறோம். பிழை நீக்கி உரை வகைப்பாளர்களின் செயல்பாட் கூடுதலாக, இது போன்ற ஒரு பெங்க்மார்க் விளக்கங்களின் விளைவுகளை மட்டும் மதிப்பு மட்டும் இல்லை ஆனால் அவர்களின் விளைவு</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Name Ko'rsatilgan vazifani bajarish uchun ularning foydalanuvchilari qanday foydalanadi? Bu vissiya qogʻozida biz benchmark kerak bo'lishi kerakligini hoc-hoc orzularning foydalanishini foydalanishiga foydalanishimiz kerak. Bu oxiriga birinchi darajada, biz kerakli xossalarni hisoblaymiz. Bu qanday benchmark matn darajalarini deb atashga ega boʻlishi kerak. Ko'pchilik, bu benchmark faqat tafsilotning effektini qiymatga foydalanishini foydalanadi, balki ularning effektligini ham ishlatish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Phương pháp giải thích hậu trường là một loại phương pháp quan trọng giúp hiểu lý do căn bản cho quyết định của mô hình được đào tạo. Nhưng chúng có ích gì cho người dùng cuối để hoàn thành một nhiệm vụ cụ thể? Trong tờ giấy chứng minh này, chúng tôi ủng hộ việc cần một tiêu chuẩn để dễ dàng đánh giá các phương pháp giải thích hậu trường. Như một bước đầu tiên đến mục đích này, chúng tôi liệt kê các đặc tính khả năng đáng mong đợi mà một điểm chuẩn như thế sẽ có cho nhiệm vụ phân tích đoạn mã hóa. Thêm vào đó, chúng tôi nhấn mạnh rằng một điểm chuẩn mực như thế giúp không chỉ đánh giá hiệu quả của giải thích mà còn hiệu quả của nó.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Пост-хок методите за обяснение са важен клас подходи, които помагат да се разбере обосновката в основата на решението на обучен модел. Но колко полезни са те за крайния потребител при изпълнението на дадена задача? В този документ за визия се аргументира необходимостта от референтен показател, който да улесни оценките на полезността на методите за пощенски обяснения. Като първа стъпка към тази цел изброяваме желаните свойства, които такъв бенчмарк трябва да притежава за задачата за отстраняване на грешки текстови класификатори. Освен това подчертаваме, че такъв показател улеснява не само оценката на ефективността на обясненията, но и тяхната ефективност.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Post-hoc verklaringsmethoden zijn een belangrijke klasse van benaderingen die helpen begrijpen wat de reden is die ten grondslag ligt aan de beslissing van een getraind model. Maar hoe nuttig zijn ze voor een eindgebruiker bij het uitvoeren van een bepaalde taak? In dit vision paper pleiten we voor de noodzaak van een benchmark om evaluaties van het nut van post-hoc verklaringsmethoden te vergemakkelijken. Als eerste stap daartoe noemen we wenselijke eigenschappen op die een dergelijke benchmark zou moeten hebben voor het debuggen van tekstclassificatoren. Daarnaast benadrukken we dat een dergelijke benchmark niet alleen de effectiviteit van verklaringen, maar ook de efficiëntie van verklaringen vergemakkelijkt.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Posthočke metode objašnjavanja su važna klasa pristupa koja pomaže razumjeti razlog pod odlukom obučenog model a. Ali koliko su korisni za krajnjeg korisnika za postizanje određenog zadatka? U ovom vizijskom papiru tvrdimo da je potrebna kritika za olakšanje procjene korisnosti posthočnih metoda objašnjavanja. Kao prvi korak do ovog kraja, brojimo poželjne vlasništvo koje bi takva kritika trebala posjedovati za zadatak klasifikatora propuštanja teksta. Osim toga, naglašavamo da takva kritika olakšava ne samo procjenu učinkovitosti objašnjenja, nego i njihovu učinkovitost.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Post-hoc forklaringsmetoder er en vigtig klasse af tilgange, der hjælper med at forstå begrundelsen bag en trænet models beslutning. Men hvor nyttige er de for en slutbruger til at udføre en given opgave? I dette visionsdokument argumenterer vi for behovet for et benchmark for at lette evalueringer af nytten af post-hoc forklaringsmetoder. Som et første skridt til dette formål opregner vi ønskelige egenskaber, som en sådan benchmark bør besidde til opgaven med fejlfinding af tekstklassifikationer. Desuden fremhæver vi, at et sådant benchmark ikke kun gør det lettere at vurdere effektiviteten af forklaringerne, men også deres effektivitet.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Post-hoc Erklärungsmethoden sind eine wichtige Klasse von Ansätzen, die helfen, die Gründe zu verstehen, die der Entscheidung eines trainierten Modells zugrunde liegen. Aber wie nützlich sind sie für den Endbenutzer, um eine bestimmte Aufgabe zu erfüllen? In diesem Vision Paper argumentieren wir die Notwendigkeit eines Benchmarks, um Bewertungen des Nutzens von Post-hoc-Erklärungsmethoden zu erleichtern. Als ersten Schritt zu diesem Zweck zählen wir wünschenswerte Eigenschaften auf, die ein solcher Benchmark für das Debuggen von Textklassifikatoren besitzen sollte. Darüber hinaus heben wir hervor, dass ein solcher Benchmark nicht nur die Wirksamkeit von Erklärungen, sondern auch deren Effizienz beurteilt.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Metode penjelasan post-hoc adalah kelas penting pendekatan yang membantu memahami rasional yang mendasarkan keputusan model terlatih. Tapi betapa berguna bagi pengguna akhir untuk menyelesaikan tugas tertentu? Dalam kertas penglihatan ini, kita berdebat kebutuhan benchmark untuk memudahkan evaluasi utilitas metode penjelasan post-hoc. Sebagai langkah pertama untuk tujuan ini, kita enumerasikan properti yang diinginkan bahwa benchmark seperti itu harus memiliki untuk tugas penyahpepijatan klasifikasi teks. Selain itu, kami menyatakan bahwa benchmark seperti itu memudahkan tidak hanya menilai efektivitas penjelasan tetapi juga efektivitas mereka.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>روش توضیح بعد از هوک یک کلاس مهم از طریق‌ها است که کمک می‌کنند به فهمیدن منطقی که بر اساس تصمیم یک مدل آموزش داده شده است. ولی چقدر برای یک کاربر پایان برای انجام کار دادن کار مفید هستند؟ در این کاغذ دیدگاه، ما بحث می‌کنیم که نیازی برای یک نقشه‌بندی برای آسانی ارزیابی استفاده از روش توضیح بعد هوک است. به عنوان اولین مرحله برای این پایان، ما ویژگی‌های خواسته‌ای را شماره می‌کنیم که چنین مرحله باید برای وظیفه‌ی تنظیم‌کنندگان متن را داشته باشد. علاوه بر این، ما تفصیل می‌کنیم که چنین نقشه‌ای نه تنها ارزیابی موثرت توضیح‌ها را تشکیل می‌دهد، بلکه موثرت آنها را هم تشکیل می‌دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>사후 해석 방법은 중요한 방법으로 훈련 모델 결정의 기본 원리를 이해하는데 도움이 된다.그러나 최종 사용자가 주어진 임무를 완성하는 데 얼마나 도움이 됩니까?이 소망 논문에서 우리는 사후 해석 방법의 효용에 대한 평가를 촉진하기 위한 기준이 필요하다고 생각한다.이 목표를 실현하는 첫 번째 단계로서, 우리는 이러한 기준 테스트가 텍스트 분류기를 디버깅할 때 갖춰야 할 이상적인 속성을 열거했다.또한 이러한 기준은 해석의 유효성을 평가하는 데 도움이 될 뿐만 아니라 그 효율을 평가하는 데도 도움이 된다고 강조한다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_af>Post-hoc verduidelingsmetodes is 'n belangrike klas van toegang wat help verstaan die rationale ondersteunde 'n opgelei model se besluit. Maar hoe nuttig is hulle vir 'n einde-gebruiker om 'n gegewe taak te volbring? In hierdie gesigte papier, ons argumenteer die behoefte vir 'n benchmark om evaluasies van die nuttigheid van post-hoc uitduidelingsmetodes te maak. As 'n eerste stap na hierdie einde, tel ons desimale eienskappe wat sodanige 'n benchmark moet besit vir die taak van ontfouting van teks klassifiseerders. In addition, we highlight that such a benchmark facilitates not only the effectiveness of explanations but also their efficiency.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>የፖስታዊ አካባቢ ትርጓሜዎች የተማረ የሞዴል ውሳኔን በመጠቀም የሚችሉትን የሚያስተውሉ የግልጹ ደረጃ ናቸው፡፡ ነገር ግን የተሰጠውን ስራ ለመፈጸም እንዴት ይጠቅማል? በዚህ የራእይ ሕትመት፣ የፖስታ-አካል የግልፅ ማረጃ ማሳየትን ለማግኘት የቅርጽ ማረፊያ ያስፈልጋል፡፡ ወደዚህ መጨረሻ የመጀመሪያ እርምጃዎች፣ እንደዚህ የቅርብ መክፈት የጽሑፍ ክፍተቶችን ለማሳሰል ስራ እንዲወስደው ያስፈልጋል፡፡ Additionally, we highlight that such a benchmark facilitates not only assessing the effectiveness of explanations but also their efficiency.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sw>Utawala wa ufafanuzi wa baada ya hoc ni aina muhimu ya namna ambazo zinasaidia kuelewa msingi wa uamuzi wa muundo ulioendeshwa. Lakini ni kiasi gani kinafaa kwa mtumiaji wa mwisho wa kutekeleza kazi hiyo? Katika karatasi hii ya maono, tunahoji haja ya bendera ili kusaidia tafsiri ya matumizi ya njia za maelezo baada ya hoc. As a first step to this end, we enumerate desirable properties that such a benchmark should possess for the task of debugging text classifiers.  Kwa nyongeza, tunaonyesha kuwa bendera hiyo inasaidia si tu kutathmini ufanisi wa maelezo bali pia ufanisi wao.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>Metodat e shpjegimit pas-hoc janë një klasë e rëndësishme metodash që ndihmojnë të kuptojnë arsyetimin bazuar në vendimin e një modeli të stërvitur. Por sa të dobishme janë ato për një përdorues përfundimtar për të kryer një detyrë të caktuar? In this vision paper, we argue the need for a benchmark to facilitate evaluations of the utility of post-hoc explanation methods.  Si një hap i parë për këtë qëllim, ne enumerojmë pronësitë e dëshirueshme që një normë e tillë duhet të ketë për detyrën e klasifikuesve të tekstit debugging. Përveç kësaj, ne theksojmë se një normë e tillë lehtëson jo vetëm vlerësimin e efektshmërisë së shpjegimeve por gjithashtu efektshmërinë e tyre.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Ýakyndan soňra düşündirim yöntemleri eğitilen bir nusganyň kararyny düşünmesine kömek eden möhüm bir nusgadyr. Emma bu zady berilen zady başarmak üçin soňky wužiwar üçin nähili faydaly? Bu görnöşim kagyzynda, geçmişi soňra düşündirim yöntemlerini çykarmak üçin bir benchmark gerekdigini tartışýarys. Bu soňunda ilkinji adım bolsa, şol bir benchmark üçin hat larynyň täblisasynda bolmaly hasaplanýarys. Ayrıca, bu şekilde düzeltmenin sadece a çıklamaların etkinliğini değerlendirmesini kolaylaştırdığını söylüyoruz.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_bn>পোস্ট-হোকের ব্যাখ্যা মাধ্যম হচ্ছে একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ক্লাস যা প্রশিক্ষিত মডেলের সিদ্ধান্তের ভিত্তিতে যুক কিন্তু তারা কিভাবে কাজ পূর্ণ করতে পারে শেষ ব্যবহারকারীর জন্য? এই দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি পত্রিকায়, আমরা বেনম্যার্কের প্রয়োজনীয় যুক্তি দিচ্ছি পোস্ট-হোক ব্যাখ্যা পদ্ধতির ব্যবহারের মাধ্ এই শেষ পর্যন্ত প্রথম পদক্ষেপ হিসেবে আমরা প্রয়োজনীয় বৈশিষ্ট্য হিসেবে হিসেব করি যে এই ধরনের বেনম্যার্ক টেক্সট বিভাগের এছাড়াও আমরা উল্লেখ করি যে এই ধরনের বেনম্যার্ক শুধুমাত্র ব্যাখ্যার কার্যক্রমের মূল্য দেয় না, বরং তাদের কার্যকর্মের</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Պետ-հոք բացատրության մեթոդները կարևոր մոտեցումների դասարան են, որոնք օգնում են հասկանալ վարժեցված մոդելի որոշումների հիմնական ռացիոնալը: Բայց ինչքա՞ն օգտակար են դրանք վերջնական օգտագործողների համար որոշակի խնդիր կատարելու համար: Այս տեսողական թղթի մեջ մենք պնդում ենք հարաբերական նպատակի կարիքը, որպեսզի հեշտացնենք հետ-հոք բացատրման մեթոդների օգտակարության գնահատումները: Առաջին քայլը այս նպատակին է, որ մենք ցույց ենք տալիս ցանկալի հատկությունները, որոնք պետք է ունենան այս հարաբերականը տեքստի դասակարգումների ձախողման խնդրի համար: Additionally, we highlight that such a benchmark facilitates not only assessing the effectiveness of explanations but also their efficiency.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Post hoc a çıqlama metodları təhsil edilmiş modelinin kararını anlamağa kömək edən möhkəm bir növ tərzidir. Lakin bu işi yerinə yetirmək üçün son istifadəçi üçün nə qədər fayda verirlər? Bu görünüş kağıdında, post-hoc a çıqlama metodlarının istifadəsini asanlaşdırmaq üçün benchmark ehtiyacını mübahisə edirik. Bu sonun ilk adımı kimi, bu benchmark mətn klasifikatçıları ayırılma işinə sahib olması üçün istəyən xüsusiyyətləri sayırıq. Əksinə, biz bu benchmark ancaq a çıq-aydınlıqların faydalanılığını değerləşdirmək üçün asanlaşdırırıq.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Posthočke metode objašnjenja su važna klasa pristupa koja pomaže razumjeti razlog pod odlukom obučenog model a. Ali koliko su korisni za krajnjeg korisnika za postizanje određenog zadatka? U ovom vizijskom papiru tvrdimo da je potrebna kritika za olakšanje procjene korisnosti posthočnih metoda objašnjenja. Kao prvi korak do ovog kraja, izračunamo željne vlasništvo koje bi takva kritika trebala posjedovati za zadatak klasifikatora za debugging teksta. Osim toga, naglašavamo da takva kritika olakšava ne samo procjenu učinkovitosti objašnjenja, nego i njihovu učinkovitost.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Post-hoc selgitusmeetodid on oluline klass lähenemisviise, mis aitavad mõista koolitatud mudeli otsuse aluseks olevat põhjendust. Kui kasulikud on need lõppkasutajale antud ülesande täitmisel? Käesolevas visiooni dokumendis väidame vajadust võrdlusaluse järele, mis hõlbustaks hindamist post hoc selgitusmeetodite kasulikkuse kohta. Esimese sammuna loetleme soovitavad omadused, mis sellisel võrdlusalusel peaks olema tekstiklassifitseerijate silumiseks. Lisaks rõhutame, et selline võrdlusalus ei hõlbusta mitte ainult selgituste tõhususe hindamist, vaid ka nende tõhususe hindamist.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ca>Els mètodes d'explicació post-hoc s ón una classe important d'enfocaments que ajuden a entendre la raó subjacente a la decisió d'un model entrenat. But how useful are they for an end-user towards accomplishing a given task?  En aquest paper de visió, argumentem la necessitat d'un punt de referència per facilitar les evaluacions de l'utilitat dels mètodes d'explicació post-hoc. Com a primer pas cap a aquest objectiu, enumeram les propietats desitjables que aquest punt de referència hauria de tenir per a la tasca de classificadors de text de depuració. A més, destaquem que aquest punt de referència facilita no només la valoració de l'eficacia de les explicacions, sinó també la seva eficiència.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Post-hoc selitysmenetelmät ovat tärkeä joukko lähestymistapoja, jotka auttavat ymmärtämään koulutetun mallin päätöksen taustalla olevia perusteita. Mutta kuinka hyödyllisiä ne ovat loppukäyttäjälle tietyn tehtävän suorittamisessa? Tässä visio-asiakirjassa väitämme, että tarvitaan vertailuarvo, joka helpottaa post-hoc -selitysmenetelmien hyödyllisyyden arviointia. Ensimmäisenä askeleena tässä tarkoituksessa luetellaan halutut ominaisuudet, jotka tällaisella vertailukohdalla pitäisi olla tekstiluokittelijoiden virheenkorjaukseen. Lisäksi korostamme, että tällainen vertailuarvo helpottaa selitysten tehokkuuden lisäksi myös niiden tehokkuuden arviointia.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_cs>Post-hoc vysvětlení metody jsou důležitou třídou přístupů, které pomáhají porozumět důvodu rozhodnutí trénovaného modelu. Ale jak užitečné jsou pro koncového uživatele při splnění daného úkolu? V tomto vizuálním článku argumentujeme potřebu referenčního měřítka pro usnadnění hodnocení užitečnosti post-hoc vysvětlovacích metod. Jako první krok k tomuto účelu vyjmenujeme žádoucí vlastnosti, které by měl mít takový benchmark pro úkol ladění klasifikátorů textu. Kromě toho zdůrazňujeme, že takový benchmark usnadňuje nejen hodnocení efektivity vysvětlení, ale také jejich efektivity.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_jv>Awakdhéwé éntuk apakno sing dikarepaké kelas kuwi nggawe gerakan luwih panelusuran politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Awakdhéwé éntuk nglanggar kuwi, kita Rasané nggawe bener nggawe bendhèké nggawe barang nggawe barang nggawe barang kelangan sistem sing tapi tho. Taning Ngerti tambah, awak dhéwé nglanggar kanggo ngerasakno iki dadi aturan kanggo nyeasahan kanggo ngerasakno perkaraan luwih nyong nggawe nguasakno</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Posthoc metode pojasnjevanja so pomemben razred pristopov, ki pomagajo razumeti utemeljitev odločitve usposobljenega modela. Toda kako koristni so za končnega uporabnika pri izpolnjevanju določene naloge? V tem vizijskem dokumentu zagovarjamo potrebo po referenčnem merilu za lažje ocenjevanje uporabnosti post-hoc metod pojasnjevanja. Kot prvi korak v ta namen naštejemo zaželene lastnosti, ki jih mora imeti taka referenčna vrednost za nalogo razhroščevanja besedilnih klasifikatorjev. Poleg tega poudarjamo, da takšna referenčna vrednost ne omogoča le ocenjevanja učinkovitosti pojasnil, temveč tudi njihove učinkovitosti.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Tsarin fassarar bayan-hoc, yana da wata jama'a na muhimu wa matsayi wanda yana taimakon su fahimta da rabon da ke ƙara karkacin wani misalin da aka tsare shi. To, yãya amfaninsu yake a lõkacin da aka hukunta al'amarin? Daga wannan takardan gani, Munã jãyayya da umakinci ga bangon aiki dõmin ya sauƙa ƙara ƙaddara wa amfani da shiryoyin ayukan bayan-hoc. Kayya da ƙẽtare na farko zuwa wannan ƙara, muna ƙidãya game da properties wanda za'a so, ba ya kamata ta iya mallakar wa aikin mai shiryarwa na matsayi. Ina ƙara, za mu ƙayyade, cewa wannan bangon zai iya amfani da su ba fãce idan an ƙaddara fassarar fassararsu, kuma amma da fassararsu.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>Post-hoc explanation methods are an important class of approaches that help understand the rationale underlying a trained model's decision. འོན་ཀྱང་། འདི་དག་ནི་མཇུག་གི་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་བྱ་འགུལ་ལ་རྒྱས་སྐྱོར་བ་ཅི་རེ་བ་སྤྱོད་པ་ཡིན་ནམ། ང་ཚོས་མཐོང་སྣང་གི་ཤོག་བུ་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་བརྗོད་མཁན་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལུགས་རྗེས་སུ་འཇུག་གམ། མཇུག་མམ་འདི་ལ་ཐོག་མའི་གོ་རིམ་དང་པོ་ཞིག་གིས་ཉེན་ཁ་ཡོད་པའི་ངོ་བོར་ཆོག འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་མཚོན་ནི་བཟོ་མཁན་ཞིག་གིས་གསལ་བཤད་འགྲེལ་བ་དེ་ལས་ཁོང་ཚོའི་ལས་སྒྲུབ་ཐང་མིན་པར་མཐུན</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>שיטות ההסבר לאחר הופעות הן מעמד חשוב של גישות שעוזרות להבין את ההגיון שביסוד ההחלטה של מודל מאומן. אבל כמה הם שימושיים למשתמש סופי כדי להשלים משימה מסוימת? בעיתון החזון הזה, אנחנו מתווכחים על הצורך לנקודת רמז כדי להקל את הערכות של שימוש שיטות הסבר לאחר ההוקו. As a first step to this end, we enumerate desirable properties that such a benchmark should possess for the task of debugging text classifiers.  בנוסף, אנו מזכירים כי נקודת רמז כזו מקדימה לא רק להעריך את היעילות של ההסברים, אלא גם את היעילות שלהם.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>