<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.gwc">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-02-07">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 11th Global Wordnet Conference</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Piek</first><last>Vossen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Christiane</first><last>Fellbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>Global Wordnet Association</publisher>
      <address>University of South Africa (UNISA)</address>
      <month>January</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="edc87ddd">2021.gwc-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="392ac3ba">2021.gwc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>gwc-2021-global</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>On Universal Colexifications</title>
      <author><first>Hongchang</first><last>Bao</last></author>
      <author><first>Bradley</first><last>Hauer</last></author>
      <author><first>Grzegorz</first><last>Kondrak</last></author>
      <pages>1–7</pages>
      <abstract>Colexification occurs when two distinct concepts are lexified by the same word. The term covers both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polysemy">polysemy</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homonym">homonymy</a>. We posit and investigate the hypothesis that no pair of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concepts</a> are colexified in every language. We test our hypothesis by analyzing colexification data from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BabelNet">BabelNet</a>, Open Multilingual WordNet, and CLICS. The results show that our hypothesis is supported by over 99.9 % of colexified concept pairs in these three <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_resource">lexical resources</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="e0a4555c">2021.gwc-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>bao-etal-2021-universal</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Practical Approach on Implementation of WordNets for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_South_Africa">South African Languages</a><fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>ets for <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>outh <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>frican Languages</title>
      <author><first>Tshephisho Joseph</first><last>Sefara</last></author>
      <author><first>Tumisho Billson</first><last>Mokgonyane</last></author>
      <author><first>Vukosi</first><last>Marivate</last></author>
      <pages>20–25</pages>
      <abstract>This paper proposes the implementation of WordNets for five South African languages, namely, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northern_Sotho_language">Sepedi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tswana_language">Setswana</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tshivenda_language">Tshivenda</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zulu_language">isiZulu</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xhosa_language">isiXhosa</a> to be added to open multilingual WordNets (OMW) on natural language toolkit (NLTK). The African WordNets are converted from Princeton WordNet (PWN) 2.0 to 3.0 to match the synsets in PWN 3.0. After conversion, there were 7157, 11972, 1288, 6380, and 9460 lemmas for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northern_Sotho_language">Sepedi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tswana_language">Setswana</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tshivenda_language">Tshivenda</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zulu_language">isiZulu</a> and isiX- hosa respectively. Setswana, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xhosa_language">isiXhosa</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northern_Sotho_language">Sepedi</a> contains more lemmas compared to 8 languages in OMW and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zulu_language">isiZulu</a> contains more lemmas compared to 7 languages in OMW. A library has been published for continuous development of African WordNets in OMW using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NLTK">NLTK</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="4239dc71">2021.gwc-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>sefara-etal-2021-practical</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/josephsefara/africanwordnet" additional="false">josephsefara/africanwordnet</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Ask2Transformers : Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>sk2<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ransformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title>
      <author><first>Oscar</first><last>Sainz</last></author>
      <author><first>German</first><last>Rigau</last></author>
      <pages>44–52</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we present a system that exploits different pre-trained Language Models for assigning domain labels to WordNet synsets without any kind of supervision. Furthermore, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is not restricted to use a particular set of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name">domain labels</a>. We exploit the knowledge encoded within different off-the-shelf pre-trained Language Models and task formulations to infer the domain label of a particular WordNet definition. The proposed zero-shot system achieves a new state-of-the-art on the English dataset used in the evaluation.</abstract>
      <url hash="d8affe52">2021.gwc-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>sainz-rigau-2021-ask2transformers</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Ask2Transformers: rotulagem de domínio zero-shot com modelos de linguagem pré-treinados</title_pt>
      <title_ar>Ask2Transformers: وضع العلامات على المجال بدون طلقة باستخدام نماذج اللغة المحددة مسبقًا</title_ar>
      <title_es>Ask2Transformers: etiquetado de dominios Zero-Shot con modelos de lenguaje preentrenados</title_es>
      <title_hi>Ask2Transformers: पूर्व प्रशिक्षित भाषा मॉडल के साथ शून्य-शॉट डोमेन लेबलिंग</title_hi>
      <title_ja>Ask 2 Transformers:事前に訓練された言語モデルを使用したゼロショットドメインのラベル付け</title_ja>
      <title_zh>Ask2Transformers:用预训语零次域</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Ask2Transformers: Lipéadú Fearainn Zero-Shot le Múnlaí Teanga Réamhthraenáilte</title_ga>
      <title_hu>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain címkézés előzetes nyelvi modellekkel</title_hu>
      <title_el>Επισήμανση τομέα μηδενικού πυροβολισμού με προκαθορισμένα μοντέλα γλώσσας</title_el>
      <title_kk>Ask2Transformers: Zero- Shot домен жарлығы Pretrained Language Models</title_kk>
      <title_ka>Ask2Transformers: Zero- Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_ka>
      <title_it>Ask2Transformers: Etichettatura del dominio Zero-Shot con modelli linguistici pretrained</title_it>
      <title_lt>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain label with Pretrained Language Models</title_mk>
      <title_ml>ആസ്ക്2Transformers: Zero- Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_ms>
      <title_pl>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain etykietowanie z pretrenowanymi modelami językowymi</title_pl>
      <title_no>Ask2Transformers: Zero- Shot Domenemerkelapp med Pretrained Language Models</title_no>
      <title_mt>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_mt>
      <title_si>Ask2Transferers: Zero- Shot Domain Labeling with Precrained language Models</title_si>
      <title_mn>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_mn>
      <title_ro>Ask2Transformers: Etichetarea domeniului Zero-Shot cu modele lingvistice pretrained</title_ro>
      <title_so>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_so>
      <title_sr>Ask2Transformers: označavanje nulo-pucnjave domena sa preliječenim jezičkim modelima</title_sr>
      <title_ur>Ask2Transformers: Zero- Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_ur>
      <title_sv>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain märkning med Pretrained Language Models</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Ask2Transformers: Zero- Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_ta>
      <title_vi>Ask2transformer: nhãn phông chữ Zero-Shot với Chế độ Ngôn ngữ sẵn sàng</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_uz>
      <title_hr>Ask2Transformers: označavanje nulo-pucnjave domena s modelima preliječenih jezika</title_hr>
      <title_da>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domæne mærkning med Pretrained Language Models</title_da>
      <title_bg>Трансформатори: етикетиране на домейн с предварително тренирани езикови модели</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labeling met vooraf getrainde taalmodellen</title_nl>
      <title_de>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain Labeling mit vortrainierten Sprachmodellen</title_de>
      <title_fa>تغییردهنده‌های Ask2: نقاشی دامین صفر- شلیک با مدل زبان پرتارین</title_fa>
      <title_id>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain Label dengan Model Bahasa Terlatih</title_id>
      <title_sw>Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_sw>
      <title_ko>Ask2Transformers: 미리 훈련된 언어 모델을 사용한 제로 포역 표기</title_ko>
      <title_sq>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain Labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_sq>
      <title_am>Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_am>
      <title_tr>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Açmak Dil Modelleri ile etiketlenen Açmak</title_tr>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_hy>Transforme: Zer- shot վայր Labeling</title_hy>
      <title_az>Ask2Transformers: Pretrained Dil Modelləri ilə Zero-Shot Domain etiketi</title_az>
      <title_bn>Ask2TransFormers: Zero- Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language mode</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Ask2Transformers: označavanje nulo-pucnjave domena sa modelima preliječenih jezika</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Ask2Transformers: Etiquetat de domini zero amb models de llenguatge pretrained</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain -merkinnät esikoulutetuilla kielimalleilla</title_fi>
      <title_cs>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labeling s předtrénovanými jazykovými modely</title_cs>
      <title_et>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot domeeni märgistamine eeltreenitud keelemudelitega</title_et>
      <title_jv>Ask2Transformer: nulo-shot domain label with Prescared Language model</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Ask2Transformers: označevanje domene Zero-Shot s predtreniranimi jezikovnimi modeli</title_sk>
      <title_ha>Transformers: Zero- shot Domen labels with PreTrafied language Models</title_ha>
      <title_he>Ask2Transformers: Zero- Shot Domain Label with Pretrained Language Models</title_he>
      <title_bo>Ask2Transformers: Zero-Shot Domain labelling with Pretrained Language Models</title_bo>
      <abstract_pt>Neste artigo apresentamos um sistema que explora diferentes Modelos de Linguagem pré-treinados para atribuir rótulos de domínio a synsets WordNet sem qualquer tipo de supervisão. Além disso, o sistema não está restrito a usar um conjunto específico de rótulos de domínio. Exploramos o conhecimento codificado em diferentes modelos de linguagem pré-treinados prontos para uso e formulações de tarefas para inferir o rótulo de domínio de uma definição específica do WordNet. O sistema zero-shot proposto atinge um novo estado da arte no conjunto de dados em inglês usado na avaliação.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>في هذا البحث نقدم نظامًا يستغل نماذج لغوية مختلفة مُدربة مسبقًا لتعيين تسميات المجال لمزامنة WordNet دون أي نوع من الإشراف. علاوة على ذلك ، لا يقتصر النظام على استخدام مجموعة معينة من تسميات المجال. نحن نستغل المعرفة المشفرة في نماذج لغوية وصياغات مهام مختلفة جاهزة للاستخدام في الأسواق لاستنتاج تسمية المجال لتعريف WordNet معين. يحقق نظام اللقطة الصفرية المقترح أحدث ما توصلت إليه التقنية في مجموعة البيانات الإنجليزية المستخدمة في التقييم.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>En este artículo presentamos un sistema que aprovecha diferentes modelos de lenguaje previamente entrenados para asignar etiquetas de dominio a synsets de WordNet sin ningún tipo de supervisión. Además, el sistema no está restringido al uso de un conjunto particular de etiquetas de dominio. Aprovechamos el conocimiento codificado en diferentes modelos lingüísticos preentrenados y formulaciones de tareas disponibles para inferir la etiqueta de dominio de una definición de WordNet en particular. El sistema de tiro cero propuesto logra un nuevo estado de la técnica en el conjunto de datos en inglés utilizado en la evaluación.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、あらかじめ訓練されたさまざまな言語モデルを利用して、何らかの監督なしにWordNetシンセットにドメインラベルを割り当てるシステムを提示する。さらに、システムは、特定のセットのドメインラベルを使用することに制限されない。私たちは、さまざまな既製の事前トレーニングされた言語モデルとタスクの定式化内でエンコードされた知識を活用して、特定のWordNet定義のドメインラベルを推測します。提案されたゼロショットシステムは、評価に使用された英語のデータセットで最新のものを実現します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>इस पेपर में हम एक ऐसी प्रणाली प्रस्तुत करते हैं जो किसी भी प्रकार के पर्यवेक्षण के बिना वर्डनेट सिंसेट को डोमेन लेबल असाइन करने के लिए विभिन्न पूर्व-प्रशिक्षित भाषा मॉडल का शोषण करती है। इसके अलावा, सिस्टम डोमेन लेबल के किसी विशेष सेट का उपयोग करने के लिए प्रतिबंधित नहीं है। हम किसी विशेष WordNet परिभाषा के डोमेन लेबल का अनुमान लगाने के लिए विभिन्न ऑफ-द-शेल्फ पूर्व-प्रशिक्षित भाषा मॉडल और कार्य योगों के भीतर एन्कोडेड ज्ञान का शोषण करते हैं। प्रस्तावित शून्य-शॉट प्रणाली मूल्यांकन में उपयोग किए जाने वाले अंग्रेजी डेटासेट पर एक नया अत्याधुनिक प्राप्त करती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>于本文中,立一系统,当统用预练言语模样,于无监督者,将域标配WordNet合为集。 此外统不限用一组特定域标签。 因异成之先训言语、任公式编码之知以推特定WordNet义之域。 所建零射系统于评估英文数据集上成最先进之法。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Sa pháipéar seo cuirimid i láthair córas a bhaineann leas as Múnlaí Teanga réamh-oilte éagsúla chun lipéid fearainn a shannadh do shinsets WordNet gan aon mhaoirseacht. Ina theannta sin, níl srian ar an gcóras sraith ar leith de lipéid fearainn a úsáid. Bainimid leas as an eolas atá ionchódaithe laistigh de Mhúnlaí Teanga réamhoilte éagsúla lasmuigh den tseilf agus foirmlithe tascanna le tátal a bhaint as lipéad fearainn de shainmhíniú WordNet ar leith. Baineann an córas lámhaigh nialasach atá beartaithe amach staid nua den scoth ar an tacar sonraí Béarla a úsáidtear sa mheastóireacht.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Ebben a tanulmányban egy olyan rendszert mutatunk be, amely különböző előre képzett nyelvi modelleket használ ki a WordNet szinkronkészletekhez tartománycímkék bármilyen felügyelet nélkül történő hozzárendelésére. Ezenkívül a rendszer nem korlátozódik egy adott domain címkék használatára. Kihasználjuk a különböző, előre képzett nyelvi modellekben és feladatformációkban kódolt ismereteket, hogy következtessük egy adott WordNet definíció domain címkéjét. A javasolt nulla lövéses rendszer az értékelés során használt angol adatkészleten új korszerűséget ér el.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Σε αυτή την εργασία παρουσιάζουμε ένα σύστημα που εκμεταλλεύεται διαφορετικά προ-εκπαιδευμένα μοντέλα γλώσσας για την ανάθεση ετικετών τομέων σε σύνσετ χωρίς οποιαδήποτε επίβλεψη. Επιπλέον, το σύστημα δεν περιορίζεται στη χρήση ενός συγκεκριμένου συνόλου ετικετών τομέα. Εκμεταλλευόμαστε τις γνώσεις που κωδικοποιούνται μέσα σε διαφορετικά έτοιμα προσχεδιασμένα γλωσσικά μοντέλα και διατυπώσεις εργασιών για να συμπεράνουμε την ετικέτα τομέα ενός συγκεκριμένου ορισμού. Το προτεινόμενο σύστημα μηδενικού πυροβολισμού επιτυγχάνει μια νέα κατάσταση τεχνολογίας στο αγγλικό σύνολο δεδομένων που χρησιμοποιήθηκε στην αξιολόγηση.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დომენტში ჩვენ ჩვენ აჩვენებთ სისტემა, რომელიც გამოყენებს განსხვავებული წარმოადგენული ენის მოდელები WordNet სინქესტებში, რომელიც არაფერი ნახვა ნახვა მოდელების შესაძლებ დამატებით, სისტემა არ არის დასაზღვრებულია დემომინის ნიშანების განსაზღვრებით. ჩვენ გამოვიყენებთ განსხვავებული WordNet განსაზღვრების დიომენტის მოდელები და დავაკეთებული ფორმულები, რომლებიც განსხვავებული სიტყვების დიომენტის ლებლის ჩატვირთვას. პროგრამების ნულ სტატის სისტემა ახალი სტატის შესახებ ინგლისური მონაცემების შესახებ გამოყენებული მონაცემების შესახებ.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>In questo articolo presentiamo un sistema che sfrutta diversi modelli linguistici pre-addestrati per assegnare etichette di dominio ai sinonimi WordNet senza alcun tipo di supervisione. Inoltre, il sistema non è limitato all'utilizzo di un particolare set di etichette di dominio. Sfruttamo le conoscenze codificate all'interno di diversi modelli linguistici pre-addestrati e formulazioni di compiti per dedurre l'etichetta di dominio di una particolare definizione di WordNet. Il sistema zero-shot proposto raggiunge un nuovo stato dell'arte sul set di dati inglese utilizzato nella valutazione.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente mes pristatome sistemą, kuri naudoja skirtingus iš anksto parengtus kalbos modelius, skirtus paskirti domeno etiketes WordNet sintetiniams įrenginiams be jokios priežiūros. Be to, sistema nėra apribota tam tikru domeno etiketės rinkiniu. Naudojame žinias, koduotas įvairiuose iš anksto parengtuose kalbos modeliuose ir užduočių formuluotėse, kad būtų galima nustatyti tam tikros WordNet apibrėžties domeno etiketę. Siūloma nulinės nuotraukos sistema užtikrina naujausią pažangą vertinant anglų duomenų rinkinį.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағазда біз WordNet қадамдастыру үшін әр түрлі алдын- оқылған тіл үлгілерін қолдану жүйесін келтіреміз. Қосымша, жүйе домен жарлықтарын қолдану үшін шектелмеген. Біз WordNet анықтамасының доменнің белгісін келтіру үшін әртүрлі қоршау үшін қолданылған мәліметтерді қолданып қолданамыз. Нөл сүрту жүйесі бағалау үшін қолданылатын ағылшын деректер жиынының жаңа күйін жеткізеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Во оваа хартија претставуваме систем кој експлоатира различни предобучени јазични модели за додавање на ознаки на домени на WordNet синсети без никаков вид на надзор. Furthermore, the system is not restricted to use a particular set of domain labels.  Го искористуваме знаењето кодирано во различни предобучени јазички модели и формулации за задачи, надвор од полицата, за да се заклучи доменската етикета на одредена WordNet дефиниција. Предложениот систем со нула снимка постигнува нова најнова технологија на англискиот компјутер на податоци што се користи во проценката.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Dalam kertas ini kami memperkenalkan sistem yang mengeksploitasi Model Bahasa yang berlainan yang dilatih-dilatih untuk menyerahkan label domain kepada penyegerakan WordNet tanpa sebarang jenis pengawasan. Lagipun, sistem tidak diharamkan untuk menggunakan set tertentu label domain. Kami mengeksploitasi pengetahuan terkod dalam Model Bahasa yang dilatih-dilatih luar rak yang berbeza dan formulasi tugas untuk menyimpulkan label domain bagi definisi WordNet tertentu. Sistem tembakan sifar yang diusulkan mencapai keadaan baru pada set data Inggeris yang digunakan dalam penilaian.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ വ്യത്യസ്ത പരിശീലന ഭാഷ മോഡലുകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന ഒരു സിസ്റ്റം കാണിക്കുന്നു. വാര്‍ഡ് നെറ്റ് സിനിസ്റ്റുകളില്‍ വ കൂടാതെ, ഒരു സിസ്റ്റം ഡൊമെയിന്‍ ലേബലുകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കാന്‍ സിസ്റ്റം പരിധിയില്ല. നമ്മള്‍ വ്യത്യസ്തമായ വാര്‍ഡ്നെറ്റിന്റെ വിശദീകരണത്തിന്റെ ഡൊമെയിന്‍ ലേബ്ലേറ്റിന്റെ നിര്‍ണ്ണയത്തില്‍ വ്യത്യസ്തമായ വിവരങ്ങള്‍  പ്രൊദ്ദേശിക്കപ്പെട്ട പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായ വെടിവെക്കുന്ന സിസ്റ്റം വിന്യാസത്തില്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് ഡാ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_pl>W artykule przedstawiamy system, który wykorzystuje różne wstępnie przeszkolone modele językowe do przypisywania etykiet domen do zestawów WordNet bez jakiegokolwiek nadzoru. Ponadto system nie jest ograniczony do używania określonego zestawu etykiet domen. Wykorzystujemy wiedzę zakodowaną w różnych gotowych wstępnie przeszkolonych modelach językowych i formułach zadań, aby wywnioskować etykietę domeny określonej definicji WordNet. Proponowany system zero-shot osiąga nowy state-of-the-art na angielskim zbiorze danych użytym w ocenie.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mt>F’dan id-dokument nippreżentaw sistema li tisfrutta mudelli lingwistiċi mħarrġa minn qabel differenti għall-assenjazzjoni ta’ tikketti tad-dominju lis-sinsetts WordNet mingħajr kwalunkwe tip ta’ superviżjoni. Barra minn hekk, is-sistema mhijiex ristretta biex tuża sett partikolari ta’ tikketti tad-dominju. Aħna nesfruttaw l-għarfien ikkodifikat fi ħdan mudelli lingwistiċi mħarrġa minn qabel li mhumiex fuq l-ixkaffa u formulazzjonijiet ta’ kompiti differenti biex ininferu t-tikketta tad-dominju ta’ definizzjoni WordNet partikolari. Is-sistema proposta b’zero shot tikseb avvanz ġdid dwar is-sett tad-dejta Ingliż użat fl-evalwazzjoni.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаасан дээр бид WordNet-ийн шинжлэх ухааны хэл загварыг ашиглах системийг ашиглаж байна. Түүнчлэн систем тодорхой домены жагсаалтыг ашиглахын тулд хязгаарлагддаггүй. Бид WordNet тодорхой тодорхойлолтын тодорхойлолтын тодорхойлолтын тулд өөр хэл загвар болон ажлын тодорхойлолтуудыг ашигладаг. Нэг шалгалтын систем нь дүгнэлт дээр хэрэглэгдсэн Англи өгөгдлийн сангийн шинэ урлагийн хувьд хүргэж чадна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>I denne papiret viser vi eit systemet som ekspluaterer ulike før- trengte språk- modeller for å tilordna domenemerkelapper til WordNet- synsett utan nokon type overvaking. I tillegg er systemet ikkje begrenset for å bruka eit spesielt set domenemerkelapp. Vi ekspluaterer kunnskaden koda i ulike fråskalf før- trenga språk- modeller og oppgåveformasjonar for å gjere domenemerket til eit spesielt WordNet- definisjon. Den foreslåde nullsatte systemet oppnår eit nytt kunsttilstand på datasettet engelsk som vert brukt i evalueringa.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>În această lucrare prezentăm un sistem care exploatează diferite modele lingvistice pre-instruite pentru atribuirea etichetelor de domeniu Synseturilor WordNet fără nici un fel de supraveghere. În plus, sistemul nu este limitat la utilizarea unui anumit set de etichete de domenii. Exploatăm cunoștințele codificate în cadrul diferitelor modele lingvistice pre-instruite și formulări de sarcini pentru a deduce eticheta domeniului unei anumite definiții WordNet. Sistemul zero-shot propus realizează o nouă tehnologie de ultimă oră în ceea ce privește setul de date în limba engleză utilizat în evaluare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>මේ පැත්තේ අපි පද්ධතියක් ප්‍රවේශ කරනවා වෙනස් ප්‍රවේශ කරපු භාෂාවක් මොඩේමින් ලේබිල් විදිහට WordNet සංවේශනය නොවි ඉතින්, පද්ධතිය ප්‍රතිශේෂයක් ඩොමේන් ලේබල් සැටියක් භාවිත කරන්න සීමාවක් නැහැ. අපි වෙනස් වෙනස් විශේෂ භාෂාව ප්‍රධානය කරපු භාෂාව මොඩේල්ස් වලින් විශේෂ විශේෂාවේ ඩොමේන් ලේබල් වලින් ප්‍ර ඉංග්‍රීසි දත්ත සූද්ධානයේ අලුත් ස්ථානයක් ලැබෙනවා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalkan waxaan ku soo bandhignaa nidaam kala duwan oo lagu bartay afka hore, si aan looga dhigno calaamadaha internetka looga dhigo synetiyada WordNet oo aan loola jeedin. Sidoo kale nidaamka ma xadeyn in lagu isticmaalo alaab gaar ah. Waxaynu isticmaalnay aqoonta ku qoran qaababka afka hore ee lagu baray iyo qaababka shaqada si aan ugu dhicin calaamada internetka oo gaar ah qorniinka WordNet. nidaamka la soo jeeday zero-ganacsi wuxuu gaadhaa xaalad cusub oo ku saabsan kaartaynta macluumaadka ingiriisiga.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>U ovom papiru predstavljamo sistem koji iskorištava različite predobučene jezičke modele za dodavanje etiketa domena sinkronizaciji WordNet a bez ikakvog nadzora. Osim toga, sistem nije ograničen za upotrebu određenog set a etiketa domena. Koristimo znanje kodirano unutar različitih izvan police predobučenih jezičkih modela i formulacija zadataka kako bi zaradili etiketu domena određene definicije WordNet a. Predloženi sistem za nulu pucnjavu postiže novo stanje umjetnosti na engleskom setu podataka koji se koristi u procjeni.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தில் எந்த வகையான கண்காணிப்பு இல்லாமல் களம் சிட்டைகளை ஒதுக்குவதற்கு வேறு முன் பயிற்சி மொழி மாதிரிகளை பயன்படுத்து அதற்கும், குறிப்பிட்ட குறிப்பிட்ட களம் சிட்டைகளை பயன்படுத்த அமைப்பு கட்டமைக்கப்படவில்லை. நாங்கள் வேறு வித்தியாசமான அறிவு குறியீட்டிட்ட அறிவிப்பை பயன்படுத்துகிறோம் முன் பயிற்சி மொழி மாதிரி மற்றும் பணி வடிவமைப்புகள பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட பூஜ்ஜியம் சுட்டு அமைப்பு மதிப்பில் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட ஆங்கிலத்தின் தகவல் அமைப்பில் புதிய நில</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم اس کاغذ میں ایک سیسٹم پیش آموزش کی زبان موڈل کے مطابق مختلف طریقے سے استعمال کرتے ہیں جو WordNet سینسٹ کو کسی طرح کی نظارت کے بغیر ڈومین لیبل ڈیجی کرتا ہے۔ اور اس کے علاوہ، سیسٹم ڈومین لیبل کے ایک خاص مجموعہ سے استعمال کرنے کے لئے محدود نہیں ہے. ہم اس علم کو مختلف فائدہ کے شالف سے پہلے تدریس کی زبان مدلس اور تابع فرمول کے ذریعہ مطابق ایک ویرڈنیٹ کی تعریف کے دامین لیبل کے ذریعہ دکھانے کے لئے استعمال کرتے ہیں. پیشنهاد صفر-شٹ سیسٹم نے انگلیسی ڈیٹ سٹ پر ایک نئی حالت-آرت پہنچائی ہے جو ارزیابی میں استعمال کیا گیا ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_sv>I denna uppsats presenterar vi ett system som utnyttjar olika förklädda språkmodeller för att tilldela domänetiketter till WordNet-synuppsättningar utan någon form av övervakning. Dessutom är systemet inte begränsat till att använda en viss uppsättning domänetiketter. Vi utnyttjar kunskapen kodad inom olika färdiga språkmodeller och uppgiftsformler för att härleda domänmärkningen för en viss WordNet-definition. Det föreslagna nollskottssystemet uppnår en ny toppmodern nivå på den engelska datamängd som använts i utvärderingen.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_vi>Trong tờ giấy này chúng tôi giới thiệu một hệ thống dùng những mô- đun ngôn ngữ đã được đào tạo khác nhau để bố trí nhãn miền cho các cấu hình WordNet mà không cần bất cứ sự giám sát nào. Hơn nữa, hệ thống không bị hạn chế để dùng một loạt các nhãn miền đặc biệt. Chúng tôi tận dụng những kiến thức được mã hóa trong những mô- đun ngôn ngữ được đào tạo sẵn, và các công thức nhiệm vụ khác nhau để ám chỉ hiệu miền của một định nghĩa riêng WordNet. Hệ thống "bắn không" đã được đề nghị đạt được bước tiến mới trên bộ dữ liệu Anh sử dụng trong phần đánh giá.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Bu hujjatda, biz qoʻllanmagan boshqa taʼminlovchi tillar modellarini WordNet synthesizlarga qoʻllash uchun domen yorliqlarini qoʻllash uchun ishlatiladigan tizimni koʻrsatimiz. Koʻrsatilgan, tizim foydalanish uchun maxsus foydalanuvchi boʻlmaydi. We exploit the knowledge encoded within different off-the-shelf pre-trained Language Models and task formulations to infer the domain label of a particular WordNet definition.  Taʼrifi qilingan ingliz maʼlumotlar sahifasi yangi holatni amalga oshadi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_hr>U ovom papiru predstavljamo sustav koji koristi različite predobučene jezičke modele za dodavanje etiketa domena sinkronizaciji WordNet a bez ikakvog nadzora. Osim toga, sistem nije ograničen za upotrebu određenog set a etiketa domena. Koristimo znanje kodirano unutar različitih izvan police predobučenih jezičkih modela i formulacija zadatka kako bi se uvodili etiketu domena određene definicije WordNet a. Predloženi sustav nula pucnjave postiže novo stanje umjetnosti na engleskom setu podataka koji se koristi u procjeni.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>I denne artikel præsenterer vi et system, der udnytter forskellige forududdannede sprogmodeller til at tildele domænetiketter til WordNet Synsets uden nogen form for overvågning. Desuden er systemet ikke begrænset til at bruge et bestemt sæt domænetegnelser. Vi udnytter den viden, der er kodet inden for forskellige færdiguddannede sprogmodeller og opgaveformuleringer til at udlede domænetypen for en bestemt WordNet-definition. Det foreslåede nulskudssystem opnår et nyt state-of-the-art på det engelske datasæt, der anvendes i evalueringen.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>В настоящата статия представяме система, която експлоатира различни предварително обучени езикови модели за присвояване на етикети на домейни на синсети без никакъв вид надзор. Освен това системата не е ограничена да използва конкретен набор от етикети на домейн. Ние използваме знанията, кодирани в различни предварително обучени езикови модели и формулировки на задачи, за да извлечем етикета на домейна на определена дефиниция. Предложената система за нулев изстрел постига ново състояние на изкуството на английския набор от данни, използван при оценката.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>In dit artikel presenteren we een systeem dat gebruik maakt van verschillende vooraf getrainde Taalmodellen voor het toewijzen van domeinlabels aan WordNet synsets zonder enige vorm van toezicht. Bovendien is het systeem niet beperkt tot het gebruik van een bepaalde set domeinlabels. We benutten de kennis die is gecodeerd binnen verschillende standaard voorgetrainde taalmodellen en taakformuleringen om het domeinlabel van een bepaalde WordNet definitie af te leiden. Het voorgestelde zero-shot systeem bereikt een nieuwe state-of-the-art op de Engelse dataset die bij de evaluatie wordt gebruikt.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Dalam kertas ini kami mempersembahkan sistem yang mengeksploitasi Model Bahasa yang berbeda pra-terlatih untuk menyerahkan label domain ke Sinset WordNet tanpa jenis pengawasan apapun. Selain itu, sistem tidak terbatas untuk menggunakan set tertentu label domain. We exploit the knowledge encoded within different off-the-shelf pre-trained Language Models and task formulations to infer the domain label of a particular WordNet definition.  Sistem zero-shot yang diusulkan mencapai state-of-the-art baru pada set data Inggris yang digunakan dalam evaluasi.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>در این کاغذ یک سیستم را نشان می دهیم که مدل های پیش آموزش زبانی مختلف را برای تهیه کردن نقاشی دامنه به سنزت WordNet بدون هیچ نوع بررسی استفاده می کند. علاوه بر این، سیستم برای استفاده از مجموعه مخصوص برچسب‌های دومین محدود نیست. ما از دانش‌هایی که در مدل‌های پیش آموزش زبان و فرمول‌های وظیفه‌ای متفاوت شده‌اند، کودک شده‌اند، استفاده می‌کنیم تا نقشه‌های ویژه‌ی تعریف WordNet خاصی را وارد کند. سیستم صفر شلیک پیشنهاد یک وضعیت جدید هنری در مجموعه داده های انگلیسی که در ارزیابی استفاده می‌شود رسیده می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Katika karatasi hii tunaweka mfumo unaotumia Modeli tofauti za Kilugha zilizofundishwa kabla ya kutoa mabango ya domain kwa syntazamo la WordNet bila kufuatilia aina yoyote. Zaidi ya hayo, mfumo haujazuiwa kutumia seti maalum za nyumbani. Tunatumia maarifa yaliyoandikwa ndani ya maeneo mbalimbali ya mifumo ya lugha na miundo mbinu ya kazi ili kuipunguza alama ya ndani ya ufafanuzi maalum wa WordNet. Mfumo huu unapendekezwa kutopigwa risasi sifuri unaweza kupata hali mpya ya sanaa kwenye seti ya takwimu za Kiingereza inayotumiwa katika uchunguzi huo.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_de>In diesem Beitrag stellen wir ein System vor, das verschiedene vortrainierte Sprachmodelle nutzt, um WordNet-Synsets Domänenlabels ohne jegliche Aufsicht zuzuweisen. Darüber hinaus ist das System nicht auf die Verwendung bestimmter Domain-Labels beschränkt. Wir nutzen das Wissen, das in verschiedenen vortrainierten Sprachmodellen und Aufgabenformulierungen codiert ist, um das Domänenlabel einer bestimmten WordNet-Definition abzuleiten. Das vorgeschlagene Zero-Shot-System erreicht einen neuen Stand der Technik auf dem bei der Auswertung verwendeten englischen Datensatz.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyzda başga bir sistemi WordNet'e sözleşmeleri beýleki öňünden öňünden eğitilen dil nusgalaryny ulanýan. Munuň üçin sistemi belli etiketlerden ullanmak üçin yada şartlanmaýar. Bir WordNet tanımlamasının domena etiketini a şmak için farklı şekilde kodlanmış bilimleri kullanırız. Nusgala sistemasy çykyşda ullanýan iňlis sanatynyň täze bir möhümmetini ýetip biler.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>In hierdie papier vertoon ons 'n stelsel wat uitbrei verskillende voorsoekte Taal Modelle vir toewying van domein etikette na WordNet sinkronisasies sonder enige soort van supervisie. Verder is die stelsel nie beperk om 'n bepaalde stel van domein etikette te gebruik nie. Ons gebruik die kennis gekodeer binne verskillende af-die-shelf voor-onderwerp Taal Modelle en taak formulasies om die domein etiket van 'n spesifieke WordNet definisie te infeer. Die voorgestelde nulskoot stelsel bereik 'n nuwe staat van die kuns op die Engelske datastel wat in die evaluasie gebruik word.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_ko>본고에서 우리는 이 시스템이 서로 다른 예비 훈련 언어 모델을 이용하여WordNet 문법 집합에 역 라벨을 분배하고 어떠한 감독도 필요 없다는 시스템을 제시했다.또한 특정 도메인 레이블 세트를 사용하는 것에 제한이 없습니다.우리는 기존의 미리 훈련된 언어 모델과 작업 공식에서 인코딩된 지식을 이용하여 특정한WordNet이 정의한 필드 라벨을 추정합니다.제안된 영포 시스템은 평가에 사용된 영어 데이터 집합에서 새로운 최첨단 수준을 실현했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sq>In this paper we present a system that exploits different pre-trained Language Models for assigning domain labels to WordNet synsets without any kind of supervision.  Përveç kësaj, sistemi nuk është i kufizuar për të përdorur një sërë të veçantë etiketash domini. Ne shfrytëzojmë njohuritë e koduara brenda modeleve të ndryshme gjuhësh të trajnuara jashtë raftit dhe formulimeve të detyrave për të përfshirë etiketën e domenit të një përcaktimi të veçantë WordNet. Sistemi i propozuar zero-shot arrin një state-of-the-art të ri në kompletin e të dhënave angleze të përdorur në vlerësim.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>In this paper we present a system that exploits different pre-trained Language Models for assigning domain labels to WordNet synsets without any kind of supervision.  ከዚህም በላይ ስርዓቱ የተለየ የዶሜን ምልክቶች ለመጠቀም አይከለክልም፡፡ የቋንቋ ቋንቋ ሞዴል እና የስራ መልዕክቶች ውስጥ የተለየውን እውቀት በተለየ ቃላት መጻሕፍት ማሳየት እናደርጋለን፡፡ በተገኘው የ0 ነጥብ ስርዓት በአዲስ የኢንግሊዝኛ ዳታተር ላይ በተጠቃሚ አዲስ የልዩ አርእስት አግኝቷል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağızda başqa təhsil edilmiş dil modellərini WordNet sinqutlarına bağlamaq üçün müxtəlif təhsil edilmiş sistemi göstəririk. Daha sonra, sistem müəyyən bir domain etiketlərini istifadə etməyə qadağan deyil. Biz müxtəlif WordNet tanımlamasının domena etiketini sübut etmək üçün müxtəlif təhsil edilmiş dil modellərində kodlanmış bilgiləri istifadə edirik. Qıymetdə istifadə edilən İngilis veri qutusunda yeni bir məlumat sistemi başa çatdı.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>En aquest article presentem un sistema que explota diferents models de llenguatge pré-entrenats per assenyar etiquetes de domini a sínsets WordNet sense cap mena de supervisió. A més, el sistema no està limitat a utilitzar un conjunt particular d'etiquetes de domini. Exploitem el coneixement codificat dins diferents models de llenguatge pré-entrenats fora de la plataforma i formulacions de tasques per inferir l'etiqueta de domini d'una definició WordNet concreta. El sistema de fotografies zero proposat aconsegueix una nova tecnologia en el conjunt de dades anglès utilitzat en l'evaluació.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>U ovom papiru predstavljamo sistem koji koristi različite predobučene jezičke modele za dodavanje etiketa domena sinkronizaciji WordNet a bez ikakvog nadzora. Osim toga, sistem nije ograničen za upotrebu određenog set a etiketa domena. Koristimo znanje kodirano u različitim izvan police predobučenim jezičkim modelima i formulacijama zadatka kako bi inferirali etiketu domena određene definicije WordNet. Predloženi sistem nula pucnjave postiže novo stanje umjetnosti na engleskom setu podataka koji se koristi u procjeni.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_bn>এই কাগজটিতে আমরা একটি সিস্টেম উপস্থাপন করি যা পূর্ব প্রশিক্ষিত ভাষার মোডেল ব্যবহার করে কোন ধরনের দেখাশোনা ছাড়া ডোমেইন লেবেল বানা এছাড়াও, বিশেষ কিছু ডোমেইন লেবেল ব্যবহারের জন্য সিস্টেম সীমাবদ্ধ নয়। আমরা বিভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভাষার প্রশিক্ষিত ভাষা মোডেল এবং কাজের বিষয়টি ব্যবহার করি একটি বিশেষ ওয়ার্ডনেট নির্ধারণের ডোমেইন লেবেলেটের প্রত The proposed zero-shot system achieves a new state-of-the-art on the English dataset used in the evaluation.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Այս թղթի մեջ մենք ներկայացնում ենք մի համակարգ, որը օգտագործում է տարբեր նախապատրաստված լեզվի մոդելներ, որպեսզի տիեզերական պիտակները բաժանեն WordNet սինսետներին առանց որևէ տեսակի վերահսկողության: Ավելին, համակարգը սահմանափակված չէ տիեզերքի պիտակների որոշակի շարք օգտագործելու: Մենք օգտագործում ենք գիտելիքները, որոնք կոդավորված են տարբեր անդաշտային նախապատրաստված լեզվի մոդելներում և խնդիրների ձևավորումներում որոշակի WordNet-ի սահմանման բնագավառի պիտակ պարզելու համար: Առաջարկված զրո-կրակային համակարգը հասնում է անգլերենի տվյալների համակարգի նոր զարգացումը, որը օգտագործվում է գնահատման մեջ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa esittelemme järjestelmän, joka hyödyntää erilaisia ennalta koulutettuja kielimalleja verkkotunnusten osoittamiseksi WordNet-synzeteille ilman minkäänlaista valvontaa. Järjestelmä ei myöskään rajoitu käyttämään tiettyjä verkkotunnuksia. Hyödynnämme eri valmiiksi koulutetuissa kielimalleissa ja tehtäväformulaatioissa koodattua tietoa päätelläksemme tietyn WordNet-määritelmän verkkotunnuksen. Ehdotetulla nollashot-järjestelmällä saavutetaan arvioinnissa käytetty englanninkielinen aineisto.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_cs>V tomto článku představujeme systém, který využívá různé předškolené jazykové modely pro přiřazení doménových štítků synsetům WordNet bez jakéhokoliv dohledu. Kromě toho systém není omezen na použití konkrétní sady doménových štítků. Využíváme znalosti zakódované v rámci různých standardně předškolených jazykových modelů a formulací úloh k odvození doménového popisu konkrétní definice WordNet. Navržený systém nulového výstřelu dosahuje nového stavu techniky na anglickém datovém souboru použitém při hodnocení.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas töös tutvustame süsteemi, mis kasutab erinevaid eelõpetatud keelemudeleid domeenimärgiste määramiseks WordNet sünkroonidele ilma mingisuguse järelevalveta. Lisaks ei ole süsteem piiratud konkreetse domeenimärgiste komplekti kasutamisega. Me kasutame erinevates eelväljaõpetatud keelemudelites ja ülesannete vormingutes kodeeritud teadmisi, et järeldada konkreetse WordNeti definitsiooni domeenimärgist. Kavandatud null-shot süsteemiga saavutatakse hindamisel kasutatud inglise andmekogumi uus tehnika tase.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>Nang paper nyoe nambah sistem sing paling yang sampeyan luwih dumadhingan banggambar model kanggo nggawe domain etiket kanggo Word net sinaturan secang ngon cah akeh sistem. This is a special set of domain label. We use the knowingthat koded in a new off-the-shell before-cured Language Modes and task formations to see the domain label of a special Word net definetion. Sistem sing dipunanggé nul-ot nggawe barang nggawe sistem sing gawe dataset Inggris barang nggawe tarjamahan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Daga cikin wannan takardan, Munã bãyar da wani na'ura wanda ke amfani da Modellun da aka yi wa zaman-hakari da za'a buɗe wa alama na ɗabi'a zuwa sunayen ayuka na WdNet, kuma bã da wani irin tsari ba. Furan haka, ba za'a ƙayyade system don a yi amfani da wasu alama na'ura. Munã amfani da ilmi wanda aka kodi cikin shirin bayan-shelf da aka yi wa zaman-wa-shirin da aka yi wa aikin aiki da za'a yi ƙaranci cikin alama ɗin Domen na ƙayyade wani ƙayyade na KaldNet. Tsarin da aka buƙata sifo-shot ya sami wani halin-mai-art kan tsarin maɓallin Ingiriya da ake amfani da cikin evalutan.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>בעיתון הזה אנו מציגים מערכת שמניצלת מודלים שפות שונים מאומנים מראש להסגיר תוויות תחום לסינסטים WordNet ללא שום סוג של פיקוח. חוץ מזה, המערכת לא מוגבלת להשתמש בסט מסוים של תוויות תחום. אנו מנצלים את הידע המקודם בתוך מודלים שפות מאומנים מראש מחוץ למדף שונים ומתאימים משימות כדי להוציא את תווית התחום של הגדרת WordNet מסוימת. The proposed zero-shot system achieves a new state-of-the-art on the English dataset used in the evaluation.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>In this paper we present a system that exploits different pre-trained Language Models for assigning domain labels to WordNet synsets without any kind of supervision. Furthermore, the system is not restricted to use a particular set of domain labels. We exploit the knowledge encoded within different off-the-shelf pre-trained Language Models and task formulations to infer the domain label of a particular WordNet definition. གྲངས་སྐུད་ཀྱི་མ་ལག་གིས་འཆར་བརྟན་ན་དབྱིན་ཡིག་སྒྲུང་ནང་སྤྱོད་པའི་གནས་སྟངས་གསར་བ་ཞིག་རྟོགས་ཐུབ།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku predstavljamo sistem, ki izkorišča različne vnaprej usposobljene jezikovne modele za dodeljevanje oznak domen WordNet synsetom brez kakršnega koli nadzora. Poleg tega sistem ni omejen na uporabo določenega nabora oznak domen. Izkoriščamo znanje, kodirano v različnih predhodno usposobljenih jezikovnih modelih in formulacijah nalog, da ugotovimo oznako domene določene definicije WordNet. Predlagani ničelni sistem dosega novo najsodobnejšo vrednost angleškega nabora podatkov, ki se uporablja pri ocenjevanju.</abstract_sk>
      </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Monolingual Word Sense Alignment as a Classification Problem</title>
      <author><first>Sina</first><last>Ahmadi</last></author>
      <author><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <pages>73–80</pages>
      <abstract>Words are defined based on their meanings in various ways in different resources. Aligning word senses across monolingual lexicographic resources increases domain coverage and enables integration and incorporation of data. In this paper, we explore the application of classification methods using manually-extracted features along with representation learning techniques in the task of word sense alignment and semantic relationship detection. We demonstrate that the performance of classification methods dramatically varies based on the type of semantic relationships due to the nature of the task but outperforms the previous experiments.</abstract>
      <url hash="c7363d23">2021.gwc-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>ahmadi-mccrae-2021-monolingual</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>The GlobalWordNet Formats : Updates for 2020<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>lobal<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et Formats: Updates for 2020</title>
      <author><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael Wayne</first><last>Goodman</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexandre</first><last>Rademaker</last></author>
      <author><first>Ewa</first><last>Rudnicka</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis Morgado Da</first><last>Costa</last></author>
      <pages>91–99</pages>
      <abstract>The Global Wordnet Formats have been introduced to enable wordnets to have a common representation that can be integrated through the Global WordNet Grid. As a result of their adoption, a number of shortcomings of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_format">format</a> were identified, and in this paper we describe the extensions to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_format">formats</a> that address these issues. These include : ordering of senses, dependencies between wordnets, pronunciation, syntactic modelling, relations, sense keys, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata">metadata</a> and RDF support. Furthermore, we provide some perspectives on how these changes help in the integration of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnets</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="37765de7">2021.gwc-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>mccrae-etal-2021-globalwordnet</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/globalwordnet/english-wordnet" additional="false">globalwordnet/english-wordnet</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Semantic Analysis of Verb-Noun Derivation in Princeton WordNet<fixed-case>P</fixed-case>rinceton <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et</title>
      <author><first>Verginica</first><last>Mititelu</last></author>
      <author><first>Svetlozara</first><last>Leseva</last></author>
      <author><first>Ivelina</first><last>Stoyanova</last></author>
      <pages>108–117</pages>
      <abstract>We present here the results of a morphosemantic analysis of the verb-noun pairs in the Princeton WordNet as reflected in the standoff file containing pairs annotated with a set of 14 semantic relations. We have automatically distinguished between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zero-derivation">zero-derivation</a> and affixal derivation in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a> and identified the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affix">affixes</a> and manually checked the results. The data show that for each semantic relation an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affix">affix</a> prevails in creating new words, although we can not talk about their specificity with respect to such a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_relation">relation</a>. Moreover, certain pairs of verb-noun semantic primes are better represented for each semantic relation, and some semantic clusters (in the form of WordNet subtrees) take shape as a result. We thus employ a large-scale data-driven linguistically motivated analysis afforded by the rich derivational and morphosemantic description in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> to the end of capturing finer regularities in the process of derivation as represented in the semantic properties of the words involved and as reflected in the structure of the lexicon.</abstract>
      <url hash="084d70ae">2021.gwc-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>mititelu-etal-2021-semantic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>OdeNet : Compiling a GermanWordNet from other Resources<fixed-case>O</fixed-case>de<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et: Compiling a <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>erman<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et from other Resources</title>
      <author><first>Melanie</first><last>Siegel</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <pages>192–198</pages>
      <abstract>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_WordNet">Princeton WordNet</a> for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English language</a> has been used worldwide in NLP projects for many years. With the OMW initiative, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnets</a> for different languages of the world are being linked via identifiers. The parallel development and linking allows new multilingual application perspectives. The development of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a> for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German language</a> is also in this context. To save development time, existing resources were combined and recompiled. The result was then evaluated and improved. In a relatively short time a resource was created that can be used in projects and continuously improved and extended.</abstract>
      <url hash="18ec63f1">2021.gwc-1.22</url>
      <bibkey>siegel-bond-2021-odenet</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Text Document Clustering : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">Wordnet</a> vs. TF-IDF vs. Word Embeddings<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet vs. <fixed-case>TF</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>IDF</fixed-case> vs. Word Embeddings</title>
      <author><first>Michał</first><last>Marcińczuk</last></author>
      <author><first>Mateusz</first><last>Gniewkowski</last></author>
      <author><first>Tomasz</first><last>Walkowiak</last></author>
      <author><first>Marcin</first><last>Będkowski</last></author>
      <pages>207–214</pages>
      <abstract>In the paper, we deal with the problem of unsupervised text document clustering for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_language">Polish language</a>. Our goal is to compare the modern approaches based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language modeling</a> (doc2vec and BERT) with the classical <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_programming_languages_by_type">ones</a>, i.e., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TF-IDF">TF-IDF</a> and wordnet-based. The experiments are conducted on three <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> containing qualification descriptions. The experiments’ results showed that wordnet-based similarity measures could compete and even outperform modern embedding-based approaches.</abstract>
      <url hash="11fd5f7d">2021.gwc-1.24</url>
      <bibkey>marcinczuk-etal-2021-text</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>Neural Language Models vs Wordnet-based Semantically Enriched Representation in CST Relation Recognition<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet-based Semantically Enriched Representation in <fixed-case>CST</fixed-case> Relation Recognition</title>
      <author><first>Arkadiusz</first><last>Janz</last></author>
      <author><first>Maciej</first><last>Piasecki</last></author>
      <author><first>Piotr</first><last>Wątorski</last></author>
      <pages>223–233</pages>
      <abstract>Neural language models, including transformer-based models, that are pre-trained on very large corpora became a common way to represent text in various tasks, including recognition of textual semantic relations, e.g. Cross-document Structure Theory. Pre-trained models are usually fine tuned to downstream tasks and the obtained vectors are used as an input for deep neural classifiers. No linguistic knowledge obtained from resources and tools is utilised. In this paper we compare such universal approaches with a combination of rich graph-based linguistically motivated sentence representation and a typical neural network classifier applied to a task of recognition of CST relation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_language">Polish</a>. The representation describes selected levels of the sentence structure including description of lexical meanings on the basis of the wordnet (plWordNet) synsets and connected SUMO concepts. The obtained results show that in the case of difficult relations and medium size training corpus semantically enriched text representation leads to significantly better results.</abstract>
      <url hash="0703aac0">2021.gwc-1.26</url>
      <bibkey>janz-etal-2021-neural</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>What is on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">Social Media</a> that is not in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a>? A Preliminary Analysis on the TwitterAAE Corpus<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et? A Preliminary Analysis on the <fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter<fixed-case>AAE</fixed-case> Corpus</title>
      <author><first>Cecilia</first><last>Domingo</last></author>
      <author><first>Tatiana</first><last>Gonzalez-Ferrero</last></author>
      <author><first>Itziar</first><last>Gonzalez-Dios</last></author>
      <pages>234–242</pages>
      <abstract>Natural Language Processing tools and resources have been so far mainly created and trained for standard varieties of language. Nowadays, with the use of large amounts of data gathered from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>, other varieties and registers need to be processed, which may present other challenges and difficulties. In this work, we focus on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and we present a preliminary analysis by comparing the TwitterAAE corpus, which is annotated for ethnicity, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> by quantifying and explaining the online language that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> misses.</abstract>
      <url hash="684077a4">2021.gwc-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>domingo-etal-2021-social</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="30">
      <title>Toward the creation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNets</a> for ancient Indo-European languages<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>ets for ancient <fixed-case>I</fixed-case>ndo-<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>uropean languages</title>
      <author><first>Erica</first><last>Biagetti</last></author>
      <author><first>Chiara</first><last>Zanchi</last></author>
      <author><first>William Michael</first><last>Short</last></author>
      <pages>258–266</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents the work in progress toward the creation of a family of WordNets for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanskrit">Sanskrit</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Greek">Ancient Greek</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latin">Latin</a>. Building on previous attempts in the field, we elaborate these efforts bridging together WordNet relational semantics with theories of meaning from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_linguistics">Cognitive Linguistics</a>. We discuss some of the innovations we have introduced to the WordNet architecture, to better capture the polysemy of words, as well as Indo-European language family-specific features. We conclude the paper framing our work within the larger picture of resources available for ancient languages and showing that WordNet-backed search tools have the potential to re-define the kinds of questions that can be asked of ancient language corpora.</abstract>
      <url hash="77766339">2021.gwc-1.30</url>
      <bibkey>biagetti-etal-2021-toward</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="32">
      <title>Teaching Through Tagging   Interactive Lexical Semantics</title>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Bond</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrew</first><last>Devadason</last></author>
      <author><first>Melissa Rui Lin</first><last>Teo</last></author>
      <author><first>Luís Morgado</first><last>da Costa</last></author>
      <pages>273–283</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we discuss an ongoing effort to enrich students’ learning by involving them in sense tagging. The main goal is to lead students to discover how we can represent meaning and where the limits of our current theories lie. A subsidiary goal is to create sense tagged corpora and an accompanying linked lexicon (in our case wordnets). We present the results of tagging several texts and suggest some ways in which the tagging process could be improved. Two authors of this paper present their own experience as students. Overall, students reported that they found the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tag_(metadata)">tagging</a> an enriching experience. The annotated corpora and changes to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a> are made available through the NTU multilingual corpus and associated wordnets (NTU-MC).</abstract>
      <url hash="35765cef">2021.gwc-1.32</url>
      <bibkey>bond-etal-2021-teaching</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>