<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.americasnlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Indigenous Languages of the Americas</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Manuel</first><last>Mager</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Arturo</first><last>Oncevay</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Annette</first><last>Rios</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ivan Vladimir Meza</first><last>Ruiz</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alexis</first><last>Palmer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Graham</first><last>Neubig</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Katharina</first><last>Kann</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.americasnlp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="beb9eed7">2021.americasnlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>americasnlp-2021-natural</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Investigating variation in written forms of Nahuatl using character-based language models<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>ahuatl using character-based language models</title>
      <author><first>Robert</first><last>Pugh</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Tyers</last></author>
      <pages>21–27</pages>
      <abstract>We describe experiments with character-based language modeling for written variants of Nahuatl. Using a standard LSTM model and publicly available <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bible_translations">Bible translations</a>, we explore how character language models can be applied to the tasks of estimating mutual intelligibility, identifying genetic similarity, and distinguishing written variants. We demonstrate that these simple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> are able to capture similarities and differences that have been described in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">linguistic literature</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="ba4bb55f">2021.americasnlp-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.americasnlp-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>pugh-tyers-2021-investigating</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/lguyogiro/nahuatl-variant-charlms-americasnlp" additional="false">lguyogiro/nahuatl-variant-charlms-americasnlp</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Morphological Segmentation for Seneca<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>eneca</title>
      <author><first>Zoey</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Robert</first><last>Jimerson</last></author>
      <author><first>Emily</first><last>Prud’hommeaux</last></author>
      <pages>90–101</pages>
      <abstract>This study takes up the task of low-resource morphological segmentation for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seneca_language">Seneca</a>, a critically endangered and morphologically complex Native American language primarily spoken in what is now New York State and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ontario">Ontario</a>. The labeled data in our experiments comes from two sources : one digitized from a publicly available grammar book and the other collected from informal sources. We treat these two sources as distinct domains and investigate different evaluation designs for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_selection">model selection</a>. The first design abides by standard practices and evaluate models with the in-domain development set, while the second one carries out evaluation using a development domain, or the out-of-domain development set. Across a series of monolingual and crosslinguistic training settings, our results demonstrate the utility of neural encoder-decoder architecture when coupled with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-task_learning">multi-task learning</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="371b8485">2021.americasnlp-1.10</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.americasnlp-1.10</doi>
      <bibkey>liu-etal-2021-morphological</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/zoeyliu18/seneca" additional="false">zoeyliu18/seneca</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Representation of Yine [ Arawak ] Morphology by Finite State Transducer Formalism<fixed-case>Y</fixed-case>ine [<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rawak] Morphology by Finite State Transducer Formalism</title>
      <author><first>Adriano</first><last>Ingunza Torres</last></author>
      <author><first>John</first><last>Miller</last></author>
      <author><first>Arturo</first><last>Oncevay</last></author>
      <author><first>Roberto</first><last>Zariquiey Biondi</last></author>
      <pages>102–112</pages>
      <abstract>We represent the complexity of Yine (Arawak) morphology with a finite state transducer (FST) based morphological analyzer. Yine is a low-resource indigenous polysynthetic Peruvian language spoken by approximately 3,000 people and is classified as ‘definitely endangered’ by UNESCO. We review Yine morphology focusing on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphophonology">morphophonology</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Possessive">possessive constructions</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Predicate_(grammar)">verbal predicates</a>. Then we develop FSTs to model these components proposing techniques to solve challenging problems such as complex patterns of incorporating open and closed category arguments. This is a work in progress and we still have more to do in the development and verification of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analyzer">analyzer</a>. Our analyzer will serve both as a tool to better document the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yine">Yine language</a> and as a component of natural language processing (NLP) applications such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spell_checker">spell checking</a> and correction.</abstract>
      <url hash="fa1d4d59">2021.americasnlp-1.11</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryCode" hash="3b960847">2021.americasnlp-1.11.OptionalSupplementaryCode.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.americasnlp-1.11</doi>
      <bibkey>ingunza-torres-etal-2021-representation</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Expanding Universal Dependencies for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polysynthetic_language">Polysynthetic Languages</a> : A Case of St. Lawrence Island Yupik<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependencies for Polysynthetic Languages: A Case of <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>t. <fixed-case>L</fixed-case>awrence <fixed-case>I</fixed-case>sland <fixed-case>Y</fixed-case>upik</title>
      <author><first>Hyunji Hayley</first><last>Park</last></author>
      <author><first>Lane</first><last>Schwartz</last></author>
      <author><first>Francis</first><last>Tyers</last></author>
      <pages>131–142</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the development of the first Universal Dependencies (UD) treebank for St. Lawrence Island Yupik, an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">endangered language</a> spoken in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beringia">Bering Strait region</a>. While the UD guidelines provided a general framework for our annotations, language-specific decisions were made necessary by the rich morphology of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polysynthetic_language">polysynthetic language</a>. Most notably, we annotated a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> at the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morpheme">morpheme level</a> as well as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word">word level</a>. The morpheme level annotation was conducted using an existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphology_(linguistics)">morphological analyzer</a> and manual disambiguation. By comparing the two resulting annotation schemes, we argue that morpheme-level annotation is essential for polysynthetic languages like St. Lawrence Island Yupik. Word-level annotation results in degenerate trees for some Yupik sentences and often fails to capture syntactic relations that can be manifested at the morpheme level. Dependency parsing experiments provide further support for morpheme-level annotation. Implications for UD annotation of other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polysynthetic_language">polysynthetic languages</a> are discussed.</abstract>
      <url hash="49a8ac83">2021.americasnlp-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.americasnlp-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>park-etal-2021-expanding</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>Findings of the AmericasNLP 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>mericas<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>mericas</title>
      <author><first>Manuel</first><last>Mager</last></author>
      <author><first>Arturo</first><last>Oncevay</last></author>
      <author><first>Abteen</first><last>Ebrahimi</last></author>
      <author><first>John</first><last>Ortega</last></author>
      <author><first>Annette</first><last>Rios</last></author>
      <author><first>Angela</first><last>Fan</last></author>
      <author><first>Ximena</first><last>Gutierrez-Vasques</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis</first><last>Chiruzzo</last></author>
      <author><first>Gustavo</first><last>Giménez-Lugo</last></author>
      <author><first>Ricardo</first><last>Ramos</last></author>
      <author><first>Ivan Vladimir</first><last>Meza Ruiz</last></author>
      <author><first>Rolando</first><last>Coto-Solano</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexis</first><last>Palmer</last></author>
      <author><first>Elisabeth</first><last>Mager-Hois</last></author>
      <author><first>Vishrav</first><last>Chaudhary</last></author>
      <author><first>Graham</first><last>Neubig</last></author>
      <author><first>Ngoc Thang</first><last>Vu</last></author>
      <author><first>Katharina</first><last>Kann</last></author>
      <pages>202–217</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents the results of the 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indigenous_languages_of_the_Americas">Indigenous Languages of the Americas</a>. The shared task featured two independent tracks, and participants submitted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation systems</a> for up to 10 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indigenous_language">indigenous languages</a>. Overall, 8 teams participated with a total of 214 submissions. We provided <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training sets</a> consisting of data collected from various sources, as well as manually translated sentences for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">development and test sets</a>. An official <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(medicine)">baseline</a> trained on this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a> was also provided. Team submissions featured a variety of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_architecture">architectures</a>, including both statistical and neural models, and for the majority of languages, many teams were able to considerably improve over the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline</a>. The best performing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> achieved 12.97 ChrF higher than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline</a>, when averaged across languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="ac069c84">2021.americasnlp-1.23</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.americasnlp-1.23</doi>
      <bibkey>mager-etal-2021-findings</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/flores">FLoRes</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/xnli">XNLI</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>نتائج مهمة الأمريكتين NLP 2021 المشتركة حول الترجمة الآلية المفتوحة للغات السكان الأصليين في الأمريكتين</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Descobertas da tarefa compartilhada AmericasNLP 2021 sobre tradução automática aberta para línguas indígenas das Américas</title_pt>
      <title_es>Hallazgos de la tarea compartida AmericasNLP 2021 sobre traducción automática abierta para las lenguas indígenas de las Américas</title_es>
      <title_zh>美洲NLP 2021美洲土语开机器翻译者</title_zh>
      <title_ja>南北アメリカ先住民言語のオープンマシン翻訳に関するアメリカNLP 2021共有タスクの調査結果</title_ja>
      <title_hi>अमेरिका की स्वदेशी भाषाओं के लिए ओपन मशीन अनुवाद पर अमेरिकासंकल्प 2021 साझा कार्य के निष्कर्ष</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Torthaí Thasc Roinnte AmericasNLP 2021 ar Aistriúchán Meaisín Oscailte do Theangacha Dúchasacha Mheiriceá</title_ga>
      <title_ka>AmericasNLP 2021-ის გარეშე მოქმედება ამერიკის ინდიგენო ენების გარეშე მაქინის გარეშე</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Az AmericasNLP 2021 megosztott feladatának eredményei az amerikai őslakos nyelvek nyílt gépi fordításáról</title_hu>
      <title_it>Risultati del compito condiviso AmericasNLP 2021 sulla traduzione automatica aperta per le lingue indigene delle Americhe</title_it>
      <title_el>Ευρετήματα της Κοινής Εργασίας για την Ανοικτή Μηχανική Μετάφραση για τις Ιθαγενείς Γλώσσες της Αμερικής</title_el>
      <title_kk>АмерикаNLP 2021 жылы Америкалық тілдер үшін Open Machine аудару тапсырмасының ортақ тапсырмасы</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Penemuan AmerikaNLP 2021 Tugas Berkongsi mengenai Terjemahan Mesin Buka untuk Bahasa Indigenous Amerika</title_ms>
      <title_mk>Најдовме заедничка задача на АмериканцитеNLP 2021 за отворен машински превед за домородните јазици на Америка</title_mk>
      <title_ml>അമേരിക്കകക്കാരുടെ കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നത് NLP 2021 പങ്കെടുത്ത ടാസ്കിന്‍ തുറന്ന മെഷീന്‍ പരിഭാഷകളില്‍ നിന്നും അമേരിക്ക</title_ml>
      <title_lt>Amerikos išvados</title_lt>
      <title_mt>Sejbiet tal-AmerikasNLP 2021 Kompitu Konġunt dwar Traduzzjoni Miftuħa tal-Makkinarju għal-Lingwi Indiġeni tal-Amerika</title_mt>
      <title_pl>Wyniki amerykańskiegoNLP 2021 Wspólne zadanie dotyczące otwartego tłumaczenia maszynowego dla języków rdzennych Ameryk</title_pl>
      <title_mn>АмерикаNLP 2021 оны Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas</title_mn>
      <title_no>Finningar av AmericasNLP 2021 Delt oppgåve om Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas</title_no>
      <title_si>ඇමෙරිකාස් න්ලෝප් 2021 සාමාන්‍ය වැඩක් හොයාගන්න ඇමරිකාස් භාෂාවල් සඳහා විශේෂ පරිවර්තනය</title_si>
      <title_sr>Nalazi američkog NLP 2021. zajedničkog zadatka o prevodu otvorenog mašine za Indijanske jezike Amerike</title_sr>
      <title_so>Findings of AmericasNLP 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of Americas</title_so>
      <title_ro>Concluziile misiunii comune AmericasNLP 2021 privind traducerea automată deschisă pentru limbile indigene din Americi</title_ro>
      <title_ta>அமெரிக்காName</title_ta>
      <title_ur>امریکائیس NLP 2021 کے شریک ٹاکس پر اوپن ماشین کی ترجمہ آمریکا کی Indigenous Languages کے لئے</title_ur>
      <title_sv>Resultaten av AmericasNLP 2021 delad uppgift om öppen maskinöversättning för inhemska språk i Amerika</title_sv>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Nghiên cứu của rượu Châu Mỹ khôn 2021 Làm nhiệm vụ chia sẻ về việc dịch cơ mở cho ngôn ngữ bản của Mỹ</title_vi>
      <title_da>Resultater af AmericasNLP 2021 delt opgave om åben maskinoversættelse for oprindelige sprog i Amerika</title_da>
      <title_hr>Pronaći zajednički zadatak Američkog NLP 2021. godine o prevodu otvorenog stroja za Indijanske jezike Amerike</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Conclusies van de AmericasNLP 2021 Gedeelde Taak over Open Machine Translation voor inheemse talen van Amerika</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Резултати от съвместната задача за отворен машинен превод за местните езици на Америка за 2021 г.</title_bg>
      <title_de>Ergebnisse des AmericasNLP 2021 Gemeinsame Aufgabe zur offenen maschinellen Übersetzung für indigene Sprachen Amerikas</title_de>
      <title_id>Findings of the AmericasNLP 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas</title_id>
      <title_ko>AmericasNLP 2021년 아메리카 원주민 언어 개방식 기계 번역의 공동 임무에 대한 발견</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Matokeo ya Wamarekani NLP 2021 yalishiriki kazi kwenye Tafsiri ya Open Mashine kwa Lugha za wenyeji wa Marekani</title_sw>
      <title_tr>AmericasNLP 2021-nji ýylda Amerika'laryň ýerli diller üçin Aç Makina Terjime hakynda paylaş görevi</title_tr>
      <title_af>Findings van die AmerikaansNLP 2021 Gedeelde Opdrag op Open Masjien Vertaling vir Indigenous Taal van die Amerika</title_af>
      <title_sq>Gjetjet e Amerikës NLP 2021</title_sq>
      <title_fa>Findings of the Americas NLP 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas</title_fa>
      <title_am>NLP 2021 የተቀራረበ ስራዎችን በክፈት Machine ትርጓሜ ላይ የአሜሪካውያን ቋንቋዎች ላይ</title_am>
      <title_hy>Ամերիկայի 2021 թվականի ՆԼՊ-ի բաց մեքենայի թարգմանման հանձնարարությունները Ամերիկայի բնական լեզուների համար</title_hy>
      <title_bn>আমেরিকান এনএলপি ২০২১ সালের কাজ শেয়ার করা হয়েছে মেশিন অনুবাদে আমেরিকার আদিবাসী ভাষার জন্য উন্মুক্ত মেশিন অনুবাদ</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Nalazi američkog NLP 2021. zajedničkog zadatka o prevodu otvorenog mašine za Indijanske jezike Amerike</title_bs>
      <title_az>AmericaNLP 2021'nin Açıq Makina Çevirməsi üçün Amerika'nın Indijin Dillərinin paylaşılmış Taski</title_az>
      <title_ca>Results of the AmericasNLP 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Zjištění AmericasNLP 2021 Sdílený úkol o otevřeném strojovém překladu pro domorodé jazyky Ameriky</title_cs>
      <title_fi>AmericasNLP 2021:n päätelmät Amerikan alkuperäiskansojen kielten avoimen konekäännöksen yhteisestä tehtävästä</title_fi>
      <title_et>Ameerika Ühendriikide põliskeelte avatud masintõlke jagatud ülesanne 2021. aasta Ameerika Ühendriikide põliskeelte jaoks</title_et>
      <title_jv>Finding of the AmarkasiNLP 2020 Joined tasks on Open Masine translation for individual Languages of the Amarok</title_jv>
      <title_he>מציאות האמריקאיםNLP 2021 משימה משותפת על תרגום מכונות פתוחות לשפות מקומיות של האמריקאים</title_he>
      <title_ha>@ info: whatsthis</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Ugotovitve skupne naloge AmericasNLP 2021 o odprtem strojnem prevajanju avtohtonih jezikov Amerike</title_sk>
      <title_bo>AmericasNLP 2021 རྣམ་གྲངས་ཀྱི་རྩིས་མོ Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas</title_bo>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo presenta los resultados de la tarea compartida de 2021 sobre traducción automática abierta para las lenguas indígenas de las Américas. La tarea compartida contó con dos temas independientes, y los participantes enviaron sistemas de traducción automática para hasta 10 idiomas indígenas. En total, participaron 8 equipos con un total de 214 presentaciones. Proporcionamos conjuntos de capacitación que consistían en datos recopilados de varias fuentes, así como frases traducidas manualmente para los conjuntos de desarrollo y prueba. También se proporcionó una línea de base oficial capacitada en estos datos. Las presentaciones de los equipos incluían una variedad de arquitecturas, incluidos modelos estadísticos y neuronales, y para la mayoría de los idiomas, muchos equipos pudieron mejorar considerablemente con respecto a la línea de base. Los sistemas con mejor rendimiento alcanzaron 12,97 CHrF más que la base, cuando se promediaron en todos los idiomas.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ar>تعرض هذه الورقة نتائج المهمة المشتركة لعام 2021 حول الترجمة الآلية المفتوحة للغات الشعوب الأصلية في الأمريكتين. تضمنت المهمة المشتركة مسارين مستقلين ، وقدم المشاركون أنظمة ترجمة آلية لما يصل إلى 10 لغات أصلية. بشكل عام ، شاركت 8 فرق بإجمالي 214 مشاركة. قدمنا مجموعات تدريب تتكون من بيانات تم جمعها من مصادر مختلفة ، بالإضافة إلى جمل مترجمة يدويًا لمجموعات التطوير والاختبار. كما تم توفير خط أساس رسمي تم تدريبه على هذه البيانات. تضمنت عمليات إرسال الفريق مجموعة متنوعة من البنى ، بما في ذلك النماذج الإحصائية والعصبية ، وبالنسبة لغالبية اللغات ، تمكنت العديد من الفرق من التحسين بشكل كبير على خط الأساس. حققت أفضل الأنظمة أداءً 12.97 ChrF أعلى من خط الأساس ، عند حساب المتوسط عبر اللغات.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo apresenta os resultados da Tarefa Compartilhada de 2021 sobre Tradução Automática Aberta para Línguas Indígenas das Américas. A tarefa compartilhada contou com duas faixas independentes e os participantes enviaram sistemas de tradução automática para até 10 idiomas indígenas. Ao todo, 8 equipes participaram com um total de 214 inscrições. Fornecemos conjuntos de treinamento que consistem em dados coletados de várias fontes, bem como frases traduzidas manualmente para os conjuntos de desenvolvimento e teste. Uma linha de base oficial treinada nesses dados também foi fornecida. Os envios de equipe apresentavam uma variedade de arquiteturas, incluindo modelos estatísticos e neurais e, para a maioria das linguagens, muitas equipes conseguiram melhorar consideravelmente em relação à linha de base. Os sistemas com melhor desempenho alcançaram 12,97 ChrF acima da linha de base, quando a média entre os idiomas.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、アメリカ先住民言語のオープンマシン翻訳に関する2021年の共有タスクの結果を紹介します。共有タスクには2つの独立したトラックがあり、参加者は最大10の先住民言語の機械翻訳システムを提出しました。全体で8チームが参加し、合計214件の応募があった。さまざまなソースから収集されたデータからなるトレーニングセットと、開発およびテストセットのために手動で翻訳された文章を提供しました。このデータについてトレーニングを受けた公式のベースラインも提供された。チームの提出物には、統計モデルとニューラルモデルの両方を含むさまざまなアーキテクチャが含まれており、ほとんどの言語では、多くのチームがベースラインを大幅に改善することができました。最高のパフォーマンスを発揮するシステムは、言語間で平均した場合、ベースラインよりも12.97 ChrF高い値を達成しました。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>本文言2021年美洲土著言开机器翻译共享其事。 共享事兼两独道,参与者提交至10种语言机器翻译系统。 凡8支队参赛,凡214分参赛作。 供训练集,包括诸源数,及开发、测试手动译句。 给以训练之官基线。 团队言有架构,计神经有形,多言多团队,大幅改于基线。 性最佳者,统于诸语中均比基线高出 12.97 ChrF。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर अमेरिका की स्वदेशी भाषाओं के लिए ओपन मशीन अनुवाद पर 2021 साझा कार्य के परिणामों को प्रस्तुत करता है। साझा कार्य में दो स्वतंत्र ट्रैक शामिल थे, और प्रतिभागियों ने 10 स्वदेशी भाषाओं के लिए मशीन अनुवाद प्रणाली प्रस्तुत की। कुल मिलाकर, 8 टीमों ने कुल 214 प्रस्तुतियों के साथ भाग लिया। हमने विभिन्न स्रोतों से एकत्र किए गए डेटा से युक्त प्रशिक्षण सेट प्रदान किए, साथ ही विकास और परीक्षण सेट के लिए मैन्युअल रूप से अनुवादित वाक्य भी प्रदान किए। इस डेटा पर प्रशिक्षित एक आधिकारिक आधार रेखा भी प्रदान की गई थी। टीम सबमिशन में सांख्यिकीय और तंत्रिका मॉडल दोनों सहित विभिन्न प्रकार के आर्किटेक्चर शामिल थे, और अधिकांश भाषाओं के लिए, कई टीमें बेसलाइन पर काफी सुधार करने में सक्षम थीं। सबसे अच्छा प्रदर्शन करने वाली प्रणालियों ने बेसलाइन की तुलना में 12.97 ChrF अधिक प्राप्त किया, जब भाषाओं में औसत किया गया।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirtear i láthair sa pháipéar seo torthaí Thasc Roinnte 2021 ar Aistriúchán Meaisín Oscailte do Theangacha Dúchasacha Mheiriceá. Bhí dhá rian neamhspleácha i gceist leis an tasc roinnte, agus chuir rannpháirtithe isteach córais aistriúcháin mheaisín ar feadh suas le 10 dteanga dhúchais. Ar an iomlán, ghlac 8 bhfoireann páirt agus 214 aighneacht san iomlán. Chuireamar tacair oiliúna ar fáil ina raibh sonraí a bailíodh ó fhoinsí éagsúla, chomh maith le habairtí a aistríodh de láimh le haghaidh na tacair forbartha agus tástála. Cuireadh bonnlíne oifigiúil oilte ar na sonraí seo ar fáil freisin. Bhain éagsúlacht ailtireachta le haighneachtaí foirne, lena n-áirítear samhlacha staitistiúla agus néaracha, agus d’fhormhór na dteangacha, bhí go leor foirne in ann feabhsú go mór thar an mbunlíne. Bhain na córais is fearr feidhmíochta amach 12.97 ChrF níos airde ná an bhunlíne, nuair a meánaíodh iad trasna teangacha.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία παρουσιάζει τα αποτελέσματα της κοινής εργασίας για την ανοικτή μηχανική μετάφραση για τις αυτόχθονες γλώσσες της Αμερικής. Η κοινή εργασία περιελάμβανε δύο ανεξάρτητες διαδρομές και οι συμμετέχοντες υπέβαλαν συστήματα μηχανικής μετάφρασης για έως και δέκα αυτόχθονες γλώσσες. Συνολικά, συμμετείχαν οκτώ ομάδες με συνολικά 214 υποβολές. Παρέχουμε εκπαιδευτικά σύνολα που αποτελούνται από δεδομένα που συλλέγονται από διάφορες πηγές, καθώς και χειροκίνητα μεταφρασμένες προτάσεις για τα σετ ανάπτυξης και δοκιμών. Παρουσιάστηκε επίσης επίσημη βάση αναφοράς εκπαιδευμένη σε αυτά τα δεδομένα. Οι υποβολές των ομάδων περιελάμβαναν μια ποικιλία αρχιτεκτονικών, συμπεριλαμβανομένων στατιστικών και νευρωνικών μοντέλων, και για την πλειοψηφία των γλωσσών, πολλές ομάδες ήταν σε θέση να βελτιωθούν σημαντικά σε σχέση με τη βασική βάση. Τα συστήματα με τις καλύτερες επιδόσεις πέτυχαν 12.97 χρF υψηλότερα από τη βασική γραμμή, όταν μετρήθηκαν κατά μέσο όρο σε όλες τις γλώσσες.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a tanulmány bemutatja az amerikai őslakos nyelvek nyílt gépi fordításáról szóló 2021-es megosztott feladat eredményeit. A közös feladat két független számot tartalmazott, a résztvevők pedig legfeljebb 10 őshonos nyelvre nyújtottak be gépi fordítási rendszert. Összességében 8 csapat vett részt, összesen 214 pályázattal. Különböző forrásokból gyűjtött adatokból álló képzési készleteket, valamint manuálisan lefordított mondatokat biztosítottunk a fejlesztési és tesztkészletekhez. Ezekre az adatokra vonatkozóan képzett hivatalos kiindulási pontot is benyújtottak. A csapatok benyújtása különböző architektúrákat tartalmazott, beleértve a statisztikai és neurális modelleket is, és a nyelvek többségében sok csapat képes volt jelentősen javulni a kiinduláshoz képest. A legjobb teljesítményű rendszerek 12,97 ChrF-t értek el a kiindulási értéknél, ha nyelvenként átlagosan értékelték.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დოკუმენტის შემდეგ 2021 წლის გარეშე ამერიკაში გახსნა მაქსინური თარგუმარების შემდეგ გარეშე. საზოგადოებული დავალება იყო ორი განსაზოგადოებული სიტყვები, და მოწყობილობელი მაქინის გაგრძელების სისტემი 10 ენაზე. ყველაფერად, 8 ჯგუფი გაყოფილი 214 გაყოფილებებით. ჩვენ განვიყენეთ სტრიქციის სრულები, რომლებიც განსხვავებული წიგნიდან დაიყენებული მონაცემები, რომლებიც პირდაპირად განვითარების და ტესტის სრულების შესა ამ მონაცემებზე უფრო მეტსალური ფესტური ხაზი იყო. კომპუნეციები განსაზღვრებულია განსხვავებული არქტიქტურები, რომელიც ორივე სტატისტიკალური და ნეიროლური მოდელები, და უფრო მეტი ენათებისთვის, ბევრი კომპუნეტები შეუ ნაი-ეჲბპთრვ ოპაგთრვლნთ ჟთჟრვმთ ეჲჟრигნაჳა 12,97 კპყტ ოჲ-დჲლვმთ ჲრ ბაჱლთნთწ, კჲდარჲ ჟპვღნაჳა ენვჱთრვ.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_mk>Овој весник ги претставува резултатите од Соделената задача 2021 за отворен машински превед за домородните јазици на Америка. Според заедничката задача беа две независни траги и учесниците поднесоа машински преведувачки системи за до 10 домородни јазици. Вкупно, 8 тимови учествуваа со вкупно 214 поднесувања. Ние обезбедивме обуки кои се состојат од податоци собрани од различни извори, како и рачно преведени реченици за развојот и тестовите. Исто така, беше обезбедена официјална основа обучена за овие податоци. Предлозите на тимот имаа различни архитектури, вклучувајќи ги и статистичките и нервните модели, и за повеќето јазици, многу тимови беа во можност значително да се подобрат во однос на основата. Најдобрите системи постигнаа 12,97 ХРФ повисоко од основната вредност, кога се проценуваат меѓу јазиците.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз 2021 жылы Америка тілдерінің Open Machine аудармасының ортақ тапсырманың нәтижесін көрсетеді. Ортақ тапсырманың екі тәуелсіз жолы болды, және қатысушылар 10 тілдерге дейін машинаны аудару жүйелерін жіберді. Жалпы, 8 топтар 214 жіберіліміне қатысу үшін қатысушы болды. Біз әртүрлі көзінен жинақталған деректерді, және қолмен жасау және сынақтар жинақтарына аударылған мәліметтерді қолданып бердік. Бұл деректерге оқылған официалдық негізгі сызық келтірілді. Топтар архитектураларды бірнеше архитектураларды көрсетті, статистикалық мен невралдық моделдері және тілдердің көпшілігі үшін көптеген топтар негізгі сызыққа көп жақсарту мүмкін болды. Ең жақсы орындалатын жүйелер негізгі жолдан 12,97 кр. ф. ф. жүйелерді орташа тілдерде орташа жеткізгенде.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Kertas ini memperkenalkan hasil Tugas Berkongsi 2021 untuk Terjemahan Mesin Buka untuk Bahasa Indigenous Amerika. Tugas berkongsi mengandungi dua trek independen, dan peserta menghantar sistem terjemahan mesin untuk sehingga 10 bahasa asli. Overall, 8 teams participated with a total of 214 submissions.  Kami menyediakan set latihan yang mengandungi data yang dikumpulkan dari berbagai sumber, serta kalimat terjemahan secara manual untuk set pembangunan dan ujian. Pangkalan dasar rasmi yang dilatih pada data ini juga diberikan. Penghantaran pasukan mengandungi pelbagai arkitektur, termasuk model statistik dan saraf, dan untuk kebanyakan bahasa, banyak pasukan mampu memperbaiki secara konsideratif atas asas. Sistem prestasi terbaik mencapai 12.97 ChrF lebih tinggi dari asas, apabila rata-rata dalam bahasa.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo presenta i risultati del compito condiviso 2021 sulla traduzione automatica aperta per le lingue indigene delle Americhe. Il compito condiviso comprendeva due tracce indipendenti e i partecipanti hanno presentato sistemi di traduzione automatica per un massimo di 10 lingue indigene. Complessivamente, 8 squadre hanno partecipato con un totale di 214 candidature. Abbiamo fornito set di formazione costituiti da dati raccolti da varie fonti, nonché frasi tradotte manualmente per lo sviluppo e i set di test. È stata inoltre fornita una base ufficiale addestrata su questi dati. Le presentazioni dei team presentavano una varietà di architetture, inclusi modelli statistici e neurali, e per la maggior parte dei linguaggi, molti team sono stati in grado di migliorare notevolmente rispetto al basale. I sistemi più performanti hanno raggiunto 12,97 ChrF in più rispetto al basale, una media tra le lingue.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ 2021 പങ്കാളിയാക്കപ്പെട്ട ട ടാസ്കിന്‍റെ ഫലങ്ങള്‍ പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്നു The shared task featured two independent tracks, and participants submitted machine translation systems for up to 10 indigenous languages.  മൊത്തം 8 ടീം 214 കീഴടങ്ങളോടൊപ്പം പങ്കുചേര്‍ന്നു. വിവിധ സ്രോതസ്സുകളില്‍ നിന്നും ശേഖരിക്കപ്പെട്ട വിവരങ്ങളുടെ കൂട്ടത്തിലുള്ള ട്രെയിനിങ്ങള്‍ പരിശീലന സജ്ജീകരണങ ഈ വിവരങ്ങളില്‍ പഠിപ്പിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഒരു ഓഫിക്കല്‍ ബേസ്ലൈന്‍ പരിശീലനം ലഭ്യമായിരുന്നു. ടീമിന്റെ സജ്ജീകരണങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് വ്യത്യസ്ത്രീകങ്ങള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയിരിക്കുന്നു. സ്റ്റാസ്റ്റിസ്റ്റിക്കലും ന്യൂറല്‍ മോഡലുകളും കൂടിയിരിക്ക ഏറ്റവും നല്ല പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്ന സിസ്റ്റം 12.97 ക്രിസ്റ്റ് ബെസ്റ്റ്ലൈനിലേക്കാള്‍ ഉയര്‍ന്നു. ഭാഷകള</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente pateikiami 2021 m. bendros užduoties dėl atviro automatinio vertimo vietinėms Amerikos kalboms rezultatai. Bendroje užduotyje dalyvavo du nepriklausomi keliai ir dalyviai pateikė mašinų vertimo sistemas iki 10 vietinių kalbų. Iš viso dalyvavo 8 komandos, iš viso pateikusios 214 paraiškas. We provided training sets consisting of data collected from various sources, as well as manually translated sentences for the development and test sets.  Taip pat buvo pateikta oficiali bazinė informacija, parengta remiantis šiais duomenimis. Ekipai pateikė įvairias architektūras, įskaitant ir statistinius, ir nervinius modelius, o daugumoje kalbų daugelis komandų galėjo gerokai pagerinti palyginti su pradiniu lygiu. Geriausių rezultatų sistemų vidurkis buvo 12,97 ChrF didesnis už pradinę.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jippreżenta r-riżultati tal-Kompitu Konġunt tal-2021 dwar it-Traduzzjoni Miftuħa tal-Makkinarju għal-Lingwi Indiġeni tal-Amerika. Il-kompitu kondiviż kellu żewġ binarji indipendenti, u l-parteċipanti ssottomettew sistemi ta’ traduzzjoni bil-magna għal sa 10 lingwi indiġeni. B’mod ġenerali, 8 timijiet ipparteċipaw b’total ta’ 214 sottomissjoni. Aħna pprovdejna settijiet ta’ taħriġ li jikkonsistu minn dejta miġbura minn diversi sorsi, kif ukoll sentenzi tradotti manwalment għall-iżvilupp u settijiet tat-testijiet. Ġiet ipprovduta wkoll linja bażi uffiċjali mħarrġa dwar din id-dejta. Is-sottomissjonijiet tat-tim kienu jinkludu varjetà ta’ arkitetturi, inklużi kemm mudelli statistiċi kif ukoll newrali, u għall-maġġoranza tal-lingwi, ħafna timijiet kienu kapaċi jtejbu konsiderevolment fuq il-linja bażi. Is-sistemi bl-aħjar prestazzjoni kisbu 12.97 ChrF ogħla mil-linja bażi, meta l-medja kienet bejn il-lingwi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>W artykule przedstawiono wyniki wspólnego zadania dotyczącego otwartego tłumaczenia maszynowego dla języków rdzennych Ameryk. Wspólne zadanie obejmowało dwa niezależne ścieżki, a uczestnicy przesłali systemy tłumaczenia maszynowego dla maksymalnie dziesięciu języków rdzennych. Ogólnie rzecz biorąc, osiem zespołów uczestniczyło z łącznie 214 zgłoszeń. Dostarczyliśmy zestawy szkoleniowe składające się z danych zebranych z różnych źródeł, a także ręcznie przetłumaczonych zdań do zestawów deweloperskich i testowych. Przedstawiono również oficjalną bazę podstawową przeszkoloną na podstawie tych danych. Zgłoszenia zespołów obejmowały różne architektury, w tym modele statystyczne i neuronowe, a w przypadku większości języków wiele zespołów udało się znacznie poprawić w porównaniu z bazową. Najlepiej wydajne systemy osiągnęły 12.97 ChrF wyższy niż baza wyjściowa, gdy uśredniono w różnych językach.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare prezintă rezultatele misiunii partajate 2021 privind traducerea automată deschisă pentru limbile indigene din America. Sarcina comună a cuprins două piese independente, iar participanții au prezentat sisteme de traducere automată pentru până la 10 limbi indigene. În total, 8 echipe au participat cu un total de 214 de depuneri. Am furnizat seturi de instruire constând din date colectate din diferite surse, precum și propoziții traduse manual pentru seturile de dezvoltare și testare. De asemenea, a fost furnizată o bază oficială instruită pe aceste date. Depunerile echipei au prezentat o varietate de arhitecturi, inclusiv modele statistice și neurale, iar pentru majoritatea limbilor, multe echipe au reușit să se îmbunătățească considerabil față de nivelul de referință. Cele mai performante sisteme au obținut 12,97 ChrF mai mari decât valoarea inițială, atunci când se calculează media între limbi.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir predstavlja rezultate zajedničkog zadatka 2021. godine o prevodu otvorenog mašine za Indijanske jezike Amerike. Podijeljeni zadatak je uključio dva nezavisnog traga, i učesnici su podnijeli sisteme prevoda mašine za do 10 jezika korisnika. U ukupnom slučaju, 8 timova sudjelovalo je u ukupnom broju 214 podataka. Mi smo pružili komplete obuke koje sastoje od podataka koji su skupljeni iz različitih izvora, kao i ručno prevedene rečenice za razvoj i testove. Takođe je pružena zvanična osnovna linija obučena na ovim podacima. Predloženja tima ukazala je na razne arhitekture, uključujući i statističke i neuralne modele, i za većinu jezika, mnoge timove su bile u mogućnosti da značajno poboljšaju na osnovnoj liniji. Najbolji izvršni sistem postigao je 12,97 krF viši od početne linije, kada je prosječan na jezicima.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ පත්තුව පෙන්වන්නේ 2021 සාමාන්‍ය වැඩක් අරින්දු භාෂාවල් සඳහා අරින්දු මැෂින් භාෂාව සඳහා විශේෂ සමාගත වැඩක් විශේෂයෙන් ස්ථාවත් පැත්තක් දෙකක් තියෙනවා, සමාගත්තකාරියෝ පද්ධතියේ පද්ධතිය පද්ධත සම්පූර්ණයෙන්, කණ්ඩායම් 8 කණ්ඩායම් එක්ක 214 පිළිගන්න එක්ක සම්පූර්ණයෙන්. අපි ප්‍රශ්නය සම්බන්ධ කරලා තියෙන්නේ විවිධ ප්‍රශ්නය සහ පරීක්ෂණ සම්බන්ධ කරලා තියෙන දත්ත සංගුණ මේ තොරතුරු වලින් ප්‍රධානික අධ්‍යාතික ප්‍රධානයක් තියෙනවා. කණ්ඩායම් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් විවිධ ස්ථාපනයක් තියෙනවා, ස්ථාපනය සහ න්‍යූරල් මෝඩේල් දෙන්නම්, වඩා භාෂාවට වඩා ගොඩක් කණ හොඳම වැඩ කරන්න පද්ධතිය 12.97 ක්රෝෆ් විශ්වාසයෙන් වැඩියි, භාෂාවක් වලින් විශ්වාසයෙන් වැඩිය</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Kanu warqaddan wuxuu soo saaraa resultinta shaqada la sharciyey 2021 oo ku saabsan turjumidda furan machine for indigenous languages of Americas. Shaqoda la qaybsadaa waxay leeyihiin laba kooxooyin oo xor ah, kuwa ka qeybqaadayna waxay u soo dhiibeen nidaamka turjumidda machine ee ugu badnaan 10 luuqadood oo indigenous ah. Inta caadiga ah 8 koox ayaa ka qeybqaaday dhammaan 214 submissions. Waxaan diyaarinay koorasyo waxbarasho ah oo ka mid ah macluumaad laga soo ururiyey qaarkood, sidoo kale xarumo lagu turjumay horumarinta iyo imtixaanka. Sidoo kale waxaa la bixiyaa shabakadda rasmi ah oo lagu tababaray macluumaadkan. Team submissions featured a variety of architectures, including both statistical and neural models, and for the majority of languages, many teams were able to considerably improve over the baseline.  Isticmaalka ugu fiican ee sameynta waxay gaadhay 12.97 ChrF oo ka sareeya qoraalka hoose, marka lagu qiyaasay luuqadaha oo dhan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас 2021 оны Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas хувилбарын үр дүнг харуулдаг. Хоёр тогтнолтой загварыг харуулсан бөгөөд оролцогчдын оролцогчдын тулд 10 хэл хүртэл машин орчуулах системийг тавьсан. Эцэст нь 8 баг 214 хүмүүст оролцсон. Бид олон эх үүсвэрээс цуглуулагдсан өгөгдлийн багц болон хөгжлийн болон шалгалтын хэлбэрээс гараар орчуулагдсан өгөгдлийн багц байгуулагдсан. Энэ мэдээлэл дээр сургалтын үндсэн үндсэн шугам ч мөн өгсөн. Баг дамжуулалт нь олон архитектурууд, статистик, мэдрэлийн загварууд болон ихэнх хэл дээр олон баг суурь шугам дээр маш их сайжруулж чадна. Хамгийн сайн үйлдвэрлэлтийн систем нь суурь шулуунаас 12.97 КрФ өндөртэй болсон.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats presenterar resultaten av 2021 delad uppgift om öppen maskinöversättning för inhemska språk i Amerika. Den delade uppgiften innehöll två oberoende spår och deltagarna skickade in maskinöversättningssystem för upp till tio inhemska språk. Totalt deltog 8 lag med totalt 214 bidrag. Vi tillhandahöll utbildningsuppsättningar bestående av data som samlats in från olika källor samt manuellt översatta meningar för utveckling och testuppsättningar. En officiell baslinje utbildad på dessa data tillhandahölls också. Teaminlämningar innehöll en mängd olika arkitekturer, inklusive både statistiska och neurala modeller, och för de flesta språk kunde många team avsevärt förbättra jämfört med baslinjen. De bäst presterande systemen uppnådde 12,97 ChrF högre än baslinjen, om medelvärdet var över olika språk.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret viser resultatet av den delte oppgåva 2021 på Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas. Den delte oppgåva viste to uavhengige spor, og deltakarane sendte maskinsomsetjingssystemet for opp til 10 indirekte språk. Overalt delta 8 grupper med totalt 214 tillegg. Vi oppgav opplæringssett som inneheld data samla frå ulike kilder, og manuelt omsett setningar for utviklinga og testsett. Ein offisiell grunnlinje trengt på denne dataen var også tilgjengeleg. Gruppeopplysningar viste fleire arkitektur, inkludert både statistiske og neuralmodeller, og for dei fleste språk var mange grupper i stand til å forbetra stort på baselinja. Den beste utføringssystemene har oppnådd 12,97 ChrF høgare enn baseline, når det gjennomsnittet på språk.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தின் 2021 பகிர்ந்த பணியின் முடிவுகளை அமெரிக்காவின் திறந்த இயந்திரம் மொழிபெயர்ப்பில் கூடுகிறது. பங்கிடப்பட்ட பணியில் இரண்டு சுதந்திரமான தடங்கள் குறிப்பிட்டது, மற்றும் பங்கீட்டாளர்கள் 10 க்கு மேல் உள்ள மொழிகளுக மொத்தமாக, 8 குழுக்கள் 214 கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. நாம் பயிற்சி அமைப்புகளை வழங்கினோம் பல மூலங்களிலிருந்து சேகரிக்கப்பட்ட தரவு இந்த தரவுகளில் பயிற்சி செய்யப்பட்ட ஒரு வழக்கமான அடிப்படைக்கோடு வழங்கப்பட்டது. குழு வழங்குகள் பல்வேறு கட்டுரைகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, புள்ளிவிவரம் மற்றும் நரம்பு மாதிரிகளையும் சேர்த்துள்ளது, பெரும்பாலான மொழிகளுக்கு, பல சிறந்த செயல்படுத்தும் அமைப்புகள் 12.97 கிரிஎஃப் அடிப்படை வரிசையை விட அதிகமாக அடைந்தது, சராசரி மொழிகள் மூலம்.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>This paper presents the results of the 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas. مشترک کام نے دو سفارشی ٹراک کو شامل کیا اور مشترک نے 10 زبانوں تک ماشین ترجمہ سیسٹم کو ملا دیا۔ عملہ میں، 8 ٹیموں نے 214 مسلمانوں کے ساتھ شریک کیا۔ ہم نے تدریس سٹ کی جو مختلف سروروں سے جمع کئے گئے ہیں، اور اپنا تدریس سٹ کے مطابق مطابق تدریس کیا گیا ہے. اس ڈیٹا پر آموزش کی ایک رسمی بنسلین بھی دی گئی۔ تیم کے مطابق ایک طرح کی معماری شامل ہوئی تھی، دونوں ایسٹیسٹی اور نیورل مدل، اور بہت سی زبانوں کے لئے بہت سی تیم بنیاس لین پر بہت اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اضافہ کر سکتے تھے. جب زبانوں میں متوسط ہوا تو سب سے بہترین عملہ نظام 12.97 کریفوں سے بلند ہوگئے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu sahifa 2021 shartlangan vazifaning natijalarini Amerika uchun ochiq mashina tarjima qiladi. Boʻlishilgan vazifa esa ikkita boshqaruv yo'llar bilan ishlatiladi, va qismilar 10 ta taqdim tillardan mashina tarjima tizimini qoʻllangan. Umumiy, 8 guruhi 214 muammolar bilan birga ega bo'lgan. We provided training sets consisting of data collected from various sources, as well as manually translated sentences for the development and test sets.  Ushbu maʼlumotda faqat bir rasmi bazal satri qoʻllangan. Guruh taʼminlovchilari, statistical va neyrol modellari, va ko'pchilik tillar uchun ko'pchilik guruhlar asosiy satrlarida juda yaxshi o'zgarishga ega. Bu eng yaxshi bajarish tizimi baseline sohasida 12.97 KrF yuqoriga olingan, har xil tillar soni o'rtasida.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này trình bày kết quả của công việc chia sẻ sẻ về máy mở cho nước Mỹ. Nhiệm vụ chia sẻ gồm hai đường ray độc lập, và những người tham gia đã gửi dịch vụ máy cho đến mười ngôn ngữ bản xứ. Tổng kết, 8 các đội đã tham gia một tập tin tuyệt đối 94. Chúng tôi cung cấp các tập tin gồm dữ liệu thu thập từ các nguồn khác nhau, và các câu được dịch bằng tay cho các bộ phát triển và thử nghiệm. Một cơ sở cơ bản chính thức đào tạo về dữ liệu này đã được cung cấp. Cấu trúc của nhóm chứa nhiều kiến trúc, bao gồm cả các mô hình thống kê và thần kinh, và phần lớn ngôn ngữ, nhiều đội đã có thể cải thiện đáng kể qua cơ sở cơ bản. Những hệ thống trình diễn tốt nhất đạt đến 12.97 ChrF cao hơn so với thực địa, khi giữa các ngôn ngữ.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия представя резултатите от съвместната задача за отворен машинен превод за местни езици на Америка през 2021 г. Споделената задача включваше две независими песни, а участниците представиха системи за машинен превод за до 10 местни езика. Общо 8 отбора участваха с общо 214 кандидатури. Предоставяме тренировъчни комплекти, състоящи се от данни, събрани от различни източници, както и ръчно преведени изречения за разработката и тестовите комплекти. Предоставена е и официална база, обучена на тези данни. Отборните предложения включват различни архитектури, включително както статистически, така и неврални модели, а за повечето езици много екипи успяха значително да се подобрят в сравнение с базовата линия. Най-добре представящите системи постигат 12,97 по-високи от изходните, когато се изчисляват средно между езиците.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel presenteert de resultaten van de 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation voor inheemse talen van Amerika. De gedeelde taak bestond uit twee onafhankelijke tracks, en de deelnemers dienden machinevertaalsystemen in voor maximaal tien inheemse talen. Over het algemeen namen acht teams deel met in totaal 214 inzendingen. We leverden trainingssets bestaande uit gegevens verzameld uit verschillende bronnen, evenals handmatig vertaalde zinnen voor de ontwikkel- en testsets. Er werd ook een officiële basislijn verstrekt die op deze gegevens is getraind. Team inzendingen hadden een verscheidenheid aan architecturen, waaronder zowel statistische als neurale modellen, en voor de meeste talen waren veel teams in staat om aanzienlijk te verbeteren ten opzichte van de baseline. De best presterende systemen bereikten 12.97 ChrF hoger dan baseline, wanneer gemiddeld in verschillende talen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir predstavlja rezultate zajedničkog zadatka 2021. godine o prevodu stroja za Indijanske jezike Amerike. Podijeljeni zadatak uključio je dvije nezavisne tragove i učesnici podnijeli su sustave za prevod strojeva do 10 jezika korijena. Ukupno, 8 timova sudjelovalo su u ukupnom ukupu 214 podataka. Mi smo pružili komplete obuke koje sastoje od podataka prikupljenih iz različitih izvora, kao i ručno prevedene rečenice za razvoj i testove. Predložena je i zvanična početna linija obučena na ovim podacima. Predloženja tima uključivala su razne arhitekture, uključujući i statističke i neuralne modele, i za većinu jezika, mnoge timove su mogle znatno poboljšati na početnoj liniji. Najbolji izvodnji sustavi postigli su 12,97 ChrF viši od početne linije, kada su prosječni na jezicima.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Dette papir præsenterer resultaterne af 2021 delt opgave om åben maskinoversættelse for oprindelige sprog i Amerika. Den fælles opgave omfattede to uafhængige spor, og deltagerne indsendte maskinoversættelsessystemer til op til 10 oprindelige sprog. Samlet set deltog 8 hold med i alt 214 indsendelser. Vi leverede træningssæt bestående af data indsamlet fra forskellige kilder samt manuelt oversatte sætninger til udviklings- og testsættene. Der blev også fremlagt en officiel baseline uddannet på disse data. Teamindsendelser indeholdt en række forskellige arkitekturer, herunder både statistiske og neurale modeller, og for de fleste sprog var mange teams i stand til at forbedre sig betydeligt i forhold til baseline. De bedst ydende systemer opnåede 12,97 ChrF højere end baseline, når gennemsnittet måles på tværs af sprog.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag stellt die Ergebnisse der "Gemeinsamen Task on Open Machine Translation for Indigenous Languages of the Americas" vor. Die gemeinsame Aufgabe umfasste zwei unabhängige Tracks, und die Teilnehmer übermittelten maschinelle Übersetzungssysteme für bis zu zehn einheimische Sprachen. Insgesamt nahmen acht Teams mit insgesamt 214 Einreichungen teil. Wir stellten Trainingssets zur Verfügung, bestehend aus Daten aus verschiedenen Quellen, sowie manuell übersetzten Sätzen für die Entwicklungs- und Testsets. Außerdem wurde ein offizielles Basismaterial bereitgestellt, das auf diesen Daten geschult wurde. Die eingereichten Teams zeigten eine Vielzahl von Architekturen, einschließlich statistischer und neuronaler Modelle, und für die meisten Sprachen konnten sich viele Teams gegenüber der Baseline erheblich verbessern. Die leistungsfähigsten Systeme erreichten 12.97 ChrF höher als die Basiswerte, wenn sie sprachübergreifend gemittelt wurden.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini memperlihatkan hasil dari tugas terbagi 2021 tentang Penerjemahan Mesin terbuka untuk bahasa asli Amerika. Tugas berbagi memiliki dua jejak independen, dan peserta mengirimkan sistem terjemahan mesin untuk sampai 10 bahasa asli. Secara umum, 8 tim berpartisipasi dengan total 214 pengiriman. Kami menyediakan set pelatihan yang terdiri dari data yang dikumpulkan dari berbagai sumber, serta kalimat terjemahan secara manual untuk perkembangan dan set tes. Sebuah dasar dasar resmi yang dilatih pada data ini juga diberikan. Pemberian tim mengandung berbagai arsitektur, termasuk model statistik dan saraf, dan untuk kebanyakan bahasa, banyak tim mampu meningkat lebih jauh dari dasar. Sistem prestasi terbaik mencapai 12,97 ChrF lebih tinggi dari dasar, ketika rata-rata di berbagai bahasa.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Gazeti hili linaonyesha matokeo ya kazi za mwaka 2021 zilizoshirikishwa kwenye Tafsiri ya Open Mashine kwa Lugha za wenyeji wa Marekani. Kazi hiyo ilishirikishwa ilionyesha njia mbili huru, na washiriki waliwasilisha mfumo wa utafsiri wa mashine kwa ajili ya lugha 10 za wenyeji. Kwa ujumla, timu 8 walishiriki na jumla ya ujumbe wa 214. Tulifanya seti za mafunzo ikiwa ni pamoja na taarifa zilizokusanywa kutoka vyanzo mbalimbali, pamoja na sentensi zilizotafsiriwa kwa mikononi kwa ajili ya maendeleo na seti za jaribio. Mtandao rasmi aliyefundishwa kwenye taarifa hizi pia ulitolewa. Vitumizi vya timu vilionyesha majengo mbalimbali, ikiwa ni pamoja na mifano ya takwimu na neura, na kwa lugha nyingi, timu nyingi zilikuwa na uwezo wa kuboresha zaidi kwenye mitandao ya msingi. Mifumo bora ya kufanya kazi ilifanikiwa KrF 12.97 zaidi ya msingi, wakati wa wastani katika lugha mbalimbali.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 2021년 아메리카 원주민 언어 개방식 기계번역 공유 임무의 결과를 소개한다.공유 임무는 두 개의 독립된 궤도를 포함하고 참가자들은 10가지에 달하는 원주민 언어의 기계 번역 시스템을 제출했다.총 8개 팀이 참여해 214건의 의견서를 제출했다.우리는 각종 출처에서 수집한 데이터로 구성된 교육집과 개발 및 테스트집에 사용되는 수동 번역 문장을 제공합니다.이 데이터에 대한 공식 기초 교육도 제공했다.단체가 제출한 내용은 각종 구조를 포함하고 통계모델과 신경모델을 포함하며 대다수 언어에 대해 많은 단체들이 기선을 바탕으로 현저한 개선을 할 수 있다.전체 언어가 평균적일 때 가장 성능이 좋은 시스템은 베이스라인보다 12.97ChrF 높습니다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ نتایج کار مشترک ۲۰۱۲ در مورد ترجمه ماشین باز برای زبان Indigenous of the Americas را نشان می دهد. وظیفه مشترک دو رد مستقل و شرکتگران سیستم‌های ترجمه ماشین را برای ۱۰ زبان اصلی ارائه کردند. در کل، ۸ تیم با کل 214 تسلیم شرکت کردند. ما مجموعه آموزش را از اطلاعات که از منبع مختلف جمع شده‌اند، و جمله‌ها را به دستی برای توسعه و آزمایش تغییر دادیم. یک خط پایین رسمی که روی این داده آموزش داده شده است همچنین داده شد. تسلیم‌های تیم‌ها از طریق معماری‌های مختلف را مشخص می‌کردند، شامل هر دو مدل‌های آماری و عصبی، و برای بیشتر زبان‌ها، بسیاری از تیم‌ها توانستند در خط پایین زیادی بهتر کنند. بهترین سیستم‌های اجرایی ۱۲.۹۷ کرف بالاتر از خط بنیادی رسید، زمانی که در طول زبانها متوسط می‌شد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument paraqet rezultatet e detyrës së përbashkët të 2021 për përkthimin e hapur të makinave për gjuhët indígene të Amerikës. Detyra e përbashkët paraqiti dy gjurmë të pavarura dhe pjesëmarrësit paraqitën sisteme përkthimi automatik për deri në 10 gjuhë vendase. Në përgjithësi, 8 ekipe morën pjesë me një total prej 214 paraqitjesh. Ne ofruam grupe trajnimi që përbëhen nga të dhënat e mbledhura nga burime të ndryshme, si dhe nga fjalët e përkthyera manualisht për grupet e zhvillimit dhe testimit. U ofrua gjithashtu një bazë zyrtare e trajnuar në këto të dhëna. Paraqitjet e ekipit paraqitën një shumëllojshmëri arkitekturash, duke përfshirë si modelet statistikë ashtu edhe neuronale dhe për shumicën e gjuhëve, shumë ekipe ishin në gjendje të përmirësoheshin konsiderueshëm mbi bazën. Sistemet me performancë më të mirë arritën 12.97 krof më të lartë se baza, kur mesatarisht përtej gjuhëve.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz 2021-nji ýylyň Aç Maşynyň Amerika dilleriniň ýerli dilleri üçin Maşynyň terjime edilmegi barada paýlaşan zadyň netijesini görkezýär. Paýlaşan täblisaň iki seresap hatlary bardy we çykyşlyklar 10 ýerli dillere üçin maşynyň terjime sistemlerini belledi. Halkara 8 topar 214 gönderme bilen chikanchasy boldy. Biz dürli çeşitli çeşmelerden toplanýan maglumatlardan we çykyş we testler üçin el terjime edilen cümleleri tasarryldyk. Bu maglumaty üçin resmi tabanly hatlar hem bereldi. Topar görkezilişi birnäçe arhitekturlary, statistik we neural modelleri we köp diller üçin köp topar baseline üstünde gowylaşdyryp bilýärdi. Iň gowy çykyş sistemalary baseline derejesinden 12,97 Çrf ýokaryna ýetdi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>ይህ ገጽ በ2021 የተሰራጨውን ስራዎችን ለየአሜሪካ የአገሪካ ቋንቋዎች ትርጓሜ ላይ የተከፈተ የመሳሳይ ትርጉም ያሳያል፡፡ የተካፈሉት ስራ ሁለት ነፃ የግንኙነት ግንቦች እና ተጋሪዎቹ ከ10 የአገሩ ቋንቋዎች በላይ የመሻሻሻን ትርጉም ስርዓቶች ሰጥተዋል፡፡ በጠቅላላ፣ 8 ቡድን በ214 ውጤቶች ላይ ተጋጠሙ፡፡ ከልዩ ዓይነቶች የተሰበሰቡትን ዳታዎችን እና ለመፍጠር እና ለመፈተና ተርጓሚዎችን በእጃቸው የተዘረጉትን ተርጓሚዎች ሰጥተናል፡፡ የዚህ ዳታ የተጠቃሚ ባለሥልጣናት መደገፊያውን ደግሞ አቀረበ፡፡ Team submissions featured a variety of architectures, including both statistical and neural models, and for the majority of languages, many teams were able to considerably improve over the baseline.  የተሻለ የሥርዓት ስርዓት 12.97 ክሪፍ በቋንቋ ቋንቋዎች ላይ በተለየ ጊዜ ከፍተኛ ሆኖ አግኝቷል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier stel die resultate van die 2021 Gedeelde Taak op Open Masjien Vertaling vir Indigenous Taal van die Amerika. Die gedeelde taak het twee onafhanklike snitte gedeel, en deelnaders het masjien vertalingsstelsels voorgestuur vir tot by 10 indigenoese tale. Totaal het 8 teams gedeel met 'n totaal van 214 onderskrifte. Ons verskaf onderwerp stelle wat bestaan van data versamel van verskeie bronne, en ook hand vertaal setinge vir die ontwikkeling en toets stelle. 'n Ofisiele basislien wat op hierdie data opgelei is is ook verskaf. Skep onderstellings het 'n verskillende arkitektuur gedeel, insluitend beide statistiese en neurale modele, en vir die meeste tale was baie teame in staat om te beter oor die basislien. Die beste uitvoerde stelsels het 12,97 ChrF hoër as basislien bereik, wanneer gemiddelde oor tale.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Այս հոդվածը ներկայացնում է Ամերիկայի բնական լեզուների բաց մեքենային թարգմանման 2021 թվականի ընդհանուր հանձնարարության արդյունքները: Այս ընդհանուր խնդիրը ներկայացրեց երկու անկախ ճանապարհ, և մասնակիցները ներկայացրեցին մեքենային թարգմանման համակարգեր մինչև 10 բնիկ լեզուների համար: Ընդհանուր առմամբ, 8 թիմ մասնակցել է 214 ներկայացումների հետ: Մենք տրամադրեցինք ուսուցման համակարգեր, որոնք կազմված էին տարբեր աղբյուրներից հավաքված տվյալներից, ինչպես նաև ձեռքով թարգմանված նախադասություններից զարգացման և փորձարկումների համակարգերի համար: Այս տվյալների վրա նաև սովորեցված պաշտոնական հիմք տրամադրվեց: Team submissions featured a variety of architectures, including both statistical and neural models, and for the majority of languages, many teams were able to considerably improve over the baseline.  Ամենալավ արդյունավետ համակարգերը հասան 12.97 ChrF-ից ավելի բարձր, քան հիմնական համակարգերը, երբ միջինը տարբեր լեզուներում էր:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটি ২০২১ সালের শেয়ার করা কাজের ফলাফল দেখাচ্ছে আমেরিকার আদিবাসী ভাষার জন্য উন্মুক্ত মেশিন অনুবাদের উপর। শেয়ার কর্মটি দুটি স্বাধীন ট্র্যাক দিয়েছে এবং অংশগ্রহণকারীরা ১০ জন আদিবাসী ভাষার জন্য মেশিন অনুবাদ সিস্টেম জ সাধারণত ৮ টি দল ২১৪ টি প্রতিযোগিতায় অংশগ্রহণ করেছে। আমরা প্রশিক্ষণের সেট প্রদান করেছি যা বিভিন্ন সূত্র থেকে সংগ্রহ করা তথ্যের মধ্যে রয়েছে, আর নিজেদের উন্নয়ন ও পরীক্ষা সেটের এই তথ্যে প্রশিক্ষিত একটি অফিসিয়াল বেসেলাইন প্রশিক্ষণ প্রদান করা হয়েছে। গ্রুপের প্রতিষ্ঠানগুলোতে বিভিন্ন প্রতিষ্ঠান, যার মধ্যে রয়েছে পরিসংখ্যান এবং নিউরেল মডেল এবং বেশীরভাগ ভাষার জন্য অনেক দল বেসেলাইনের বিভিন সবচেয়ে ভালো প্রদর্শনী সিস্টেম বেসাইলাইনের চেয়ে ১২. ৭৭ ক্রিএফ পেয়েছে, যখন সাধারণ ভাষায় বেড়ে গেছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir predstavlja rezultate zajedničkog zadatka 2021. godine o prevodu otvorenog mašine za Indijanske jezike Amerike. Podijeljeni zadatak je uključio dvije nezavisne tragove, a učesnici su podnijeli sisteme prevoda mašine za do 10 jezika korisnika. U ukupnom slučaju, 8 timova sudjelovalo su u ukupnom iznosu 214 podataka. Mi smo pružili komplete obuke koje sastoje od podataka koji su skupljeni iz različitih izvora, kao i ručno prevedene rečenice za razvoj i testove. Također je pružena zvanična osnovna linija obučena na ovim podacima. Predloženja tima uključivala je razne arhitekture, uključujući i statističke i neuralne modele, i za većinu jezika, mnoge timove su mogle znatno poboljšati na početnoj liniji. Najbolji izvršni sistem postigao je 12,97 ChrF viši od početne linije, kada je prosječan na jezicima.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest article presenta els resultats de la tasca compartida 2021 sobre traducció màquina oberta de llengües indígenes d'Amèrica. La tasca compartida tenia dues pistes independents, i els participants van enviar sistemes de traducció màquina per fins a 10 llengües indígenes. En general, 8 equips van participar amb un total de 214 presentacions. Vam proporcionar conjunts d'entrenament que consisteixen en dades recollides de diverses fonts, com també en frases traduïdes manualment per als conjunts de desenvolupament i prova. També es va proporcionar una base oficial entrenada en aquestes dades. Team submissions featured a variety of architectures, including both statistical and neural models, and for the majority of languages, many teams were able to considerably improve over the baseline.  Els sistemes de millor rendiment van aconseguir 12,97 CRF més alts que el basal, quan la mitjana va ser entre les llengües.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek představuje výsledky sdíleného úkolu 2021 na otevřeném strojovém překladu pro domorodé jazyky Ameriky. Společný úkol obsahoval dvě nezávislé stopy a účastníci předložili systémy strojového překladu až pro deset domorodých jazyků. Celkově se zúčastnilo osm týmů s celkem 214 příspěvky. Poskytli jsme školicí sady sestávající z dat shromážděných z různých zdrojů, stejně jako ručně přeložené věty pro vývojové a testovací sady. Byl rovněž poskytnut oficiální základní základní základní výcvik vyškolený na základě těchto údajů. Týmové příspěvky obsahovaly různé architektury, včetně statistických i neuronových modelů, a pro většinu jazyků se mnoho týmů podařilo výrazně zlepšit oproti základnímu principu. Nejlepší výkonné systémy dosáhly 12.97 ChrF vyšší než základní hodnota, když jsou průměrné napříč jazyky.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt 2021'nin Açıq Makina Çevirməsi üçün Amerika'nın Indijin Dilləri üçün paylaşılan işin sonuçlarını göstərir. Bu paylaşılmış işin iki bağımsız parçasını göstərdi və iştirakçilər 10 yerli dillərə qədər maşına çevirim sistemlərini təyin etdilər. Bütün bunlar, 8 dəstə 214 təbliğ etdi. Biz müxtəlif kaynaqlardan toplanmış məlumatlardan olan təhsil qurmaqlarını və təhsil qurmaqlarını əllə çevirib təhsil etdik. Bu məlumatlarda təhsil edilmiş resmi təhsil də verildi. Tüm təsdiqləyicisi, statistik və nöral modellərin də dahil olmaqla, çoxluğu dillərə çoxluğu üçün çoxlu dəstələr baseline üstündə çox yaxşılıq edə bilərdilər. Ən yaxşı təhsil sistemləri, dillərdə ortalamaq üçün 12,97 ChrF səviyyədən yüksək oldu.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas dokumendis tutvustatakse Ameerika põliskeelte avatud masintõlke jagatud ülesande 2021. aasta tulemusi. Ühine ülesanne hõlmas kahte sõltumatut rada ning osalejad esitasid masintõlke süsteemid kuni kümnele põliseelsele keelele. Kokku osales 8 meeskonda kokku 214 osalejaga. Pakkusime erinevatest allikatest kogutud andmetest koosnevaid koolituskomplekte ning käsitsi tõlgitud lauseid arendus- ja testikomplektide jaoks. Samuti esitati nende andmete põhjal koolitatud ametlik algväärtus. Meeskonna esitatud tööd hõlmasid mitmesugused arhitektuurid, sealhulgas nii statistilised kui ka närvimudelid, ning enamiku keelte puhul suutsid paljud meeskonnad oluliselt paraneda võrreldes lähtetasemega. Kõige paremini toimivad süsteemid saavutasid 12,97 ChrF kõrgema algtasemega võrreldes, kui arvutati keskmiselt keelte vahel.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa esitellään vuoden 2021 yhteisen tehtävän avoimen konekäännöksen tulokset Amerikan alkuperäiskielille. Yhteiseen tehtävään kuului kaksi itsenäistä kappaletta, ja osallistujat toimittivat konekäännösjärjestelmät jopa kymmenelle alkuperäiskielelle. Yhteensä 8 joukkuetta osallistui ja yhteensä 214 hakemusta. Tarjosimme harjoitussarjoja, jotka koostuivat eri lähteistä kerätystä aineistosta sekä manuaalisesti käännettyjä lauseita kehitys- ja testisarjoja varten. Virallinen lähtötilanne, joka oli koulutettu näistä tiedoista, toimitettiin myös. Tiimitiedotukset sisälsivät monenlaisia arkkitehtuureja, mukaan lukien sekä tilastolliset että neuromallit, ja useimpien kielten osalta monet tiimit pystyivät parantamaan huomattavasti lähtötasoon verrattuna. Parhaiten suoriutuvat järjestelmät saavuttivat 12,97 ChrF enemmän kuin lähtötilanne, kun keskiarvo oli eri kielillä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Gambar iki bakal nggawe sawetara tanggal nggawe Mbak nggawe Open Mas Terjamah kanggo Kemerdekaan Karo Mbak kanggo Kemerdekaan kanggo Kemerdekaan Karo Mbak Mbak bener Mulai, 8 Grup mengko karo hal Kasumi Awak dhéwé wis nggawe aturan macem sing nggawe data cokaké sak pernik, lan kabèh dilanjut manut kanggo nggawe aturan kanggo kebebasan lan tentang. offline Grup endimbang ngomong akeh akeh akeh akeh akeh, gambar dadi model sing dadi dadi, lan alah sing dumadhi kanggo langgar, akeh sing takot akeh iso nggawe barang sampeyan sing bisa luwih dumadhi iki. Awak dhéwé sistem sing luwih sing diranggawe 12.1997</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>העיתון הזה מציג את תוצאות המשימה המשותפת של 2021 על התרגום של מכונות פתוחות לשונות מקומיות של אמריקה. המשימה המשותפת הכילה שני עקבות עצמאות, והמשתתפים שלחו מערכות תרגום מכונות עד 10 שפות מקומיות. באופן כללי, 8 קבוצות השתתפו בסך הכל ב-214 הצעות. We provided training sets consisting of data collected from various sources, as well as manually translated sentences for the development and test sets.  גם סימן רשמי מאומן על הנתונים האלה. הוציאות צוות היו מגוון של ארכיטקטורות, כולל גם דוגמנים סטטיסטיים וגם עצביים, וברוב השפות, קבוצות רבות הצליחו להשתפר באופן משמעותי מעל הבסיס. מערכות ההופעה הטובה ביותר השיגו 12.97 ChrF גבוהה יותר מבסיס, כאשר ממוצע בין שפות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>@ info: status Yin aikin da aka raba su haɗi sun ƙayyade hanyõyi biyu masu huru, kuma mãsu haɗuwa sun gabãtar da tsarin translation na mashine dõmin up to 10 languages masu hushi. A jumla, jama'a 8-jama'a sun haɗa da jumla na 214 silunan. We provided training sets consisting of data collected from various sources, as well as manually translated sentences for the development and test sets.  An ba da wani rasmi mai tsari a kan wannan data. Tsarin jumawa na jami na ƙunsa da wasu matsala masu tsarin, kamar duk misãlai na statistical da neural, kuma don mafi yawan harshen, jama'a mãsu yawa sun iya iya ƙaranci a kan salon. Babbar masu yin amfani da na'ura sun sami ChrF 12.97 mafi girma daga layin, idan an tsammaci duk harshe.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku so predstavljeni rezultati skupne naloge o odprtem strojnem prevajanju za avtohtone jezike Amerike leta 2021. Skupna naloga je vključevala dve neodvisni skladbi, udeleženci pa so predložili sisteme strojnega prevajanja za do 10 avtohtonih jezikov. Skupno je sodelovalo 8 ekip s skupno 214 prijavami. Zagotovili smo nabore usposabljanj, ki so sestavljeni iz podatkov, zbranih iz različnih virov, ter ročno prevedenih stavkov za razvoj in testne nabore. Predloženi so bili tudi uradni izhodiščni podatki, usposobljeni na podlagi teh podatkov. Prijave ekip so vključevale različne arhitekture, vključno s statističnimi in nevralnimi modeli, za večino jezikov pa so se številne ekipe znatno izboljšale v primerjavi z izhodiščem. Najboljši sistemi so dosegli 12,97 ChrF višje od izhodiščne vrednosti, če so bili izračunani povprečje med jeziki.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>2021ལོའི་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་ཁ་ཕྱེ་བའི་མ་ལག་གི་སྐད་རིགས་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་མཉམ་སྤྱོད་ཀྱི་བྱ་རིམ་མངོན་འཆར་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། མཉམ་སྤྱོད་ཀྱི་ལས་འགུལ་གྱིས་དུས་རབས་པའི་གླེང་རིམ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་འདྲ་བྱུང་བ་ཡིན་པ། ཞུགས་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་མ་ལག་འཁ འཇུག་བརྡན་དུ་ཚོགས་ཁང་༨་རྣམས་གྲངས་སུ་214 བརྗོད་མཁན་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་རྗེས་སུ་འབྱུང་ཁུངས་མི་འདྲ་བའི་གནད་དོན་གྱི་སྒྲིག་ཐད་སྙད་འཛུགས་བྱས་པ་དེ་ཚོར་སྐྱེས་ཚོགས་ལ་སྒྲིག་ཆ་ གཞུང་འབྲེལ་གྱི་གཞུང་ལྡན་ཞིག་ཀྱང་སྒྲུབ་ཅན་གྱི་ཡིག་ཆ་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་བྱིས་ཚར་བ་རེད། Tim submissions featured various architectures, including statistics and neural models, and for the majority of languages, many teams were able to considerably improve over the baseline. བཀོལ་སྤྱོད་མ་ལག་ཆེ་ཤོས་དུ་རྨང་གཞིའི་ཕྱོགས་ལས་མཐོ་ཤོས་ཐུབ་པ་ལྟར། སྐད་རིགས་འདི་ཕྱོགས་ནས་མཐོ་ཤོས་དུས་ཚ</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>The REPU CS’ SpanishQuechua Submission to the AmericasNLP 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation<fixed-case>REPU</fixed-case> <fixed-case>CS</fixed-case>’ <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>panish–<fixed-case>Q</fixed-case>uechua Submission to the <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>mericas<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> 2021 Shared Task on Open Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Oscar</first><last>Moreno</last></author>
      <pages>241–247</pages>
      <abstract>We present the submission of REPUcs to the AmericasNLP machine translation shared task for the low resource language pair SpanishQuechua. Our neural machine translation system ranked first in Track two (development set not used for training) and third in Track one (training includes development data). Our contribution is focused on : (i) the collection of new parallel data from different web sources (poems, lyrics, lexicons, handbooks), and (ii) using large SpanishEnglish data for pre-training and then fine-tuning the SpanishQuechua system. This paper describes the new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_text">parallel corpora</a> and our approach in detail.</abstract>
      <url hash="0d16c89a">2021.americasnlp-1.27</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.americasnlp-1.27</doi>
      <bibkey>moreno-2021-repu</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="29">
      <title>The Helsinki submission to the AmericasNLP shared task<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>elsinki submission to the <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>mericas<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> shared task</title>
      <author><first>Raúl</first><last>Vázquez</last></author>
      <author><first>Yves</first><last>Scherrer</last></author>
      <author><first>Sami</first><last>Virpioja</last></author>
      <author><first>Jörg</first><last>Tiedemann</last></author>
      <pages>255–264</pages>
      <abstract>The University of Helsinki participated in the AmericasNLP shared task for all ten language pairs. Our multilingual NMT models reached the first rank on all language pairs in track 1, and first rank on nine out of ten language pairs in track 2. We focused our efforts on three aspects : (1) the collection of additional data from various sources such as Bibles and political constitutions, (2) the cleaning and filtering of training data with the OpusFilter toolkit, and (3) different multilingual training techniques enabled by the latest version of the OpenNMT-py toolkit to make the most efficient use of the scarce data. This paper describes our efforts in detail.</abstract>
      <url hash="c92b8108">2021.americasnlp-1.29</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.americasnlp-1.29</doi>
      <bibkey>vazquez-etal-2021-helsinki</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>