<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.naloma">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-10-27">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st and 2nd Workshops on Natural Logic Meets Machine Learning (NALOMA)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Aikaterini-Lida</first><last>Kalouli</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Lawrence S.</first><last>Moss</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Groningen, the Netherlands (online)</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="68bf91c3">2021.naloma-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="b8097cd2">2021.naloma-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>naloma-2021-workshops</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Attentive Tree-structured Network for Monotonicity Reasoning</title>
      <author><first>Zeming</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <pages>12–21</pages>
      <abstract>Many state-of-art neural models designed for monotonicity reasoning perform poorly on downward inference. To address this shortcoming, we developed an attentive tree-structured neural network. It consists of a tree-based long-short-term-memory network (Tree-LSTM) with soft attention. It is designed to model the syntactic parse tree information from the sentence pair of a reasoning task. A self-attentive aggregator is used for aligning the representations of the premise and the hypothesis. We present our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> and evaluate it using the Monotonicity Entailment Dataset (MED). We show and attempt to explain that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> outperforms existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> on MED.</abstract>
      <url hash="cfbaf3f9">2021.naloma-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>chen-2021-attentive</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/help">HELP</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/med">MED</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/snli">SNLI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Transferring Representations of Logical Connectives</title>
      <author><first>Aaron</first><last>Traylor</last></author>
      <author><first>Ellie</first><last>Pavlick</last></author>
      <author><first>Roman</first><last>Feiman</last></author>
      <pages>22–25</pages>
      <abstract>In modern natural language processing pipelines, it is common practice to pretrain a generative language model on a large corpus of text, and then to finetune the created representations by continuing to train them on a discriminative textual inference task. However, it is not immediately clear whether the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meaning_(linguistics)">logical meaning</a> necessary to model <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logical_consequence">logical entailment</a> is captured by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> in this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paradigm">paradigm</a>. We examine this pretrain-finetune recipe with language models trained on a synthetic propositional language entailment task, and present results on test sets probing models’ knowledge of axioms of first order logic.</abstract>
      <url hash="8ba0ccc2">2021.naloma-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>traylor-etal-2021-transferring</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Monotonic Inference for Underspecified Episodic Logic</title>
      <author><first>Gene</first><last>Kim</last></author>
      <author><first>Mandar</first><last>Juvekar</last></author>
      <author><first>Lenhart</first><last>Schubert</last></author>
      <pages>26–40</pages>
      <abstract>We present a method of making natural logic inferences from Unscoped Logical Form of Episodic Logic. We establish a correspondence between inference rules of scope resolved Episodic Logic and the natural logic treatment by Snchez Valencia (1991a), and hence demonstrate the ability to handle foundational natural logic inferences from prior literature as well as more general nested monotonicity inferences.</abstract>
      <url hash="7d7fd64d">2021.naloma-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>kim-etal-2021-monotonic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Bayesian Classification and Inference in a Probabilistic Type Theory with Records<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>ayesian Classification and Inference in a Probabilistic Type Theory with Records</title>
      <author><first>Staffan</first><last>Larsson</last></author>
      <author><first>Robin</first><last>Cooper</last></author>
      <pages>51–59</pages>
      <abstract>We propose a probabilistic account of semantic inference and classification formulated in terms of probabilistic type theory with records, building on Cooper et. al. (2014) and Cooper et. al. We suggest probabilistic type theoretic formulations of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naive_Bayes_classifier">Naive Bayes Classifiers</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_network">Bayesian Networks</a>. A central element of these constructions is a type-theoretic version of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_variable">random variable</a>. We illustrate this account with a simple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_game">language game</a> combining probabilistic classification of perceptual input with probabilistic (semantic) inference.</abstract>
      <url hash="6d329532">2021.naloma-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>larsson-cooper-2021-bayesian</bibkey>
    <title_ar>التصنيف والاستدلال البايزي في نظرية النوع الاحتمالي مع السجلات</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Classificação Bayesiana e Inferência em uma Teoria Probabilística de Tipos com Registros</title_pt>
      <title_fr>Classification bayésienne et inférence dans une théorie probabiliste des types avec enregistrements</title_fr>
      <title_es>Clasificación e inferencia bayesiana en una teoría de tipos probabilística con registros</title_es>
      <title_ja>記録を持つ確率的型理論におけるベイズ分類と推論</title_ja>
      <title_zh>所记概率类贝叶斯类推理</title_zh>
      <title_hi>Bayesian वर्गीकरण और अभिलेखों के साथ एक संभाव्य प्रकार सिद्धांत में अनुमान</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Байесовская классификация и вывод в вероятностной теории типа с записями</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Aicmiú agus Tátal Bayesian i dTeoiric Chineál Dóchúil le Taifid</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Μπαγιεζική ταξινόμηση και συμπέρασμα σε μια πιθανή θεωρία τύπων με αρχεία</title_el>
      <title_hu>Bajeáziai osztályozás és inferencia egy valószínűsíthető típuselméletben rekordokkal</title_hu>
      <title_it>Classificazione bayesiana e inferenza in una teoria del tipo probabilistico con record</title_it>
      <title_kk>Байезия классификациясы мен маңызды түрінің теориясы</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Bayesian Classification and Inference in a Probabilistic Type Theory with Records</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Bayesian Classification and Inference in Probabilistic Type Theory with Records</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Klasifikasi dan Inferensi Bayesian dalam Teori Jenis Kemungkinan dengan Rekod</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ഒരു സാധ്യതരത്തിലുള്ള തരത്തിലുള്ള ബെയിസിയന്‍ ക്ലാസ്സിഷനും പ്രഭുവും റെക്കോര്‍ഡുകളുമായുള്ള പ്രമേയം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Klassifikazzjoni u Inferenza Bayesian a f’Teorija tat-Tip Probabilistiku b’Rekords</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Байзийн классификаци болон хамгийн чухал төрлийн теори дээр</title_mn>
      <title_no>Name</title_no>
      <title_pl>Klasyfikacja Bayesowska i wniosek w prawdopodobnej teorii typu z rekordami</title_pl>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_ro>Clasificarea bayeziană și inferența într-o teorie de tip probabilistic cu înregistrări</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Bayesijska klasifikacija i infekcija u verovatnoj teoriji tipa sa rekordima</title_sr>
      <title_so>Bayesian Classification and Inference in a Tiyaar Type of Probability with Records</title_so>
      <title_sv>Bayesian Klassificering och inferens i en sannolik typteori med register</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>بائئسئي کلاسيفٹ اور انفارنس راکورڈ کے ساتھ شائستہ طرح تئوري میں</title_ur>
      <title_vi>KCharselect unicode block name của một số bệnh dịch</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_bg>Байезийска класификация и заключение в вероятна теория на типа с записи</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Bayesijska klasifikacija i infekcija u vjerojatnoj teoriji tipa s rekordima</title_hr>
      <title_de>Bayessche Klassifikation und Schlussfolgerung in einer probabilistischen Typentheorie mit Datensätzen</title_de>
      <title_nl>Bayesiaanse Classificatie en Inferentie in een Probabilistische Type Theorie met Records</title_nl>
      <title_da>Bayesian klassificering og inferens i en sandsynlig typeteori med poster</title_da>
      <title_id>Klasifikasi dan Inferensi Bayesian dalam Teori Tipe Kemungkinan Dengan Rekaman</title_id>
      <title_fa>تئوری نوع احتمالی با ثبت‌ها</title_fa>
      <title_ko>확률 유형 이론 중의 베일스의 분류와 추리를 기록하고 있다</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Makala na Kuingiliwa kwa Bayesia katika Tamko la a in a inayowezekana na Takwimu</title_sw>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_tr>Kaynaklar bilen Beýezi Taýpi we Taýpi Taýpi</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Klasifikimi dhe Inferenca Bayesian në një Teori të Tipit Probabilist me Rekorde</title_sq>
      <title_am>ፋይል sን መክፈት አልቻለም፦ %s፦ %s</title_am>
      <title_hy>Բեյզիացի դասակարգումը և ինֆերենսը հավանական տեսակի տեսության մեջ</title_hy>
      <title_az>B톛diyal캼 Klasifikat v톛 캻nf톛renci Q톛rcl톛yici T칲r칲 Teoriyas캼nda</title_az>
      <title_bn>সম্ভাব্য ধরনের থিওরিতে বেয়েসিয়ান ক্লাসিকেশন এবং ইনফারেন্স</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Bayesijska klasifikacija i infekcija u teoriji mogućnosti tipa sa rekordima</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Bayesian Classification and Inference in a Probabilistic Type Theory with Records</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Bayesovská klasifikace a inference v pravděpodobné typové teorii se záznamy</title_cs>
      <title_et>Bayesi klassifikatsioon ja järeldus tõenäolise tüübi teoorias kirjetega</title_et>
      <title_fi>Bayesian luokitus ja päätelmä todennäköisessä tyyppiteoriassa tietueilla</title_fi>
      <title_jv>bayesi</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>שיעור בייזי ונפרנס בתאוריה של סוג סביר עם רשומות</title_he>
      <title_sk>Bayezijska klasifikacija in sklepanje v verjetni teoriji tipa z zapisi</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Bayesian Classification and Inference in a Probabilistic Type Theory with Records</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقترح حسابًا احتماليًا للاستدلال الدلالي والتصنيف المصاغ من حيث نظرية النوع الاحتمالي مع السجلات ، بناءً على Cooper et. آل. (2014) و Cooper et. آل. (2015). نقترح الصيغ النظرية من النوع الاحتمالي لمصنفات Naive Bayes وشبكات Bayesian. العنصر المركزي في هذه التركيبات هو نسخة من النوع النظري لمتغير عشوائي. نوضح هذا الحساب بلعبة لغوية بسيطة تجمع بين التصنيف الاحتمالي للمدخلات الحسية والاستدلال الاحتمالي (الدلالي).</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Propomos uma explicação probabilística de inferência semântica e classificação formulada em termos de teoria de tipos probabilísticos com registros, com base em Cooper et. al. (2014) e Cooper et. al. (2015). Sugerimos formulações teóricas do tipo probabilísticas de Classificadores Naive Bayes e Redes Bayesianas. Um elemento central dessas construções é uma versão teórica de tipo de uma variável aleatória. Ilustramos esse relato com um jogo de linguagem simples que combina classificação probabilística de entrada perceptiva com inferência probabilística (semântica).</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Nous proposons un compte rendu probabiliste de l'inférence sémantique et de la classification formulés en termes de théorie probabiliste des types avec des enregistrements, en s'appuyant sur Cooper et al. (2014) et Cooper et al. (2015). Nous suggérons des formulations probabilistes de théorie des types de classificateurs bayésiens naïfs et de réseaux bayésiens. Un élément central de ces constructions est une version théorique de type d'une variable aléatoire. Nous illustrons ce récit par un jeu de langage simple combinant une classification probabiliste de l'entrée perceptuelle avec une inférence probabiliste (sémantique).</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Proponemos un relato probabilístico de la inferencia semántica y la clasificación formulado en términos de teoría probabilística de tipos con registros, basándose en Cooper et. al. (2014) y Cooper et. al. (2015). Sugerimos formulaciones teóricas de tipo probabilístico de Naive Bayes Classifiers y Bayesian Networks. Un elemento central de estas construcciones es una versión teórica de tipos de una variable aleatoria. Ilustramos este relato con un juego de lenguaje simple que combina la clasificación probabilística de la entrada perceptual con la inferencia probabilística (semántica).</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>クーパーら（ 2014 ）とクーパーら（ 2015 ）に基づいて、記録を伴う確率論的型理論の観点から定式化された意味推論と分類の確率論的記述を提案する。Naive Bayes ClassifiersとBayesian Networksの確率論的型理論的定式化を提案します。これらの構築の中心的な要素は、ランダム変数の型理論的なバージョンである。我々は、知覚入力の確率的分類と確率的（意味的）推論を組み合わせた単純な言語ゲームでこの説明を例示する。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>立Cooper et之语义,推类之概率,以概率为基。 (2014)与Cooper等。 （2015）. 吾侪建素贝叶斯器贝叶斯网络之概率论公式。 其构心元素,随机变量类论版本也。 以一简言戏言之,该游戏合感知所输概率类概率(语义)推理。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम रिकॉर्ड के साथ संभाव्य प्रकार के सिद्धांत के संदर्भ में तैयार किए गए शब्दार्थ अनुमान और वर्गीकरण के एक संभाव्य खाते का प्रस्ताव करते हैं, जो कूपर एट पर निर्माण करता है। al. (2014) और कूपर एट। अल (2015)। हम भोले Bayes क्लासिफायर्स और Bayesian नेटवर्क के संभाव्य प्रकार सैद्धांतिक योगों का सुझाव देते हैं। इन निर्माणों का एक केंद्रीय तत्व एक यादृच्छिक चर का एक प्रकार-सैद्धांतिक संस्करण है। हम इस खाते को एक सरल भाषा खेल के साथ चित्रित करते हैं जो संभावित (शब्दार्थ) अनुमान के साथ अवधारणात्मक इनपुट के संभावित वर्गीकरण के संयोजन के साथ होता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Предложен вероятностный учет семантического вывода и классификации, сформулированных в терминах вероятностной теории типов с записями, на основе Cooper et. al. (2014) и Cooper et. al. (2015). Мы предлагаем теоретические формулировки наивных классификаторов Байеса и байесовских сетей вероятностного типа. Центральным элементом этих построений является тип-теоретическая версия случайной переменной. Мы иллюстрируем этот счет простой языковой игрой, объединяющей вероятностную классификацию входного восприятия с вероятностным (семантическим) выводом.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Molaimid cuntas dóchúlachtach ar thátal shéimeantach agus ar aicmiú arna fhoirmiú i dtéarmaí teoiric cineáil dóchúlachta le taifid, ag tógáil ar Cooper et. al. (2014) agus Cooper et. al. (2015). Molaimid foirmithe teoiriciúla de chineál probabilistic de Aicmitheoirí Naive Bayes agus Líonraí Bayesian. Gné lárnach de na tógálacha seo is ea leagan cineál-teoiriciúil d'athróg randamach. Léirímid an cuntas seo le cluiche simplí teanga a chomhcheanglaíonn aicmiú dóchúlachta an ionchuir aireachtála le tátal dóchúil (shéimeantach).</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ გვეძლევა სემონტიკური ინფრენციის და კლასიფიკაციის შესახებ პრობილისტიკური ტიპის თეორიის შესახებ, რომელიც წიგნის შესახებ, Cooper et. al. (2014) და Cooper et. al. (2015). ჩვენ გვეყველას შესაბამისი ტიპი ტეორეტიკური ფორმაციები Naive Bayes კლასიფერების და Bayesian Networks. ამ კონფიგურაციების ცენტრალური ელემენტი არის კონფიგურაციის ტიპის ტეორეტიკური ვერსია. ჩვენ ამ წიგნის გამოსახულებას ერთადერთი ენის თამაში გამოყენებთ, რომელიც შესაბამისი კლასიფიკაციის შესაბამისი შესაბამისი შესაბამისი (semantic) ინფრენცია.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A szemantikai következtetés és osztályozás valószínűségi beszámolóját javasoljuk, amelyet a valószínűségi típuselmélet szempontjából megfogalmaztunk rekordokkal, Cooper et al. (2014) és Cooper et al. (2015) alapján. Javasoljuk Naive Bayes Classifiers és Bayesian Networks valószínűsíthető típusú elméleti formuláit. Ezeknek a konstrukcióknak a központi eleme egy véletlenszerű változó típuselméleti változata. Ezt a beszámolót egy egyszerű nyelvi játékkal illusztráljuk, amely ötvözi az észlelési bemenet valószínűségi osztályozását és a valószínűségi (szemantikai) következtetéssel.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Προτείνουμε μια πιθανολογική καταγραφή σημασιολογικών συμπερασμάτων και ταξινόμησης που διατυπώνεται με βάση την πιθανολογική θεωρία τύπων με αρχεία, στηριζόμενη στην Κούπερ κ.α. (2014) και Κούπερ κ.α. (2015). Προτείνουμε πιθανολογικές θεωρητικές διατυπώσεις των αφελών ταξινομητών Μπάγιες και των δικτύων Μπάγιες. Κεντρικό στοιχείο αυτών των κατασκευών είναι η τυποθεωρητική έκδοση μιας τυχαίας μεταβλητής. Παρουσιάζουμε αυτή την αφήγηση με ένα απλό γλωσσικό παιχνίδι που συνδυάζει πιθανή ταξινόμηση της αντιληπτικής εισόδου με πιθανή (σημασιολογική) συμπέρασμα.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Proponiamo un resoconto probabilistico dell'inferenza semantica e della classificazione formulata in termini di teoria del tipo probabilistico con record, basandosi su Cooper et. al. (2014) e Cooper et. al. (2015). Suggeriamo formulazioni teoriche di tipo probabilistico di Classificatori Naive Bayes e Reti Bayesiane. Un elemento centrale di queste costruzioni è una versione teorica del tipo di una variabile casuale. Illustriamo questo racconto con un semplice gioco linguistico che combina classificazione probabilistica dell'input percettivo con inferenza probabilistica (semantica).</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>We propose a probabilistic account of semantic inference and classification formulated in terms of probabilistic type theory with records, building on Cooper et. al. (2014) and Cooper et. al. (2015).  Siūlome tikėtiną teorinę Naive Bayes klasifikatorių ir Bayesian tinklų formą. A central element of these constructions is a type-theoretic version of a random variable.  Mes iliustruojame šią sąskaitą paprastu kalbų žaidimu, derinančiu perceptualinio įvedimo probabilistinį klasifikavimą su probabilistine (semantine) išvada.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>We propose a probabilistic account of semantic inference and classification formulated in terms of probabilistic type theory with records, building on Cooper et. al. (2014) and Cooper et. al. (2015).  Предлагаме веројатни теоретски формулации на Naive Bayes Classifiers и Bayesian Networks. Централен елемент на овие конструкции е тип-теоретска верзија на случајна променлива. We illustrate this account with a simple language game combining probabilistic classification of perceptual input with probabilistic (semantic) inference.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Біз симантикалық инфиденциялық және классификациялық тіркелгісін жазып, Cooper т. д. (2014) және Cooper т. д. (2015). Біз Naive Bayes классификаторлары және Bayesian желінің теоретикалық түрлерінің формулацияларын ұсынамыз. Бұл құрылымдардың орталық элементі - кездейсоқ айнымалының түрі теориялық нұсқасы. Біз бұл тіркелгіні қарапайым тіл ойынымен көрсетедік. Бұл тіркелгіні қарапайым (semantic) деңгейіндегі ықтималдық келтіру үшін біріктіріп тұрады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami cadangkan akaun kemungkinan dari kesimpulan semantik dan kelasukan yang dibentuk dalam terma teori jenis kemungkinan dengan rekod, berdiri pada Cooper et al. (2014) dan Cooper et al. (2015). Kami cadangkan bentuk teori jenis kebarangkalian dari Pengarah Naive Bayes dan Rangkaian Bayesian. Unsur pusat konstruksi ini adalah versi-teori jenis pembolehubah rawak. Kami memperlihatkan akaun ini dengan permainan bahasa sederhana yang menggabungkan kelasukan kemungkinan input peraptual dengan kesimpulan kemungkinan (semantik).</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>നമ്മള്‍ ഒരു സാധ്യതകള്‍ പ്രായശ്ചിത്രത്തില്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്ന സെമാന്റിക് അപകടത്തിന്റെയും ക്ലാസ്ഫിക്കേഷനുമുള്ള അക്കൌണ്ട് പ് നമ്മള്‍ നാവ് ബെയ്സ് ക്ലാസിഫയര്‍സിന്റെയും ബെയിസ്യന്‍ നെറ്റ്വര്‍ക്കുകളുടെയും തരത്തിലുള്ള തിയോറിറ്റിക് രൂപങ് ഈ നിര്‍മ്മാണങ്ങളുടെ മദ്ധ്യ മൂലകങ്ങള്‍ ഒരു കുറിച്ചില്ലാത്ത മാറിയുള്ള തരത്തിലെ തിയോറിക്ക് പതിപ്പാ നമ്മള്‍ ഈ അക്കൗണ്ടിനെ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നത് സാധ്യതയുള്ള (semantic) അപകടത്തോടൊപ്പം സാധ്യതയുള്ള ക്ലാസ്ഫിക്കല്‍ കൂട്ടിച്ചേര്‍ക്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nipproponu kont probabilistiku ta’ inferenza semantika u klassifikazzjoni fformulati f’termini ta’ teorija tat-tip probabilistiku b’rekords, li jibnu fuq Cooper et. al. (2014) u Cooper et. al. (2015). Aħna ssuġġerixxu formulazzjonijiet teoretiċi tat-tip probabilistiku tal-Klassifikaturi Naive Bayes u n-Netwerks Bayesiani. Element ċentrali ta’ dawn il-kostruzzjonijiet huwa verżjoni teoretika tat-tip ta’ varjabbli aleatorja. Illustraw dan il-kont b’logħob sempliċi tal-lingwa li jgħaqqad il-klassifikazzjoni probabilistika tal-input perċettwali ma’ inferenza probabilistika (semantika).</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Бид магадлалтай төрлийн онолын хувьд бүтээгдэхүүний магадлал халдвар болон хуваарилалтын тооны санал дэвшүүлж байна. Cooper et.al. (2014) болон Cooper et.al. (2015). Бид Naive Bayes Classifiers болон Bayesian Networks-ийн магадлал төрлийн теоретикийн томъёонуудыг санал дэвшүүлнэ. Эдгээр бүтээлүүдийн төв элемент нь санамсаргүй хувьсалын төрлийн теоретик хувилбар юм. Бид энэ тоонуудыг энгийн хэл тоглоомоор харуулж, магадгүй (semantic) халдвартай ойлголтын хөрөнгө оруулалтын магадлалтай хуваалцааны хуваалцаа болгодог.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Vi foreslår eit sannsynlig konto på semantisk infeksjon og klassifikasjon formert i forhold til sannsynlige type-teorie med opptak, bygging på Cooper et. al. (2014) og Cooper et. al. (2015). Vi foreslår sannsynlige type teoretiske formlar av Naive Bayes- klassifiserar og Bayesian- nettverk. Ein sentralelement av desse konstruksjonane er ein type teoretisk versjon av ein tilfeldig variabel. Vi illustrerer denne kontoen med ein enkel språksspel som kombinerer sannsynlig klassifikasjon av oppfattig inndata med sannsynlig (semantisk) infeksjon.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Proponujemy rachunek prawdopodobieństwa wniosków semantycznych i klasyfikacji sformułowany pod kątem teorii typu probabilistycznego z zapisami, w oparciu o Cooper et. al. (2014) i Cooper et. al. (2015). Proponujemy formuły teoretyczne typu probabilistycznego Naive Bayesa Classifiers i Bayesa Networks. Centralnym elementem tych konstrukcji jest teoretyczna wersja zmiennej losowej. Ilustrujemy tę relację prostą grą językową łączącą prawdopodobną klasyfikację wejścia perceptualnego z prawdopodobnym (semantycznym) wnioskiem.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Propunem o relatare probabilistică a inferenței semantice și clasificării formulate în termeni de teoria tipului probabilistic cu înregistrări, bazându-se pe Cooper et. al. (2014) și Cooper et. al. (2015). Sugerăm formulări teoretice de tip probabilistic ale clasificatoarelor naive Bayes și rețelelor bayesiane. Un element central al acestor construcții este o versiune teoretică de tip a unei variabile aleatorii. Ilustrăm acest cont cu un simplu joc lingvistic care combină clasificarea probabilistică a intrării perceptuale cu inferența probabilistică (semantică).</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Predlažemo verovatan račun semantičke infekcije i klasifikacije formulisanog u smislu teorije verovatnih tipa sa dosijeima, izgradnjom na Cooperu i tako dalje. (2014) i Cooperu i tako dalje. (2015). Predlažemo verovatnoj teorijskoj formaciji Naive Bayes klasifikatora i Bayesianskih mreža. Centralni element ove konstrukcije je teorijska verzija nasumične varijante tipa. Ilustriramo ovaj račun jednostavnom jezičkom igrom koja kombinuje verovatnu klasifikaciju perceptualnog ulaska sa verovatnošću (semantičnom) infekcijom.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu soo bandhignaynaa xisaab suurtagal ah oo ku qoran kooper et. al. (2014) iyo Cooper et. al. (2015). Waxan soo jeedaynaa noocyo teoretic ah oo Naive Bayes Classifiers iyo Bayesian Network. Qaybta dhexe ee dhismahan waa nooc-theoretical version of a random variable. Waxaynu sameynaa akawnkan oo ku qoran ciyaar fudud oo ku qoran fasaxa aragtida oo suurtagal ah oo ku jirta cawinaad (semantic).</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Vi föreslår en probabilistisk redogörelse för semantisk inferens och klassificering formulerad i termer av probabilistisk typteori med register, baserat på Cooper et. al. (2014) och Cooper et. al. (2015). Vi föreslår sannolikhetsteoretiska formuleringar av Naive Bayes Classifiers och Bayesian Networks. Ett centralt element i dessa konstruktioner är en typteoretisk version av en slumpvariabel. Vi illustrerar detta med ett enkelt språkspel som kombinerar sannolik klassificering av perceptuell input med sannolik (semantisk) inferens.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாம் ஒரு சாத்தியமான கணக்கை நினைவூட்டுகிறோம் மற்றும் வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது சாத்தியமான வகையான திடீரியோவில் பதிவுகள், Cooper et. al. கட்டுதல் கூப்பர் et.  நாம் நேவ் பேய் சிறப்பாளர்கள் மற்றும் பேயிசியன் வலைப்பின்னல்களின் தியூரியல் வடிவமைப்பை பரிந்துரைக்கிறோம். இந்த கட்டமைப்பின் மையம் உறுப்பு ஒரு குறிப்பில்லாத மாறியின் வகை தியூரிக் பதிப்பு. நாம் இந்த கணக்கை எளிய மொழி விளையாட்டுடன் வெளிப்படுத்துகிறோம். பார்வையில் உள்ளீட்டின் வகைப்பாட்டை சேர்க்கும் போதும்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم ایک شانس حساب کی پیشنهاد کریں گے کہ شانس طرح تئوری کے مطابق کوپر اٹ. ال. (2014) اور کوپر اٹ. ال. (2015) کی تصویر کی تصویر کی۔ ہم نے Naive Bayes Classifiers اور Bayesian Networks کے احتمالی طرح تئوریٹی فرمول کو پیش کرتا ہے. ان ساختاروں کی مرکزی عنصر ایک طرح-نظریہ ویرائل کی ایک نسخہ ہے. ہم اس حساب کو ایک ساده زبان کھیل کے ساتھ نمایش دیتے ہیں جس میں احساساتی (semantic) کفار کے ساتھ احساساتی اینپیٹ کا کلاسپیٹ کرتا ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_si>අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා සැමැන්ටික් පරීක්ෂණය සහ පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා, කූපර් ට.  අපි කියන්නේ නේව් බේස් ක්ලාසිෆාර්ස් සහ බේසියාන් ජාලවාර්ක්ස් ගැන සාමාන්‍ය විද්‍යාත්මක විද්‍යාවය. මේ නිර්මාණයේ මධ්‍යම අවශ්‍ය තත්වයක් තර්ගයක් වෙනස් වෙනස් වර්ගයක්. අපි මේ ගිණුම සාමාන්‍ය භාෂාවක් සෙල්ලම් කරනවා සම්බන්ධ භාෂාවක් සෙල්ලම් කරනවා සම්බන්ධ විශ්වාසික විශ්වාස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_uz>Biz muvaffaqiyatli narsalar, Cooper et. al (2014) va Cooper et. al (2015) bilan birlashtirilgan semantik kasalliklarning hisobotini tahrirlash mumkin. Biz Naiv Bayes klassifierlari va Bayesiya tarmoqlari uchun teoretik turlarini talab qilamiz. Ushbu buyruqlarning markaziy element - Tasodifiy oʻzgaruvchining turi teoretik versiyasi. Biz bu hisobni oddiy tilning oʻyinlari bilan tasavvur qilamiz, ammo o o'ylab ko'rinish (semantik) o'smirligini birlashtirish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi đề nghị giải thích rõ ràng về ngụ ý và phân tích theo mức độ xác định theo lý thuyết kiểu di chúc với các hồ sơ, dựa trên Cooper et. al. (bây giờ) và Cooper et. Chúng tôi đề nghị các mô tả thuyết học về kiểu thể của Naive Bayes ngã giá và Bayisian Networks. Một yếu tố trung tâm của những công trình này là một phiên bản định lí kiểu của một biến số ngẫu nhiên. Chúng tôi mô tả tài khoản này với một trò chơi ngôn ngữ đơn giản kết hợp mức độ nhận thức theo cách chấp nhận cùng với ngụ ý xác thực.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Предлагаме вероятностен разказ на семантичното заключение и класификация, формулиран от гледна точка на вероятностната теория на типа с записи, базиран на Купър и др. (2014) и Купър и др. (2015). Предлагаме вероятностни типови теоретични формулировки на Нейви Байс Класификатори и Байсийски мрежи. Централен елемент на тези конструкции е типова теоретична версия на случайна променлива. Ние илюстрираме този разказ с проста езикова игра, съчетаваща вероятностна класификация на възприятието вход с вероятностно (семантично) заключение.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We stellen een probabilistisch verslag voor van semantische inferentie en classificatie geformuleerd in termen van probabilistische typetheorie met records, voortbouwend op Cooper et.al. (2014) en Cooper et.al. (2015). We stellen probabilistische type theoretische formuleringen voor van naïeve Bayes classifiers en Bayesian Networks. Een centraal element van deze constructies is een typetheoretische versie van een willekeurige variabele. We illustreren dit verhaal met een eenvoudig taalspel dat probabilistische classificatie van perceptuele input combineert met probabilistische (semantische) inferentie.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Vi foreslår en probabilistisk redegørelse for semantisk inferens og klassifikation formuleret i form af probabilistisk typeteori med optegnelser, baseret på Cooper et al. (2014) og Cooper et al. (2015). Vi foreslår probabilistiske type teoretiske formuleringer af Naive Bayes Classifiers og Bayesian Networks. Et centralt element i disse konstruktioner er en typeteoretisk version af en tilfældig variabel. Vi illustrerer denne beretning med et simpelt sprogspil, der kombinerer probabilistisk klassificering af perceptuel input med probabilistisk (semantisk) inferens.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Predlažemo vjerojatni račun semantičke infekcije i klasifikacije formuliranog u smislu teorije vjerojatnosti tipa s dosijeima, izgrađenim na Cooper et. al. (2014) i Cooper et. al. (2015). Predlažemo vjerojatnost teorijske formulacije Naive Bayes klasifikatora i Bayesianskih mreža. Centralni element ove konstrukcije je teorijska verzija tipa nasumične promjene. Ilustriramo ovaj račun jednostavnom jezičkom igrom kombinirajući vjerojatno klasifikaciju perceptualnog ulaska sa vjerojatnom (semantičnom) infekcijom.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Wir schlagen eine probabilistische Darstellung der semantischen Inferenz und Klassifizierung vor, die in Bezug auf probabilistische Typentheorie mit Datensätzen formuliert wird, basierend auf Cooper et. al. (2014) und Cooper et. al. (2015). Wir schlagen probabilistische typtheoretische Formulierungen von Naiven Bayes-Klassifizierern und Bayes-Netzwerken vor. Ein zentrales Element dieser Konstruktionen ist eine typtheoretische Version einer Zufallsvariablen. Wir illustrieren diesen Bericht mit einem einfachen Sprachspiel, das probabilistische Klassifizierung von perzeptuellen Eingaben mit probabilistischer (semantischer) Inferenz kombiniert.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kami mengusulkan sebuah rekening probabilis dari kesimpulan semantis dan klasifikasi terbentuk dalam terma teori tipe probabilis dengan catatan, berdiri pada Cooper et al. (2014) dan Cooper et al. (2015). Kami sarankan formulasi teori tipe probabilis dari Klasifikasi Naive Bayes dan Rangkaian Bayesian. Elemen pusat dari konstruksi ini adalah versi tipe-teori dari variabel acak. Kami menggambarkan rekening ini dengan permainan bahasa sederhana yang menggabungkan klasifikasi probabilis dari input persepsi dengan inferensi probabilis (semantis).</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 쿠퍼 등(2014)과 쿠퍼 등(2015)을 토대로 확률 유형 이론과 기록을 바탕으로 하는 의미 추리와 분류의 확률 해석을 제시했다.우리는 소박한 베일러 분류기와 베일러 네트워크의 확률 유형 이론 공식을 제시했다.이런 구조의 중심 요소는 무작위 변수의 유형 이론 버전이다.우리는 간단한 언어 게임으로 이 점을 설명한다. 이 게임은 감지 입력의 확률 분류와 확률(의미) 추리를 결합시킨다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>ما یک حساب احتمالی از آلودگی‌های semantic و classification را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که در نظریه‌های نوع احتمالی با ثبت‌ها، بر روی کوپر و آل. (۲۰۱۴) و کوپر و آل. (۲۰۱۵). ما پیشنهاد می‌کنیم فرمول‌های نظریه‌ی نوع احتمالاتی از کلاس‌های نایو بیز و شبکه‌های بایزی‌ها. یک عنصر مرکزی از این ساختمان نسخه‌ی نظریه‌ای از یک متغیر تصادفی است. ما این حساب را با بازی زبان ساده نمایش می‌دهیم که شامل تفریق احتمالات ورودی مشاهده می‌کند با احتمالات تفاوت (semantic) تفاوت.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>We propose a probabilistic account of semantic inference and classification formulated in terms of probabilistic type theory with records, building on Cooper et. al. (2014) and Cooper et. al. (2015).  Tunapendekeza aina inayowezekana ya aina ya nadharia ya michoro ya wataalamu wa Bayes na mitandao ya Bayesia. Kitu cha katikati cha majengo haya ni toleo la aina ya nadharia ya mabadiliko yasiyo na uhakika. Tunaelezea akaunti hii kwa mchezo rahisi wa lugha ukiunganisha usambazaji wa uwezekano wa kuandika kwa mtazamo na uwezekano wa kupunguza (semantic).</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Ons voorstel 'n waarskynlike rekening van semantiese inferensie en klasifikasie geformeer in terms of waarskynlike tipe teorie met opneem, bou op Cooper et. al. (2014) en Cooper et. al. (2015). Ons voorstel waarskynlik tipe teorieese formulasies van Naive Bayes Classifiers en Bayesian Netwerke. 'n Sentraal element van hierdie konstruksies is 'n tipe- teorieese weergawe van' n willekeurige veranderlike. Ons illustreer hierdie rekening met 'n eenvoudige taal speletjie wat waarskynlik klasifikasie van perceptual invoer met waarskynlik (semantiese) inferensie kombinerer.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Biz semantik hasaplanjaň we klasifikasyýanyň muhtemelen hili teoriýa ýazylýan, Cooper etkinleşeni we Cooper etkinleşeni maslahat berýäris. (2014) we Cooper etkinleşeni. Najve Bayes klassiferi we Bayesian Networks'in muhtemelen tipi teoretik formüllerini teklif ediyoruz. Bu yapıların merkezi elementi, tesadüf bir çeşitli tür teoretik sürümidir. Biz bu hasaby (semantik) senedi bir dil oýunlary bilen görkez.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Ne propozojmë një llogari probabiliste të inferencës semantike dhe klasifikimit të formuluar në terma të teorisë së tipit probabilist me regjistrime, duke ndërtuar në Cooper et al. (2014) dhe Cooper et al. (2015). Ne sugjerojmë formulime teorike të llojit probabilist të klasifikuesve Naive Bayes dhe rrjeteve Bayesian. Një element qendror i këtyre ndërtimeve është një version lloj-teoretik i një ndryshuese të rastësishme. Ne e ilustrojmë këtë llogari me një lojë të thjeshtë gjuhësh që kombinon klasifikimin probabilistik të hyrjes perceptuale me inferencën probabilistike (semantike).</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>በኮፕር et. al. እና Cooper et. የነዌብ ባይስ ክላሲያዎችን እና የባይስያ ኔትርክ አካባቢዎችን እና የጥያቄ አካባቢዎችን መግለጫ እናስባለን፡፡ የእነዚህ አካባቢዎች መካከለኛ አካል - ዓይነት-theoretical version of a random variable. ይህንን አካባቢ በቋንቋ ጨዋታ እናሳውቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք առաջարկում ենք սեմանտիկ հետևանքների և դասակարգումների հավանական հաշվարկը, որը ձևավորված է հավանական տեսակի տեսության առումով ձայնագրությունների հետ, հիմնված Cooper et al. (2014) և Cooper et al. (2015). Մենք առաջարկում ենք հավանական տեսական տեսակի կառուցվածքներ Նայվ Բեյզ դասավորողների և Բեյզիական ցանցերի համար: Այս կառուցվածքների կենտրոնական տարրերը պատահական փոփոխականների տեսակի տեսակի տարբերակն է: Մենք ներկայացնում ենք այս հաշիվը մի պարզ լեզվային խաղով, որը համադրում է ընկալումների հավանական դասակարգումը հավանական (սեմանտիկ) եզրակացության հետ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Biz semantik infeksiyonun və klasifikasiyanın imkansızlıq hesabını təklif edirik, mümkünlük növ teorisi ilə, Cooper et. al. (2014) və Cooper et. al. (2015). Biz Naive Bayes Klasifikləri və Bayesian Sənələrinin mümkün olaraq teorik formüllərini təbliğ edirik. Bu inşalların mərkəzi elementi rastgele variablanın türü teoriki versiyasıdır. Biz bu hesabı çox basit dil oyunu ilə göstəririk ki, bu hesabı mümkün olaraq (semantik) infeksiyonla imkansızlıq girişinin müvəffəqiyyəti ilə birləşdirir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>We propose a probabilistic account of semantic inference and classification formulated in terms of probabilistic type theory with records, building on Cooper et. al. (2014) and Cooper et. al. (2015).  আমরা প্রস্তাব করছি নাইভ বেইস ক্লাসিফার এবং বেয়েশিয়ান নেটওয়ার্কের সম্ভাব্য ধরনের ততিত্বের বৈশিষ্ট্য। এই নির্মাণের কেন্দ্রীয় উপাদান হচ্ছে একটি অদ্ভুত ভেরিয়েলের ধরনের থিওরিক সংস্করণ। আমরা এই অ্যাকাউন্টের বর্ণনা করি সাধারণ ভাষার খেলার মাধ্যমে যা দৃষ্টিভঙ্গিকার ইনপুটের সাথে সম্ভাব্য (সেমেন্টিক) অসুসংক্রা</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Predlažemo vjerojatni račun semantičke infekcije i klasifikacije formuliranog u smislu teorije mogućnosti tipa sa dosijeima, izgrađenim na Cooper et. al. (2014) i Cooper et. al. (2015). Predlažemo verovatnoj teorijskoj formaciji Naive Bayes klasifikatora i Bayesianskih mreža. Centralni element ove konstrukcije je tipovna teorijska verzija nasumične varijante. Ilustriramo ovaj račun jednostavnom jezičkom igrom koja kombinuje verovatnu klasifikaciju perceptualnog ulaska sa verovatnošću (semantičnom) infekcijom.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Proposem un compte probabilístic de la inferència semàntica i la classificació formulat en termes de teoria del tipus probabilístic amb registres, basant-se en Cooper et al. (2014) i Cooper et al. (2015). We suggest probabilistic type theoretic formulations of Naive Bayes Classifiers and Bayesian Networks.  Un element central d'aquestes construccions és una versió teòrica del tipus d'una variable aleatòria. Illustrem aquest compte amb un joc de llenguatge senzill que combina la classificació probabilista de la entrada perceptual amb la inferència probabilista (semàntica).</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Navrhujeme pravděpodobnostní popis sémantické inference a klasifikace formulovaný z hlediska teorie pravděpodobnostních typů se záznamy, stavějící na Cooperovi et. al. (2014) a Cooperovi et. al. (2015). Navrhujeme pravděpodobnostní teoretické formulace naivních Bayesových klasifikátorů a Bayesovských sítí. Ústředním prvkem těchto konstrukcí je typově teoretická verze náhodné proměnné. Tento účet ilustrujeme jednoduchou jazykovou hrou kombinující pravděpodobnostní klasifikaci perceptuálního vstupu s pravděpodobnostní (sémantickou) inferencí.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Pakume välja tõenäolise konto semantilisest järeldusest ja klassifikatsioonist, mis on sõnastatud tõenäosusliku tüübi teoorias kirjetega, tuginedes Cooper et al. (2014) ja Cooper et. al. (2015). Me soovitame tõenäoliselt tüüpi teoreetilisi vorme Naive Bayes Classifiers ja Bayesian Networks. Nende konstruktsioonide keskseks elemendiks on juhusliku muutuja tüübi teoreetiline versioon. Me illustreerime seda kontot lihtsa keelemänguga, mis ühendab tajusisendi tõenäosusliku klassifikatsiooni tõenäosusliku (semantilise) järeldusega.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Ehdotamme todennäköistä selvitystä semanttisesta päättelystä ja luokittelusta, joka on muotoiltu probabilistisen tyyppiteorian ja tietueiden perusteella Cooper et. al. (2014) ja Cooper et. al. (2015). Ehdotamme todennäköisiä tyyppiteoreettisia formulaatioita Naive Bayes Classifiers ja Bayesian Networks. Näiden rakennelmien keskeinen elementti on satunnaismuuttujan tyyppiteoreettinen versio. Kuvaamme tätä kertomusta yksinkertaisella kielipelillä, jossa yhdistyvät havainnollisen syötteen todennäköisyysluokitus todennäköisyyteen (semanttiseen) päättelyyn.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé ngerasakno perbudalistik kuwi semanti luhuran karo kelompok nggawe barang kelompok sing ngewehke nggawe Tipe sanalistik karo akeh kayimit, gagale nggawe Mungkin et. al (2013) lan colla et. al (2013). Awak dhéwé ngerasakno perbudhakan ngerasakno perbudhakan ngerasakno anu Mbeje Baye Laptop" and "Desktop Awak dhéwé éntuk éntuk nggawe barang kelangan seneng luwih, yen nggawe barang nggawe barang seneng pisan seneng pisan praksistik (semanti)</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>אנו מציעים חשבון סימניסטי של ההנחה הסמנטית והקליפורציה התוכננות במונחים של תיאוריה סוג סימניסטי עם רשומות, בניין על Cooper et. al. (2014) ו Cooper et. al. (2015). We suggest probabilistic type theoretic formulations of Naive Bayes Classifiers and Bayesian Networks.  A central element of these constructions is a type-theoretic version of a random variable.  אנו מציגים את החשבון הזה עם משחק שפה פשוט שילוב סיפור סיפורי של הכניסה התפיסה עם ההנחה סיפוריסטית (סמנטית).</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Munã goyyar da wani akan kafin na kasar mutane da aka samu da fasarin da aka samu da takardar littafin mai yiwuwa da aka samu karatun karãtun littafin, na ginar kan Cooper et. al. (2014) da Cooper et. al. (2015). Tuna ƙayyade probabilistic typi theoretic formulas of Naive Bayes Classifiers and Bayesian Networks. Wata ƙanshi na tsakiya daga wannan salon, shi ne wata nau'in-teoretic version of an variable da randa. Tuna bayyana wannan akan da wani game da harshe na sauƙi, mai sambawa da fassarar mai yiwuwa da ke samu'a cikin shirin ayuka na gane da mai yiwuwa (semantic) ƙaranci.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Predlagamo verjetnostni račun semantične sklepe in klasifikacije, formuliran v smislu teorije verjetnostnih tipov z zapisi, ki temelji na Cooper et. al. (2014) in Cooper et. al. (2015). Predlagamo verjetnostne tipske teoretične formulacije Naive Bayes Classifiers in Bayesian Networks. Osrednji element teh konstrukcij je tipskoteoretična verzija naključne spremenljivke. Ta račun ponazarjamo s preprosto jezikovno igro, ki združuje verjetnostno klasifikacijo zaznavnega vnosa s verjetnostno (semantično) sklepanje.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་semantic inference་དང་དབྱེ་རིགས་ཀྱི་རྒྱུ་རྐྱེན་གྱི་ཐོག་ལས་བྱུང་བ་སྐྱེན་གྱི་རྩིས་ཐོག་ཅིག་བཤད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་Naive Bayes Classifiers དང་Bayesian Networks ཚོའི་ཆོས་ཉིད་ཀྱི་དབྱེ་རིགས་ལུགས་སྔོན་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་། A central element of these constructions is a type-theoretic version of a random variable. ང་ཚོས་རྩིས་ཐོ་འདི་ལ་སྟབས་བདེ་བའི་སྐད་རིགས་ཞིག་གིས་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་བྱས་ཆོས་མཉམ་དུ་གཏོང་བ།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>