<collection id="2021.calcs">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Fifth Workshop on Computational Approaches to Linguistic Code-Switching</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Thamar</first><last>Solorio</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Shuguang</first><last>Chen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alan W.</first><last>Black</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mona</first><last>Diab</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sunayana</first><last>Sitaram</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Victor</first><last>Soto</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Emre</first><last>Yilmaz</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anirudh</first><last>Srinivasan</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.calcs-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="238b0a33">2021.calcs-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>calcs-2021-approaches</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Translate and Classify: Improving Sequence Level Classification for <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish-<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>indi Code-Mixed Data</title>
      <author><first>Devansh</first><last>Gautam</last></author>
      <author><first>Kshitij</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Manish</first><last>Shrivastava</last></author>
      <pages>15&#8211;25</pages>
      <abstract>Code-mixing is a common phenomenon in multilingual societies around the world and is especially common in social media texts. Traditional NLP systems, usually trained on monolingual corpora, do not perform well on code-mixed texts. Training specialized models for code-switched texts is difficult due to the lack of large-scale datasets. Translating code-mixed data into standard languages like English could improve performance on various code-mixed tasks since we can use transfer learning from state-of-the-art English models for processing the translated data. This paper focuses on two sequence-level classification tasks for English-Hindi code mixed texts, which are part of the GLUECoS benchmark - Natural Language Inference and Sentiment Analysis. We propose using various pre-trained models that have been fine-tuned for similar English-only tasks and have shown state-of-the-art performance. We further fine-tune these models on the translated code-mixed datasets and achieve state-of-the-art performance in both tasks. To translate English-Hindi code-mixed data to English, we use mBART, a pre-trained multilingual sequence-to-sequence model that has shown competitive performance on various low-resource machine translation pairs and has also shown performance gains in languages that were not in its pre-training corpus.</abstract>
      <url hash="43f455d9">2021.calcs-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.calcs-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>gautam-etal-2021-translate</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/devanshg27/cm_translatify" additional="false">devanshg27/cm_translatify</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/glue">GLUE</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/multinli">MultiNLI</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/snli">SNLI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Exploring Text-to-Text Transformers for <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish to <fixed-case>H</fixed-case>inglish Machine Translation with Synthetic Code-Mixing</title>
      <author><first>Ganesh</first><last>Jawahar</last></author>
      <author><first>El Moatez Billah</first><last>Nagoudi</last></author>
      <author><first>Muhammad</first><last>Abdul-Mageed</last></author>
      <author><first>Laks</first><last>Lakshmanan, V.S.</last></author>
      <pages>36&#8211;46</pages>
      <abstract>We describe models focused at the understudied problem of translating between monolingual and code-mixed language pairs. More specifically, we offer a wide range of models that convert monolingual English text into Hinglish (code-mixed Hindi and English). Given the recent success of pretrained language models, we also test the utility of two recent Transformer-based encoder-decoder models (i.e., mT5 and mBART) on the task finding both to work well. Given the paucity of training data for code-mixing, we also propose a dependency-free method for generating code-mixed texts from bilingual distributed representations that we exploit for improving language model performance. In particular, armed with this additional data, we adopt a curriculum learning approach where we first finetune the language models on synthetic data then on gold code-mixed data. We find that, although simple, our synthetic code-mixing method is competitive with (and in some cases is even superior to) several standard methods (backtranslation, method based on equivalence constraint theory) under a diverse set of conditions. Our work shows that the mT5 model, finetuned following the curriculum learning procedure, achieves best translation performance (12.67 BLEU). Our models place first in the overall ranking of the English-Hinglish official shared task.</abstract>
      <url hash="b5947756">2021.calcs-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.calcs-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>jawahar-etal-2021-exploring</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/phinc">PHINC</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title><fixed-case>C</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>e<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>: Towards Code-Mixed Translation Using Parallel Monolingual Sentences</title>
      <author><first>Devansh</first><last>Gautam</last></author>
      <author><first>Prashant</first><last>Kodali</last></author>
      <author><first>Kshitij</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Anmol</first><last>Goel</last></author>
      <author><first>Manish</first><last>Shrivastava</last></author>
      <author><first>Ponnurangam</first><last>Kumaraguru</last></author>
      <pages>47&#8211;55</pages>
      <abstract>Code-mixed languages are very popular in multilingual societies around the world, yet the resources lag behind to enable robust systems on such languages. A major contributing factor is the informal nature of these languages which makes it difficult to collect code-mixed data. In this paper, we propose our system for Task 1 of CACLS 2021 to generate a machine translation system for English to Hinglish in a supervised setting. Translating in the given direction can help expand the set of resources for several tasks by translating valuable datasets from high resource languages. We propose to use mBART, a pre-trained multilingual sequence-to-sequence model, and fully utilize the pre-training of the model by transliterating the roman Hindi words in the code-mixed sentences to Devanagri script. We evaluate how expanding the input by concatenating Hindi translations of the English sentences improves mBART&#8217;s performance. Our system gives a BLEU score of 12.22 on test set. Further, we perform a detailed error analysis of our proposed systems and explore the limitations of the provided dataset and metrics.</abstract>
      <url hash="b23b1521">2021.calcs-1.7</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.calcs-1.7</doi>
      <bibkey>gautam-etal-2021-comet</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/devanshg27/cm_translation" additional="false">devanshg27/cm_translation</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>On the logistical difficulties and findings of Jopara Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <author><first>Marvin</first><last>Ag&#252;ero-Torales</last></author>
      <author><first>David</first><last>Vilares</last></author>
      <author><first>Antonio</first><last>L&#243;pez-Herrera</last></author>
      <pages>95&#8211;102</pages>
      <abstract>This paper addresses the problem of sentiment analysis for Jopara, a code-switching language between Guarani and Spanish. We first collect a corpus of Guarani-dominant tweets and discuss on the difficulties of finding quality data for even relatively easy-to-annotate tasks, such as sentiment analysis. Then, we train a set of neural models, including pre-trained language models, and explore whether they perform better than traditional machine learning ones in this low-resource setup. Transformer architectures obtain the best results, despite not considering Guarani during pre-training, but traditional machine learning models perform close due to the low-resource nature of the problem.</abstract>
      <url hash="95ba47a6">2021.calcs-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.calcs-1.12</doi>
      <bibkey>aguero-torales-etal-2021-logistical</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/mmaguero/josa-corpus" additional="false">mmaguero/josa-corpus</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title><fixed-case>C</fixed-case>odemixed<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>: An Extensible and Open <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Toolkit for Code-Mixing</title>
      <author><first>Sai Muralidhar</first><last>Jayanthi</last></author>
      <author><first>Kavya</first><last>Nerella</last></author>
      <author><first>Khyathi Raghavi</first><last>Chandu</last></author>
      <author><first>Alan W</first><last>Black</last></author>
      <pages>113&#8211;118</pages>
      <abstract>The NLP community has witnessed steep progress in a variety of tasks across the realms of monolingual and multilingual language processing recently. These successes, in conjunction with the proliferating mixed language interactions on social media, have boosted interest in modeling code-mixed texts. In this work, we present CodemixedNLP, an open-source library with the goals of bringing together the advances in code-mixed NLP and opening it up to a wider machine learning community. The library consists of tools to develop and benchmark versatile model architectures that are tailored for mixed texts, methods to expand training sets, techniques to quantify mixing styles, and fine-tuned state-of-the-art models for 7 tasks in Hinglish. We believe this work has the potential to foster a distributed yet collaborative and sustainable ecosystem in an otherwise dispersed space of code-mixing research. The toolkit is designed to be simple, easily extensible, and resourceful to both researchers as well as practitioners. Demo: &lt;http://k-ikkees.pc.cs.cmu.edu:5000&gt; and Library: &lt;https://github.com/murali1996/CodemixedNLP&gt;</abstract>
      <url hash="8ab04c65">2021.calcs-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.calcs-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>jayanthi-etal-2021-codemixednlp</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/murali1996/CodemixedNLP" additional="false">murali1996/CodemixedNLP</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Normalization and Back-Transliteration for Code-Switched Data</title>
      <author><first>Dwija</first><last>Parikh</last></author>
      <author><first>Thamar</first><last>Solorio</last></author>
      <pages>119&#8211;124</pages>
      <abstract>Code-switching is an omnipresent phenomenon in multilingual communities all around the world but remains a challenge for NLP systems due to the lack of proper data and processing techniques. Hindi-English code-switched text on social media is often transliterated to the Roman script which prevents from utilizing monolingual resources available in the native Devanagari script. In this paper, we propose a method to normalize and back-transliterate code-switched Hindi-English text. In addition, we present a grapheme-to-phoneme (G2P) conversion technique for romanized Hindi data. We also release a dataset of script-corrected Hindi-English code-switched sentences labeled for the named entity recognition and part-of-speech tagging tasks to facilitate further research.</abstract>
      <url hash="c6d8a7d3">2021.calcs-1.15</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.calcs-1.15</doi>
      <bibkey>parikh-solorio-2021-normalization</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Abusive content detection in transliterated <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>engali-<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish social media corpus</title>
      <author><first>Salim</first><last>Sazzed</last></author>
      <pages>125&#8211;130</pages>
      <abstract>Abusive text detection in low-resource languages such as Bengali is a challenging task due to the inadequacy of resources and tools. The ubiquity of transliterated Bengali comments in social media makes the task even more involved as monolingual approaches cannot capture them. Unfortunately, no transliterated Bengali corpus is publicly available yet for abusive content analysis. Therefore, in this paper, we introduce an annotated Bengali corpus of 3000 transliterated Bengali comments categorized into two classes, abusive and non-abusive, 1500 comments for each. For baseline evaluations, we employ several supervised machine learning (ML) and deep learning-based classifiers. We find support vector machine (SVM) shows the highest efficacy for identifying abusive content. We make the annotated corpus freely available for the researcher to aid abusive content detection in Bengali social media data.</abstract>
      <url hash="b1df1791">2021.calcs-1.16</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.calcs-1.16</doi>
      <bibkey>sazzed-2021-abusive</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/sazzadcsedu/abusivecorpus" additional="false">sazzadcsedu/abusivecorpus</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Are Multilingual Models Effective in Code-Switching?</title>
      <author><first>Genta Indra</first><last>Winata</last></author>
      <author><first>Samuel</first><last>Cahyawijaya</last></author>
      <author><first>Zihan</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Zhaojiang</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrea</first><last>Madotto</last></author>
      <author><first>Pascale</first><last>Fung</last></author>
      <pages>142&#8211;153</pages>
      <abstract>Multilingual language models have shown decent performance in multilingual and cross-lingual natural language understanding tasks. However, the power of these multilingual models in code-switching tasks has not been fully explored. In this paper, we study the effectiveness of multilingual language models to understand their capability and adaptability to the mixed-language setting by considering the inference speed, performance, and number of parameters to measure their practicality. We conduct experiments in three language pairs on named entity recognition and part-of-speech tagging and compare them with existing methods, such as using bilingual embeddings and multilingual meta-embeddings. Our findings suggest that pre-trained multilingual models do not necessarily guarantee high-quality representations on code-switching, while using meta-embeddings achieves similar results with significantly fewer parameters.</abstract>
      <url hash="05776079">2021.calcs-1.20</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.calcs-1.20</doi>
      <bibkey>winata-etal-2021-multilingual</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/lince">LinCE</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>