<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.clpsych">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Seventh Workshop on Computational Linguistics and Clinical Psychology: Improving Access</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Nazli</first><last>Goharian</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Philip</first><last>Resnik</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Andrew</first><last>Yates</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Molly</first><last>Ireland</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kate</first><last>Niederhoffer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Rebecca</first><last>Resnik</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.clpsych-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="a311aa20">2021.clpsych-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>clpsych-2021-linguistics</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Understanding who uses Reddit : Profiling individuals with a self-reported bipolar disorder diagnosis<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>eddit: Profiling individuals with a self-reported bipolar disorder diagnosis</title>
      <author><first>Glorianna</first><last>Jagfeld</last></author>
      <author><first>Fiona</first><last>Lobban</last></author>
      <author><first>Paul</first><last>Rayson</last></author>
      <author><first>Steven</first><last>Jones</last></author>
      <pages>1–14</pages>
      <abstract>Recently, research on mental health conditions using public online data, including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reddit">Reddit</a>, has surged in NLP and health research but has not reported user characteristics, which are important to judge generalisability of findings. This paper shows how existing NLP methods can yield information on clinical, demographic, and identity characteristics of almost 20 K Reddit users who self-report a bipolar disorder diagnosis. This population consists of slightly more feminine- than masculine-gendered mainly young or middle-aged US-based adults who often report additional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mental_disorder">mental health diagnoses</a>, which is compared with general Reddit statistics and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epidemiology">epidemiological studies</a>. Additionally, this paper carefully evaluates all methods and discusses ethical issues.</abstract>
      <url hash="e918a603">2021.clpsych-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.1</doi>
      <bibkey>jagfeld-etal-2021-understanding</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/glorisonne/reddit_bd_user_characteristics" additional="false">glorisonne/reddit_bd_user_characteristics</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/smhd">SMHD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Individual Differences in the Movement-Mood Relationship in Digital Life Data</title>
      <author><first>Glen</first><last>Coppersmith</last></author>
      <author><first>Alex</first><last>Fine</last></author>
      <author><first>Patrick</first><last>Crutchley</last></author>
      <author><first>Joshua</first><last>Carroll</last></author>
      <pages>25–31</pages>
      <abstract>Our increasingly digitized lives generate troves of data that reflect our behavior, beliefs, mood, and wellbeing. Such digital life data provides crucial insight into the lives of patients outside the healthcare setting that has long been lacking, from a better understanding of mundane patterns of exercise and sleep routines to harbingers of emotional crisis. Moreover, information about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Differential_psychology">individual differences</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personality_psychology">personalities</a> is encoded in digital life data. In this paper we examine the relationship between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mood_(psychology)">mood</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinesiology">movement</a> using linguistic and biometric data, respectively. Does increased physical activity (movement) have an effect on a person’s mood (or vice-versa)? We find that weak group-level relationships between movement and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mood_(psychology)">mood</a> mask interesting and often strong relationships between the two for individuals within the group. We describe these individual differences, and argue that individual variability in the relationship between movement and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mood_(psychology)">mood</a> is one of many such factors that ought be taken into account in wellbeing-focused apps and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence">AI systems</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="8508a7cd">2021.clpsych-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>coppersmith-etal-2021-individual</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Suicide Risk Prediction by Tracking Self-Harm Aspects in Tweets : NUS-IDS at the CLPsych 2021 Shared Task<fixed-case>NUS</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>IDS</fixed-case> at the <fixed-case>CLP</fixed-case>sych 2021 Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Sujatha Das</first><last>Gollapalli</last></author>
      <author><first>Guilherme Augusto</first><last>Zagatti</last></author>
      <author><first>See-Kiong</first><last>Ng</last></author>
      <pages>93–98</pages>
      <abstract>We describe our system for identifying users at-risk for suicide based on their tweets developed for the CLPsych 2021 Shared Task. Based on research in mental health studies linking self-harm tendencies with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suicide">suicide</a>, in our system, we attempt to characterize self-harm aspects expressed in user tweets over a period of time. To this end, we design SHTM, a Self-Harm Topic Model that combines <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latent_Dirichlet_allocation">Latent Dirichlet Allocation</a> with a self-harm dictionary for modeling daily tweets of users. Next, differences in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mood_(psychology)">moods</a> and topics over time are captured as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> to train a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning model</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suicide_prediction">suicide prediction</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="90f8d91f">2021.clpsych-1.10</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryCode" hash="a588af6c">2021.clpsych-1.10.OptionalSupplementaryCode.zip</attachment>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryData" hash="a0bd310f">2021.clpsych-1.10.OptionalSupplementaryData.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.10</doi>
      <bibkey>gollapalli-etal-2021-suicide</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Using Psychologically-Informed Priors for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suicide_prediction">Suicide Prediction</a> in the CLPsych 2021 Shared Task<fixed-case>CLP</fixed-case>sych 2021 Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Avi</first><last>Gamoran</last></author>
      <author><first>Yonatan</first><last>Kaplan</last></author>
      <author><first>Almog</first><last>Simchon</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Gilead</last></author>
      <pages>103–109</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our approach to the CLPsych 2021 Shared Task, in which we aimed to predict suicide attempts based on Twitter feed data. We addressed this challenge by emphasizing reliance on prior domain knowledge. We engineered novel theory-driven features, and integrated prior knowledge with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empirical_evidence">empirical evidence</a> in a principled manner using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_inference">Bayesian modeling</a>. While this theory-guided approach increases <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias_(statistics)">bias</a> and lowers <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> on the training set, it was successful in preventing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overfitting">over-fitting</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> provided reasonable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification accuracy</a> on unseen test data (0.68 = AUC= 0.84). Our approach may be particularly useful in prediction tasks trained on a relatively small data set.</abstract>
      <url hash="a10c45ed">2021.clpsych-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.12</doi>
      <bibkey>gamoran-etal-2021-using</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Analysis of Behavior Classification in Motivational Interviewing</title>
      <author><first>Leili</first><last>Tavabi</last></author>
      <author><first>Trang</first><last>Tran</last></author>
      <author><first>Kalin</first><last>Stefanov</last></author>
      <author><first>Brian</first><last>Borsari</last></author>
      <author><first>Joshua</first><last>Woolley</last></author>
      <author><first>Stefan</first><last>Scherer</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammad</first><last>Soleymani</last></author>
      <pages>110–115</pages>
      <abstract>Analysis of client and therapist behavior in counseling sessions can provide helpful insights for assessing the quality of the session and consequently, the client’s behavioral outcome. In this paper, we study the automatic classification of standardized behavior codes (annotations) used for assessment of psychotherapy sessions in Motivational Interviewing (MI). We develop <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> and examine the classification of client behaviors throughout MI sessions, comparing the performance by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> trained on large pretrained embeddings (RoBERTa) versus interpretable and expert-selected features (LIWC). Our best performing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> using the pretrained RoBERTa embeddings beats the baseline model, achieving an F1 score of 0.66 in the subject-independent 3-class classification. Through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_inference">statistical analysis</a> on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a> results, we identify prominent LIWC features that may not have been captured by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> using pretrained embeddings. Although <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a> using LIWC features underperforms RoBERTa, our findings motivate the future direction of incorporating auxiliary tasks in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification of MI codes</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="b532c9da">2021.clpsych-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>tavabi-etal-2021-analysis</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Automatic Detection and Prediction of Psychiatric Hospitalizations From Social Media Posts</title>
      <author><first>Zhengping</first><last>Jiang</last></author>
      <author><first>Jonathan</first><last>Zomick</last></author>
      <author><first>Sarah Ita</first><last>Levitan</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Serper</last></author>
      <author><first>Julia</first><last>Hirschberg</last></author>
      <pages>116–121</pages>
      <abstract>We address the problem of predicting psychiatric hospitalizations using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">linguistic features</a> drawn from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media posts</a>. We formulate this novel task and develop an approach to automatically extract time spans of self-reported psychiatric hospitalizations. Using this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>, we build <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Predictive_modelling">predictive models</a> of psychiatric hospitalization, comparing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">feature sets</a>, user vs. post classification, and comparing model performance using a varying time window of posts. Our best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> achieves an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-number">F1</a> of.718 using 7 days of posts. Our results suggest that this is a useful framework for collecting hospitalization data, and that social media data can be leveraged to predict acute psychiatric crises before they occur, potentially saving lives and improving outcomes for individuals with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mental_disorder">mental illness</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="3273c7fe">2021.clpsych-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>jiang-etal-2021-automatic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Automated coherence measures fail to index <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thought_disorder">thought disorder</a> in individuals at risk for psychosis</title>
      <author><first>Kasia</first><last>Hitczenko</last></author>
      <author><first>Henry</first><last>Cowan</last></author>
      <author><first>Vijay</first><last>Mittal</last></author>
      <author><first>Matthew</first><last>Goldrick</last></author>
      <pages>129–150</pages>
      <abstract>Thought disorder   linguistic disturbances including incoherence and derailment of topic   is seen in individuals both with and at risk for psychosis. Methods from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">computational linguistics</a> have increasingly sought to quantify <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thought_disorder">thought disorder</a> to detect group differences between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinical_trial">clinical populations</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_control">healthy controls</a>. While previous work has been quite successful at these classification tasks, the lack of interpretability of the computational metrics has made it unclear whether they are in fact measuring <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thought_disorder">thought disorder</a>. In this paper, we dive into these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Measure_(mathematics)">measures</a> to try to better understand what they reflect. While we find group differences between at-risk and healthy control populations, we also find that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistic">measures</a> mostly do not correlate with existing measures of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thought_disorder">thought disorder symptoms</a> (what they are intended to measure), but rather correlate with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">surface properties of the speech</a> (e.g., sentence length) and sociodemographic properties of the speaker (e.g., race). These results highlight the importance of considering interpretability and front and center as the field continues to grow. Ethical use of computational measures like those studied here   especially in the high-stakes context of clinical care   requires us to devote substantial attention to potential biases in our measures.</abstract>
      <url hash="fc1f0849">2021.clpsych-1.16</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.16</doi>
      <bibkey>hitczenko-etal-2021-automated</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Detecting Cognitive Distortions from Patient-Therapist Interactions</title>
      <author><first>Sagarika</first><last>Shreevastava</last></author>
      <author><first>Peter</first><last>Foltz</last></author>
      <pages>151–158</pages>
      <abstract>An important part of Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT) is to recognize and restructure certain negative thinking patterns that are also known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_distortion">cognitive distortions</a>. The aim of this project is to detect these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distortion">distortions</a> using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a>. We compare and contrast different types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">linguistic features</a> as well as different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification algorithms</a> and explore the limitations of applying these techniques on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sample_size_determination">small dataset</a>. We find that pre-trained Sentence-BERT embeddings to train an SVM classifier yields the best results with an F1-score of 0.79. Lastly, we discuss how this work provides insights into the types of linguistic features that are inherent in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_distortion">cognitive distortions</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="00e3bcee">2021.clpsych-1.17</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.17</doi>
      <bibkey>shreevastava-foltz-2021-detecting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>Evaluating Automatic Speech Recognition Quality and Its Impact on Counselor Utterance Coding</title>
      <author><first>Do June</first><last>Min</last></author>
      <author><first>Verónica</first><last>Pérez-Rosas</last></author>
      <author><first>Rada</first><last>Mihalcea</last></author>
      <pages>159–168</pages>
      <abstract>Automatic speech recognition (ASR) is a crucial step in many natural language processing (NLP) applications, as often available data consists mainly of raw speech. Since the result of the ASR step is considered as a meaningful, informative input to later steps in the NLP pipeline, it is important to understand the behavior and failure mode of this step. In this work, we analyze the quality of ASR in the psychotherapy domain, using motivational interviewing conversations between therapists and clients. We conduct domain agnostic and domain-relevant evaluations using standard evaluation metrics and also identify domain-relevant keywords in the ASR output. Moreover, we empirically study the effect of mixing ASR and manual data during the training of a downstream NLP model, and also demonstrate how additional local context can help alleviate the error introduced by noisy ASR transcripts.</abstract>
      <url hash="70e338c6">2021.clpsych-1.18</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.18</doi>
      <bibkey>min-etal-2021-evaluating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Safeguarding against spurious AI-based predictions : The case of automated verbal memory assessment<fixed-case>AI</fixed-case>-based predictions: The case of automated verbal memory assessment</title>
      <author><first>Chelsea</first><last>Chandler</last></author>
      <author><first>Peter</first><last>Foltz</last></author>
      <author><first>Alex</first><last>Cohen</last></author>
      <author><first>Terje</first><last>Holmlund</last></author>
      <author><first>Brita</first><last>Elvevåg</last></author>
      <pages>181–191</pages>
      <abstract>A growing amount of psychiatric research incorporates machine learning and natural language processing methods, however findings have yet to be translated into actual clinical decision support systems. Many of these studies are based on relatively small datasets in homogeneous populations, which has the associated risk that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> may not perform adequately on new data in real clinical practice. The nature of serious mental illness is that it is hard to define, hard to capture, and requires frequent monitoring, which leads to imperfect data where attribute and class noise are common. With the goal of an effective AI-mediated clinical decision support system, there must be computational safeguards placed on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> used in order to avoid spurious predictions and thus allow humans to review data in the settings where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> are unstable or bound not to generalize. This paper describes two approaches to implementing safeguards : (1) the determination of cases in which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> are unstable by means of attribute and class based outlier detection and (2) finding the extent to which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> show <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inductive_bias">inductive bias</a>. These <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Safeguard">safeguards</a> are illustrated in the automated scoring of a story recall task via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing methods</a>. With the integration of human-in-the-loop machine learning in the clinical implementation process, incorporating safeguards such as these into the models will offer patients increased protection from spurious predictions.</abstract>
      <url hash="57ac577c">2021.clpsych-1.20</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.20</doi>
      <bibkey>chandler-etal-2021-safeguarding</bibkey>
    <title_ar>الحماية من التنبؤات الزائفة المستندة إلى الذكاء الاصطناعي: حالة التقييم الآلي للذاكرة اللفظية</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Proteção contra previsões espúrias baseadas em IA: o caso da avaliação automatizada da memória verbal</title_pt>
      <title_es>Protección contra predicciones falsas basadas en IA: el caso de la evaluación automática de la memoria verbal</title_es>
      <title_ja>偽のAIベースの予測からの保護：自動言語記憶評価のケース</title_ja>
      <title_hi>नकली एआई-आधारित भविष्यवाणियों के खिलाफ सुरक्षा: स्वचालित मौखिक स्मृति मूल्यांकन का मामला</title_hi>
      <title_zh>防AI虚占:自语记评事例</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Cosaint i gcoinne tuar bréagacha AI-bhunaithe: Cás measúnú cuimhne briathartha uathoibrithe</title_ga>
      <title_ka>დახმარება AI-დაბათებული წარმოდგენების შესახებ: ავტომატიური გერბალური მეხსიერების შესახებ</title_ka>
      <title_el>Προστασία από ψευδείς προβλέψεις βασισμένες στην τεχνητή νοημοσύνη: Η περίπτωση της αυτοματοποιημένης αξιολόγησης της λεκτικής μνήμης</title_el>
      <title_hu>Védelem a hamis AI-alapú előrejelzésekkel szemben: Az automatizált verbális memóriaértékelés esete</title_hu>
      <title_it>Salvaguardia contro false previsioni basate sull'IA: il caso della valutazione automatica della memoria verbale</title_it>
      <title_mk>Заштита од непријатни предвидувања базирани на ВИ: случајот на автоматизирана проценка на вербалната меморија</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Sauga nuo priešiškų AI pagrįstų prognozių: automatinio žodinės atminties vertinimo atvejis</title_lt>
      <title_kk>Автоматты вербалды жады оқу үшін</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Melindungi terhadap ramalan AI berasaskan yang menggerunkan: Kasus penilaian memori verbal automatik</title_ms>
      <title_ml>പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട AI-അടിസ്ഥാനമായ പ്രവചനങ്ങളില്‍ നിന്നും സൂക്ഷിക്കുന്നത് സൂക്ഷിച്ചുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു:</title_ml>
      <title_no>Trygg mot spesifiserte AI-baserte foregåver: Tilfellet av automatisk verbal minne-vurdering</title_no>
      <title_mt>Salvagwardja kontra tbassir spurjuż ibbażat fuq l-AI: Il-każ ta’ valutazzjoni awtomatizzata tal-memorja verbali</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Архи мэдлэг суурилсан тодорхойлолтуудын эсрэг хамгаалах: автоматжуулсан үгийн санамжийн тодорхойлолтын тухай</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Ochrona przed fałszywymi prognozami opartymi na sztucznej inteligencji: przypadek zautomatyzowanej oceny pamięci werbalnej</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Protejarea împotriva predicțiilor false bazate pe AI: cazul evaluării automate a memoriei verbale</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Èuvanje od strašnih predviđanja na AI-u: sluèaj automatske procjene verbalnog pamćenja</title_sr>
      <title_si>ආරක්ෂා කරන්න AI-අධාරිත ප්‍රශ්නයක් විරුද්ධ වෙනුවෙන්: ස්වයංක්‍රිය වාර්තාවක් මතක පරිශ්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Ka ilaalinashada ka hor dhigidda warqadaha AI-ku saleysan: Kaartaynta xasuusta si gaar ah loo isticmaalay</title_so>
      <title_sv>Skydd mot falska AI-baserade förutsägelser: Fallet med automatisk bedömning av verbalt minne</title_sv>
      <title_ta>பிரச்சனையான AI-அடிப்படையிலுள்ள முன்னோட்டங்களை விட்டும் பாதுகாப்புக் கொள்வது: தானியங்கிய சார்ந்த</title_ta>
      <title_ur>آئ کی بنیادی پیش بینی سے محافظت کرتی ہے: اتوماٹی کلام یاد آزمائش کا کیس</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Bảo vệ chống lại những dự đoán giả tạo của AI: trường hợp đánh giá tự động trí nhớ miệng</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Защита от фалшиви прогнози, базирани на изкуствен интелект: Случаят с автоматизираната оценка на устната памет</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Bescherming tegen valse AI-gebaseerde voorspellingen: het geval van geautomatiseerde verbale geheugenbeoordeling</title_nl>
      <title_da>Beskyttelse mod falske AI-baserede forudsigelser: Tilfældet med automatisk verbal hukommelse vurdering</title_da>
      <title_id>Melindungi dari prediksi berbasis AI yang menggoda: Kasus penilaian memori verbal otomatis</title_id>
      <title_ko>인공지능 기반의 허위 예측 방지: 자동 언어 기억 평가 사례</title_ko>
      <title_hr>Čuvanje od strašnih predviđanja na AI-u: slučaj automatske procjene verbalnog sjećanja</title_hr>
      <title_de>Schutz vor falschen KI-basierten Vorhersagen: Der Fall der automatisierten verbalen Gedächtnisbewertung</title_de>
      <title_tr>Aýratyn faýllary goramak: Aýratyn esasy hatyrlamasynyň kiçidi</title_tr>
      <title_fa>محافظت از پیش‌بینی‌هایی که بر اساس AI بسته‌اند: پرونده ارزیابی حافظه‌های زبانی خودکار</title_fa>
      <title_sq>Mbrojtja kundër parashikimeve të shqetësuara bazuar në AI: rasti i vlerësimit të kujtesës së automatizuar verbale</title_sq>
      <title_sw>Kulinda dhidi ya utabiri wenye asili ya AI:</title_sw>
      <title_hy>ԱԲ-ի հիմնված վատ կանխատեսումների դեպքում պաշտպանությունը. ավտոմատիկ բերբալ հիշողության գնահատման դեպքում</title_hy>
      <title_az>Ağır tədbirlərə qarşı təhlükəsizlik təhlükəsizlər təhlükəsizlər: Avtomatik sözlər yada vuruşması</title_az>
      <title_af>Beskerming teen speursielle AI-gebaseerde voorskoue: Die geval van outomatiese verbale geheue-evaluering</title_af>
      <title_am>የ.አ-አ-አ-አዳራሽ ትንቢት ከመጠበቅ የሚጠብቅ: የራሳቸውን የአባቢል መታሰቢያ ማስታወስ ማስታወሻ ጉዳይ</title_am>
      <title_cs>Ochrana před falešnými predikcemi založenými na umělé inteligenci: Případ automatizovaného hodnocení verbální paměti</title_cs>
      <title_bn>স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভিত্তিক আল-ভিত্তিক ভবিষ্যদ্বাণীর বিরুদ্ধে নিরাপত্তা রক্ষা করা: স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে স্বয়ংক্</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Čuvanje od strašnih predviđanja na AI-u: slučaj automatske procjene verbalnog sjećanja</title_bs>
      <title_fi>Suojautuminen vääriltä tekoälypohjaisilta ennusteilta: Automaattisen verbaalisen muistin arvioinnin tapaus</title_fi>
      <title_et>Kaitse valede AI-põhiste prognooside eest: automatiseeritud verbaalse mälu hindamise juhtum</title_et>
      <title_ca>Salvaguarda contra prediccions espirituals basades en AI: El cas de l'avaluació automatitzada de la memòria verbal</title_ca>
      <title_he>Safeguarding against spurious AI-based predictions: The case of automated verbal memory assessment</title_he>
      <title_sk>Zaščita pred lažnimi napovedmi na podlagi umetne inteligence: primer avtomatiziranega ocenjevanja verbalnega spomina</title_sk>
      <title_ha>QXml</title_ha>
      <title_bo>spurious AI-based predictions:The case of automated verbal memory assessment</title_bo>
      <title_jv>Nguasai kang dipunanggé uwong-apik tukong ning AI:</title_jv>
      <abstract_pt>Uma quantidade crescente de pesquisas psiquiátricas incorpora métodos de aprendizado de máquina e processamento de linguagem natural, no entanto, as descobertas ainda precisam ser traduzidas em sistemas reais de apoio à decisão clínica. Muitos desses estudos são baseados em conjuntos de dados relativamente pequenos em populações homogêneas, o que tem o risco associado de que os modelos possam não ter um desempenho adequado em novos dados na prática clínica real. A natureza da doença mental grave é que é difícil de definir, difícil de capturar e requer monitoramento frequente, o que leva a dados imperfeitos onde ruídos de atributo e classe são comuns. Com o objetivo de um sistema eficaz de suporte à decisão clínica mediado por IA, deve haver salvaguardas computacionais colocadas nos modelos usados para evitar previsões espúrias e, assim, permitir que os humanos revisem dados nas configurações em que os modelos são instáveis ou fadados a não generalizar. Este artigo descreve duas abordagens para a implementação de salvaguardas: (1) a determinação de casos em que os modelos são instáveis por meio da detecção de outliers baseada em atributos e classes e (2) encontrar a extensão em que os modelos mostram viés indutivo. Essas salvaguardas são ilustradas na pontuação automatizada de uma tarefa de recordação de história por meio de métodos de processamento de linguagem natural. Com a integração do aprendizado de máquina human-in-the-loop no processo de implementação clínica, a incorporação de salvaguardas como essas nos modelos oferecerá aos pacientes maior proteção contra previsões espúrias.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Una cantidad cada vez mayor de investigaciones psiquiátricas incorpora el aprendizaje automático y los métodos de procesamiento del lenguaje natural, sin embargo, los hallazgos aún no se han traducido en sistemas de apoyo a las decisiones clínicas. Muchos de estos estudios se basan en conjuntos de datos relativamente pequeños en poblaciones homogéneas, lo que conlleva el riesgo de que los modelos no funcionen adecuadamente con datos nuevos en la práctica clínica real. La naturaleza de la enfermedad mental grave es que es difícil de definir, difícil de capturar y requiere un monitoreo frecuente, lo que conduce a datos imperfectos donde el ruido de atributos y clases es común. Con el objetivo de un sistema eficaz de apoyo a la toma de decisiones clínicas mediado por IA, se deben colocar salvaguardas computacionales en los modelos utilizados para evitar predicciones falsas y, por lo tanto, permitir que los humanos revisen los datos en entornos donde los modelos son inestables o están obligados a no generalizar. Este artículo describe dos enfoques para implementar salvaguardas: (1) la determinación de casos en los que los modelos son inestables mediante la detección de valores atípicos basada en atributos y clases y (2) encontrar el grado en que los modelos muestran sesgo inductivo. Estas medidas de seguridad se ilustran en la puntuación automática de una tarea de recuperación de historias mediante métodos de procesamiento del lenguaje natural. Con la integración del aprendizaje automático human-in-the-loop en el proceso de implementación clínica, la incorporación de salvaguardas como estas en los modelos ofrecerá a los pacientes una mayor protección contra predicciones falsas.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ar>تتضمن كمية متزايدة من الأبحاث النفسية التعلم الآلي وطرق معالجة اللغة الطبيعية ، ولكن النتائج لم تترجم بعد إلى أنظمة دعم القرار السريرية الفعلية. تعتمد العديد من هذه الدراسات على مجموعات بيانات صغيرة نسبيًا في مجموعات سكانية متجانسة ، والتي لها مخاطر مرتبطة بأن النماذج قد لا تعمل بشكل كافٍ على البيانات الجديدة في الممارسة السريرية الحقيقية. تكمن طبيعة المرض العقلي الخطير في صعوبة تعريفه ، وصعوبة التقاطه ، ويتطلب مراقبة متكررة ، مما يؤدي إلى بيانات غير كاملة حيث تكون السمة والضوضاء الطبقية شائعة. بهدف نظام دعم القرار السريري الفعال بوساطة الذكاء الاصطناعي ، يجب أن تكون هناك ضمانات حسابية موضوعة على النماذج المستخدمة من أجل تجنب التنبؤات الزائفة ، وبالتالي السماح للبشر بمراجعة البيانات في الإعدادات حيث تكون النماذج غير مستقرة أو ملزمة بعدم التعميم. تصف هذه الورقة طريقتين لتنفيذ الضمانات: (1) تحديد الحالات التي تكون فيها النماذج غير مستقرة عن طريق الكشف عن العوامل الخارجية القائمة على السمة والفئة و (2) إيجاد المدى الذي تظهر به النماذج التحيز الاستقرائي. يتم توضيح هذه الضمانات في التسجيل الآلي لمهمة استدعاء القصة عبر طرق معالجة اللغة الطبيعية. مع دمج التعلم الآلي للإنسان في الحلقة في عملية التنفيذ السريري ، فإن دمج مثل هذه الضمانات في النماذج سيوفر للمرضى حماية متزايدة من التنبؤات الزائفة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_ja>ますます増加する精神医学的研究には、機械学習と自然言語処理方法が組み込まれていますが、調査結果はまだ実際の臨床的意思決定支援システムに変換されていません。 これらの研究の多くは、均質な集団における比較的小さなデータセットに基づいており、実際の臨床実践では、モデルが新しいデータに対して適切に機能しない可能性があるという関連するリスクを有する。 深刻な精神疾患の性質は、定義が難しく、捕捉が難しく、頻繁なモニタリングが必要であり、属性とクラスノイズが一般的な不完全なデータにつながることです。 AIを介した効果的な臨床的意思決定支援システムを目標に、偽予測を回避し、モデルが不安定であるか、あるいは一般化する必要がない状況で人間がデータをレビューできるようにするために、使用されるモデルに計算的保護手段を設ける必要があります。 本稿では， （ 1 ）属性とクラスに基づく外れ値検出によってモデルが不安定である場合の判定と， （ 2 ）モデルが帰納的バイアスを示す程度を求める2つのアプローチを説明する． これらの保護手段は、自然言語処理方法を介したストーリーリコールタスクの自動スコアリングに示されている。 ヒューマンインザループ機械学習が臨床実装プロセスに統合されることで、これらのような保護手段をモデルに組み込むことで、偽の予測から患者をより保護することができます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>益多者精神病学合机器学自然语言处之,而治未转为实临床决支持系统。 其间多论同质人群小数,此有相关风险,即模形或不能尽行于临床实践。 精神疾病质难义,难捕难监测,性类噪声常数未尽也。 所以人工智能介导者临床决策支持系统者,必算护其用,以避虚占,以听人之不定、绑定不泛化之数。 本文言保障之法:(1)以属性类检定不定,及(2)见模形见归差。 此保护措施自然语言所以自评分也。 随临床之机器学成,纳诸如此之保障,以为大护,使免虚占之害。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>मनोवैज्ञानिक अनुसंधान की बढ़ती मात्रा में मशीन लर्निंग और प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रसंस्करण विधियों को शामिल किया गया है, हालांकि निष्कर्षों को अभी तक वास्तविक नैदानिक निर्णय समर्थन प्रणालियों में अनुवाद ति नहीं किया गया है। इनमें से कई अध्ययन सजातीय आबादी में अपेक्षाकृत छोटे डेटासेट पर आधारित हैं, जिसमें संबंधित जोखिम है कि मॉडल वास्तविक नैदानिक अभ्यास में नए डेटा पर पर्याप्त रूप से प्रदर्शन नहीं कर सकते हैं। गंभीर मानसिक बीमारी की प्रकृति यह है कि इसे परिभाषित करना मुश्किल है, कैप्चर करना मुश्किल है, और लगातार निगरानी की आवश्यकता होती है, जो अपूर्ण डेटा की ओर जाता है जहां विशेषता और वर्ग शोर आम हैं। एक प्रभावी एआई-मध्यस्थता नैदानिक निर्णय समर्थन प्रणाली के लक्ष्य के साथ, नकली भविष्यवाणियों से बचने के लिए उपयोग किए जाने वाले मॉडल पर कम्प्यूटेशनल सुरक्षा उपाय होने चाहिए और इस प्रकार मनुष्यों को उन सेटिंग्स में डेटा की समीक्षा करने की अनुमति देनी चाहिए जहां मॉडल अस्थिर हैं या सामान्यीकरण करने के लिए बाध्य नहीं हैं। यह पेपर सुरक्षा उपायों को लागू करने के लिए दो दृष्टिकोणों का वर्णन करता है: (1) उन मामलों का निर्धारण जिसमें मॉडल विशेषता और वर्ग आधारित बाहरी पहचान के माध्यम से अस्थिर होते हैं और (2) उस हद तक खोजते हैं जिस तक मॉडल आगमनात्मक पूर्वाग्रह दिखाते हैं। इन सुरक्षा उपायों को प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रसंस्करण विधियों के माध्यम से एक कहानी याद कार्य के स्वचालित स्कोरिंग में चित्रित किया गया है। नैदानिक कार्यान्वयन प्रक्रिया में मानव-इन-द-लूप मशीन लर्निंग के एकीकरण के साथ, मॉडल में इन जैसे सुरक्षा उपायों को शामिल करने से रोगियों को नकली भविष्यवाणियों से बढ़ी हुई सुरक्षा प्रदान की जाएगी।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cuimsíonn méid méadaitheach taighde síciatrach modhanna foghlama meaisín agus próiseála teanga nádúrtha, ach tá na torthaí fós le haistriú go córais tacaíochta cinntí cliniciúla iarbhír. Tá go leor de na staidéir seo bunaithe ar thacair sonraí sách beag i ndaonraí aonchineálacha, a bhfuil an riosca gaolmhar leis go bhféadfadh sé nach bhfeidhmeoidh na samhlacha go leormhaith ar shonraí nua i bhfíor-chleachtas cliniciúil. Is é nádúr na meabhairghalar tromchúiseach go bhfuil sé deacair a shainiú, go bhfuil sé deacair é a ghabháil, agus éilíonn sé monatóireacht mhinic, rud a fhágann go mbíonn sonraí neamhfhoirfe mar a mbíonn tréithe agus torann aicme coitianta. Agus é mar sprioc córas éifeachtach tacaíochta cinntí cliniciúla trí AI, ní mór coimircí ríomhaireachtúla a chur ar na samhlacha a úsáidtear chun tuartha bréagacha a sheachaint agus ar an gcaoi sin ligean do dhaoine sonraí a athbhreithniú sna suímh ina bhfuil samhlacha éagobhsaí nó ina bhfuil ceangal orthu gan ginearálú. Déanann an páipéar seo cur síos ar dhá chur chuige maidir le cosaintí a chur i bhfeidhm: (1) cásanna a chinneadh ina bhfuil samhlacha éagobhsaí trí bhrath asluiteach bunaithe ar thréithe agus aicme agus (2) ag fáil amach a mhéid a léiríonn samhlacha laofacht ionduchtach. Léirítear na cosaintí seo sa scóráil uathoibrithe ar thasc chun scéal a athghairm trí mhodhanna próiseála teanga nádúrtha. Le comhtháthú na meaisínfhoghlama daonna-i-an-lúb sa phróiseas cur chun feidhme cliniciúil, tabharfar cosaint mhéadaithe d'othair ó thuartha bréagacha trí chosaintí mar iad seo a ionchorprú sna samhlacha.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Egyre nagyobb mennyiségű pszichiátriai kutatás magában foglalja a gépi tanulást és a természetes nyelvfeldolgozási módszereket, azonban az eredményeket még nem fordították át tényleges klinikai döntéstámogató rendszerekbe. Ezek közül sok vizsgálat homogén populációkra vonatkozó viszonylag kis adatkészleteken alapul, ami azzal a kockázattal jár, hogy a modellek valós klinikai gyakorlatban nem teljesítenek megfelelően új adatokat. A súlyos mentális betegségek jellege az, hogy nehéz meghatározni, nehéz rögzíteni, és gyakori monitorozást igényel, ami tökéletlen adatokhoz vezet, ahol az attribútum és az osztály zaja gyakori. A hatékony AI által mediált klinikai döntéstámogató rendszer célja érdekében számítástechnikai biztosítékokat kell alkalmazni az alkalmazott modellekre annak érdekében, hogy elkerüljék a hamis előrejelzéseket, és így lehetővé tegyék az emberek számára, hogy olyan környezetben vizsgálják át az adatokat, ahol a modellek instabilak vagy nem általánosítanak. A tanulmány a biztosítékok végrehajtásának két megközelítését ismerteti: (1) azon esetek meghatározását, amikor a modellek instabilak attribútumok és osztályok alapú különböző értékek detektálásával és (2) meghatározását, hogy a modellek milyen mértékben mutatnak induktív elfogultságot. Ezeket a biztosítékokat a történetvisszahívási feladatok automatizált pontozása illusztrálja természetes nyelvfeldolgozási módszerekkel. A humán-in-the-loop gépi tanulás klinikai megvalósítási folyamatba történő integrálásával az ilyen biztosítékok beépítése a modellekbe fokozott védelmet nyújt a betegeknek a hamis előrejelzésekkel szemben.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Μια αυξανόμενη ποσότητα ψυχιατρικής έρευνας ενσωματώνει μεθόδους μηχανικής μάθησης και επεξεργασίας φυσικής γλώσσας, ωστόσο τα ευρήματα δεν έχουν μεταφραστεί ακόμα σε πραγματικά συστήματα υποστήριξης κλινικών αποφάσεων. Πολλές από αυτές τις μελέτες βασίζονται σε σχετικά μικρά σύνολα δεδομένων σε ομοιογενείς πληθυσμούς, γεγονός που συνεπάγεται τον κίνδυνο ότι τα μοντέλα ενδέχεται να μην λειτουργήσουν επαρκώς σε νέα δεδομένα στην πραγματική κλινική πρακτική. Η φύση της σοβαρής ψυχικής ασθένειας είναι ότι είναι δύσκολο να προσδιοριστεί, δύσκολο να συλληφθεί και απαιτεί συχνή παρακολούθηση, η οποία οδηγεί σε ατελείωτα δεδομένα όπου χαρακτηριστικά και θόρυβος κατηγορίας είναι κοινός. Με στόχο ένα αποτελεσματικό σύστημα υποστήριξης κλινικών αποφάσεων μέσω της τεχνητής νοημοσύνης, πρέπει να υπάρχουν υπολογιστικές διασφαλίσεις στα μοντέλα που χρησιμοποιούνται προκειμένου να αποφευχθούν ψευδείς προβλέψεις και έτσι να επιτραπεί στους ανθρώπους να επανεξετάσουν δεδομένα σε περιβάλλοντα όπου τα μοντέλα είναι ασταθή ή υποχρεωμένα να μην γενικεύσουν. Η παρούσα εργασία περιγράφει δύο προσεγγίσεις για την εφαρμογή των διασφαλίσεων: (1) τον προσδιορισμό των περιπτώσεων στις οποίες τα μοντέλα είναι ασταθή μέσω της ανίχνευσης χαρακτηριστικών και κλάσεων και (2) τον προσδιορισμό του βαθμού στον οποίο τα μοντέλα παρουσιάζουν επαγωγική προκατάληψη. Αυτές οι διασφαλίσεις απεικονίζονται στην αυτοματοποιημένη βαθμολογία μιας εργασίας ανάκλησης ιστοριών μέσω μεθόδων επεξεργασίας φυσικής γλώσσας. Με την ενσωμάτωση της μηχανικής μάθησης του ανθρώπου στον βρόχο στη διαδικασία κλινικής εφαρμογής, η ενσωμάτωση τέτοιων διασφαλίσεων στα μοντέλα θα προσφέρει στους ασθενείς αυξημένη προστασία από ψευδείς προβλέψεις.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>მექსიკონიური განსხვავებული სისტემაში მაქსიკონიური განსხვავება და მექსიკონიური ენის განსხვავება შეიყვანს, მაგრამ შესაძლებლობები არ უნდა იყოს რეალური კლინიური განსხვავ ბევრი ამ კვლევების უფრო მცირე მონაცემები ჰომოგენური პოლიციაში დაბაზიან, რომელიც აქვს დაკავშირებული რისკი, რომ მოდელები შეიძლება ახალი მონაცემებზე რეალური კლინიკური პ ჟვპთჲჱნჲ მთჟლთფნჲ ჟლჲბჲეჟრგჲ ვ, ფვ ვ რპსენჲ ეა ევტთნთპაქ, რპსენჲ ეა ჱაჳგანვქ, თ ეა თჟკაქ ფვჟრჲ მჲნთრპთპაŒვ, კჲვრჲ ოპთეყლზაგა ნვოპვკლძფთგთ ეატპთრთ თ კლაჟა ეფექტიური AI-მედიარებული კლინიკური განსახულების სისტემის მიზეზით, უნდა იყოს კომპუტაციალური დაახლოები, რომლებიც გამოიყენებული მოდელში გამოყენებული მოდელში, რომ გამოცდილობა ძალიან წარმოდგენების შესაძლებლობად და ეს დოკუმენტი გამოსახულებს ორი დახმარების შესაძლებლობა: 1) მოდელების განსახულება, რომელიც მოდელები არსებულია ატრიბუტის და კლასის ბაზეული გარეშე განსახულებაზე და 2) მოდელების განსახულება, რომელიც მოდელები ინდი ეს დარწმუნებელები აჩვენებულია ისტორიის ავტომატიური შემოწმებაში, რომელიც სახელსახური ენის პროცესი მეტისების გამოყენებით. კლინიკური გამოყენების პროცესში ადამიანის ინტერგურაციას, როგორც ეს მოდელში მოწყობინება, მოწყობინებს პაციენტებს უფრო მეტი დარწმუნება კლინიკური გამოყენების პროცესში.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Una crescente quantità di ricerca psichiatrica incorpora metodi di apprendimento automatico e di elaborazione del linguaggio naturale, tuttavia i risultati devono ancora essere tradotti in sistemi di supporto alle decisioni cliniche reali. Molti di questi studi si basano su set di dati relativamente piccoli in popolazioni omogenee, con il rischio associato che i modelli non funzionino adeguatamente sui nuovi dati nella pratica clinica reale. La natura della malattia mentale grave è che è difficile da definire, difficile da catturare e richiede un monitoraggio frequente, che porta a dati imperfetti in cui attributo e rumore di classe sono comuni. Con l'obiettivo di un efficace sistema di supporto alle decisioni cliniche mediato dall'IA, devono essere poste garanzie computazionali sui modelli utilizzati al fine di evitare previsioni false e quindi consentire agli esseri umani di rivedere i dati nelle impostazioni in cui i modelli sono instabili o destinati a non generalizzare. Questo documento descrive due approcci all'attuazione delle misure di salvaguardia: (1) la determinazione dei casi in cui i modelli sono instabili mediante il rilevamento di valori anomali basati su attributi e classi e (2) la determinazione della misura in cui i modelli mostrano distorsioni induttive. Queste salvaguardie sono illustrate nel punteggio automatizzato di un compito di richiamo della storia attraverso metodi di elaborazione del linguaggio naturale. Con l'integrazione del machine learning umano in the loop nel processo di implementazione clinica, incorporare tali salvaguardie nei modelli offrirà ai pazienti una maggiore protezione da previsioni false.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Vis daugiau psichiatrinių tyrimų apima mašinų mokymąsi ir natūralius kalbų apdorojimo metodus, tačiau rezultatai dar neturi būti perkelti į faktines klinikinių sprendimų priėmimo paramos sistemas. Daugelis šių tyrimų yra pagrįsti palyginti mažais homogeninių populiacijų duomenų rinkiniais, dėl kurių kyla su tuo susijusi rizika, kad modeliai gali netinkamai atlikti naujų duomenų tikroje klinikinėje praktikoje. The nature of serious mental illness is that it is hard to define, hard to capture, and requires frequent monitoring, which leads to imperfect data where attribute and class noise are common.  Siekiant veiksmingos su AI susijusios klinikinės sprendimų priėmimo rėmimo sistemos, modeliams turi būti taikomos kompiuterinės apsaugos priemonės, kad būtų išvengta prieštaringų prognozių ir taip žmonės galėtų peržiūrėti duomenis tokiose aplinkybėse, kuriose modeliai yra nestabili arba kurios nėra įpareigotos apskritai išplisti. Šiame dokumente aprašomi du apsaugos priemonių įgyvendinimo metodai: 1) atvejų, kai modeliai yra nestabili nustatant požymius ir klase pagrįstus ribinius nuokrypius, nustatymas ir 2) atvejų, kai modeliai rodo induktyvią nukrypimą, nustatymas. Šios apsaugos priemonės parodomos automatiškai įvertinant istorijos atšaukimo užduotį naudojant natūralius kalbų apdorojimo metodus. Įtraukus žmogaus mokymąsi ciklo viduje į klinikinį įgyvendinimo procesą, tokių apsaugos priemonių įtraukimas į modelius suteiks pacientams didesnę apsaugą nuo neigiamų prognozių.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Психиатриялық зерттеулердің көптеген саны машинаны оқыту және табиғи тілдердің өңдеу әдістерін қолданады, бірақ табулар әлі клиникалық шешім қолдау жүйелеріне аударылмаған. Бұл зерттеулердің көпшілігі гомогендер жиындарындағы салыстырмалы кішкентай деректер жиындарына негізделген. Бұл үлгілер шын клиникалық практикадағы жаңа деректерді жасау мүмкін емес. Маңызды психикалық аурулардың қасиеті - атрибуттар мен класс дыбыстарын анықтау, қатты түсіру және көптеген бақылау керек. Бұл атрибуттар мен класс дыбыстарының жалпы мәліметтеріне сәйкес береді Эффективті AI-медиативті клиникалық шешімдерді қолдау жүйесінің мақсатында, мәліметтер дұрыс болмайтын немесе жалпы болмайтын мәліметтерге қолданылатын үлгілер үшін компьютерлік қауіпсіздік қорғаушылары болу керек. Со Бұл қағаз қауіпсіздерді қорғау үшін екі арқылы анықтайды: (1) үлгілердің атрибуттары мен класс негіздеген шолғыштарды анықтау арқылы дәрежелерді анықтау және (2) үлгілердің индуктивті шолғыштарды көрсету арқылы. Бұл қауіпсіздерді табиғи тілдерді өңдеу әдістері арқылы автоматты түрде тапсырманы еске салуда көрсетіледі. Клиниялық іске асыру процесінде адамдардың іске асыратын машинаны біріктіру үшін, мысалы үлгілерге қауіпсіздіктерді қосу үшін пациенттердің қауіпсіздігінен қауіпсіздік көмектеседі.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Sebuah jumlah penelitian psikiatri yang meningkat melibatkan pembelajaran mesin dan kaedah pemprosesan bahasa semulajadi, bagaimanapun penemuan belum diterjemahkan ke sistem sokongan keputusan klinik sebenar. Banyak kajian ini berasaskan pada set data relatif kecil dalam populasi homogen, yang mempunyai risiko berkaitan bahawa model mungkin tidak melakukan secara adekwat pada data baru dalam praktek klinik sebenar. Sifat penyakit mental yang serius adalah ia sukar untuk menentukan, sukar untuk ditangkap, dan memerlukan pengawasan sering, yang membawa kepada data yang tidak sempurna di mana atribut dan bunyi kelas adalah umum. Dengan tujuan sistem sokongan keputusan klinik mediasi AI yang berkesan, mesti terdapat perlindungan komputasi ditempatkan pada model yang digunakan untuk menghindari ramalan yang menggerunkan dan dengan itu membenarkan manusia untuk meninjau data dalam tetapan di mana model tidak stabil atau terikat untuk tidak menyebarkan. Kertas ini menggambarkan dua pendekatan untuk melaksanakan keselamatan: (1) penentuan kes-kes dimana model tidak stabil melalui atribut dan pengesan luar berdasarkan kelas dan (2) mencari jangkauan mana model menunjukkan bias induktif. Perlindungan ini digambarkan dalam skor automatik tugas pemulihan cerita melalui kaedah pemprosesan bahasa alami. Dengan integrasi pembelajaran mesin manusia-dalam-loop dalam proses implementasi klinik, memasukkan perlindungan seperti ini ke dalam model akan menambah perlindungan pesakit daripada ramalan yang menggerunkan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Ammont dejjem jikber ta’ riċerka psikjatrika jinkorpora metodi ta’ tagħlim tal-magni u pproċessar tal-lingwi naturali, madankollu s-sejbiet għad iridu jiġu tradotti f’sistemi ta’ appoġġ tad-deċiżjonijiet kliniċi attwali. Ħafna minn dawn l-istudji huma bbażati fuq settijiet ta’ dejta relattivament żgħar f’popolazzjonijiet omoġenji, li għandhom ir-riskju assoċjat li l-mudelli jistgħu ma jwettqux b’mod adegwat fuq dejta ġdida fil-prattika klinika reali. In-natura ta’ mard mentali serju hija li huwa diffiċli li wieħed jiddefinixxi, diffiċli li jinqabad, u jeħtieġ monitoraġġ frekwenti, li jwassal għal dejta imperfetta fejn l-attribut u l-istorbju tal-klassi huma komuni. Bil-għan ta’ sistema effettiva ta’ appoġġ għad-deċiżjonijiet kliniċi medjata mill-AI, għandu jkun hemm salvagwardji komputattivi mqiegħda fuq il-mudelli użati sabiex jiġu evitati tbassir spurjuż u b’hekk il-bnedmin ikunu jistgħu jirrevedu d-dejta fl-ambjenti fejn il-mudelli mhumiex stabbli jew marbuta ma jiġġeneralizzawx. Dan id-dokument jiddeskrivi żewġ approċċi għall-implimentazzjoni tas-salvagwardji: (1) id-determinazzjoni tal-każijiet li fihom il-mudelli mhumiex stabbli permezz tal-identifikazzjoni tal-karatteristiċi u tal-klassi bbażati fuq il-periferiji u (2) is-sejba tal-punt sa fejn il-mudelli juru preġudizzju induttiv. Dawn is-salvagwardji huma murija fil-punteġġ awtomatizzat ta’ kompitu ta’ ġbir lura ta’ storji permezz ta’ metodi naturali ta’ pproċessar tal-lingwi. Bl-integrazzjoni tat-tagħlim tal-magni umani fil-loop fil-proċess ta’ implimentazzjoni klinika, l-inkorporazzjoni ta’ salvagwardji bħal dawn fil-mudelli se toffri lill-pazjenti aktar protezzjoni minn tbassir spurjuż.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>മൈക്കിറ്ററിക് ഗവേഷണം വളര്‍ന്നുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നുവെങ്കിലും മെഷീന്‍ പഠിക്കുന്നതും സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷ പ്രക്രിയശ്ചിത്രത്തിലു ഈ പഠനങ്ങളില്‍ പലരും കൂടുതല്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ ചെറിയ ഡാറ്റാസേറ്റുകള്‍ സങ്കല്‍പ്പിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. അതിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ ബന്ധപ്പെട്ടിരിക ഗുരുതരമായ മാനസിക രോഗങ്ങളുടെ പ്രകൃതി എന്താണെന്നാല്‍ പിടികൂടുന്നത്, പിടികൂടുന്നതിന് കഠിനമായി നിരീക്ഷിക്കുന്നത്, പ്രാധാരണമാ പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട പ്രവചനങ്ങള്‍ ഒഴിവാക്കാന്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന മോഡലുകളില്‍ കണക്കൂട്ടികേറ്റ് സുരക്ഷാകര്‍ത്തികള്‍ സ്ഥാപിക്കേണ്ടതുണ്ട്. അതുകൊണ്ട് മോഡലുകള്‍ സ്ഥിരമായ ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ സുരക്ഷാകര്‍ത്താവിനെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കാന്‍ രണ്ട് വഴികള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു: (1) വ്യവസ്ഥയും ക്ലാസിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തുള്ള മാതൃകങ്ങള്‍ സ്ഥി സ്വാഭാവികമായ ഭാഷ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്ന രീതികളിലൂടെ ഈ സുരക്ഷാകര്‍ത്താവുകള്‍ സ്വയം സ്കോര്‍ട്ട് ചെയ്യുന With the integration of human-in-the-loop machine learning in the clinical implementation process, incorporating safeguards such as these into the models will offer patients increased protection from spurious predictions.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mk>Растечкиот број психијатриски истражувања вклучува машинско учење и природни методи на процес на јазик, но откритијата сé уште не се преведени во системи за поддршка на клиничките одлуки. Многу од овие студии се базирани на релативно мали податоци во хомогени популации, кои имаат поврзан ризик дека моделите можеби не извршуваат соодветно на новите податоци во вистинската клиничка практика. Природата на сериозната ментална болест е дека е тешко да се дефинира, тешко да се фати, и бара често мониторинг, што води до несовршени податоци каде атрибутите и класната бучава се чести. Со цел на ефикасен систем за поддршка на клиничките одлуки посреден со AI, мора да се поставуваат компјутатурни заштити на моделите кои се користат со цел да се избегнат непријатни предвидувања и со тоа да им се овозможи на луѓето да ги прегледаат податоците во поставувањата каде моделите се нестабилни Овој документ опишува два пристапи кон спроведувањето на заштитните мерки: (1) одредувањето на случаите во кои моделите се нестабилни со помош на детекција на атрибути и класа базирани надворешни страни и (2) откривање на степенот во кој моделите покажуваат индуктивни предрас Овие заштитни мерки се илустрирани во автоматското оценување на задачата за повлекување на приказните преку природни методи на процес на јазик. Со интеграцијата на машинското учење во врска со човекот во процесот на клиничка спроведување, вклучувањето на заштитни мерки како овие во моделите ќе им понуди на пациентите зголемена заштита од непријатни предвидувања.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_pl>Coraz większa liczba badań psychiatrycznych obejmuje uczenie maszynowe i metody przetwarzania języka naturalnego, jednak wyniki nie zostały jeszcze przełożone na rzeczywiste systemy wspierania decyzji klinicznych. Wiele z tych badań opiera się na stosunkowo małych zbiorach danych w populacjach jednorodnych, co wiąże się z ryzykiem, że modele mogą nie działać odpowiednio na podstawie nowych danych w praktyce klinicznej. Charakter poważnych chorób psychicznych polega na tym, że trudno je zdefiniować, trudno uchwycić i wymaga częstego monitorowania, co prowadzi do niedoskonałych danych, w których szum atrybutów i klasy są powszechne. W celu stworzenia skutecznego systemu wspierania decyzji klinicznych za pośrednictwem sztucznej inteligencji, należy zastosować zabezpieczenia obliczeniowe stosowane modele, aby uniknąć fałszywych przewidywań i tym samym umożliwić ludziom przegląd danych w warunkach, w których modele są niestabilne lub zobowiązane do nieuogólniania. W artykule opisano dwa podejścia do wdrażania zabezpieczeń: (1) określenie przypadków, w których modele są niestabilne za pomocą wykrywania atrybutów i klas opartych na wykrywaniu odstających oraz (2) ustalenie stopnia, w jakim modele wykazują tendencje indukcyjne. Te zabezpieczenia są ilustrowane w zautomatyzowanej ocenie zadania przywoływania historii za pomocą metod przetwarzania języka naturalnego. Dzięki integracji uczenia maszynowego człowieka w pętli w procesie wdrażania klinicznego, włączenie takich zabezpieczeń do modeli zapewni pacjentom większą ochronę przed fałszywymi przewidywaniami.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Un număr tot mai mare de cercetări psihiatrice încorporează metode de învățare automată și procesare a limbajului natural, cu toate acestea, constatările nu au fost încă traduse în sisteme reale de sprijin pentru decizii clinice. Multe dintre aceste studii se bazează pe seturi de date relativ mici în populații omogene, ceea ce prezintă riscul asociat ca modelele să nu funcționeze în mod adecvat pe noile date din practica clinică reală. Natura bolilor mentale grave este că acestea sunt greu de definit, greu de capturat și necesită monitorizare frecventă, ceea ce duce la date imperfecte în cazul în care atributele și zgomotul de clasă sunt comune. În scopul unui sistem eficient de sprijin al deciziilor clinice mediat de AI, trebuie să existe măsuri de protecție computațională plasate pe modelele utilizate pentru a evita predicțiile false și astfel să permită oamenilor să revizuiască datele în setările în care modelele sunt instabile sau obligate să nu generalizeze. Această lucrare descrie două abordări pentru implementarea garanțiilor: (1) determinarea cazurilor în care modelele sunt instabile prin detectarea unor valori anormale bazate pe atribute și clase și (2) identificarea măsurii în care modelele prezintă o distorsiune inductivă. Aceste măsuri de protecție sunt ilustrate în scorul automat al unei sarcini de reamintire a poveștii prin metode de prelucrare a limbajului natural. Odată cu integrarea învățării automate umane în buclă în procesul de implementare clinică, încorporarea unor astfel de măsuri de protecție în modele va oferi pacienților o protecție sporită împotriva predicțiilor false.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mn>Сэтгэл санааны судалгааны их хэмжээнд машины суралцах болон байгалийн хэл үйлдвэрлэх арга барилгадаг. Гэхдээ ололтууд үнэндээ клиникийн шийдвэрлэлийн тусламжтай системд орлуулагддаггүй. Эдгээр судалгаануудын ихэнх нь ижил хүн амын дотор харьцангуй жижиг өгөгдлийн сангууд дээр суурилсан. Энэ нь загварууд жинхэнэ клиникийн дасгал дээр шинэ өгөгдлийн сангуудыг хэрэгжүүлэх эрсдэлтэй Маш чухал сэтгэл санааны өвчин нь тодорхойлж, барьж авах хэцүү, ихэвчлэн ажиллах хэрэгтэй гэсэн үг. Энэ нь харилцаа, хичээл дуу хоолойг бүрэн тодорхойлж чадахгүй мэдээлэл юм. ДОХ-ын эффективны клиникийн шийдвэрлэлийн системийн тусламжтай зорилгоор тооцоололтын аюулгүй байдал байх ёстой. Энэхүү үед хүмүүст загвар тогтворгүй эсвэл ерөнхийлөгч байхгүй байх боломжтой байдаг тооцоололтын аюулгүй байдал байх ёстой. Энэ цаас аюулгүй хамгаалалтуудыг хэрэгжүүлэх хоёр арга замыг тайлбарладаг: (1) загваруудын тодорхойлолт нь харилцаа, хичээл суурилсан газрын нээлт болон (2) загваруудын үр дүнг харуулах хэмжээг олж мэддэг. Эдгээр аюулгүй хамгаалагчид байгалийн хэл үйлдвэрлэлийн арга хэлбэрээр автоматжуулагдсан түүхийг автоматжуулахад харуулсан. Хүн дотор холбоотой машин суралцахын тулд клиникийн дасгал үйлдвэрлэлийн үйлдвэрлэлд, эдгээр загваруудыг нэгтгэх мэт аюулгүй хамгаалалтуудыг загвар руу оруулах нь өвчтөнүүдийг буруу таамаглалтаас илүү аюул</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Ein økende mengd psykiatriske forskning inkluderer maskinelæring og naturspråkshandteringsmetodar, men finningar må enno verta omsetta til aktive kliniske beslutningssystemer. Mange av desse studiane er basert på relativt lite datasett i homogeneske populasjonar, som har den tilknytte risikoen for at modellen kan ikkje utføra adekvitet på nye data i reelle kliniske praksis. Det er vanskeleg å definera, vanskeleg å henta, og krev ofte overvaking, som fører til uavhengige data der attributt og klassestøy er vanskeleg. Med målet til eit effektivt AI-mediart klinisk beslutningsstyrkesystemet må det vera datasikkerheiter plassert på modelane som skal unngå forskjellige forebyggingar, og dermed kan menneske gjennomgå data i innstillingane der modeller er ikkje stabile eller både ikkje generellisert. Denne papiret beskriver to tilnærmingar til å implementera tryggleikslar: (1) avgjering av tilfellene som modeller er ikkje stabil ved hjelp av oppdaging av attributt og klassebaserte omrisset og (2) å finna kor mykje modeller viser induktive forsiktighet. Desse tryggartene er illustrarte i den automatiske oppløysinga av ei storleik som reknar oppgåva ved hjelp av naturlege språkshandsamingsmetodar. Med integrasjonen av menneskemaskinelæring i løysinga i løysinga av den kliniske implementasjonsprosessen, vil inkludere sikkerheita slik som desse i modelane tilbys pacientane økt beskyttelse frå dårlige foregåver.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_so>Baaritaanka dhimirka oo koraya waxaa ka mid ah qaababka barashada maskaxda iyo qaababka baaritaanka afka dabiiciga ah, habase yeeshee waa in lagu turjumaa nidaamka kaalmada go'aanka ee dhabta ah. Waxbarashadan qaarkood waxay ku saleysan yihiin sawirro yar oo ku yaala dadka isku wada dhaqdhaqaaqa ah, kaas oo haysta khatar la xiriira in tusaaladu aysan ku sameyn karin macluumaad cusub oo ku saabsan tababarka dhakhtarka caafimaadka. Madowga cudurka dhimirka ah waa in ay adag tahay in la caddeeyo, in la qabsado, si adag loo baahan yahay in la ilaaliyo, taas oo sababto macluumaad aan khatar lahayn, meesha qaylada fasalka iyo qaylada ay caadi u yihiin. Ujeedada kaalmada go'aanka ee caafimaadka caafimaadka ee AI waa in lagu sameeyaa ammaanka xisaabta ah oo lagu isticmaalay si uu uga diido wixii la sii sheegay oo aad u baahan tahay, sidaas darteed dadku wuxuu u fasaxaa inay macluumaadka ka ka baaraandegaan qoraalka, marka modellada ay ku tabar jaban yihiin ama aan ku qasbin in in lagu sameeyo. Qoraalkan waxaa ku qoran laba qaab oo lagu soo dejiyo badbaadada: (1) go'aanka xaaladaha lagu soo dejiyo tusaalooyin ay ku taagnaan yihiin sida ay u baahan yihiin qalabka iyo fasalka si ka hooseeya iyo (2) si aad u hesho qaababka ay sameynayso qalabka waxqabadka. Badbaadadan waxaa lagu soo bandhigaa goobaha loo isticmaalayo goobaha lagu soo xusuusto oo lagu qorayo qaababka baaritaanka luuqada dabiicadda ah. Inta la qabsashada machadka qofka lagu baranayo baaritaanka caafimaadka, waxaa lagu siinayaa ammaanka, tusaale ahaan tusaale ahaan loo soo galo tusaale ahaan in bukaanku uu kordhiyo badbaado ka sii kordhiya wixii la sii sheegay.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>En växande mängd psykiatrisk forskning innefattar maskininlärning och metoder för naturlig språkbehandling, men resultaten har ännu inte omsatts till faktiska kliniska beslutsstödssystem. Många av dessa studier bygger på relativt små datamängder i homogena populationer, vilket har den associerade risken att modellerna inte fungerar tillräckligt på nya data i verklig klinisk praxis. Naturen av allvarlig psykisk ohälsa är att den är svår att definiera, svår att fånga och kräver regelbunden övervakning, vilket leder till ofullständiga data där attribut och klassljud är vanligt. Med målet om ett effektivt AI-medierat kliniskt beslutsstöd måste det finnas beräkningsskydd på de modeller som används för att undvika falska förutsägelser och därmed tillåta människor att granska data i miljöer där modeller är instabila eller bundna att inte generalisera. Denna uppsats beskriver två tillvägagångssätt för att implementera skyddsåtgärder: (1) fastställande av fall där modeller är instabila med hjälp av attribut- och klassbaserad avvikelsedetektion och (2) hitta i vilken utsträckning modeller uppvisar induktiv bias. Dessa skyddsåtgärder illustreras i den automatiska poängsättningen av en berättelse återkallande uppgift via naturliga språkbehandlingsmetoder. Genom att integrera human-in-the-loop maskininlärning i den kliniska implementeringsprocessen kommer att införliva sådana skyddsåtgärder i modellerna att erbjuda patienterna ökat skydd mot falska förutsägelser.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Povećana količina psihijatrijskih istraživanja uključuje metode učenja mašina i prirodnog jezika, međutim, nalazi još uvek nisu prevedeni u sisteme podrške kliničkih odluka. Mnogi od tih ispitivanja su temeljeni na relativno malim podacima u homogenijalnim populacijama, koja ima povezan rizik da modeli ne mogu adekvatno izvršiti na novim podacima u stvarnoj kliničkoj praksi. Priroda ozbiljne mentalne bolesti je da je teško definisati, teško uhvatiti i zahtevati često praćenje, što vodi do nepovršenih podataka gde su atributi i zvuk klase zajednički. Sa ciljem efikasnog sustava podrške kliničkim odlukama koji posreduje AI, moraju biti računalne sigurnosti postavljene na modele koji se koriste kako bi izbjegli neprijatne predviđanja i tako omogućili ljudima da pregledaju podatke u postavkama gdje su modeli nestabilni ili ne povezani da se generalizuju. Ovaj papir opisuje dva pristupa provedbi sigurnosnih zaštita: 1) određivanje slučajeva u kojima su modeli nestabilni putem otkrivanja atributa i klase otkrivanja izveštaja i 2) pronalaženja mjere u kojoj modeli pokazuju induktivne predrasude. Ovi zaštitnici su ilustrirani u automatskom izviđanju priče koja se sjeća zadatka putem metoda prirodnog obradivanja jezika. Sa integracijom učenja ljudskih uređaja u loopu u kliničkom procesu provedbe, uključujući sigurnosne zaštite kao što su ove u modele, ponudiće pacijentima povećanu zaštitu od strašnih predviđanja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>විශ්වාසික විශේෂ පරීක්ෂණයේ පරීක්ෂණය සහ ස්වභාවික භාෂා පරීක්ෂණ විධානය සම්බන්ධ කරනවා, ඒත් හොයාගන්න මේ අභ්‍යාසයෙන් ගොඩක් අධ්‍යාසය සමාන්‍ය පොඩි දත්ත සූදානයක් සමාන්‍ය විශේෂයෙන් අධ්‍යාසය කරනවා, ඒකෙන් සමාන්‍ය විශේෂ සාධාරණ මානසික රෝගේ ස්වභාවිතය තමයි ඒක විශ්වාස කරන්න අමාරුයි, අල්ලගන්න අමාරුයි, සහ සාමාන්‍ය පරීක්ෂණය අවශ්‍යයි, ඒකෙ සහ හැකිය AI-mediated ප්‍රශ්නයක් තීරණ පද්ධතිය, පරිගණනය ආරක්ෂක පද්ධතියෙන් තියෙන්න ඕන, පරිගණනය ආරක්ෂක පද්ධතියෙන් තියෙන්නේ ප්‍රයෝජන විශ්නය නැති කරන මේ පැත්තේ ආරක්ෂක අවස්ථාවක් දෙකක් විස්තර කරනවා ආරක්ෂක අවස්ථාවක් වෙනුවෙන්: (1) මොඩල් අවස්ථාවක් නොස්ථාවක් වෙනුවෙන් අවස්ථාවක් සහ පර මේ ආරක්ෂක ආරක්ෂකයෝ ස්වයංක්‍රීය භාෂාව පරීක්ෂණ විදියට ස්වයංක්‍රීය විදියට කතාවක් මතක් කරප මිනිස්සු වලින් ලූප් පද්ධතියේ ඉගෙන ගන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්නේ, මොඩේල් වලින් ආරක්ෂක ආරක්ෂකය සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න පුළුවන් රෝ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>روانپزشکی تحقیقات کی بڑھتی ہوئی مقدار میں ماشین کی تعلیم اور طبیعی زبان پردازی طریقوں میں شامل ہوتی ہے، لیکن اچھی طریقوں کو حقیقی کلینیکی تصمیم پشتیبانی سیستموں میں ترجمہ نہیں کیا جاتا۔ ان تعلیمات میں سے بہت سی نسبت چھوٹی ڈیٹ سٹوں پر بنیاد ہیں جن کے پاس مشترک خطر ہے کہ موڈل کو حقیقی کلینیکی تجارت میں نئی ڈیٹ پر اچھی طرح عمل نہیں کرسکتے۔ سنگین روانی بیماری کی طبیعت یہ ہے کہ تعریف کرنے، پکڑنے کے لئے مشکل ہے اور بہت سی مواظب کرنے کی ضرورت ہے، جہاں آبریٹ اور کلاس غږ مشکل ہیں، غیر پاکیزہ دکھانے کی وجہ ہے. ایک مفید AI-میڈیٹ کلینیکی تصمیم مدد سیسٹم کے ذریعہ سے کامپیوتروں کی امن نگہبانی موجود ہونا چاہیے کہ ان موڈلوں پر استعمال کیے جاتے ہیں کہ مضبوط پیش بینی سے منع کریں اور اسی طرح انسانوں کو ایسی سیٹیوں میں ڈاٹ کی حفاظت کریں جہاں موڈلوں unstable یا عمو This paper describes two approaches to implementing safeguards: (1) the determination of cases in which models are unstable by attribute and class based outlier detection and (2) finding the extent to which models show inductive bias. یہ امن نگہبانوں کو طبیعی زبان پردازی طریقے سے ایک کہانی کو یاد کرنے کے لئے اٹوٹ سکونٹ میں دکھایا جاتا ہے. انسان کی لاپ میں ماشین کی تعلیم کے ساتھ کلینیکی عملومات کی پروسس میں، ایسے امن گارڈوں میں شامل کرتا ہے جیسے یہ موڈل میں ہیں، بیماروں کو ضروری پیش بینی سے زیادہ محافظت دے گا۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>அதிகரிக்கும் நிறைய மையப்பட்ட ஆராய்ச்சி இயந்திரம் கற்றல் மற்றும் இயற்கையான மொழி செயல்படுத்தல் முறைகளை உள்ளடக்குகிறது, ஆனால் முடிவுகள இந்த பெரும்பாலான ஆய்வுகள் ஒருங்கிணைத்த மக்களில் சிறிய தரவுத்தளங்களை அடிப்படையாக இருக்கிறது, இது தொடர்புடைய ஆபத்தில் இருக்கிறது, ம தீவிரமான மனநோய் என்பது என்னவென்றால், பிடிப்பதற்கு கடினமானது, மற்றும் வேகமாக கண்காணிப்பது தேவைப்படும், அது குணப்பு மற்றும் வகுப்பு ஒலி பொ செயல்படுத்தப்பட்ட AI-mediated சுகாதாரண தீர்ப்பு ஆதரவு முறைமையின் இலக்குக் கொண்டு மாதிரிகளில் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட கணக்கிட்ட பாதுகாப்பு இந்த தாள் பாதுகாப்புகாப்புகளை செயல்படுத்த இரண்டு வழிகளை குறிப்பிடுகிறது: (1) குணங்கள் மற்றும் வகுப்பு அடிப்படையில் உள்ள மாதிரியாக இருக்கும் மூலம் த இந்த பாது மாதிரிகளில் பாதுகாப்புகாப்பாற்றுகளை சேர்த்து கொள்ளும் மனிதன் உள்ளிடும் கணினியை ஒருங்கிணைக்கும் போது நோயாளிகளின் பாதுகாப்பு ம</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Ko'pchilik taʼminlovchisi mashinani o'rganish va tabiiy tilni boshqarish usullarini o'rganish mumkin, ammo o o'zgarishlarni hozirga qoʻllash tizimga tarjima qilish kerak. Bu bir nechta o'qituvchilar faqat bir necha maʼlumot satrlariga asoslangan. Bu holatda modellar ҳақиқий klinik tizimida yangi maʼlumotga yetarli narsa bajarishi mumkin mumkin. Muhimlik kasalliklarning tabi, qabul qilish qiyin va ko'p monitorlash kerak, bu hodisa va sinfning tovushlari umumiy bo'lgan maʼlumotga ega bo'lishi mumkin. Name Bu qogʻoz xavfsizlikni bajarish uchun ikkita usulni aytish mumkin: (1) xususiyatlarni ajratish mumkin, holatning asosida va sinfning asosida ko'proq qismini aniqlash imkoniyatini va (2) modellarning xususiyatlarini aniqlash imkoniyatini topishi mumkin. Bu xavfsizlik asboblar asl tilni boshqarish usullari bilan avtomatik ravishda aniqlanadi. Ko'pchilik jarayonini o'rganish odamlarni birlashtirishda, bu modellarga xavfsizliklarni qo'shish mumkin. Bu modellarda qo'llanmalarning ko'proq kutishdan foydalanishini qo'shiladi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Một số lượng lớn nghiên cứu tâm thần liên quan đến việc học máy móc và phương pháp xử lý ngôn ngữ tự nhiên, tuy nhiên những phát hiện chưa được dịch thành hệ thống hỗ trợ quyết định lâm sàng. Hầu hết các nghiên cứu này dựa trên một dữ liệu nhỏ tương đối trong một dân số đồng bộ, có khả năng các mô phỏng không cung cấp đầy đủ dựa trên dữ liệu mới trong thực tế kinh tế lâm sàng. Tính chất của bệnh tâm thần nghiêm trọng là nó rất khó xác định, khó thu được, và yêu cầu giám sát thường xuyên, dẫn đến những dữ liệu không hoàn hảo ở những nơi thường có nhạc cụ và tiếng ồn lớp. Với mục đích của một hệ thống hỗ trợ quyết định tỉnh táo dựa trên AI hiệu quả, phải có biện pháp bảo vệ tính trên các mẫu được đặt ra để tránh những dự đoán giả tạo và cho phép con người xem lại dữ liệu trong những thiết lập không ổn định hay không thể tổng hợp. Tờ giấy này mô tả hai phương pháp để thực hiện biện pháp bảo vệ: 1) xác định các trường hợp các mô-đun không ổn định bằng cách phát hiện con người ngoài giá trị hàng lớp và (2) xác định tỷ lệ dẫn đầu của mô hình. Những biện pháp bảo mật này được minh họa trong việc ghi âm một nhiệm vụ phục hồi truyện bằng phương pháp xử lý ngôn ngữ tự nhiên. Với việc nhập vào hệ thống máy tính con người trong vòng học trong tiến trình ứng dụng lâm sàng, hợp những biện pháp an toàn như thế này vào các mô hình sẽ giúp bệnh nhân được bảo vệ khỏi những dự đoán sai lầm.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Все повече психиатрични изследвания включват машинно обучение и методи за обработка на естествения език, но резултатите все още не са преведени в реални системи за подкрепа на клиничните решения. Много от тези проучвания се основават на сравнително малки набори от данни при хомогенни популации, което има свързания риск моделите да не работят адекватно на нови данни в реалната клинична практика. Естеството на сериозното психично заболяване е, че е трудно да се определи, трудно да се улови и изисква често наблюдение, което води до несъвършени данни, където атрибутът и шумът от класа са често срещани. С цел постигане на ефективна система за подкрепа на клиничните решения, посредством ИИ, трябва да има изчислителни предпазни мерки върху използваните модели, за да се избегнат фалшиви прогнози и по този начин да се позволи на хората да преглеждат данните в условия, в които моделите са нестабилни или не са обвързани с генерализиране. Настоящата статия описва два подхода за прилагане на предпазни мерки: (1) определяне на случаите, в които моделите са нестабилни чрез откриване на отклонения въз основа на атрибути и класове и (2) намиране на степента, в която моделите показват индуктивно отклонение. Тези предпазни мерки са илюстрирани в автоматизираното оценяване на задача за припомняне на история чрез методи за обработка на естествен език. С интегрирането на машинното обучение в процеса на клинично изпълнение, включването на предпазни мерки като тези в моделите ще предложи на пациентите повишена защита от фалшиви прогнози.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Een toenemende hoeveelheid psychiatrisch onderzoek omvat machine learning en natuurlijke taalverwerkingsmethoden, maar bevindingen moeten nog worden vertaald in werkelijke klinische beslissingssystemen. Veel van deze studies zijn gebaseerd op relatief kleine datasets in homogene populaties, wat het risico inhoudt dat de modellen niet voldoende presteren op basis van nieuwe gegevens in de praktijk. De aard van ernstige psychische aandoeningen is dat deze moeilijk te definiëren zijn, moeilijk te vangen zijn en frequente monitoring vereisen, wat leidt tot onvolledige gegevens waar kenmerk- en klassenruis gebruikelijk zijn. Met het doel van een effectief AI-gemedieerd klinisch beslissingsondersteuningssysteem, moeten er computationele veiligheidsmaatregelen worden geplaatst op de gebruikte modellen om valse voorspellingen te voorkomen en zo mensen in staat te stellen gegevens te beoordelen in omgevingen waar modellen instabiel zijn of niet generaliseren. Dit artikel beschrijft twee benaderingen voor het implementeren van veiligheidsmaatregelen: (1) het vaststellen van gevallen waarin modellen instabiel zijn door middel van attribuut- en klasse-gebaseerde uitschieters detectie en (2) het vaststellen van de mate waarin modellen inductieve bias vertonen. Deze veiligheidsmaatregelen worden geïllustreerd in het geautomatiseerde scoren van een story recall taak via natuurlijke taalverwerkingsmethoden. Met de integratie van human-in-the-loop machine learning in het klinische implementatieproces zal het opnemen van dergelijke beveiligingsmaatregelen in de modellen patiënten meer bescherming bieden tegen valse voorspellingen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>En stigende mængde psykiatrisk forskning omfatter maskinlæring og metoder til behandling af naturligt sprog, men resultaterne er endnu ikke omsat til faktiske kliniske beslutningsstøttesystemer. Mange af disse undersøgelser er baseret på relativt små datasæt i homogene populationer, hvilket har den tilhørende risiko for, at modellerne måske ikke fungerer tilstrækkeligt på nye data i reel klinisk praksis. Karakteren af alvorlig psykisk sygdom er, at den er svær at definere, svær at fange og kræver hyppig overvågning, hvilket fører til ufuldstændige data, hvor egenskaber og klassestøj er almindelige. Med målet om et effektivt AI-medieret klinisk beslutningsstøttesystem skal der være beregningsmæssige sikkerhedsforanstaltninger placeret på de anvendte modeller for at undgå falske forudsigelser og dermed give mennesker mulighed for at gennemgå data i de omgivelser, hvor modeller er ustabile eller forpligtet til ikke at generalisere. Dette dokument beskriver to tilgange til implementering af sikkerhedsforanstaltninger: (1) bestemmelse af tilfælde, hvor modeller er ustabile ved hjælp af attribut- og klassebaseret afvigende detektion og (2) finde i hvilket omfang modellerne viser induktiv bias. Disse sikkerhedsforanstaltninger illustreres i den automatiserede scoring af en historietilbagekaldelsesopgave via metoder til behandling af naturligt sprog. Med integrationen af human-in-the-loop machine learning i den kliniske implementeringsproces vil integreringen af sådanne sikkerhedsforanstaltninger i modellerne give patienterne øget beskyttelse mod falske forudsigelser.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Sebuah jumlah penelitian psikiatri yang meningkat mengangkut belajar mesin dan metode proses bahasa alam, bagaimanapun penemuan belum diterjemahkan ke sistem dukungan keputusan klinis yang sebenarnya. Many of these studies are based on relatively small datasets in homogeneous populations, which has the associated risk that the models may not perform adequately on new data in real clinical practice.  Alam penyakit mental yang serius adalah bahwa sulit untuk mendefinisikan, sulit untuk ditangkap, dan membutuhkan pengawasan sering, yang mengarah ke data yang tidak sempurna di mana atribut dan suara kelas adalah umum. Dengan tujuan sistem dukungan keputusan klinik yang efektif mediasi AI, harus ada perlindungan komputasi yang ditempatkan pada model yang digunakan untuk menghindari prediksi yang mengganggu dan sehingga memungkinkan manusia untuk meninjau data dalam pengaturan di mana model tidak stabil atau terikat untuk tidak menyebarkan. Kertas ini menjelaskan dua pendekatan untuk memaksa perlindungan: (1) penentuan kasus di mana model tidak stabil dengan cara atribut dan kelas berdasarkan deteksi luar dan (2) menemukan jangkauan ke mana model menunjukkan bias induktif. Perlindungan ini diilustrasikan dalam skor otomatis dari tugas recall cerita melalui metode proses bahasa alami. Dengan integrasi pembelajaran mesin manusia-dalam-loop dalam proses implementasi klinik, memasukkan perlindungan seperti ini ke dalam model akan menambah perlindungan pasien dari prediksi yang menggerunkan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Ein wachsender Teil der psychiatrischen Forschung umfasst maschinelles Lernen und natürliche Sprachverarbeitungsmethoden, jedoch müssen die Erkenntnisse noch in tatsächliche klinische Entscheidungsunterstützungssysteme übersetzt werden. Viele dieser Studien basieren auf relativ kleinen Datensätzen in homogenen Populationen, was das Risiko birgt, dass die Modelle auf neuen Daten in der realen klinischen Praxis nicht ausreichend funktionieren. Schwere psychische Erkrankungen sind schwer zu definieren, schwer zu erfassen und erfordern eine häufige Überwachung, was zu unvollkommenen Daten führt, bei denen Attribut- und Klassenrauschen häufig vorkommen. Mit dem Ziel eines effektiven KI-vermittelten klinischen Entscheidungsunterstützungssystems müssen die verwendeten Modelle computergestützt abgesichert werden, um falsche Vorhersagen zu vermeiden und so den Menschen zu ermöglichen, Daten in Umgebungen zu überprüfen, in denen Modelle instabil sind oder nicht generalisiert werden müssen. Die vorliegende Arbeit beschreibt zwei Ansätze zur Implementierung von Schutzmaßnahmen: (1) die Bestimmung von Fällen, in denen Modelle instabil sind, mittels attribut- und klassenbasierter Ausreißerdetektion und (2) die Bestimmung des Ausmaßes, in dem Modelle induktive Verzerrungen aufweisen. Diese Sicherheitsvorkehrungen werden in der automatisierten Bewertung einer Story-Recall-Aufgabe mittels natürlicher Sprachverarbeitungsmethoden veranschaulicht. Durch die Integration von Human-in-the-Loop Machine Learning in den klinischen Implementierungsprozess bietet die Integration solcher Schutzmechanismen in die Modelle den Patienten erhöhten Schutz vor falschen Vorhersagen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_hr>Povećana količina psihijatrijskih istraživanja uključuje metode učenja i obrade prirodnog jezika, međutim, nalazi još uvijek nisu prevedeni u stvarne sustave potpore kliničkih odluka. Mnogi od tih ispitivanja su temeljeni na relativno malim podacima u homogennim populacijama, koja ima povezan rizik da modeli ne mogu adekvatno izvršiti na novim podacima u stvarnoj kliničkoj praksi. Priroda ozbiljne mentalne bolesti je da je teško definirati, teško uhvatiti i zahtijevati često praćenje, što vodi do nepovršenih podataka gdje su pripis i zvuk klase zajednički. S ciljem učinkovitog sustava podrške kliničkim odlukama koji posreduje AI, moraju biti računalne sigurnosti postavljene na modele koji se koriste kako bi se izbjegavali neprekidne predviđanja i tako omogućili ljudima da pregledaju podatke u postavkama gdje su modeli nestabilni ili ne obavezni za generalizaciju. Ovaj papir opisuje dva pristupa provedbi sigurnosnih čuvara: 1) određivanje slučajeva u kojima su modeli nestabilni s pomoću otkrivanja atributa i klase temeljenih izvještaja i 2) pronalaženja mjere u kojoj se modeli pokazuju induktivne predrasude. Ove zaštite su ilustrirane u automatskom izvještaju priče koja se sjeća zadatka prirodnim metodama obrade jezika. U kliničkom procesu provedbe, uključujući sigurnosne zaštite poput ovih u modele, ponudit će pacijentima povećanu zaštitu od strašnih predviđanja.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_ko>점점 더 많은 정신병학 연구가 기계 학습과 자연 언어 처리 방법을 결합시켰지만 연구 결과는 아직 실제 임상 결정 지원 시스템으로 전환되지 않았다.이러한 연구 중 많은 것이 동질인 사람들 중 상대적으로 작은 데이터 집합을 바탕으로 이루어진 것이다. 이것은 관련 위험이 있다. 즉, 이런 모델들은 실제 임상 실천에서 새로운 데이터를 충분히 집행하지 못할 수도 있다.심각한 정신질환의 본질은 정의하기 어렵고 포착하기 어려우며 빈번한 모니터링이 필요하다. 이로 인해 속성과 소음이 흔히 볼 수 있는 데이터가 완선하지 않다.효과적인 인공지능이 개도하는 임상 결정 지원 시스템을 구축하기 위해서는 사용된 모델에 대해 계산 보호 조치를 취해 허위 예측을 피하고 인류가 모델이 불안정하거나 요약할 수 없는 상황에서 데이터를 심사할 수 있도록 해야 한다.본고는 두 가지 보장 조치를 실현하는 방법을 묘사했다. (1) 속성과 유형을 바탕으로 하는 이군점 검측을 통해 모델이 불안정한 상황을 확정하고 (2) 모델이 귀납적 편차를 나타내는 정도를 찾아낸다.자연 언어 처리 방법을 통해 이야기 회상 임무에 대한 자동 평점은 이러한 보장 조치를 설명한다.사람들이 회로기계 학습이 임상 실시 과정에서 통합됨에 따라 이러한 보장 조치를 모델에 포함시키면 환자에게 허위 예측의 영향을 받지 않도록 더욱 큰 보호를 제공할 것이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>A growing amount of psychiatric research incorporates machine learning and natural language processing methods, however findings have yet to be translated into actual clinical decision support systems.  Tafiti nyingi hizi zinatumiwa na seti ndogo katika idadi ya watu mashoga, ambazo zina hatari inayohusiana na kuwa miundo mbinu hazijaweza kutekeleza takwimu mpya katika mazoea halisi ya kliniki. Huduma ya ugonjwa mkubwa wa akili ni kwamba ni vigumu kuelezea, vigumu kukamatwa, na inahitaji ufuatiliaji wa mara kwa mara, ambapo unapelekea taarifa zisizo sahihi ambapo sauti za tabaka na sauti za darasa ni kawaida. Kwa lengo la mfumo wa uungwaji wa uamuzi wa kliniki uliotengenezwa kati ya AI, lazima kuwepo na ulinzi wa kompyuta uliotumiwa ili kuepuka utabiri mkubwa na kwa hiyo kuwaruhusu binadamu kuangalia taarifa katika mazingira ambayo mifumo hayana imara au inalazimika kutokujalisha. Kanisa hili linaelezea mbili mbili za kutekeleza ulinzi: (1) uamuzi wa kesi ambazo mifano hayana imara kwa njia ya utambuzi na darasa lililoko nje zaidi na (2) kutafuta kiwango ambacho mifano inaonyesha upendeleo wa viwanda. Ulinzi hawa unaonyesha katika kuchukuliwa kwa moja kwa moja katika kazi ya hadithi inayokumbuka kupitia njia za upasuaji wa lugha asili. Kutokana na kuunganishwa kwa mashine ya binadamu yanayojifunza katika mchakato wa utekelezaji wa kliniki, kuingiza ulinzi kama vile hizi katika mifano yatawapa wagonjwa kuongezeka ulinzi dhidi ya utabiri usio na nguvu.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>تعداد افزایش تحقیقات روانپزشکی شامل یادگیری ماشین و روش‌های پرداخت زبان طبیعی است، ولی یادگیری هنوز به سیستم حمایت تصمیم‌گیری کلینیک ترجمه نمی‌شوند. بسیاری از این تحقیقات بر اساس مجموعه‌های داده‌های نسبتا کوچک در جمعیت‌های همجنس است که خطر ارتباط دارد که مدل‌ها ممکن است به اندازه کافی بر داده‌های جدید در تمرین کلینیک واقعی انجام ندهند. طبيعت بيماري رواني جدي اينه که تعريف کردن، دستگير کردن، سخت است و نياز به تماشاگر اغلب است، که به اطلاعات غير کامل مي رسد جايي که خصوصي و صداي کلاس مشترک هستند. با هدف یک سیستم حمایت تصمیم کلینیک با AI موثر، باید محافظت محاسبه‌های کامپیوتری بر مدل‌های استفاده شده باشد تا از پیش‌بینی‌های ناپذیری فرار کند و به این‌سان به مردم اجازه دهد که داده‌ها را در تنظیمات‌هایی که مدل‌ها ناپذیر و ناپذیر هستند، تحقیق کنند این کاغذ دو دستیابی برای عملکرد نگهبان را توصیف می‌کند: (۱) تعیین کردن پرونده‌هایی که مدل‌ها به وسیله شناسایی خصوصیت‌ها و درجه‌های بیرون‌آوری‌های پایه‌دار و (۲) پیدا کردن اندازه‌ای که مدل‌ها به کجا روی‌آوری‌های فعال این نگهبانان در جستجوی اتوماتیک یک داستان از طریق روش‌های پرداخت زبان طبیعی نشان داده می‌شوند. با آموزش ماشین‌های انسان در داخل لوپ در فرایند عملکرد کلینیکی، شامل نگهبانی مانند این‌ها در مدل‌ها، بیماران را از پیش‌بینی‌های ناراحتی افزایش محافظت می‌دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Psikiýatik araştyrmalaryň köp bölegi maşynyň öwrenmesi we tebigy diller işlemesi ýoldaşdyr, ýöne tapylar kliniýa karar sistemalara entek terjime edilmeli. Bu araştyrmalaryň köpüsi homogeniýan milletlerinde ýakyn kiçi maglumat setirlerine daýanýar, nusgalaryň hakyky klinikiýa praktikada täze maglumatlarda ýeterlik ýagdaýa mümkin däldir. Gowy duýgyn ýarawsyzlyklaryň tebigaty düşünmek kyn, ýaramak kyn we köplenç gözlemek gerek bolup, hatlaryň we klas sesiniň orta bolan ýerde netijeli maglumatlara ýok edýär. AI-mediýanly klinik karar sistemi golaýynyň amasynda, nusgasyzlyk öňünden çykmak üçin ullanýan hasaplançylyk goraglary bar we bu şekilde adamlaryň modelleriň stabil ýa-da döredilemeýän düzümlerde maglumatlary barlamagyna rugsat bermesine mümkin edýär. Bu kagyz goragçylary implementlemek üçin iki gollany tassyýar: (1) nusgalaryň häzirde atribut we klas tabanly çykyş tanyşylary bilen stabiliz däldigini tassyýar we (2) nusgalaryň nähili indukýa sowgatlary görkezýär. Bu goragçylar tebigy dil işleýän yöntemleri bilen ýazylan hekaýanyň otomatik almasynda görkezildi. Adam loop sistemasynda kliniki implementasynda öwrenmek isleýän maşynynyň integrasy bilen, nusgalary şol ýaly nusgalary daşarylýar we hastalary tarapyndan goramagyny köpräk berer.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>'n groei hoeveelheid psychiatric research inkorpreer masjien leer en natuurlike taal verwerking metodes, maar gevinde moet nog oorweeg word in werklike kliniske besluidingsstelsels. Baie van hierdie studie is gebaseer op relativief klein datastelle in homogeen populasie, wat die geassosieerde risiko het dat die modele dalk nie adequate uitvoer op nuwe data in reël kliniese praksie nie. Die natuur van ernstige mentale siekte is dat dit moeilik is om te definieer, moeilik om te vang en te benodig dikwels monitoring, wat lei na onvolledige data waar attribute en klas ruis gemeenskap is. Met die doel van 'n effektief AI-mediaerde kliniske besluit stelsel, moet daar rekenaar veiligheide wees wat op die modele gebruik word om verskeie voorskoue te verdwyn en dus toelaat mense data te hersien in die instellings waar modele is unstable of nie gebind om te genereer nie. Hierdie papier beskrywe twee toegang tot die implementering van veilighede: (1) die bepaal van gevalle waarin modele is onstabile deur die eienskappe en klas gebaseerde buitenskappe beskrywing en (2) die uitbreiding waarmee modele induktiewe voorspoedige vertoon word. Hierdie veilighede is illustreer in die outomatiese skaring van 'n storie herhaal taak deur natuurlike taal verwerking metodes. Met die integrasie van menslike-in-loop-masjien leer in die kliniese implementasie-proses, by die inkorporering van veilighede soos hierdie in die modele sal paciente verhoog beskerming van verwagte voorskou.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>A growing amount of psychiatric research incorporates machine learning and natural language processing methods, however findings have yet to be translated into actual clinical decision support systems.  Այս ուսումնասիրություններից շատերը հիմնված են համեմատաբար փոքր տվյալների համակարգերի վրա, որոնք ունեն համախմբված ռիսկի, որ մոդելները իրական կլինիկական գործընթացում նոր տվյալների վրա բավարար չափով չեն աշխատում: Շատ լուրջ մտավոր հիվանդությունների բնույթն այն է, որ դժվար է սահմանել, դժվար է ընկալել և պահանջում է հաճախ վերահսկողություն, ինչը հանգեցնում է անկատարյալ տվյալներին, որտեղ առանձնահատկությունները և դասարանի աղմուկը ԱԲ-ի միջոցով արդյունավետ կլինիկական որոշումների աջակցության համակարգի նպատակով, պետք է հաշվարկների պաշտպանություններ տեղադրվեն մոդելների վրա, որոնք օգտագործվում են, որպեսզի խուսափեն խիստ կանխատեսումներից և այնպես թույլ տան մարդկանց վերանայել տվյալները այնպիսի This paper describes two approaches to implementing safeguards: (1) the determination of cases in which models are unstable by means of attribute and class based outlier detection and (2) finding the extent to which models show inductive bias.  Այս պաշտպանությունները ցույց են տալիս պատմության վերադարձման խնդիրների ավտոմատիկ գնահատման մեթոդներով: Մարդկային-շրջանակի մեքենայի ուսումնասիրության ինտեգրացումը կլինիկական իրականացման գործընթացի մեջ, ներառելով այնպիսի պաշտպանակներ, ինչպիսիք են սրանք մոդելների մեջ, հիվանդներին կտա ավելի մեծ պաշտպանություն խիստ կանխատեսում</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu psikiyatrik araştırmaların böyüklüyü maşın öyrənməsi və təbiətli dil işləmə metodlarını birləşdirir, amma tapılmaların hələ də həqiqətən klinik karar vermək sistemlərinə çevirilmesi lazımdır. Bu araştırmaların çoxu homogeniyal nümunələrdə çox kiçik verilən qurbanlara dayanan, modellərin həqiqət kliniki praksiyada yeni məlumatlarda yeterli olması mümkün olan riski var. Ciddi ruhsal xəstəliyinin təbiəti təsdiqlənmək, tutmaq zordur və çox sıxıntılı gözləmə ehtiyacı vardır. Bu təbiəti və sınıf səslərinin ortaq olduğu təbiətlərin tamamlanmasız məlumatlarına yol açar. Müvəffəqi AI-medialı klinik karar sisteminin dəstəklərinin məqsədilə, modellərin istifadə edilməsi və ya generalizməsi üçün istifadə edilməsi üçün modellərə istifadə edilməsi üçün hesablama mühafizəçiləri olmalı və insanlara modellərin istifadə edilməsi üçün verilən məlumatları dərhal dəyişdirməyə izin verməlidir. Bu kağıt təhlükəsizliklərin istifadə etməsi üçün iki tərzim tərzini təsdiqləyir: 1) modellərin nəticəsi və sınıf təhlükəsizlikləri vasitəsilə istifadə edilməsi və 2) modellərin nəticəsi təhlükəsizlikləri göstərməsi üçün istifadə edilməsi olaraq çəkilir. Bu təhlükəsizlər təbiətli dil işləmə metodları vasitəsilə bir hekayənin avtomatik təhlükəsində göstərilmişdir. İnsan-in-loop makinelərin birləşdirilməsi ilə kliniki istifadə sürətində, modellərə bənzər mühafizəçilərin birləşdirilməsi təsirli tədbirlərdən xəstələrə mühafizəçilik artıracaq.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_sq>Një sasi në rritje kërkimi psikiatrik përfshin mësimin e makinave dhe metodat natyrore të përdorimit të gjuhës, megjithatë gjetjet ende nuk duhet përkthyer në sistemet aktuale të mbështetjes së vendimeve klinike. Shumë nga këto studime janë bazuar në grupe të dhënash relativisht të vogla në popullsitë homogjene, e cila ka rrezikun e lidhur që modelet mund të mos kryejnë në mënyrë të përshtatshme mbi të dhënat e reja në praktikën reale klinike. Natyra e sëmundjeve mentale serioze është se është e vështirë të përcaktohet, e vështirë të kapet dhe kërkon mbikqyrje të shpeshtë, e cila çon në të dhëna të papërshtatshme ku atributet dhe zhurma e klasës janë të zakonshme. Me qëllimin e një sistemi efektiv të mbështetjes së vendimeve klinike të ndërmjetësuar nga AI, duhet të ketë mbrojtje kompjuterike të vendosura në modelet e përdorura me qëllim që të shmangin parashikimet e shqetësueshme dhe kështu të lejojnë njerëzit të shqyrtojnë të dhënat në rregullimet ku modelet janë të paqëndrueshëm apo të lidhur për të mos gjeneralizuar Ky dokument përshkruan dy qasje për zbatimin e mbrojtjeve: (1) përcaktimin e rasteve në të cilat modelet janë të paqëndrueshëm nëpërmjet zbulimit të atributeve dhe klasave të jashtme dhe (2) gjetjen e shkallës në të cilën modelet tregojnë paragjykim induktiv. Këto mbrojtje janë ilustruar në shënimin e automatizuar të një detyre të tërheqjes së historisë nëpërmjet metodave natyrore të përdorimit të gjuhës. Me integrimin e mësimit të makinerisë njerëzore-në-loop në procesin e zbatimit klinik, përfshirja e mbrojtjeve të tilla si këto në modele do të ofrojë pacientëve mbrojtje të rritur nga parashikimet e shqetësueshme.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bs>Povećana količina psihijatrijskih istraživanja uključuje metode učenja strojeva i prirodnog jezika, međutim, nalazi još uvijek nisu prevedeni u stvarne sisteme podrške kliničkih odluka. Mnogi od tih ispitivanja su temeljeni na relativno malim podacima u homogennim populacijama, koja ima povezan rizik da modeli ne mogu adekvatno izvršiti na novim podacima u stvarnoj kliničkoj praksi. Priroda ozbiljne mentalne bolesti je da je teško definisati, teško uhvatiti i zahtijevati često praćenje, što vodi do nepovršenih podataka gdje su atributi i zvuk klase zajednički. Sa ciljem efikasnog sustava podrške kliničkih odluka koji posreduje AI, moraju biti računalne sigurnosti postavljene na modele koji se koriste kako bi izbjegli neprijatne predviđanja i tako omogućili ljudima da pregledaju podatke u postavkama gdje su modeli nestabilni ili ne povezani da se generalizuju. Ovaj papir opisuje dva pristupa provedbi sigurnosnih zaštita: 1) određivanje slučajeva u kojima su modeli nestabilni pomoću otkrivanja atributa i klase otkrivanja izveštaja i 2) pronalaženja mjere u kojoj modeli pokazuju induktivne predrasude. Ove zaštite su ilustrirane u automatskom izvještaju priče koja se sjeća zadatka putem metoda obrade prirodnog jezika. U kliničkom procesu provedbe, uključujući sigurnosne zaštite poput ovih u modele, ponudit će pacijentima povećanu zaštitu od strašnih predviđanja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_am>ብዛት የpsychiatric ምርመራ ማስተማርንና የፍጥረቱ ቋንቋ ማቀናቀሚያ ሥርዓቶችን ያስተካክላል፤ ነገር ግን ፍጥረቶቹ ገና ወደ እውነተኛ የኪኒካሌ ውሳኔ የድጋፍ ምርጫዎችን ለመተረጉም አይችሉም፡፡ ከእነዚህ ብዙ ትምህርት በተጨማሪው ጥቂት ዳታዎችን በመስመር ላይ በመሠረት ነው፤ እናም ምሳሌዎቹ በአዲስ ቅድሚያ ፕሮግራም ውስጥ አዲስ ዳታዎችን በማስፈልግ አይችሉም፡፡ የደካማ ደዌ ሥርዓት፣ ለመያዝ ማረጋገጥ፣ ለመግለጽ አጭንቅ ነው፣ በቁጥጥር ማየት ያስፈልጋል፡፡ አ-አ-መካከለኛ የቻይና የጥያቄ የፍትወት ድጋፍ ስርዓት በተደረገ ጉዳይ፣ ለጥያቄ ትንቢት ለመራቀቅ በሚደረጉት ዓይነቶች ላይ የተደረገ የቁጥጥር ደጋጊዎች ሊኖሩ ይገባዋል፡፡ ይህ ፕሮግራም የደህንነት መግለጫ ለመፈለግ ሁለት ደረጃዎችን ይናገራል:(1) በጥቅምት እና በክፍለ ክፍል ላይ የተመሳሳይ እና (2) መተላለፊያዎች የደህንነት ክፍል በሚያሳየው ጥያቄ እና የክፍለ ጥያቄ ጥያቄ በሚያሳየው ጥያቄ እና (2) እነዚህ ደኅንነት በተፈጠረው ቋንቋ ማቀናቀል ሥርዓት በተለየ የታሪክ ማስታወስ ስራትን በተለየ ነው፡፡ በቻሎኒካዊ አካባቢ ፕሮጀክት ውስጥ የሰው ድምፅ ማውቀትን በተጠቃቀሙ ጊዜ፣ እንደነዚህ በዓይነቶች ውስጥ ያሉትን ደኅንነትን በመጠቀም፣ ደካማዎችን ከጥልቅ ትንቢት ከታዋቂዎች መጠበቅ ይጨመርላቸዋል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_cs>Rostoucí množství psychiatrického výzkumu zahrnuje strojové učení a metody zpracování přirozeného jazyka, nicméně poznatky ještě nebyly převedeny do skutečných systémů podpory klinického rozhodování. Mnohé z těchto studií jsou založeny na relativně malých datových souborech homogenních populací, což s sebou spojuje riziko, že modely nemusí dostatečně fungovat na základě nových dat v reálné klinické praxi. Povaha závažných duševních onemocnění spočívá v tom, že je obtížné definovat, obtížně zachytit a vyžaduje časté sledování, což vede k nedokonalým údajům, kde jsou atributy a šum třídy běžné. S cílem efektivního systému podpory klinického rozhodování zprostředkovaného umělou inteligencí musí být na používané modely umístěna výpočetní ochrana, aby se zabránilo falešným předpovědím a umožnilo lidem přezkoumat data v prostředí, kde jsou modely nestabilní nebo vázané k zobecňování. Tento článek popisuje dva přístupy k implementaci ochranných opatření: (1) určení případů, kdy jsou modely nestabilní pomocí detekce atributů a tříd založené na odlehlých lištách a (2) zjištění míry, do jaké modely vykazují indukční zkreslení. Tyto bezpečnostní opatření jsou ilustrovány v automatizovaném skórování úkolu vyvolání příběhu pomocí metod zpracování přirozeného jazyka. Díky integraci strojového učení člověka ve smyčce do klinického implementačního procesu nabídne začlenění takových ochranných opatření do modelů pacientům zvýšenou ochranu před falešnými predikcemi.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>Una quantitat creixent de recerca psiquiàtrica incorpora mètodes d'aprenentatge automàtic i de processament natural de llenguatges, però els descobriments encara no s'han traduit en sistemes de suport clínic real de decisions. Molts d'aquests estudis estan basats en conjunts de dades relativament petits en poblacions homogènes, que tenen el risc associat que els models no funcionin adequadament en les noves dades en pràctiques clíniques reals. La naturalesa de les malalties mentals graves és que és difícil de definir, difícil de capturar, i requereix una monitorització freqüent, que porta a dades imperfectes on els atributs i el soroll de classe són comuns. Amb l'objectiu d'un sistema eficaç de suport clínic de decisions mediat per AI, s'han de posar salvaguardies computacionals als models utilitzats per evitar prediccions espirituals i permetre així als humans revisar les dades en entorns on els models són instables o vinculats a no generalitzar-se. This paper describes two approaches to implementing safeguards: (1) the determination of cases in which models are unstable by means of attribute and class based outlier detection and (2) finding the extent to which models show inductive bias.  These safeguards are illustrated in the automated scoring of a story recall task via natural language processing methods.  Amb l'integració de l'aprenentatge de màquines humanes en circuit en el procés de implementació clínica, incorporar salvaguardies com aquestes als models oferirà als pacients una protecció més gran de les prediccions espirituals.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Üha suurem hulk psühhiaatrilisi uuringuid hõlmab masinõppe ja loodusliku keele töötlemise meetodeid, kuid tulemused ei ole veel tõlgendatud tegelikeks kliiniliste otsuste tugisüsteemideks. Paljud neist uuringutest põhinevad suhteliselt väikestel andmekogumitel homogeensetes populatsioonides, millega kaasneb risk, et mudelid ei pruugi reaalses kliinilises praktikas uute andmete põhjal piisavalt toimida. Tõsise vaimuhaiguse olemus seisneb selles, et seda on raske määratleda, raske jäädvustada ja nõuab sagedast jälgimist, mis viib ebatäiuslike andmeteni, kus atribuudi ja klassi müra on levinud. Tõhusa tehisintellekti poolt vahendatud kliiniliste otsuste toetamise süsteemi eesmärgil tuleb kasutatavatele mudelitele rakendada arvutuslikke kaitsemeetmeid, et vältida valeprognoose ja võimaldada seega inimestel vaadata andmeid olukordades, kus mudelid on ebastabiilsed või mitte üldistada. Käesolevas dokumendis kirjeldatakse kahte lähenemisviisi kaitsemeetmete rakendamisele: 1) nende juhtumite kindlaksmääramine, kus mudelid on ebastabiilsed atribuudi- ja klassipõhise võõrväärtuste tuvastamise abil, ja 2) mudelite induktiivse kallaku tuvastamise määramine. Neid kaitsemeetmeid illustreerib loo tagasikutsumise ülesande automaatne skoorimine looduskeele töötlemise meetodite abil. Inimese-silmuses masinõppe integreerimisega kliinilisesse rakendusprotsessi pakub selliste kaitsemeetmete lisamine mudelitesse patsientidele suuremat kaitset valede prognooside eest.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bn>বৃদ্ধির পরিমাণ মানসিক গবেষণা মেশিন শিক্ষা এবং প্রাকৃতিক ভাষা প্রক্রিয়ার পদ্ধতিতে অন্তর্ভুক্ত হয়েছে, তবে এখনো ক্লিনিক্যাল সিদ্ধ এই সমস্ত গবেষণাগুলোর অনেকেই সমকামীন জনসংখ্যাগুলোতে আপাতকভাবে ছোট ডাটাসেট ভিত্তিতে রয়েছে, যার সাথে সংশ্লিষ্ট ঝুঁকি রয়েছে যে মড গুরুত্বপূর্ণ মানসিক অসুস্থের প্রকৃতি হচ্ছে যে গ্রেফতারের জন্য কঠিন, গ্রেফতার করা কঠিন এবং প্রায়শ পর্যবেক্ষণের প্রয়োজন, যা কোথায় ব With the goal of an effective AI-mediated clinical decision support system, there must be computational safeguards placed on the models used in order to avoid spurious predictions and thus allow humans to review data in the settings where models are unstable or bound not to generalize.  এই প্রবন্ধে নিরাপত্তা ব্যবহারের জন্য দুটি পদ্ধতি বর্ণনা করেছে: (১) ক্ষেত্রের মাধ্যমে মডেলের সিদ্ধান্ত নির্ধারণ করা হয়েছে বৈশিষ্ট্য এবং ক্লাসের ভিত্ প্রাকৃতিক ভাষা প্রক্রিয়ার পদ্ধতির মাধ্যমে স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে একটি গল্পের স্মৃতির স্কোরে এই নিরাপত্তা নিরা ক্লিনিক্যাল প্রয়োগ প্রক্রিয়ায় মানুষ-লুপ-ইন-লুপ মেশিন শিক্ষা শিক্ষা প্রক্রিয়ার সাথে যোগাযোগ করার পর, যেমন মডেলে এই নিরাপত্তার সাথে য</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_fi>Yhä useammassa psykiatrisessa tutkimuksessa käytetään koneoppimista ja luonnollisen kielen käsittelymenetelmiä, mutta löydöksiä ei ole vielä käännetty todellisiksi kliinisten päätösten tukijärjestelmiksi. Monet näistä tutkimuksista perustuvat suhteellisen pieniin tietoaineistoihin homogeenisista populaatioista, johon liittyy riski, että mallit eivät välttämättä toimi riittävästi uusien tietojen perusteella todellisessa kliinisessä käytännössä. Vakavan mielenterveyssairauden luonne on se, että sitä on vaikea määritellä, vaikea tallentaa ja vaatii säännöllistä seurantaa, mikä johtaa epätäydellisiin tietoihin, joissa attribuutti- ja luokkamelu ovat yleisiä. Tehokkaan tekoälyvälitteisen kliinisen päätöksenteon tukijärjestelmän saavuttamiseksi malleihin on asetettava laskennallisia suojatoimia väärien ennusteiden välttämiseksi ja siten ihmisten on voitava tarkastella tietoja tilanteissa, joissa mallit ovat epävakaita tai eivät yleisty. Tässä artikkelissa kuvataan kahta lähestymistapaa suojatoimien toteuttamiseen: (1) sellaisten tapausten määrittäminen, joissa mallit ovat epävakaita attribuutti- ja luokkapohjaisen poikkeavien havaintojen avulla ja (2) mallien induktiivisen harhan määrittäminen. Näitä suojatoimia havainnollistetaan tarinan palautustehtävän automaattisessa pisteytyksessä luonnollisen kielen käsittelymenetelmillä. Kun human-in-the-loop koneoppiminen integroidaan kliiniseen käyttöönottoprosessiin, tällaisten suojatoimien sisällyttäminen malleihin tarjoaa potilaille paremman suojan valheellisilta ennusteilta.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé éntuk sistem sing perbudhakan kanggo resmi sistem sing nggawe barang kelas karo perusahaan winih, kuwi nggarap kuwi mau, dadi kapan kanggo ngerasakno sistem supoyo nggunakake sistem sing dadi. Awak dhéwé éntuk akeh pisan-sanggunaké iki dadi supoyo akeh dataset sing mengko nèng populer, sing ngewehke nggawe bener dhéwé kuwi model sing bisa akeh nggawe data in sing isiné kanggo praksi sing klènik. Ndheke sakjane sakjane isi nglarakno kuwi susah-susahe kuwi nggawe, gampang kanggo nggawe kethok, lan njukke dituruti ngucap akeh bantuan sing apik, sekondi kang data sing bakal terus nggawe atiribute lan kelas sing koyok barang. Wis Global bending"), ("Relative position to a reference point defines global bending direction and amount"), "bending direction Wonten keamanan langkung wigatining langkung wigatining perusahaan anyar tentang nggawe nguasai perusahaan winih. Dadine sistem sing beraksi perbudhakan-sangan sing diranggap karo sistem sing klènik, ingkang dipunangé keamanan sing luwih dumadhi sing nganggep kuwi model sing bisa pasar kanggo ngerasai perbudhakan langkung sampek.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Ana ƙari da lissafi na kasa yana cikin shirin karatun masu bara da karatun harshen na asali, kuma amma, ba za a taƙaita fassarar musamman ba zuwa tsarin ƙarami ta halinsa. Babu masu yawa daga wannan fassarar kwamfyuta ana ƙayyade data masu ƙarami a cikin wasu mutane da ke haɗuwa, wanda yana da risiko mai daidai cẽwa misãlai bã za su iya cika adequata kan data masu cikin mazaɓa na gaskiya. Tsarin kasar nau'i mai girma, yana da adadi a bayyana, mai tsanani wa kãma, kuma yana da muhimmar tsarin da ake buka, wanda yana ƙara wa data masu daidai a wurin da sauri na ƙayyade. Ga goan a yi amfani da tsarin taimakon kayan cire-AI-kafin, za'a sami tsarin lissafi wanda aka yi amfani da shi a kan misalin ayuka don ya yi amfani da shi dõmin kada ya iya lissafa ko kuma don ka yarda mutane su canza data a cikin kayan daidaita da misalin su ba'a tabbatar da su ko ba za'a zartar da shi ba. Wannan takardan na gaya wa hanyoyin biyu masu yin amfani da tsari: (1) hukuncin alama wanda misãlai za'a tabbatar da su a cikinsa, a bayan zane-zane da zane-zane masu ƙaranci kuma (2) ya gane gwargwadon da misãlai ke nuna tabar da masu kiyaye. An bayyana waɗannan tsari cikin shirin farat ɗaya na ƙidãya wa aikin wani historin da aka tunãtar da shi, a cikin hanyoyin aiki na fassarar harshen. Idan an haɗa mutum-in-loop-in-mazaɓa da aka karanta shi a cikin jarrabar zartar da kuma aka shigar da tsari kamar wannan a cikin misalin, za'a nuna wa wagonjwa tsari daga bastarwa.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Naraščajoče število psihiatričnih raziskav vključuje strojno učenje in metode obdelave naravnega jezika, vendar pa ugotovitve še niso prevedene v dejanske sisteme za podporo kliničnim odločanjem. Številne od teh študij temeljijo na relativno majhnih naborih podatkov pri homogenih populacijah, kar ima povezano tveganje, da modeli morda ne bodo ustrezno delovali na novih podatkih v resnični klinični praksi. Narava resnih duševnih bolezni je, da jih je težko opredeliti, težko zajeti in zahteva pogosto spremljanje, kar vodi do nepopolnih podatkov, kjer sta atributni in razredni hrup pogosti. Z namenom učinkovitega sistema podpore kliničnim odločanjem, ki ga posreduje AI, je treba na uporabljene modele uvesti računalniške varovalne ukrepe, da bi se izognili lažnim napovedovanjem in tako ljudem omogočili pregled podatkov v okoljih, kjer so modeli nestabilni ali se ne smejo posplošiti. Ta prispevek opisuje dva pristopa k izvajanju zaščitnih ukrepov: (1) določitev primerov, v katerih so modeli nestabilni z odkrivanjem oddaljenosti na podlagi atributov in razredov, ter (2) ugotavljanje obsega, v katerem modeli kažejo induktivno pristranskost. Ti zaščitni ukrepi so ponazorjeni z avtomatiziranim ocenjevanjem opravila odpoklica zgodbe z metodami obdelave naravnega jezika. Z vključitvijo strojnega učenja človeka v zanko v klinični proces izvajanja bo vključitev takšnih zaščitnih učinkov v modele bolnikom ponudila večjo zaščito pred lažnimi napovedi.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>A growing amount of psychiatric research incorporates machine learning and natural language processing methods, however findings have yet to be translated into actual clinical decision support systems.  Many of these studies are based on relatively small datasets in homogeneous populations, which has the associated risk that the models may not perform adequately on new data in real clinical practice.  הטבע של מחלות נפשית רצינית הוא שקשה להגדיר, קשה לתפוס, ודריך מעקב תדיר, מה שמוביל למידע לא מושלם שבו התכונות והרעש בכיתה הם נפוצים. With the goal of an effective AI-mediated clinical decision support system, there must be computational safeguards placed on the models used in order to avoid spurious predictions and thus allow humans to review data in the settings where models are unstable or bound not to generalize.  This paper describes two approaches to implementing safeguards: (1) the determination of cases in which models are unstable by means of attribute and class based outlier detection and (2) finding the extent to which models show inductive bias.  These safeguards are illustrated in the automated scoring of a story recall task via natural language processing methods.  עם האינטגרציה של מכונת הלימוד האנושית בתהליך ההפעלה הקליניקלי, הכילוי של אמצעי הגנה כמו אלה לתוך הדוגמנים יציע למטופלים הגנה גדולה מפני צפיות מרגיעות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ཞེས་འཇུག་ཟམ་སྦྱོར་བའི་ལྟ་བུའི་ནང་དུ་མི་མཐུན་གྱིས་དང་རང་བཞིན་གྱི་སྐད་ཡིག ལྟ་བ་འདི་དག་གི་ནང་དུ་ཆེས་ཉུང་བའི་མི་སྐྱེས་ཚོགས་ལ་ཆུང་བའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག རང་བཞིན་གནད་མེད་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་ནད་ཅིག་ནི་ངོས་འཛིན་བྱེད་ན་དཀའ་ངལ་ཡོད། With the goal of an effective AI-mediated clinical decision support system, there must be computational safeguards placed on the models used to avoid spurious predictions and thus allow humans to review data in the settings where models are unstable or bound to generalize. This paper describes two approaches to implementing safeguards: (1) the determination of cases in which models are unstable by means of attribute and class based outlier detection and (2) finding the extent to which models show inductive bias. སྲུང་སྐྱོབ་འདི་དག་གིས་རང་འགུལ་གྱིས་གཏམ་གླེང་སྒྲུང་གི་ནང་དུ་མཐོང་ནུས་རང་བཞིན་གྱིས་རྐྱེན་སྐྱོང་བ་འདི་ལ With the integration of human-in-the-loop machine learning in the clinical implementation process, incorporating safeguards such as these into the models will offer patients increased protection from spurious predictions.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>Towards Understanding the Role of Gender in Deploying Social Media-Based Mental Health Surveillance Models</title>
      <author><first>Eli</first><last>Sherman</last></author>
      <author><first>Keith</first><last>Harrigian</last></author>
      <author><first>Carlos</first><last>Aguirre</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Dredze</last></author>
      <pages>217–223</pages>
      <abstract>Spurred by advances in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a>, developing social media-based mental health surveillance models has received substantial recent attention. For these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> to be maximally useful, it is necessary to understand how they perform on various subgroups, especially those defined in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Protected_group">protected characteristics</a>. In this paper we study the relationship between user demographics   focusing on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender">gender</a>   and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Depression_(mood)">depression</a>. Considering a population of Reddit users with known genders and depression statuses, we analyze the degree to which depression predictions are subject to biases along gender lines using domain-informed classifiers. We then study our models’ parameters to gain qualitative insight into the differences in posting behavior across genders.</abstract>
      <url hash="03e554e8">2021.clpsych-1.23</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.clpsych-1.23</doi>
      <bibkey>sherman-etal-2021-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>