<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.sdp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Scholarly Document Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Iz</first><last>Beltagy</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Arman</first><last>Cohan</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Guy</first><last>Feigenblat</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dayne</first><last>Freitag</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Tirthankar</first><last>Ghosal</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Keith</first><last>Hall</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Drahomira</first><last>Herrmannova</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Petr</first><last>Knoth</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kyle</first><last>Lo</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Philipp</first><last>Mayr</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Robert M.</first><last>Patton</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Michal</first><last>Shmueli-Scheuer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anita</first><last>de Waard</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kuansan</first><last>Wang</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Lucy Lu</first><last>Wang</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.sdp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="f7ce0583">2021.sdp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sdp-2021-scholarly</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Keyphrase Extraction from Scientific Articles via Extractive Summarization</title>
      <author><first>Chrysovalantis Giorgos</first><last>Kontoulis</last></author>
      <author><first>Eirini</first><last>Papagiannopoulou</last></author>
      <author><first>Grigorios</first><last>Tsoumakas</last></author>
      <pages>49–55</pages>
      <abstract>Automatically extracting keyphrases from scholarly documents leads to a valuable concise representation that humans can understand and machines can process for tasks, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">information retrieval</a>, article clustering and article classification. This paper is concerned with the parts of a scientific article that should be given as input to keyphrase extraction methods. Recent deep learning methods take titles and abstracts as input due to the increased <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_complexity_theory">computational complexity</a> in processing long sequences, whereas traditional approaches can also work with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">full-texts</a>. Titles and abstracts are dense in keyphrases, but often miss important aspects of the articles, while full-texts on the other hand are richer in keyphrases but much noisier. To address this trade-off, we propose the use of extractive summarization models on the full-texts of scholarly documents. Our empirical study on 3 article collections using 3 keyphrase extraction methods shows promising results.</abstract>
      <url hash="ab1057a1">2021.sdp-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sdp-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>kontoulis-etal-2021-keyphrase</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/intelligence-csd-auth-gr/keyphrase-extraction-via-summarization" additional="false">intelligence-csd-auth-gr/keyphrase-extraction-via-summarization</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>The Effect of Pretraining on Extractive Summarization for Scientific Documents</title>
      <author><first>Yash</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Pawan Sasanka</first><last>Ammanamanchi</last></author>
      <author><first>Shikha</first><last>Bordia</last></author>
      <author><first>Arjun</first><last>Manoharan</last></author>
      <author><first>Deepak</first><last>Mittal</last></author>
      <author><first>Ramakanth</first><last>Pasunuru</last></author>
      <author><first>Manish</first><last>Shrivastava</last></author>
      <author><first>Maneesh</first><last>Singh</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohit</first><last>Bansal</last></author>
      <author><first>Preethi</first><last>Jyothi</last></author>
      <pages>73–82</pages>
      <abstract>Large pretrained models have seen enormous success in extractive summarization tasks. In this work, we investigate the influence of pretraining on a BERT-based extractive summarization system for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_literature">scientific documents</a>. We derive significant performance improvements using an intermediate pretraining step that leverages existing summarization datasets and report state-of-the-art results on a recently released scientific summarization dataset, SciTLDR. We systematically analyze the intermediate pretraining step by varying the size and domain of the pretraining corpus, changing the length of the input sequence in the target task and varying target tasks. We also investigate how intermediate pretraining interacts with contextualized word embeddings trained on different domains.</abstract>
      <url hash="826fc418">2021.sdp-1.9</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sdp-1.9</doi>
      <bibkey>gupta-etal-2021-effect</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Finding Pragmatic Differences Between Disciplines</title>
      <author><first>Lee</first><last>Kezar</last></author>
      <author><first>Jay</first><last>Pujara</last></author>
      <pages>83–90</pages>
      <abstract>Scholarly documents have a great degree of variation, both in terms of content (semantics) and structure (pragmatics). Prior work in scholarly document understanding emphasizes <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a> through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_summarization">document summarization</a> and corpus topic modeling but tends to omit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pragmatics">pragmatics</a> such as document organization and flow. Using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus of scholarly documents</a> across 19 disciplines and state-of-the-art language modeling techniques, we learn a fixed set of domain-agnostic descriptors for document sections and retrofit the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> to these descriptors (also referred to as normalization). Then, we analyze the position and ordering of these descriptors across documents to understand the relationship between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discipline">discipline</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structure">structure</a>. We report within-discipline structural archetypes, variability, and between-discipline comparisons, supporting the hypothesis that scholarly communities, despite their size, diversity, and breadth, share similar avenues for expressing their work. Our findings lay the foundation for future work in assessing research quality, domain style transfer, and further pragmatic analysis.</abstract>
      <url hash="6724d9e5">2021.sdp-1.10</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sdp-1.10</doi>
      <bibkey>kezar-pujara-2021-finding</bibkey>
    <title_es>Encontrar diferencias pragmáticas entre disciplinas</title_es>
      <title_ar>إيجاد اختلافات عملية بين التخصصات</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Trouver des différences pragmatiques entre les disciplines</title_fr>
      <title_pt>Encontrando Diferenças Pragmáticas Entre as Disciplinas</title_pt>
      <title_zh>见学科之间务实差异</title_zh>
      <title_ja>分野間の実用的な違いを見つける</title_ja>
      <title_hi>विषयों के बीच व्यावहारिक अंतर ढूँढना</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Выявление прагматических различий между дисциплинами</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Difríochtaí Pragmatacha idir Disciplíní a Fháil</title_ga>
      <title_ka>პრაგმატიკური განსხვავებები დისკიპლინის შორის ძებნა</title_ka>
      <title_el>Εύρεση πρακτικών διαφορών μεταξύ πειθαρχίων</title_el>
      <title_hu>Pragmatikus különbségek megtalálása a fegyelmek között</title_hu>
      <title_it>Trovare differenze pragmatiche tra le discipline</title_it>
      <title_kk>Дисциплиндер арасындағы прагматикалық айырмашылығын табу</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Pragmatinių diskiplinų skirtumų nustatymas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Најдување прагматски разлики меѓу дисциплините</title_mk>
      <title_ml>ഡിസ്കിപ്ലൈനുകള്‍ക്കിടയില്‍ പ്രാഗ്മാറ്റിക് വ്യത്യാസങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടെത്തുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Is-sejba ta’ Differenzi Prammatiċi Bejn id-Dixxiplini</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Дисциплийн хооронд Pragmatic Differences-г олох</title_mn>
      <title_ms>Mencari Perbezaan Pragmatik Antara Gaya</title_ms>
      <title_no>Finn pragmatiske forskjeller mellom disklinjer</title_no>
      <title_pl>Znalezienie pragmatycznych różnic między dyscyplinami</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Găsirea diferențelor pragmatice între discipline</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Pronaći Pragmatske razlike između diskiplina</title_sr>
      <title_si>ප්‍රාග්මතික වෙනස් හොයාගන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Raadinta iskuullada tacliinta</title_so>
      <title_sv>Att hitta pragmatiska skillnader mellan discipliner</title_sv>
      <title_ta>வித்தியாசமான வேறுபாடுகளை தேடுகிறது</title_ta>
      <title_ur>دیسکیپلین کے درمیان Pragmatic Differences Finding</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Tìm Điểm khác biệt giữa các kỷ luật</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Намиране на прагматични различия между дисциплините</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Pronaći Pragmatske razlike između diskiplina</title_hr>
      <title_id>Finding Pragmatic Differences Between Disciplines</title_id>
      <title_de>Pragmatische Unterschiede zwischen Disziplinen finden</title_de>
      <title_da>At finde pragmatiske forskelle mellem discipliner</title_da>
      <title_nl>Het vinden van pragmatische verschillen tussen disciplines</title_nl>
      <title_tr>Discipliniň arasynda Pragmatik üýtgewleri tapmak</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Kutafuta tofauti za Ujadala kati ya Udhibiti</title_sw>
      <title_ko>학과 간의 어용 차이를 발견하다</title_ko>
      <title_fa>پیدا کردن تفاوتهای Pragmatic Between Disciplines</title_fa>
      <title_af>Soek Pragmatike Verskilte tussen Diskiplyne</title_af>
      <title_sq>Finding Pragmatic Differences Between Disciplines</title_sq>
      <title_am>dialogs-action</title_am>
      <title_az>Disciplines arasındakı Pragmatik Farklılıqları tapmaq</title_az>
      <title_bn>ডিস্কিপ্লাইনের মধ্যে প্রাগ্যামেটিক বিভাগ খুঁজে বের করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Pronaći Pragmatske razlike između diskiplina</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Finding Pragmatic Differences Between Disciplines</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Nalezení pragmatických rozdílů mezi disciplínami</title_cs>
      <title_et>Pragmaatiliste erinevuste leidmine distsipliinide vahel</title_et>
      <title_fi>Pragmaattisten erojen löytäminen kurinpitojen välillä</title_fi>
      <title_hy>Finding Pragmatic Differences Between Disciplines</title_hy>
      <title_he>Finding Pragmatic Differences Between Disciplines</title_he>
      <title_jv>Finding</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Iskanje pragmatičnih razlik med disciplinami</title_sk>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_bo>བསྡུས་ཕྱོགས་སྐོར་དང་བར་དུ་Pragmatic Differences</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تتمتع الوثائق العلمية بدرجة كبيرة من الاختلاف ، سواء من حيث المحتوى (الدلالات) والبنية (البراغماتية). يؤكد العمل السابق في فهم المستندات العلمية على الدلالات من خلال تلخيص المستند ونمذجة موضوع المجموعة ولكنه يميل إلى حذف البراغماتية مثل تنظيم المستندات وتدفقها. باستخدام مجموعة من الوثائق العلمية عبر 19 تخصصًا وتقنيات نمذجة اللغة الحديثة ، نتعلم مجموعة ثابتة من الواصفات الحيادية للمجال لأقسام المستندات و "تعديل" المجموعة إلى هذه الواصفات (يشار إليها أيضًا باسم "التطبيع" "). بعد ذلك ، نقوم بتحليل موضع وترتيب هذه الواصفات عبر المستندات لفهم العلاقة بين الانضباط والهيكل. نُبلغ عن النماذج البدائية الهيكلية داخل التخصص ، والتنوع ، والمقارنات بين التخصصات ، مما يدعم الفرضية القائلة بأن المجتمعات العلمية ، على الرغم من حجمها وتنوعها واتساعها ، تشترك في طرق مماثلة للتعبير عن عملهم. تضع النتائج التي توصلنا إليها الأساس للعمل المستقبلي في تقييم جودة البحث ونقل نمط المجال والمزيد من التحليل العملي.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Os documentos acadêmicos apresentam um grande grau de variação, tanto em termos de conteúdo (semântica) quanto de estrutura (pragmática). O trabalho anterior na compreensão de documentos acadêmicos enfatiza a semântica por meio da sumarização de documentos e modelagem de tópicos de corpus, mas tende a omitir a pragmática, como organização e fluxo de documentos. Usando um corpus de documentos acadêmicos em 19 disciplinas e técnicas de modelagem de linguagem de última geração, aprendemos um conjunto fixo de descritores agnósticos de domínio para seções de documentos e “retrofit” o corpus para esses descritores (também chamados de “normalização "). Em seguida, analisamos a posição e a ordenação desses descritores nos documentos para entender a relação entre disciplina e estrutura. Relatamos arquétipos estruturais dentro da disciplina, variabilidade e comparações entre disciplinas, apoiando a hipótese de que as comunidades acadêmicas, apesar de seu tamanho, diversidade e amplitude, compartilham avenidas semelhantes para expressar seu trabalho. Nossas descobertas estabelecem as bases para trabalhos futuros na avaliação da qualidade da pesquisa, transferência de estilo de domínio e análise pragmática adicional.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Los documentos académicos tienen un alto grado de variación, tanto en términos de contenido (semántica) como de estructura (pragmática). El trabajo previo en la comprensión de documentos académicos enfatiza la semántica a través del resumen de documentos y el modelado de temas de corpus, pero tiende a omitir pragmáticos como la organización y el flujo de documentos. Mediante el uso de un corpus de documentos académicos de 19 disciplinas y técnicas de modelado lingüístico de vanguardia, aprendemos un conjunto fijo de descriptores independientes del dominio para las secciones del documento y «adaptamos» el corpus a estos descriptores (también denominados «normalización»). Luego, analizamos la posición y el orden de estos descriptores en los documentos para entender la relación entre disciplina y estructura. Presentamos arquetipos estructurales dentro de la disciplina, variabilidad y comparaciones entre disciplinas, lo que respalda la hipótesis de que las comunidades académicas, a pesar de su tamaño, diversidad y amplitud, comparten vías similares para expresar su trabajo. Nuestros hallazgos sientan las bases para el trabajo futuro en la evaluación de la calidad de la investigación, la transferencia de estilos de dominio y un mayor análisis pragmático.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>Les documents savants présentent une grande variation, tant en termes de contenu (sémantique) que de structure (pragmatique). Les travaux antérieurs sur la compréhension des documents savants mettent l'accent sur la sémantique par le biais de la synthèse de documents et de la modélisation de sujets de corpus, mais ont tendance à omettre les pratiques telles que l'organisation et le flux À l'aide d'un corpus de documents scientifiques couvrant 19 disciplines et de techniques de modélisation langagière de pointe, nous apprenons un ensemble fixe de descripteurs indépendants du domaine pour les sections de documents et nous « adaptons » le corpus à ces descripteurs (également appelée « normalisation »). Ensuite, nous analysons la position et l'ordre de ces descripteurs dans les documents afin de comprendre la relation entre la discipline et la structure. Nous présentons des archétypes structurels au sein d'une discipline, une variabilité et des comparaisons entre disciplines, soutenant l'hypothèse selon laquelle les communautés savantes, malgré leur taille, leur diversité et leur ampleur, partagent des voies similaires pour exprimer leur travail. Nos résultats jettent les bases des futurs travaux d'évaluation de la qualité de la recherche, du transfert de style de domaine et d'autres analyses pragmatiques.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_zh>学术文献(语义学)与结构(语用学)殊异。 学术文档通前文档摘要及语料库主题建模强语义,然向于省略诸如文档、流程之类语用学。 跨19学科之学文档语料库与先进之言建模术,吾为文档部习定域不可言符,而改语料库为符(亦谓之"规范化")。 然后论符在文档位序,以知学科构之际。 告学科内之原型,可变性比于学科间,赞其伪设,虽学术团体规模,多样性广度,有似类焉。 臣等考为未来评量、领域风移、更加务实分定基业。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ja>学術文書は、内容（意味論）と構造（実用論）の両方において、大きな変動がある。 学術的文書理解における先行研究は、文書要約とコーパストピックモデリングを通じて意味論を強調するが、文書の構成やフローなどの実用性を省略する傾向がある。 19の分野にわたる学術文書のコーパスと最先端の言語モデリング技術を使用して、私たちは文書セクションのための固定された一連のドメイン非推論的記述子を学習し、コーパスをこれらの記述子に「改造」します（「正規化」とも呼ばれます）。 次に、文書間でこれらの記述子の位置と順序を分析して、規律と構造の関係を理解します。 私たちは、規模、多様性、幅広さにもかかわらず、学術コミュニティが仕事を表現するための同様の手段を共有しているという仮説を裏付ける、学問分野内の構造的アーキタイプ、変動性、および学問分野間の比較を報告しています。 私たちの調査結果は、研究の質、ドメインスタイルの転送、およびさらなる実用的な分析を評価する今後の作業の基礎を築いています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>विद्वानों के दस्तावेजों में सामग्री (शब्दार्थ) और संरचना (व्यावहारिक) दोनों के संदर्भ में भिन्नता की एक बड़ी डिग्री है। विद्वानों के दस्तावेज़ की समझ में पूर्व कार्य दस्तावेज़ सारांशीकरण और कॉर्पस विषय मॉडलिंग के माध्यम से शब्दार्थ पर जोर देता है, लेकिन दस्तावेज़ संगठन और प्रवाह जैसे व्यावहारिकताओं को छोड़ देता है। 19 विषयों और अत्याधुनिक भाषा मॉडलिंग तकनीकों में विद्वानों के दस्तावेजों के एक कॉर्पस का उपयोग करते हुए, हम दस्तावेज़ अनुभागों के लिए डोमेन-अज्ञेयवादी वर्णनकर्ताओं का एक निश्चित सेट सीखते हैं और इन वर्णनकर्ताओं को कॉर्पस को "रेट्रोफिट" करते हैं (जिसे "सामान्यीकरण" के रूप में भी जाना जाता है)। फिर, हम अनुशासन और संरचना के बीच संबंधों को समझने के लिए दस्तावेजों में इन वर्णनकर्ताओं की स्थिति और आदेश का विश्लेषण करते हैं। हम अनुशासन संरचनात्मक archetypes, परिवर्तनशीलता, और बीच-अनुशासन तुलना के भीतर रिपोर्ट करते हैं, इस परिकल्पना का समर्थन करते हैं कि विद्वानों के समुदाय, उनके आकार, विविधता और चौड़ाई के बावजूद, अपने काम को व्यक्त करने के लिए समान रास्ते साझा करते हैं। हमारे निष्कर्ष अनुसंधान की गुणवत्ता, डोमेन शैली हस्तांतरण, और आगे व्यावहारिक विश्लेषण का आकलन करने में भविष्य के काम के लिए नींव रखते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Ученые документы имеют большую степень вариативности, как с точки зрения содержания (семантика), так и структуры (прагматика). Предыдущая работа в научном понимании документов делает акцент на семантике через обобщение документов и моделирование тем корпуса, но, как правило, опускает прагматику, такую как организация и поток документов. Используя корпус научных документов по 19 дисциплинам и современные методы языкового моделирования, мы изучаем фиксированный набор доменно-диагностических дескрипторов для разделов документов и «перестраиваем» корпус на эти дескрипторы (также называемые «нормализацией»). Затем мы анализируем положение и порядок расположения этих дескрипторов в различных документах, чтобы понять взаимосвязь между дисциплиной и структурой. Мы сообщаем о внутридисциплинарных структурных архетипах, изменчивости и междисциплинарных сравнениях, поддерживая гипотезу о том, что научные сообщества, несмотря на их размер, разнообразие и широту, разделяют похожие пути для выражения своей работы. Наши выводы закладывают основу для будущей работы по оценке качества исследований, переносу стиля домена и дальнейшему прагматическому анализу.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Tá éagsúlacht mhór ag baint le doiciméid léannta, ó thaobh ábhair (séimeantaic) agus struchtúir (pragmataic). Cuireann réamhobair i dtuiscint doiciméad léannta béim ar shéimeantaic trí achoimre doiciméad agus samhaltú topaicí corpais ach fágtar ar lár pragmataic cosúil le heagrú agus sreabhadh doiciméad. Agus corpas de dhoiciméid scolártha á n-úsáid againn thar 19 ndisciplíní agus teicníochtaí samhaltaithe teanga úrscothacha, foghlaimímid sraith sheasta de thuairisceoirí fearainn-agnóiseacha do mhíreanna doiciméad agus “aisfheistiú” an corpas ar na tuairisceoirí seo (ar a dtugtar “normalú” freisin. ”). Ansin, déanaimid anailís ar shuíomh agus ord na dtuairisceoirí seo trasna doiciméad chun an gaol idir smacht agus struchtúr a thuiscint. Tuairiscímid archetypes struchtúracha laistigh den disciplín, ar inathraitheacht, agus ar chomparáidí idir disciplíní, ag tacú leis an hipitéis go roinneann pobail léannta, in ainneoin a méid, a n-éagsúlacht agus a leithead, bealaí comhchosúla chun a gcuid oibre a chur in iúl. Leagann ár dtorthaí an bonn le haghaidh obair amach anseo maidir le cáilíocht taighde, aistriú stíl fearainn, agus tuilleadh anailíse pragmatach a mheas.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Τα επιστημονικά έγγραφα έχουν μεγάλο βαθμό διακύμανσης, τόσο ως προς το περιεχόμενο (σημασιολογία) όσο και ως προς τη δομή (πραγματιστική). Η προηγούμενη εργασία στην κατανόηση επιστημονικών εγγράφων δίνει έμφαση στη σημασιολογία μέσω της σύνοψης εγγράφων και της μοντελοποίησης θεμάτων σώματος, αλλά τείνει να παραλείψει ρεαλιστικές όπως η οργάνωση και η ροή εγγράφων. Χρησιμοποιώντας ένα σώμα επιστημονικών εγγράφων σε 19-κλάδους και σύγχρονες τεχνικές γλωσσικής μοντελοποίησης, μαθαίνουμε ένα σταθερό σύνολο γνωστικών περιγραφών για ενότητες εγγράφων και "αναβαθμίζουμε" το σώμα σε αυτούς τους περιγραφείς (που επίσης αναφέρονται ως "ομαλοποίηση"). Στη συνέχεια, αναλύουμε τη θέση και τη σειρά αυτών των περιγραφέων σε έγγραφα για να κατανοήσουμε τη σχέση μεταξύ πειθαρχίας και δομής. Αναφέρουμε δομικά αρχέτυπα εντός του κλάδου, μεταβλητότητα και συγκρίσεις μεταξύ του κλάδου, υποστηρίζοντας την υπόθεση ότι οι επιστημονικές κοινότητες, παρά το μέγεθος, την ποικιλομορφία και το εύρος τους, μοιράζονται παρόμοιες οδούς έκφρασης του έργου τους. Τα ευρήματά μας θέτουν τα θεμέλια για μελλοντικές εργασίες στην αξιολόγηση της ποιότητας της έρευνας, της μεταφοράς στυλ τομέα και περαιτέρω πραγματιστικής ανάλυσης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A tudományos dokumentumok nagyfokú változatossággal rendelkeznek, mind a tartalom (szemantika), mind a struktúra (pragmatika) tekintetében. A tudományos dokumentumok megértésében végzett korábbi munka a szemantikát hangsúlyozza a dokumentumok összefoglalásán és a korpusztéma modellezésén keresztül, de hajlamos kihagyni a pragmatikát, mint például a dokumentumszervezés és az áramlás. 19 tudományterület tudományos dokumentumainak és a legkorszerűbb nyelvmodellezési technikáknak köszönhetően megtanuljuk a dokumentum szakaszokhoz tartozó domain-agnosztikus leírók rögzített halmazát, és "átalakítjuk" a korpuszt ezekre a leírókra (más néven "normalizáció"). Ezután elemezzük ezeknek a leíróknak a pozícióját és sorrendjét a dokumentumok között, hogy megértsük a fegyelem és a struktúra közötti kapcsolatot. Tudományágon belüli strukturális archetípusokról, változékonyságról és diszciplináris összehasonlításokról beszámolunk, alátámasztva azt a hipotézist, hogy a tudományos közösségek méretük, sokszínűségük és szélességük ellenére hasonló utakat osztanak munkájuk kifejezéséhez. Eredményeink megalapozzák a kutatási minőség értékelésében, a domain stílus átadásában és a további pragmatikus elemzésekben végzett jövőbeli munka alapját.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>სკოლადიური დოკუმენტები უფრო დიდი განსხვავება, რომელიც შემდგომარეობის (სიმენტიკის) და სტრუქტურის (პრაგმატიკის) შესახებ. პირველი სამუშაო სწავლიერი დოკუმენტის გაგრძნობაში სამუშაო სემენტიკები დააწყება დოკუმენტიკების კუმენტიკების შესახებ და კოპუპუსს ტემენტიკის მოდელის 19 დისპლინტების და სურათის მოდელური ტექნოგიების კოპუსს გამოყენებთ, ჩვენ ვისწავლით დომენტის ადნოსტიკური მოდელურების კოპუტირების კოპუტირების კოპუტირების კოპუტირებისთვის და კოპუტის კოპუტირებისთვის შემდეგ ვიანალიზებთ პოზიცია და მოწყობილობას დოკუმენტების განსაზღვრება, რომ გავიგოთ დისპლიციონ და სტრუქტურის შესახებ. ჩვენ დისპეცილინური სტრუქტური არქეტიპების შორის, განსხვავებელობა და დისპეცილინური შემდგომარების შორის შემდგომარებით შეგვიყვანეთ, რომ სტრუქტური საზოგადოებების, განსხვავებულობა ჩვენი შესაძლებლობები უნდა მომავალე სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო მუშაოდ გავაკეთოთ სწორედ სტრინსი, სტრინსი სტრინსი და დამატე</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>I documenti scientifici presentano un grande grado di variazione, sia in termini di contenuto (semantica) che di struttura (pragmatica). Il lavoro precedente nella comprensione accademica dei documenti enfatizza la semantica attraverso la sintesi dei documenti e la modellazione degli argomenti del corpus, ma tende a omettere pragmatiche come l'organizzazione e il flusso dei documenti. Utilizzando un corpus di documenti accademici in 19 discipline e tecniche di modellazione linguistica all'avanguardia, impariamo un insieme fisso di descrittori agnostici di dominio per le sezioni di documenti e 'retrofit' il corpus a questi descrittori (chiamati anche 'normalizzazione'). Analizziamo quindi la posizione e l'ordine di questi descrittori attraverso i documenti per comprendere la relazione tra disciplina e struttura. Riportiamo archetipi strutturali all'interno della disciplina, variabilità e confronti tra discipline, sostenendo l'ipotesi che le comunità accademiche, nonostante le loro dimensioni, diversità e ampiezza, condividano strade simili per esprimere il loro lavoro. I nostri risultati gettano le basi per il lavoro futuro nella valutazione della qualità della ricerca, trasferimento dello stile del dominio e ulteriore analisi pragmatica.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Moksliniai dokumentai labai skiriasi turinio (semantikos) ir struktūros (pragmatikos) požiūriu. Ankstesnis mokslo dokumentų supratimo darbas pabrėžia semantiką apibendrinant dokumentus ir modeliuojant corpus temą, tačiau paprastai pragmatikos, pavyzdžiui, dokumentų organizavimas ir srautas, neišvengiamas. Naudojant mokslinius dokumentus 19 disciplinų ir moderniausius kalbų modeliavimo metodus, mes išmokome fiksuotą domeno agnostinių aprašų rinkinį dokumentų skirsniams ir "pritaikyti" korpusą prie šių aprašų (taip pat vadinamą "normalizacija"). Tada analizuojame šių aprašų poziciją ir tvarkymą įvairiuose dokumentuose, kad suprastume drausmės ir struktūros santykius. Pranešame apie struktūrinius archetypus, kintamumą ir tarpdisciplininius palyginimus įvairiose srityse, remiant hipotezę, kad mokslo bendruomenės, nepaisant jų dydžio, įvairovės ir plotio, turi panašius būdus savo darbui išreikšti. Mūsų išvados yra pagrindas būsimam darbui vertinant mokslinių tyrimų kokybę, srities stilių perdavimą ir tolesnę pragmatinę analizę.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Научните документи имаат голем степен на варијација, како во однос на содржината (семантика) и структурата (прагматика). Prior work in scholarly document understanding emphasizes semantics through document summarization and corpus topic modeling but tends to omit pragmatics such as document organization and flow.  Користејќи корпус научни документи низ 19 дисциплини и најсовремени техники на моделирање јазик, научиме фиксен сет на домен-агностички дескриптори за секции на документи и 'ретрофитирање' на корпусот на овие дескриптори (исто така наречен како 'нормализација'). Потоа, ја анализираме позицијата и наредбата на овие дискриптори преку документи за да ја разбереме врската помеѓу дисциплината и структурата. Ние известуваме во рамките на дисциплината структурни архетипи, варијабилност и меѓудисциплинарни споредби, поддржувајќи ја хипотезата дека научните заедници, и покрај нивната големина, различност и ширина, споделуваат слични патишта за изразување на нивната работа. Нашите откритија се основа на идната работа во проценката на квалитетот на истражувањето, трансферот на стилот на домените и понатамошната прагматска анализа.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Мұғалімді құжаттар мазмұның (semantics) және құрылымының (pragmatics) қасиетінде өзгерістер көп деңгейі бар. Білім құжаттың алдыңғы жұмысын түсініп, құжаттың тұжырымдамасын және корпус нақыштарды моделдеу арқылы, бірақ құжаттың құжаттың жұмысын және қарымдамасы сияқты 19 дисциплин және әртүрлі тілді модель технологияларындағы білім құжаттардың корпусын қолдану үшін біз құжаттың бөліктері үшін доменге агностикалық түсініктерді білеміз және корпусын осы түсініктерге қайта қайта қарау (сонымен қа Содан кейін, бұл құжаттардың орналасуын және реттеу үшін дисциплина мен құрылғының қатынасын түсінуге болады. Біз дициплиналық структуралық архитектиптер, айнымалылығы және дисциплиналық салыстырудың арасында хабарлаймыз. Олардың өлшемі, әртүрлік және ұзындығы, жұмысын көрсету үшін ұқсас жолдарын біртіндеп қолдана Біздің табуларымыз келесі жұмыстың негізін зерттеу сапасы, домендің стилді аудару және қосымша прагматикалық анализ оқуға арналған.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Scholarly documents have a great degree of variation, both in terms of content (semantics) and structure (pragmatics).  Kerja terdahulu dalam pemahaman dokumen sains menekankan semantik melalui penghuraian dokumen dan pemodelan topik corpus tetapi cenderung untuk melepaskan pragmatik seperti organisasi dokumen dan aliran. Dengan menggunakan korpus dokumen sains melalui 19 disiplin dan teknik pemodelan bahasa state-of-the-art, kami belajar set tetap penerangan domain-agnostik untuk seksyen dokumen dan 'retrofit' corpus ke penerangan ini (juga disebut 'normalisasi'). Kemudian, kami menganalisis kedudukan dan perintah penerangan ini melalui dokumen untuk memahami hubungan antara disiplin dan struktur. Kami laporkan dalam disiplin arketype struktur, variabiliti, dan perbandingan diantara disiplin, menyokong hipotesis bahawa komuniti ilmuwan, walaupun saiz, pelbagai, dan lebar mereka, berkongsi jalan yang sama untuk mengekspresikan kerja mereka. Penemuan kami meletakkan dasar untuk kerja masa depan dalam menilai kualiti kajian, pemindahan gaya domain, dan analisis pragmatik lanjut.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Id-dokumenti xjentifiċi għandhom grad kbir ta’ varjazzjoni, kemm f’termini ta’ kontenut (semantika) kif ukoll struttura (prammatika). Il-ħidma preċedenti fil-fehim tad-dokumenti xjentifiċi tenfasizza s-semantika permezz tas-sommarju tad-dokumenti u l-immudellar tas-suġġetti corpus iżda għandha t-tendenza li tħalli barra l-pragmatiċi bħall-organizzazzjoni tad-dokumenti u l-fluss. Bl-użu ta’ korpus ta’ dokumenti xjentifiċi f’19-il dixxiplina u tekniki ta’ mudellar tal-lingwi l-aktar avvanzati, nitgħallmu sett fiss ta’ deskritturi tad-dominju-agnostiċi għat-taqsimiet tad-dokumenti u 'retrofit' il-korpus għal dawn id-deskritturi (imsejħa wkoll 'normalizzazzjoni'). Imbagħad, nagħmlu analiżi tal-pożizzjoni u l-ordni ta’ dawn id-deskritturi fid-dokumenti biex nifhmu r-relazzjoni bejn id-dixxiplina u l-istruttura. Aħna nirrappurtaw arkitetipi strutturali, varjabilità u paraguni bejn id-dixxiplini fi ħdan id-dixxiplina, li jappoġġjaw l-ipoteżi li l-komunitajiet xjentifiċi, minkejja d-daqs, id-diversità, u l-wisa’ tagħhom, għandhom mezzi simili biex jesprimu x-xogħol tagħhom. Is-sejbiet tagħna jistabbilixxu l-bażi għal ħidma futura fil-valutazzjoni tal-kwalità tar-riċerka, it-trasferiment tal-istil tad-dominju, u analiżi prammatika ulterjuri.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>സ്കൂളില്‍ രേഖകള്‍ക്ക് വ്യത്യാസങ്ങളുടെ വലിയ ഡിഗ്രി ഉണ്ട്, ഉള്ളടക്കത്തിന്‍റെ (സെമാന്റിക്സ്) സ്ഥാനത്തിന്‍റെയും ഘ പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട രേഖയില്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിക്കുന്നതിന് മുമ്പ് രേഖയുടെ സംസ്കാരത്തിലും കോര്‍പ്പുസിന്റെ പ്രമേയത്തിന്റെയും മോഡലിങ്ങില 19 ഡിസ്കിപ്ലൈനുകളിലും രാജ്യത്തിലുമുള്ള ഭാഷ മോഡലിങ്ങ് ടെക്നിക്ക് ടെക്കോര്‍പ്പുകളിലുമുള്ള രേഖകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ച്, നമ്മള്‍ രേഖകളുടെ വിഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ക്കും രേഖകളുടെ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ക്കും പു പിന്നെ നമ്മള്‍ ഈ രേഖകളുടെ സ്ഥാനം അന്വേഷിക്കുന്നു, ഡിസ്കിപ്ലൈനും ഘടനയുടെയും ഇടയിലുള്ള ബന്ധം മനസ്സിലാക്കുന്നതിന ഡിസ്കിപ്ലൈനിന്റെ ഉള്ളിലുള്ള ആർക്കിട്ടീവിഷയങ്ങള്‍, വ്യത്യാസവും, ഡിസ്പിലിന്റെ തുല്യത്തിനും ഇടയിലുള്ള പ്രഖ്യാപിക്കുന്നു, വിദ്യാഭ്യാസികളായ സമൂഹത നമ്മുടെ കണ്ടുപിടികള്‍ ഭാവിയുടെ ജോലിക്കുള്ള അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ അടിസ്ഥാനം വെച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. പഠിക്കുന്നത</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Scholardokument har stor variasjon, både med innhald (semantikk) og struktur (pragmatisk). Førre arbeid i tidlegare dokumentforståelse understrekar semantikk gjennom sammendraging av dokument og modellering av tema på korpus, men tenderer til å fjerna pragmatikk som dokumentorganisasjon og flug. I bruk av ein korpus av forstande dokument over 19 discipliner og tilstandspråk modelleringsteknikk, lærer vi eit fast sett av domeneagnostiske skildrar for dokumentseksjonar og « retrofit » korpusen til desse skildringane (også kalla « normalisering »). Så analyserer vi posisjonen og ordning av desse deskriptorane over dokument for å forstå forholdet mellom disciplina og strukturen. Vi rapporterer inne-discipline strukturelle arkitetypar, variabilitet og mellom-disciplinesammenlikningar, og støttar hypotesien at forskjellige fellesskap, selv om storleiken, mangfold og breidd sine, deler liknande avena for å uttrykke arbeidet sine. Finningane våre lager fundamentet for framtidige arbeid i å vurdere forskningskvalitet, domenestiloverføring og framtidige pragmatisk analyse.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_mn>Сургуулийн баримтууд бүтээгдэхүүн (semantics) болон бүтээгдэхүүний (pragmatic) хувьд маш их өөрчлөлт байдаг. Сургуулийн баримт ойлгохын өмнөх ажил баримт нийлүүлэх, корпус сэдэв загварын загварын аргаар үр дүнг тодорхойлж байдаг. Гэхдээ баримт байгууллага, урсгал зэрэг прагматикуудыг алдагдах болно. 19 дисциплин болон урлагийн хэл загварын технологи дээр судлаачид баримтуудын корпус ашиглан бид баримтуудын хэсэгт агностик тодорхойлогчийг суралцаж, корпус нь эдгээр тодорхойлогчид (мөн "нормализация" гэж нэрлэдэг). Дараа нь бид эдгээр тодорхойлогчдын байр суурь болон захиралдаг бичиг баримтуудын харилцаа ойлгохын тулд шинжилгээ хийсэн. Бид дисциплины бүтэц архитектуруудын дотор, өөрчлөлт болон дисциплины хоорондын харьцуулалтыг тайлбарлаж, эрдэмтэн нийгмийн хэмжээнд, олон янзын, өргөн хэмжээнд ч ажлыг илэрхийлэх төстэй арга замыг хуваалцаж байна. Бидний ололтууд ирээдүйн ажилдаа судалгааны чанар, зохион байрлалын шилжүүлэлт болон дахиад прагматикийн шинжилгээг тодорхойлдог.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Dokumenty naukowe mają duży stopień zróżnicowania, zarówno pod względem treści (semantyka), jak i struktury (pragmatyka). Wcześniejsze prace w naukowym rozumieniu dokumentów kładą nacisk na semantykę poprzez podsumowanie dokumentów i modelowanie tematów korpusów, ale zwykle pomijają pragmatykę, taką jak organizacja dokumentów i przepływ dokumentów. Wykorzystując korpus dokumentów naukowych w 19-dyscyplinach oraz najnowocześniejsze techniki modelowania językowego, uczymy się stałego zestawu deskryptorów agnostycznych dla sekcji dokumentów i "modernizujemy" korpus do tych deskryptorów (zwanych również "normalizacją"). Następnie analizujemy pozycję i porządek tych deskryptorów w dokumentach, aby zrozumieć związek między dyscypliną a strukturą. Raportujemy wewnątrz dyscypliny archetypy strukturalne, zmienność i porównania między dyscyplinami, popierając hipotezę, że społeczności naukowe, mimo ich wielkości, różnorodności i szerokości, mają podobne możliwości wyrażania swojej pracy. Nasze wyniki stanowią podstawę do przyszłych prac w zakresie oceny jakości badań, transferu stylu domeny i dalszej analizy pragmatycznej.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_so>Dukumentiyadu waxay leeyihiin shahaado faro badan oo kala duwan, marka lagu jiro waxyaabaha (semantics) iyo dhismaha (pragmatics). Shaqo hore oo ku qoran dukumentiga waxgarashada waxyaabaha barashada ah wuxuu ku qoran yahay mid ku qoran sameynta dukumentiyada iyo tusaale ahaan muuqashada mada qofka, laakiin wuxuu ka tagaa caadooyinka sida ururka dukumentiga iyo socoshada. Sida lagu isticmaalayo dukumentiyada waxbarashada oo ku qoran 19-cilmiga iyo qoraalka qoraalka afka farshaxanka, waxaynu barnaa koox kamid ah oo ku qoran qoraalka internetka iyo qaybaha dukumentiyada iyo qaybaha 'dib u celi' (waxaa kaloo lagu magacaabaa 'normalization'). Markaas waxaynu baaraynaa meeshii iyo nidaamka qoraalkaas oo warqadaha gudihiisa ah si aan u garanayno xiriirka u dhexeeya cilmiga iyo dhismaha. Waxaannu wargelinaynaa sawirada dhismaha dhismaha gudaha ah, isbedelka, isbarbarka iyo u dhexeeya isbardhiga cilmiga, waxaynu caawinaynaa fikirrada bulshada iskuullada, in kastoo ay yihiin tirada, kala duduwan iyo ballaadhka, si ay u muuqato shaqadooda. Shaqooyinkayadii waxay aasaaska u dhigeen shaqada mustaqbalka ah si ay u qiimeyso qiimeynta baaritaanka, wareejinta qaababka deegaanka iyo baaritaanka caadiga ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>ශ්‍යාලික ලිපින්තුවන්ට ලොකු වෙනස් විශාල විශාලයක් තියෙනවා, දෙන්නම් සාමාන්ත්‍රික (සෙමැන්ටික්) ස ප්‍රධාන විද්‍යාපිත විද්‍යාපෘති විද්‍යාපෘතියේ ප්‍රධාන විද්‍යාප්‍ත විද්‍යාප්‍ත විද්‍යාප්‍ත විද්‍යාප්‍ත විද්‍යාප්‍ත විද Using a Corpus of science papers over 19 disciplines and state-of-the-art language Modelling Technics, we learnt a Fixed set of domain-agostic Description for Documentation Secions and 'retropht' the Corpus to this Description (as well as 'Normization'). ඊට පස්සේ, අපි විශ්ලේෂණය කරනවා මේ විශ්ලේෂකයන්ගේ ස්ථානය සහ අණිවිධානය සඳහා විශ්ලේෂණය සහ සංවිධ අපි වාර්තා කරනවා ඇතුළු විද්‍යාපණ සංස්ථාපණ විද්‍යාපණය, විද්‍යාපණය, සහ අතර-විද්‍යාපණය සම්පූර්ණය, විද්‍යාපණය සම්පූර්ණය සමාජ අපේ හොයාගන්නේ අනාගතයේ වැඩේ විශේෂ විශේෂය, ඩෝමින් ස්ථානය ගැනීම, තව ප්‍රාග්මික විශ්ලේෂණය අව</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Vetenskapliga dokument har en stor variation, både vad gäller innehåll (semantik) och struktur (pragmatik). Tidigare arbete inom vetenskaplig dokumentförståelse betonar semantik genom dokumentsammanfattning och korpusämnesmodellering men tenderar att utelämna pragmatik som dokumentorganisation och flöde. Med hjälp av en korpus av vetenskapliga dokument inom 19 discipliner och toppmoderna språkmodelleringstekniker lär vi oss en fast uppsättning domänagnostiska deskriptorer för dokumentavsnitt och "eftermonterar" korpusen till dessa deskriptorer (även kallad normalisering). Därefter analyserar vi positionen och ordningen av dessa deskriptorer över dokument för att förstå förhållandet mellan disciplin och struktur. Vi rapporterar inom disciplinen strukturella arketyper, variabilitet och jämförelser mellan discipliner, vilket stöder hypotesen att vetenskapliga samhällen, trots sin storlek, mångfald och bredd, delar liknande vägar för att uttrycka sitt arbete. Våra resultat lägger grunden för framtida arbete med att bedöma forskningskvalitet, domänstilsöverföring och ytterligare pragmatisk analys.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ro>Documentele științifice au un grad mare de variație, atât în ceea ce privește conținutul (semantica), cât și structura (pragmatica). Lucrările anterioare în înțelegerea documentelor științifice accentuează semantica prin rezumarea documentelor și modelarea subiectelor corpus, dar tinde să omită pragmatici cum ar fi organizarea documentelor și fluxul. Folosind un corpus de documente științifice din 19 discipline și tehnici de modelare lingvistică de ultimă generație, învățăm un set fix de descriptori agnostici pentru secțiunile de documente și "modernizăm" corpul la acești descriptori (denumiți și "normalizare"). Apoi, analizăm poziția și ordinea acestor descriptori în documente pentru a înțelege relația dintre disciplină și structură. Raportăm arhetipuri structurale în cadrul disciplinei, variabilitate și comparații între discipline, susținând ipoteza că comunitățile științifice, în ciuda dimensiunii, diversității și lățimii lor, împărtășesc căi similare de exprimare a muncii lor. Rezultatele noastre pun bazele pentru activitatea viitoare în evaluarea calității cercetării, transferul stilului domeniului și analiza pragmatică ulterioară.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Školski dokumenti imaju veliku varijaciju, kako u smislu sadržaja (semantika) i strukture (pragmatika). Prije posla u znanstvenom dokumentu razumijevanju naglašava semantiku kroz sažetak dokumenta i modeliranje teme korpusa, ali je tendencija da napusti pragmatiku poput organizacije dokumenta i toka. Koristeći korpus stipendijskih dokumenta preko 19 disciplina i tehnika modeliranja jezika države umjetnosti, naučimo fiksnu skupu domena-agnostičkih opisača za sekcije dokumenta i 'obnovimo' korpus ovim opisačima (takođe se zove 'normalizacija'). Onda analiziramo poziciju i naređenje ovih opisača preko dokumenta kako bi razumeli odnos između discipline i strukture. Prijavljujemo unutar disciplinskih strukturnih arhitepova, variabilnosti i između disciplinskih usporedba, podržavajući hipotezu da naučne zajednice, uprkos njihovoj veličini, raznolikosti i širini, dijele slične avente za izražavanje svojih radova. Naši nalazi su temelj za budući rad u procjeni kvalitete istraživanja, transfer stila domena i daljnje pragmatične analize.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>புள்ளியில் ஆவணங்களுக்கு மிகப்பெரிய மாறுபாடு உள்ளடக்கத்திலும் அமைப்புகளிலும் உள்ளடக்கத்திலும் மாறுதல் உள்ளது. புரிந்து கொள்ளும் பொருள் புரிந்து புரிந்து முன்னிருப்பு வேலை ஆவணத்தின் சுருக்கம் மற்றும் குறும்பு தலைப்பு மாதிரியாக்கத் 19 வடிவமைப்புகள் மற்றும் நிலையான- கலை மொழி மாதிரி மாதிரி தொழில்நுட்பத்தை பயன்படுத்தி நாம் ஆவண பிரிவுகளுக்கும் ஒரு நிறைய குறிப்புகளை கற்றுக் கொள்கிறோம் 'மீட்டெடு' என்று இந் Then, we analyze the position and ordering of these descriptors across documents to understand the relationship between discipline and structure.  நாம் வடிவமைப்பு கட்டுப்பாட்டு வடிவமைப்புகளுக்குள் உள்ளிருந்து தெரிவிக்கிறோம், வேறுபாடு, மற்றும் வடிப்பின் ஒப்பீடுகளுக்கிடையே தெரிவிக்கிறோம்,  எங்கள் கண்டுபிடிப்புகள் எதிர்கால வேலைக்கான அடித்தளத்தை அமைத்து ஆராய்ச்சி தரம், களம் பாணி மாற்றம், மற்றும் மே</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>علمی سند کے لئے بہت بڑی تغییر درجہ ہے، دونوں منصفات (semantics) اور ساختار (pragmatics) کے مطابق۔ دانشمندی دفتر میں پہلے کام سمجھنے کے ذریعہ دفتر جمع کرنا اور کورپوس ٹوپ موڈلینگ کے ذریعہ سیمانٹیکوں کو تسبیح دیتا ہے لیکن اس کے ذریعہ پراگٹیکوں کو چھوڑ دیتا ہے جیسے دفتر سازمان اور فلاں۔ 19 دیسپلینوں اور ایٹیٹ کی زبان نمڈلینگ ٹیکنیک کے درمیان علمی دکھانیوں کی کورپوس کے استعمال کرتے ہیں، ہم دکھانے ٹکڑوں کے لئے دامنی-agnostic دکھانے والوں کا ایک ثابت مجموعہ سیکھتے ہیں اور ان دکھانے والوں کے لئے کورپوس کو دوبارہ دکھا دیتے ہیں (اس سے بھی 'normalization' نامیدے جاتے اس کے بعد ہم ان دکھانے والوں کی موقعیت اور سفارش کے ذریعہ تحقیق کرتے ہیں تاکہ دیسپانی اور ساختار کے درمیان رابطہ سمجھیں. ہم الزام کے اندر تفریق کی ساختار الکتروئیپ، متفاوت، اور الزام کے درمیان تفریق کے مطابق گزارتے ہیں، جو علمی کمونٹیوں کی مدد کرتی ہے، ان کے اندازے، متفاوت اور گھاٹ کے باوجود، ان کے کام کے مطابق مشابہ طریقوں میں شامل ہوتے ہیں ہمارے نتیجے آگے کے کاموں کے لئے بنیاد مقرر کر رہے ہیں تحقیقات کی کیفیت، ڈومین استیل ٹرانسٹر، اور اضافہ پراگرماتیک تحقیقات کے مطابق۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Tài liệu học có độ khác biệt lớn, cả về nội dung (ngữ nghĩa) và cấu trúc (thực dụng). Công việc trước đây trong sự hiểu biết tài liệu khoa học nhấn mạnh ngữ pháp qua việc mô phỏng tài liệu và tạo mẫu về chủ đề tập thể nhưng có xu hướng bỏ qua thực dụng như tổ chức tài liệu và dòng chảy. Sử dụng một tập hợp tài liệu khoa học trong các lĩnh vực 19 và các kỹ thuật tạo mẫu ngôn ngữ nghệ thuật hiện đại, chúng tôi đã học được một bộ mô tả cụ thể về nét văn bản và "sửa chữa" tập thể cho các mô tả này (còn được gọi là "bình thường). Sau đó, chúng tôi phân tích vị trí và xếp các mô tả này qua các tài liệu để hiểu mối quan hệ giữa kỷ luật và cấu trúc. Chúng tôi báo cáo các mẫu sắc về cấu trúc nội quy, độ biến thiên, và những so sánh giữa kỷ luật, ủng hộ giả thuyết rằng các cộng đồng khoa học, mặc dù kích thước, đa dạng và chiều rộng, chia sẻ tương tự nhau để bộc lộ công việc. Những nghiên cứu của chúng tôi tạo nên nền tảng cho công việc tương lai để đánh giá chất lượng nghiên cứu, chuyển đổi kiểu miền, và phân tích thực tế hơn.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Doimiy hujjatlar tarkibi (semantik) va tuzuvlar (pragmatika) bilan bir darajada ajratiladi. Name 19 ta taʼminlovchi hujjatlardan foydalanish va taʼminlovchi soʻzning holati modeli usulida, biz hujjatning qismlari uchun domen-agnostik descriptori va 'retrofit' tarkibini bu descriptorega qaramasdan qoʻllanma o'rganamiz. Keyin biz bu hujjatlarning joyini taʼrif qilamiz, discipline va tuzuvlar orasidagi munosabatlarni tushunamiz. Biz taʼminlovchi muammolarning oʻlchami, muloqat va kengligi qo'llanmalarning o'zgartirish uchun o'xshash qo'llanmalarni qo'llamiz. Bizning murojaatlarimiz kelajakdagi ishni tasavvur qilish sifatida, domen uslub uzatishni va boshqa pragmatik analyzerini qidirish uchun asosini yaratdik.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Научните документи имат голяма степен на вариация, както по отношение на съдържанието (семантика), така и структурата (прагматика). Предишната работа в научното разбиране на документите набляга на семантиката чрез обобщаване на документи и моделиране на корпусни теми, но има тенденция да пропуска прагматика като организация и поток на документи. Използвайки корпус от научни документи в 19 дисциплини и най-съвременни техники за езиково моделиране, научаваме фиксиран набор от агностични домейни дескриптори за документни раздели и "адаптираме" корпуса към тези дескриптори (наричани още "нормализиране"). След това анализираме позицията и подреждането на тези дескриптори в документите, за да разберем връзката между дисциплина и структура. Докладваме структурните архетипи в рамките на дисциплината, вариабилността и сравненията между дисциплината, подкрепяйки хипотезата, че научните общности, въпреки размера, разнообразието и ширината си, споделят сходни начини за изразяване на работата си. Нашите констатации поставят основата за бъдеща работа в оценката на качеството на научните изследвания, трансфера на домейн стил и по-нататъшен прагматичен анализ.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Wetenschappelijke documenten hebben een grote mate van variatie, zowel inhoudelijk (semantiek) als structureel (pragmatiek). Eerder werk in wetenschappelijk documentbegrip benadrukt semantiek door middel van document samenvatting en corpus topic modellering, maar heeft de neiging om pragmatica zoals documentorganisatie en -flow weg te laten. Met behulp van een corpus van wetenschappelijke documenten over 19-disciplines en state-of-the-art taalmodelleringstechnieken leren we een vaste set domeinagnostische descriptoren voor documentsecties en 'retrofit' het corpus naar deze descriptoren (ook wel 'normalisatie' genoemd). Vervolgens analyseren we de positie en volgorde van deze descriptoren in documenten om de relatie tussen discipline en structuur te begrijpen. We rapporteren binnen discipline structurele archetypen, variabiliteit en vergelijkingen tussen disciplines, die de hypothese ondersteunen dat wetenschappelijke gemeenschappen, ondanks hun grootte, diversiteit en breedte, vergelijkbare manieren hebben om hun werk uit te drukken. Onze bevindingen leggen de basis voor toekomstig onderzoek naar onderzoekskwaliteit, domeinstijltransfer en verdere pragmatische analyse.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Školski dokumenti imaju veliku stupnju varijacije, kako u smislu sadržaja (semantika) i strukture (pragmatika). Prije posla u znanstvenom razumijevanju dokumenta naglašava semantiku kroz sažetak dokumenta i modeliranje teme korpusa, ali je tendencija da napusti pragmatiku poput organizacije dokumenta i toka. Koristeći korpus znanstvenih dokumenta preko 19 disciplina i tehnika modeliranja jezika države umjetnosti, naučimo određenu skupu domena agnostičkih opisivača za dijelove dokumenta i 'povratak' korpusa na ove opisivače (također se naziva 'normalizacija'). Onda analiziramo poziciju i naređenje ovih opisača preko dokumenta kako bi razumjeli odnos između discipline i strukture. Prijavljujemo unutar disciplinskih strukturnih arhitepova, variabilnosti i između disciplinskih usporedba, podržavajući hipotezu da naučne zajednice, uprkos njihovoj veličini, raznolikosti i širini, dijele slične avente za izražavanje svojih radova. Naši nalazi su temelj za budući rad u procjeni kvalitete istraživanja, prenošenja stila domena i daljnje pragmatične analize.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Videnskabelige dokumenter har en stor variation, både med hensyn til indhold (semantik) og struktur (pragmatik). Tidligere arbejde i videnskabelig dokumentforståelse lægger vægt på semantik gennem dokumentopsummering og korpustemamodellering, men har tendens til at udelade pragmatik som dokumentorganisation og flow. Ved hjælp af et korpus af videnskabelige dokumenter på tværs af 19 discipliner og state-of-the-art sprogmodelleringsteknikker lærer vi et fast sæt domæneagnostiske deskriptorer til dokumentsektioner og 'retrofit' korpustet til disse deskriptorer (også kaldet 'normalisering'). Derefter analyserer vi placeringen og rækkefølgen af disse deskriptorer på tværs af dokumenter for at forstå forholdet mellem disciplin og struktur. Vi rapporterer inden for disciplinen strukturelle arketyper, variabilitet og mellem discipliner sammenligninger, hvilket understøtter hypotesen om, at videnskabelige samfund, på trods af deres størrelse, diversitet og bredde, deler lignende veje til at udtrykke deres arbejde. Vores resultater lægger fundamentet for det fremtidige arbejde med at vurdere forskningskvalitet, domænestileoverførsel og yderligere pragmatisk analyse.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Wissenschaftliche Dokumente weisen sowohl inhaltlich (Semantik) als auch strukturell (Pragmatik) große Variationen auf. Bisherige Arbeiten im wissenschaftlichen Dokumentenverständnis legen den Schwerpunkt auf Semantik durch Dokumentenverfassung und Korpusthemenmodellierung, verzichten jedoch eher auf Pragmatik wie Dokumentenorganisation und -fluss. Mit Hilfe eines Korpus wissenschaftlicher Dokumente über 19-Disziplinen hinweg und modernster Sprachmodellierungstechniken erlernen wir einen festen Satz domänennagnostischer Deskriptoren für Dokumentenabschnitte und "nachrüsten" den Korpus auf diese Deskriptoren (auch als "Normalisierung" bezeichnet). Anschließend analysieren wir die Position und Reihenfolge dieser Deskriptoren über Dokumente hinweg, um die Beziehung zwischen Disziplin und Struktur zu verstehen. Wir berichten über disziplinübergreifende strukturelle Archetypen, Variabilität und Vergleiche zwischen Disziplinen und unterstützen die Hypothese, dass wissenschaftliche Gemeinschaften trotz ihrer Größe, Vielfalt und Breite ähnliche Möglichkeiten haben, ihre Arbeit auszudrücken. Unsere Erkenntnisse legen den Grundstein für zukünftige Arbeiten zur Beurteilung der Forschungsqualität, des Domänenstiltransfers und weiterer pragmatischer Analysen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>مدارک دانشگاهی درجه بزرگی از تغییرات دارند، هر دو به عنوان محتوای (semantics) و ساختار (pragmatics). کارهای پیشینه در سند دانشمندی که درک می‌کند، از طریق جمع کردن سند و مدل‌سازی موضوع کورپوس تسبیح می‌کند، ولی به عنوان سازمان سند و جریان پروژه‌های پراگرماتیک را ترک می‌کند. با استفاده از یک مجموعه از مدارک دانشمندی در ۱۹ دستور و تکنیک مدل کردن زبان هنری، یک مجموعه از توصیف‌کننده‌های دامنی-agnostic برای بخش‌های سند یاد می‌گیریم و "بازسازی" کورپوس به این توصیف‌کننده‌ها (همچنین به عنوان "normalization") یاد می‌گیریم. سپس، ما موقعیت و دستور این توضیح‌کنندگان را در طول مدارک تحلیل می‌کنیم تا رابطه بین الگو و ساختار درک کنند. ما در داخل طراحی ساختاری، تغییر قابلیت و بین تغییر دیسپالین را گزارش می‌دهیم، که با وجود اندازه، تنوع و گسترش جامعه دانشمندان، از طریق تغییر دادن فرضیه‌های مشابهی برای تعریف کارشان شریک می‌کنند. نتیجه‌های ما بنیادی برای کار آینده در ارزیابی کیفیت تحقیقات، انتقال استیل دامنی و تحلیل پراگرماتیک بیشتر قرار می‌دهند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Dokumen sekolah memiliki tingkat variasi yang besar, baik dalam terma konten (semantik) dan struktur (pragmatik). Pekerjaan sebelumnya dalam pemahaman dokumen ilmiah menekankan semantik melalui penglihatan dokumen dan model topik corpus tetapi cenderung untuk melewatkan pragmatik seperti organisasi dokumen dan aliran. Using a corpus of scholarly documents across 19 disciplines and state-of-the-art language modeling techniques, we learn a fixed set of domain-agnostic descriptors for document sections and 'retrofit' the corpus to these descriptors (also referred to as 'normalization').  Kemudian, kami menganalisis posisi dan perintah deskriptor ini melalui dokumen untuk memahami hubungan antara disiplin dan struktur. Kami melaporkan dalam disiplin arkiteip struktural, variabilitas, dan perbandingan antara disiplin, mendukung hipotesis bahwa komunitas ilmuwan, meskipun ukuran, diversitas, dan lebar mereka, berbagi jalan yang sama untuk mengekspresikan pekerjaan mereka. Our findings lay the foundation for future work in assessing research quality, domain style transfer, and further pragmatic analysis.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>학술 문헌은 내용(어의)과 구조(어용) 방면에서 어느 정도 차이가 있다.이전의 학술 문서 이해 업무는 문서 요약과 어료 라이브러리 주제 모델링을 통해 의미를 실현하는 것을 강조했지만 문서 조직과 흐름 등 어용학을 소홀히 했다.우리는 19개 학과의 학술 문헌 자료 라이브러리와 가장 선진적인 언어 모델링 기술을 사용하여 문서 부분에 고정된 분야의 알 수 없는 묘사 부호를 학습하고 자료 라이브러리를 이러한 묘사 부호('규범화'라고도 부른다)로 개조했다.그 다음에 우리는 이 묘사부호들이 문서에 있는 위치와 순서를 분석하여 학과와 구조 간의 관계를 이해한다.우리는 학과 내의 구조 원형, 가변성과 학과 간의 비교를 보고했고 이러한 가설을 지지했다. 즉, 학술 단체는 규모, 다양성과 넓이가 다르지만 그의 작품을 표현하는 데 비슷한 경로를 가지고 있다는 것이다.우리의 발견은 앞으로 연구의 질, 분야의 풍격 이동과 진일보한 어용 분석을 평가하는 데 기반을 다졌다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Taarifa za shule zina kiwango kikubwa cha mabadiliko, kwa mukhtadha wa maudhui (semantics) na muundo (pragmatics). Prior work in scholarly document understanding emphasizes semantics through document summarization and corpus topic modeling but tends to omit pragmatics such as document organization and flow.  Kwa kutumia makala ya dokumu za kisomi katika maeneo 19 na mbinu za mifano ya lugha ya sanaa, tunajifunza mfululizo wa maelezo ya ndani kwa ajili ya sekta za nyaraka na 'kurudisha' kwenye maelezo haya (pia inaitwa 'utaratibu wa kawaida'). Kisha, tunachambua nafasi na amri ya maelezo haya katika nyaraka zote ili kuelewa uhusiano kati ya uadui na muundo. We report within-discipline structural archetypes, variability, and between-discipline comparisons, supporting the hypothesis that scholarly communities, despite their size, diversity, and breadth, share similar avenues for expressing their work.  Matokeo yetu yaliweka msingi wa kazi za baadae katika kutathmini ubora wa utafiti, uhamishaji wa mitindo ya ndani, na uchambuzi uliofanywa zaidi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Mekdebi belgeleri içerikler (semantik) ve yapılar (pragmatik) şeklinde büyük bir deñişiklik derecesi bar. Bilim desktapynda öňki işleri semantikleri desktap jemlasyny we korpus meýdançasynda görkezmeleri täzeden geçirýär, ýöne sened organizasiýasy we aklygy ýaly pragmatiklerden çykarýar. 19 discipliniň we sungatçylyk dili modelleýän teknikleriň üstünde bilim adamlaryň bir korpusyny ulanyp, biz sened bölümleriniň beýleki agnostik tassymlaryny we bu tassymlaryň köpüsini (hem 'normalization' diýip adlanýarys). Sonra, biz bu deskriptçilerin ýerini we düzümlerini desktaplaryň arasynda düşünmek üçin çözümlendik. Biz discipliniň strukturlarynyň içinde, üýtgeşik we disiplin arasynda deňleşenleri baglaşýarys, bilim adamlarynyň ölçüsi, çeşitlilikleri we genişlikleri bilen meňzeş ýoldyklaryny beýleki ýoldyrlaryna golaýlaşýarys. Çaplarymyz gelejekde işleriň esasy, domeniň stili terjimesini we ýeterlik pragmatik çözümlerini çözmekde esasy çykar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>ሰነዱን በጥምቀት ሰነድ፣ የጥቅምት (semantics) እና መሠረት (pragmatics) ጥያቄ የልዩ ልዩነት ጥያቄ አለባቸው፡፡ የሰነድ አቀማመጥ እና የኮርፓስ ጉዳይ ምሳሌ በማድረግ የተጠቃሚ ሰነድ ማስታወቂያውን አስቀድሞ ሥራ ግን እንደ ሰነድ አካባቢ ድርጅት እና ፈሳሽ እንደተፈላጊ ጥያቄዎችን ትተዋል፡፡ በ19 ባሕላዊ ሰነዶች እና የቋንቋ-ቋንቋ ምሳሌ አስተያየት እየተጠቃሚ ሰነድ እና ለሰነድ ክፍሎች እና ለዚህ ጽሑፎች (ደግሞ ‘normal’) የተጠቃሚ የዶሜን-agnostic ጽሑፎችን እና ‘መልስ’ የሚል ክፍተቶችን እናስተማራለን፡፡ ከዚህም በኋላ እነዚህን ጽሑፎች ማዘጋጀት እና በሰነድ ሰነዶች መካከል ግንኙነትን ለማስተዋል እናስተዋልታለን፡፡ We report within-discipline structural archetypes, variability, and between-discipline comparisons, supporting the hypothesis that scholarly communities, despite their size, diversity, and breadth, share similar avenues for expressing their work.  ግንኙነታችን ለኋለኛይቱ ሥራ መሠረትን ለመፍጠር ጥያቄ፣ የድሜን ዘይት መቀናቀል እና ለጥያቄ አስተያየት መሠረት አቆመዋል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Scholarly documents have a great degree of variation, both in terms of content (semantics) and structure (pragmatics).  Puna e paraardhshme në kuptimin e dokumenteve shkencore thekson semantikën nëpërmjet përmbledhjes së dokumenteve dhe modelimit të temave corpus, por ka tendencë të braktisë pragmatikë të tilla si organizata e dokumenteve dhe rrjedhja. Duke përdorur një korpus dokumentesh shkencore nëpër 19 disiplina dhe teknika të modelimit të gjuhës më të moderne, ne mësojmë një sërë fikse të përshkrimtarëve domain-agnostik për seksionet e dokumenteve dhe 'retrofit' korpus për këta përshkrimtarë (të quajtur gjithashtu 'normalizim'). Pastaj, ne analizojmë pozicionin dhe urdhërimin e këtyre përshkrimtarëve nëpër dokumente për të kuptuar marrëdhëniet midis disiplinës dhe strukturës. Ne raportojmë brenda disiplinës arketype strukturore, variabilitet dhe krahasime midis disiplinës, duke mbështetur hipotezën se komunitetet shkencore, pavarësisht nga madhësia, diversiteti dhe gjerësia e tyre, ndajnë rrugë të ngjashme për shprehjen e punës së tyre. Zbulimet tona vënë themelin e punës së ardhshme në vlerësimin e cilësisë së kërkimit, transferimit të stilit të dominit dhe analizës pragmatike të mëtejshme.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bn>স্কুলে ডকুমেন্টের মধ্যে বিভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ডিগ্রি রয়েছে, বিষয়বস্তু (সেম্যান্টিক) এবং কাঠামোর মাধ্যমে উভয Prior work in scholarly document understanding emphasizes semantics through document summarization and corpus topic modeling but tends to omit pragmatics such as document organization and flow.  ১৯ শিক্ষাবিদ্যালয় এবং রাষ্ট্র-শিল্পী ভাষার মডেলিং প্রযুক্তি ব্যবহার করে আমরা নথি বিভাগের জন্য একটি নির্ধারিত সেট ডোমেইন-অ্যাগ্নোস্টিক বিবরণ শিখেছি এবং 'পুনরায় ফিরিয়ে নি তারপর আমরা শিক্ষাপ্রাপ্ত এবং কাঠামোর মধ্যে যে সম্পর্ক বুঝতে পারি সারা ডকুমেন্টের বিভিন্ন অবস্থান এবং নির্দেশ দিয়ে আমরা শিক্ষার্থীর মধ্যে কাঠামো আর্কারেটাইপ, বিভিন্ন এবং শিক্ষার্থীর তুলনায় সংবাদ প্রদান করি যে শিক্ষাগত সম্প্রদায়ের মাপ, বৈচিত্র্য, এবং প্রসার সত্ত্বেও আমাদের আবিস্কার ভবিষ্যতের কাজের জন্য ভিত্তিতে গবেষণার মান, ডোমেইন স্টাইল পরিবর্তনের মাধ্যমে গবেষণা, আরো বিশ্লে</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Scholarly documents have a great degree of variation, both in terms of content (semantics) and structure (pragmatics).  Առաջին աշխատանքը գիտական փաստաթղթերի ընկալումը նշանակում է սեմանտիկան փաստաթղթերի համառոտագրման և կորպուս թեմայի մոդելների միջոցով, բայց հակված է թողնել այնպիսի պրագմատիկա, ինչպիսիք են փաստաթղթերի կազմակերպությունը և Օգտագործելով գիտնական փաստաթղթեր 19 ոլորտում և ամենաբարձր լեզվի մոդելավորման մեթոդներ, մենք սովորում ենք փաստաթղթերի հատվածների բնորոշ դասակարգ ագնոստիկ նկարագրողներ և "վերադասակարգ" մարմինը այս նկարագրողներին (որը նաև կոչվում է "նորմալիզացիա"): Հետո մենք վերլուծում ենք այս նկարագրերի դիրքը և կարգավորումը փաստաթղթերի միջև, որպեսզի հասկանանք գիտակցության և կառուցվածքի միջև կապը: We report within-discipline structural archetypes, variability, and between-discipline comparisons, supporting the hypothesis that scholarly communities, despite their size, diversity, and breadth, share similar avenues for expressing their work.  Մեր հայտնաբերությունները հիմնադրում են հետազոտության որակի գնահատման ապագա աշխատանքի հիմքը, բնագավառի ոճի փոխանցումը և ապագա պրագմատիկ վերլուծությունը:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>M…ôkt…ôb bel…ôl…ôrind…ô m√ľxt…ôlif d…ôyiŇüiklik var, h…ôr ikisi d…ô m…ôlumat (semantik) v…ô struktur (pragmatik) il…ô. Bilim s…ôhif…ôl…ôrind…ô …ôvv…ôlki iŇül…ôr m…ôlumatńĪ bel…ô d√∂k√ľm…ô qurńüulamasńĪ v…ô korpus m…ôlumatńĪ modeliyind…ôn t…ôsirl…ôndirir, amma bel…ô d√∂k√ľm organizasyonu v…ô akńĪŇüńĪ kimi pragmatikl…ôri t…ôrk edir. 19 disciplinin v…ô sanatlńĪ dil modellik teknikl…ôrinin arasńĪndakńĪ bilimsel bel…ôl…ôrin korpusu istifad…ô ed…ôr…ôk, bel…ôl…ôrin b√∂l√ľml…ôrinin d…ôyiŇüdirilm…ôsi √ľ√ß√ľn d…ôyiŇüdirilmiŇü domain-agnostik t…ôrzl…ôrini √∂yr…ônirik v…ô bu t…ôrzl…ôrin…ô korpusu "retrofit" √∂yr…ônirik. Sonra, biz bu yazńĪcńĪlarńĪn m…ôqamńĪnńĪ v…ô s…ôhif…ôl…ôr arasńĪndakńĪ iliŇükisini anlamaq √ľ√ß√ľn analiz edirik. Biz diziplinin strukturlu arŇüitipl…ôrinin i√ßind…ô, d…ôyiŇüiklik v…ô diziplinin arasńĪnda m√ľ…ôyy…ônl…ôŇüdirirl…ôr, bilimsel toplumlarńĪn b√∂y√ľkl√ľk, m√ľxt…ôlif v…ô geniŇüliyi olmasńĪna rańümen onlarńĪn iŇüini ifad…ô etm…ôk √ľ√ß√ľn eyni yollar paylaŇüńĪrlar. Bizim tapńĪlarńĪmńĪz g…ôl…ôc…ôk iŇül…ôr √ľ√ß√ľn t…ôhsil kaliteti, domena stili transfer v…ô daha √ßox pragmatik analizi deńüerl…ôŇüdirm…ôkd…ô qurular.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_af>Skolaarde dokumente het 'n groot grad van veranderinge, beide ingevolge inhoud (semantieke) en struktuur (pragmatike). Vorige werk in die wetlike dokument verstanding bepaal semantieke deur dokument opsomming en korpus onderwerp modellering, maar tendeer na verwerp pragmatike soos dokumentorganisasie en vloei. By gebruik van 'n korpus van wetenskaplike dokumente oor 19 dissipels en staat-van-die-kunste taal modelleringteknike, leer ons 'n vaste stel domein-agnostiese beskrywers vir dokument seksies en 'retrofit' die korpus na hierdie beskrywers (ook bekend as 'normalisering'). Dan, ons analyseer die posisie en ordening van hierdie beskrywers oor dokumente om die verwanting tussen discipline en struktuur te verstaan. Ons rapporteer binne-disipliniese strukturele arkitetipes, veranderbaarheid en tussen-disipliniese vergelykings, ondersteun die hipotees wat studende gemeenskappe, ten ag van hul grootte, verskeidigheid en breedte, vergelykende avenue vir hulle werk te uitdruk. Ons gevinde lê die fondasie vir toekomstige werk in die vurdering van resekkingkwaliteit, domeinstyl oordrag en verdere pragmatiske analisie.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_cs>Vědecké dokumenty mají velký stupeň variací, a to jak z hlediska obsahu (sémantiky), tak struktury (pragmatiky). Předchozí práce v oblasti vědeckého porozumění dokumentů klade důraz na sémantiku prostřednictvím shrnutí dokumentů a modelování témat korpusu, ale má tendenci vynechat pragmatiku, jako je organizace dokumentů a tok dokumentů. Použitím korpusu vědeckých dokumentů napříč 19-disciplínami a nejmodernějších jazykových modelovacích technik se naučíme pevnou sadu doménově agnostických deskriptorů pro sekce dokumentů a "retrofit" korpus na tyto deskriptory (také označované jako "normalizace"). Poté analyzujeme pozici a uspořádání těchto deskriptorů napříč dokumenty, abychom porozuměli vztahu mezi disciplínou a strukturou. Popisujeme strukturální archetypy, variabilitu a porovnání mezi disciplínami a podporujeme hypotézu, že vědecké komunity, navzdory své velikosti, rozmanitosti a šířce, sdílejí podobné cesty pro vyjádření své práce. Naše zjištění položí základ pro budoucí práci v oblasti hodnocení kvality výzkumu, transferu doménového stylu a další pragmatické analýzy.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Teaduslikud dokumendid on väga erinevad nii sisu (semantika) kui ka struktuuri (pragmaatika) poolest. Varasem töö teadusliku dokumendi mõistmise alal rõhutab semantikat dokumendi kokkuvõtte ja korpuse teemade modelleerimise kaudu, kuid kaldub välja jätma pragmaatikat, nagu dokumendi korraldus ja voog. Kasutades teaduslikke dokumente 19 erialal ja kaasaegseid keelemudeldamismeetodeid, õpime dokumendijaotiste jaoks fikseeritud domeeni agnostiliste kirjelduste komplekti ja "moderniseerime" korpuse nende kirjeldustega (mida nimetatakse ka "normaliseerimiseks"). Seejärel analüüsime nende kirjelduste positsiooni ja järjestust dokumentides, et mõista distsipliini ja struktuuri vahelist seost. Me anname teada distsipliinisisesed struktuurilised arhetüübid, varieeruvus ja distsipliinidevahelised võrdlused, toetades hüpoteesi, et teaduslikud kogukonnad, vaatamata oma suurusele, mitmekesisusele ja laiusele, jagavad sarnaseid võimalusi oma töö väljendamiseks. Meie tulemused panevad aluse tulevasele tööle teadusuuringute kvaliteedi hindamisel, domeenistiili ülekandmisel ja edasisel pragmaatilisel analüüsil.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>Školski dokumenti imaju veliku stupnju varijacije, kako u smislu sadržaja (semantika) i strukture (pragmatika). Prije posla u znanstvenom razumijevanju dokumenta naglašava semantiku kroz sažetak dokumenta i modeliranje teme korpusa, ali je tendencija da napusti pragmatiku poput organizacije dokumenta i toka. Koristeći korpus znanstvenih dokumenta preko 19 disciplina i tehnika modeliranja jezika države umjetnosti, naučimo fiksnu skupu domena agnostičkih opisivača za sekcije dokumenta i 'povratak' korpusa na ove opisivače (takođe se zove 'normalizacija'). Onda analiziramo poziciju i naređenje ovih opisača preko dokumenta kako bi razumjeli odnos između discipline i strukture. Prijavljujemo unutar disciplinskih strukturnih arhitepova, variabilnosti i između disciplinskih usporedba, podržavajući hipotezu da naučne zajednice, uprkos njihovoj veličini, raznolikosti i širini, dijele slične avente za izražavanje svojih radova. Naši nalazi su temelj za budući rad u procjeni kvalitete istraživanja, transfer stila domena i daljnje pragmatične analize.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_fi>Tieteelliset asiakirjat vaihtelevat suuresti sekä sisällön (semantiikan) että rakenteen (pragmatiikan) osalta. Aiempi tieteellinen dokumenttien ymmärtäminen painottaa semantiikkaa dokumenttien yhteenvetojen ja korpusaiheiden mallintamisen avulla, mutta yleensä jättää pois pragmatiikkaa, kuten dokumenttien organisointia ja virtausta. Käyttämällä 19 tieteenalan tieteellisiä asiakirjoja ja viimeisintä tekniikkaa hyödyntävää kielimallinnustekniikkaa opimme kiinteän joukon toimialueen agnostisia kuvauksia asiakirjaosioihin ja 'jälkisovittamalla' korpus näihin kuvauksiin (kutsutaan myös 'normalisointi'). Tämän jälkeen analysoimme näiden kuvaajien sijaintia ja järjestystä dokumenteissa ymmärtääksemme kurinalaisuuden ja rakenteen välistä suhdetta. Raportoimme tieteenalojen sisäisiä rakenteellisia arkkityyppejä, vaihtelevuutta ja tieteenalojen välisiä vertailuja tukeen hypoteesia siitä, että tiedeyhteisöillä on koostaan, monimuotoisuudestaan ja laajuudestaan huolimatta samanlaisia tapoja ilmaista työtään. Tuloksemme luovat perustan tulevalle tutkimukselle laadun arvioinnissa, toimialueen tyylin siirrossa ja käytännön analyysissä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>Scholarly documents have a great degree of variation, both in terms of content (semantics) and structure (pragmatics).  Prior work in scholarly document understanding emphasizes semantics through document summarization and corpus topic modeling but tends to omit pragmatics such as document organization and flow.  Utilitzant un cos de documents científics a través de 19 disciplines i tècniques de modelació de llenguatges més avançades, aprenem un conjunt fixe de descriptors de domini-agnòstics per seccions de documents i 'retrofit' el corpus a aquests descriptors (també anomenats 'normalització'). Llavors analitzem la posició i l'ordre d'aquests descriptors a través de documents per entendre la relació entre disciplina i estructura. Rapportem arquetips estructurals, variabilitats i comparacions entre disciplines dins la disciplina, donant suport a la hipòtesi que les comunitats científices, malgrat la seva mida, diversitat i ampleur, comparteixen camins similars per expressar el seu treball. Els nostres descobriments estan les bases de la futura feina en l'evaluació de la qualitat de la recerca, la transfer ència d'estil de domini i més anàlisi pragmàtica.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_jv>Dokumen Pedang saiki karo akeh dhéwé, sampeyan ngono nggawe barang (semanti) lan structural (pragumatik). Awak dhéwé éntuk karo Dokumen sing paling-awak kuwi nyanggalih basa semanti kuwi nggawe tarjamahan karo modèl tema banget kuwi nggawe pragumatik yo koyo ngono dokumen sing bakal dumadhi. Ngawe gunakake corus of acadèid dokumen karo 19 disiplin lan state-of-the-arts language modelining teknik, kita siji as êng a fixed set of domain-ageostc descriptor for document segmentions and 'retOft' the corus to this descriptor (tambah terus 'normal'). Njuk, awak dhéwé beraksi perusahaan lan urip-urip kuwi nggawe Dokumen kuwi nggawe barang sampek karo disiplin lan sak structural. Awak dhéwé éntuk karo-disiplin structural karo akeh-akeh, dadi karo karo-disiplin karo nggawe lan nggunakake suputes kuwi kesempatan acara dhéwé, gak dhéwé kuwi kesempatan, ngregani soko akeh lan kejahatan, iso nggawe barang-aké suputes kanggo ngeralakno. We find find the Foundation for next job in assessing R&amp;D quality, domain style transfer, and additional pragmatic testing.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Znanstveni dokumenti imajo veliko različnosti, tako glede vsebine (semantike) kot strukture (pragmatike). Predhodno delo na področju znanstvenega razumevanja dokumentov poudarja semantiko skozi povzetek dokumentov in modeliranje teme korpusa, vendar navaja izpustiti pragmatiko, kot sta organizacija dokumentov in tok. Z uporabo korpusa znanstvenih dokumentov v 19 disciplinah in najsodobnejših tehnik jezikovnega modeliranja se naučimo fiksnega nabora domensko-agnostičnih deskriptorjev za odseke dokumentov in korpus "prilagodimo" tem deskriptorjem (imenovanim tudi "normalizacija"). Nato analiziramo položaj in vrstni red teh deskriptorjev v dokumentih, da bi razumeli razmerje med disciplino in strukturo. Poročamo znotrajdisciplinske strukturne arhetipe, variabilnost in meddisciplinske primerjave ter podpiramo hipotezo, da si znanstvene skupnosti kljub svoji velikosti, raznolikosti in širini delijo podobne načine za izražanje svojega dela. Naše ugotovitve postavljajo temelje za prihodnje delo pri ocenjevanju kakovosti raziskav, prenosu domenskega sloga in nadaljnji pragmatični analizi.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>Scholarly documents have a great degree of variation, both in terms of content (semantics) and structure (pragmatics).  Prior work in scholarly document understanding emphasizes semantics through document summarization and corpus topic modeling but tends to omit pragmatics such as document organization and flow.  בשימוש בקורפוס של מסמכים מדעיים ברחבי 19 משמעות וטכניקות דגמנית שפת מצוינות, אנו לומדים קבועה של תוארי אגנוסטיקה-שטח עבור חלקי מסמכים 'ו 'מחדש' את הקורפוס לתארי אלה (שנקרא גם 'נורמליזציה'). ואז, אנו מנתחים את המיקום והזמנה של התיאורים האלה ברחבי מסמכים כדי להבין את מערכת היחסים בין משמעת לבין מבנה. We report within-discipline structural archetypes, variability, and between-discipline comparisons, supporting the hypothesis that scholarly communities, despite their size, diversity, and breadth, share similar avenues for expressing their work.  Our findings lay the foundation for future work in assessing research quality, domain style transfer, and further pragmatic analysis.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>@ info: tooltip Kayyan aiki a cikin dokuman da aka karanta, ana fahimta, yana ƙayyade masu motsi na takardar ƙararin takardar da muhallin maɓallin nau'i, kuma yana kasa yin sauri daga abubuwa kamar shirin takardar da shirin kode. Yi amfani da kowacin takardar takarda masu sani a kowaci cikin littafan 19 na'ura da masu motsi na-cikin-harshen-sanar, za'a sanar da wasu shiryoyin ayuka masu daidaita na-agnostic wa rabon-dukkan takarda da 'retrofit' korbas zuwa waɗannan cewa "normal". Sa'an nan, Munã yi anayya ga wurin da Muke umurni da waɗannan descriptori a kan dukkan takardan, dõmin su fahimta danganci tsakanin disiplin da tsarin. Munã bãyar da bisani da bakwai-cikin-disiplin, masu variani da tsakanin-disiplin, kuma masu ƙarfafa da misãlai da jamii masu sani, kuma kõ da girma, da sãɓãnin da faɗi, sai su yi rabo da misãlai masu daidaita dõmin su bayyana aikin su. MataimakinMu na sami asalin aikin nan gaba ɗaya a kan anakiri tsarin research, transfer style na guda, da kuma misãlin bayani.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>སློབ་གྲྭའི་ཡིག་ཆ་ལ་རྣམས་ནང་དོན་འགྱུར་བའི་ཚད་ལྡན་ཤིག་ཡོད། ཤེས་རིག་གི་ཡིག་ཆ་ལ་སྔོན་གྱི་ལས་སྦྱོར་བ་ནི་རྣམ་པ་ཚོ་བློ་གཏོང་དང་མཛོད་ཁང་གི་གནད་དོན་དག་ལ་བསྟར་ན། Using a corpus of scholarly documents across 19 disciplines and state-of-the-art language modeling techniques, we learn a fixed set of domain-agnostic descriptors for document sections and 'retrofit' the corpus to these descriptors (also referred to as 'normalization'). འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་ཡིག་ཆ་འདི་དག་གི་གནས་ཡུལ་ཞིབ་དཔྱད་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡིག་ཆ་དང་དབྱིབས་སྦྲེལ་མཐུད་དེ་རྟོགས་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་ཤེས་བྱེད་དབུགས་གཙོ་རིམ་དང་། སྣ་ཚོགས་དང་སྒྲིག་གི་མཐུན་སྒྲིག་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་གཏོང་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། Our findings lay the foundation for future work in assessing research quality, domain style transfer, and further pragmatic analysis.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Extractive Research Slide Generation Using Windowed Labeling Ranking</title>
      <author><first>Athar</first><last>Sefid</last></author>
      <author><first>Prasenjit</first><last>Mitra</last></author>
      <author><first>Jian</first><last>Wu</last></author>
      <author><first>C Lee</first><last>Giles</last></author>
      <pages>91–96</pages>
      <abstract>Presentation slides generated from original research papers provide an efficient form to present research innovations. Manually generating presentation slides is labor-intensive. We propose a method to automatically generates slides for scientific articles based on a corpus of 5000 paper-slide pairs compiled from conference proceedings websites. The sentence labeling module of our method is based on SummaRuNNer, a neural sequence model for extractive summarization. Instead of ranking sentences based on semantic similarities in the whole document, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a> measures the importance and novelty of sentences by combining semantic and lexical features within a sentence window. Our method outperforms several baseline methods including SummaRuNNer by a significant margin in terms of ROUGE score.</abstract>
      <url hash="3b9dcf40">2021.sdp-1.11</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sdp-1.11</doi>
      <bibkey>sefid-etal-2021-extractive</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/atharsefid/Extractive_Research_Slide_Generation_Using_Windowed_Labeling_Ranking" additional="false">atharsefid/Extractive_Research_Slide_Generation_Using_Windowed_Labeling_Ranking</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/5k-presetation-slides">5k_presetation_slides</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Unsupervised document summarization using pre-trained sentence embeddings and graph centrality</title>
      <author><first>Juan</first><last>Ramirez-Orta</last></author>
      <author><first>Evangelos</first><last>Milios</last></author>
      <pages>110–115</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our submission for the LongSumm task in SDP 2021. We propose a method for incorporating sentence embeddings produced by deep language models into extractive summarization techniques based on graph centrality in an unsupervised manner. The proposed method is simple, fast, can summarize any kind of document of any size and can satisfy any length constraints for the summaries produced. The method offers competitive performance to more sophisticated <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervised_learning">supervised methods</a> and can serve as a proxy for abstractive summarization techniques</abstract>
      <url hash="b96b587b">2021.sdp-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sdp-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>ramirez-orta-milios-2021-unsupervised</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>QMUL-SDS at SCIVER : Step-by-Step Binary Classification for Scientific Claim Verification<fixed-case>QMUL</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>SDS</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>SCIVER</fixed-case>: Step-by-Step Binary Classification for Scientific Claim Verification</title>
      <author><first>Xia</first><last>Zeng</last></author>
      <author><first>Arkaitz</first><last>Zubiaga</last></author>
      <pages>116–123</pages>
      <abstract>Scientific claim verification is a unique challenge that is attracting increasing interest. The SCIVER shared task offers a benchmark scenario to test and compare claim verification approaches by participating teams and consists in three steps : relevant abstract selection, rationale selection and label prediction. In this paper, we present team QMUL-SDS’s participation in the shared task. We propose an approach that performs scientific claim verification by doing binary classifications step-by-step. We trained a BioBERT-large classifier to select abstracts based on pairwise relevance assessments for each claim, title of the abstract and continued to train it to select rationales out of each retrieved abstract based on claim, sentence. We then propose a two-step setting for label prediction, i.e. first predicting NOT_ENOUGH_INFO or ENOUGH_INFO, then label those marked as ENOUGH_INFO as either SUPPORT or CONTRADICT. Compared to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline system</a>, we achieve substantial improvements on the dev set. As a result, our team is the No. 4 team on the leaderboard.</abstract>
      <url hash="c8ee47ef">2021.sdp-1.15</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sdp-1.15</doi>
      <bibkey>zeng-zubiaga-2021-qmul</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/XiaZeng0223/sciverbinary" additional="false">XiaZeng0223/sciverbinary</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/fever">FEVER</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/scifact">SciFact</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>