<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.bionlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 20th Workshop on Biomedical Language Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Dina</first><last>Demner-Fushman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kevin Bretonnel</first><last>Cohen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sophia</first><last>Ananiadou</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Junichi</first><last>Tsujii</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="9d6b408e">2021.bionlp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9670b428">2021.bionlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>bionlp-2021-biomedical</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Scalable Few-Shot Learning of Robust Biomedical Name Representations</title>
      <author><first>Pieter</first><last>Fivez</last></author>
      <author><first>Simon</first><last>Suster</last></author>
      <author><first>Walter</first><last>Daelemans</last></author>
      <pages>23–29</pages>
      <abstract>Recent research on robust representations of biomedical names has focused on modeling large amounts of fine-grained conceptual distinctions using complex neural encoders. In this paper, we explore the opposite <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paradigm">paradigm</a> : training a simple encoder architecture using only small sets of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Name">names</a> sampled from high-level biomedical concepts. Our encoder post-processes pretrained representations of biomedical names, and is effective for various types of input representations, both domain-specific or unsupervised. We validate our proposed few-shot learning approach on multiple biomedical relatedness benchmarks, and show that it allows for continual learning, where we accumulate information from various conceptual hierarchies to consistently improve encoder performance. Given these findings, we propose our approach as a low-cost alternative for exploring the impact of conceptual distinctions on robust biomedical name representations.</abstract>
      <url hash="15454166">2021.bionlp-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>fivez-etal-2021-scalable</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/clips/fewshot-biomedical-names" additional="false">clips/fewshot-biomedical-names</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ehr-rel">EHR-Rel</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>SAFFRON : tranSfer leArning For Food-disease RelatiOn extractioN<fixed-case>SAFFRON</fixed-case>: tran<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>fer le<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>rning For Food-disease <fixed-case>R</fixed-case>elati<fixed-case>O</fixed-case>n extractio<fixed-case>N</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Gjorgjina</first><last>Cenikj</last></author>
      <author><first>Tome</first><last>Eftimov</last></author>
      <author><first>Barbara</first><last>Koroušić Seljak</last></author>
      <pages>30–40</pages>
      <abstract>The accelerating growth of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_data">big data</a> in the biomedical domain, with an endless amount of electronic health records and more than 30 million citations and abstracts in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed">PubMed</a>, introduces the need for automatic structuring of textual biomedical data. In this paper, we develop a method for detecting relations between food and disease entities from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_(literary_theory)">raw text</a>. Due to the lack of annotated data on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Food">food</a> with respect to health, we explore the feasibility of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">transfer learning</a> by training BERT-based models on existing datasets annotated for the presence of cause and treat relations among different types of biomedical entities, and using them to recognize the same relations between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Food">food and disease entities</a> in a dataset created for the purposes of this study. The best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> achieve macro averaged F1 scores of 0.847 and 0.900 for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Causality">cause and treat relations</a>, respectively.</abstract>
      <url hash="b447feb6">2021.bionlp-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>cenikj-etal-2021-saffron</bibkey>
    <title_ar>الزعفران: وسيلة نقل آمنة لاستخراج العلاقة بين الأمراض الغذائية</title_ar>
      <title_es>AZAFRÁN: aprendizaje de transferencia para la extracción de la relación alimento-enfermedad</title_es>
      <title_pt>AÇAFRÃO: APRENDIZAGEM DE TRANSFERÊNCIA PARA EXTRAÇÃO DA RELAÇÃO ALIMENTAR-DOENÇA</title_pt>
      <title_ja>サフラン： tranSfer leArning for Food - disease RelatiOn extractioN</title_ja>
      <title_zh>藏红花:移食疾关提取物</title_zh>
      <title_hi>केसर: transfer leArning खाद्य रोग के लिए RelatiOn extractioN</title_hi>
      <title_ga>SAFFRON: FOGHLAMA A AISTRIĂš D'EiscEACHT CAIDRIMH Bia-Galar</title_ga>
      <title_el>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning για την εξαγωγή σχέσης τροφής-ασθενειών</title_el>
      <title_ka>პანჟტვპ ლვ აპნთნდ ჱა ჳპანა-ბჲლვმთ ჟლსზვნთვ ნა ვკჟრპაკრთჲნ</title_ka>
      <title_hu>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation ExtractioN</title_hu>
      <title_mk>Трансфер леArning For Food-Disease RelatiOn Extraction</title_mk>
      <title_kk>САФФРОН: Трансфер ле-Арнинг Тыйық-аурулар қатынасыOn extractioN</title_kk>
      <title_it>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-Disease Relation ExtractioN</title_it>
      <title_lt>SAFFRON: Transfer leArning For Food-disease RelatiOn extractionN</title_lt>
      <title_ml>സാഫ്രോണ്‍: tranSfer leArning For Food- disease Relation extractioN</title_ml>
      <title_mn>САФФРОН: Хоосон өвчинтэй холбоотой трансфер</title_mn>
      <title_mt>SAFFRON: transfer leArning For Food-disease RelatiOn extraction</title_mt>
      <title_ms>SAFFRON: Transfer leArning For Food-disease RelatiOn extraction</title_ms>
      <title_ro>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning Pentru Relația cu Boala Alimentară ExtractioN</title_ro>
      <title_no>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation extractioN</title_no>
      <title_si>සැෆ්රෝන්: ට්‍රෑන්ස්ෆර් ලියාර්නිංග් කෑම-රෝගිකය සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන්.</title_si>
      <title_pl>SAFFRON: transSfer leArning dla ekstrakcji związków żywnościowo-chorobowych</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Transfer leArning za povezanje s hranom i bolestima</title_sr>
      <title_ta>சாஃப்ரான்: tranSfer leArning For Food- disease Relation extractioN</title_ta>
      <title_sv>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation ExtractioN</title_sv>
      <title_ur>سفارفون: ٹرانسفر لئرنگ کھانا بیماری رابطہ پر بیٹراکتیون</title_ur>
      <title_so>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation extractioN</title_so>
      <title_uz>TranSfer leArning For Food- disease Relation extractioN</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Name=Kate ProjectmanagerComment</title_vi>
      <title_bg>САФРОН: трансфер леАрнинг за връзка хранително-болести Екстракция</title_bg>
      <title_da>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation ExtractioN</title_da>
      <title_hr>SAFFRON: transSfer leArning za povezanje s hranom i bolestima</title_hr>
      <title_nl>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning Voor de Relatie van Voedselziekten</title_nl>
      <title_de>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-Disease Relation ExtractoN</title_de>
      <title_id>SAFFRON: Transfer leArning For Food-disease RelatiOn extraction</title_id>
      <title_ko>붉은 꽃: 식품 질병 관계 추출에 사용되는 전이 학습</title_ko>
      <title_sw>SAFFRON: TranSfer leArning For Food-related Relations On extractioN</title_sw>
      <title_fa>رابطه بیماری غذا و بیماری بیرون بیرون</title_fa>
      <title_af>SafFRON: tranSfer leArning vir Food-disease Relation extractioN</title_af>
      <title_tr>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation extractioN</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Transfer leArning For Food-disease RelatiOn extraction</title_sq>
      <title_am>TranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation extractioN</title_am>
      <title_bn>স্যাফ্রোন: ট্রানফার লেArning For Food- রোগ সম্পর্কিত</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Transfer leArning za povezanje s hranom i bolestima</title_bs>
      <title_hy>Սաֆրոն. տրանսֆերֆ լեյնը</title_hy>
      <title_cs>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning pro extrakci vztahu mezi potravinami a chorobami</title_cs>
      <title_az>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation ExtractioN</title_az>
      <title_fi>SAFFRON: transSfer leArning For Food-disease relationExtrationN</title_fi>
      <title_ca>SAFFRON: Transfer leArning For Food-disease RelatiOn extraction</title_ca>
      <title_et>SAFFRON: transSfer leArning toidu ja haiguste suhete ekstraheerimiseks</title_et>
      <title_jv>Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles Subtitles</title_jv>
      <title_he>ספרון:</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>SAFFRON: transSfer leArning Za razmerje med hrano in boleznimi EkstrakcijoN</title_sk>
      <title_bo>SAFFRON: tranSfer leArning For Food-disease Relation extractioN</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>إن النمو المتسارع للبيانات الضخمة في المجال الطبي الحيوي ، مع وجود عدد لا نهائي من السجلات الصحية الإلكترونية وأكثر من 30 مليون استشهاد وملخص في PubMed ، يقدم الحاجة إلى هيكلة تلقائية للبيانات الطبية الحيوية النصية. في هذه الورقة ، نطور طريقة لاكتشاف العلاقات بين كيانات الغذاء والمرض من النص الخام. نظرًا لعدم وجود بيانات مشروحة حول الغذاء فيما يتعلق بالصحة ، فإننا نستكشف جدوى نقل التعلم من خلال تدريب النماذج المستندة إلى BERT على مجموعات البيانات الحالية المشروحة لوجود علاقات السبب والمعالجة بين أنواع مختلفة من الكيانات الطبية الحيوية ، واستخدامها في التعرف على نفس العلاقات بين كيانات الغذاء والمرض في مجموعة بيانات تم إنشاؤها لأغراض هذه الدراسة. تحقق أفضل النماذج متوسط درجات F1 الكلي من 0.847 و 0.900 لعلاقات السبب والعلاج ، على التوالي.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>O crescimento acelerado do big data no domínio biomédico, com uma quantidade infinita de registros eletrônicos de saúde e mais de 30 milhões de citações e resumos no PubMed, introduz a necessidade de estruturação automática de dados biomédicos textuais. Neste artigo, desenvolvemos um método para detectar relações entre alimentos e entidades de doença a partir de texto bruto. Devido à falta de dados anotados sobre alimentos no que diz respeito à saúde, exploramos a viabilidade de transferência de aprendizado treinando modelos baseados em BERT em conjuntos de dados existentes anotados para a presença de relações de causa e tratamento entre diferentes tipos de entidades biomédicas e usando-os para reconhecer as mesmas relações entre entidades de alimentos e doenças em um conjunto de dados criado para os propósitos deste estudo. Os melhores modelos alcançam pontuações F1 médias macro de 0,847 e 0,900 para as relações de causa e tratamento, respectivamente.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>El crecimiento acelerado del big data en el dominio biomédico, con una cantidad infinita de historiales médicos electrónicos y más de 30 millones de citas y resúmenes en PubMed, introduce la necesidad de estructurar automáticamente los datos biomédicos textuales. En este artículo, desarrollamos un método para detectar las relaciones entre las entidades alimentarias y las enfermedades a partir del texto sin procesar. Debido a la falta de datos anotados sobre los alimentos con respecto a la salud, exploramos la viabilidad de transferir el aprendizaje mediante la capacitación de modelos basados en BERT en conjuntos de datos existentes anotados para la presencia de relaciones de causa y tratamiento entre diferentes tipos de entidades biomédicas, y usándolos para reconocer las mismas relaciones entre las entidades alimentarias y las enfermedades en un conjunto de datos creado para los fines de este estudio. Los mejores modelos alcanzan puntuaciones F1 macropromediadas de 0,847 y 0,900 para las relaciones de causa y tratamiento, respectivamente.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>バイオメディカル分野でのビッグデータの急速な成長は、無限の量の電子健康記録と、PubMedでの3,000万を超える引用と要約によって、テキストバイオメディカルデータの自動構造化の必要性をもたらします。本稿では、生テキストから食品と疾患主体との関係を検出する方法を開発する。健康に関する食品に関する注釈付きデータが不足しているため、私たちは、原因の存在と異なるタイプの生物医学的エンティティ間の関係を処理するために注釈付けされた既存のデータセットにBERTベースのモデルをトレーニングし、それらを使用して、この研究の目的のために作成されたデータセットで食品と疾患エンティティとの間の同じ関係を認識することによって、転送学習の実現可能性を探ります。ベストモデルは、原因と治療の関係について、それぞれ0.847と0.900のマクロ平均F 1スコアを達成します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>生物医学领大数者速长,及PubMed无穷者电子健康记录过3000万次引摘要,引入文本生物医学数自结构化之需。 在本文中,我们开发了一种原始文本中检测食物和病实体的法术。 以乏食与康强之数,求迁徙之可行性,法在今数集上练基于BERT,此数集为异类生物医学实体之间,存而用之,以别为本而创数与病实同也。 至治各得0.8470.900宏观均F1分数。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>बायोमेडिकल डोमेन में बड़े डेटा की तेजी से वृद्धि, इलेक्ट्रॉनिक स्वास्थ्य रिकॉर्ड की एक अंतहीन मात्रा और PubMed में 30 मिलियन से अधिक उद्धरणों और सार तत्वों के साथ, पाठ्य बायोमेडिकल डेटा की स्वचालित संरचना की आवश्यकता का परिचय देती है। इस पेपर में, हम कच्चे पाठ से भोजन और रोग संस्थाओं के बीच संबंधों का पता लगाने के लिए एक विधि विकसित करते हैं। स्वास्थ्य के संबंध में भोजन पर एनोटेटेड डेटा की कमी के कारण, हम विभिन्न प्रकार के बायोमेडिकल संस्थाओं के बीच कारणों और उपचार संबंधों की उपस्थिति के लिए एनोटेट किए गए मौजूदा डेटासेट पर BERT-आधारित मॉडल को प्रशिक्षित करके हस्तांतरण सीखने की व्यवहार्यता का पता लगाते हैं, और इस अध्ययन के उद्देश्यों के लिए बनाए गए डेटासेट में भोजन और रोग संस्थाओं के बीच समान संबंधों को पहचानने के लिए उनका उपयोग करते हैं। सबसे अच्छा मॉडल क्रमशः कारण और इलाज संबंधों के लिए 0.847 और 0.900 के मैक्रो औसत F1 स्कोर प्राप्त करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Mar gheall ar fhás tapa na sonraí móra sa réimse bithleighis, le méid gan teorainn de thaifid sláinte leictreonacha agus níos mó ná 30 milliún lua agus achoimrí i PubMed, tugtar isteach an gá atá le struchtúr uathoibríoch ar shonraí téacsúla bithleighis. Sa pháipéar seo, forbraímid modh chun an caidreamh idir eintitis bia agus galair a bhrath ó théacs amh. Mar gheall ar an easpa sonraí anótáilte ar bhia maidir le sláinte, déanaimid iniúchadh ar fhéidearthacht na foghlama aistrithe trí mhúnlaí bunaithe ar BERT a thraenáil ar thacair sonraí atá ann cheana atá anótáilte le haghaidh láithreacht caidreamh cúise agus cóireála i measc cineálacha éagsúla eintiteas bithleighis, agus iad a úsáid chun an caidreamh céanna idir eintitis bia agus galair a aithint i dtacar sonraí a cruthaíodh chun críocha an staidéir seo. Baineann na samhlacha is fearr amach scóir meán F1 macra de 0.847 agus 0.900 don chaidreamh cúise agus cóireála, faoi seach.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η επιταχυνόμενη ανάπτυξη των μεγάλων δεδομένων στον τομέα της βιοϊατρικής, με ένα ατελείωτο αριθμό ηλεκτρονικών ιατρικών αρχείων και πάνω από 30 εκατομμύρια παραπομπές και περιλήψεις στο PubMed, εισάγει την ανάγκη για αυτόματη διάρθρωση κειμένων βιοϊατρικών δεδομένων. Στην παρούσα εργασία, αναπτύσσουμε μια μέθοδο για την ανίχνευση σχέσεων μεταξύ τροφίμων και ασθενειών από ακατέργαστο κείμενο. Λόγω της έλλειψης σχολιασμένων δεδομένων για τα τρόφιμα σε σχέση με την υγεία, διερευνούμε τη σκοπιμότητα της μάθησης μεταφοράς εκπαιδεύοντας μοντέλα βασισμένα σε υπάρχοντα σύνολα δεδομένων σχολιασμένα για την παρουσία αιτίας και τις σχέσεις αντιμετώπισης μεταξύ διαφορετικών τύπων βιοϊατρικών οντοτήτων, και τη χρήση τους για την αναγνώριση των ίδιων σχέσεων μεταξύ των οντοτήτων τροφίμων και ασθενειών σε ένα σύνολο δεδομένων που δημιουργήθηκε για τους σκοπούς της παρούσας μελέτης. Τα καλύτερα μοντέλα επιτυγχάνουν μακρομεσαίες βαθμολογίες των 0.847 και 0.900 για τις σχέσεις αιτίας και θεραπείας αντίστοιχα.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ბიომედიციო დემონიში დიდი მონაცემების გაზრდილობა, ელექტონო ჯანმრთო მონაცემების ბეჭდვილი ზომა და უფრო 30 მილიონის სიტრაქტირები და აბსტრაქტირები PubMed-ში, აჩვენებს ტექსტულ ბი ამ წიგნიში ჩვენ განვითარებთ წიგნის და დაავადებული ელემენტების განსაზღვრების მეტი. ჩვენ განსხვავებთ განსხვავებული ბერტის მოდელების განსხვავებაში მონაცემების შესახებ და განსხვავებაზე განსხვავებული ბიომედიციო ინტერნეციების შესახებ განსხვავებაში მონაცემების შესაძლებლობა, რომელიც არსებობს მონაცე და ისინი გამოყენება იგივე პრობლემების შესახებ, რომლებიც ამ სწავლების მიზეზებისთვის შექმნილი მონაცემები და დაავადებული ელემენტების განმავლობაში. ნაი-ეჲბპთრვ მჲევლთ ეჲჟრигნარ მაკპჲ ჟპვენთრვ F1 ნაოყლნთ 0,847 და 0,900 ნაოყლნთ ნაოყლნთ ჱა ოპთფთნარა თ ეჲდჲგჲპთ გპყჱკთ.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A Big Data gyorsuló növekedése az orvosbiológiai területen, végtelen mennyiségű elektronikus egészségügyi nyilvántartással és több mint 30 millió idézettel és absztrakttal a PubMed-ben, felvetette a szöveges orvosbiológiai adatok automatikus strukturálásának szükségességét. Ebben a tanulmányban kidolgozunk egy módszert az élelmiszer- és betegségentitások közötti kapcsolatok kimutatására nyers szövegből. Az élelmiszerekre vonatkozó, egészségügyi adatok hiánya miatt a különböző típusú orvosbiológiai szervezetek közötti ok- és kezelési kapcsolatok jelenlétére vonatkozó BERT-alapú modellek képzésével vizsgáljuk meg az átviteli tanulás megvalósíthatóságát. A tanulmány céljából létrehozott adatkészletben az élelmiszerek és betegségek közötti azonos kapcsolatok felismerésére és felhasználására. A legjobb modellek makróátlagos F1 pontszámot érnek el 0,847, illetve 0,900 az ok- és kezelési kapcsolatok tekintetében.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>L'accelerazione della crescita dei big data nel settore biomedico, con una quantità infinita di cartelle cliniche elettroniche e più di 30 milioni di citazioni e abstract in PubMed, introduce la necessità di strutturare automaticamente i dati biomedici testuali. In questo articolo, sviluppiamo un metodo per rilevare le relazioni tra entità alimentari e malattie dal testo grezzo. A causa della mancanza di dati annotati sugli alimenti rispetto alla salute, esploriamo la fattibilità del trasferimento di apprendimento attraverso la formazione di modelli basati su BERT su set di dati esistenti annotati per la presenza di relazioni di causa e trattamento tra diversi tipi di entità biomediche, e utilizzarle per riconoscere le stesse relazioni tra entità alimentari e malattie in un set di dati creato per gli scopi di questo studio. I migliori modelli raggiungono punteggi F1 medi macro di 0,847 e 0,900 rispettivamente per le relazioni causa e trattamento.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Биологиялық медицина доменінде үлкен деректердің өсімінің көтерілуі, электрондық саулық жазулар мен PubMed-де 30 миллион көтерілік және абстрактердің көтерілігін автоматты түрде биомедикалық деректерді құру қажетті болады Бұл қағазда, біз тамақ мен аурулардың арасындағы қатынасын табу әдісін жасадық. Біз саулық қатынасы туралы тәжірибелі мәліметтер жоқ себебі, BERT негіздеген деректер жиындарының өзгертілген бағдарламалардың әртүрлі биомедикалық құрылғылар арасындағы қатынастарын қабылдау мүмкіндігін зерттейміз, Бұл зерттеу үшін құрылған деректер қорларының бір қатынасын анықтау үшін оларды қолдануға болады. Ең жақсы үлгілер макросының орташа 0,847 және 0,900 жылдамдығын жеткізеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Dėl spartesnio didelių biomedicinos duomenų augimo, kuriame yra nekilnojamas elektroninių sveikatos įrašų kiekis ir daugiau kaip 30 mln. PubMed citacijų ir abstraktų, būtina automatiškai struktūruoti tekstinius biomedicinos duomenis. Šiame dokumente parengiame metodą maisto ir ligų subjektų santykiams nustatyti iš žaliavinio teksto. Kadangi nėra užrašytų maisto produktų duomenų apie sveikatą, tiriame galimybę perduoti mokymąsi rengiant BERT pagrįstus modelius apie esamus duomenų rinkinius, užrašytus dėl priežasties ir skirtingų rūšių biomedicinių subjektų santykių, - ir jų naudojimas siekiant pripažinti tuos pačius maisto ir ligų subjektų santykius šiam tyrimui sukurtame duomenų rinkinyje. Geriausiais modeliais gaunami atitinkamai 0,847 ir 0,900 makroekonominiai F1 balai dėl priežasties ir gydymo santykių.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Pemecut pertumbuhan data besar dalam domain biomedis, dengan jumlah tak terhingga rekod kesehatan elektronik dan lebih dari 30 juta citasi dan abstrak dalam PubMed, memperkenalkan keperluan untuk strukturasi automatik data biomedis teks. Dalam kertas ini, kami mengembangkan kaedah untuk mengesan hubungan antara makhluk makanan dan penyakit dari teks mentah. Kerana kekurangan data yang dicatat tentang makanan berkaitan dengan kesehatan, kami mengeksplorasi kemungkinan pemindahan belajar dengan melatih model berdasarkan BERT pada set data yang ada yang dicatat untuk kehadiran penyebab dan rawatan hubungan antara jenis-jenis entiti biomedis yang berbeza, - dan menggunakannya untuk mengenali hubungan yang sama antara entiti makanan dan penyakit dalam set data yang dicipta untuk tujuan kajian ini. Model terbaik mencapai nilai F1 makro rata-rata 0.847 dan 0.900 untuk penyebab dan rawatan hubungan, berdasarkan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Растот на големите податоци во биомедицинскиот домен, со бескрајна количина електронски здравствени записи и повеќе од 30 милиони цитати и апстракти во PubMed, ја воведува потребата за автоматска структурација на текстуалните биомедицински податоци. Во овој весник, развиваме метод за откривање на односите помеѓу ентитетите за храна и болести од суров текст. Поради недостатокот на анотирани податоци за храната во однос на здравјето, ја истражуваме физибилитетот на трансфер на учење со обука на модели базирани на БЕРТ на постојните податоци анотирани за присуството на причина и третирање на односите меѓу различните видови биомедицинс И користејќи ги за да ги препознаат истите односи меѓу ентитетите за храна и болести во податоци создадени за целите на оваа студија. Најдобрите модели достигнуваат макро просечни оценки на F1 од 0,847 и 0,900 за причината, односно за третманот на односите.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>ബൈവിമെഡിക്കല്‍ ഡോമെയിനിലെ വലിയ വിവരങ്ങളുടെ വേഗതയുള്ള വൃദ്ധത്തില്‍, എക്ട്രോണിക് ആരോഗ്യ രേഖകളും പുബ്മെഡിലെ 30 മില്യണ്‍ കോട്ടറുകളും ഉപേക്ഷിക്കുന്നവരുമാ ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍, ഭക്ഷണവും രോഗവസ്തുക്കള്‍ക്കും തമ്മിലുള്ള ബന്ധങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടുപിടിക്കാന്‍ ഒരു രീതിയാണ് ഞങ്ങള്‍ നിര്‍മ് ഭക്ഷണത്തിന്റെ ആഹാരം കുറിച്ചുള്ള വിശദീകരിക്കുന്ന വിവരങ്ങള്‍ കാരണം ബെര്‍ട്ടി അടിസ്ഥാനമായി പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിന്റെ സാധ്യതയാണ് നമ്മള്‍ പരിശോധിക്കുന്നത്. ന ഈ പഠനത്തിന്റെ ഉദ്ദേശങ്ങള്‍ക്കായി സൃഷ്ടിക്കുന്ന ഒരു ഡാറ്റാസറ്റില്‍ ഭക്ഷണവും രോഗവസ്തുക്കള്‍ക്കും തമ്മിലുള്ള ഏറ്റവും നല്ല മോഡലുകള്‍ നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കുന്നതിന്റെ കാരണത്തിനും ബന്ധങ്ങള്‍ ചികിത്സിക്കുന്നതിനുമായി എഫ്1 സ്കോര്‍ എടുക്കു</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Биологийн эрүүл мэндийн хэмжээнд том өгөгдлийн өсөлт хурдан, цахилгаан эрүүл мэндийн бичил баримтын хэмжээтэй, Пубмед-д 30 сая гаруй зохиолууд болон абстрактикүүд нь textual biomedical өгөгдлийн автоматик бүтээх шаардлагатай байдаг. Энэ цаасан дээр бид хоол болон өвчин зүйлсийн хоорондын харилцааны холбоотой арга зохион байгуулдаг. Эрүүл мэндийн тухай хоолны талаар сэтгэл хөдлөл өгөгдлийн байдал байхгүй учраас бид BERT-ийн сургалтын загвар дээр суралцах боломжтой байдлыг судлах боломжтой болсон. Биологийн эрүүл мэндийн байгууллагуудын урьдчилан сэтгэл хөдлөл Энэ судалгааны зорилгоор бүтээсэн өгөгдлийн сангийн хоорондох хоорондох холбоотой адилхан харилцаа ойлгохын тулд ашиглаж байна. Хамгийн шилдэг загварууд нь F1 дундаж 0,847 болон 0,900 тоонуудыг шалтгаан болон эмчилгээний холбоотой.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Przyspieszający się wzrost big data w dziedzinie biomedycznej, z nieskończoną ilością elektronicznych dokumentów zdrowia oraz ponad 30-milionów cytatów i streszczeń w PubMed, wprowadza potrzebę automatycznej strukturyzacji tekstowych danych biomedycznych. W artykule opracowano metodę wykrywania relacji między jednostkami żywnościowymi a chorobami z tekstu surowego. Ze względu na brak adnotacji danych dotyczących żywności w zakresie zdrowia, badamy możliwość transferowego uczenia się poprzez szkolenie modeli opartych na BERT na istniejących zbiorach danych adnotacjonowanych pod kątem obecności przyczyn i leczenia relacji między różnymi typami podmiotów biomedycznych, i wykorzystanie ich do rozpoznawania tych samych relacji między jednostkami żywnościowymi a chorobami w zbiorze danych stworzonym na potrzeby niniejszego opracowania. Najlepsze modele osiągają makro uśrednione wyniki F1 0.847 i 0.900 odpowiednio dla relacji przyczynowych i leczniczych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Den akselererende veksten av store data i biomedisinske domenet, med ein uendelig mengd av elektroniske helseprogram og fleire enn 30 millioner sitasjonar og abstrakt i PubMed, introduserer nødvendighet for automatisk strukturering av tekstuale biomedisinske data. I denne papiret utviklar vi ein metode for å finna forhold mellom mat og sykdommer frå råtekst. På grunn av manglene av annoterarte data om mat i respekt til helse, utforskar vi feiligheten for å lære overføringar ved å lære BERT-baserte modeller på eksisterande datasett merke på tilstand til grunn og behandling av forhold mellom ulike typar biomedisinske entiteter, og bruk dei for å gjenkjenne samme forholdet mellom mat og sykdommer i eit dataset som er laga for dette studiet. Den beste modellen gjennomsnittlige F1- poeng med 0,847 og 0,900 for grunnen og behandlingar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Povećavajući rast velikih podataka u biomedicinskom domenu, sa beskrajnom količinom elektronskih zdravstvenih podataka i više od 30 miliona citacija i abstraktata u PubMedu, predstavlja potrebu za automatskom strukturom tekstualnih biomedicinskih podataka. U ovom papiru razvijamo metodu za otkrivanje odnosa između hrane i bolesti iz sirovog teksta. Zbog nedostatka annotiranih podataka o hrani u odnosu na zdravlje, istražujemo mogućnost učenja premeštaja modelima koji su osnovani na BERT-u na postojećim podacima koje su navodne za prisustvo uzroka i liječenje odnosa među različitim vrstama biomedicinskih entiteta, i koristeći ih kako bi prepoznali iste odnose između hrane i bolesnih subjekta u kompetu podataka stvorenom za ciljeve ove studije. Najbolji modeli postižu srednji nivo F1 od 0,847 i 0,900 za uzrok i tretman odnosa.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_mt>It-tkabbir aċċellerat ta’ dejta kbira fid-dominju bijomediku, b’ammont bla tmiem ta’ rekords elettroniċi tas-saħħa u aktar minn 30 miljun ċitazzjoni u astratt f’PubMed, jintroduċi l-ħtieġa għal strutturazzjoni awtomatika ta’ dejta bijomedika testwali. F’dan id-dokument, a ħna niżviluppaw metodu biex niskopru r-relazzjonijiet bejn l-entitajiet tal-ikel u l-mard mit-test mhux ipproċessat. Minħabba n-nuqqas ta’ dejta annotata dwar l-ikel fir-rigward tas-saħħa, nesploraw il-fattibbiltà tat-tagħlim tat-trasferiment permezz tat-taħriġ ta’ mudelli bbażati fuq BERT dwar settijiet ta’ dejta eżistenti annotati għall-preżenza ta’ kawża u jittrattaw relazzjonijiet fost tipi differenti ta’ entitajiet bijomediċi, ) u l-użu tagħhom biex jirrikonoxxu l-istess relazzjonijiet bejn entitajiet tal-ikel u l-mard f’sett ta’ dejta maħluq għall-finijiet ta’ dan l-istudju. L-aħjar mudelli jiksbu punteġġi F1 makro medji ta’ 0.847 u 0.900 għall-kawża u r-relazzjonijiet ta’ kura, rispettivament.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_sv>Den accelererande tillväxten av big data inom biomedicinsk domän, med en oändlig mängd elektroniska journaler och mer än 30 miljoner citeringar och abstracts i PubMed, introducerar behovet av automatisk strukturering av textdata. I denna uppsats utvecklar vi en metod för att upptäcka relationer mellan livsmedel och sjukdomsentiteter från råtext. På grund av bristen på kommenterade data om livsmedel med avseende på hälsa undersöker vi möjligheten att överföra lärande genom att utbilda BERT-baserade modeller på befintliga datauppsättningar kommenterade för förekomsten av orsaks- och behandlingsrelationer mellan olika typer av biomedicinska enheter. och använda dem för att identifiera samma relationer mellan livsmedel och sjukdomsenheter i en datauppsättning som skapats för denna studie. De bästa modellerna uppnår makrogränsade F1-poäng på 0,847 respektive 0,900 för orsaks- och behandlingsrelationerna.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>The speed of great data in the biodoctor domain, with an end number of electron Health Records and more than 30 billion citation and extratracts in PubMed, presents the needed for automate Strructing of texture biodoctor data. මේ පැත්තට, අපි කෑම සහ රෝගිකත්වය අතර සම්බන්ධයක් හොයාගන්න විධානයක් හොයාගන්න. නිසා ස්වාස්ථාවක් ගැන බලාපොරොත්තු දත්ත නැති නිසා අපි පරික්ෂා කරනවා BERT-අධාරිත දත්ත සැකසුම් සඳහා වෙනස් වර්ගයේ ජීවිත වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාවක්  ඒ වගේම ඔවුන්ව භාවිතා කරනවා කෑම සහ රෝගිකය සම්බන්ධතාවක් අතර සම්බන්ධතාවක් අඳුරගන්න. හොඳම මොඩල් එක්ක මැක්රෝ විශේෂයෙන් සාමාන්‍ය F1 ස්කෝර් 0,847 හා 0,900 විශේෂයෙන් සාමාන්‍ය සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන් ස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>புப்மெட்டில் உள்ள பெரிய தரவுகளின் வளர்ச்சியை விரைவாக்குகிறது, முடிவில்லாத அளவு மின்னஞ்சல் செயல் பதிவுகள் மற்றும் 30 மில்லியன் கூறுகள் மற்றும் ஒதுக்குறி இந்த காகிதத்தில், நாம் குறைந்த உரையில் இருந்து உணவு மற்றும் நோய் பொருள்களுக்கிடையே தொடர்புகளை கண்டறிய ஒர பிரெட்டி அடிப்படையான மாதிரிகளை பயிற்சி செய்து கொண்டு பிரெட்டி மாதிரிகளை பயிற்சி செய்து தற்போதைய தகவல் அமைப்புகளில் குறிப்பிட்ட தகவல் காரணத்தால், வேறு  இந்த ஆராய்ச்சியின் காரணமாக உருவாக்கப்பட்ட தகவல் அமைப்பில் உணவு மற்றும் நோய் பொருள்களுக்கிடையே ஒரே தொடர்பை அறிந் சிறந்த மாதிரிகள் சராசரியான F1 மதிப்புகள் 0. 847 மற்றும் 0. 900 காரணம் மற்றும் தொடர்புகளை சராசரியாக பெறுகிறது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ro>Creșterea accelerată a datelor mari în domeniul biomedical, cu o cantitate nesfârșită de dosare electronice de sănătate și peste 30 de milioane de citate și rezumate în PubMed, introduce necesitatea structurării automate a datelor biomedicale textuale. În această lucrare, dezvoltăm o metodă de detectare a relațiilor dintre entitățile alimentare și boli din text brut. Din cauza lipsei de date adnotate cu privire la alimente în ceea ce privește sănătatea, explorăm fezabilitatea transferului de învățare prin instruirea modelelor bazate pe BERT pe seturi de date existente adnotate pentru prezența relațiilor de cauză și tratament între diferite tipuri de entități biomedicale, şi folosindu-le pentru a recunoaşte aceleaşi relaţii dintre entităţile alimentare şi boli într-un set de date creat în scopul acestui studiu. Cele mai bune modele obțin scoruri F1 medii macro de 0,847 și 0,900 pentru relațiile cauză și tratament, respectiv.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>The accelerating growth of big data in the biomedical domain, with an endless amount of electronic health records and more than 30 million citations and abstracts in PubMed, introduces the need for automatic structuring of textual biomedical data.  Qoraalkan waxaynu ku qornaa qaab aan ku ogaano xiriirka u dhexeeya cuntada iyo cudurada, taas oo laga soo qoro qoraal xunxun. Sababtooda darteed baahida macluumaadka ku saabsan cuntada la xiriira caafimaadka, waxaynu baaraynaa suurtagalka barashada waxbarashada ee lagu baranayo tusaalayaal BERT-based oo ku qoran samooyin macluumaadka heysta oo la dhibaataysay joogitaanka sababta ah iyo xiriirka u dhexeeya noocyada dhakhaatiirta ah oo kala duduwan, iyo isticmaalkooda si ay u aqoonsadaan isku xiriir u dhexeeya cuntada iyo cudurada, taas oo lagu sameeyo kooxda macluumaadka ee loo sameeyo waxbarashadan darteed. Tusaalada ugu wanaagsan waxay u baahan karaan macro qiyaastii ugu dhexeeya 0.847 iyo 0.900 sababta iyo daryeelka xiriirka.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ur>بیولوڈیسی ڈومین میں بڑے ڈاٹے کی تغییر پھیلانے کی توزیع ہے، ایک بے پایان الکترونیکی سلامتی ریکوارڈ کے ساتھ اور 30 میلیون سے زیادہ سیٹراکت اور اگستراکت پٹ میڈ میں، تفصیل بیولوڈیسی ڈاٹوں کی آٹوٹ ساختار اس کاغذ میں ہم ایک طریقہ ایجاد کریں گے کہ کھانا اور بیماری کے درمیان رشتہ پیدا کریں۔ غذا کے معاملہ میں غذا کے ذریعہ مطلع ہونے والی اطلاعات کے باعث، ہم نے BERT کے معاملہ میں موجودہ ڈاٹ سٹ کی آموزش کے ذریعہ تدریس کرنے کے قابل تحقیق کرنے کے ذریعہ تحقیق کیا ہے اور مختلف طریقوں کے بیولوڈیسی انٹیسیٹوں کے معاملہ میں اور ان کا استعمال کرتا ہے کہ کھانا اور بیماری اختیاروں کے درمیان ایک دوسری رابطہ پہچان سکیں اس تحقیق کے لئے بنایا گیا ہے. سب سے بہترین نمونڈل مکرو کے متوسط فی 1 سکوٹ کو 0.847 اور 0.900 دلیل کے لئے پہنچ سکتے ہیں اور دراصل رابطہ کے معاملہ کے معاملہ کے معاملہ میں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Bu qogʻozda, biz qanchalik matn va kasallik obʼektlarining orasidagi munosabatlarni aniqlash usulini yaratishimiz mumkin. Foydalanish haqida taʼminlovchi maʼlumot yoʻq sababi, biz saqlangan mavjud maʼlumot bazasini o'rganish imkoniyatlarini o'rganish mumkin, biz bu bajarish modellari uchun mavjud maʼlumotlar tizimini o'rganish mumkin, sabablar mavjud bo'lgan va bir xil tibbiy tibbiy tibbiy tibbiy va ulardan foydalanishni shu taʼminot uchun yaratilgan xavfli va kasallik tizimlar orasidagi bir xil munosabatlarni aniqlash mumkin. Yaxshi modellar faqat bilan bogʻlash va boshqarish uchun o'xshash 0.847 va 0.900 foydalanish uchun Makro o'rtacha foydalanadi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Sự phát triển nhanh chóng của dữ liệu lớn trong lĩnh vực sinh học, với một lượng không ngừng các ghi chép sức khỏe điện tử và hơn 30triệu ghi chú và trừu tượng trong Phổ Sinh, đòi hỏi cấu trúc tự động các dữ liệu sinh học. Trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi phát triển một phương pháp để tìm ra mối quan hệ giữa các thực thể ăn thịt và bệnh tật từ văn bản thô. Do thiếu dữ liệu ghi chú về thực phẩm về sức khỏe, chúng tôi khám phá khả năng học chuyển nhượng nhờ huấn luyện các mô hình dựa trên các bộ dữ liệu tồn tại được ghi chú cho sự hiện diện của nguyên nhân và đối xử quan hệ giữa các loại sinh học khác nhau, và sử dụng chúng để nhận ra mối quan hệ tương tự giữa thực thể thức ăn và bệnh tật trong một bộ dữ liệu được tạo ra cho mục đích của nghiên cứu này. Những mẫu tốt nhất đạt được điểm số F1 số lượng 0.897 và 0.910 về nguyên nhân và đối xử quan hệ.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Ускоряващият растеж на големите данни в биомедицинската област, с безкрайно количество електронни здравни досиета и над 30 милиона цитати и резюмета в ПубМед, въвежда необходимостта от автоматично структуриране на текстови биомедицински данни. В настоящата статия разработваме метод за откриване на взаимоотношения между хранителните и болестните субекти от суров текст. Поради липсата на анотирани данни за храните по отношение на здравето, изследваме осъществимостта на трансферното обучение чрез обучение на базирани на БРТ модели на съществуващи набори от данни, анотирани за наличието на причинни и третирани отношения между различните видове биомедицински субекти, и използването им за разпознаване на същите взаимоотношения между хранителните и болестните субекти в набор от данни, създаден за целите на настоящото изследване. Най-добрите модели постигат макро средни резултати от 0,847 и 0,900 съответно за причината и лечението.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Den accelererende vækst af big data på det biomedicinske område, med en endeløs mængde elektroniske sundhedsoplysninger og mere end 30 millioner citater og abstracts i PubMed, introducerer behovet for automatisk strukturering af tekstdata biomedicinske data. I denne artikel udvikler vi en metode til detektering af relationer mellem fødevarer og sygdomsenheder fra rå tekst. På grund af manglen på annoterede data om fødevarer med hensyn til sundhed undersøger vi muligheden for at overføre læring ved at træne BERT-baserede modeller på eksisterende datasæt annoteret for tilstedeværelsen af årsag og behandling relationer mellem forskellige typer biomedicinske enheder. og bruge dem til at genkende de samme relationer mellem fødevarer og sygdomsenheder i et datasæt skabt til formålet med denne undersøgelse. De bedste modeller opnår makro-gennemsnitlige F1 scores på henholdsvis 0,847 og 0,900 for årsags- og behandlingsforholdene.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>De toenemende groei van big data in het biomedisch domein, met een eindeloze hoeveelheid elektronische medische dossiers en meer dan 30 miljoen citaten en abstracts in PubMed, introduceert de behoefte aan automatische structurering van tekstuele biomedische gegevens. In dit artikel ontwikkelen we een methode voor het detecteren van relaties tussen voedsel en ziekte entiteiten uit ruwe tekst. Vanwege het ontbreken van geannoteerde gegevens over voedsel met betrekking tot gezondheid, onderzoeken we de haalbaarheid van transfer learning door BERT-gebaseerde modellen te trainen op bestaande datasets geannoteerd op de aanwezigheid van oorzaak en behandeling relaties tussen verschillende soorten biomedische entiteiten, en deze te gebruiken om dezelfde relaties tussen voedsel en ziekte entiteiten te herkennen in een dataset die voor de doeleinden van dit onderzoek is gecreëerd. De beste modellen bereiken macro gemiddelde F1 scores van 0.847 en 0.900 voor respectievelijk oorzaak- en behandelrelaties.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Povećavajući rast velikih podataka u biomedicinskom domenu, s beskrajnom količinom elektronskih zdravstvenih zapisa i više od 30 milijuna citacija i apstraktata u PubMedu, predstavlja potrebu za automatskom strukturom tekstualnih biomedicinskih podataka. U ovom papiru razvijamo metodu za otkrivanje odnosa između hrane i bolesnika iz sirovog teksta. Zbog nedostatka annotiranih podataka o hrani u pogledu zdravlja, istražujemo mogućnost učenja prijenosa, obučavajući modele na osnovu BERT-a na postojećim podacima označenim za prisutnost uzroka i liječenje odnosa među različitim vrstama biomedicinskih subjekta, i koristiti ih kako bi prepoznali iste odnose između hrane i bolesnih subjekta u skupini podataka koji su stvoreni za svrhu ovog ispitivanja. Najbolji modeli postignu prosječne mjerene rezultate F1 od 0,847 i 0,900 za uzrok i liječenje odnosa.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Das beschleunigte Wachstum von Big Data im biomedizinischen Bereich, mit einer endlosen Menge an elektronischen Krankenakten und mehr als 30-Millionen Zitaten und Abstracts in PubMed, führt zur Notwendigkeit der automatischen Strukturierung von textuellen biomedizinischen Daten. In diesem Beitrag entwickeln wir eine Methode zur Erkennung von Zusammenhängen zwischen Lebensmitteln und Krankheiten aus Rohtexten. Aufgrund des Mangels an annotierten Daten über Lebensmittel in Bezug auf Gesundheit untersuchen wir die Machbarkeit von Transfer Learning durch Training von BERT-basierten Modellen auf bestehenden Datensätzen, die auf das Vorhandensein von Ursachen und Behandlungsbeziehungen zwischen verschiedenen Arten von biomedizinischen Einheiten annotiert wurden. Sie werden verwendet, um die gleichen Beziehungen zwischen Lebensmitteln und Krankheiten in einem Datensatz zu erkennen, der für die Zwecke dieser Studie erstellt wurde. Die besten Modelle erzielen makrodurchschnittliche F1-Werte von 0.847 und 0.900 für die Ursache- bzw. Behandlungsbeziehungen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>The accelerating growth of big data in the biomedical domain, with an endless amount of electronic health records and more than 30 million citations and abstracts in PubMed, introduces the need for automatic structuring of textual biomedical data.  Dalam kertas ini, kami mengembangkan metode untuk mendeteksi hubungan antara makhluk makanan dan penyakit dari teks mentah. Karena kekurangan data yang dicatat tentang makanan berkaitan dengan kesehatan, kami mengeksplorasi feasibilitas transfer belajar dengan melatih model berdasarkan BERT pada set data yang ada yang dicatat untuk kehadiran penyebab dan memperlakukan hubungan antara jenis yang berbeda dari entitas biomedis, Dan menggunakannya untuk mengenali hubungan yang sama antara makhluk makanan dan penyakit dalam set data yang diciptakan untuk tujuan penelitian ini. Model terbaik mencapai nilai F1 makro rata-rata 0,847 dan 0,900 untuk penyebab dan memperlakukan hubungan, sesuai.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>바이오메디컬 분야 빅데이터의 가속 성장과 수많은 전자 건강 기록과 펍메드에서 3천만 개가 넘는 인용문과 요약문을 통해 텍스트 바이오메디컬 데이터를 자동으로 구축하는 수요가 도입됐다.본고에서 우리는 원시 텍스트에서 음식과 질병의 실체 간의 관계를 측정하는 방법을 개발했다.건강과 관련된 식품 주석 데이터가 부족하기 때문에 우리는 BERT 모델을 바탕으로 이동 학습의 타당성을 탐색하는 훈련을 실시했다. 이 모델은 기존의 데이터 집합을 바탕으로 서로 다른 유형의 생물의학 실체 간의 인과 관계의 존재를 주석했다.본 연구의 목적을 위해 만들어진 데이터를 이용하여 음식과 질병 실체 간의 동일한 관계를 식별한다.가장 좋은 모델은 인과관계와 치료관계에서 F1의 거시적 평균 점수가 각각 0.847과 0.900이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>سرعت افزایش داده های بزرگ در حوزه بیوپزشکی، با تعداد بی نهایت از مدارک سلامتی الکترونیکی و بیش از ۳۰ میلیون شهرات و اخراج در PubMed، نیازی برای ساختن خودکار داده های بیوپزشکی متن را معرفی می کند. در این کاغذ، ما یک روش برای کشف رابطه بین غذا و بیماری از متن خالی توسعه می کنیم. به دلیل lack of annotated data on food with respect to health, we explore the feasibility of transfer learning by training BERT based models on existing datasets annotated for the presence of cause and treat relations among different types of biomedical entities, و از آنها استفاده می‌کند تا همان رابطه‌ای بین غذا و بیماری را در مجموعه داده‌ها برای هدف این مطالعه شناسایی کند. بهترین مدل‌های مکرو در میانگین نمونه‌های F1 از 0.847 و 0.900 برای هدف و درمان رابطه‌ها در میانگین رسیده است.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Kuongezeka kuongezeka kwa takwimu kubwa katika maeneo ya kitabibu, kwa kiasi kikubwa cha rekodi za afya ya umeme na zaidi ya matangazo milioni 30 na mabadiliko ya PubMed, inaonyesha haja ya kutengeneza taarifa za kitabibu za biotics. Katika karatasi hii, tunatengeneza njia ya kutambua mahusiano kati ya chakula na ugonjwa kutoka kwenye maandishi mabaya. Kutokana na ukosefu wa taarifa za chakula kuhusiana na afya, tunagundua uwezekano wa kuhamisha elimu kwa mafunzo ya miundo yenye msingi wa BERT kwenye seti za taarifa zinazopinga kutokuwepo kwa sababu na kutibu mahusiano kati ya aina mbalimbali za viwanda vya afya,  and using them to recognize the same relations between food and disease entities in a dataset created for the purposes of this study.  Mifano bora zaidi hupata kiwango cha wastani wa F1 cha 0.847 na 0.900 kwa sababu na kutibu mahusiano.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Biomedical domenynda uly maglumatlaryň ýetişimi ýokarylýar, elektronik saglyk kayıtlaryň iň bolmadygy kadary we PubMed-de 30 milliýden köp gabat we çykyşlaryň ewirilmesi gerekdigini aýdýar. Bu kagyzda, iýmit we keselläk taýýarlaryň arasyndaky baglaýyşyny çyz metinden tapmak üçin bir yöntem gelişýäris. Saglyk bilen ilgili iýmit barada nähili täsirli maglumatlary ýok bolmagynyň sebäbi, BERT-a tabanly modalary öwrenmäge mümkinçilik ukyplaryň barlygyny maslahat berýäris we munyň meňzeş biýolaryň birnäçe milletleriniň barlygyny duýýarys. We olary bu araştyrmanyň amaçlary üçin ýene-de nahar we hasta zatlaryň arasyndaky baglaýyşyny tanamak üçin ullanýarlar. En iyi modeller, macro ortalaması 0,847 ve 0,900 noktalar üçin ortalama noktalar elde edildi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>በbiomedical አካባቢ ውስጥ ታላላቅ ዳታዎችን ማድረግ የሚቻኮል፣ የኢሌክትሮኒካዊ ጤናዊ ካርሰቶች እና በፉብሜድ 30 ሚሊዮን ጥያቄዎች እና የጥብረት አካባቢዎች የጽሑፍ የbiomedical ዳታዎችን በመሠረት ያስፈልጋል፡፡ በዚህ ካላት፣ ምግብ እና የደዌብ አካላት መካከል ግንኙነትን ከጥሩ ጽሑፍ ለማግኘት ልማድ እናደርጋለን፡፡ ምግብን በጤና ላይ የሚያስጨንቀው ዳታ ስለጎደለበት ምክንያት፣ በተለያዩ ዓይነት የbiomedical አካላት መካከል ለመቀበል እና ግንኙነትን ለመቀበል የBERT ሥርዓት በሚደረገው ዳታተሮችን በማስተማርና እና በመቀበል በተለያዩ የደካማ አካል አካባቢዎችን በመቀበል እናስፈልጋለን፡፡ እና በተጠቃሚ የዚህ ትምህርት ምክንያት በተፈጠረ ዳታተር ውስጥ የመብል እና የደዌብ አካላት መካከል አንድ ግንኙነት እንዲያውቁ እየተጠቃቀሙ ነው፡፡ መልካሞቹ ምሳሌዎች በተለየው የF1 መለያ ጥያቄ የ0.847 እና 0.900 የውይይት ግንኙነትን ለመቀበል ያግኛሉ፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Rritja e përshpejtueshme e të dhënave të mëdha në fushën biomedikale, me një sasi të pafund të regjistrimeve shëndetësore elektronike dhe më shumë se 30 milion citate dhe abstrakte në PubMed, paraqet nevojën për strukturimin automatik të të dhënave tekstuale biomedikale. Në këtë letër, ne zhvillojmë një metodë për zbulimin e marrëdhënieve midis njësive ushqimore dhe sëmundjeve nga teksti i papërpunuar. Për shkak të mungesës së të dhënave të anotuara mbi ushqimin lidhur me shëndetin, ne eksplorojmë realizueshmërinë e transferimit të mësimit duke trajnuar modele të bazuara në BERT mbi të dhënat ekzistuese të anotuara për praninë e shkakut dhe trajtojmë marrëdhëniet midis llojeve të ndryshme të njësive biomedike, Dhe përdorimi i tyre për të njohur të njëjtat marrëdhënie midis njësive ushqimore dhe sëmundjeve në një grup të dhënash të krijuar për qëllimet e këtij studimi. The best models achieve macro averaged F1 scores of 0.847 and 0.900 for the cause and treat relations, respectively.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Բիոբժշկական ոլորտում մեծ տվյալների արագացող աճը, որն ունի անվերջ քանակությամբ էլեկտրոնային առողջապահության ձայնագրություններ և ավելի քան 30 միլիոն մեջբերումներ և վերացական գրառումներ, ներկայացնում է տեքստոմալ բիոբժշկական տվյալների ավտոմատիկ Այս թղթի մեջ մենք ստեղծում ենք մի մեթոդ սննդի և հիվանդության անհատների միջև հարաբերությունների հայտնաբերելու համար աղբ տեքստից: Քանի որ սննդի մասին առողջության առումով գրված տվյալների բացակայությունն է, մենք ուսումնասիրում ենք, թե արդյոք կարելի է փոխանցել ուսումնասիրությունը BER-ի հիմնված մոդելների ուսուցման միջոցով գոյություն ունեցող տվյալների համակարգերի վրա, որոնք գրված են պատճառի առկայության համար և Եվ օգտագործելով դրանք այս ուսումնասիրության նպատակով ստեղծված տվյալների համակարգում նույն հարաբերությունները ճանաչելու համար: Լավագույն մոդելները հասնում են մակարո միջին F1-ի գնահատականներին՝ 0.84 7 և 0.900 պատճառի համար, և բուժում են հարաբերությունները:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_af>Die versnellende groot data in die biomediese domein, met 'n oneindelike hoeveelheid elektroniese gesondrekord en meer as 30 miljoen sitasies en abstrakte in PubMed, introduseer die behoefte vir outomatiese strukturering van tekstuele biomediese data. In hierdie papier ontwikkel ons 'n metode om verhouding tussen voedsel en siekte entiteite te ontdek van rooi teks. Dus die ontbreek van aanmerkte data oor kos met betrekking tot gesondheid, ondersoek ons die feilikheid van oordrag onderwerp deur die onderwerp van BERT-gebaseerde modele op bestaande datastelle wat aanmerk word vir die voorsiening van oorsaak en behandeling onder verskillende tipes biomediese entiteite, en hulle gebruik om dieselfde verwantings tussen voedsel en siekte entiteite te herken in 'n datastel geskep vir die doels van hierdie studie. Die beste modele bereik makro gemiddelde F1 aantal van 0,847 en 0,900 vir die oorsaak en behandeling van relasies, respektief.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_bn>বায়োমেডিকেল ডোমেইনের বড় তথ্য বৃদ্ধি ব্যবস্থার ব্যবস্থা ব্যবস্থা ব্যবস্থা বেড়ে যায়, যার পরিমাণ ইলেক্ট্রোনিক স্বাস্থ্য রেকর্ড এবং পুবেমেদের ৩০ মিলিয়ন এই পত্রিকায় আমরা খাদ্য এবং রোগের বিষয়বস্তুর মধ্যে সম্পর্ক খুঁজে বের করার একটি পদ্ধতি তৈরি করি। স্বাস্থ্যের ব্যাপারে খাদ্যের অভাবের কারণে আমরা বিবেরেট ভিত্তিক মডেলের প্রশিক্ষণের মাধ্যমে বিভিন্ন ধরনের বায়োমেডিকেল বিষয়বস্তুর মধ্যে সম্পর্কের জন্য বিদ এবং তাদের ব্যবহার করে এই গবেষণার উদ্দেশ্যে খাদ্য এবং রোগের বিষয়বস্তুর মধ্যে একই সম্পর্ক স্বীকার করার জন্য। সবচেয়ে ভালো মডেল ম্যাক্রো ম্যাক্রোর সাধারণ এফ১ স্কোরের মাধ্যমে কারণ এবং সম্পর্কের সাথে আচরণের জন্য ০. ৮47 এবং ০. ৯০০।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>El creixement acceleratiu de grans dades en el domini biomèdic, amb una quantitat infinita de registres electrònics de salut i més de 30 milions de citacions i abstractes a PubMed, introdueix la necessitat d'estructurar automàticament les dades biomèdices textuals. En aquest article, desenvolupem un mètode per detectar les relacions entre els aliments i les entitats de malalties a partir del text brut. A causa de la falta de dades anotates sobre aliments en relació a la salut, estudiem la viabilitat d'aprenentatge de transfer ència formant models basats en BERT sobre conjunts de dades existents anotats per la presença de causa i tractar relacions entre diferents tipus d'entitats biomèdiques, i utilitzar-los per reconèixer les mateixes relacions entre els aliments i les entitats de malalties en un conjunt de dades creat pels propòsits d'aquest estudi. Els millors models aconsegueixen puntuacions F1 de 0,847 i 0,900 per la causa i tracten les relacions, respectivament.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_az>Böyük məlumatların yüksək məlumatlarını biomedical domeində tezliklə artırmağı, müəyyən bir miktar elektronik sağlamlıq kayıtları və PubMed'də 30 milyondan daha çox sitayiş və abstraktlar ilə, textual biomedical məlumatlarının avtomatik qurulması lazımını göstərir. Bu kağızda, yemək və xəstəlik məlumatının arasındakı bağlantıları keşfetmək üçün bir yol təhsil edirik. Sağlamlıq haqqındakı yemək haqqında məlumatlar yoxdur, BERT tabanlı modellərə təhsil edilən məlumatlar haqqında məlumatların olması və biomedicin məlumatları arasında müxtəlif məlumatların əlaqələrini təhsil edib təhsil etmək mümkünlüyünü keşfetmişik, Bu təhsil üçün yaratdığı verilənlər üçün yemək və xəstəlik məlumatları arasında eyni əlaqələri tanıtmaq üçün istifadə edirlər. Ən yaxşı modellər makro olaraq 0,847 və 0,900 f1 dərəcələrinin ortalamasını nəticə edir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Povećavajući rast velikih podataka u biomedicinskom domenu, sa beskrajnom količinom elektronskih zdravstvenih podataka i više od 30 miliona citacija i apstraktata u PubMedu, predstavlja potrebu za automatskom strukturom tekstualnih biomedicinskih podataka. U ovom papiru razvijamo metodu za otkrivanje odnosa između hrane i bolesnika iz sirovog teksta. Zbog nedostatka annotiranih podataka o hrani u pogledu zdravlja, istražujemo mogućnost učenja prijenosa, obučavajući modele na osnovu BERT-a na postojećim podacima koje su navodne za prisustvo uzroka i liječenje odnosa među različitim vrstama biomedicinskih entiteta, i koristeći ih kako bi prepoznali iste odnose između hrane i bolesnih subjekta u kompetu podataka stvorenom za ciljeve ove studije. Najbolji modeli postignu prosječne procjene F1 od 0,847 i 0,900 za uzrok i liječenje odnosa.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Zrychlující se růst velkých dat v biomedicínské oblasti, s nekonečným množstvím elektronických zdravotních záznamů a více než třicet milionů citací a abstraktů v PubMedu, přináší potřebu automatického strukturování textových biomedicínských dat. V tomto článku vyvíjíme metodu detekce vztahů mezi potravinovými a chorobnými entitami ze surového textu. Vzhledem k nedostatku anotovaných dat o potravinách s ohledem na zdraví zkoumáme možnost transferového učení školením modelů založených na BERT na existujících datových sadách anotovaných pro přítomnost příčin a léčbu vztahů mezi různými typy biomedicínských subjektů, a použití jejich k rozpoznání stejných vztahů mezi potravinovými a chorobnými entitami v datové sadě vytvořené pro účely této studie. Nejlepší modely dosahují makro průměrného F1 skóre 0,847 a 0,900 pro příčinu a léčbu vztahů.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Suureandmete kiirenev kasv biomeditsiinivaldkonnas, lõputu hulga elektrooniliste terviseandmete ning rohkem kui 30 miljoni tsitaati ja kokkuvõttega PubMedis, toob kaasa vajaduse automaatse struktureerimise tekstuaalsete biomeditsiiniandmete. Käesolevas töös töötame välja meetodi toidu- ja haigusüksuste suhete tuvastamiseks toortekstist. Kuna puuduvad märgitud andmed toidu kohta seoses tervisega, uurime siirdeõppe teostatavust, koolitades BERT-põhiseid mudeleid olemasolevatel andmekogumitel, mis on märgitud põhjuste ja ravi seoste olemasolu eri tüüpi biomeditsiiniliste üksuste vahel, ja kasutades neid samade suhete tuvastamiseks toidu- ja haigusüksuste vahel käesoleva uuringu eesmärgil loodud andmekogumis. Parimate mudelite puhul saavutatakse makrokeskmine F1 skoor vastavalt 0,847 ja 0,900 põhjus- ja ravisuhete puhul.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Biolääketieteen big datan kiihtyvä kasvu, loputon määrä sähköisiä terveystietoja ja yli 30 miljoonaa lainausta ja tiivistelmää PubMedissä, tuo mukanaan tarpeen automaattiselle biolääketieteellisen datan jäsentämiselle. Tässä työssä kehitämme menetelmän, jolla havaitaan ruoka- ja tautientiteettien väliset suhteet raakatekstistä. Koska elintarvikkeista terveyteen liittyviä merkintöjä ei ole, tutkimme siirtooppimisen toteutettavuutta kouluttamalla BERT-pohjaisia malleja olemassa oleviin tietoaineistoihin, joissa on merkintä syy- ja hoitosuhteiden olemassaolosta erityyppisten biolääketieteellisten yksiköiden välillä, Näiden avulla tunnistetaan samat suhteet elintarvike- ja tautientiteettien välillä tässä tutkimuksessa luodussa aineistossa. Parhaat mallit saavuttavat makrokeskiarvon F1-pisteet 0,847 ja 0,900 syy- ja hoitosuhteiden osalta.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Go Nang kuwi iki, awak dhéwé nggawe sistem kanggo kebutuhan resmi sakjane karo nganggo cara-cara sing dirampakan Text. Taning perbudhakan langkung dadi tanggal sing beraksi barêng-barêng, kéné iso nglanggar kuwi kapan kanggo ngilangno sistêm kuwi nggawe gerakan kanggo ngilangno sistem sing isiné BERT nganggep sistem dadi sing isiné dhéwé, sing berarti nggawe perusahaan kawit perusahaan karo perusahaan anyar sampeyan ingkang dibêngé deep Names</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>הגידול המאיץ של נתונים גדולים בתחום הביומדיקאי, עם כמות אינסופית של רשומות בריאות אלקטרוניות ויותר מ-30 מיליון ציטוטים ואסטרקטים בפאבמד, מציג את הצורך למבנה אוטומטית של נתונים ביומדיקים טקסטאליים. בעיתון הזה, אנחנו מפתחים שיטה לגלות יחסים בין יחידות מזון ומחלות מתוך טקסט גרוע. בגלל חוסר נתונים מועטפים על מזון בנוגע לבריאות, אנו חוקרים את האפשרות של ההעברה ללמוד על ידי אימון מודלים מבוססים BERT על קבוצות נתונים קיימות מועטפים בנוגע לנוכחות סיבה ולטיפול יחסים בין סוגים שונים של יחסים ביולוגיים, ולהשתמש בהם כדי להכיר את אותו מערכות יחסים בין יחידות מזון ומחלות במערכת נתונים שנוצרה למטרות המחקר הזה. הדוגמנים הטובים ביותר משיגים נקודות F1 בממוצע של 0.847 ו-0.900 למטרה ולהטפל במערכת יחסים, בהתאם.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Akwai mai gaggãwa da yawan data masu girma a cikin lokacin da aka dawwama, da cikakken rekodi na tarakiki na alboniki da kuma a ƙari 30 millions na citori da kuma abracts a Pubmed, yana ƙunsa da haji na ƙidãya farat-ɗabi'a na ƙidãya na zaluman biyayyaki na rubutu. Daga wannan takardan, Munã ƙãga wani hanyoyi wa gane danganta a tsakanin abinci da abubuwa daga matsayin raw. Due da bã da an yi cũtarwa ba da data a kan abinci masu hushi ga afya, munã ƙidãya the feasiƙanci of transfer learning by Trainin misãlai na BERT-based kan data masu cũtarwa ga halarce da kuma ka yi danganci a tsakãnin nau'i-nau'in-nau'i da wasu abubuwa, kuma suna amfani da su dõmin su gane mazaunin tsakãnin abinci da jiran su cikin wani dataset wanda aka halitta dõmin amfani da wannan littãfi. Babban motsalar da suka sami makaro mai tsakanin F1-nau'in 0.847 da 0.9100 wa saba da kuma a yi amfani da haɗi.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>The accelerating growth of big data in the biomedical domain, with an endless amount of electronic health records and more than 30 million citations and abstracts in PubMed, introduces the need for automatic structuring of textual biomedical data. འོག་གི་ཤོག་བུ་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོས་རྒྱ་ནག་དང་སྙན་རིས་དབར་གྱི་འབྲེལ་བ་དེ་རྟོགས་ཐབས་ཤིག་གསར་བསྐྲུན་ཡོ འཕྲོད་བསྟེན་དང་སྐྱོན་བརྗོད་པའི་ནང་དུ་བློ་གཏོང་བའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག་ཆ་ལ་ཉུང་བའི་ཉེན་ཁ་ཡོད་ལ་བསྟེན་ནས་ ང་ཚོས་BERT ལས་གནས་ཚུལ་གྱི་དཔེ་གཞུང་དང་མཉམ་དུ་ཡོད་པའི་མ ཁོང་ཚོས་ལག་ལེན་འཐབ་པ་དེ་དག་གི་བརྩལ་ཞིབ་དང་སྙན་འཛུལ་གྱི་མཐུན་སྣེ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་འབྲེལ་བ་གཅིག་རྟོགས་གནང་། མིག་སྔར་གཟུགས་རྗེས་མཐའ་དག་གིས་མི་རྣམས་དང་འབྲེལ་བ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ཚད་གཅིག་མཚུངས་ཡོད།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_sk>Pospešujoča rast velikih podatkov na biomedicinski področju z neskončno količino elektronskih zdravstvenih evidenc in več kot 30 milijoni citatov in povzetkov v PubMedu uvaja potrebo po avtomatičnem strukturiranju besedilnih biomedicinskih podatkov. V prispevku razvijamo metodo za odkrivanje odnosov med prehranskimi in boleznimi subjekti iz surovega besedila. Zaradi pomanjkanja označenih podatkov o hrani v zvezi z zdravjem raziskujemo izvedljivost prenosnega učenja z usposabljanjem modelov, ki temeljijo na BERT, na obstoječih naborih podatkov, označenih za prisotnost vzrokov in zdravljenja med različnimi vrstami biomedicinskih subjektov, in jih uporabljajo za prepoznavanje enakih odnosov med prehranskimi in boleznimi subjekti v naboru podatkov, ustvarjenih za namene te študije. Najboljši modeli dosegajo makropovprečno oceno F1 0,847 oziroma 0,900 za razmerje med vzrokom in zdravljenjem.</abstract_sk>
      </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Overview of the MEDIQA 2021 Shared Task on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Summarization">Summarization</a> in the Medical Domain<fixed-case>MEDIQA</fixed-case> 2021 Shared Task on Summarization in the Medical Domain</title>
      <author><first>Asma</first><last>Ben Abacha</last></author>
      <author><first>Yassine</first><last>Mrabet</last></author>
      <author><first>Yuhao</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Chaitanya</first><last>Shivade</last></author>
      <author><first>Curtis</first><last>Langlotz</last></author>
      <author><first>Dina</first><last>Demner-Fushman</last></author>
      <pages>74–85</pages>
      <abstract>The MEDIQA 2021 shared tasks at the BioNLP 2021 workshop addressed three tasks on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_summarization">summarization</a> for medical text : (i) a question summarization task aimed at exploring new approaches to understanding complex real-world consumer health queries, (ii) a multi-answer summarization task that targeted aggregation of multiple relevant answers to a biomedical question into one concise and relevant answer, and (iii) a radiology report summarization task addressing the development of clinically relevant impressions from radiology report findings. Thirty-five teams participated in these shared tasks with sixteen working notes submitted (fifteen accepted) describing a wide variety of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> developed and tested on the shared and external datasets. In this paper, we describe the tasks, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a>, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> and techniques developed by various teams, the results of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evaluation">evaluation</a>, and a study of correlations among various summarization evaluation measures. We hope that these shared tasks will bring new research and insights in biomedical text summarization and evaluation.</abstract>
      <url hash="6915890f">2021.bionlp-1.8</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.8</doi>
      <bibkey>ben-abacha-etal-2021-overview</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/mediqa-ans">MEDIQA-AnS</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/meqsum">MeQSum</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>WBI at MEDIQA 2021 : Summarizing Consumer Health Questions with Generative Transformers<fixed-case>WBI</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>MEDIQA</fixed-case> 2021: Summarizing Consumer Health Questions with Generative Transformers</title>
      <author><first>Mario</first><last>Sänger</last></author>
      <author><first>Leon</first><last>Weber</last></author>
      <author><first>Ulf</first><last>Leser</last></author>
      <pages>86–95</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our contribution for the MEDIQA-2021 Task 1 question summarization competition. We model the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(computing)">task</a> as conditional generation problem. Our concrete pipeline performs a finetuning of the large pretrained generative transformers PEGASUS (Zhang et al.,2020a) and BART (Lewis et al.,2020). We used the resulting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> as strong baselines and experimented with (i) integrating structured knowledge via entity embeddings, (ii) ensembling multiple generative models with the generator-discriminator framework and (iii) disentangling summarization and interrogative prediction to achieve further improvements. Our best performing model, a fine-tuned vanilla PEGASUS, reached the second place in the competition with an ROUGE-2-F1 score of 15.99. We observed that all of our additional measures hurt performance (up to 5.2 pp) on the official test set. In course of a post-hoc experimental analysis which uses a larger validation set results indicate slight performance improvements through the proposed extensions. However, further analysis is need to provide stronger evidence.</abstract>
      <url hash="b5ba736a">2021.bionlp-1.9</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.9</doi>
      <bibkey>sanger-etal-2021-wbi</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>BDKG at MEDIQA 2021 : System Report for the Radiology Report Summarization Task<fixed-case>BDKG</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>MEDIQA</fixed-case> 2021: System Report for the Radiology Report Summarization Task</title>
      <author><first>Songtai</first><last>Dai</last></author>
      <author><first>Quan</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Yajuan</first><last>Lyu</last></author>
      <author><first>Yong</first><last>Zhu</last></author>
      <pages>103–111</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents our winning system at the Radiology Report Summarization track of the MEDIQA 2021 shared task. Radiology report summarization automatically summarizes radiology findings into free-text impressions. This year’s task emphasizes the generalization and transfer ability of participating systems. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is built upon a pre-trained Transformer encoder-decoder architecture, i.e., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PEGASUS">PEGASUS</a>, deployed with an additional domain adaptation module to particularly handle the transfer and generalization issue. Heuristics like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ensemble_learning">ensemble</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_normalization">text normalization</a> are also used. Our system is conceptually simple yet highly effective, achieving a ROUGE-2 score of 0.436 on test set and ranked the 1st place among all participating systems.</abstract>
      <url hash="0ca5ce23">2021.bionlp-1.11</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.11</doi>
      <bibkey>dai-etal-2021-bdkg</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>damo_nlp at MEDIQA 2021 : Knowledge-based Preprocessing and Coverage-oriented Reranking for Medical Question Summarization<fixed-case>MEDIQA</fixed-case> 2021: Knowledge-based Preprocessing and Coverage-oriented Reranking for Medical Question Summarization</title>
      <author><first>Yifan</first><last>He</last></author>
      <author><first>Mosha</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <author><first>Songfang</first><last>Huang</last></author>
      <pages>112–118</pages>
      <abstract>Medical question summarization is an important but difficult task, where the input is often complex and erroneous while annotated data is expensive to acquire. We report our participation in the MEDIQA 2021 question summarization task in which we are required to address these challenges. We start from pre-trained conditional generative language models, use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_base">knowledge bases</a> to help correct input errors, and rerank single system outputs to boost coverage. Experimental results show significant improvement in string-based metrics.</abstract>
      <url hash="1040da26">2021.bionlp-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.12</doi>
      <bibkey>he-etal-2021-damo</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/meqsum">MeQSum</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Stress Test Evaluation of Biomedical Word Embeddings</title>
      <author><first>Vladimir</first><last>Araujo</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrés</first><last>Carvallo</last></author>
      <author><first>Carlos</first><last>Aspillaga</last></author>
      <author><first>Camilo</first><last>Thorne</last></author>
      <author><first>Denis</first><last>Parra</last></author>
      <pages>119–125</pages>
      <abstract>The success of pretrained word embeddings has motivated their use in the biomedical domain, with contextualized embeddings yielding remarkable results in several biomedical NLP tasks. However, there is a lack of research on quantifying their behavior under <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stress_(biology)">severe stress scenarios</a>. In this work, we systematically evaluate three language models with adversarial examples   automatically constructed tests that allow us to examine how robust the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> are. We propose two types of stress scenarios focused on the biomedical named entity recognition (NER) task, one inspired by spelling errors and another based on the use of synonyms for medical terms. Our experiments with three <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benchmark_(computing)">benchmarks</a> show that the performance of the original <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> decreases considerably, in addition to revealing their weaknesses and strengths. Finally, we show that adversarial training causes the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> to improve their robustness and even to exceed the original performance in some cases.</abstract>
      <url hash="34b6a8cc">2021.bionlp-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>araujo-etal-2021-stress</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ialab-puc/BioNLP-StressTest" additional="false">ialab-puc/BioNLP-StressTest</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bc5cdr">BC5CDR</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/blue">BLUE</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ncbi-disease-1">NCBI Disease</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>BioELECTRA : Pretrained Biomedical text Encoder using Discriminators<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>io<fixed-case>ELECTRA</fixed-case>:Pretrained Biomedical text Encoder using Discriminators</title>
      <author><first>Kamal raj</first><last>Kanakarajan</last></author>
      <author><first>Bhuvana</first><last>Kundumani</last></author>
      <author><first>Malaikannan</first><last>Sankarasubbu</last></author>
      <pages>143–154</pages>
      <abstract>Recent advancements in pretraining strategies in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> have shown a significant improvement in the performance of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> on various text mining tasks. We apply ‘replaced token detection’ pretraining technique proposed by ELECTRA and pretrain a biomedical language model from scratch using biomedical text and vocabulary. We introduce BioELECTRA, a biomedical domain-specific language encoder model that adapts ELECTRA for the Biomedical domain. WE evaluate our model on the BLURB and BLUE biomedical NLP benchmarks. BioELECTRA outperforms the previous models and achieves state of the art (SOTA) on all the 13 datasets in BLURB benchmark and on all the 4 Clinical datasets from BLUE Benchmark across 7 different NLP tasks. BioELECTRA pretrained on PubMed and PMC full text articles performs very well on Clinical datasets as well. BioELECTRA achieves new SOTA 86.34%(1.39 % accuracy improvement) on MedNLI and 64 % (2.98 % accuracy improvement) on PubMedQA dataset.</abstract>
      <url hash="eeff0c07">2021.bionlp-1.16</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.16</doi>
      <bibkey>kanakarajan-etal-2021-bioelectra</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bc5cdr">BC5CDR</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/biosses">BIOSSES</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/blue">BLUE</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/blurb">BLURB</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bioasq">BioASQ</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/chemprot">ChemProt</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ddi">DDI</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hoc-1">HOC</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/mednli">MedNLI</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ncbi-disease-1">NCBI Disease</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/pubmed-pico-element-detection-dataset">PubMed PICO Element Detection Dataset</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/pubmedqa">PubMedQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/squad">SQuAD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Word centrality constrained representation for keyphrase extraction</title>
      <author><first>Zelalem</first><last>Gero</last></author>
      <author><first>Joyce</first><last>Ho</last></author>
      <pages>155–161</pages>
      <abstract>To keep pace with the increased generation and digitization of documents, automated methods that can improve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_engine_technology">search</a>, discovery and mining of the vast body of literature are essential. Keyphrases provide a concise representation by identifying salient concepts in a document. Various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervised_learning">supervised approaches</a> model <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keyphrase_extraction">keyphrase extraction</a> using local context to predict the label for each token and perform much better than the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unsupervised_learning">unsupervised counterparts</a>. Unfortunately, this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Method_(computer_programming)">method</a> fails for short documents where the context is unclear. Moreover, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keyword_(linguistics)">keyphrases</a>, which are usually the gist of a document, need to be the central theme. We propose a new extraction model that introduces a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centrality">centrality constraint</a> to enrich the word representation of a Bidirectional long short-term memory. Performance evaluation on 2 publicly available datasets demonstrate our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> outperforms existing state-of-the art approaches.</abstract>
      <url hash="ab295abd">2021.bionlp-1.17</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.17</doi>
      <bibkey>gero-ho-2021-word</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/zhgero/keyphrases_centrality" additional="false">zhgero/keyphrases_centrality</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>End-to-end Biomedical Entity Linking with Span-based Dictionary Matching</title>
      <author><first>Shogo</first><last>Ujiie</last></author>
      <author><first>Hayate</first><last>Iso</last></author>
      <author><first>Shuntaro</first><last>Yada</last></author>
      <author><first>Shoko</first><last>Wakamiya</last></author>
      <author><first>Eiji</first><last>Aramaki</last></author>
      <pages>162–167</pages>
      <abstract>Disease name recognition and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normalization_(statistics)">normalization</a> is a fundamental process in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biomedical_text_mining">biomedical text mining</a>. Recently, neural joint learning of both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(computing)">tasks</a> has been proposed to utilize the mutual benefits. While this approach achieves high performance, disease concepts that do not appear in the training dataset can not be accurately predicted. This study introduces a novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/End-to-end_principle">end-to-end approach</a> that combines span representations with dictionary-matching features to address this problem. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> handles unseen concepts by referring to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dictionary">dictionary</a> while maintaining the performance of neural network-based models. Experiments using two major datasaets demonstrate that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> achieved competitive results with strong baselines, especially for unseen concepts during training.</abstract>
      <url hash="21860744">2021.bionlp-1.18</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.18</doi>
      <bibkey>ujiie-etal-2021-end</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bc5cdr">BC5CDR</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>Context-aware query design combines knowledge and data for efficient reading and reasoning</title>
      <author><first>Emilee</first><last>Holtzapple</last></author>
      <author><first>Brent</first><last>Cochran</last></author>
      <author><first>Natasa</first><last>Miskov-Zivanov</last></author>
      <pages>238–246</pages>
      <abstract>The amount of biomedical literature has vastly increased over the past few decades. As a result, the sheer quantity of accessible information is overwhelming, and complicates manual information retrieval. Automated methods seek to speed up <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">information retrieval</a> from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medical_literature">biomedical literature</a>. However, such automated methods are still too time-intensive to survey all existing biomedical literature. We present a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methodology</a> for automatically generating literature queries that select relevant papers based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">biological data</a>. By using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gene_expression">differentially expressed genes</a> to inform our literature searches, we focus <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_extraction">information extraction</a> on mechanistic signaling details that are crucial for the disease or context of interest.</abstract>
      <url hash="b3448888">2021.bionlp-1.26</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.26</doi>
      <bibkey>holtzapple-etal-2021-context</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Measuring the relative importance of full text sections for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">information retrieval</a> from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_literature">scientific literature</a>.</title>
      <author><first>Lana</first><last>Yeganova</last></author>
      <author><first>Won Gyu</first><last>Kim</last></author>
      <author><first>Donald</first><last>Comeau</last></author>
      <author><first>W John</first><last>Wilbur</last></author>
      <author><first>Zhiyong</first><last>Lu</last></author>
      <pages>247–256</pages>
      <abstract>With the growing availability of full-text articles, integrating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstract_(summary)">abstracts</a> and full texts of documents into a unified representation is essential for comprehensive search of scientific literature. However, previous studies have shown that navely merging <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstract_(summary)">abstracts</a> with full texts of articles does not consistently yield better performance. Balancing the contribution of query terms appearing in the abstract and in sections of different importance in full text articles remains a challenge both with traditional bag-of-words IR approaches and for neural retrieval methods. In this work we establish the connection between the BM25 score of a query term appearing in a section of a full text document and the probability of that document being clicked or identified as relevant. Probability is computed using Pool Adjacent Violators (PAV), an isotonic regression algorithm, providing a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maximum_likelihood_estimation">maximum likelihood estimate</a> based on the observed data. Using this probabilistic transformation of BM25 scores we show an improved performance on the PubMed Click dataset developed and presented in this study, as well as the 2007 TREC Genomics collection.</abstract>
      <url hash="7ed457fb">2021.bionlp-1.27</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.27</doi>
      <bibkey>yeganova-etal-2021-measuring</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="31">
      <title>SB_NITK at MEDIQA 2021 : Leveraging Transfer Learning for Question Summarization in Medical Domain<fixed-case>SB</fixed-case>_<fixed-case>NITK</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>MEDIQA</fixed-case> 2021: Leveraging Transfer Learning for Question Summarization in Medical Domain</title>
      <author><first>Spandana</first><last>Balumuri</last></author>
      <author><first>Sony</first><last>Bachina</last></author>
      <author><first>Sowmya</first><last>Kamath S</last></author>
      <pages>273–279</pages>
      <abstract>Recent strides in the healthcare domain, have resulted in vast quantities of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Streaming_data">streaming data</a> available for use for building intelligent knowledge-based applications. However, the challenges introduced to the huge volume, velocity of generation, variety and variability of this medical data have to be adequately addressed. In this paper, we describe the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> and results for our submission at MEDIQA 2021 Question Summarization shared task. In order to improve the performance of summarization of consumer health questions, our method explores the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">transfer learning</a> to utilize the knowledge of NLP transformers like BART, T5 and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PEGASUS">PEGASUS</a>. The proposed models utilize the knowledge of pre-trained NLP transformers to achieve improved results when compared to conventional deep learning models such as LSTM, RNN etc. Our team SB_NITK ranked 12th among the total 22 submissions in the official final rankings. Our BART based model achieved a ROUGE-2 F1 score of 0.139.</abstract>
      <url hash="88abd0d7">2021.bionlp-1.31</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.31</doi>
      <bibkey>balumuri-etal-2021-sb</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/c4">C4</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/meqsum">MeQSum</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="33">
      <title>QIAI at MEDIQA 2021 : Multimodal Radiology Report Summarization<fixed-case>QIAI</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>MEDIQA</fixed-case> 2021: Multimodal Radiology Report Summarization</title>
      <author><first>Jean-Benoit</first><last>Delbrouck</last></author>
      <author><first>Cassie</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Rubin</last></author>
      <pages>285–290</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the solution of the QIAI lab sent to the Radiology Report Summarization (RRS) challenge at MEDIQA 2021. This paper aims to investigate whether using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multimodality">multimodality</a> during training improves the summarizing performances of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> at test-time. Our preliminary results shows that taking advantage of the visual features from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X-ray">x-rays</a> associated to the radiology reports leads to higher evaluation metrics compared to a text-only baseline system. These improvements are reported according to the automatic evaluation metrics METEOR, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BLEU">BLEU</a> and ROUGE scores. Our experiments can be fully replicated at the following address : https:// github.com/jbdel/vilmedic.</abstract>
      <url hash="776cfe25">2021.bionlp-1.33</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.33</doi>
      <bibkey>delbrouck-etal-2021-qiai</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/jbdel/vilmedic" additional="false">jbdel/vilmedic</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="37">
      <title>MNLP at MEDIQA 2021 : Fine-Tuning PEGASUS for Consumer Health Question Summarization<fixed-case>MNLP</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>MEDIQA</fixed-case> 2021: Fine-Tuning <fixed-case>PEGASUS</fixed-case> for Consumer Health Question Summarization</title>
      <author><first>Jooyeon</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Huong</first><last>Dang</last></author>
      <author><first>Ozlem</first><last>Uzuner</last></author>
      <author><first>Sam</first><last>Henry</last></author>
      <pages>320–327</pages>
      <abstract>This paper details a Consumer Health Question (CHQ) summarization model submitted to MEDIQA 2021 for shared task 1 : Question Summarization. Many CHQs are composed of multiple sentences with typos or unnecessary information, which can interfere with automated question answering systems. Question summarization mitigates this issue by removing this unnecessary information, aiding automated systems in generating a more accurate summary. Our summarization approach focuses on applying multiple pre-processing techniques, including question focus identification on the input and the development of an ensemble method to combine question focus with an abstractive summarization method. We use the state-of-art abstractive summarization model, PEGASUS (Pre-training with Extracted Gap-sentences for Abstractive Summarization), to generate abstractive summaries. Our experiments show that using our ensemble method, which combines abstractive summarization with question focus identification, improves performance over using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_summarization">summarization</a> alone. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> shows a ROUGE-2 F-measure of 11.14 % against the official test dataset.</abstract>
      <url hash="95c2c2b9">2021.bionlp-1.37</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.bionlp-1.37</doi>
      <bibkey>lee-etal-2021-mnlp</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/meqsum">MeQSum</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>