<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.inlg">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-09-20">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 14th International Conference on Natural Language Generation</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Anya</first><last>Belz</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Angela</first><last>Fan</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ehud</first><last>Reiter</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yaji</first><last>Sripada</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Aberdeen, Scotland, UK</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="fd554c4d">2021.inlg-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="61c58746">2021.inlg-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>inlg-2021-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Neural Methodius Revisited : Do Discourse Relations Help with Pre-Trained Models Too?</title>
      <author><first>Aleksandre</first><last>Maskharashvili</last></author>
      <author><first>Symon</first><last>Stevens-Guille</last></author>
      <author><first>Xintong</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>White</last></author>
      <pages>12–23</pages>
      <abstract>Recent developments in natural language generation (NLG) have bolstered arguments in favor of re-introducing explicit coding of discourse relations in the input to neural models. In the Methodius corpus, a meaning representation (MR) is hierarchically structured and includes <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse_analysis">discourse relations</a>. Meanwhile pre-trained language models have been shown to implicitly encode rich linguistic knowledge which provides an excellent resource for NLG. By virtue of synthesizing these lines of research, we conduct extensive experiments on the benefits of using pre-trained models and discourse relation information in MRs, focusing on the improvement of discourse coherence and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Correctness_(computer_science)">correctness</a>. We redesign the Methodius corpus ; we also construct another Methodius corpus in which MRs are not hierarchically structured but flat. We report experiments on different versions of the corpora, which probe when, where, and how pre-trained models benefit from MRs with discourse relation information in them. We conclude that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse_analysis">discourse relations</a> significantly improve NLG when data is limited.</abstract>
      <url hash="c3d2f45e">2021.inlg-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>maskharashvili-etal-2021-neural</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/aleksadre/methodiusneuralinlg2021" additional="false">aleksadre/methodiusneuralinlg2021</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Chefbot : A Novel Framework for the Generation of Commonsense-enhanced Responses for Task-based Dialogue Systems</title>
      <author><first>Carl</first><last>Strathearn</last></author>
      <author><first>Dimitra</first><last>Gkatzia</last></author>
      <pages>46–47</pages>
      <abstract>Conversational systems aim to generate responses that are accurate, relevant and engaging, either through utilising neural end-to-end models or through slot filling. Human-to-human conversations are enhanced by not only the latest utterance of the interlocutor, but also by recalling relevant information about concepts / objects covered in the dialogue and integrating them into their responses. Such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information">information</a> may contain recent referred concepts, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commonsense_knowledge">commonsense knowledge</a> and more. A concrete scenario of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue">dialogues</a> is the cooking scenario, i.e. when an artificial agent (personal assistant, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robot">robot</a>, chatbot) and a human converse about a recipe. We will demo a novel system for commonsense enhanced response generation in the scenario of cooking, where the conversational system is able to not only provide directions for cooking step-by-step, but also display commonsense capabilities by offering explanations of how objects can be used and provide recommendations for replacing ingredients.<i>commonsense</i> capabilities by offering explanations of how objects can be used and provide recommendations for replacing ingredients.</abstract>
      <url hash="532dee8f">2021.inlg-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>strathearn-gkatzia-2021-chefbot</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Predicting Antonyms in Context using BERT<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Ayana</first><last>Niwa</last></author>
      <author><first>Keisuke</first><last>Nishiguchi</last></author>
      <author><first>Naoaki</first><last>Okazaki</last></author>
      <pages>48–54</pages>
      <abstract>We address the task of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opposite_(semantics)">antonym prediction</a> in a context, which is a fill-in-the-blanks problem. This task setting is unique and practical because it requires <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contrast_(linguistics)">contrastiveness</a> to the other word and naturalness as a text in filling a blank. We propose methods for fine-tuning pre-trained masked language models (BERT) for context-aware antonym prediction. The experimental results demonstrate that these methods have positive impacts on the prediction of antonyms within a context. Moreover, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evaluation">human evaluation</a> reveals that more than 85 % of predictions using the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> are acceptable as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opposite_(semantics)">antonyms</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="ffc3387c">2021.inlg-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>niwa-etal-2021-predicting</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/semeval-2018-task-9-hypernym-discovery">SemEval-2018 Task 9: Hypernym Discovery</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Examining Covert Gender Bias : A Case Study in Turkish and English Machine Translation Models<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>urkish and <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish Machine Translation Models</title>
      <author><first>Chloe</first><last>Ciora</last></author>
      <author><first>Nur</first><last>Iren</last></author>
      <author><first>Malihe</first><last>Alikhani</last></author>
      <pages>55–63</pages>
      <abstract>As Machine Translation (MT) has become increasingly more powerful, accessible, and widespread, the potential for the perpetuation of bias has grown alongside its advances. While overt indicators of bias have been studied in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>, we argue that covert biases expose a problem that is further entrenched. Through the use of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_language">gender-neutral language Turkish</a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">gendered language English</a>, we examine cases of both overt and covert gender bias in MT models. Specifically, we introduce a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_method">method</a> to investigate asymmetrical gender markings. We also assess <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a> in the attribution of personhood and examine occupational and personality stereotypes through overt bias indicators in MT models. Our work explores a deeper layer of bias in MT models and demonstrates the continued need for language-specific, interdisciplinary methodology in MT model development.</abstract>
      <url hash="5260729e">2021.inlg-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>ciora-etal-2021-examining</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/NurIren/Gender-Bias-in-TR-to-EN-MT-Models" additional="false">NurIren/Gender-Bias-in-TR-to-EN-MT-Models</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Explaining Decision-Tree Predictions by Addressing Potential Conflicts between Predictions and Plausible Expectations</title>
      <author><first>Sameen</first><last>Maruf</last></author>
      <author><first>Ingrid</first><last>Zukerman</last></author>
      <author><first>Ehud</first><last>Reiter</last></author>
      <author><first>Gholamreza</first><last>Haffari</last></author>
      <pages>114–127</pages>
      <abstract>We offer an approach to explain Decision Tree (DT) predictions by addressing potential conflicts between aspects of these predictions and plausible expectations licensed by background information. We define four types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conflict_(process)">conflicts</a>, operationalize their identification, and specify explanatory schemas that address them. Our human evaluation focused on the effect of explanations on users’ understanding of a DT’s reasoning and their willingness to act on its predictions. The results show that (1) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Explanation">explanations</a> that address potential conflicts are considered at least as good as baseline explanations that just follow a DT path ; and (2) the conflict-based explanations are deemed especially valuable when users’ expectations disagree with the DT’s predictions.</abstract>
      <url hash="0a6f5d87">2021.inlg-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>maruf-etal-2021-explaining</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Underreporting of errors in NLG output, and what to do about it<fixed-case>NLG</fixed-case> output, and what to do about it</title>
      <author><first>Emiel</first><last>van Miltenburg</last></author>
      <author><first>Miruna</first><last>Clinciu</last></author>
      <author><first>Ondřej</first><last>Dušek</last></author>
      <author><first>Dimitra</first><last>Gkatzia</last></author>
      <author><first>Stephanie</first><last>Inglis</last></author>
      <author><first>Leo</first><last>Leppänen</last></author>
      <author><first>Saad</first><last>Mahamood</last></author>
      <author><first>Emma</first><last>Manning</last></author>
      <author><first>Stephanie</first><last>Schoch</last></author>
      <author><first>Craig</first><last>Thomson</last></author>
      <author><first>Luou</first><last>Wen</last></author>
      <pages>140–153</pages>
      <abstract>We observe a severe under-reporting of the different kinds of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Errors-in-variables_models">errors</a> that Natural Language Generation systems make. This is a problem, because mistakes are an important indicator of where systems should still be improved. If authors only report overall performance metrics, the research community is left in the dark about the specific weaknesses that are exhibited by ‘state-of-the-art’ research. Next to quantifying the extent of error under-reporting, this position paper provides recommendations for error identification, analysis and reporting.</abstract>
      <url hash="a17c8e0e">2021.inlg-1.14</url>
      <attachment type="Supplementary_Attachment" hash="302452fb">2021.inlg-1.14.Supplementary_Attachment.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>van-miltenburg-etal-2021-underreporting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>What can Neural Referential Form Selectors Learn?</title>
      <author><first>Guanyi</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <author><first>Fahime</first><last>Same</last></author>
      <author><first>Kees</first><last>van Deemter</last></author>
      <pages>154–166</pages>
      <abstract>Despite achieving encouraging results, neural Referring Expression Generation models are often thought to lack transparency. We probed neural Referential Form Selection (RFS) models to find out to what extent the linguistic features influencing the RE form are learned and captured by state-of-the-art RFS models. The results of 8 probing tasks show that all the defined <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> were learned to some extent. The probing tasks pertaining to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Referent">referential status</a> and syntactic position exhibited the highest performance. The lowest performance was achieved by the probing models designed to predict discourse structure properties beyond the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_(linguistics)">sentence level</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="00e09a6e">2021.inlg-1.15</url>
      <attachment type="Supplementary_Attachment" hash="634b0c83">2021.inlg-1.15.Supplementary_Attachment.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>chen-etal-2021-neural-referential</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/webnlg">WebNLG</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>SAPPHIRE : Approaches for Enhanced Concept-to-Text Generation<fixed-case>SAPPHIRE</fixed-case>: Approaches for Enhanced Concept-to-Text Generation</title>
      <author><first>Steven Y.</first><last>Feng</last></author>
      <author><first>Jessica</first><last>Huynh</last></author>
      <author><first>Chaitanya Prasad</first><last>Narisetty</last></author>
      <author><first>Eduard</first><last>Hovy</last></author>
      <author><first>Varun</first><last>Gangal</last></author>
      <pages>212–225</pages>
      <abstract>We motivate and propose a suite of simple but effective improvements for concept-to-text generation called SAPPHIRE : Set Augmentation and Post-hoc PHrase Infilling and REcombination. We demonstrate their effectiveness on generative commonsense reasoning, a.k.a. the CommonGen task, through experiments using both BART and T5 models. Through extensive automatic and human evaluation, we show that SAPPHIRE noticeably improves <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_simulation">model</a> performance. An in-depth qualitative analysis illustrates that SAPPHIRE effectively addresses many issues of the baseline model generations, including lack of commonsense, insufficient specificity, and poor fluency.</abstract>
      <url hash="35a791e3">2021.inlg-1.21</url>
      <bibkey>feng-etal-2021-sapphire</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/styfeng/sapphire" additional="false">styfeng/sapphire</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/commongen">CommonGen</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>Generation Challenges : Results of the Accuracy Evaluation Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Craig</first><last>Thomson</last></author>
      <author><first>Ehud</first><last>Reiter</last></author>
      <pages>240–248</pages>
      <abstract>The Shared Task on Evaluating Accuracy focused on techniques (both manual and automatic) for evaluating the factual accuracy of texts produced by neural NLG systems, in a sports-reporting domain. Four teams submitted evaluation techniques for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a>, using very different approaches and techniques. The best-performing submissions did encouragingly well at this difficult <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a>. However, all automatic submissions struggled to detect factual errors which are semantically or pragmatically complex (for example, based on incorrect computation or inference).</abstract>
      <url hash="611b4355">2021.inlg-1.23</url>
      <bibkey>thomson-reiter-2021-generation</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ehudreiter/accuracysharedtask" additional="false">ehudreiter/accuracysharedtask</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>The ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluations in NLG : Overview and Results<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>epro<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>en Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluations in <fixed-case>NLG</fixed-case>: Overview and Results</title>
      <author><first>Anya</first><last>Belz</last></author>
      <author><first>Anastasia</first><last>Shimorina</last></author>
      <author><first>Shubham</first><last>Agarwal</last></author>
      <author><first>Ehud</first><last>Reiter</last></author>
      <pages>249–258</pages>
      <abstract>The NLP field has recently seen a substantial increase in work related to reproducibility of results, and more generally in recognition of the importance of having shared definitions and practices relating to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evaluation">evaluation</a>. Much of the work on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reproducibility">reproducibility</a> has so far focused on metric scores, with reproducibility of human evaluation results receiving far less attention. As part of a research programme designed to develop theory and practice of reproducibility assessment in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a>, we organised the first shared task on reproducibility of human evaluations, ReproGen 2021. This paper describes the shared task in detail, summarises results from each of the reproduction studies submitted, and provides further comparative analysis of the results. Out of nine initial team registrations, we received submissions from four teams. Meta-analysis of the four reproduction studies revealed varying degrees of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reproducibility">reproducibility</a>, and allowed very tentative first conclusions about what types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evaluation">evaluation</a> tend to have better <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reproducibility">reproducibility</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="f6d3a5f2">2021.inlg-1.24</url>
      <bibkey>belz-etal-2021-reprogen</bibkey>
    <title_ar>مهمة ReproGen المشتركة حول استنساخ التقييمات البشرية في NLG: نظرة عامة والنتائج</title_ar>
      <title_es>La tarea compartida de ReproGen sobre la reproducibilidad de las evaluaciones humanas en NLG: descripción general y resultados</title_es>
      <title_pt>A Tarefa Compartilhada ReproGen sobre Reprodutibilidade de Avaliações Humanas em NLG: Visão Geral e Resultados</title_pt>
      <title_ja>NLGにおけるヒト評価の再現性に関するReproGen共有タスク：概要と結果</title_ja>
      <title_zh>ReproGenNLG中人伦评再现性之共同任务:概述和终</title_zh>
      <title_hi>ReproGen NLG में मानव मूल्यांकन की पुनरुत्पादन पर साझा कार्य: अवलोकन और परिणाम</title_hi>
      <title_ga>An Tasc Comhroinnte ReproGen ar In-atáirgtheacht Measúnuithe Daonna i NLG: Forbhreathnú agus Torthaí</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ReproGen shared task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluations in NLG: Overview and Results</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A ReproGen közös feladata az emberi értékelések reprodukálhatóságáról az NLG-ben: áttekintés és eredmények</title_hu>
      <title_el>Η κοινή εργασία αναπαράστασης για την αναπαραγωγιμότητα των ανθρώπινων αξιολογήσεων στο ΝΓΚ: Επισκόπηση και αποτελέσματα</title_el>
      <title_it>Il compito condiviso di ReproGen sulla riproducibilità delle valutazioni umane in NLG: panoramica e risultati</title_it>
      <title_kk>Құрамындағы Адам бағалауының қайта- қайта- қайта- қайта- қайта- қайта- қайта- қайта- қарау және нәтижелері</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Bendra ReproGen užduotis dėl žmogaus vertinimų reprodukcijos NLG: Apžvalga ir rezultatai</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Преглед и резултати</title_mk>
      <title_ml>എംഎല്‍ജി</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Comment</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Il-Kompitu Konġunt ta’ ReproGen dwar ir-Riproduċibbiltà tal-Evalwazzjonijiet Umani fl-NLG: Ħarsa ġenerali u Riżultati</title_mt>
      <title_no>ReproGen-delt oppgåve om reproduktivitet av menneskelige evalueringar i NLG: Oversyning og resultat</title_no>
      <title_mn>The ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluation in NLG: Overview and Results</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Wspólne zadanie reproGen dotyczące reprodukcyjności ocen ludzkich w NLG: przegląd i wyniki</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Sarcina comună ReproGen privind reproductibilitatea evaluărilor umane în GNL: Prezentare generală și rezultate</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Podijeljeni zadatak Reproгенa o reproduktivnosti ljudskih procjena u NLG: Pregled i rezultati</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>The ReproGen Shared Task on Reproductibility of Human Evaluations in NLG: Overview and Results</title_so>
      <title_sv>ReproGen delade uppgifter om reproducerbarhet av mänskliga utvärderingar i NLG: Översikt och resultat</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>NLG میں انسان کی ارزیابی کے بارے میں ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluation: Overview and Results</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Nhiệm vụ chia sẻ Repro Gen về khả năng tái phát của dự án người trong NLG: dư luận và kết quả</title_vi>
      <title_da>ReproGen's fælles opgave om reproducerbarhed af menneskelige evalueringer i NLG: Oversigt og resultater</title_da>
      <title_bg>Споделена задача за възпроизводимостта на човешките оценки в НЛГ: преглед и резултати</title_bg>
      <title_de>Die gemeinsame Aufgabe der ReproGen zur Reproduzierbarkeit menschlicher Evaluationen in NLG: Übersicht und Ergebnisse</title_de>
      <title_nl>De gezamenlijke taak van reproGen over reproduceerbaarheid van menselijke evaluaties in NLG: Overzicht en resultaten</title_nl>
      <title_ko>NLG에서 인간 평가의 재현성: 개술과 결과의 ReproGen 공유 작업</title_ko>
      <title_fa>وظیفه مشترک بازنشستگان در مورد بازنشستگی ارزیابی انسان در NLG: Overview and Results</title_fa>
      <title_id>The ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluations in NLG: Overview and Results</title_id>
      <title_tr>The ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluations in NLG: Overview and Results</title_tr>
      <title_af>Die ReproGen Gedeelde Opdrag oor Herstelling van menslike Evaluasies in NLG: Oorskou en Resultate</title_af>
      <title_sq>Detyra e përbashkët e ReproGen mbi riprodhimin e vlerësimeve njerëzore në NLG: Përfshirje dhe rezultate</title_sq>
      <title_am>The ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducity of Human Evolution in NLG: Overview and Results</title_am>
      <title_hy>ՆԼԳ-ում մարդկային գնահատականների վերարտադրողականության ընդհանուր հանձնարարությունը՝ ընդհանուր դիտարկում և արդյունքներ</title_hy>
      <title_bn>এনএলজিতে মানব পরিস্থিতির প্রতিফলিতি সম্পর্কে রিপ্রোজেন শেয়ার করা কাজ শেয়ার করেছে: পর্যবেক্ষণ এবং ফলাফল</title_bn>
      <title_hr>Podijeljeni zadatak ReproGena o reproduktivnoj procjeni ljudskih procjena u NLG: Pregled i rezultati</title_hr>
      <title_ca>La ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluations at NLG: Overview and Results</title_ca>
      <title_bs>Podijeljeni zadatak ReproGena o reproduktivnosti ljudskih procjena u NLG: Pregled i rezultati</title_bs>
      <title_sw>Mwandishi wa ReproGen alishiriki kazi ya Uhalalishaji wa Tathmini za Binadamu katika NLG: Kufuatilia na Matokeo</title_sw>
      <title_cs>Společný úkol reprodukce reprodukovatelnosti lidských hodnocení v NLG: Přehled a výsledky</title_cs>
      <title_et>ReproGeni jagatud ülesanne inimhinnangute reprodutseeritavuse kohta NLG-s: ülevaade ja tulemused</title_et>
      <title_az>NLG'də İnsan değerlendirmələrinin yenilənməsi haqqında ReproGen paylaşdırılmış iş: Görüş və Sonuçlar</title_az>
      <title_fi>ReproGen Shared Task on Reprodutible of Human Evaluations in NLG: Yleiskatsaus ja tulokset</title_fi>
      <title_jv>The repo Gen shared tasks on repotecible of Human invaluations in NLG: Subview and output</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_he>המשימה המשותפת של ReproGen על ניצחון הערכות האנושיות ב NLG:</title_he>
      <title_sk>Skupna naloga ReproGen o reproduktibilnosti človeških ocen v NLG: pregled in rezultati</title_sk>
      <title_bo>ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluations in NLG: Overview and Results</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>شهد مجال البرمجة اللغوية العصبية مؤخرًا زيادة كبيرة في العمل المتعلق بإمكانية تكرار النتائج ، وبشكل أكثر عمومية اعترافًا بأهمية وجود تعاريف وممارسات مشتركة تتعلق بالتقييم. ركز الكثير من العمل على التكاثر حتى الآن على الدرجات المترية ، مع إعادة إنتاج نتائج التقييم البشري التي لا تحظى باهتمام أقل بكثير. كجزء من برنامج بحث مصمم لتطوير نظرية وممارسة تقييم قابلية التكاثر في البرمجة اللغوية العصبية ، قمنا بتنظيم أول مهمة مشتركة حول إمكانية استنساخ التقييمات البشرية ، ReproGen 2021. تصف هذه الورقة المهمة المشتركة بالتفصيل وتلخص النتائج من كل دراسة من دراسات الاستنساخ المقدمة ، وتوفر مزيدًا من التحليل المقارن للنتائج. من أصل تسعة تسجيلات أولية للفريق ، تلقينا إرسالات من أربعة فرق. كشف التحليل التلوي لدراسات الاستنساخ الأربع عن درجات متفاوتة من قابلية التكاثر ، وسمح باستنتاجات أولية مؤقتة للغاية حول أنواع التقييم التي تميل إلى التكاثر بشكل أفضل.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>El campo de la PNL ha visto recientemente un aumento sustancial en el trabajo relacionado con la reproducibilidad de los resultados y, de manera más general, en reconocimiento de la importancia de compartir definiciones y prácticas relacionadas con la evaluación. Gran parte del trabajo sobre reproducibilidad se ha centrado hasta ahora en las puntuaciones métricas, y la reproducibilidad de los resultados de la evaluación humana recibe mucha menos atención. Como parte de un programa de investigación diseñado para desarrollar la teoría y la práctica de la evaluación de la reproducibilidad en la PNL, organizamos la primera tarea compartida sobre la reproducibilidad de las evaluaciones en humanos, ReProGen 2021. Este documento describe la tarea compartida en detalle, resume los resultados de cada uno de los estudios de reproducción presentados y proporciona un análisis comparativo adicional de los resultados. De los nueve registros iniciales de equipos, recibimos propuestas de cuatro equipos. El metanálisis de los cuatro estudios de reproducción reveló diversos grados de reproducibilidad y permitió sacar primeras conclusiones muy tentativas sobre qué tipos de evaluación tienden a tener una mejor reproducibilidad.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>O campo da PNL tem visto recentemente um aumento substancial no trabalho relacionado à reprodutibilidade dos resultados e, mais geralmente, em reconhecimento da importância de ter definições e práticas compartilhadas relacionadas à avaliação. Muito do trabalho sobre reprodutibilidade até agora se concentrou em pontuações métricas, com a reprodutibilidade dos resultados da avaliação humana recebendo muito menos atenção. Como parte de um programa de pesquisa projetado para desenvolver teoria e prática de avaliação de reprodutibilidade em PNL, organizamos a primeira tarefa compartilhada sobre reprodutibilidade de avaliações humanas, ReproGen 2021. Este artigo descreve a tarefa compartilhada em detalhes, resume os resultados de cada um dos estudos de reprodução apresentados, e fornece uma análise comparativa adicional dos resultados. Das nove inscrições iniciais de equipes, recebemos inscrições de quatro equipes. A meta-análise dos quatro estudos de reprodução revelou graus variados de reprodutibilidade e permitiu primeiras conclusões muito provisórias sobre quais tipos de avaliação tendem a ter melhor reprodutibilidade.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>NLP分野では、最近、結果の再現性に関連する作業が大幅に増加しており、より一般的には、評価に関連する定義と実践を共有することの重要性を認識しています。 再現性に関する研究の多くは、これまでメトリックスコアに焦点を当てており、人間の評価結果の再現性は、それほど注目されていません。 NLPにおける再現性評価の理論と実践を開発するために設計された研究プログラムの一環として、私たちは人間の評価の再現性に関する最初の共有タスクReproGen 2021を組織しました。 本稿では、共有タスクを詳細に説明し、提出された各再現研究の結果をまとめ、結果のさらなる比較分析を提供する。 初期の9チーム登録のうち、4チームから提出を受けた。 4つの再現性研究のメタアナリシスは、さまざまな程度の再現性を明らかにし、どのタイプの評価がより良い再現性を有する傾向があるかについての非常に暫定的な最初の結論を可能にした。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>NLP领域近见重复性事大幅增,而博见评估之要。 至于目前为止,可重复性之大体,皆集指标分,人伦评可重复性,关注要少多。 其在NLP也重复性论行之一也,吾为首论可重复性之共同任务ReproGen 2021。 本文详细描述同务,总其每项复制究,更加剖析。 九初团队注册,得自四团队提。 凡四生之会,析而异可重复性,许其可否重复性得非常之论。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>एनएलपी क्षेत्र ने हाल ही में परिणामों की पुनरुत्पादन क्षमता से संबंधित काम में काफी वृद्धि देखी है, और अधिक आम तौर पर मूल्यांकन से संबंधित साझा परिभाषाओं और प्रथाओं के महत्व की मान्यता में। पुनरुत्पादन पर अधिकांश काम ने अब तक मीट्रिक स्कोर पर ध्यान केंद्रित किया है, जिसमें मानव मूल्यांकन परिणामों की पुनरुत्पादकता बहुत कम ध्यान प्राप्त कर रही है। एनएलपी में पुनरुत्पादन मूल्यांकन के सिद्धांत और अभ्यास को विकसित करने के लिए डिज़ाइन किए गए एक शोध कार्यक्रम के हिस्से के रूप में, हमने मानव मूल्यांकन, ReproGen 2021 की पुनरुत्पादकता पर पहला साझा कार्य आयोजित किया। यह पेपर विस्तार से साझा कार्य का वर्णन करता है, प्रस्तुत किए गए प्रजनन अध्ययनों में से प्रत्येक से परिणामों को संक्षेप में प्रस्तुत करता है, और परिणामों का आगे तुलनात्मक विश्लेषण प्रदान करता है। नौ प्रारंभिक टीम पंजीकरणों में से, हमें चार टीमों से प्रस्तुतियां मिलीं। चार प्रजनन अध्ययनों के मेटा-विश्लेषण से पुनरुत्पादन की अलग-अलग डिग्री का पता चला, और किस प्रकार के मूल्यांकन में बेहतर पुनरुत्पादन होता है, इसके बारे में बहुत ही अस्थायी पहले निष्कर्षों की अनुमति दी।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Chonacthas méadú suntasach i réimse an NLP le déanaí ar an obair a bhaineann le hin-atáirgtheacht na dtorthaí, agus go ginearálta mar aitheantas ar an tábhacht a bhaineann le sainmhínithe agus cleachtais chomhroinnte a bhaineann le meastóireacht. Tá go leor den obair ar atáirgtheacht dírithe go dtí seo ar scóir mhéadracha, agus is lú i bhfad a tugadh aird ar atáirgtheacht thorthaí na meastóireachta daonna. Mar chuid de chlár taighde atá deartha chun teoiric agus cleachtas measúnaithe in-atáirgtheachta a fhorbairt i NLP, d’eagraíomar an chéad tasc comhroinnte ar atáirgtheacht na meastóireachtaí daonna, ReproGen 2021. Déanann an páipéar seo cur síos mionsonraithe ar an tasc roinnte, déanann sé achoimre ar thorthaí gach ceann de na staidéir atáirgeadh. curtha isteach, agus soláthraíonn sé tuilleadh anailíse comparáideach ar na torthaí. As naoi gclárú foirne tosaigh, fuaireamar aighneachtaí ó cheithre fhoireann. Léirigh meitea-anailís ar na ceithre staidéar atáirgeadh céimeanna éagsúla in-atáirgtheachta, agus cheadaigh sé na chéad chonclúidí an-seallaidh faoi na cineálacha meastóireachta a mbíonn in-atáirgtheacht níos fearr ag baint leo.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>NLP პანელი ახლა აღმოჩნდა მნიშვნელოვანი პროგრამის გამოსახულებელობას და უფრო საერთოდ განსახულებელი განსახულებების და პროგრამის გამოსახულებელობას. მნიშვნელოვანი მუშაობაზე, რომელიც მეტრიკური მონაცემებისთვის, ადამიანის გაუმუშაობის გაუმუშაობას, რომელიც უფრო მეტრიკური მონაცემებისთვის გაუმუ როგორც პროგრამის ნაწილი პროგრამის ნაწილი, რომელიც განახლებელად განვითარება ტეორია და პრაქტიკის განვითარება განვითარება NLP-ში, ჩვენ პირველი გაყოფილი საქმედება ადამიანის გაუმუშავებ ამ დოკუმენტი განსაზღვრებულია განსაზღვრებული დავალების განსაზღვრებულია, განსაზღვრებულია ყოველ განსაზღვრებული განსაზღვრების განსაზღვრებულია, და დაახლოებით შემდეგ შე 9 პირველი ტიმის რეგისტრაციებიდან ჩვენ 4 ჯგუფიდან მივიღეთ წინასწორება. მეტა-ანალიზია ოთხი განმხლებელობის განმხლებელობის განმხლებელობის განსხვავებული გრადუსების განმხლებელობის მეტა-ანალიზია, და ძალიან განმხლებელი პირველი შესაძლებელობა, რომელიც უფრო უ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Az NKP területén a közelmúltban jelentős mértékben nőtt az eredmények reprodukálhatóságával kapcsolatos munka, és általában annak elismerése, hogy fontos az értékeléssel kapcsolatos meghatározások és gyakorlatok megosztása. A reprodukálhatóságra irányuló munka nagy része eddig a metrikus pontszámokra összpontosított, az emberi értékelési eredmények reprodukálhatóságának sokkal kevesebb figyelmet kapott. A reprodukálhatóság elméletének és gyakorlatának kidolgozására irányuló kutatási program részeként megszerveztük az emberi értékelések reprodukálhatóságával kapcsolatos első közös feladatot, a ReproGen 2021-et. Ez a tanulmány részletesen ismerteti a közös feladatot, összefoglalja az egyes benyújtott reprodukciós vizsgálatok eredményeit, és további összehasonlító elemzést nyújt az eredményekről. A kilenc kezdeti csapat regisztrációból négy csapattól kaptunk pályázatokat. A négy reprodukciós vizsgálat metaanalízise különböző mértékű reprodukálhatóságot mutatott ki, és nagyon kísérleti első következtetéseket tett lehetővé arra vonatkozóan, hogy milyen típusú értékelés általában jobb reprodukálhatósággal rendelkezik.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Ο τομέας NLP έχει πρόσφατα παρατηρήσει σημαντική αύξηση των εργασιών που σχετίζονται με την αναπαραγωγιμότητα των αποτελεσμάτων, και γενικότερα αναγνωρίζοντας τη σημασία των κοινών ορισμών και πρακτικών σχετικά με την αξιολόγηση. Μεγάλο μέρος της εργασίας για την αναπαραγωγιμότητα έχει ως τώρα επικεντρωθεί σε μετρικές βαθμολογίες, με την αναπαραγωγιμότητα των αποτελεσμάτων της ανθρώπινης αξιολόγησης να λαμβάνει πολύ λιγότερη προσοχή. Στο πλαίσιο ενός ερευνητικού προγράμματος που σχεδιάστηκε για την ανάπτυξη της θεωρίας και της πρακτικής της αξιολόγησης της αναπαραγωγιμότητας στο ΝΛΠ, οργανώσαμε το πρώτο κοινό έργο για την αναπαραγωγιμότητα των ανθρώπινων αξιολογήσεων, την ReproGen 2021. Η παρούσα εργασία περιγράφει λεπτομερώς το κοινό έργο, συνοψίζει τα αποτελέσματα από κάθε μία από τις υποβληθείσες μελέτες αναπαραγωγής και παρέχει περαιτέρω συγκριτική ανάλυση των αποτελεσμάτων. Από τις εννέα αρχικές εγγραφές ομάδων, λάβαμε αιτήσεις από τέσσερις ομάδες. Η μετα-ανάλυση των τεσσάρων μελετών αναπαραγωγής αποκάλυψε διαφορετικούς βαθμούς αναπαραγωγιμότητας και επέτρεψε πολύ διστακτικά πρώτα συμπεράσματα σχετικά με το ποια είδη αξιολόγησης τείνουν να έχουν καλύτερη αναπαραγωγιμότητα.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Il settore PNL ha recentemente visto un notevole aumento dei lavori relativi alla riproducibilità dei risultati e, più in generale, riconoscendo l'importanza di condividere definizioni e pratiche relative alla valutazione. Gran parte del lavoro sulla riproducibilità si è finora concentrato sui punteggi metrici, con la riproducibilità dei risultati della valutazione umana che ha ricevuto molta meno attenzione. Nell'ambito di un programma di ricerca volto a sviluppare teoria e pratica della valutazione della riproducibilità in PNL, abbiamo organizzato il primo compito condiviso sulla riproducibilità delle valutazioni umane, ReproGen 2021. Questo articolo descrive in dettaglio il compito condiviso, sintetizza i risultati di ciascuno degli studi di riproduzione presentati e fornisce un'ulteriore analisi comparativa dei risultati. Su nove iscrizioni iniziali, abbiamo ricevuto contributi da quattro squadre. La metaanalisi dei quattro studi sulla riproduzione ha rivelato diversi gradi di riproducibilità, e ha permesso prime conclusioni molto provvisorie su quali tipi di valutazione tendono ad avere una migliore riproducibilità.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>На полето НЛП неодамна се забележа значително зголемување на работата поврзана со репродуктибилноста на резултатите, и погенерално признавање на важноста на споделувањето дефиниции и практики поврзани со евалуацијата. Голем дел од работата на репродуктибилитетот досега се фокусираше на метричните резултати, при што репродуктибилитетот на резултатите на човечката оценка добива многу помалку внимание. Како дел од истражувачката програма дизајнирана за развој на теорија и практика на проценка на репродуктибилноста во НЛП, ја организиравме првата заедничка задача за репродуктибилноста на човечките проценки, Репоген 2021. Овој документ ја опишува заедничката задача во детали, ги сумира резултатите од секоја од поднесените студии за репродукција и обезбедува понатамошна споредлива анализа на резултатите. Out of nine initial team registrations, we received submissions from four teams.  Метаанализата на четирите студии за репродукција откри различни степени на репродуктибилност, и дозволи многу привремени први заклучоци за какви видови на евалуација имаат подобра репродуктибилност.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Neseniai NLP srityje labai padidėjo darbas, susijęs su rezultatų atkuriamumu, ir apskritai pripažįstama, kad svarbu turėti bendras su vertinimu susijusias apibrėžtis ir praktiką. Dauguma reprodukcijos darbų iki šiol daugiausia dėmesio skiriama metriniams rezultatams, o žmogaus vertinimo rezultatų reprodukcijai skiriama daug mažiau dėmesio. Pagal mokslinių tyrimų programą, kuria siekiama plėtoti NLP reprodukcijos vertinimo teoriją ir praktiką, surengėme pirmą bendrą žmogaus vertinimų reprodukcijos užduotį ReproGen 2021. This paper describes the shared task in detail, summarises results from each of the reproduction studies submitted, and provides further comparative analysis of the results.  Iš devynių pradinių komandos registracijų gavome paraiškas iš keturių komandų. Keturių reprodukcijos tyrimų metaanalizė parodė skirtingą reprodukcijos laipsnį ir leido padaryti labai preliminarias pirmąsias išvadas, kokių rūšių vertinimas paprastai turi geresnį reprodukcijos laipsnį.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Жуырдағы NLP өрісі нәтижелердің қайталанушылықтың жұмысын көптеген жұмыс істейтін жұмысын көрді, және оқиғалармен қатынау үшін ортақтастырылған анықтамалар мен практикалардың маңыздығын түсіні Репродукциялық жұмысының көпшілігі көпшілігі метрикалық нәтижелеріне назар аударды, адамдардың оқу нәтижелерін қайталау нәтижелері көп деңгейінде көп назар НЛП теориясын және репродукциялық оқиғаларын жасау үшін құрылған зерттеу бағдарламасының бірінші бөлінген тапсырманы адамдардың репродукциялық оқиғаларының репродукциялығын, РепродoGen 2021 жы Бұл қағаз ортақтастырылған тапсырманы егжей- тегжейлі түсіндіреді, жіберілген репродукция зерттеулерінің нәтижесін жазып, нәтижелердің жалғастырмалы анализ береді. Бастапқы топтардың тоғыз белгісінен төрт топтардан жіберілген. Төрт репродукциялық зерттеулердің мета анализ түрлі репродукциялық градустарын көрсетті. Бірінші оқу түрлерінің қандай жақсы репродукциялық түрлері бар екендігін бірінші жағдайда бірінші жа</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Medan NLP baru-baru ini telah melihat peningkatan yang besar dalam kerja berkaitan dengan reproducibiliti keputusan, dan secara umum dalam pengakuan penting mempunyai definisi dan praktek berkongsi berkaitan dengan penilaian. Banyak pekerjaan mengenai kemudahan reproduksi telah fokus pada skor metrik, dengan kemudahan reproduksi keputusan penilaian manusia menerima jauh kurang perhatian. Sebagai sebahagian dari program kajian yang direka untuk mengembangkan teori dan praktek penilaian reproduksi di NLP, kami mengatur tugas berkongsi pertama mengenai reproduksi penilaian manusia, ReproGen 2021. Kertas ini menjelaskan tugas berkongsi secara terperinci, menghitung keputusan dari setiap kajian reproduksi yang dihantar, dan menyediakan analisis perbandingan lanjut keputusan. Dari sembilan pendaftaran pasukan awal, kami menerima pengiriman dari empat pasukan. Analisis meta empat kajian reproduksi menunjukkan darjah-darjah reproduksi yang berbeza, dan membenarkan kesimpulan pertama yang sangat tentatif mengenai jenis penilaian cenderung untuk mempunyai reproduksi yang lebih baik.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>അടുത്തുതന്നെ NLP ഫീള്‍ഡ് ഫലങ്ങളുടെ പ്രവർത്തനവുമായി ബന്ധപ്പെട്ട ജോലിയുടെ വലിയ പ്രധാനപ്പെടുത്തുന്നത് കണ്ടിട്ടുണ്ട്. അതിനാല്‍ വിലയില്‍  പ്രവർത്തിക്കുന്നതിനെപ്പറ്റി പലതും മെറ്റിക്ക് സ്കോരിനെക്കുറിച്ച് ശ്രദ്ധിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. മനുഷ്യരുടെ വിലാസപ്രക നിര്‍മ്മിക്കാന്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കുന്ന ഒരു പരിശോധന പ്രോഗ്രാമിന്റെ ഭാഗമായി നമ്മള്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കുന്നത് നിര്‍മ്മിക്കുന്നതിന്റെയും പ്രായോഗ്ര ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ പങ്കെടുത്ത ജോലിയെ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു, ഓരോ പ്രവർത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്ന പദ്ധതിയില്‍ നിന്നും ഉത്തരവിനുള്ള ഫലങ് ആദ്യമായ ഒന്‍പത് ടീമില്‍ നിന്നും നമുക്ക് നാല് ടീമില്‍ നിന്നും കീഴടങ്ങള്‍ ലഭിച്ചു. നാലു പ്രവർത്തിക്കാനുള്ള പഠനങ്ങളിലെ മെറ്റ-അന്വേഷണം വ്യത്യസ്ത ഡിഗ്രി വെളിപ്പെടുത്തിയിരിക്കുന്നു. പ്രവർത്തകത്തിന്റെ ആദ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-qasam tal-NLP dan l-a ħħar wera żieda sostanzjali fix-xogħol relatat mar-riproduċibbiltà tar-riżultati, u b’mod aktar ġenerali fir-rikonoxximent tal-importanza li jkun hemm definizzjonijiet u prattiki kondiviżi relatati mal-evalwazzjoni. Il-biċċa l-kbira tax-xogħol dwar ir-riproduċibbiltà s’issa ffukat fuq il-punteġġi metriċi, bir-riproduċibbiltà tar-riżultati tal-evalwazzjoni umana li tirċievi ħafna inqas attenzjoni. Bħala parti minn programm ta’ riċerka mfassal biex jiżviluppa t-teorija u l-prattika tal-valutazzjoni tar-riproduċibbiltà fil-NLP, organizzaw l-ewwel kompitu kondiviż dwar ir-riproduċibbiltà tal-evalwazzjonijiet umani, ReproGen 2021. Dan id-dokument jiddeskrivi l-kompitu kondiviż fid-dettall, jiġbor fil-qosor ir-riżultati minn kull wieħed mill-istudji dwar ir-riproduzzjoni sottomessi, u jipprovdi analiżi komparattiva ulterjuri tar-riżultati. Minn disa’ reġistrazzjonijiet inizjali tat-tim, irċevejna sottomissjonijiet minn erba’ timijiet. Meta-analiżi tal-erba’ studji dwar ir-riproduzzjoni żvelat gradi varji ta’ riproduċibbiltà, u ppermettiet l-ewwel konklużjonijiet tentattivi ħafna dwar liema tipi ta’ evalwazzjoni għandhom tendenza li jkollhom riproduċibbiltà aħjar.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>НЛП талбар саяхан үр дүний үр дүнтэй холбогдолтой ажлын тухай ихэвчлэн нэмэгдэж байгааг харсан. Харин ихэвчлэн үнэлгээтэй холбогдолтой тодорхойлолт болон дасгал хөдөлгөөний чухал ач холбогдолтой гэ Ихэнх үржигдэх үйлдэл нь метрийн тоонууд дээр анхаарлаа төвлөрсөн. Хүн төрөлхтний оюутнуудын үржигдэх үр дүнг маш бага анхаарлаа авдаг. NLP-д үржих боломжтой оюутнуудын онол болон дасгал хөгжүүлэхэд зориулсан судалгааны програмын нэг хэсэг болгон бид хүн төрөлхтний оюутнуудын үржих боломжтой үйлдэл, ReproGen 2021 оны анхны хуваалцааг Энэ цаас хэвлэгдсэн ажлыг нарийвчлан тайлбарлаж, дамжуулагдсан үржвэрлэлийн судалгааны үр дүнг цуглуулж, үр дүнгийн харьцуулалтын шинжилгээг илүү харьцуулдаг. Эхний 9 багийн регистрациудаас бид 4 багийн даалгавар авсан. Дөрвөн үржүүлэх судалгааны мета-анализ нь үржүүлэх хэмжээний өөр өөр хэмжээсүүдийг харуулсан. Тэгээд хамгийн сайн үржүүлэх хэмжээсүүдийн талаар үнэлэх анхны шийдвэр гаргасан.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>NLP-feltet har nyleg sett ein betydelig økning i arbeidet relatert til reproduktiviteten av resultat, og meir vanlegvis i gjenkjenning av viktigheten for å ha delte definisjonar og praksis relatert til evaluering. Mange av arbeidet på reproduktivitet har så langt fokusert på metriske poeng, med reproduktivitet av menneskelige evalueringsresultat mottar mykje mindre oppmerking. Som ein del av eit forskningsprogram utviklet teori og praksis for reproduktivitetsverdi i NLP, organisert vi den første delte oppgåva om reproduktiviteten av menneske evalueringar, ReproGen 2021. Denne papiret beskriver delt oppgåva i detaljar, samanserer resultatet frå kvar av reproduksjonsstudiane som vert sendt, og tilbyr meir sammenlignbare analyse av resultatene. I 9 opphavsregistrasjonar motteke vi tillegg frå fire grupper. Metaanalysen av dei fire reproduksjonsstudiane viste forskjellige grader av reproduktivitet, og tillatt svært tentativ første konklusjonar om kva typar evalueringa tenderer å ha bedre reproduktivitet.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>W dziedzinie NLP odnotowano ostatnio znaczny wzrost prac związanych z powtarzalnością wyników, a bardziej ogólnie w świetle uznania znaczenia wspólnych definicji i praktyk związanych z oceną. Duża część prac nad powtarzalnością dotychczas koncentrowała się na wynikach metrycznych, przy czym odtwarzalność wyników oceny ludzkiej poświęca znacznie mniejszą uwagę. W ramach programu badawczego mającego na celu opracowanie teorii i praktyki oceny odtwarzalności w NLP zorganizowaliśmy pierwsze wspólne zadanie dotyczące powtarzalności ocen ludzkich – ReproGen 2021. Niniejszy artykuł szczegółowo opisuje wspólne zadanie, podsumowuje wyniki każdego z przedłożonych badań reprodukcyjnych oraz przedstawia dalszą analizę porównawczą wyników. Spośród dziewięciu początkowych rejestracji zespołów otrzymaliśmy zgłoszenia od czterech zespołów. Metaanaliza czterech badań reprodukcyjnych ujawniła różny stopień powtarzalności i pozwoliła na bardzo wstępne wnioski dotyczące tego, jakie rodzaje oceny mają tendencję do lepszej powtarzalności.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>În domeniul PNL s-a constatat recent o creștere substanțială a activităților legate de reproductibilitatea rezultatelor și, mai general, recunoașterea importanței unor definiții și practici comune în ceea ce privește evaluarea. O mare parte din lucrările privind reproductibilitatea s-a concentrat până în prezent pe scorurile metrice, reproductibilitatea rezultatelor evaluării umane fiind mult mai puțină atenție. În cadrul unui program de cercetare menit să dezvolte teoria și practica evaluării reproductibilității în PNL, am organizat prima sarcină comună privind reproductibilitatea evaluărilor umane, ReproGen 2021. Această lucrare descrie în detaliu sarcina comună, rezumă rezultatele fiecărui studiu de reproducere prezentat și oferă o analiză comparativă suplimentară a rezultatelor. Din nouă înscrieri inițiale în echipă, am primit trimiteri de la patru echipe. Metaanaliza celor patru studii de reproducere a relevat grade diferite de reproductibilitate și a permis primele concluzii foarte provizorii cu privire la tipurile de evaluare tind să aibă o reproductibilitate mai bună.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Polje NLP nedavno je vidio značajno povećanje rada povezanog sa reproduktivnošću rezultata, i uglavnom u priznanju važnosti zajedničkih definicija i prakse u vezi procjene. Većina posla o reproduktivnosti je do sada usredotočena na metričke rezultate, s reproduktivnošću rezultata procjene ljudskih ocjena koji primaju mnogo manje pažnje. Kao dio istraživačkog programa dizajniranog za razvoj teorije i prakse procjene reproduktivnosti u NLP-u, organizovali smo prvi zajednički zadatak o reproduktivnosti ljudskih procjena, ReproGen 2021. Ovaj papir detaljno opisuje zajednièki zadatak, sažete rezultate svakog podanih ispitivanja reprodukcije i pruža daljnju usporednu analizu rezultata. Od devet prvih registracija tima, dobili smo podatke od četiri ekipe. Metaanaliza četiri ispitivanja reprodukcije otkrila je različite stepenice reproduktivnosti i omogućila vrlo tentativne prve zaključke o tome kakve vrste procjene čine da imaju bolju reproduktivnost.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>NLP ක්‍ෂේත්රය අලුත් දැක්කා වැඩේ විශාල විශාල විශාල විශාල විශාල විශාල විදියට, ඒ වගේම සාමාන්‍ය විශාල විශාල විශ ගොඩක් දේවල් ප්‍රවර්තනයේ වැඩේ ඉතින් මෙට්‍රික් ස්කෝර්ට් වලට ප්‍රවර්තනය කරලා තියෙනවා, මිනිස්සු විශ්ලේෂණයේ  NLP වල පරීක්ෂණ ප්‍රවෘත්තියේ කොටසක් විදිහට සිද්ධ විශ්වාස කරන්න සිද්ධ විදිහය සහ ප්‍රවෘතිකරණය නිර්මාණය කරන්න, අපි පළමුව මේ පැත්තේ විස්තර විස්තරයෙන් සම්බන්ධ වැඩක් විස්තර කරනවා, ප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිපරීක්ෂණ පරීක්ෂණයෙන් පිළිබ පටන් ගත්ත කණ්ඩායම් නයක් නැවත, අපි කණ්ඩායම් හතරයෙන් පිළිගත්තා. මෙටා-විශ්ලේෂණයේ ප්‍රතිපත්ති පරීක්ෂණය හතරයි ප්‍රතිපත්ති පරීක්ෂණය විශේෂ කරලා තියෙන්නේ වෙනස් විදියට ප්‍රතිපත්ත</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Dhulka NLP ee ugu dhowaad wuxuu arkay kordhiska shaqada oo la xiriira qofka la xiriira la soo celin karo resultiyada, iyo si ka badan loo aqoonsado muhiimka la xiriira qayb-qayb-qaybinta iyo falimaha la xiriira qiimeynta. Shaqo badan oo ku saabsan qofka la soo celinayo ilaa hada waxay ku kalsoonaaday qiimeynta dadka, waxaana ka soo celin kara caqliga qiimeynta biniaadamka. Sida qayb ka mid ah barnaamijka waxbarashada oo loo qoray in loo horumariyo fikrada iyo baaritaanka kaartaynta qofka la soo celinayo ee NLP, waxaan qabannay shaqadii ugu horeeyay ee la qaybsaday in la soo celiyo qiimeynta dadka, ReproGen 2021. Kanu wuxuu si gaar ah ugu qoran yahay shaqada la qaybsaday, wuxuuna soo jeedaa dhamaadka waxbarashada dugsiga lagu soo qoray, wuxuuna sidoo kale u fidiyaa baaritaanka fasaxa. Isu diiwaangelinta sagaalka kooxda ee bilowga ah ayaannu ka helnay mid ka mid ah afar koox. Baaritaanka afarta waxbarasho ee qoyska waxaa muuqday shahaado kala duduwan ee qofka la soo celinayo, wuxuuna fasaxay dhamaadyo ugu horraysa ee ku saabsan qiimeynta caymiska qoyska ugu wanaagsan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>The NLP field has recently seen a substantial increase in work related to reproducibility of results, and more generally in recognition of the importance of having shared definitions and practices relating to evaluation.  பெரும்பாலோசனையின் பல வேலை மெட்ரிக் மதிப்புகளின் மீது கவனத்தை ஏற்படுத்தி இருக்கிறது, மனித மதிப்புகளின் பெருக்கல் முடிவு NLP-ல் பெரும்பாட்டு மதிப்புகளை உருவாக்குவதற்கான ஒரு ஆராய்ச்சி திட்டத்தின் பகுதி இந்த தாள் பகிர்ந்த பணியை விவரமாக விளக்குகிறது, ஒவ்வொரு முதல் படிப்புகளிலிருந்தும் சுருக்கும் முடிவுகளை வெளிப்படுத்த நாங்கள் நான்கு குழுக்களில் இருந்து ஒப்புக்கொள்கிறோம். நான்கு புதுப்பித்தல் படிப்புகளின் மெடா ஆராய்ச்சி வெவ்வேறு டிகிரிகள் பெரும்பாட்டின் வித்தியாசமான முதல் முடிவுகளை அனுமதித்த</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_sv>Inom det nationella handlingsprogrammet har det nyligen skett en avsevärd ökning av arbetet med reproducerbarhet av resultat, och mer allmänt med tanke på vikten av att ha gemensamma definitioner och metoder för utvärdering. Mycket av arbetet med reproducerbarhet har hittills fokuserat på metriska poäng, där reproducerbarheten av mänskliga utvärderingsresultat har fått mycket mindre uppmärksamhet. Som en del av ett forskningsprogram som syftar till att utveckla teori och praktik för reproducerbarhetsbedömning i NLP organiserade vi den första gemensamma uppgiften om reproducerbarhet av mänskliga utvärderingar, ReproGen 2021. Denna uppsats beskriver den gemensamma uppgiften i detalj, sammanfattar resultaten från varje inlämnad reproduktionsstudie och ger ytterligare jämförande analys av resultaten. Av nio första lagregistreringar fick vi bidrag från fyra lag. Metaanalysen av de fyra reproduktionsstudierna visade på olika grad av reproducerbarhet och möjliggjorde mycket försiktiga första slutsatser om vilka typer av utvärdering som tenderar att ha bättre reproducerbarhet.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>NLP فیلڈ نے اچھے وقت نتیجے کے بارے میں بہت زیادہ اضافہ کیا ہے اور اس سے زیادہ عمدہ مشترک تعریف اور تحقیق کے معاملہ میں مشترک تعریف کرنے کا اہم پہچان لیا ہے. اور بہت سے کام جن کے بارے میں دوبارہ پیدا ہونے والی ہے یہاں تک کہ متریک اسکور پر تمرکز کیا گیا ہے اور انسان کی ارزیابی کا دوبارہ پیدا ہونے والی نتیجے بہت کم توجه حاصل کرتے ہیں۔ NLP میں ایک تحقیقات پروگرامی کا حصہ بنایا گیا تھا کہ نظریہ اور فعالیت کی آزمائش کی تئوری اور فعالیت کی تئوری کو تولید کرنے کے لئے، ہم نے انسان کی آزمائش کے بارے میں پہلی مشترک کام کا سازمان کیا تھا، ReproGen 2021. This paper describes the shared task in detail, summarizes the results of each of the reproduction studies submitted, and provides further comparative analysis of the results. نو پہلی ٹیم کی رئیسٹریسٹر میں سے ہم نے چار ٹیموں سے مہمانی حاصل کی۔ چار پھلانے کے مطابق تحقیقات کی مٹا-تحقیقات نے مختلف درجے پھلانے کی اور بہترین پھلانے والی تحقیقات کے بارے میں بہترین نتیجے کی اجازت دی۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Ngày gần đây, lĩnh vực N.L.A. đã nhận thấy một sự tăng vọt công việc liên quan đến khả năng tái tạo kết quả, và thường xuyên hơn là để nhận ra tầm quan trọng của việc chia sẻ định nghĩa và thủ tục về đánh giá. Phần lớn công trình về khả năng sinh sản đã được nghiên cứu về điểm đo mét, với khả năng sinh sản của kết quả đánh giá con người ít được chú ý hơn. Một phần của một chương trình nghiên cứu nhằm phát triển lý thuyết và thực hành đánh giá khả năng sinh sản tại Njala, chúng tôi đã tổ chức một nhiệm vụ chia sẻ đầu tiên về khả năng sinh sản của loài người, Repro Gen 2021. Tờ giấy này mô tả chi tiết nhiệm vụ chia sẻ, tổng hợp kết quả từ mỗi nghiên cứu sinh sản đã nộp, và cung cấp một phân tích tương đối tiếp theo về kết quả. Trong chín đội tuyển đăng ký đầu tiên, chúng tôi nhận được thư từ bốn đội. Phân tích siêu phân tích của bốn nghiên cứu sinh sản cho thấy khả năng sinh sản khác nhau và cho phép những kết luận đầu tiên rất xúc động về các loại đánh giá có thể có khả năng sinh sản tốt hơn.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Yaqinda NLP maydoni natijalar qo'llanmalari bilan ishni katta ko'paytirishni ko'rsatadi, va ko'p narsalarni qiymatga bog'langan aniqlashning muhimligini aniqlash mumkin. Ko'pchiliklik vazifalarining ko'p ishlari metrik qiymatlariga foydalanadi. Inson qiymatlarining qo'shilishi natijalari juda kichkina foydalanadi. As part of a research programme designed to develop theory and practice of reproducibility assessment in NLP, we organised the first shared task on reproducibility of human evaluations, ReproGen 2021.  Ushbu qogʻoz bilan bogʻliq vazifani aniqlaydi, har bir taklif qilingan taʼminlovchi natijalaridan hisoblanadi va natijalarni koʻpaytirish natijalarini bajaradi. Birinchi guruh registratidan 9 guruhdan, biz to'rtta guruhdan imkoniyatlarni qabul qildik. Toʻrtta taʼminlovchi o'rganishlarning meta-analysi qo'llangan darajadagi darajadagi darajaga ko'rinadi, va qiymatning turini qanday yaxshi qo'llashga ega bo'lganligini anglatadi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>В областта на НЛП наскоро се наблюдава значително увеличаване на работата, свързана с възпроизводимостта на резултатите, и по-общо с признаването на значението на споделените определения и практики, свързани с оценката. Голяма част от работата по възпроизводимостта досега се фокусира върху метричните оценки, като възпроизводимостта на резултатите от оценката при хора получава далеч по-малко внимание. Като част от научноизследователска програма, предназначена за разработване на теория и практика за оценка на възпроизводимостта в НЛО, ние организирахме първата споделена задача за възпроизводимостта на човешките оценки, РепоГен 2021. Тази статия описва подробно споделената задача, обобщава резултатите от всяко от представените проучвания за възпроизвеждане и предоставя допълнителен сравнителен анализ на резултатите. От девет първоначални регистрации в екипа получихме предложения от четири отбора. Метаанализа на четирите проучвания за репродукция показва различна степен на възпроизводимост и позволява много колебливи първи заключения за това какви видове оценка са склонни да имат по-добра възпроизводимост.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Op het gebied van het NLP is onlangs een aanzienlijke toename van de werkzaamheden op het gebied van reproduceerbaarheid van resultaten te zien geweest, en meer in het algemeen gezien het belang van gemeenschappelijke definities en praktijken op het gebied van evaluatie. Veel van het werk over reproduceerbaarheid is tot dusver gericht op metrische scores, waarbij reproduceerbaarheid van menselijke evaluatieresultaten veel minder aandacht krijgt. Als onderdeel van een onderzoeksprogramma dat bedoeld is om theorie en praktijk van reproduceerbaarheidsbeoordeling in NLP te ontwikkelen, organiseerden we de eerste gezamenlijke taak over reproduceerbaarheid van menselijke evaluaties, ReproGen 2021. Dit artikel beschrijft de gedeelde taak in detail, vat de resultaten van elk van de ingediende reproductiestudies samen en biedt verdere vergelijkende analyse van de resultaten. Van de negen eerste teamregistraties kregen we inzendingen van vier teams. Meta-analyse van de vier reproductiestudies toonde verschillende mate van reproduceerbaarheid aan, en gaf zeer voorlopige eerste conclusies over welke soorten evaluaties doorgaans een betere reproduceerbaarheid hebben.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Der NLP-Bereich hat in letzter Zeit eine erhebliche Zunahme der Arbeiten im Zusammenhang mit der Reproduzierbarkeit der Ergebnisse und allgemein in Anerkennung der Bedeutung gemeinsamer Definitionen und Praktiken im Zusammenhang mit der Bewertung festgestellt. Ein Großteil der Arbeiten zur Reproduzierbarkeit konzentrierte sich bisher auf metrische Scores, wobei die Reproduzierbarkeit menschlicher Bewertungsergebnisse weitaus weniger Beachtung fand. Im Rahmen eines Forschungsprogramms zur Entwicklung von Theorie und Praxis der Reproduzierbarkeitsbewertung in NLP organisierten wir die erste gemeinsame Aufgabe zur Reproduzierbarkeit menschlicher Evaluationen, ReproGen 2021. Dieser Beitrag beschreibt die gemeinsame Aufgabe im Detail, fasst die Ergebnisse der eingereichten Reproduktionsstudien zusammen und bietet eine weitere vergleichende Analyse der Ergebnisse. Von neun ersten Teamanmeldungen erhielten wir Einreichungen von vier Teams. Die Metaanalyse der vier Reproduktionsstudien ergab unterschiedliche Reproduzierbarkeitsgrade und erlaubte sehr zaghafte erste Schlussfolgerungen darüber, welche Auswertungsarten tendenziell eine bessere Reproduzierbarkeit aufweisen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>NLP 분야에서는 최근 결과 재현성과 관련한 작업이 크게 늘었고, 평가와 관련한 정의와 실천을 공유하는 것이 중요하다는 인식이 일반적이다.지금까지 재현성에 대한 대부분의 작업이 도량점수에 집중되면서 인류 평가 결과의 재현성에 대한 관심은 훨씬 적었다.NLP에서의 재현성 평가 이론과 실천을 개발하기 위한 연구 계획의 일환으로 우리는 인류 평가의 재현성에 대한 최초의 공유 임무인 ReproGen 2021을 조직했다.본고는 공유 임무를 상세하게 묘사하고 제출한 각 생식 연구의 결과를 총괄하며 결과를 더욱 비교 분석했다.최초의 9개 팀 등록 중, 우리는 4개 팀의 제출을 받았다.네 가지 생식 연구에 대한 모음 분석은 어느 정도의 재현성을 제시했고 어떤 유형의 평가가 더 좋은 재현성을 가진다는 결론을 초보적으로 얻었다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>زمینه NLP اخیراً افزایش زیادی در کار مربوط به بازگشت نتایج دیده است، و عموماً در تشخیص اهمیت تعریف‌های مشترک و تمرین‌های مربوط به ارزیابی است. بسیاری از کارهای روی بازآفرینی تا حالا روی امتیاز متریک تمرکز کرده است، با بازآفرینی نتایج ارزیابی انسان به کمتر توجه می‌گیرد. به عنوان بخشی از برنامه تحقیقات طراحی برای توسعه نظریه و تمرین تولید تولید تولید تولید تولید تولید تولید تولید تولید تولید تولید تولید در NLP، اولین کار مشترک را در مورد تولید تولید تولید تولید کردن انسان،  این کاغذ کار مشترک را با جزئیات توصیف می‌کند، نتیجه‌ها را از هر مطالعه‌های تولید می‌کند و تحلیل مقایسه‌ای بیشتر از نتیجه‌ها را پیشنهاد می‌کند. از نو شرکت گروه اول، از چهار تیم تحویل گرفتیم. تحلیل Meta-Analysis of the four reproduction studies revealed different degrees of reproducibility, and allowed very tentative conclusions about what types of evaluation tend to have better reproducibility.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Ardhi ya NLP hivi karibuni imeonekana kuongezeka kwa kiwango kikubwa cha kazi inayohusiana na uzalishaji wa matokeo, na kwa ujumla kutambua umuhimu wa kushirikiana maelezo na mazoea yanayohusiana na uchunguzi. Kazi nyingi kuhusu umoja wa uzazi imejikita zaidi kwenye vipindi vya umeme, na uzalishaji wa matokeo ya uchunguzi wa binadamu yanapokea umaarufu kidogo. Kama sehemu ya mpango wa utafiti uliobuniwa kuendeleza nadharia na utafiti wa tathmini za uzazi nchini NLP, tuliandaa jukumu la kwanza lililoshirikishwa juu ya uzalishaji wa tathmini za binadamu, ReproGen 2021. Gazeti hili linaelezea jukumu la kushirikiana kwa kina, matokeo ya muhtasari kutoka kila tafiti za uzazi zilizotolewa, na inatoa uchambuzi wa matokeo yanayofanana zaidi. Katika kuandikishwa kwa timu tisa ya mwanzo, tulipokea ujumbe kutoka timu nne. Uchambuzi wa tafiti hizi nne za uzazi ulionyesha vyeo tofauti vya uzazi, na kuliruhusu hitimisho la kwanza kuhusu namna gani ya uchunguzi unavyokuwa na umuhimu bora zaidi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_da>NLP-området har for nylig oplevet en betydelig stigning i arbejdet i forbindelse med resultaternes reproducerbarhed og mere generelt i erkendelse af vigtigheden af at have fælles definitioner og praksis i forbindelse med evaluering. Meget af arbejdet med reproducerbarhed har hidtil fokuseret på metriske scorer, og reproducerbarheden af menneskelige evalueringsresultater har fået langt mindre opmærksomhed. Som led i et forskningsprogram, der skal udvikle teori og praksis for reproducerbarhedsvurdering i NLP, organiserede vi den første fælles opgave om reproducerbarhed af menneskelige evalueringer, ReproGen 2021. Denne artikel beskriver den fælles opgave i detaljer, sammenfatter resultaterne fra hver af de indsendte reproduktionsundersøgelser og giver yderligere sammenlignende analyse af resultaterne. Ud af ni oprindelige teamregistreringer modtog vi indsendelser fra fire teams. Metaanalysen af de fire reproduktionsundersøgelser viste varierende grad af reproducerbarhed og gav mulighed for meget foreløbige første konklusioner om, hvilke typer evalueringer der har tendens til at have bedre reproducerbarhed.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>NLP polje nedavno vidio je značajan povećan rad povezan s reproduktivnošću rezultata i uglavnom u priznanju važnosti zajedničkih definicija i prakse u vezi procjene. Većina posla o reproduktivnosti do sada je usredotočena na metričke rezultate, s reproduktivnošću rezultata procjene ljudskih osoba koji primaju mnogo manje pažnje. Kao dio istraživačkog programa dizajniranog za razvoj teorije i prakse procjene reproduktivnosti u NLP-u, organizovali smo prvi zajednički zadatak o reproduktivnosti ljudskih procjena, ReproGen 2021. Ovaj papir detaljno opisuje zajednički zadatak, sažete rezultate svakog podanih ispitivanja reprodukcije i pruža daljnju usporedbenu analizu rezultata. Od devet prvih registracija tima dobili smo podatke od četiri ekipe. Metaanaliza četiri ispitivanja reprodukcije otkrila je različite stupnje reproduktivnosti i omogućila vrlo tentativne prve zaključke o tome kakve vrste procjene čine bolju reproduktivnost.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_sq>Fusha e NLP ka parë kohët e fundit një rritje thelbësore në punën lidhur me riprodhimin e rezultateve dhe më përgjithësisht në njohjen e rëndësisë së përcaktimit të përbashkët dhe praktikave lidhur me vlerësimin. Shumë nga puna mbi riprodhimin është përqëndruar deri tani në rezultatet metrike, me riprodhimin e rezultateve të vlerësimit njerëzor që marrin më pak vëmendje. Si pjesë e një programi kërkimesh të dizajnuar për të zhvilluar teorinë dhe praktikën e vlerësimit të riprodhueshmërisë në NLP, ne organizuam detyrën e parë të përbashkët mbi riprodhueshmërinë e vlerësimeve njerëzore, ReproGen 2021. Ky dokument përshkruan në hollësi detyrën e përbashkët, përmbledh rezultatet e secilit nga studimet e riprodhimit të paraqitura dhe ofron analizë të mëtejshme krahasuese të rezultateve. Nga nëntë regjistrime fillestare të ekipit, morëm paraqitje nga katër ekipe. Metaanaliza e katër studimeve të riprodhimit zbuloi grada të ndryshme riprodhimi dhe lejoi përfundime shumë të parakohshme të para rreth tipeve të vlerësimit që kanë tendencë të kenë riprodhimi më të mirë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>NLP sahypasy ýakynda netijeleri täzelikleýänligi barada işleýän işleriň has baglanmasyny we deňleýänligi barada paylaşyk definisyonlaryň we praktikleriň wajyplygyny tanaýar. Köp çagalandyrylygyň köpüsi metrik nokatlara üns berdi we adamlaryň deňleşenlerine täzeden üns berilýär. NLP'da ýetişdirijilik duýgulamanyň teoriýasy we praktika gelişmek üçin tassyklanan bir araştyrma programynyň bir bölegi bolup, birinji adam çykyşlaryň täzelikleriniň täzelikligi barada ýetişdirilýänlik üçin ýerleşdirdik, ReproGen 2021 Bu kagyz paýlaşylýan zadyny detaylar şeklinde tassyýar, üýtgeden reproducsiýa öwrenmeleriniň netijelerini we netijelerini daşyrdyr. Dokuz başlangyç topardan bölegimizden dört topardan rugsat aldyk. 4 täzeliklik öwrenmeleriniň meta-analizi çarpyşlygyň derejesi çarpyşlygyň derejesini görkezildi we çözgütli ilkinji çözümleri nähili çarpyşlygyň gowylaşdyrylygy barada örän tentativ çözümleri bardyr.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Die NLP veld het onlangs 'n groot vergroot vergroting in werk wat verwanter is met reproduksibiliteit van resultate, en meer algemeen in herken van die belangrikheid van gedeelde definisies en praksies wat verwanter is met evaluasie. Baie van die werk op reproduktiviteit het so ver gefokus op metriese punte, met reproduktiviteit van menslike evaluasie resultate wat baie minder aandag ontvang word. As deel van 'n ondersoek program ontwerp om teoriee en praksie van reproduktiviteitsevaluering in NLP te ontwikkel, het ons die eerste gedeelde taak organiseer oor reproduktiviteit van menslike evaluasies, ReproGen 2021. Hierdie papier beskryf die gedeelde taak in detail, opsomming resultate van elke van die oorgestuurde reproduksie studie en verskaf verdere vergelykbare analisie van die resultate. Van nege aanvanklike span registrasies het ons ondersteuning ontvang van vier teams. Metaanalisie van die vier reproduksie studie het verskillende grade van reproduktiviteit geopenbaar, en toegelaat baie tentatiewe eerste konklusies oor watter tipes van evaluasie beter reproduktiviteit het.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>በአሁኑ ጊዜ የNLP መሬት ፍሬዎችን በኩል የሚያሳድገውን ሥራ ያበዛል፡፡ በብዙ ሥራ በጥንቃቄ ላይ እስከ ዛሬ ድረስ የሜትሪክ ደረጃዎች ላይ ተማክሮአል፤ የሰው ውጤት ግንኙነት ግንኙነት በጣም ትንሽ ትኩረት እንዲቀበል ነው፡፡ በNLP የመጀመሪያውን ትምህርት እና የግንኙነት ሽፋን ለማድረግ የማስፈልግ ፕሮግራም ክፍል ሆነን የሰው ውሳኔ ግንኙነት በሙሉ አካባቢ፣ ReproGen 2021. This paper describes the shared task in detail, summarises results from each of the reproduction studies submitted, and provides further comparative analysis of the results.  ከዘጠኝ የመጀመሪያ የቡድን registration ውስጥ ከአራቱ ቡድን ጥያቄዎችን ተቀበልን፡፡ የአራቱ የዘረጀት ትምህርት ማተሚያ የሚለይ የግልጾች ደረጃዎች የሚለዩ ደረጃዎች እና የመጀመሪያውን ፍጥረት ማድረግ ምን ዓይነት አካሄድ እንዲሻል ይደረጋል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>ՆԼՊ ոլորտը վերջերս տեսել է արդյունքների վերարտադրողականության հետ կապված աշխատանքի նշանակալի աճ և, ավելի ընդհանուր առմամբ, գնահատման հետ կապված ընդհանուր սահմանումների և գործողությունների կարևորության ճանաչելու համար: Կարգադրելիության ոլորտում գործողությունների մեծ մասը մինչ այժմ կենտրոնացել է մետրական գնահատականների վրա, մարդկային գնահատականների արդյունքների վերարտադրելիությունը շատ ավելի քիչ ուշադրություն ստանում է: Որպես մի ուսումնասիրության ծրագիր, որը նախագծված է վերարտադրողականության գնահատման տեսության և պրակտիկայի զարգացմանը ՆԼՊ-ում, մենք կազմակերպեցինք մարդկային գնահատումների վերարտադրողականության առաջին ընդհանուր խնդիրը՝ Ռեպոգե Այս թղթին մանրամասն ներկայացնում է ընդհանուր խնդիրը, համառոտագրում է ներկայացված վերարտադրման յուրաքանչյուր ուսումնասիրության արդյունքները և ապահովում է արդյունքների համեմատական վերլուծություն: Սկզբնական իննը խմբի գրանցումներից մենք ստացանք ներկայացումներ չորս խմբից: Չորս վերարտադրման ուսումնասիրությունների մետավերլուծությունը բացահայտեց վերարտադրողականության տարբեր աստիճաններ, և թույլ տվեց շատ փորձարկվող առաջին եզրակացություններ այն մասին, թե ինչպիսի տեսակներ գնահատում են հակված ավելի լավ վերար</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_id>Lapangan NLP baru-baru ini melihat peningkatan besar dalam pekerjaan yang berhubungan dengan reproduksibilitas hasil, dan secara umum dalam pengakuan penting memiliki definisi dan praktek berbagi yang berhubungan dengan evaluasi. Banyak pekerjaan tentang reproduksibilitas telah sejauh ini fokus pada skor metrik, dengan reproduksibilitas hasil evaluasi manusia menerima jauh lebih sedikit perhatian. As part of a research programme designed to develop theory and practice of reproducibility assessment in NLP, we organised the first shared task on reproducibility of human evaluations, ReproGen 2021.  Kertas ini menjelaskan tugas berbagi secara rinci, mengungkapkan hasil dari setiap studi reproduksi yang dihantar, dan menyediakan analisis perbandingan lanjut dari hasil. Dari sembilan rekaman tim awal, kami menerima pengiriman dari empat tim. Meta-analisis dari empat studi reproduksi menunjukkan berbagai derajat reproduksibilitas, dan memungkinkan kesimpulan pertama yang sangat tentatif tentang jenis evaluasi cenderung untuk memiliki reproduksibilitas yang lebih baik.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_az>NLP sahəsi son zamanlarda sonuçların yenidən təmizlənəcəyi işlərə çox böyük bir artırma gördü və daha genellik təmizlənəcəyi tərzlərin və tərzlərin müqabilində paylaşılmasının vacibətini tanımadı. Yenidən yenilənmək haqqında çox iş metrik nöqtələrinə, insan değerlendirməsi sonuçlarının yenilənməsi daha az paylaşır. NLP'də yenilənmək təcrübəsini təşkil etmək üçün təşkil edilmiş bir araştırma proqramının bir parçası olaraq, insan değerlendirmələrinin yenilənməsi haqqında ilk paylaşdığı işi, ReproGen 2021. Bu kağıt paylaşılan işləri detaylı təsdiqləyir, təsdiqlənən hər təhsil təhsil təhsil təhsil təhsil etdir və sonuçların daha çox salıcı analizi təhsil edir. Dokuz başlangıç timin registrasyonundan dörd dəstədən təklif aldıq. Dörd reproduktiv təhsilinin meta-analizi müxtəlif dərəcələrinin reproduktivlığı göstərdi və nələr təhsil etdiyinin daha yaxşı reproduktivlığı barəsində çox çətin ilk sonuçlarına izin verdi.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>সম্প্রতি এনএলপি ক্ষেত্রে ফলাফলের প্রবণতার সাথে সম্পর্কিত কাজের ব্যাপারে বৃদ্ধি পেয়েছে এবং মূল্যের সাথে সম্পর্কিত সংস্কার ও কর্মকাণ্ডের Much of the work on reproducibility has so far focused on metric scores, with reproducibility of human evaluation results receiving far less attention.  এনএলপিতে গবেষণা প্রোগ্রামের একটি অংশ হিসেবে আমরা প্রথম শেয়ার করেছি মানুষের মূল্যের প্রবণতা সম্পর্কে, রিপ্রোজেন ২০২১। এই পত্রিকা বিস্তারিত ভাগাভাগি করা কাজের ব্যাখ্যা করেছে, প্রত্যেকটি প্রজন্ম গবেষণার ফলাফলের সারসাম্প্রদান করেছে এবং ফলাফলের আরো  নয়টি প্রাথমিক দলের নিবন্ধনের মধ্যে আমরা চারটি দল থেকে প্রতিবেদন পেয়েছি। চারটি প্রজন্ম গবেষণার মেটা বিশ্লেষণ প্রকাশিত হয়েছে প্রবণতার বিভিন্ন ডিগ্রি প্রকাশিত হয়েছে এবং প্রথম সিদ্ধান্ত নিয়েছে যে কোন ধরনে</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>Recentment, el camp del NLP ha vist un augment substancial de la feina relacionada amb la reproducibilitat dels resultats, i, en general, en reconeixement de l'importància de tenir definicions i pràctiques compartides relacionades amb l'evaluació. Molta de la feina sobre la reproducibilitat s'ha centrat fins ara en puntuacions mètriques, amb molta menys atenció a la reproducibilitat dels resultats de l'evaluació humana. Com part d'un programa de recerca dissenyat per desenvolupar teoria i pràctica d'evaluació de reproducibilitat en NLP, vam organitzar la primera tasca compartida sobre reproducibilitat de les evaluacions humanes, la ReproGen 2021. Aquest paper descriu en detall la tasca compartida, resume els resultats de cada estudi de reproducció presentat i proporciona més anàlisi comparativa dels resultats. De les nove inscripcions inicials, vam rebre presentacions de quatre equips. La meta-anàlisi dels quatre estudis de reproducció va revelar diferents graus de reproducibilitat i va permetre primeres conclusions molt tentatives sobre quins tipus d'evaluació tendeixen a tenir una millor reproducibilitat.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>V oblasti NLP v poslední době došlo k výraznému nárůstu práce související s reprodukovatelností výsledků a obecněji s uznáním významu sdílených definic a postupů týkajících se hodnocení. Velká část práce na reprodukovatelnosti se zatím zaměřuje na metrické skóre, přičemž reprodukovatelnost výsledků hodnocení lidí je věnována mnohem menší pozornosti. V rámci výzkumného programu zaměřeného na rozvoj teorie a praxe hodnocení reprodukovatelnosti v NLP jsme uspořádali první společný úkol o reprodukovatelnosti lidských hodnocení, ReproGen 2021. Tento článek podrobně popisuje sdílený úkol, shrnuje výsledky každé z předložených reprodukčních studií a poskytuje další srovnávací analýzu výsledků. Z devíti počátečních týmových registrací jsme obdrželi příspěvky od čtyř týmů. Metaanalýza čtyř reprodukčních studií odhalila různé stupně reprodukovatelnosti a umožnila velmi předběžné závěry o tom, jaké typy hodnocení mají tendenci lepší reprodukovatelnost.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Uue tööprogrammi valdkonnas on hiljuti märkimisväärselt suurenenud tulemuste korratavusega seotud töö ning üldisemalt tunnustades hindamisega seotud ühiste määratluste ja tavade tähtsust. Palju reprodutseeritavuse alasest tööst on seni keskendunud meetrilistele skooritele, kusjuures inimeste hindamise tulemuste reprodutseeritavus on palju vähem tähelepanu pööratud. Uurimisprogrammi osana, mille eesmärk on arendada NLP reprodutseeritavuse hindamise teooriat ja praktikat, korraldasime esimese ühise ülesande inimhindamiste reprodutseeritavuse kohta, ReproGen 2021. Käesolevas dokumendis kirjeldatakse ühist ülesannet üksikasjalikult, tehakse kokkuvõte iga esitatud reproduktsiooniuuringu tulemustest ja esitatakse tulemuste täiendav võrdlev analüüs. Üheksast esimesest meeskonna registreerimisest saime ettepanekud neljalt meeskonnalt. Nelja reproduktsiooniuuringu metaanalüüs näitas erinevat reproduktsioonivõimet ja võimaldas väga esialgseid järeldusi selle kohta, millist tüüpi hindamisel kipub olema parem reproduktsioonivõime.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Uusi ohjelma on viime aikoina lisännyt huomattavasti tulosten toistettavuuteen liittyvää työtä ja yleisesti ottaen ottaen tunnustanut arviointiin liittyvien yhteisten määritelmien ja käytäntöjen tärkeyden. Suuri osa toistettavuutta koskevasta työstä on tähän mennessä keskittynyt metrisiin pisteisiin, ja ihmisten arviointitulosten toistettavuus on saanut paljon vähemmän huomiota. Osana tutkimusohjelmaa, jonka tarkoituksena on kehittää uusittavuusarvioinnin teoriaa ja käytäntöä NLP:ssä, järjestimme ensimmäisen yhteisen tehtävän ihmisen arviointien toistettavuudesta, ReproGen 2021. Tässä artikkelissa kuvataan yhteistä tehtävää yksityiskohtaisesti, esitetään yhteenveto kunkin toimitetun lisääntymistutkimuksen tuloksista ja esitetään tarkempi vertaileva analyysi tuloksista. Yhdeksästä ensimmäisestä tiimirekisteröinnistä saimme ehdotuksia neljältä tiimiltä. Neljän lisääntymistutkimuksen metaanalyysi paljasti vaihtelevia toistettavuusasteita ja antoi hyvin alustavat ensimmäiset johtopäätökset siitä, millaisilla arvioinneilla on yleensä parempi toistettavuus.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bs>NLP polje nedavno vidio je značajno povećanje rada povezanog sa reproduktivnošću rezultata, i uglavnom u priznanju važnosti zajedničkih definicija i prakse u vezi procjene. Većina posla o reproduktivnosti do sada je usredotočena na metričke rezultate, s reproduktivnošću rezultata procjene ljudskih ocjena koji primaju mnogo manje pažnje. Kao dio istraživačkog programa dizajniranog za razvoj teorije i prakse procjene reproduktivnosti u NLP-u, organizovali smo prvi zajednički zadatak o reproduktivnosti ljudskih procjena, ReproGen 2021. Ovaj papir detaljno opisuje zajednički zadatak, sažete rezultate svakog podanih ispitivanja reprodukcije i pruža daljnju usporedbenu analizu rezultata. Od devet prvih registracija tima, dobili smo podatke od četiri ekipe. Metaanaliza četiri ispitivanja reprodukcije otkrila je različite stepenice reproduktivnosti i omogućila vrlo tentativne prve zaključke o tome kakve vrste procjene čine da imaju bolju reproduktivnost.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_jv>(NLP) Dayone ono langkung karo akeh pisan bak ngucap-suarani, dadi sekondisih barang metar, dadi kajane jejaraké uwong sing nguasakno. Taning barêng-barêng program sing dibenakno kanggo nggawe theoria karo pratik sing beraksi urip urip nLP, kawula nggawe ngubah sing mbênêr nggawe barang urip nêmêr, Refo Gen 2020. Gambar iki dipoleh nggambar kelompok ntawehke nggawe Detayle, sumulatan gewis dipoleh bak mulalah sing ngewehke nggawe, lan ngewehke kut-kut tanggal dipoleh banjur. Mungkin sesuk gawe ngupakan pating 9 meta-edalusi karo akeh basa ripurasi uwong gak dhéwé éntuk urip, dadi sing perusahaan kelas tualke sampek kapan kuwi tindakan karo paké rapurasi sak terus-terus kuwi:</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Firin NLP na ƙara wani mai girma wa aikin da ke yi husũma game da duba na matsalar, kuma yana da gane muhimu da ya yi rabo da fassarar da aikin da ke danganta. Akwai yawa daga aikin a kan duffai har sai ya yi makini a kan score na metric, da dubi'in evaluci na mutane ta ƙara muhimmanci. As part of a research programme designed to develop theory and practice of reproducibility assessment in NLP, we organised the first shared task on reproducibility of human evaluations, ReproGen 2021.  Wannan takardan na bayyana the share of the aikin da aka ƙayyade shi daki-daki, yana ƙarami matsala daga kõwane fassarar dubu da aka bãyar da shi, kuma yana bãyar da yana sami-sami da fassaran. Daga kashi na farko na juma, mun motsa misãlai daga jama'a huɗu. Ana yi meta-anarrai ga karatun huɗu karatun za'a nuna darajõji dabam a cikin duffai, kuma ya yarda da fassarar farko a kan wane irin muhimmada ke da mafi alhẽri a duba.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>שדה NLP ראה לאחרונה גידול משמעותי בעבודה קשור לשחזור התוצאות, ובכלל יותר בהכרה של חשיבות של הגדרות והתרגילים משותפים בקשר להערכה. רוב העבודה על התרבות התמקדה עד כה על נקודות מטריות, עם התרבות של תוצאות הערכה האנושית מקבלת הרבה פחות תשומת לב. כחלק מתוכנית מחקר שמתכננת לפתח תיאוריה ופעולה של הערכת התחזוקות ב-NLP, ארגנו את המשימה הראשונה המשותפת על התחזוקות של הערכות האנושיות, ReproGen 2021. העבודה הזו מתארת את המשימה המשותפת בפרטים, מסכם תוצאות מכל מחקר ההרבות שנשלח, ומספק ניתוח משווה נוסף של התוצאות. מתוך תשע רשומות קבוצה ראשונות, קיבלנו הודעות מארבעה קבוצות. המטה-ניתוח של ארבעה מחקרי ההרבות חשף מעלות שונות של ניתוח ההרבות, ואפשר מסקנות ראשונות מוקדמות מאוד על אילו סוגי הערכה נוטים להיות ניתוח ההרבות טוב יותר.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Na področju novega delovnega programa se je nedavno znatno povečalo delo v zvezi s ponovljivostjo rezultatov in bolj splošno zaradi priznavanja pomena skupnih opredelitev in praks v zvezi z vrednotenjem. Veliko dela na področju ponovljivosti se je doslej osredotočalo na metrične rezultate, pri čemer je bila ponovljivost rezultatov ocenjevanja pri ljudeh veliko manj pozornosti namenjena. V okviru raziskovalnega programa za razvoj teorije in prakse ocenjevanja ponovljivosti v NLP smo organizirali prvo skupno nalogo o ponovljivosti ocenjevanja človeka, ReproGen 2021. Ta prispevek podrobno opisuje skupno nalogo, povzema rezultate vsake predložene študije razmnoževanja in ponuja nadaljnjo primerjalno analizo rezultatov. Od devetih začetnih prijav ekipe smo prejeli prispevke štirih ekip. Metaanaliza štirih študij razmnoževanja je pokazala različne stopnje ponovljivosti in omogočila zelo poskusne prve zaključke o tem, katere vrste vrednotenja imajo ponavadi boljšo ponovljivost.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>NLP མ་དེ་ལྟ་བུ་མཐོང་ནུས་ཚོད་ཁག་ཆེ་བསྐྱེད་ཚད་རྒྱལ་ཁབ་དང་འབྲེལ་བའི་བྱ་རྐྱེན་ཚད་ཉེ་ཆར་ཡོད། Most of the work on reproducibility have so far focused on metric scores, with reproducibility of human evaluation results receiving far less attention. NLP ནང་དུ་གཞི་རྩལ་ལས་འཚོལ་ཞིབ་ཀྱི་ལས་རིམ་གྱི་ཆ་ཤས་ཁག་གིས་དཔྱད་གཏོང་མཁན་དང་བྱ་རིམ་ལ་སྒྲིག ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་གསལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་བྱ་རིམ་ལ་གསལ་བཤད་པ་དང་། རྩིས་བ་སྒྲུབ་ཀྱི་ནང་འཁོད་རྣམས་ལས་ཕར་ཐོན་ཚུལ་ལྡན་བྱེད་ས འགོ་འཛུགས་མཁན་གྱི་བྱ་མིའི་དྲ་དམངས་9ལས། ང་ཚོས་དབར་གྱི་བཞི་མིའི་ནང་གི་སྐྱེས་ཚུལ་ལེན་བྱུང་། རྒྱལ་ཁབ་ཀྱི་ལྟ་བ་ཚོའི་ནང་གི་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་དཔྱད་ཚད་བཞིན་པ་ཚོར་བ་སྐྱེན་ཚུལ་གྱི་ཚད་མ་འདྲ་ཞིག་བྱས་ཡོད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Automatic Verification of Data Summaries</title>
      <author><first>Rayhane</first><last>Rezgui</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammed</first><last>Saeed</last></author>
      <author><first>Paolo</first><last>Papotti</last></author>
      <pages>271–275</pages>
      <abstract>We present a generic method to compute thefactual accuracy of a generated data summarywith minimal user effort. We look at the prob-lem as a fact-checking task to verify the nu-merical claims in the text. The verification al-gorithm assumes that the data used to generatethe text is available. In this paper, we describehow the proposed solution has been used toidentify incorrect claims about basketball tex-tual summaries in the context of the AccuracyShared Task at INLG 2021.</abstract>
      <url hash="87ee832b">2021.inlg-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>rezgui-etal-2021-automatic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="31">
      <title>A Reproduction Study of an Annotation-based Human Evaluation of MT Outputs<fixed-case>MT</fixed-case> Outputs</title>
      <author><first>Maja</first><last>Popović</last></author>
      <author><first>Anya</first><last>Belz</last></author>
      <pages>293–300</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we report our reproduction study of the Croatian part of an annotation-based human evaluation of machine-translated user reviews (Popovic, 2020). The work was carried out as part of the ReproGen Shared Task on Reproducibility of Human Evaluation in NLG. Our aim was to repeat the original study exactly, except for using a different set of evaluators. We describe the experimental design, characterise differences between original and reproduction study, and present the results from each study, along with analysis of the similarity between them. For the six main evaluation results of Major / Minor / All Comprehension error rates and Major / Minor / All Adequacy error rates, we find that (i) 4/6 system rankings are the same in both studies, (ii) the relative differences between systems are replicated well for Major Comprehension and Adequacy (Pearson’s   0.9), but not for the corresponding Minor error rates (Pearson’s 0.36 for Adequacy, 0.67 for Comprehension), and (iii) the individual system scores for both types of Minor error rates had a higher degree of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reproducibility">reproducibility</a> than the corresponding Major error rates. We also examine <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inter-annotator_agreement">inter-annotator agreement</a> and compare the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotations</a> obtained in the original and reproduction studies.</abstract>
      <url hash="d8082155">2021.inlg-1.31</url>
      <bibkey>popovic-belz-2021-reproduction</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="33">
      <title>DialogSum Challenge : Summarizing Real-Life Scenario Dialogues<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ialog<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>um Challenge: Summarizing Real-Life Scenario Dialogues</title>
      <author><first>Yulong</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <author id="yang-liu-edinburgh"><first>Yang</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Yue</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <pages>308–313</pages>
      <abstract>We propose a shared task on summarizing real-life scenario dialogues, DialogSum Challenge, to encourage researchers to address challenges in dialogue summarization, which has been less studied by the summarization community. Real-life scenario dialogue summarization has a wide potential application prospect in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chatbot">chat-bot</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_assistant">personal assistant</a>. It contains unique challenges such as special discourse structure, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference">coreference</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pragmatics">pragmatics</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_sense">social common sense</a>, which require specific representation learning technologies to deal with. We carefully annotate a large-scale dialogue summarization dataset based on multiple public dialogue corpus, opening the door to all kinds of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_summarization">summarization models</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="5c2b25d1">2021.inlg-1.33</url>
      <bibkey>chen-etal-2021-dialogsum-challenge</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/dream">DREAM</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/dailydialog">DailyDialog</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/dialogsum">DialogSum</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/mutual">MuTual</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="34">
      <title>Quality Evaluation of the Low-Resource Synthetically Generated Code-Mixed Hinglish Text<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>inglish Text</title>
      <author><first>Vivek</first><last>Srivastava</last></author>
      <author><first>Mayank</first><last>Singh</last></author>
      <pages>314–319</pages>
      <abstract>In this shared task, we seek the participating teams to investigate the factors influencing the quality of the code-mixed text generation systems. We synthetically generate code-mixed Hinglish sentences using two distinct approaches and employ human annotators to rate the generation quality. We propose two subtasks, quality rating prediction and annotators’ disagreement prediction of the synthetic Hinglish dataset. The proposed subtasks will put forward the reasoning and explanation of the factors influencing the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quality_(business)">quality</a> and human perception of the code-mixed text.</abstract>
      <url hash="7ca3c662">2021.inlg-1.34</url>
      <bibkey>srivastava-singh-2021-quality</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="35">
      <title>Shared Task on Feedback Comment Generation for Language Learners</title>
      <author><first>Ryo</first><last>Nagata</last></author>
      <author><first>Masato</first><last>Hagiwara</last></author>
      <author><first>Kazuaki</first><last>Hanawa</last></author>
      <author><first>Masato</first><last>Mita</last></author>
      <author><first>Artem</first><last>Chernodub</last></author>
      <author><first>Olena</first><last>Nahorna</last></author>
      <pages>320–324</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we propose a generation challenge called Feedback comment generation for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_acquisition">language learners</a>. It is a task where given a text and a span, a system generates, for the span, an explanatory note that helps the writer (language learner) improve their writing skills. The motivations for this challenge are : (i) practically, it will be beneficial for both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_acquisition">language learners</a> and teachers if a computer-assisted language learning system can provide feedback comments just as human teachers do ; (ii) theoretically, feedback comment generation for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_acquisition">language learners</a> has a mixed aspect of other generation tasks together with its unique features and it will be interesting to explore what kind of generation technique is effective against what kind of writing rule. To this end, we have created a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> and developed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline systems</a> to estimate baseline performance. With these preparations, we propose a generation challenge of feedback comment generation.</abstract>
      <url hash="b671e03a">2021.inlg-1.35</url>
      <bibkey>nagata-etal-2021-shared</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>