<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.iwcs">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-10-26">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 14th International Conference on Computational Semantics (IWCS)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Sina</first><last>Zarrieß</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Johan</first><last>Bos</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Rik</first><last>van Noord</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Lasha</first><last>Abzianidze</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Groningen, The Netherlands (online)</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="8f88d3fb">2021.iwcs-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="8c78ef9d">2021.iwcs-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>iwcs-2021-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Switching Contexts : Transportability Measures for NLP<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Guy</first><last>Marshall</last></author>
      <author><first>Mokanarangan</first><last>Thayaparan</last></author>
      <author><first>Philip</first><last>Osborne</last></author>
      <author><first>André</first><last>Freitas</last></author>
      <pages>1–10</pages>
      <abstract>This paper explores the topic of transportability, as a sub-area of generalisability. By proposing the utilisation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metrics</a> based on well-established statistics, we are able to estimate the change in performance of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP models</a> in new contexts. Defining a new measure for transportability may allow for better estimation of NLP system performance in new domains, and is crucial when assessing the performance of NLP systems in new tasks and domains. Through several instances of increasing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_complexity_theory">complexity</a>, we demonstrate how lightweight domain similarity measures can be used as estimators for the transportability in NLP applications. The proposed transportability measures are evaluated in the context of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named-entity_recognition">Named Entity Recognition</a> and Natural Language Inference tasks.</abstract>
      <url hash="a46138ff">2021.iwcs-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>marshall-etal-2021-switching</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ai-systems/transportability" additional="false">ai-systems/transportability</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/multinli">MultiNLI</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/snli">SNLI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Applied Temporal Analysis : A Complete Run of the FraCaS Test Suite<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>ra<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>a<fixed-case>S</fixed-case> Test Suite</title>
      <author><first>Jean-Philippe</first><last>Bernardy</last></author>
      <author><first>Stergios</first><last>Chatzikyriakidis</last></author>
      <pages>11–20</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we propose an implementation of temporal semantics that translates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tree_(data_structure)">syntax trees</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Well-formed_formula">logical formulas</a>, suitable for consumption by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coq">Coq proof assistant</a>. The analysis supports a wide range of phenomena including : temporal references, temporal adverbs, aspectual classes and progressives. The new semantics are built on top of a previous system handling all sections of the FraCaS test suite except the temporal reference section, and we obtain an accuracy of 81 percent overall and 73 percent for the problems explicitly marked as related to temporal reference. To the best of our knowledge, this is the best performance of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_system">logical system</a> on the whole of the FraCaS.</abstract>
      <url hash="39ab80fd">2021.iwcs-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>bernardy-chatzikyriakidis-2021-applied</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Critical Thinking for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">Language Models</a></title>
      <author><first>Gregor</first><last>Betz</last></author>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Voigt</last></author>
      <author><first>Kyle</first><last>Richardson</last></author>
      <pages>63–75</pages>
      <abstract>This paper takes a first step towards a critical thinking curriculum for neural auto-regressive language models. We introduce a synthetic corpus of deductively valid arguments, and generate artificial argumentative texts to train CRiPT : a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Critical_thinking">critical thinking</a> intermediarily pre-trained transformer based on GPT-2. Significant transfer learning effects can be observed : Trained on three simple core schemes, CRiPT accurately completes conclusions of different, and more complex types of arguments, too. CRiPT generalizes the core argument schemes in a correct way. Moreover, we obtain consistent and promising results for NLU benchmarks. In particular, CRiPT’s zero-shot accuracy on the GLUE diagnostics exceeds GPT-2’s performance by 15 percentage points. The findings suggest that intermediary pre-training on texts that exemplify basic reasoning abilities (such as typically covered in critical thinking textbooks) might help <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> to acquire a broad range of reasoning skills. The synthetic argumentative texts presented in this paper are a promising starting point for building such a critical thinking curriculum for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="781d8e32">2021.iwcs-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>betz-etal-2021-critical</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/debatelab/aacorpus" additional="false">debatelab/aacorpus</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/glue">GLUE</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/logiqa">LogiQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/snli">SNLI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Monotonicity Marking from Universal Dependency Trees<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependency Trees</title>
      <author><first>Zeming</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <author><first>Qiyue</first><last>Gao</last></author>
      <pages>121–131</pages>
      <abstract>Dependency parsing is a tool widely used in the field of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural language processing</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">computational linguistics</a>. However, there is hardly any work that connects dependency parsing to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monotonic_function">monotonicity</a>, which is an essential part of logic and linguistic semantics. In this paper, we present a system that automatically annotates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monotonic_function">monotonicity information</a> based on Universal Dependency parse trees. Our system utilizes surface-level monotonicity facts about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantifier_(logic)">quantifiers</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_item">lexical items</a>, and token-level polarity information. We compared our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>’s performance with existing systems in the literature, including NatLog and ccg2mono, on a small evaluation dataset. Results show that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> outperforms NatLog and ccg2mono.</abstract>
      <url hash="c2a48d21">2021.iwcs-1.12</url>
      <attachment type="Attachment" hash="15ca85bb">2021.iwcs-1.12.Attachment.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>chen-gao-2021-monotonicity</bibkey>
      <award>Outstanding Paper</award>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/eric11eca/Udep2Mono" additional="false">eric11eca/Udep2Mono</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Is that really a question? Going beyond factoid questions in NLP<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Aikaterini-Lida</first><last>Kalouli</last></author>
      <author><first>Rebecca</first><last>Kehlbeck</last></author>
      <author><first>Rita</first><last>Sevastjanova</last></author>
      <author><first>Oliver</first><last>Deussen</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Keim</last></author>
      <author><first>Miriam</first><last>Butt</last></author>
      <pages>132–143</pages>
      <abstract>Research in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> has mainly focused on factoid questions, with the goal of finding quick and reliable ways of matching a query to an answer. However, human discourse involves more than that : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_technology">it</a> contains non-canonical questions deployed to achieve specific communicative goals. In this paper, we investigate this under-studied aspect of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> by introducing a targeted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a>, creating an appropriate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> and providing baseline models of diverse nature. With this, we are also able to generate useful insights on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> and open the way for future research in this direction.</abstract>
      <url hash="4989e886">2021.iwcs-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>kalouli-etal-2021-really</bibkey>
      <award>Outstanding Paper</award>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/kkalouli/rquet" additional="false">kkalouli/rquet</pwccode>
    <title_fr>Est-ce vraiment une question ? Au-delà des questions factuelles en PNL</title_fr>
      <title_ar>هل هذا حقا سؤال؟ تجاوز الأسئلة الواقعية في البرمجة اللغوية العصبية</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Isso é realmente uma pergunta? Indo além das questões factóides na PNL</title_pt>
      <title_es>¿Es realmente una pregunta? Ir más allá de las preguntas factoides en la PNL</title_es>
      <title_ja>それは本当に質問ですか？ NLPにおける事実に基づく質問を超えて</title_ja>
      <title_zh>此真一问乎? 超NLP中事实</title_zh>
      <title_hi>क्या यह वास्तव में एक सवाल है? एनएलपी में तथ्यात्मक प्रश्नों से परे जाना</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Это действительно вопрос? Выход за рамки фактических вопросов в NLP</title_ru>
      <title_ga>An ceist í sin i ndáiríre? Ag dul níos faide ná ceisteanna factoid i NLP</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ეს ნამდვილად კითხვა? Name</title_ka>
      <title_it>E' davvero una domanda? Andare oltre le questioni di fatto nel PNL</title_it>
      <title_hu>Ez tényleg egy kérdés? Túllépni a tényleges kérdéseken az NLP-ben</title_hu>
      <title_el>Είναι αλήθεια ερώτηση; Πέρα από τα πραγματικά ερωτήματα στο NLP</title_el>
      <title_mk>Навистина ли е тоа прашање? Going beyond factoid questions in NLP</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Betulkah itu soalan? Melewati soalan faktoid dalam NLP</title_ms>
      <title_ml>അതൊരു ചോദ്യം തന്നെയാണോ? Going beyond factoid questions in NLP</title_ml>
      <title_kk>Бұл шынымен сұрақ ма? Name</title_kk>
      <title_mt>Is that really a question?  Li jmorru lil hinn mill-mistoqsijiet fattojdi fil-NLP</title_mt>
      <title_no>Er det virkelig eit spørsmål? Går over faktoidspørsmål i NLPName</title_no>
      <title_mn>Энэ үнэхээр асуулт үү? NLP дахь фактоид асуултуудаас гадна</title_mn>
      <title_lt>Ar tai tikras klausimas? Daugiau nei faktiniai klausimai NLP</title_lt>
      <title_ro>Chiar e o întrebare? Depășirea întrebărilor concrete în PNL</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Je li to stvarno pitanje? Prelazi iznad faktoidnih pitanja u NLP-u</title_sr>
      <title_si>ඒක ඇත්තටම ප්‍රශ්නයක්ද? Name</title_si>
      <title_ta>அது உண்மையில் ஒரு கேள்வி? NLP கேள்விகளுக்கு மேல் செல்கிறது</title_ta>
      <title_ur>یہ واقعی ایک سوال ہے؟ NLP میں فکتوئیڈ سوال کے بعد</title_ur>
      <title_pl>To naprawdę pytanie? Wyjście poza faktyczne pytania w NLP</title_pl>
      <title_so>taasi ma dhab tahay su'aal? U socoshada su'aalo ka badan ee NLP</title_so>
      <title_sv>Är det verkligen en fråga? Att gå bortom faktiska frågor i det nationella handlingsprogrammet</title_sv>
      <title_uz>Bu rostdan savol? Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Đó thật sự là một câu hỏi? Vượt xa các câu hỏi về nhân tố NLP.</title_vi>
      <title_da>Er det virkelig et spørgsmål? Ud over faktiske spørgsmål i NLP</title_da>
      <title_nl>Is dat echt een vraag? Verder gaan dan feitelijke vragen in NLP</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Je li to stvarno pitanje? Prelazi iznad faktoidnih pitanja u NLP-u</title_hr>
      <title_de>Ist das wirklich eine Frage? Über faktische Fragen im NLP hinausgehen</title_de>
      <title_bg>Това наистина ли е въпрос? Отвъд фактическите въпроси в НЛП</title_bg>
      <title_id>Apakah itu benar-benar pertanyaan? Melewati pertanyaan faktoid di NLP</title_id>
      <title_ko>이게 정말 문제인가요?NLP의 요소를 뛰어넘는 문제</title_ko>
      <title_fa>اين واقعا يه سوال هست؟ فراتر از سوالات فاکتوئید در NLP</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Ni swali kweli? Kuenda zaidi ya maswali ya ukweli katika NLP</title_sw>
      <title_af>Is dit regtig 'n vraag? Comment</title_af>
      <title_sq>A është kjo vërtet një pyetje? Shkojmë përtej pyetjeve faktike në NLP</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Արդյո՞ք դա իսկապես հարց է: Գնալով ավելի շատ ֆակտոիկական հարցեր ՆԼՊ-ում,</title_hy>
      <title_tr>Bu hakykatdanam soragmy? NLP'da faktoid soraglary öňünden geçmek</title_tr>
      <title_am>ይህ በእውነት ጥያቄ ነውን? Going beyond factoid questions in NLP</title_am>
      <title_bn>এটা কি সত্যিই একটা প্রশ্ন? এনএলপিতে ফ্যাক্টোয়েড প্রশ্নের বাইরে যাচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Je li to stvarno pitanje? Prelazi iznad faktoidnih pitanja u NLP-u</title_bs>
      <title_ca>És realment una pregunta? Allà més enllà de les preguntes de facto en NLP</title_ca>
      <title_az>Bu h톛qiq톛t톛n bir sual edir? NLP'd톛 faktoid suallar캼ndan 칬tr칲</title_az>
      <title_cs>To je opravdu otázka? Překračující faktické otázky v NLP</title_cs>
      <title_et>On see tõesti küsimus? NLP tegelikest küsimustest kaugemale minek</title_et>
      <title_fi>Onko tuo todella kysymys? NLP:n tosiasiallisia kysymyksiä pidemmälle meneminen</title_fi>
      <title_sk>Je to res vprašanje? Prekoračitev dejanskih vprašanj v novem delovnem programu</title_sk>
      <title_ha>Shin wannan wani tambayi ne? Going beyond tambayar faktoid in NLP</title_ha>
      <title_jv>Kuwi tenan seneng persian po ? Gak ono langkung werak-werak gak bakal ning NLP</title_jv>
      <title_he>זו באמת שאלה? לעבור מעבר לשאלות עובדות ב-NLP</title_he>
      <title_bo>འདི་ངོ་མ་རང་གི་དྲི་ཚིག་ཅིག་རེད། NLP ནང་དུ་ཡིག་གནས་ཚུལ་གྱི་རྗེས་སུ་འབྲི་མ་ཐུབ་པ་ལས་</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>ركز البحث في البرمجة اللغوية العصبية بشكل أساسي على أسئلة الحقائق ، بهدف إيجاد طرق سريعة وموثوقة لمطابقة استعلام مع إجابة. ومع ذلك ، فإن الخطاب البشري ينطوي على أكثر من ذلك: فهو يحتوي على أسئلة غير أساسية يتم نشرها لتحقيق أهداف تواصلية محددة. في هذه الورقة ، نحقق في هذا الجانب غير المدروس من البرمجة اللغوية العصبية من خلال تقديم مهمة مستهدفة ، وإنشاء مجموعة مناسبة للمهمة وتقديم نماذج أساسية ذات طبيعة متنوعة. مع هذا ، نحن قادرون أيضًا على تكوين رؤى مفيدة حول المهمة وفتح الطريق للبحث المستقبلي في هذا الاتجاه.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>La investigación en PNL se ha centrado principalmente en cuestiones factoides, con el objetivo de encontrar formas rápidas y fiables de hacer coincidir una consulta con una respuesta. Sin embargo, el discurso humano implica más que eso: contiene preguntas no canónicas desplegadas para lograr objetivos comunicativos específicos. En este artículo, investigamos este aspecto poco estudiado de la PNL mediante la introducción de una tarea específica, la creación de un corpus apropiado para la tarea y la provisión de modelos de referencia de diversa naturaleza. Con esto, también podemos generar información útil sobre la tarea y abrir el camino para futuras investigaciones en esta dirección.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>La recherche en PNL s'est principalement concentrée sur des questions factuelles, dans le but de trouver des moyens rapides et fiables de faire correspondre une requête à une réponse. Cependant, le discours humain implique plus que cela : il contient des questions non canoniques déployées pour atteindre des objectifs de communication spécifiques. Dans cet article, nous étudions cet aspect sous-étudié de la PNL en introduisant une tâche ciblée, en créant un corpus approprié pour la tâche et en fournissant des modèles de base de nature diverse. Grâce à cela, nous sommes également en mesure de générer des informations utiles sur la tâche et d'ouvrir la voie à de futures recherches dans ce sens.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_ja>NLPの研究は、主に事実に基づく質問に焦点を当てており、クエリと回答を一致させる迅速で信頼できる方法を見つけることを目標としています。しかし、人間の議論にはそれ以上のものが含まれています。特定のコミュニケーション目標を達成するために展開された非正統的な質問が含まれています。この論文では、対象を絞ったタスクを導入し、そのタスクに適切なコーパスを作成し、多様な性質のベースラインモデルを提供することによって、NLPのこの研究不足の側面を調査する。これにより、タスクに関する有用な洞察を生み出し、この方向への将来の研究への道を開くこともできます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_pt>A pesquisa em PNL concentrou-se principalmente em questões factóides, com o objetivo de encontrar maneiras rápidas e confiáveis de combinar uma consulta com uma resposta. No entanto, o discurso humano envolve mais do que isso: contém questões não canônicas desdobradas para atingir objetivos comunicativos específicos. Neste artigo, investigamos esse aspecto pouco estudado da PNL introduzindo uma tarefa direcionada, criando um corpus apropriado para a tarefa e fornecendo modelos básicos de natureza diversa. Com isso, também podemos gerar insights úteis sobre a tarefa e abrir caminho para futuras pesquisas nessa direção.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_zh>NLP之论主集于事实,求其速可恃之术,将询与对案相匹。 然则人言之远不止于此:其包非规范也,所以成特定也。 其在本文,引入之务,创立适语料,资异性之基线,以究NLP之未足究也。 有如此,吾亦能有用,为未来于此方究开道路。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>Исследования в NLP в основном сосредоточены на фактических вопросах с целью нахождения быстрых и надежных способов сопоставления запроса с ответом. Однако человеческий дискурс включает в себя нечто большее: он содержит неканонические вопросы, используемые для достижения конкретных коммуникативных целей. В этой статье мы исследуем этот недостаточно изученный аспект NLP, вводя целевую задачу, создавая соответствующий корпус для задачи и предоставляя базовые модели разнообразного характера. С этим, мы также можем произвести полезные проницательности на задаче и открыть путь для будущих исследований в этом направлении.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_hi>एनएलपी में अनुसंधान ने मुख्य रूप से तथ्यात्मक प्रश्नों पर ध्यान केंद्रित किया है, जिसमें उत्तर के लिए एक क्वेरी से मिलान करने के त्वरित और विश्वसनीय तरीके खोजने के लक्ष्य के साथ। हालांकि, मानव प्रवचन में इससे अधिक शामिल है: इसमें विशिष्ट संचार लक्ष्यों को प्राप्त करने के लिए तैनात गैर-विहित प्रश्न शामिल हैं। इस पेपर में, हम एक लक्षित कार्य शुरू करके, कार्य के लिए एक उपयुक्त कॉर्पस बनाकर और विविध प्रकृति के बेसलाइन मॉडल प्रदान करके एनएलपी के इस अंडर-स्टडी किए गए पहलू की जांच करते हैं। इसके साथ, हम कार्य पर उपयोगी अंतर्दृष्टि उत्पन्न करने और इस दिशा में भविष्य के अनुसंधान के लिए रास्ता खोलने में भी सक्षम हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Dhírigh taighde in NLP go príomha ar cheisteanna factoideacha, agus é mar sprioc bealaí tapa iontaofa a aimsiú chun ceist a mheaitseáil le freagra. Mar sin féin, tá níos mó ná sin i gceist le dioscúrsa daonna: tá ceisteanna neamhchanónacha ann a úsáidtear chun sainspriocanna cumarsáide a bhaint amach. Sa pháipéar seo, déanaimid imscrúdú ar an ngné seo de NLP nach ndéantar staidéar uirthi trí thasc spriocdhírithe a thabhairt isteach, corpas cuí a chruthú don tasc agus samhlacha bonnlíne de chineál ilghnéitheach a sholáthar. Leis seo, táimid in ann léargais úsáideacha a ghiniúint ar an tasc agus an bealach a oscailt do thaighde amach anseo sa treo seo.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η έρευνα στο ΝΛΠ έχει επικεντρωθεί κυρίως σε πραγματικές ερωτήσεις, με στόχο την εύρεση γρήγορων και αξιόπιστων τρόπων αντιστοίχισης ενός ερωτήματος σε μια απάντηση. Ωστόσο, ο ανθρώπινος λόγος περιλαμβάνει περισσότερα από αυτό: περιέχει μη κανονικές ερωτήσεις που αναπτύσσονται για την επίτευξη συγκεκριμένων επικοινωνιακών στόχων. Σε αυτή την εργασία, διερευνούμε αυτή την υπομελετημένη πτυχή της εισάγοντας μια στοχευμένη εργασία, δημιουργώντας ένα κατάλληλο σώμα για την εργασία και παρέχοντας βασικά μοντέλα διαφορετικής φύσης. Με αυτό, είμαστε επίσης σε θέση να παράγουμε χρήσιμες γνώσεις σχετικά με το έργο και να ανοίξουμε το δρόμο για μελλοντική έρευνα προς αυτή την κατεύθυνση.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az NLP kutatása elsősorban tényleges kérdésekre összpontosított, azzal a céllal, hogy gyors és megbízható módszereket találjon a lekérdezés és a válasz összehangolására. Az emberi diskurzus azonban ennél többet is magában foglal: konkrét kommunikációs célok elérésére alkalmazott nem kanonikus kérdéseket tartalmaz. Ebben a tanulmányban egy célzott feladat bevezetésével, a feladathoz megfelelő korpusz létrehozásával és különböző jellegű alapvető modellek biztosításával vizsgáljuk az NLP ezt alul tanulmányozott aspektusát. Ezzel hasznos betekintéseket tudunk generálni a feladatról, és megnyitjuk az utat a jövőbeli kutatások előtt ebben az irányban.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>NLP-ში პროცემები ძირითად ფექტოიდის კითხვებისთვის კონუქტირებულია, მიზეზით წინ და დარწმუნებელი გზების შესაძლებლობა, რომლებიც საპასუხისთვის შე მაგრამ ადამიანის დისკურსი უფრო მეტი იქნება, რომელიც არ არის კანონიკური კითხვები, რომელიც გამოყენებულია სპექტიკური კომუნიკაციური მიზეზების მიზეზ ამ დოკუნეში, ჩვენ განსხვავებთ NLP-ის განსხვავებული აპექტირების შესახებ მისაღებული რაოდენობას, შექმნა სწორი კოპუუსი რაოდენობისთვის და განსხვავებული ნაწილის ბაზალური მოდელ ამ შემთხვევაში ჩვენ შეგვიძლია შევქმნა გამოსახულებელი მონაცემების შესახებ და გახსნა მომავალეთ შესწავლობას ამ მხარეს.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_kk>NLP зерттеулерінің негізінде фактоид сұрақтарына көздеген, сұрақтарды жауапқа сәйкес келетін және сенімді жолдарды табу мақсатымен көздеген. Бірақ адамдардың дискуссиясы бұдан артық болады: бұл жерде контактты мақсаттарды жеткізу үшін каноникалық емес сұрақтар бар. Бұл қағазда, NLP бағытталған аспекті зерттеп, мақсатты тапсырманы келтіріп, тапсырма үшін қорпус құрып, әртүрлі түрлі тәуелдердің негізгі үлгілерін береміз. Бұл және біз тапсырманың пайдалы түсініктерін жасап, келесі зерттеулердің жолын осы бағытта аша аламыз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>NLP moksliniai tyrimai daugiausia buvo susiję su faktiniais klausimais, siekdami rasti greitus ir patikimus būdus, kaip atsakyti į klausimą. Tačiau žmogaus kalba apima daugiau nei tai: joje pateikiami ne kanoniški klausimai, skirti konkretiems komunikaciniams tikslams pasiekti. Šiame dokumente tiriame šį nepakankamai išnagrinėtą NLP aspektą, nustatydami tikslinę užduotį, sukuriant tinkamą užduoties korpusą ir teikiant įvairių rūšių pagrindinius modelius. Taigi mes taip pat galime gauti naudingą informaciją apie užduotį ir atverti kelią būsimiems moksliniams tyrimams šia kryptimi.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Penelitian dalam NLP terutama fokus pada soalan faktoid, dengan tujuan mencari cara yang cepat dan boleh dipercayai untuk sepadan pertanyaan dengan jawapan. Namun, pembicaraan manusia melibatkan lebih dari itu: ia mengandungi soalan bukan-canonical yang digunakan untuk mencapai tujuan komunikatif tertentu. Dalam kertas ini, kami menyelidiki aspek NLP yang dibawah kajian ini dengan memperkenalkan tugas sasaran, mencipta korpus yang sesuai untuk tugas dan menyediakan model dasar sifat yang berbeza. Dengan ini, kita juga mampu menghasilkan pandangan berguna mengenai tugas ini dan membuka jalan untuk kajian masa depan dalam arah ini.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Ir-riċerka fil-NLP iffukat l-aktar fuq mistoqsijiet fattojdi, bil-għan li jinstabu modi rapidi u affidabbli biex titqabbel mistoqsija ma’ tweġiba. Madankollu, id-diskors uman jinvolvi aktar minn dak: fih mistoqsijiet mhux kanoniċi użati biex jinkisbu għanijiet komunikattivi speċifiċi. F’dan id-dokument, ninvestigaw dan l-aspett mhux studjat biżżejjed tal-NLP billi nintroduċu kompitu mmirat, inħolqu korpus xieraq għall-kompitu u nipprovdu mudelli ta’ bażi ta’ natura differenti. B’dan, nistgħu niġġeneraw ukoll għarfien utli dwar il-kompitu u niftħu t-triq għar-riċerka futura f’din id-direzzjoni.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>НЛП-ын судалгаагаар ихэнхдээ фактоид асуултуудад анхаарлаа хандуулж, хурдан, итгэлтэй арга олох зорилго юм. Гэхдээ хүн төрөлхтний яриа үүнээс илүү их байдаг: энэ нь тодорхой харилцааны зорилгоор хүрэхэд ашиглаж буй газрын асуулт бий. Энэ цаасан дээр бид NLP-ын судалгааны доор судалсан асуудлыг зорилготой ажлыг тайлбарлаж, ажлын тулд хэрэгтэй корпус бүтээж, олон төрлийн байгалийн суурь шугам загваруудыг өгдөг. Үүнээс ч мөн бид ажил дээр хэрэгтэй ойлголт бий болгож ирээдүйн судалгааны аргыг нээж чадна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_it>La ricerca nel PNL si è concentrata principalmente su domande concrete, con l'obiettivo di trovare modi rapidi e affidabili per abbinare una domanda a una risposta. Tuttavia, il discorso umano comporta molto di più: contiene domande non canoniche utilizzate per raggiungere obiettivi comunicativi specifici. In questo articolo, esaminiamo questo aspetto poco studiato della PNL introducendo un compito mirato, creando un corpus appropriato per il compito e fornendo modelli di base di diversa natura. Con questo siamo anche in grado di generare utili approfondimenti sul compito e aprire la strada alla ricerca futura in questa direzione.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Истражувањата во НЛП се фокусираа главно на фактоидните прашања, со цел да се најдат брзи и доверливи начини да се совпаѓаат прашањата со одговорот. Сепак, човечкиот дискурс вклучува повеќе од тоа: содржи неканонични прашања распоредени за постигнување специфични комуникациски цели. Во овој документ, го истражуваме овој недостасуван аспект на НЛП со воведување на целна задача, создавање соодветен корпус за задачата и обезбедување на основни модели од различна природа. Со ова, исто така, можеме да генерираме корисни информации за задачата и да го отвориме патот за идното истражување во оваа насока.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>NLP-ലെ പരിശോധന പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട ഫാക്ടോയിഡ് ചോദ്യങ്ങളില്‍ ശ്രദ്ധിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. ഉത്തരം ചോദ്യം ചേര്‍ക്കുന്നതിന് വേഗത്തി എന്നാലും മനുഷ്യരുടെ സംസാരം അതിനെക്കാള്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ ചേര്‍ന്നിരിക്കുന്നു; അതില്‍ പ്രത്യേകിച്ചുള്ള വിവരങ്ങള്‍ പ്രാപ ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ നിരീക്ഷിക്കുന്ന ഈ പ്രഭാതത്തെ പരിശോധിക്കുന്നു. നിരീക്ഷിക്കുന്ന ജോലി പരിചയപ്പെടുത്തുന്നതിനാല്‍, ജോലിക്ക് ഒര ഇതുകൊണ്ട് നമുക്ക് ജോലിയില്‍ പ്രയോജനപ്പെടുത്താന്‍ കഴിയും, ഭാവിയുടെ ഗവേഷണത്തിന് വഴി തുറക്കാനും കഴിയും.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_ro>Cercetarea în PNL s-a concentrat în principal pe întrebări de fapt, cu scopul de a găsi modalități rapide și fiabile de a potrivi o interogare cu un răspuns. Cu toate acestea, discursul uman implică mai mult decât atât: conține întrebări non-canonice desfășurate pentru atingerea unor obiective comunicative specifice. În această lucrare, investigăm acest aspect substudiat al PNL prin introducerea unei sarcini țintite, crearea unui corpus adecvat pentru sarcină și furnizarea de modele de bază de natură diversă. Prin aceasta, suntem capabili, de asemenea, să generăm perspective utile asupra sarcinii și să deschidem calea pentru cercetări viitoare în această direcție.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>Badania w NLP koncentrowały się głównie na pytaniach faktycznych, mając na celu znalezienie szybkich i rzetelnych sposobów dopasowania zapytania do odpowiedzi. Jednak dyskurs ludzki obejmuje więcej niż to: zawiera pytania niekanoniczne wykorzystywane do osiągnięcia konkretnych celów komunikacyjnych. W niniejszym artykule badamy ten niezbadany aspekt NLP poprzez wprowadzenie zadania ukierunkowanego, stworzenie odpowiedniego korpusu do tego zadania oraz dostarczenie modeli bazowych o zróżnicowanym charakterze. Dzięki temu jesteśmy również w stanie generować przydatne informacje na temat zadania i otworzyć drogę do przyszłych badań w tym kierunku.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>Istraživanje u NLP uglavnom se fokusiralo na faktoidna pitanja, sa ciljem pronalaženja brzog i pouzdanog način a odgovaranja pitanja odgovoru. Međutim, ljudski diskurs uključuje više od toga: sadrži nekanička pitanja koja se raspoređuju za postizanje specifičnih komunikacijskih ciljeva. U ovom papiru istražujemo ovaj podstudirani aspekt NLP uvođenjem ciljnog zadatka, stvaranjem odgovarajućeg korpusa za zadatak i pružanjem početnih modela raznolikosti prirode. Sa ovim možemo takođe stvoriti korisne uvide o zadatku i otvoriti put za buduće istraživanje u ovom pravcu.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_no>Forskning i NLP har hovudsakelig fokusert på faktoidspørsmål, med målet å finna rask og tiltruleg måtar å passa med ein spørsmål til ein svar. Men menneske diskursar inneheld meir enn det: det inneheld ikkje-kanoniske spørsmål som er utført for å oppnå spesifikke kommunikasjonskål. I denne papiret investigaterer vi denne understudierte aspekten av NLP ved å introdusera eit målrett oppgåve, oppretta eit passende korpus for oppgåva og tilbyr baselinjemodeller av ulike natur. Med dette kan vi også laga nyttig innsikt på oppgåva og opna måten for framtidige forskning i denne retninga.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sv>Forskning inom NLP har främst fokuserat på faktaundersökningar, med målet att hitta snabba och tillförlitliga sätt att matcha en fråga med ett svar. Mänsklig diskurs innebär dock mer än så: den innehåller icke-kanoniska frågor som används för att uppnå specifika kommunikativa mål. I denna uppsats undersöker vi denna understuderade aspekt av NLP genom att introducera en riktad uppgift, skapa en lämplig corpus för uppgiften och tillhandahålla baslinjemodeller av varierande karaktär. Med detta kan vi också generera användbara insikter om uppgiften och öppna vägen för framtida forskning i denna riktning.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>NLP වල පරීක්ෂණය ප්‍රශ්නයක් විශේෂයෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් විතරයි, ඉක්මනින් හා විශ්වාසයින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් උත්තර දෙ ඒත් මිනිස්සු කතාවක් ඒකෙන් වඩා වැඩියි: ඒකෙන් විශේෂ සම්බන්ධතාවක් ලක්ෂණය කරන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා. මේ පත්තරේ අපි NLP ගේ අඩු අධ්‍යානය කරපු ප්‍රශ්නයක් පරීක්ෂා කරනවා, ලක්ෂණ කාර්යයක් අරගෙන, වෙනස් ස්වභාවිතයේ පරීක්ෂණ ම මේකෙන් අපිට පුළුවන් වෙන්න පුළුවන් වෙන්නේ වැඩේ ප්‍රයෝජනය සහ අනාගතයේ පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා මාර්ගය අරගෙන</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Baaritaanka NLP wuxuu ugu horeyn ku kalsoonaaday su'aalaha faktoid, waxaana la jeedaa in la helo qaab dhaqso oo aamin ah oo la dhigo su'aal uu jawaabo. Si kastaba ha ahaatee hadalka dadweynaha waxey ka badan tahay: waxay ku jirtaa su'aalo aan aheyn, oo loo soo bandhigay in la gaadho goal gaar ah oo la xidhiidha. Qoraalkan waxaynu baaraynaa dhinacan NLP ee lagu akhriyey, si a an u soo bandhignayno shaqo la hago, oo aan u abuurno koob u eg shaqada, waxaana sameynaa samooyin dabiicadda kala duduwan. Taas darteed waxaynu awoodi karnaa inaannu sameyno waxyaabo faa’iido leh oo ku saabsan shaqada, waxaana furi karnaa waddada waxbarashada mustaqbalka ah ee halkan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ur>NLP میں تحقیق اکثر فاکتوئیڈ سؤال پر تمرکز کیا گیا ہے، ایک جواب کے مطابق سریع اور قابل اطمینان کے طریقے پیدا کرنے کا موقع ہے. لیکن انسان کی گفتگو اس سے زیادہ ہے: اس میں غیر کانونیک سوالات ہیں جو مخصوص معاملات کا موقع پہنچانے کے لئے استعمال کئے جاتے ہیں. اس کاغذ میں ہم نے NLP کی اس کم تحقیق کی حصہ کی تحقیق کی، ایک مقررہ کام کو معلوم کرنے کے ذریعہ، کام کے لئے ایک مناسب کورپوس بنایا اور مختلف مختلف طبیعت کے بنیادی لین نمونڈوں کو پیش کرنے کے لئے۔ اس کے ساتھ ہم بھی کام کے بارے میں فائدہ بصیرت پیدا کر سکتے ہیں اور اس طرح آگے کی تحقیق کے لئے راہ کھول سکتے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>NLP-ல் உள்ள ஆராய்ச்சி முக்கியமாக கேள்விகளை கவனம் செலுத்தி வைத்துள்ளது, விடைக்கு ஒரு கேள்வியை பொருந்தும் விரைவாகவும் நம எனினும், மனித பேச்சு அதைவிட அதிகமாக உள்ளது: குறிப்பிட்ட தொடர்பு கூட்டும் இலக்கு இந்த காகிதத்தில், நாம் இந்த குறிப்பில் ஆய்வு படிக்கப்பட்ட புள்ளியை ஆராய்ச்சி செய்கிறோம் இலக்கு செயலை முதலிக்கிறது, பணிக்கு ஒரு பொரு இதைக் கொண்டு, நாம் பணியில் பயனுள்ள உணர்வுகளை உருவாக்க முடியும் மற்றும் இந்த திசையில் எதிர்கால ஆய்வுகளுக்கு</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Name Lekin, inson suhbati bundan ko'proq o'rganishga ega bo'ladi: Bu yerda ma'lum aloqalarni bajarish uchun qo'llanmagan savollar mavjud. Bu qogʻozda, biz bu NLP qidirilgan qidirilgan qidirishni boshqaramiz, vazifa uchun juda yetarli kopus yaratish va har xil asosiy modellarini yaratish mumkin. Bu bilan biz vazifa uchun foydali narsalarni yaratib kelamiz va kelajakdagi tafitiyatning yo'lini ochish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Nghiên cứu tại Nchọc (NLP) chủ yếu nghiên cứu về các câu hỏi Factionless, mục đích tìm kiếm cách nhanh chóng và đáng tin cậy để khớp một câu trả lời. Tuy nhiên, ngôn luận con người có liên quan nhiều hơn thế: nó chứa các câu hỏi không đúng tiêu chuẩn được đặt ra để đạt mục tiêu giao tiếp cụ thể. Trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi nghiên cứu một khía cạnh chưa được nghiên cứu của ngôn ngữ NLP bằng cách nhập một nhiệm vụ mục tiêu, tạo ra một tập thể phù hợp cho nhiệm vụ và cung cấp các mô hình cơ bản đa dạng. Bằng cách này, chúng ta cũng có thể cung cấp những nhận thức hữu ích về nhiệm vụ và mở đường cho nghiên cứu tương lai theo hướng này.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Изследванията в НЛП са фокусирани основно върху фактоидни въпроси, с цел намиране на бързи и надеждни начини за свързване на заявка с отговор. Човешкият дискурс обаче включва повече от това: съдържа неканонични въпроси, разгърнати за постигане на конкретни комуникативни цели. В настоящата статия изследваме този недостатъчно проучен аспект на НЛП чрез въвеждане на целева задача, създаване на подходящ корпус за задачата и предоставяне на базови модели с разнообразен характер. С това можем да генерираме полезни прозрения за задачата и да отворим пътя за бъдещи изследвания в тази посока.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Forskning i NLP har hovedsageligt fokuseret på faktiske spørgsmål med det formål at finde hurtige og pålidelige måder at matche en forespørgsel med et svar. Men den menneskelige diskurs involverer mere end det: Den indeholder ikke-kanoniske spørgsmål, der anvendes til at nå specifikke kommunikative mål. I denne artikel undersøger vi dette underundersøgte aspekt af NLP ved at introducere en målrettet opgave, skabe et passende korpus til opgaven og levere basismodeller af forskellig karakter. Med dette kan vi også generere nyttig indsigt i opgaven og åbne vejen for fremtidig forskning i denne retning.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Istraživanje u NLP-u uglavnom se fokusiralo na faktoidna pitanja, s ciljem pronaći brz i pouzdan način odgovaranja pitanja odgovoru. Međutim, ljudska diskusija uključuje više od toga: sadrži neokanalna pitanja koja se raspoređuju za postizanje specifičnih komunikacijskih ciljeva. U ovom papiru istražujemo ovaj podstudirani aspekt NLP uvođenjem ciljnog zadatka, stvaranjem odgovarajućeg korpusa za zadatak i pružanjem početnih modela raznolikosti prirode. S ovim možemo također stvoriti korisne uvide o zadatku i otvoriti način za buduće istraživanje u ovom smjeru.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Die Forschung im NLP hat sich hauptsächlich auf faktische Fragen konzentriert, mit dem Ziel, schnelle und zuverlässige Wege zu finden, um eine Anfrage mit einer Antwort abzugleichen. Der menschliche Diskurs beinhaltet jedoch mehr als das: Er enthält nicht-kanonische Fragen, die zur Erreichung spezifischer kommunikativer Ziele eingesetzt werden. In diesem Beitrag untersuchen wir diesen zu wenig untersuchten Aspekt von NLP, indem wir eine zielgerichtete Aufgabe einführen, ein geeignetes Korpus für die Aufgabe erstellen und Basismodelle unterschiedlicher Natur bereitstellen. Damit sind wir auch in der Lage, nützliche Erkenntnisse über die Aufgabe zu generieren und den Weg für zukünftige Forschung in diese Richtung zu öffnen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_nl>Onderzoek in NLP heeft zich voornamelijk gericht op factoïde vragen, met als doel snel en betrouwbaar manieren te vinden om een vraag aan een antwoord te koppelen. Het menselijk discours omvat echter meer dan dat: het bevat niet-canonieke vragen die worden ingezet om specifieke communicatieve doelen te bereiken. In dit artikel onderzoeken we dit onderbestudeerde aspect van NLP door een gerichte taak te introduceren, een passend corpus voor de taak te creëren en basismodellen van diverse aard te bieden. Hiermee kunnen we ook nuttige inzichten genereren over de taak en de weg openen voor toekomstig onderzoek in deze richting.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Penelitian di NLP terutama fokus pada pertanyaan faktoid, dengan tujuan menemukan cara yang cepat dan dapat dipercaya untuk cocok pertanyaan dengan jawaban. Namun, pembicaraan manusia melibatkan lebih dari itu: mengandung pertanyaan yang tidak canonical yang disediakan untuk mencapai tujuan komunikatif spesifik. Dalam kertas ini, kami menyelidiki aspek yang belum dipelajari dari NLP dengan memperkenalkan tugas yang ditujukan, menciptakan tubuh yang sesuai untuk tugas ini dan menyediakan model dasar dari alam yang berbeda. Dengan ini, kita juga mampu menghasilkan pandangan berguna pada tugas ini dan membuka jalan untuk penelitian masa depan dalam arah ini.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Utafiti wa NLP umejikita zaidi kwenye maswali ya kiukweli, na lengo la kutafuta njia za haraka na yenye kuaminika ya kuunganisha swali kwa jibu. Hata hivyo, mazungumzo ya binadamu yanahusisha zaidi ya hilo: ina maswali yasiyo na makanika yaliyotumiwa ili kupata malengo maalum ya mawasiliano. Katika karatasi hii, tunachunguza suala hili la NLP kwa kuanzisha kazi yenye lengo, kutengeneza viungo sahihi kwa ajili ya kazi hiyo na kutoa mifano ya msingi ya asili tofauti. Kwa hili, tunaweza pia kutengeneza mitazamo yenye ufanisi katika kazi hiyo na kufungua njia ya utafiti wa baadaye katika mwelekeo huu.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_ko>NLP의 연구는 주로 인자 문제에 집중되었는데, 그 목적은 조회와 답안을 일치시킬 수 있는 신속하고 믿을 만한 방법을 찾는 것이다.그러나 인류의 언어는 이런 것들에 그치지 않는다. 그것은 비규범적인 문제를 포함하고 특정한 교제 목표를 실현하는 데 쓰인다.본고에서 우리는 목표 임무를 도입하고 임무에 적합한 어료 라이브러리를 만들고 서로 다른 성질의 기선 모델을 제공함으로써 NLP라는 연구가 부족한 점을 연구했다.이 점이 있으면 우리도 이 임무에 대해 유용한 견해를 가지게 되고 이 방향의 미래 연구를 위해 길을 열 수 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>تحقیقات در NLP بیشتر روی سوالات فاکتوئید تمرکز شده است، با هدف پیدا کردن راه های سریع و قابل اطمینان با یک سوال به یک جواب. ولی سخنرانی انسان بیشتر از آن شامل است: در آن سوال غیر کانونیکی است که برای رسیدن هدف‌های ارتباطی خاص استفاده می‌شود. در این کاغذ، ما این قسمت زیر مطالعه NLP را تحقیق می‌کنیم با توجه به یک کار هدف، یک کورپوس مناسب برای کار و مدل‌های پایین طبیعت مختلف را می‌سازیم. با این موضوع، ما هم قادر به تولید مشاهده های مفید در این کار هستیم و راه برای تحقیقات آینده در این مسیر باز کنیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>NLP araştırmalary hakykatdanam faktoid soraglary, çalt we güýçli bir soragy jogaba eşitmek üçin maksady bilen fokus edildi. Ýöne adamlaryň gürrüňleri şonuň ýagdaýyndan köp bolup geçirýär: munyň içinde spesalist maksadlary ýetmek üçin kanonik ýok soraglary bar. Bu kagyzda, NLP'iň azyndaky okuwçysyny barlap maksady buýruk etmäge, işiň üçin ýeterli korpusy bejermek we dürli tebigatyň esasy nusgalaryny saýlamak üçin bardyk. Bu şekilde biz hem zadyň üstünde faydaly pikirleri döredip, gelejekde barlag üçin bu yönde ýoly açyp bileris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Kërkimi në NLP është përqëndruar kryesisht në pyetje faktike, me qëllim të gjejë mënyra të shpejtë dhe të besueshme për të përputhur një pyetje me një përgjigje. Megjithatë, diskursi njerëzor përfshin më shumë se kaq: përmban çështje jo-kanonike të vendosura për të arritur qëllime të veçanta komunikuese. Në këtë letër, ne hetojmë këtë aspekt të nënstudiuar të NLP duke paraqitur një detyrë të synuar, duke krijuar një korpus të përshtatshëm për detyrën dhe duke ofruar modele bazë të natyrës së ndryshme. Me këtë, ne jemi gjithashtu në gjendje të gjenerojmë kuptime të dobishme mbi detyrën dhe të hapim rrugën për kërkimet e ardhshme në këtë drejtim.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>የNLP ምርመራ በመጀመሪያው የውይይት ጥያቄዎችን ለመግኘት ፈጥኖ እና የታመነ ጥያቄን ለመግኘት አግኝቷል፡፡ ነገር ግን የሰው ንግግር ከዚያ የበለጠ ነው፡፡ በዚህ ካላት፣ የNLP ስራትን በመግለጽ እናሳውቃለን፡፡ በዚህ ምክንያት ለስራ የሚጠቅመውን ማስታወቂያዎች እና ወደዚህ መንገድ ለመፍጠር መንገድን እንከፍታለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>ՆԼՊ-ի ուսումնասիրությունները հիմնականում կենտրոնացել են փակտոիդ հարցերի վրա, որպեսզի արագ և վստահելի միջոցներ գտնեն հարցը պատասխանի հետ համապատասխանելու համար: Այնուամենայնիվ, մարդկային խոսակցությունը ավելի շատ է ներառում, այն պարունակում է ոչ կանոնիկ հարցեր, որոնք օգտագործվում են հատուկ հաղորդակցման նպատակների հասնելու համար: Այս թղթի մեջ մենք ուսումնասիրում ենք ՆԼՊ-ի այս թերաուսումնասիրելի ասպեկտը՝ ներկայացնելով նպատակային առաջադրանք, ստեղծելով հարմար կորպոս առաջադրանքի համար և տրամադրելով տարբեր բնության հիմնական մոդելներ: Այս միջոցով մենք նաև կարող ենք ստեղծել օգտակար ընկալումներ այս խնդրի մասին և բացել ճանապարհը ապագա հետազոտությունների համար այս ուղղությամբ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>NLP-də araştırma əslində faktoid suallarına odaqlanmış, bir cevaba hızlı və güvenilir yollar tapmaq məqsədilə. Lakin insan danışması bundan daha çox daxil edir: bunun içində müəyyən müzakirçi məqsədlərini yerinə yetirmək üçün istifadə edilən canonik olmayan suallar var. Bu kağıtda, NLP'in bu a şağı təhsil edilmiş aspektini təşkil edib, iş üçün uyğun bir korpus yaratdıq və müxtəlif təhsil modellərini təmin edirik. Bununla, biz də bu işdə faydalı anlayışlar yaratmaq və gələcək araştırmaların yolunu açmaq bacarırıq.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_af>Research in NLP het heeltemal fokus op faktoide vrae, met die doel van vinnige en betroubare maniere van ooreenstemming van 'n navraag na' n antwoord te vind. Maar menslike diskursie het meer as dit aangehandel: dit bevat nie-kanoniese vrae wat gebruik word om spesifieke kommunikasiewe doels te bereik. In hierdie papier is ons hierdie ondersteunde aspekt van NLP ondersoek deur 'n doelgemaakte taak te introduseer, skep 'n geskikte korpus vir die taak en verskaf basisline modele van verskeie natuur. Met hierdie is ons ook in staat om nuttige insigte te genereer op die taak en die manier oop vir toekomstige ondersoek in hierdie rigting.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_bn>এনএলপিতে গবেষণা মূলত ফ্যাক্টোইড প্রশ্নের উপর মনোযোগ প্রদান করেছে, যার উদ্দেশ্যে একটি প্রশ্নের উত্তরের মিলিত রাস্তা খুঁজে বের করার However, human discourse involves more than that: it contains non-canonical questions deployed to achieve specific communicative goals.  এই কাগজটিতে আমরা এনএলপির নীচে গবেষণা বিষয়টি তদন্ত করি একটি লক্ষ্যবস্তুতে পরিচালিত করার মাধ্যমে, কাজের জন্য একটি যথাযথ কোর্পাস তৈরি করে এবং বিভি এর মাধ্যমে আমরা কাজের ব্যাপারে কার্যকর দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি তৈরি করতে পারি এবং ভবিষ্যতের গবেষণার পথ খুলতে পারি।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Istraživanje u NLP uglavnom se fokusiralo na faktoidna pitanja, s ciljem pronaći brze i pouzdane načine odgovaranja pitanja odgovoru. Međutim, ljudski diskurs uključuje više od toga: sadrži nekanička pitanja koja se raspoređuju za postizanje specifičnih komunikacijskih ciljeva. U ovom papiru istražujemo ovaj podstudirani aspekt NLP uvođenjem ciljnog zadatka, stvaranjem odgovarajućeg korpusa za zadatak i pružanjem početnih modela raznolikosti prirode. Sa ovim možemo također stvoriti korisne uvide o zadatku i otvoriti put za buduće istraživanje u ovom smjeru.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>La recerca en NLP s'ha centrat principalment en preguntes factoides, amb l'objectiu de trobar maneres ràpides i fiables de comparar una pregunta amb una resposta. Però el discurs humà implica més que això: conté preguntes no canòniques desplegades per aconseguir objectius comunicatius específics. En aquest paper investigam aquest aspecte poc estudiat de la NLP introduint una tasca mirada, creant un cos apropiat per a la tasca i proporcionant models de base de naturalesa diversa. With this, we are also able to generate useful insights on the task and open the way for future research in this direction.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Výzkum v NLP se zaměřil především na faktické otázky s cílem nalézt rychlé a spolehlivé způsoby, jak přiřadit dotaz k odpovědi. Lidský diskurs však zahrnuje více než to: obsahuje nekanonické otázky nasazené k dosažení konkrétních komunikačních cílů. V tomto článku zkoumáme tento nedostatečně studovaný aspekt NLP zavedením cíleného úkolu, vytvořením vhodného korpusu pro daný úkol a poskytnutím základních modelů různorodé povahy. Díky tomu jsme také schopni generovat užitečné poznatky o úkolu a otevřít cestu pro budoucí výzkum v tomto směru.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Uuringud NLP-s on keskendunud peamiselt faktilistele küsimustele, eesmärgiga leida kiired ja usaldusväärsed viisid päringu ja vastuse ühitamiseks. Inimdiskursus hõlmab aga enamat kui seda: see sisaldab mittekoonilisi küsimusi, mida rakendatakse konkreetsete kommunikatsioonieesmärkide saavutamiseks. Käesolevas dokumendis uurime uue õppekava alauuritud aspekti, tutvustades sihipärase ülesande, luues ülesande jaoks sobiva korpuse ja pakkudes erinevaid baasmudeleid. Sellega saame luua ka kasulikke ülevaateid ülesande kohta ja avada tee tulevastele teadusuuringutele selles suunas.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>NLP:n tutkimus on keskittynyt p채채asiassa faktoisiin kysymyksiin, joiden tavoitteena on l철yt채채 nopeita ja luotettavia tapoja yhdist채채 kysely vastaukseen. Ihmisen diskurssiin liittyy kuitenkin muutakin: se sis채lt채채 ei-kanonisia kysymyksi채, joita k채ytet채채n tiettyjen viestint채tavoitteiden saavuttamiseksi. T채ss채 artikkelissa tutkimme t채t채 v채h채n tutkittua NLP:n n채k철kulmaa ottamalla k채ytt철철n kohdennettu teht채v채, luomalla teht채v채채n sopiva korpus ja tarjoamalla erilaisia perusmalleja. N채in pystymme my철s tuottamaan hy철dyllist채 tietoa teht채v채st채 ja avaamaan tiet채 tulevaan tutkimukseen t채h채n suuntaan.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>Raziskave v NLP so se osredotočile predvsem na dejanska vprašanja, s ciljem iskanja hitrih in zanesljivih načinov usklajevanja poizvedbe z odgovorom. Toda človeški diskurz vključuje več kot to: vsebuje nekonska vprašanja, namenjena doseganju specifičnih komunikacijskih ciljev. V prispevku raziskujemo ta premalo preučen vidik NLP z uvedbo ciljno nalogo, ustvarjanjem ustreznega korpusa za nalogo in zagotavljanjem osnovnih modelov različne narave. S tem lahko ustvarimo tudi koristne vpoglede na nalogo in odpremo pot za prihodnje raziskave v tej smeri.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>@ action: button A lokacin da mazaɓa na mutane yana da mafiya wannan: Yanã da wasu maswali na kanoniki da aka aiko su zuwa ga sãmun goalin da aka ƙayyade wa'azi. In a cikin wannan takardan, Munã yin ƙidãya wannan ƙarani da aka karanta na NLP da ya introduce wani aikin wanda aka yi goani, yana halitta wata nau'i mai daidai wa aikin da kuma kuma yana samar da misãlai masu basalin na daban-daban. Daga wannan, tuna iya iya ƙididdige gannai masu amfani a kan aikin kuma mu buɗe hanyar da za'a sanar da littãfin bakwai a cikin wannan direction.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>NLP ནང་གི་འཚོལ་ཞིབ་ཀྱིས་དངོས་གནས་ཚུལ་འདྲི་ཚིག་དང་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་མཉམ་དུ་བཞག་ཡོད། ཡིན་ནའང་། མི་ཚོའི་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་འདི་ལས་བརྗོད་ཡོད། འོག་གི་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་འོང་ཚོས་NLP ཡི་གནས་ཚུལ་ལ་ལས་གནད་སྡུད་འདི་ལྟ་ཞིབ་བྱས་ནས་དམིགས་འབེབས་བྱས་པ་ཞིག་གསར་འཛུགས་བྱས་པའི་ འདིས་དང་། ང་ཚོས་བྱ་ཚིག་དང་། མ་འོངས་པའི་འཚོལ་ཞིབ་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ཁ་ཕྱེ་ཐུབ་པ་དེ་རེད།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>Research in NLP has mainly focused on factoid questions, with the goal of finding quick and reliable ways of matching a query to an answer.  בכל אופן, דיבור אנושי מעורב יותר מזה: הוא מכיל שאלות לא קנוניות שפותחות כדי להשיג מטרות תקשורת ספציפיות. In this paper, we investigate this under-studied aspect of NLP by introducing a targeted task, creating an appropriate corpus for the task and providing baseline models of diverse nature.  עם זה, אנחנו גם מסוגלים ליצור תובנות שימושיות על המשימה ולפתח את הדרך למחקר עתיד בכיוון הזה.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Rasané nang NLP dadi sing dikondisikno kanggo gampang Actual Nanging, kepulangan langkung wigatining luwih dumadhi iki: iso dianggap luwih dumadhi sing gak bakal terus nggawe nguasai perusahaan kelapakno Nang paper iki, kéné ujarane sakjane jenis-ujaran Aspek NLP iki dadi ngawehke nggawe barang nggawe lan ijol-ijolan cara sing nggawe barang sampek nggawe sistem sing apik dadi iki bakal terus lanjut sampek tanggal nggawe barang sampek. Ngomongé iki, kéné iso nggawe éntuk bantêr luwih dumadhi kanggo nggawe barang nggawe barang kanggo urêh dumadhi iki.</abstract_jv>
      </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Breeding Fillmore’s Chickens and Hatching the Eggs : Recombining Frames and Roles in Frame-Semantic Parsing<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>illmore’s Chickens and Hatching the Eggs: Recombining Frames and Roles in Frame-Semantic Parsing</title>
      <author><first>Gosse</first><last>Minnema</last></author>
      <author><first>Malvina</first><last>Nissim</last></author>
      <pages>155–165</pages>
      <abstract>Frame-semantic parsers traditionally predict <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Predicate_(grammar)">predicates</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frame_(artificial_intelligence)">frames</a>, and semantic roles in a fixed order. This paper explores the ‘chicken-or-egg’ problem of interdependencies between these components theoretically and practically. We introduce a flexible BERT-based sequence labeling architecture that allows for predicting frames and roles independently from each other or combining them in several ways. Our results show that our setups can approximate more complex traditional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a>’ performance, while allowing for a clearer view of the interdependencies between the pipeline’s components, and of how frame and role prediction models make different use of BERT’s layers.</abstract>
      <url hash="e8fd313a">2021.iwcs-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>minnema-nissim-2021-breeding</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Large-scale text pre-training helps with dialogue act recognition, but not without <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fine-tuning">fine-tuning</a></title>
      <author><first>Bill</first><last>Noble</last></author>
      <author><first>Vladislav</first><last>Maraev</last></author>
      <pages>166–172</pages>
      <abstract>We use dialogue act recognition (DAR) to investigate how well BERT represents utterances in dialogue, and how fine-tuning and large-scale pre-training contribute to its performance. We find that while both the standard BERT pre-training and pretraining on dialogue-like data are useful, task-specific fine-tuning is essential for good performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="96175fb0">2021.iwcs-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>noble-maraev-2021-large</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/opensubtitles">OpenSubtitles</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Variation in framing as a function of temporal reporting distance</title>
      <author><first>Levi</first><last>Remijnse</last></author>
      <author><first>Marten</first><last>Postma</last></author>
      <author><first>Piek</first><last>Vossen</last></author>
      <pages>228–238</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we measure variation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Framing_(social_sciences)">framing</a> as a function of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Framing_(social_sciences)">foregrounding</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Framing_(social_sciences)">backgrounding</a> in a co-referential corpus with a range of temporal distance. In one type of experiment, frame-annotated corpora grouped under event types were contrasted, resulting in a ranking of frames with typicality rates. In contrasting between publication dates, a different ranking of frames emerged for documents that are close to or far from the event instance. In the second type of analysis, we trained a diagnostic classifier with frame occurrences in order to let it differentiate documents based on their temporal distance class (close to or far from the event instance). The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classifier_(linguistics)">classifier</a> performs above chance and outperforms <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> with words.</abstract>
      <url hash="8b299bc5">2021.iwcs-1.22</url>
      <bibkey>remijnse-etal-2021-variation</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/cltl/hdd_analysis" additional="false">cltl/hdd_analysis</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>