<collection id="2021.sigtyp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Computational Typology and Multilingual NLP</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Vylomova</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Salesky</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sabrina</first><last>Mielke</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Gabriella</first><last>Lapesa</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ritesh</first><last>Kumar</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Harald</first><last>Hammarstr&#246;m</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ivan</first><last>Vuli&#263;</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Korhonen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Roi</first><last>Reichart</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Edoardo Maria</first><last>Ponti</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ryan</first><last>Cotterell</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="9497be23">2021.sigtyp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="52a84d6b">2021.sigtyp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sigtyp-2021-typology</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title><fixed-case>OTEANN</fixed-case>: Estimating the Transparency of Orthographies with an Artificial Neural Network</title>
      <author><first>Xavier</first><last>Marjou</last></author>
      <pages>1&#8211;9</pages>
      <abstract>To transcribe spoken language to written medium, most alphabets enable an unambiguous sound-to-letter rule. However, some writing systems have distanced themselves from this simple concept and little work exists in Natural Language Processing (NLP) on measuring such distance. In this study, we use an Artificial Neural Network (ANN) model to evaluate the transparency between written words and their pronunciation, hence its name Orthographic Transparency Estimation with an ANN (OTEANN). Based on datasets derived from Wikimedia dictionaries, we trained and tested this model to score the percentage of false predictions in phoneme-to-grapheme and grapheme-to-phoneme translation tasks. The scores obtained on 17 orthographies were in line with the estimations of other studies. Interestingly, the model also provided insight into typical mistakes made by learners who only consider the phonemic rule in reading and writing.</abstract>
      <url hash="e6fba9f1">2021.sigtyp-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigtyp-1.1</doi>
      <bibkey>marjou-2021-oteann</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/marxav/oteann3" additional="true">marxav/oteann3</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/oteannv3">OTEANNv3</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Improving Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis via Conditional Language Adversarial Nets</title>
      <author><first>Hemanth</first><last>Kandula</last></author>
      <author><first>Bonan</first><last>Min</last></author>
      <pages>32&#8211;37</pages>
      <abstract>Sentiment analysis has come a long way for high-resource languages due to the availability of large annotated corpora. However, it still suffers from lack of training data for low-resource languages. To tackle this problem, we propose Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), an end-to-end neural architecture for cross-lingual sentiment analysis without cross-lingual supervision. CLAN differs from prior work in that it allows the adversarial training to be conditioned on both learned features and the sentiment prediction, to increase discriminativity for learned representation in the cross-lingual setting. Experimental results demonstrate that CLAN outperforms previous methods on the multilingual multi-domain Amazon review dataset. Our source code is released at https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract>
      <url hash="f666fcb2">2021.sigtyp-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigtyp-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>kandula-min-2021-improving</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan" additional="false">hemanthkandula/clan</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Anlirika: An <fixed-case>LSTM</fixed-case>&#8211;<fixed-case>CNN</fixed-case> Flow Twister for Spoken Language Identification</title>
      <author><first>Andreas</first><last>Scherbakov</last></author>
      <author><first>Liam</first><last>Whittle</last></author>
      <author><first>Ritesh</first><last>Kumar</last></author>
      <author><first>Siddharth</first><last>Singh</last></author>
      <author><first>Matthew</first><last>Coleman</last></author>
      <author><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Vylomova</last></author>
      <pages>145&#8211;148</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents Anlirika&#8217;s submission to SIGTYP 2021 Shared Task on Robust Spoken Language Identification. The task aims at building a robust system that generalizes well across different domains and speakers. The training data is limited to a single domain only with predominantly single speaker per language while the validation and test data samples are derived from diverse dataset and multiple speakers. We experiment with a neural system comprising a combination of dense, convolutional, and recurrent layers that are designed to perform better generalization and obtain speaker-invariant representations. We demonstrate that the task in its constrained form (without making use of external data or augmentation the train set with samples from the validation set) is still challenging. Our best system trained on the data augmented with validation samples achieves 29.9% accuracy on the test data.</abstract>
      <url hash="57088f18">2021.sigtyp-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigtyp-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>scherbakov-etal-2021-anlirika</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>