<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.iwpt">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 17th International Conference on Parsing Technologies and the IWPT 2021 Shared Task on Parsing into Enhanced Universal Dependencies (IWPT 2021)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Stephan</first><last>Oepen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kenji</first><last>Sagae</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Reut</first><last>Tsarfaty</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Gosse</first><last>Bouma</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Djamé</first><last>Seddah</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Daniel</first><last>Zeman</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="05bb805f">2021.iwpt-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="bbff3db1">2021.iwpt-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>iwpt-2021-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>A Falta de Pan, Buenas Son Tortas : The Efficacy of Predicted UPOS Tags for Low Resource UD Parsing<fixed-case>UPOS</fixed-case> Tags for Low Resource <fixed-case>UD</fixed-case> Parsing</title>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Anderson</last></author>
      <author><first>Mathieu</first><last>Dehouck</last></author>
      <author><first>Carlos</first><last>Gómez-Rodríguez</last></author>
      <pages>78–83</pages>
      <abstract>We evaluate the efficacy of predicted UPOS tags as input features for dependency parsers in lower resource settings to evaluate how treebank size affects the impact tagging accuracy has on parsing performance. We do this for real low resource universal dependency treebanks, artificially low resource data with varying treebank sizes, and for very small treebanks with varying amounts of augmented data. We find that predicted UPOS tags are somewhat helpful for low resource treebanks, especially when fewer fully-annotated trees are available. We also find that this positive impact diminishes as the amount of data increases.</abstract>
      <url hash="dbd1e8db">2021.iwpt-1.8</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.iwpt-1.8</doi>
      <bibkey>anderson-etal-2021-falta</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Multilingual Dependency Parsing for Low-Resource African Languages : Case Studies on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bambara_language">Bambara</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolof_language">Wolof</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yoruba_language">Yoruba</a><fixed-case>A</fixed-case>frican Languages: Case Studies on <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>ambara, <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>olof, and <fixed-case>Y</fixed-case>oruba</title>
      <author><first>Cheikh M. Bamba</first><last>Dione</last></author>
      <pages>84–92</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methodology</a> for syntactic knowledge transfer between high-resource languages to extremely low-resource languages. The methodology consists in leveraging multilingual BERT self-attention model pretrained on large datasets to develop a multilingual multi-task model that can predict Universal Dependencies annotations for three African low-resource languages. The UD annotations include universal part-of-speech, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphology_(linguistics)">morphological features</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lemma_(morphology)">lemmas</a>, and dependency trees. In our experiments, we used multilingual word embeddings and a total of 11 Universal Dependencies treebanks drawn from three high-resource languages (English, French, Norwegian) and three low-resource languages (Bambara, Wolof and Yoruba). We developed various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> to test specific language combinations involving <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_contact">contemporary contact languages</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genetic_relationship_(linguistics)">genetically related languages</a>. The results of the experiments show that multilingual models that involve high-resource languages and low-resource languages with contemporary contact between each other can provide better results than combinations that only include unrelated languages. As far genetic relationships are concerned, we could not draw any conclusion regarding the impact of language combinations involving the selected low-resource languages, namely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolof_language">Wolof</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yoruba_language">Yoruba</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="b63a84ca">2021.iwpt-1.9</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.iwpt-1.9</doi>
      <bibkey>dione-2021-multilingual</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>COMBO : A New Module for EUD Parsing<fixed-case>COMBO</fixed-case>: A New Module for <fixed-case>EUD</fixed-case> Parsing</title>
      <author><first>Mateusz</first><last>Klimaszewski</last></author>
      <author><first>Alina</first><last>Wróblewska</last></author>
      <pages>158–166</pages>
      <abstract>We introduce the COMBO-based approach for EUD parsing and its implementation, which took part in the IWPT 2021 EUD shared task. The goal of this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> is to parse raw texts in 17 languages into Enhanced Universal Dependencies (EUD). The proposed approach uses COMBO to predict UD trees and EUD graphs. These <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(discrete_mathematics)">structures</a> are then merged into the final EUD graphs. Some EUD edge labels are extended with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Case_(linguistics)">case information</a> using a single language-independent expansion rule. In the official evaluation, the solution ranked fourth, achieving an average ELAS of 83.79 %. The source code is available at https://gitlab.clarin-pl.eu/syntactic-tools/combo.</abstract>
      <url hash="922fdc8d">2021.iwpt-1.16</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.iwpt-1.16</doi>
      <bibkey>klimaszewski-wroblewska-2021-combo</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Splitting EUD Graphs into Trees : A Quick and Clatty Approach<fixed-case>EUD</fixed-case> Graphs into Trees: A Quick and Clatty Approach</title>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Anderson</last></author>
      <author><first>Carlos</first><last>Gómez-Rodríguez</last></author>
      <pages>167–174</pages>
      <abstract>We present the system submission from the FASTPARSE team for the EUD Shared Task at IWPT 2021. We engaged in the task last year by focusing on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Efficiency">efficiency</a>. This year we have focused on experimenting with new ideas on a limited time budget. Our system is based on splitting the EUD graph into several <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tree_(graph_theory)">trees</a>, based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">linguistic criteria</a>. We predict these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tree_(graph_theory)">trees</a> using a sequence-labelling parser and combine them into an EUD graph. The results were relatively poor, although not a total disaster and could probably be improved with some polishing of the system’s rough edges.</abstract>
      <url hash="3798df83">2021.iwpt-1.17</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.iwpt-1.17</doi>
      <bibkey>anderson-gomez-rodriguez-2021-splitting</bibkey>
    <title_es>Dividir los gráficos de EUD en árboles: un enfoque rápido y ágil</title_es>
      <title_pt>Dividindo Gráficos EUD em Árvores: Uma Abordagem Rápida e Clatty</title_pt>
      <title_fr>Scinder les graphes EUD en arbres : une approche rapide et claire</title_fr>
      <title_ar>تقسيم الرسوم البيانية EUD إلى أشجار: منهج سريع وفظي</title_ar>
      <title_ja>EUDグラフをツリーに分割する：クイックで繊細なアプローチ</title_ja>
      <title_zh>分 EUD 图拆为树:疾速复杂之法</title_zh>
      <title_hi>पेड़ों में EUD रेखांकन विभाजन: एक त्वरित और Clatty दृष्टिकोण</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Разделение графиков EUD на деревья: быстрый и неустойчивый подход</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Graif EUD a roinnt ina gCrainn: Cur Chuige Tapa Soiléir</title_ga>
      <title_ka>EUD გრაფიების გაყოფა ხეებში: ბრძელი და კლატის მიღება</title_ka>
      <title_hu>EUD grafikonok fákra történő felosztása: egy gyors és zavaros megközelítés</title_hu>
      <title_it>Dividere i grafici EUD in alberi: un approccio rapido e clatty</title_it>
      <title_kk>EUD графикасын бұтақтарда бөлу: Жедел және бұрышты жағдай</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Разделувањето на графите на ЕУД во дрвја: Брз и скриен пристап</title_mk>
      <title_lt>EUD grafikų suskirstymas į medžius: greitas ir griežtas metodas</title_lt>
      <title_ml>EUD ഗ്രാഫ്സുകള്‍ മരങ്ങളിലേക്ക് വിഭജിക്കുന്നു:</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Pembahagian Graf EUD ke Pokok: Pendekatan Cepat dan Terpaksa</title_ms>
      <title_no>Del EUD- grafen i tre: ein rask og klatttilgang</title_no>
      <title_pl>Podział wykresów EUD na drzewa: szybkie i ostre podejście</title_pl>
      <title_el>Χωρίζοντας τα γραφήματα της EUD σε δέντρα: Μια γρήγορη και σκληρή προσέγγιση</title_el>
      <title_sr>Razdvajanje EUD Grafa u Drvo: Brzi i Clatty Približavanje</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Împărțirea graficilor EUD în copaci: o abordare rapidă și clată</title_ro>
      <title_so>Qaybisashada EUD-ka dhirta: A Quick and Clatty Approach</title_so>
      <title_si>EUD ග්‍රාෆ්ස් වර්ගයක් විතරයි: ඉක්මනින් සහ ක්ලැටි ලගින්න</title_si>
      <title_mt>It-tqassim tal-grafiċi tal-EUD f’Siġar: Approċċ Rapidu u Mwaħħal</title_mt>
      <title_mn>EUD графикийг мод руу хувааж байна: Хурдан, Клатти ойртох</title_mn>
      <title_sv>Dela upp EUD-grafer i träd: En snabb och kladdig strategi</title_sv>
      <title_ta>EUD வரைப்படங்களை மரங்களுக்கு பிரிக்கிறது: A Quick and Clatty Approach</title_ta>
      <title_ur>EUD گراف درختوں میں تقسیم کرتے ہیں: ایک سریع اور کلتی قریب</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Bộ phân chia đồ họa của ECD vào cây: A Quick and Clatty tiếp cận</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_da>Opdeling af EUD-grafer i træer: En hurtig og klattet tilgang</title_da>
      <title_hr>Razdvajanje EUD grafa u drveće: Brzi i brzi približavanje</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Разделяне на графики на дървета: бърз и шумен подход</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Het splitsen van EUD-grafieken in bomen: een snelle en clatty aanpak</title_nl>
      <title_ko>EUD 그림을 트리로 분할: 빠르고 간결한 방법</title_ko>
      <title_fa>جدا کردن گرافهای EUD به درختان: نزدیک سریع و سریع</title_fa>
      <title_de>Aufteilung von EUD-Diagrammen in Bäume: Ein schneller und kluger Ansatz</title_de>
      <title_id>Membagi Graf EUD ke Pohon: Sebuah Pendekatan Cepat</title_id>
      <title_sw>Kugawanya EUD Graphs katika miti: A Quick and Clatty Approach</title_sw>
      <title_tr>EUD ködlemeleri agaçlara bölmek: Häzir we Girişik</title_tr>
      <title_af>Skei EUD Grafies in Boom: ' n Vinnige en Clatty toegang</title_af>
      <title_am>gradients-action</title_am>
      <title_sq>Shpallja e grafikave të EUD në pemë: një qasje e shpejtë dhe e ngushtë</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Էուդի գրաֆիկների բաժանելը ծառերի մեջ՝ արագ և խճճճ մոտեցում</title_hy>
      <title_az>䕕䐠䝲慦楫泉饲楮椠懄齡捬慲愠拃뙬쎼얟擃뱲淉饫㨠䣄녺泄넠盉餠叉饴牡晬쒱⁙慸쒱湬쒱焊</title_az>
      <title_ca>Dividir els gràfics EUD en arbres: Una aproximació ràpida i clagada</title_ca>
      <title_bn>গাছে EUD গ্রাফ বিভক্ত করা হচ্ছে: একটি দ্রুত এবং ক্ল্যাটি যাওয়া</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Razdvajanje EUD Grafa u Drvo: Brzi i brzi približavanje</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Rozdělení grafů EUD na stromy: rychlý a drsný přístup</title_cs>
      <title_fi>EUD-kaavioiden jakaminen puihin: nopea ja räikeä lähestymistapa</title_fi>
      <title_et>EUD graafikute jagamine puudeks: kiire ja kindel lähenemisviis</title_et>
      <title_jv>Ngubah batir</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Razdelitev grafikonov EUD na drevesa: hiter in trmast pristop</title_sk>
      <title_he>פצלת גרפים של EUD לעצים: גישה מהירה וקלאטית</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>EUD Graphs in Splitting into Trees: A Quick and Clatty Approach</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم تقديم النظام من فريق FASTPARSE للمهمة المشتركة EUD في IWPT 2021. لقد انخرطنا في المهمة العام الماضي من خلال التركيز على الكفاءة. ركزنا هذا العام على تجربة أفكار جديدة بميزانية محدودة الوقت. يعتمد نظامنا على تقسيم الرسم البياني EUD إلى عدة أشجار ، بناءً على المعايير اللغوية. نتوقع هذه الأشجار باستخدام محلل تصنيف التسلسل ودمجها في رسم بياني EUD. كانت النتائج ضعيفة نسبيًا ، على الرغم من أنها ليست كارثة كاملة ويمكن تحسينها على الأرجح مع بعض تلميع الحواف الخشنة للنظام.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos a submissão do sistema da equipe FASTPARSE para a Tarefa Compartilhada EUD no IWPT 2021. Nos engajamos na tarefa no ano passado com foco na eficiência. Este ano, nos concentramos em experimentar novas ideias com um orçamento de tempo limitado. Nosso sistema é baseado na divisão do gráfico EUD em várias árvores, com base em critérios linguísticos. Prevemos essas árvores usando um analisador de rotulagem de sequência e as combinamos em um gráfico EUD. Os resultados foram relativamente ruins, embora não um desastre total e provavelmente poderiam ser melhorados com algum polimento das arestas do sistema.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Nous présentons la soumission du système de l'équipe FASTPARSE pour la tâche partagée EUD à l'IWPT 2021. Nous nous sommes engagés dans cette tâche l'année dernière en mettant l'accent sur l'efficacité. Cette année, nous nous sommes concentrés sur l'expérimentation de nouvelles idées avec un budget limité dans le temps. Notre système est basé sur la division du graphique EUD en plusieurs arbres, en fonction de critères linguistiques. Nous prévoyons ces arbres à l'aide d'un analyseur d'étiquetage de séquence et les combinons dans un graphique EUD. Les résultats ont été relativement médiocres, bien que ce ne soit pas un désastre total et pourraient probablement être améliorés grâce à un certain polissage des aspérités du système.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos el envío del sistema del equipo de FASTPARSE para la tarea compartida de EUD en IWPT 2021. El año pasado nos dedicamos a la tarea centrándonos en la eficiencia. Este año nos hemos centrado en experimentar con nuevas ideas con un presupuesto de tiempo limitado. Nuestro sistema se basa en dividir el gráfico EUD en varios árboles, en función de criterios lingüísticos. Predecimos estos árboles mediante un analizador de etiquetado de secuencias y los combinamos en un gráfico EUD. Los resultados fueron relativamente malos, aunque no fueron un desastre total y probablemente podrían mejorarse con un poco de pulido de los bordes ásperos del sistema.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>当社は、IWPT 2021でEUD共有タスクのためにFASTPARSEチームから提出されたシステムを提示します。私たちは昨年、効率性に焦点を当ててその仕事に従事した。今年は、期間限定の予算で新しいアイデアを試すことに焦点を当てています。当社のシステムは、言語学的基準に基づいて、EUDグラフをいくつかの木に分割することに基づいています。シーケンスラベル構文解析器を使用してこれらの木を予測し、それらをEUDグラフに組み合わせます。全くの災害ではなかったものの、比較的貧弱な結果であり、システムの粗いエッジを磨くことで改善することができたと思われる。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>展IWPT 2021于FASTPARSE团队,共EUD其统。 去岁专于效率,以成其事。 今年专注有限时。 我们的系统根据言语准将EUD图拆分为几树。 以序表记解析器占之,组合成一EUD图。 虽非全难,可以对系统粗抛光改也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम आईडब्ल्यूपीटी 2021 में ईयूडी साझा कार्य के लिए फास्टपार्स टीम से सिस्टम सबमिशन पेश करते हैं। हमने दक्षता पर ध्यान केंद्रित करके पिछले साल कार्य में लगे हुए थे। इस साल हमने सीमित समय के बजट पर नए विचारों के साथ प्रयोग करने पर ध्यान केंद्रित किया है। हमारी प्रणाली भाषाई मानदंडों के आधार पर कई पेड़ों में EUD ग्राफ को विभाजित करने पर आधारित है। हम एक अनुक्रम-लेबलिंग पार्सर का उपयोग करके इन पेड़ों की भविष्यवाणी करते हैं और उन्हें एक ईयूडी ग्राफ में जोड़ते हैं। परिणाम अपेक्षाकृत खराब थे, हालांकि कुल आपदा नहीं थी और शायद सिस्टम के किसी न किसी किनारों के कुछ चमकाने के साथ सुधार किया जा सकता था।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Мы представляем представление системы от команды FASTPARSE для совместной задачи EUD на IWPT 2021. В прошлом году мы занялись решением этой задачи, сосредоточив внимание на эффективности. В этом году мы сосредоточились на экспериментировании с новыми идеями при ограниченном бюджете времени. Наша система основана на разделении графа EUD на несколько деревьев на основе лингвистических критериев. Мы прогнозируем эти деревья с помощью анализатора маркировки последовательностей и объединяем их в EUD-график. Результаты были относительно низкими, хотя и не являлись полной катастрофой, и, вероятно, их можно было бы улучшить с помощью некоторой полировки необработанных краев системы.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid i láthair an aighneacht chórais ó fhoireann FASTPARSE don Tasc Comhroinnte EUD ag IWPT 2021. Chuamar i ngleic leis an tasc anuraidh trí dhíriú ar éifeachtúlacht. I mbliana dhíríomar ar smaointe nua a thástáil ar bhuiséad teoranta ama. Tá ár gcóras bunaithe ar ghraf EUD a roinnt ina roinnt crann, bunaithe ar chritéir theangeolaíocha. Déanaimid tuar ar na crainn seo trí úsáid a bhaint as parsálaí lipéadaithe seichimh agus cuirimid le chéile iad i ngraf EUD. Bhí na torthaí sách bocht, cé nach tubaiste iomlán iad agus is dócha go bhféadfaí iad a fheabhsú le roinnt snasta ar imill gharbh an chórais.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo la presentazione del sistema da parte del team FASTPARSE per l'EUD Shared Task a IWPT 2021. L'anno scorso ci siamo impegnati in questo compito concentrandoci sull'efficienza. Quest'anno ci siamo concentrati sulla sperimentazione di nuove idee con un budget di tempo limitato. Il nostro sistema si basa sulla suddivisione del grafico EUD in diversi alberi, sulla base di criteri linguistici. Prevediamo questi alberi usando un parser di sequenza-labeling e li combiniamo in un grafico EUD. I risultati sono stati relativamente scarsi, anche se non un disastro totale e probabilmente potrebbero essere migliorati con una certa lucidatura dei bordi ruvidi del sistema.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_hu>Bemutatjuk a FASTPARSE csapat rendszer benyújtását az EUD megosztott feladatra az IWPT 2021-en. Tavaly a hatékonyságra összpontosítva vállaltuk a feladatot. Idén arra összpontosítottunk, hogy korlátozott időköltségvetéssel kísérletezzünk új ötleteket. Rendszerünk az EUD gráf több fára történő felosztásán alapul, nyelvi kritériumok alapján. Ezeket a fákat egy szekvencia-jelölő elemző segítségével jósoljuk meg, és egy EUD grafikonba kombináljuk. Az eredmény viszonylag gyenge volt, bár nem volt teljes katasztrófa, és valószínűleg javítható a rendszer durva éleinek némi polírozásával.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ სისტემის შემდეგ FASTPARSE ჯგუფიდან EUD გაყოფილი დავალებისთვის IWPT 2021-ში. მთელი წლის ჩვენ დავაკეთებდით სამუშაოში ეფექტიურებაზე. ამ წლის ჩვენ ექსპერიმენტისთვის ახალი იდეების განსაზღვრებული დროის ბიზეტისთვის გავაკეთებთ. ჩვენი სისტემა EUD გრაფიკის გაყოფილი რამდენიმე ხედებში, ლენგურისტიკური კრიტერიტებზე დაბაზიან. ჩვენ განვიწყებთ ეს ხეები, რომლებიც შემდეგ მარტივის პანელერის გამოყენებთ და EUD გრაფიკაში შემდეგ შემდეგ შემდეგ. პვჱსლრართრვ ბწჳა პაჱლთფნჲ ბვჱბჲპნთ, მაგრამ ნვ ჟა ოყლნა კაჱარპარა თ მჲზვ ეა ბთევ ოჲ-ეჲბპვ ჟ ნწკაკგთ ოჲლთჱაუთ ნა ჟთჟრვმარა.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_mk>Го претставуваме системското поднесување од тимот ФАСТПАРС за заедничката задача на ЕУД на IWPT 2021 година. Минатата година се вклучивме во задачата со фокусирање на ефикасноста. Оваа година се фокусиравме на експериментирање со нови идеи на ограничен временски буџет. Нашиот систем е базиран на поделба на графикот на ЕУД на неколку дрва, базиран на јазички критериуми. Ги предвидуваме овие дрвја користејќи секвенциски анализатор и ги комбинираме во граф на ЕУД. The results were relatively poor, although not a total disaster and could probably be improved with some polishing of the system's rough edges.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami memperkenalkan penghantaran sistem dari pasukan FASTPARSE untuk Tugas Berkongsi EUD di IWPT 2021. Kami terlibat dalam tugas tahun lalu dengan fokus pada efisiensi. This year we have focused on experimenting with new ideas on a limited time budget.  Sistem kita berdasarkan membahagi graf EUD ke beberapa pokok, berdasarkan kriteria bahasa. Kami meramalkan pokok-pokok ini menggunakan penghurai penanda urutan dan menggabungkannya ke dalam graf EUD. Hasilnya agak lemah, walaupun bukan bencana yang sama sekali dan mungkin boleh diperbaiki dengan beberapa pencucian pinggir kasar sistem.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>നമ്മള്‍ ഫാസ്റ്റ്പാര്‍സ് ടീമില്‍ നിന്നും സിസ്റ്റം സമ്മാനിക്കുന്നു. യൂഡ് പങ്കുചേര്‍ത്ത ടാസ്കിന് വേണ്ടി യൂ കഴിഞ്ഞ വര്‍ഷം നമ്മള്‍ ജോലിയില്‍ ചേര്‍ന്നിരുന്നു. അതിന്റെ ശ്രേഷ്ഠത്തിന് ശ്രദ്ധ കാണിച്ചു. ഈ വര്‍ഷം നമ്മള്‍ പുതിയ ആശയങ്ങള്‍ പരീക്ഷിക്കുന്നതിനെപ്പറ്റി ശ്രദ്ധിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. നിര്‍ണിതമായ സമയ ബ നമ്മുടെ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്താണ് ഇയുഡി ഗ്രാഫ് പല മരങ്ങളിലേക്കും വേര്‍പെടുത്തുന്നത്. ഭാഷ ക്രിയ We predict these trees using a sequence-labelling parser and combine them into an EUD graph.  അതിന്റെ ഫലങ്ങള്‍ വളരെ ദരിദ്രനായിരുന്നു, ഒരു മൊത്തം ദുരിതം അല്ലാതെങ്കിലും, സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ കഠിനമായ ഭാഗങ്ങളില്‍ കുറച്ച</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε την υποβολή συστήματος από την ομάδα FASTPARSE για την κοινή εργασία EUD στην IWPT 2021. Αναλάβαμε το έργο πέρυσι εστιάζοντας στην αποτελεσματικότητα. Φέτος έχουμε επικεντρωθεί στον πειραματισμό με νέες ιδέες σε περιορισμένο χρονικό προϋπολογισμό. Το σύστημά μας βασίζεται στη διάσπαση του γραφήματος σε διάφορα δέντρα, με βάση γλωσσικά κριτήρια. Προβλέπουμε αυτά τα δέντρα χρησιμοποιώντας έναν αναλυτή ετικετών ακολουθίας και τα συνδυάζουμε σε ένα γράφημα EUD. Τα αποτελέσματα ήταν σχετικά φτωχά, αν και δεν ήταν ολοκληρωτική καταστροφή και θα μπορούσαν πιθανώς να βελτιωθούν με κάποια στίλβωση των τραχιών άκρων του συστήματος.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_mn>Бид системийн захиралдаа EUD хуваалцаагүй ажил 2021 оны FASTPARSE багийнхаа багийнхаа дараа илтгэнэ. Өнгөрсөн жил бид ажил дээр үр дүнтэй байдлыг анхаарлаа оролцсон. Энэ жил бид хязгаарлагдсан цагийн төсөл дээр шинэ санаануудыг туршилтад анхаарсан. Бидний систем EUD графикийг хэд хэдэн мод хувааж, хэлний шаардлагатай. Бид эдгээр модыг дарааллын маркингийн хуваагч ашиглан EUD график руу холбоотой гэж таамаглаж байна. Үүний үр дүнд харьцангуй ядуу байсан. Гэхдээ бүх гамшгууд биш ч, системийн хэцүү хэсэгт сайжруулж болох юм.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nippreżentaw is-sottomissjoni tas-sistema mit-tim FASTPARSE għall-Kompitu Konġunt tal-EUD fl-IWPT 2021. Is-sena l-oħra impenjna ruħna fil-kompitu billi ffokajna fuq l-effiċjenza. Din is-sena ffukajna fuq l-esperimentazzjoni b’ideat ġodda fuq baġit ta’ żmien limitat. Is-sistema tagħna hija bbażata fuq it-tqassim tal-graff tal-EUD f’diversi siġar, abbażi ta’ kriterji lingwistiċi. Aħna nipprevedixxu dawn is-siġar bl-użu ta’ analizzatur tat-tikkettar tas-sekwenza u ngħaqduhom f’grafika tal-EUD. Ir-riżultati kienu relattivament dgħajfa, għalkemm mhumiex diżastru totali u probabbilment jistgħu jittejbu b’xi tisfija tat-truf mhux raffinat tas-sistema.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_kk>Біз жүйелік жұмыс ішіндегі EUD ортақтастырылған тапсырманың FASTPARSE командасынан келтіріп тұрмыз 2021 жылы IWPT. Өткен жыл біз тапсырмаға көмектесу үшін көмектесдік. Бұл жыл біз жаңа идеяларды шектелген уақыт бюджетіне тәжірибеге көмектесдік. Біздің жүйеміз EUD графикасын бірнеше ағаш бөлігіне негізделген, лингвистикалық критерияларға негізделген. Біз бұл ағаштарды реттеу жарлығын талдап, EUD графикасына біріктіреміз. Нәтижелер сәйкес кедейлі болды, бірақ бұл жалпы жеңіл емес және жүйеңіздің күшті шектерінің бірнеше жақсартылуы мүмкін.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Pateikiame FASTPARSE grupės pateiktą sistemą ESD bendrai užduotims vykdyti 2021 m. IWPT. Praėjusiais metais atlikome užduotį sutelkdami dėmesį į veiksmingumą. Šiais metais daugiausia dėmesio skyrėme eksperimentams su naujomis idėjomis dėl riboto laiko biudžeto. Mūsų sistema grindžiama ESD grafiko padalijimu į keletą medžių, remiantis kalbiniais kriterijais. Mes prognozuojame šiuos medžius naudojant sekos ženklinimo analizatorių ir sujungiame juos į EUD grafiką. Rezultatai buvo palyginti prasti, nors ne visiška nelaimė ir tikriausiai galėtų būti pagerinti šiek tiek poliškus kietuosius sistemos kraštus.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ro>Vă prezentăm depunerea sistemului din partea echipei FASTPARSE pentru misiunea partajată EUD la IWPT 2021. Ne-am angajat în această sarcină anul trecut, concentrându-ne pe eficiență. Anul acesta ne-am concentrat pe experimentarea ideilor noi pe un buget limitat de timp. Sistemul nostru se bazează pe divizarea graficului EUD în mai mulți copaci, pe criterii lingvistice. Prezicem acești copaci folosind un parser de etichetare secvențială și îi combinăm într-un grafic EUD. Rezultatele au fost relativ slabe, deși nu au fost un dezastru total și ar putea fi probabil îmbunătățite cu o anumită lustruire a marginilor aspre ale sistemului.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>Przedstawiamy zgłoszenie systemowe zespołu FASTPARSE do wspólnego zadania EUD na IWPT 2021. W zeszłym roku zaangażowaliśmy się w to zadanie skupiając się na efektywności. W tym roku skupiliśmy się na eksperymentowaniu z nowymi pomysłami w ograniczonym budżecie czasowym. Nasz system opiera się na podzieleniu wykresu EUD na kilka drzew, w oparciu o kryteria językowe. Przewidujemy te drzewa za pomocą parsera znakowania sekwencji i łączymy je w wykres EUD. Wyniki były stosunkowo słabe, choć nie były całkowitą katastrofą i prawdopodobnie mogłyby zostać poprawione poprzez trochę polerowania szorstkich krawędzi systemu.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_so>Waxaannu nidaamka ka soo dhiibnaa kooxda FASTPARSE ee shaqada wadanka EUD ee IWPT 2021. sanadkii dambe waxaynu shaqada ku qabannay kalsoonaanno faa’iidada. Sannadan waxaynu ku kalsoonaannay baaritaanka fikrada cusub oo ku saabsan bajeti waqti cayiman. nidaamkayagu wuxuu ku saleysan yahay ku kala qeybin karaha EUD oo ku saleysan qeybaha luqada. Waxaynu horumarinaynaa geedahan oo lagu isticmaalayo baaritaanka labelinta, waxaana ku soo bandhijinaynaa xarafta EUD. Midhihiisu waxay ahaayeen miskiin, in kastoo uusan dhamaan dhibaato, waxaana laga yaabaa in lagu beddeli karo meelaha habka adag ee nidaamka.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer systemoppføringa frå FASTPARSE-gruppa for EUD-delt oppgåve i IWPT 2021. Vi har starta i oppgåva siste år ved å fokusera på effektivitet. I året har vi fokusert på eksperimentering med nye idear på eit begrenset tidsbbudsjet. Systemet vårt er basert på å dele EUD-grafen i fleire tre, basert på lingviske kriterier. Vi forventar disse tråda ved å bruka ein sekvensmerkelapp og kombinere dei til ein EUD-graf. Resultatet var relativt fattig, men ikkje ein totalt katastrof og kunne sannsynlegvis forbedrast med nokre polisering av vanskelige kantar i systemet.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo podatke sustava iz ekipe FASTPARSE za zajednički zadatak EUD na IWPT 2021. godini. Prošle godine smo se uključili u zadatak fokusiranjem na efikasnost. Ove godine smo se fokusirali na eksperimentiranje sa novim idejama na ograničeni vremenski budžet. Naš sistem je baziran na razdvajanju EUD grafika na nekoliko drveæa na temelju jezičkih kriterija. Predviđamo ove drveće koristeći analizatora označavanja sekvence i kombinujemo ih u EUD grafik. Rezultati su bili relativno siromašni, iako nisu potpuna katastrofa i vjerojatno bi mogli biti poboljšani s a nekim poliranjem teških ivica sistema.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>EUD பகிர்ந்த பணிக்கான FASTPARSE குழுவில் இருந்து அமைப்பு முறைமையை நாம் காண்பிக்கிறோம். நாங்கள் கடந்த வருடத்தில் பணியில் செயல்படுத்தினோம் விளைவுகளை கவனத்தில் கவனம் செலுத்தினோம். இந்த வருடத்தில் நாம் ஒரு வரம்பு நேர பரிசோதனையில் புதிய ய யோசனைகளைச் சோதித்து கவனம் செலுத்தினோம். எங்கள் அமைப்பு EUD வரைப்படத்தை பல மரங்களில் பிரித்து, மொழிமை நிறுவனங்களை அடிப்படையில் உள்ளது. நாம் இந்த மரங்களை தொடர்ந்து வரிப்படத்தை பயன்படுத்தி தொகுதி மற்றும் அவற்றை EUD வரைப்படத்தில் இணைக்க முடியும். The results were relatively poor, although not a total disaster and could probably be improved with some polishing of the system's rough edges.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم نے سٹم مسلمانوں کو فاسٹپارس ٹیم کے لئے IWPT 2021 میں شریک ٹاکس کے لئے پیش کیا ہے. ہم پہلے سال اس کام میں مشغول ہوئے کہ فعالیت پر تمرکز کریں۔ آج سال ہم نے نئی ایڈیوں کے ساتھ ایک محدودہ وقت بوجٹ پر آزمائش پر تمرکز کیا ہے۔ ہمارا سیستم EUD گراف کو چند درختوں میں تقسیم کرنے پر بنیاد ہے، زبان منصوبات پر بنیاد ہے. ہم ان درختوں کی پیش بینی کرتے ہیں ایک سطح-لابلینگ پارچر کے مطابق اور انہیں ایک EUD گراف میں ترکیب کرتے ہیں. نتائج نسبت فقیر تھے، اگرچہ کامل مصیبت نہیں تھا اور شاید سیسٹم کی سخت کناروں کے ذریعہ سے بہتر ہو سکتا تھا.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_si>අපි පද්ධතියට FASTPARSE කණ්ඩායමෙන් EUD කොටස් එක්ක IWPT 2021 වලින් කාර්යාලයට පෙනුම් දෙන්නේ. අපි පස්සේ අවුරුද්දේ වැඩේ ගියේ වැඩේ ඉන්නේ ක්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට බලන්න. මේ අවුරුද්දේ අපි අළුත් අදහසක් පරීක්ෂා කරලා තියෙන්නේ අලුත් අදහසක් අවස්ථාවක් ගැන. අපේ පද්ධතිය EUD ග්‍රාෆ් එක වර්ගයක් විතරයි, භාෂාවික විශේෂයේ අධාරිත වර්ගයක් විතරයි. අපි මේ ගස් විශ්වාස කරනවා පණිවිඩයක් ලේබිල් විශේෂකයක් භාවිත කරන්න සහ EUD ග්‍රාෆ් එක්කම් කරනවා. ප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රමාණයක් සාමාන්‍ය අනතුරු වුනා, ඒත් සම්පූර්ණ අනතුරක් නෙවෙයි, සමහරවිට පද්ධතියේ අම</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar systeminlämningen från FASTPARSE-teamet för EUD Shared Task på IWPT 2021. Vi engagerade oss i uppgiften förra året genom att fokusera på effektivitet. I år har vi fokuserat på att experimentera med nya idéer på en begränsad tidsbudget. Vårt system bygger på att dela upp EUD-grafen i flera träd, baserat på språkliga kriterier. Vi förutspår dessa träd med hjälp av en sekvensmärkning parser och kombinerar dem till en EUD-graf. Resultaten var relativt dåliga, men inte en total katastrof och kunde troligen förbättras med lite polering av systemets grova kanter.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_uz>Bu tizimni IWPT 2021 yilda AUD shartlangan vazifalar uchun FASTPARSE jamoasidan qabul qilamiz. Oldingi yil vazifani ishga harakat qildik, ta'sirlikni foydalanish mumkin. Bu yil biz cheksiz vaqt budget bilan yangi g'oyalarni tajriba qilishga foydalanamiz. Bizning tizimimizning EUD grafikni bir necha darajaga ajratish asosida, tillar kriteriga asosida. Biz shu daraxtlarni seksiz lab chiqaruvchi parametrlar bilan ishlatimiz va ularni EUD grafikga birlashtiramiz. Natijalar juda yomon edi, ammo butun katak emas va tizimning qiyin chegaralari bilan bir necha qo'shish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi giới thiệu sự đệ trình hệ thống từ đội FASTParis cho "đặc nhiệm chia sẻ" tại IWST 2021. Chúng tôi đã thực hiện nhiệm vụ năm ngoái bằng cách tập trung vào hiệu quả. Năm nay chúng ta đã tập trung thử nghiệm một ý tưởng mới về một ngân sách thời gian hạn. Hệ thống của chúng ta dựa trên việc chia đồ thị ECD thành nhiều cây, dựa trên các tiêu chuẩn ngôn ngữ. Chúng tôi dự đoán những cây này sử dụng một phân tách và kết hợp chúng thành một đồ đồ thị ECD. Kết quả khá thấp, tuy nhiên không phải là thảm họa hoàn toàn và có thể cải thiện bằng cách đánh bóng các cạnh gồ ghề.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме подаването на системата от екипа на ФАСТПАРС за Споделената задача на ЕС на ИПТ 2021. Ние се ангажирахме с тази задача миналата година, като се съсредоточихме върху ефективността. Тази година сме се фокусирали върху експериментирането с нови идеи на ограничен времеви бюджет. Нашата система се основава на разделяне на графиката на ДУС на няколко дървета, въз основа на езикови критерии. Прогнозираме тези дървета с помощта на анализатор за обозначаване на последователност и ги комбинираме в графика на EUD. Резултатите бяха сравнително слаби, макар и не тотално бедствие и вероятно биха могли да бъдат подобрени с известно полиране на грубите ръбове на системата.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Predstavljamo podatke sustava iz ekipe FASTPARSE za zajednički zadatak EUD-a na IWPT 2021. godini. Prošle godine smo se uključili u zadatak fokusiranjem na učinkovitost. Ove godine smo se fokusirali na eksperimentiranje s novim idejama na ograničeni proračun vremena. Naš sustav je temeljen na raspodjeli grafika EUD-a na nekoliko drveća, temeljenom na jezičkim kriterijima. Predviđamo ove drveće koristeći analizatora označavanja sekvence i kombinirati ih u EUD grafik. Rezultati su bili relativno siromašni, iako nije potpuna katastrofa i vjerojatno bi se mogli poboljšati s nekim poliranjem teških ivica sustava.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer systemindsendelsen fra FASTPARSE-teamet til EUD Shared Task på IWPT 2021. Vi engagerede os i opgaven sidste år ved at fokusere på effektivitet. I år har vi fokuseret på at eksperimentere med nye ideer på et begrænset tidsbudget. Vores system er baseret på at opdele EUD-grafen i flere træer baseret på sproglige kriterier. Vi forudsiger disse træer ved hjælp af en sekvensmærkning fortolker og kombinerer dem til en EUD graf. Resultaterne var relativt dårlige, omend ikke en total katastrofe og kunne sandsynligvis forbedres med en vis polering af systemets grove kanter.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Wir stellen die Systemeinreichung des FASTPARSE-Teams für die EUD Shared Task auf der IWPT 2021 vor. Im vergangenen Jahr haben wir uns dieser Aufgabe mit dem Fokus auf Effizienz verschrieben. In diesem Jahr haben wir uns auf das Experimentieren mit neuen Ideen mit einem begrenzten Zeitbudget konzentriert. Unser System basiert auf der Aufteilung des EUD-Graphen in mehrere Bäume, basierend auf linguistischen Kriterien. Wir prognostizieren diese Bäume mit einem Sequenz-Labeling Parser und kombinieren sie zu einem EUD Graph. Die Ergebnisse waren relativ schlecht, wenn auch keine totale Katastrophe und könnten wahrscheinlich mit etwas Polieren der rauen Kanten des Systems verbessert werden.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren de systeeminzending van het FASTPARSE team voor de EUD Shared Task op IWPT 2021. Vorig jaar hebben we de taak aangepakt door ons te richten op efficiëntie. Dit jaar hebben we ons gefocust op het experimenteren met nieuwe ideeën met een beperkt tijdsbudget. Ons systeem is gebaseerd op het opsplitsen van de EUD grafiek in verschillende bomen, op basis van taalkundige criteria. We voorspellen deze bomen met behulp van een sequence-labeling parser en combineren ze tot een EUD grafiek. De resultaten waren relatief slecht, maar geen totale ramp en zouden waarschijnlijk verbeterd kunnen worden met wat polijsten van de ruwe randen van het systeem.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Kami mempersembahkan pengiriman sistem dari tim FASTPARSE untuk EUD Shared Task di IWPT 2021. Kami terlibat dalam tugas tahun lalu dengan fokus pada efisiensi. This year we have focused on experimenting with new ideas on a limited time budget.  Sistem kita berdasarkan membagi grafik EUD ke beberapa pohon, berdasarkan kriteria bahasa. Kami memprediksi pohon-pohon ini menggunakan alat penapis urutan dan menggabungkannya ke grafik EUD. Hasilnya relatif buruk, meskipun bukan bencana total dan mungkin bisa diperbaiki dengan beberapa polishing pinggir kasar sistem.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>ما تسلیم سیستم را از تیم FASTPARSE برای کار مشترک EUD در IWPT 2021 پیشنهاد می کنیم. ما سال گذشته با تمرکز روی موثبت در کار مشغول شدیم. امسال ما روی آزمایش با ایده های جدید روی یک بودجه زمان محدود تمرکز کردیم. سیستم ما بر پایه تقسیم گراف EUD به چند درخت، بر اساس مقدار زبان‌شناسی است. ما این درختها را پیش بینی می کنیم که با استفاده از یک بازیگر برچسب‌های برچسب‌های برچسب‌ها استفاده می‌کنیم و آنها را به یک گراف EUD ترکیب می‌کنیم. نتیجه‌ها نسبتا فقیر بودند، اگرچه فاجعه کامل نیست و احتمالا با برخی از لبه‌های سخت سیستم بهتر می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>EUD'yň IWPT 2021-nji ýylda bölýän işi üçin sistemiň süýşini FASTPARSE toparyndan görkez. Geçen ýyl bu işe etkinlik ukyplaryna üns berýäk. Bu ýyl biz täze pikirler bilen mugallyk wagt budžetynda synanyşmaga üns berdik. Biziň sistemimiz EUD grafyny bir näçe agaç içine daýanýar, dil kriteriýasyna daýanýar. Biz bu agaçları bir sıralama etiketleyici parçacısını kullanarak EUD grafisine birleştirerek tahmin edip duruyoruz. netijeler görä garypdy, ýöne hiç hili ýaramazdy we sistemiň kyn çöplüklerini ýuwlaşdyryp bilerdi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Tunawasilisha mfumo huo kutoka timu ya FASTPARSE kwa ajili ya kazi ya kushirikiana na EUD katika IWPT 2021. Tulijihusisha kazi mwaka jana kwa kutumia lengo la ufanisi. Mwaka huu tumejikita kwenye kujaribu na mawazo mapya kwenye bajeti ya muda mdogo. Mfumo wetu unategemea kutenganisha ramani ya EUD katika miti kadhaa, kwa kutumia vigezo vya lugha. Tunatabiri mti huu kwa kutumia mchambuzi wa mfululizo na kuwaunganisha kwenye picha ya EUD. Matokeo haya yalikuwa masikini, ingawa si janga la jumla na labda yanaweza kuboreshwa kwa baadhi ya upepo mkali wa mfumo huo.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Ons voorsien die stelsel onderskrywing van die FASTPARSE-span vir die EUD deelde taak by IWPT 2021. Ons het verlede jaar in die opdrag aangetrek deur op effektief te fokus. Hierdie jaar het ons gefokus op eksperimentering met nuwe idees op 'n beperkte tydsbudžet. Ons stelsel is gebaseer op die dele van die EUD-graaf in verskeie bome, gebaseer op lingvisse kriteriërs. Ons voorskou hierdie bome gebruik 'n volgorde-etiketting ontwerker en kombinieer hulle in 'n EUD graf. Die resultate was relativief arme, alhoewel nie 'n totale katastrof en kon waarskynlik verbeter word met 'n paar polisering van die stelsel se swaar kante.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim paraqitjen e sistemit nga ekipi FASTPARSE për detyrën e përbashkët të EUD në IWPT 2021. Ne u angazhuam në detyrën vitin e kaluar duke u përqëndruar në efektshmëri. Këtë vit ne jemi përqëndruar në eksperimentimin me ide të reja në një buxhet kohor të kufizuar. Sistemi ynë është bazuar në ndarjen e grafikut të EUD në disa pemë, bazuar në kriteret gjuhësore. Ne parashikojmë këto pemë duke përdorur një analizues sekuencë-etiketash dhe i kombinojmë në një grafik EUD. Rezultatet ishin relativisht të dobëta, megjithëse jo një katastrofë totale dhe ndoshta mund të përmirësohen me disa lehtësime të kufijve të ashpra të sistemit.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_az>Biz sistemi FASTPARSE takımından EUD paylaşılan iş üçün 2021-ci IWPT tərəfindən təklif edirik. Geçən il işlərə təşkil etdik. Bu il, yeni fikirlər ilə müəyyən vaxt budžetına təşkil etdik. Sistemimiz EUD grafünü bir çox ağaclara bölməyə dayanır, dil kriteriyyətlərinə dayanan. Biz bu a ğaçları seçmə etiketləmə parçacısı ilə təmin edirik və onları EUD grafına birləşdiririk. Növbətlər relativi zəif idi, amma tamamilə fəsad deyildi və mümkün olaraq sistemin çətin kəndlərini təmizləməklə yaxşılaşdırıla bilərdi.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_am>የኢዩድ ተሳካፊ ስራዎችን በ IWPT 2021 የFASTPARSE ቡድን እናቀርባለን፡፡ ባለፈው ዓመት ስራውን በጥቅምነት ለመጠየቅ ተግባር እናስጠጋለን፡፡ በዚያች ዓመት አዲስ አሳቤዎችን በተወሰነ ጊዜ budget ላይ ለመፈተና አቆይተናል፡፡ የቋንቋዊ ክፍተቶችን በመካፈል የEUD graph ለብዙዎች ዛፎች ለመለየት የተደረገ ነው፡፡ እነዚህን ዛፎች በቁጥጥር ተሳታፊ እና በEUD graph እናሳስባቸዋለን፡፡ ፍሬዎቹም በተለየ ድሆች ነበር፣ ምንም እንኳን በሙሉ ጉዳት ሳይሆን እና የስርዓቱን ጠንካራ ክፍል በመጠቀም ይችላል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_ko>FASTPARSE 팀이 IWPT 2021에 제출한 EUD 공유 임무를 보여주는 시스템입니다.작년에 우리는 효율을 중시함으로써 이 임무를 완성했다.올해 우리는 제한된 시간 안에 새로운 아이디어를 시도하는 데 전념했다.우리 시스템은 언어 표준을 바탕으로 EUD 그림을 몇 개의 나무로 나누었다.시퀀스 라벨 파서를 사용하여 트리를 예측하고 이를 EUD 그림으로 조합했습니다.결과는 상대적으로 나쁘다. 비록 철저한 재난은 아니지만, 시스템의 거친 가장자리에 광택을 내어 개선할 수도 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք ներկայացնում ենք համակարգի ներկայացումը ՖԱՍՊԱՌՍ թիմի կողմից ԱՄՆ 2021 թվականին ընդհանուր հանձնարարության համար: Անցյալ տարի մենք ներգրավվեցինք այս խնդրին կենտրոնացնելով արդյունավետության վրա: Այս տարի մենք կենտրոնացել ենք նոր գաղափարների փորձարկումների վրա ժամանակի սահմանափակ բյուջեսի վրա: Our system is based on splitting the EUD graph into several trees, based on linguistic criteria.  Մենք կանխագուշակում ենք այս ծառերը օգտագործելով հաջորդականության պիտակավորման վերլուծում և համադրում ենք դրանք ԵՈԴ գրաֆիկի մեջ: Արդյունքները համեմատաբար աղքատ էին, չնայած, որ ոչ մի ամբողջ աղետ, և հավանաբար կարող էին բարելավվել համակարգի ծանր եզրերի որոշ լուսավորման միջոցով:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা ইউড শেয়ার করার কাজের জন্য ফাস্টপার্স টিম থেকে সিস্টেম প্রতিষ্ঠান উপস্থাপন করি। গত বছর আমরা কাজে অংশগ্রহণ করেছিলাম, কার্যকরীর উপর মনোযোগ দিয়ে। এই বছর আমরা একটি সীমিত সময় বাজেটে নতুন চিন্তা দিয়ে পরীক্ষা করার প্রতি মনোযোগ দিয়েছি। আমাদের সিস্টেম ভিত্তিক ভাষায় ইউডি গ্রাফ বিভক্ত করে বেশ কয়েকটি গাছের ভিত্তিক ভিত্তিক ভাষায়। আমরা ভবিষ্যদ্বাণী করি এই গাছগুলো একটি সেকেন্স-ল্যাবেলিং ব্যবহার করে এবং তাদের একটি ইউডি গ্রাফে একত্রিত করি। ফলাফল প্রায় দরিদ্র ছিল, যদিও পুরো বিপর্যয় নয় এবং সম্ভবত সিস্টেমের কঠিন প্রান্তের কিছু প্রান্তের সাথে কিছু প্রান্তের</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme systémové předložení od týmu FASTPARSE pro sdílený úkol EUD na IWPT 2021. Tento úkol jsme se zapojili loni zaměřením na efektivitu. Letos jsme se zaměřili na experimentování s novými nápady s omezeným časovým rozpočtem. Náš systém je založen na rozdělení grafu EUD do několika stromů na základě jazykových kritérií. Tyto stromy předpovídáme pomocí sekvenčního značení parseru a kombinujeme do EUD grafu. Výsledky byly relativně špatné, ačkoli nebyly úplná katastrofa a mohly by být pravděpodobně zlepšeny nějakým leštěním hrubých hran systému.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo podatke sustava iz ekipe FASTPARSE za zajednički zadatak EUD na IWPT 2021. godini. Prošle godine smo se uključili u zadatak fokusiranjem na učinkovitost. Ove godine smo se fokusirali na eksperimentiranje sa novim idejama na ograničeni vremenski budžet. Naš sistem je baziran na raspodjeli grafika EUD-a na nekoliko drveća, na temelju jezičkih kriterija. Predviđamo ove drveće koristeći analizatora označavanja sekvence i kombinirati ih u EUD grafik. Rezultati su bili relativno siromašni, iako nisu potpuna katastrofa i vjerojatno bi se mogli poboljšati s nekim poliranjem teških ivica sistema.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Presentam la presentació del sistema de l'equip FASTPARSE per la EUD Shared Task al IWPT 2021. We engaged in the task last year by focusing on efficiency.  Aquest any ens hem centrat en experimentar amb noves idees amb un pressupost de temps limitat. El nostre sistema està basat en dividir el gràfic EUD en varis arbres, basat en criteris lingüístics. Predim aquests arbres fent servir un analitzador d'etiqueta de seqüències i els combinem en un gràfic EUD. Els resultats eren relativament pobres, encara que no sigui un desastre total i probablement podrien millorar-se amb algun poliment dels costats durs del sistema.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Esitleme FASTPARSE meeskonna süsteemi esitamist EUD ühise ülesande jaoks IWPT 2021. Eelmisel aastal tegutsesime selles ülesandes, keskendudes tõhususele. Sel aastal oleme keskendunud uute ideedega katsetamisele piiratud ajalise eelarvega. Meie süsteem põhineb ELD graafiku jagamisel mitmeks puuks, tuginedes keelelistele kriteeriumidele. Me prognoosime neid puid jada märgistava parseri abil ja kombineerime need EUD graafikuks. Tulemused olid suhteliselt kehvad, kuigi mitte täielik katastroof ning neid saaks tõenäoliselt parandada süsteemi karedate servade poleerimisega.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esittelemme FASTPARSE-tiimin järjestelmän toimituksen EUD Shared Task -tapahtumaan IWPT 2021. Osallistuimme tehtävään viime vuonna keskittymällä tehokkuuteen. Tänä vuonna olemme keskittyneet kokeilemaan uusia ideoita rajoitetulla aikabudjetilla. Järjestelmämme perustuu EUD-kaavion jakamiseen useisiin puihin kielellisten kriteerien perusteella. Ennustamme nämä puut sekvenssimerkintää käyttäen ja yhdistämme ne EUD-kaavioksi. Tulokset olivat suhteellisen heikkoja, vaikkakaan eivät täysin tuhoisia, ja niitä voitaisiin todennäköisesti parantaa hiomalla järjestelmän karkeita reunoja.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo oddajo sistema ekipe FASTPARSE za skupno nalogo EUD na IWPT 2021. V to nalogo smo se lani lotili s poudarkom na učinkovitosti. Letos smo se osredotočili na eksperimentiranje z novimi idejami v omejenem časovnem proračunu. Naš sistem temelji na razdelitvi grafa EUD na več dreves, ki temelji na jezikovnih kriterijih. Ta drevesa napovedujemo z razčlenjevalnikom označevanja zaporedja in jih združimo v graf EUD. Rezultati so bili relativno slabi, čeprav niso popolna katastrofa in bi jih bilo verjetno mogoče izboljšati z nekaj poliranjem grobih robov sistema.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé ngeremusi sistem nggawe perintah di asla-perintah éwé nggawe Trabah IWRT 2020. Awakdhéwé éntuk nggambar barêng-barêng ngenggo kuwi wis ana sing nguasai efes. Tahun punika, awak dhéwé éntukno minggu nggawe barang nggawe ide sing luwih nèng budhet kanggo nggawe barang. Sistem-sistem sing digawesi uwong kelas-uwong ning werak batir Awak dhéwé ngerti barang iki dadi nggambar sistem-etiketing panser Pametuné awak dhéwé luwih-luwih tenan, nganggep kuwi ora mbok sing apik bênêr, lak iso ngedolö ngono nggawe sistem sing bisa seperakan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna halatar da shirin system daga the FATTPARCE team for the EUD Shared Taimar Yin IWPT 2021. Mun yi aiki a cikin aikin shekara ta shida, tuna makini ga fassarar. Ga wannan shekara, mun yi makini ga jarrabi da idãnun sãbuwa a kan budget na lokaci wanda ba da sani ba. Ana bincike na'urarmu a kan tsãge grafi na EUD zuwa ga itãce guda, a kan karatun linguistic. Ana kange waɗannan itãcen da ke yi amfani da mai fassarar-biyu kuma Muke haɗa su zuwa wani grafi na EUD. Mataimakin sun kasance mafakin kwamfyuta, kuma kõ dã bai zama wata masĩfa guda ba kuma za a iya gyãra shi da wasu na'urar na'urar na'ura.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו מציגים את ההעברה מהצוות FASTPARSE למשימה המשותפת של EUD ב IWPT 2021. התעסקנו במשימה בשנה שעברה על ידי התמקדות ביעילות. השנה התמקדנו בניסויים עם רעיונות חדשים על תקציב זמן מוגבל. המערכת שלנו מבוססת על פיצול גרף EUD לכמה עצים, מבוסס על קריטורים שפתיים. אנו חושפים את העצים האלה באמצעות מעבד סימני רצף ומשולבים אותם לתוך גרף EUD. התוצאות היו עניות יחסית, למרות שלא אסון מוחלט, וכנראה שיכול להשתפר עם קצת ניקוי של קצוות המערכת הקשה.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>We present the system submission from the FASTPARSE team for the EUD Shared Task at IWPT 2021. ང་ཚོས་འདས་པའི་ལོ་ངོ་ལི་ལས་འགུལ་གྱི་ནང་དུ་སླེབས་པའི་ལས་འགུལ་སློང་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ད་ལྟ་ང་ཚོས་ལོ་ངོ་དུས་ཚོད་ཆེན་སུ་གཏོང་བའི་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་རྒྱུ་དང་། ང་ཚོའི་མ་ལག་ནི་སྒེར་གྱི་དབྱིབས་ཆའི་གྲངས་རིགས་འདི་དབྱིབས་ཤིག་ཆའི་ནང་དུ་གཞི་རྟེན་འདུག We predict these trees using a sequence-labelling parser and combine them into an EUD graph. རྐྱེན་འབྲས་འདི་ལྟ་བུའི་གནད་དོན་འགྲུལ་པོ་ཞིག་ཡིན་ནའང་མེད་པར། མ་ལག་གི་ཕྱོགས་གནད་དོན་ཅིག་ལ་ཡར་རྒྱས་སྐྱོར་བ</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>Graph Rewriting for Enhanced Universal Dependencies<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependencies</title>
      <author><first>Bruno</first><last>Guillaume</last></author>
      <author><first>Guy</first><last>Perrier</last></author>
      <pages>175–183</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes a system proposed for the IWPT 2021 Shared Task on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">Parsing</a> into Enhanced Universal Dependencies (EUD). We propose a Graph Rewriting based system for computing Enhanced Universal Dependencies, given the Basic Universal Dependencies (UD).</abstract>
      <url hash="3292791d">2021.iwpt-1.18</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.iwpt-1.18</doi>
      <bibkey>guillaume-perrier-2021-graph</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>Biaffine Dependency and Semantic Graph Parsing for EnhancedUniversal Dependencies<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nhanced<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal Dependencies</title>
      <author><first>Giuseppe</first><last>Attardi</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniele</first><last>Sartiano</last></author>
      <author><first>Maria</first><last>Simi</last></author>
      <pages>184–188</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> used in our submission to the IWPT 2021 Shared Task. This year the official evaluation metrics was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ELAS">ELAS</a>, therefore dependency parsing might have been avoided as well as other pipeline stages like POS tagging and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lemmatization">lemmatization</a>. We nevertheless chose to deploy a combination of a dependency parser and a graph parser. The dependency parser is a biaffine parser, that uses transformers for representing input sentences, with no other feature. The graph parser is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_parser">semantic parser</a> that exploits a similar architecture except for using a sigmoid crossentropy loss function to return multiple values for the predicted arcs. The final output is obtained by merging the output of the two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parsers</a>. The dependency parser achieves top or close to top LAS performance with respect to other systems that report results on such metrics, except on low resource languages (Tamil, Estonian, Latvian).<i>IWPT 2021 Shared Task</i>. This year the official evaluation metrics was ELAS, therefore dependency parsing might have been avoided as well as other pipeline stages like POS tagging and lemmatization. We nevertheless chose to deploy a combination of a dependency parser and a graph parser. The dependency parser is a biaffine parser, that uses transformers for representing input sentences, with no other feature. The graph parser is a semantic parser that exploits a similar architecture except for using a sigmoid crossentropy loss function to return multiple values for the predicted arcs. The final output is obtained by merging the output of the two parsers. The dependency parser achieves top or close to top LAS performance with respect to other systems that report results on such metrics, except on low resource languages (Tamil, Estonian, Latvian).</abstract>
      <url hash="3262b981">2021.iwpt-1.19</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.iwpt-1.19</doi>
      <bibkey>attardi-etal-2021-biaffine</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>RobertNLP at the IWPT 2021 Shared Task : Simple Enhanced UD Parsing for 17 Languages<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>obert<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> at the <fixed-case>IWPT</fixed-case> 2021 Shared Task: Simple Enhanced <fixed-case>UD</fixed-case> Parsing for 17 Languages</title>
      <author><first>Stefan</first><last>Grünewald</last></author>
      <author><first>Frederik Tobias</first><last>Oertel</last></author>
      <author><first>Annemarie</first><last>Friedrich</last></author>
      <pages>196–203</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents our multilingual dependency parsing system as used in the IWPT 2021 Shared Task on Parsing into Enhanced Universal Dependencies. Our system consists of an unfactorized biaffine classifier that operates directly on fine-tuned XLM-R embeddings and generates enhanced UD graphs by predicting the best dependency label (or absence of a dependency) for each pair of tokens. To avoid sparsity issues resulting from lexicalized dependency labels, we replace lexical items in relations with placeholders at training and prediction time, later retrieving them from the parse via a hybrid rule-based / machine-learning system. In addition, we utilize model ensembling at prediction time. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> achieves high parsing accuracy on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blinded_experiment">blind test data</a>, ranking 3rd out of 9 with an average ELAS F1 score of 86.97.</abstract>
      <url hash="477cec25">2021.iwpt-1.21</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.iwpt-1.21</doi>
      <bibkey>grunewald-etal-2021-robertnlp</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>