<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.teachingnlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Fifth Workshop on Teaching NLP</booktitle>
      <editor><first>David</first><last>Jurgens</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Varada</first><last>Kolhatkar</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Lucy</first><last>Li</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Margot</first><last>Mieskes</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ted</first><last>Pedersen</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.teachingnlp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="076b2c31">2021.teachingnlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>teachingnlp-2021-teaching</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Teaching a Massive Open Online Course on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a></title>
      <author><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Artemova</last></author>
      <author><first>Murat</first><last>Apishev</last></author>
      <author><first>Denis</first><last>Kirianov</last></author>
      <author><first>Veronica</first><last>Sarkisyan</last></author>
      <author><first>Sergey</first><last>Aksenov</last></author>
      <author><first>Oleg</first><last>Serikov</last></author>
      <pages>13–27</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we present a new Massive Open Online Course on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a>, targeted at non-English speaking students. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Course_(education)">course</a> lasts 12 weeks, every week consists of lectures, practical sessions and quiz assigments. Three weeks out of 12 are followed by Kaggle-style coding assigments. Our course intents to serve multiple purposes : (i) familirize students with the core concepts and methods in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a>, such as language modelling or word or sentence representations, (ii) show that recent advances, including pre-trained Transformer-based models, are build upon these concepts ; (iii) to introduce architectures for most most demanded real-life applications, (iii) to develop practical skills to process texts in multiple languages. The course was prepared and recorded during 2020 and so far have received positive feedback.</abstract>
      <url hash="1d822912">2021.teachingnlp-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>artemova-etal-2021-teaching</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/squad">SQuAD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Natural Language Processing 4 All (NLP4All): A New Online Platform for Teaching and Learning NLP Concepts<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>ll): A New Online Platform for Teaching and Learning <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Concepts</title>
      <author><first>Rebekah</first><last>Baglini</last></author>
      <author><first>Hermes</first><last>Hjorth</last></author>
      <pages>28–33</pages>
      <abstract>Natural Language Processing offers new insights into language data across almost all disciplines and domains, and allows us to corroborate and/or challenge existing knowledge. The primary hurdles to widening participation in and use of these new research tools are, first, a lack of coding skills in students across K-16, and in the population at large, and second, a lack of knowledge of how NLP-methods can be used to answer questions of disciplinary interest outside of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistics">linguistics</a> and/or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_science">computer science</a>. To broaden participation in NLP and improve NLP-literacy, we introduced a new tool web-based tool called Natural Language Processing 4 All (NLP4All). The intended purpose of NLP4All is to help teachers facilitate learning with and about NLP, by providing easy-to-use interfaces to NLP-methods, data, and analyses, making it possible for non- and novice-programmers to learn NLP concepts interactively.</abstract>
      <url hash="cad60b21">2021.teachingnlp-1.3</url>
      <revision id="1" href="2021.teachingnlp-1.3v1" hash="87bed85c" />
      <revision id="2" href="2021.teachingnlp-1.3v2" hash="cad60b21" date="2021-06-01">Fixed typo in equation and added new figure</revision>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>baglini-hjorth-2021-natural</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>A New Broad NLP Training from Speech to Knowledge<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Training from Speech to Knowledge</title>
      <author><first>Maxime</first><last>Amblard</last></author>
      <author><first>Miguel</first><last>Couceiro</last></author>
      <pages>34–45</pages>
      <abstract>In 2018, the Master Sc. in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> opened at IDMC-Institut des Sciences du Digital, du Management et de la Cognition, Universit de Lorraine-Nancy, France. Far from being a creation ex-nihilo, it is the product of a history and many reflections on the field and its teaching. This article proposes epistemological and critical elements on the opening and maintainance of this so far new master’s program in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="960bf07e">2021.teachingnlp-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>amblard-couceiro-2021-new</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>A Crash Course on Ethics for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a></title>
      <author><first>Annemarie</first><last>Friedrich</last></author>
      <author><first>Torsten</first><last>Zesch</last></author>
      <pages>49–51</pages>
      <abstract>It is generally agreed upon in the natural language processing (NLP) community that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethics">ethics</a> should be integrated into any <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curriculum">curriculum</a>. Being aware of and understanding the relevant core concepts is a prerequisite for following and participating in the discourse on ethical NLP. We here present ready-made teaching material in the form of slides and practical exercises on ethical issues in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP</a>, which is primarily intended to be integrated into introductory NLP or computational linguistics courses. By making this material freely available, we aim at lowering the threshold to adding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethics">ethics</a> to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curriculum">curriculum</a>. We hope that increased awareness will enable students to identify potentially <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethics">unethical behavior</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="2373da92">2021.teachingnlp-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>friedrich-zesch-2021-crash</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Um curso intensivo sobre ética para processamento de linguagem natural</title_pt>
      <title_ar>دورة مكثفة حول أخلاقيات معالجة اللغة الطبيعية</title_ar>
      <title_es>Un curso intensivo sobre ética para el procesamiento del lenguaje natural</title_es>
      <title_ja>自然言語処理の倫理に関するクラッシュコース</title_ja>
      <title_zh>自然语言理伦理学速成班</title_zh>
      <title_hi>प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रसंस्करण के लिए नैतिकता पर एक क्रैश कोर्स</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Cúrsa tuairteála ar Eitic do Phróiseáil Teanga Nádúrtha</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Ένα μάθημα έκτακτης ανάγκης για την ηθική για την επεξεργασία φυσικής γλώσσας</title_el>
      <title_hu>A természetes nyelv feldolgozásához szükséges etikai tanfolyam</title_hu>
      <title_it>Un corso di perfezionamento sull'etica per l'elaborazione del linguaggio naturale</title_it>
      <title_kk>Табиғи тіл процессорының этикасында жаңылыс курсы</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Natūralaus kalbų apdorojimo etikos avarijų kursas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Name</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Name</title_ms>
      <title_ml>സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനത്തിനുള്ള എറ്റിക്സില്‍ ഒരു ക്രാഷ് കോര്‍സ്</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Kors ta’ Crash dwar l-Etika għall-Ipproċessar tal-Lingwi Naturali</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Байгалийн хэл үйлдвэрлэлийн этикийн хувьд</title_mn>
      <title_no>Name</title_no>
      <title_pl>Kurs awaryjny na temat etyki przetwarzania języka naturalnego</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Un curs Crash despre etică pentru procesarea limbajului natural</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Kurs sranja na etiku prirodnog jezika</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>A Crash Course on Ethics for Natural Language Processing</title_so>
      <title_sv>En kraschkurs om etik för behandling av naturligt språk</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Name</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Một lớp học về chất vấn đạo đức học về ngôn ngữ tự nhiên</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Краш курс по етика за обработка на естествени езици</title_bg>
      <title_da>Et crash kursus om etik til behandling af naturligt sprog</title_da>
      <title_hr>Kurs sranja na etiku prirodnog jezika</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Een crashcursus over ethiek voor natuurlijke taalverwerking</title_nl>
      <title_id>A Crash Course on Ethics for Natural Language Processing</title_id>
      <title_ko>자연언어처리윤리속성반</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Kikosi cha Matukio katika Utendaji wa lugha ya asili</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Dobiýal dil işlemek üçin Etika barada Ýaşyrma Kurs</title_tr>
      <title_de>Ein Crashkurs über Ethik für die Verarbeitung natürlicher Sprache</title_de>
      <title_fa>Name</title_fa>
      <title_sq>Një kurs dështimi në etikë për procesimin e gjuhës natyrore</title_sq>
      <title_am>A Crash Course on Ethics for Natural Language Processing</title_am>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_hy>Բնական լեզվի վերաբերյալ բնական էթիկայի թերադասը</title_hy>
      <title_bn>প্রাকৃতিক ভাষার প্রক্রিয়ার ইথিক্সে একটি ক্র্যাশ কোর্স</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Un curs d'ètica per al processament de llenguatges naturals</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Crash kurz o etice pro zpracování přirozeného jazyka</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Luonnollisen kielen käsittelyn etiikan kurssi</title_fi>
      <title_az>Təbiətli Dil İşləməsi üçün Etik İşyaları</title_az>
      <title_bs>Kurs sranja na etiku prirodnog jezika</title_bs>
      <title_et>Loodusliku keele töötlemise eetika kursus</title_et>
      <title_jv>Candy Curse kanggo Etik kanggo Perusahaan Inggal Pribadi</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Crash tečaj o etiki za obdelavo naravnega jezika</title_sk>
      <title_he>Name</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>Natural Language Processing On Ethics for Crash Course</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>من المتفق عليه عمومًا في مجتمع معالجة اللغة الطبيعية (NLP) أنه يجب دمج الأخلاقيات في أي منهج دراسي. يعد إدراك وفهم المفاهيم الأساسية ذات الصلة شرطًا أساسيًا لمتابعة الحوار حول البرمجة اللغوية العصبية الأخلاقية والمشاركة فيه. نقدم هنا مواد تعليمية جاهزة في شكل شرائح وتمارين عملية حول القضايا الأخلاقية في البرمجة اللغوية العصبية ، والتي تهدف في المقام الأول إلى دمجها في دورات البرمجة اللغوية العصبية التمهيدية أو دورات اللغويات الحاسوبية. من خلال إتاحة هذه المواد مجانًا ، نهدف إلى خفض عتبة إضافة الأخلاقيات إلى المناهج الدراسية. نأمل أن يمكّن الوعي المتزايد الطلاب من تحديد السلوك غير الأخلاقي المحتمل.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>En general, en la comunidad de procesamiento del lenguaje natural (NLP) se acuerda que la ética debe integrarse en cualquier plan de estudios. Conocer y comprender los conceptos básicos relevantes es un requisito previo para seguir y participar en el discurso sobre la PNL ética. Aquí presentamos material didáctico listo para usar en forma de diapositivas y ejercicios prácticos sobre cuestiones éticas en la PNL, que está destinado principalmente a integrarse en cursos introductorios de PNL o lingüística computacional. Al hacer que este material esté disponible de forma gratuita, nuestro objetivo es reducir el umbral para añadir ética al plan de estudios. Esperamos que una mayor conciencia permita a los estudiantes identificar comportamientos potencialmente poco éticos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>É geralmente aceito na comunidade de processamento de linguagem natural (PNL) que a ética deve ser integrada em qualquer currículo. Estar ciente e compreender os conceitos centrais relevantes é um pré-requisito para seguir e participar do discurso sobre a PNL ética. Apresentamos aqui material didático pronto na forma de slides e exercícios práticos sobre questões éticas em PNL, que se destina principalmente a ser integrado em cursos introdutórios de PNL ou linguística computacional. Ao disponibilizar este material gratuitamente, pretendemos diminuir o limiar para adicionar ética ao currículo. Esperamos que o aumento da conscientização permita que os alunos identifiquem comportamentos potencialmente antiéticos.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>自然言語処理（ NLP ）コミュニティでは、倫理はあらゆるカリキュラムに統合されるべきであることが一般的に合意されている。関連するコアコンセプトを認識し、理解することは、倫理的NLPに関する議論に従い、参加するための前提条件です。ここでは、NLPの倫理問題に関するスライドと実践的な演習の形式で既製の教材を提示します。これは、主に入門的なNLPまたは計算言語学コースに統合されることを意図しています。この教材を自由に利用できるようにすることで、カリキュラムに倫理を追加するためのしきい値を下げることを目指している。意識の向上により、学習者が潜在的に非倫理的な行動を特定できるようになることを願っています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>自然语言处(NLP)社区中,人普遍认为伦理,宜整合课程。 知与知相关者,循德NLP论之先也。 以幻灯片、NLP伦受业之文供成教,要在入门NLP计语言学程中。 因免费供此材,吾道在课程。 愿提高认识将使弟子识潜行。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>यह आम तौर पर प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रसंस्करण (एनएलपी) समुदाय में सहमत है कि नैतिकता को किसी भी पाठ्यक्रम में एकीकृत किया जाना चाहिए। प्रासंगिक मूल अवधारणाओं के बारे में जागरूक होने और समझने के लिए नैतिक एनएलपी पर प्रवचन में निम्नलिखित और भाग लेने के लिए एक शर्त है। हम यहां एनएलपी में नैतिक मुद्दों पर स्लाइड और व्यावहारिक अभ्यास के रूप में तैयार शिक्षण सामग्री प्रस्तुत करते हैं, जो मुख्य रूप से परिचयात्मक एनएलपी या कम्प्यूटेशनल भाषाविज्ञान पाठ्यक्रमों में एकीकृत करने का इरादा है। इस सामग्री को स्वतंत्र रूप से उपलब्ध कराकर, हम पाठ्यक्रम में नैतिकता को जोड़ने के लिए दहलीज को कम करने का लक्ष्य रखते हैं। हमें उम्मीद है कि बढ़ी हुई जागरूकता छात्रों को संभावित अनैतिक व्यवहार की पहचान करने में सक्षम बनाएगी।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Aontaítear go ginearálta sa phobal próiseála teanga nádúrtha (NLP) gur cheart an eitic a chomhtháthú in aon churaclam. Is réamhriachtanas é bheith feasach ar na croíchoincheapa ábhartha agus iad a thuiscint chun an dioscúrsa ar NLP eiticiúil a leanúint agus a bheith rannpháirteach ann. Cuirimid anseo ábhar teagaisc réamhdhéanta i láthair i bhfoirm sleamhnáin agus cleachtaí praiticiúla ar shaincheisteanna eiticiúla in NLP, atá beartaithe go príomha a chomhtháthú le cúrsaí tosaigh NLP nó ríomhtheangeolaíocht. Tríd an ábhar seo a chur ar fáil go héasca, tá sé mar aidhm againn an tairseach a ísliú chun eitic a chur leis an gcuraclam. Tá súil againn go gcuirfidh feasacht mhéadaithe ar chumas na mac léinn iompar a d’fhéadfadh a bheith mí-eiticiúil a aithint.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩემი სახელსაწინო ენის პროცესი (NLP) საზოგადოებაში მუშაობა, რომ ეტიკა უნდა იყოს ყველაფერი პროცესი პროცესიში. შესაძლებელი კონფექტების შესახებ და გაგრძნობის შესახებ უნდა იყოს შემდეგ და დაწყვეტის დისკურაში ეტიკალური NLP-ზე. ჩვენ აქ ვამხსენებთ დჲრჲგი სწავლების მატერიალი სლაიდის და პრაქტიკური განაცემების ფორმაში NLP-ში, რომელიც საუკეთესოდ უნდა იყოს ინტერგურაციული NLP ან კომპუტაციოლური ლენგურისტიკური კ ამ მატერიალს თავისუფალურად მოხმარებით, ჩვენ მინდომებით მინდომის დამატებით ეტიკას სწავლის პროგრამის დამატებით. ჩვენ გვემედით, რომ უფრო მეტი ცნობიერება იქნება სტუდენტები იდენტიფიკაცია პოტენციალურად უნეტიკალური მოქმედება.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A természetes nyelvfeldolgozó (NLP) közösségben általánosan megegyeznek arról, hogy az etikát bármely tantervbe be kell építeni. Az etikai NLP-ről szóló diskurzus követésének és részvételének előfeltétele, hogy a releváns alapfogalmak tudatában legyenek és megértsék. Itt kész oktatási anyagot mutatunk be az NLP etikai kérdéseivel foglalkozó diák és gyakorlati gyakorlatok formájában, amelyeket elsősorban bevezető NLP vagy számítógépes nyelvészeti kurzusokba integrálnak. Azáltal, hogy ezt az anyagot szabadon hozzáférhetővé tesszük, arra törekszünk, hogy csökkentsük az etika küszöbét a tantervhez. Reméljük, hogy a fokozott tudatosság lehetővé teszi a diákok számára, hogy azonosítsák a potenciálisan etikátlan viselkedést.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Γενικά συμφωνείται στην κοινότητα επεξεργασίας φυσικής γλώσσας ότι η ηθική πρέπει να ενσωματωθεί σε οποιοδήποτε πρόγραμμα σπουδών. Η γνώση και κατανόηση των σχετικών βασικών εννοιών είναι απαραίτητη προϋπόθεση για την παρακολούθηση και τη συμμετοχή στο διάλογο σχετικά με την ηθική ΝΛΠ. Παρουσιάζουμε έτοιμο διδακτικό υλικό με τη μορφή διαφανειών και πρακτικών ασκήσεων για ηθικά ζητήματα στο ΝΛΠ, το οποίο προορίζεται πρωτίστως να ενσωματωθεί σε εισαγωγικά μαθήματα ΝΛΠ ή υπολογιστικής γλωσσολογίας. Κάνοντας αυτό το υλικό ελεύθερα διαθέσιμο, στοχεύουμε στη μείωση του ορίου για την προσθήκη ηθικής στο πρόγραμμα σπουδών. Ελπίζουμε ότι η αυξημένη ευαισθητοποίηση θα επιτρέψει στους μαθητές να εντοπίσουν δυνητικά ανήθικη συμπεριφορά.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>È generalmente concordato nella comunità di elaborazione del linguaggio naturale (PNL) che l'etica dovrebbe essere integrata in qualsiasi curriculum. Essere consapevoli e comprendere i concetti fondamentali pertinenti è un prerequisito per seguire e partecipare al discorso sul PNL etico. Qui presentiamo materiale didattico pronto sotto forma di diapositive ed esercizi pratici su questioni etiche in PNL, che è destinato principalmente ad essere integrato in corsi introduttivi NLP o linguistica computazionale. Rendendo questo materiale liberamente disponibile, miriamo ad abbassare la soglia per aggiungere etica al curriculum. Speriamo che una maggiore consapevolezza consenta agli studenti di identificare comportamenti potenzialmente non etici.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Paprastai gamtos kalbų apdorojimo bendruomenėje (NLP) sutariama, kad etika turėtų būti įtraukta į bet kokias mokymo programas. Žin ėti ir suprasti svarbias pagrindines sąvokas yra būtina sąlyga, kad būtų galima sekti ir dalyvauti diskutuojant apie etišką NLP. Mes čia pristatome parengtą mokymo medžiagą sklaidų ir praktinių pratybų formos etikos klausimais NLP, kuri pirmiausia skirta integruoti į įžanginį NLP arba skaičiavimo kalbos kursus. Leidžiant šią medžiagą laisvai pasinaudoti, siekiame sumažinti mokyklų etikos papildymo ribą. Tikimės, kad didinant informuotumą studentai galės nustatyti potencialiai netišką elgesį.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Әдетте тәуелді тіл процессорында (NLP) этикасы кез келген бағдарламалар бағдарламасына ендіру керек екенін түсіндіреді. Қосымша негізгі концепцияларды білеу мен түсіну - келесі және этикалық NLP дискурстарында қатысу үшін алдындағы шарт. Біз осы жерде NLP үшін тегикалық мәселелерді және практикалық жұмыс істеу материалын жасадық. Бұл негізінде NLP немесе компьютерлік лингвистикалық курстарына енгізуге болады. Бұл материал жеткілікті қол жеткізу арқылы, біз оқыту бағдарламасына этиканы қосу үшін шегін төмендету мақсатымыз. Біз оқушыларды білімдеу үшін оқушылардың мүмкіндігін таңдауға мүмкіндік береді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Генерално се согласува во заедницата за природно обработување јазик (НЛП) дека етиката треба да се интегрира во било кој наставен план. Сознавањето и разбирањето на релевантните суштински концепти е предуслов за следење и учество во дискурсот за етичката НЛП. Тука претставуваме подготвен предавачки материјал во форма на слајдови и практични вежби за етички прашања во НЛП, кој е првенствено наменет да биде интегриран во воведувачките НЛП или компјутерски лингвистички курси. Со тоа што го поставуваме овој материјал слободно достапен, ние имаме за цел намалување на прагот за додавање етика во наставниот план. Се надеваме дека зголемената свесност ќе им овозможи на студентите да идентификуваат потенцијално неетичко однесување.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Secara umum disetujui dalam komuniti pemprosesan bahasa alam (NLP) bahawa etika patut disertai dalam mana-mana kurikulum. Mengetahui dan memahami konsep-konsep utama yang berkaitan adalah satu syarat untuk mengikuti dan berpartisipasi dalam perbicaraan mengenai NLP etika. Di sini, kami mempersembahkan bahan pengajaran bersedia dalam bentuk slaid dan latihan praktik mengenai isu etika di NLP, yang utamanya bermaksud untuk disertai dalam pelajaran NLP yang diperkenalkan atau bahasa komputasi. Dengan membuat bahan ini tersedia secara bebas, kita bertujuan untuk menurunkan ambang untuk menambah etika ke kurikulum. Kami berharap kesadaran meningkat akan membolehkan pelajar mengenali perilaku yang tidak etik.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>സ്വാഭാവികമായ ഭാഷയുടെ പ്രക്രിയശ്ചിത്രത്തില്‍ (NLP) സമൂഹത്തില്‍ സാധാരണ സമ്മതിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്നു നിയമങ്ങള്‍ ഏതൊ പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട ഉള്ള ആശയങ്ങള്‍ മനസ്സിലാക്കുകയും മനസ്സിലാക്കുകയും ചെയ്യുന്നത് പിന്തുടരുന്നതും നാഥാര്‍ത്ഥികമായ എംഎല്‍ നമ്മളിവിടെ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കപ്പെട്ട പ്രശ്നങ്ങളുടെ രൂപത്തില്‍ സ്ലൈഡുകളും പ്രാകൃതിക പ്രശ്നങ്ങളുടെയും രൂപത്തില്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഉപദേശങ്ങളുടെ വസ്ത ഈ വസ്തുക്കള്‍ സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യമായി ലഭ്യമാക്കുന്നതിനാല്‍ നിയമങ്ങള്‍ കൂട്ടിച്ചേര്‍ക്കാന്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഉദ്ദേശിക്കുന്നു. നമുക്ക് പ്രതീക്ഷിക്കുന്നത് വിദ്യാര്‍ത്ഥികള്‍ക്ക് സാധ്യതയില്ലാത്ത പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ തിരിച്ചറിയാന</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Ġeneralment huwa miftiehem fil-komunità tal-ipproċessar tal-lingwi naturali (NLP) li l-etika għandha tiġi integrata fi kwalunkwe kurrikulu. Li wieħed ikun konxju u jifhem il-kunċetti ewlenin rilevanti huwa prerekwiżit għal segwitu u parteċipazzjoni fid-diskors dwar NLP etika. Hawnhekk nippreżentaw materjal ta’ tagħlim lest fil-forma ta’ slides u eżerċizzji prattiċi dwar kwistjonijiet etiċi fil-NLP, li huwa primarjament maħsub biex jiġi integrat fil-NLP introduttorju jew fil-korsijiet lingwistiċi komputattivi. By making this material freely available, we aim at lowering the threshold to adding ethics to the curriculum.  We hope that increased awareness will enable students to identify potentially unethical behavior.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Байгалийн хэл боловсруулах (NLP) нийгэмд эдийн засаг ямар ч хөтөлбөрийн хөтөлбөрт бүрдүүлэх хэрэгтэй гэдэгт итгэдэг. Эдгээр үндсэн ойлголтыг ойлгох, ойлгох нь эдийн засгийн НLP-ын ярианд оролцох шаардлагатай. Бид энд NLP-ын шүтлэг болон практикийн асуудлын талаар бэлэн заах материалуудыг харуулж байна. Энэ нь ихэвчлэн NLP эсвэл компьютерийн хэлний сургуульд нэгтгэх зорилготой. Эдгээр материалыг чөлөөтэй ашиглаж, бид сургалтын хөтөлбөрт ёс хязгаарыг багасгахын тулд зориулсан. Бид оюутнууд магадгүй сэтгэл санааг нэмэгдүүлэх боломж олгодог гэдэгт итгэдэг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>În general, comunitatea de procesare a limbajului natural (PNL) este convenită ca etica să fie integrată în orice curriculum. Conștientizarea și înțelegerea conceptelor de bază relevante este o condiție prealabilă pentru urmărirea și participarea la discursul privind PNL etic. Aici prezentăm materiale didactice pregătite sub formă de diapozitive și exerciții practice pe probleme etice în PNL, care este destinat în principal să fie integrat în cursuri introductive PNL sau lingvistică computațională. Prin punerea la dispoziție liberă a acestui material, ne propunem să reducem pragul adăugării eticii la curriculum. Sperăm că o conștientizare sporită va permite studenților să identifice comportamentul potențial neetic.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>W społeczności przetwarzania języków naturalnych (NLP) ogólnie zgadza się, że etyka powinna być zintegrowana z każdym programem nauczania. Świadomość i zrozumienie odpowiednich podstawowych koncepcji jest warunkiem wstępnym śledzenia i uczestnictwa w dyskursie na temat etycznego NLP. Prezentujemy gotowe materiały dydaktyczne w postaci slajdów i ćwiczeń praktycznych dotyczących kwestii etycznych w NLP, które mają być przede wszystkim zintegrowane z kursami wprowadzającymi NLP lub komputerową językoznawstwa. Udostępniając ten materiał swobodnie, dążymy do obniżenia progu dodawania etyki do programu nauczania. Mamy nadzieję, że zwiększona świadomość pozwoli studentom zidentyfikować potencjalnie nieetyczne zachowania.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>U prirodnoj zajednici obrađivanja jezika (NLP) se uopšte slaže da se etika treba integrirati u bilo koji nastavni program. Svjestan i razumevanje relevantnih osnovnih koncepta je predviđenje za praćenje i sudjelovanje u diskusiji o etičkom NLP-u. Ovde predstavljamo spremno učenje materijala u obliku slajdova i praktičnih vježbi o etičkim pitanjima u NLP-u, koji je primarno nameravan da se integriše u unutrašnje NLP ili kompjuterske jezičke kurse. Uspoređivanjem ovog materijala slobodno dostupnim, ciljamo se smanjiti prag da dodamo etiku na nastavni program. Nadamo se da će povećanje svijesti omogućiti studentima da identifikuju potencijalno neobično ponašanje.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_no>Det er generelt tilordnet i den naturspråkoplinga (NLP) at etikk skal integrerast i eit program. Å forstå og forstå dei relevante kjernekonseptane er ein førehandsvising for å følgja og delta i diskursane på etiske NLP. Vi presenterer klart læringsmateriell i form av glidebrytar og praktiske øvingar på etiske problemar i NLP, som er hovudsakelig for å bli integrert i introduksjonale NLP- eller datamaskinske lingviske kursar. Ved å gjera dette materialet fritt tilgjengeleg, mål vi å låse grenseverdien til å leggja etikk til curriculum. Vi håper at økt forståelse vil gjera at studenten kan identifisera potensielt utisk oppførsel.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_si>ඒක සාමාන්‍යයෙන්ම ස්වාභාවික භාෂාව ප්‍රක්‍රියාසිකරණය (NLP) සමාජයෙන් එකතු වෙනවා කියලා හැම ක්‍රියාක්‍ර සම්බන්ධ විදියට සම්බන්ධ විදියට තේරුම් ගන්න හා තේරුම් ගන්න පුළුවන් විදියට පස්සේ පස්සේ ඉන්න අවශ්‍ය වෙ අපි මෙතන සූදානම් කරලා ඉගෙන ගන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා NLP වලින් ස්ලායිඩ් වලින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් සහ ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වලින්, මේ ප්‍රශ් මේක නිදහස් විදිහට පුළුවන් වෙන්න පුළුවන් විදිහට, අපි අදහස් කරනවා ක්‍රියාක්‍රියාලයට විශේෂතාවක් අඩ අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙන්නේ විද්‍යාපිත විද්‍යාපිත විද්‍යාපිත විද්‍යාපිත විද්‍යාපිත විද්‍යාපිත</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Inta badan waxaa lagu heshiiyaa baaritaanka afka asalka ah (NLP) in diimaha lagu qabto waxbarasho kasta. Ogaanshada iyo garashada fikrada asalka ah waa mid u baahan in la soo raaco iyo ka qeybqaato hadalka asalka ah ee NLP. Halkan waxaynu diyaarinnaa wax barashada oo loo diyaariyey nooca sawirada iyo tababar caadiga ah oo ku saabsan arimaha ethicka ee NLP, taas oo ugu horeyn loogu talagalay in la qabsado koorasyada afka xisaabta ah ee NLP ama koorasyada luuqadaha xisaabta ah. Waxyaabahan si xor ah ayaannu ugu talo galaynaa in lagu hoosaysiiyo dariiqada waxbarashada. Waxaan rajaynaynaa in ay kordhiso caqli-garashada ayaa ardayda ka heli kara inay ogaadaan tababar aan suurtagal ahayn.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Det är allmänt överenskommet i den naturliga språkbehandlingsgemenskapen (NLP) att etik bör integreras i alla läroplaner. Att vara medveten om och förstå de relevanta kärnbegreppen är en förutsättning för att följa och delta i diskursen om etisk NLP. Här presenterar vi färdigt undervisningsmaterial i form av diabilder och praktiska övningar om etiska frågor inom NLP, som främst är avsedda att integreras i introduktionskurser i NLP eller datorlingvistik. Genom att göra detta material fritt tillgängligt strävar vi efter att sänka tröskeln till att lägga till etik i läroplanen. Vi hoppas att ökad medvetenhet kommer att göra det möjligt för eleverna att identifiera potentiellt oetiskt beteende.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இயற்கையான மொழி செயல்பாடு (NLP) சமூகத்தில் இது ஒப்புக்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளது இசைமாணங்கள் எந்த மார்க்காலத்திலும் ஒன் பின்பற்றி மற்றும் புரிந்து கொள்ள முக்கியமான முன்னிருப்பு நாங்கள் இங்கே நிரந்தரமான பிரச்சனைகள் மற்றும் செயல்பாட்டின் வடிவத்தில் தயாராக்கப்பட்ட பயிற்சி பொருளை காண்பிக்கிறோம். அது முக்கியமாக NLP மொழிப இந்த பொருளை இலவசமாக கிடைக்கும் பொருளால், நாம் பள்ளிக்கு இசையை குறைக்க நோக்குகிறோம். நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம் அதிகரித்த உணர்வு மாணவர்கள் சாத்தியமான துறையான நடத்தையை கண்டறிய முடியும்.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ان کی تعلیمات میں طبیعی زبان پردازی (NLP) کی کمونٹی میں موافقت کی جاتی ہے کہ اخلاقی کسی طرح کی تعلیمات میں داخل ہونا چاہیے۔ اور سمجھ جانے اور سمجھنے کے لئے اہم اصلی نظریں اچھی طریقہ کے لئے اچھی طریقہ ہے اور اخلاقی NLP کی صحبت میں شریک ہونے کے لئے۔ ہم یہاں NLP کے اخلاقی مسئلہ کے بارے میں اسلائیڈز اور عمدہ آزمائش کی شکل میں تیار کیے جاتے ہیں، جو سب سے پہلے NLP یا کمپیوٹریشن زبان کی کورسوں میں متحد کیے جاتے ہیں. اس مواد کو آزاد طور پر موجود بنانے کے ذریعہ، ہم تعلیم کی تعلیم میں اخلاقیت کے ساتھ تدبیر کرنے کا ارادہ رکھتے ہیں. ہم امید رکھتے ہیں کہ خبردار زیادہ ہونے کی امید ہے کہ دانش آموزوں کو امکان کے طور پر غیر اخلاق رفتار پہچان سکے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Trong cộng đồng xử lý ngôn ngữ tự nhiên (N/P) thường được đồng ý rằng đạo lý nên được hoà nhập vào bất kỳ chương trình giảng dạy nào. Nhận thức và hiểu được các khái niệm cốt lõi liên quan là một điều kiện để theo dõi và tham gia vào cuộc họp về ngôn luận về ngôn ngữ đạo đức ngọt ngào. Ở đây chúng tôi có những tài liệu giáo dục sẵn sàng trong hình thức trượt tuyết và các bài tập về vấn đề đạo đức ở chọc dò tủy sống. Mục đích chính là tham gia vào khóa ngôn ngữ nội bộ. Bằng cách cung cấp những tài liệu này tự do, chúng tôi hướng tới việc giảm giới hạn để thêm đạo đức vào chương trình giảng dạy. Chúng tôi hy vọng rằng sự nhận thức lớn sẽ cho phép học sinh nhận diện hành vi phi đạo.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Umumiy o'z tilni boshqarish (NLP) jamiyasida, odamlar qo'yish maktabga birlashtirish kerak. Mavzu g'oyalarni o'rganish va tushunishni o'rganish mumkin, bizga kelishi va o'zgarishning asosiy NLP soʻzlariga qiziqarish muhim. We here present ready-made teaching material in the form of slides and practical exercises on ethical issues in NLP, which is primarily intended to be integrated into introductory NLP or computational linguistics courses.  Bu materialni xohlash bilan qo'llanmagan, biz o'quvchiga qo'shish natijasini ko'tarishga qaramaymiz. Biz o'ylaymiz, o'quvchilarni o'qituvchilarga o'xshash o'quvchilarni o'zgartirish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_hr>U prirodnoj zajednici obrađivanje jezika (NLP) se općenito slaže da se etika treba integrirati u bilo koji nastavni program. Svjestan i razumijevanje relevantnih osnovnih koncepta je predviđenje za slijedeće i sudjelovanje u diskusiji o etičkom NLP-u. Ovdje predstavljamo pripremljeni učiteljski materijal u obliku slajdova i praktičnih vježbi o etičkim pitanjima u NLP-u, koji je primarno namjeren integrirati u unutarnje NLP ili računalne jezičke kurse. Uspoređivanjem ovog materijala slobodno dostupnim, ciljamo smanjiti prag dodavanja etike nastavnom programu. Nadamo se da će povećanje svijesti omogućiti studentima da identifikuju potencijalno neobično ponašanje.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Обществено е договорено в общността за обработка на естествения език (НЛП), че етиката трябва да бъде интегрирана във всяка учебна програма. Осъзнаването и разбирането на съответните основни понятия е предпоставка за проследяване и участие в дискурса по етичен НЛП. Представяме готови учебни материали под формата на слайдове и практически упражнения по етични въпроси в НЛП, които са предназначени предимно да бъдат интегрирани в уводни курсове по НЛП или компютърна лингвистика. Чрез предоставянето на този материал свободно, ние се стремим да намалим прага за добавяне на етика към учебната програма. Надяваме се, че повишената осведоменост ще позволи на учениците да идентифицират потенциално неетично поведение.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_de>Es ist allgemein vereinbart, dass Ethik in jeden Lehrplan integriert werden sollte. Die Kenntnis und das Verständnis der relevanten Kernkonzepte ist Voraussetzung, um den Diskurs über ethische NLP zu verfolgen und daran teilzunehmen. Wir präsentieren hier fertiges Lehrmaterial in Form von Folien und praktischen Übungen zu ethischen Fragestellungen im NLP, das in erster Linie in einführende NLP- oder Computational Linguistics-Kurse integriert werden soll. Indem wir dieses Material frei zugänglich machen, wollen wir die Schwelle für Ethik in den Lehrplan senken. Wir hoffen, dass ein erhöhtes Bewusstsein es den Schülern ermöglicht, potenziell unethisches Verhalten zu erkennen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_nl>Het is algemeen overeengekomen in de natuurlijke taalverwerkingsgemeenschap (NLP) dat ethiek moet worden geïntegreerd in elk curriculum. Bewust zijn van en begrip van de relevante kernconcepten is een voorwaarde voor het volgen en deelnemen aan het discours over ethisch NLP. We presenteren hier kant-en-klare lesmateriaal in de vorm van dia's en praktische oefeningen over ethische vraagstukken in NLP, dat voornamelijk bedoeld is om te worden geïntegreerd in introductiecursussen NLP of computational linguïstiek. Door dit materiaal vrij beschikbaar te stellen, willen we de drempel verlagen om ethiek toe te voegen aan het curriculum. We hopen dat meer bewustzijn studenten in staat stelt potentieel onethisch gedrag te identificeren.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Det er generelt aftalt i det naturlige sprogbehandlingsfællesskab (NLP), at etik bør integreres i enhver læseplan. At være opmærksom på og forstå de relevante kernekoncepter er en forudsætning for at følge og deltage i diskursen om etisk NLP. Her præsenterer vi færdigt undervisningsmateriale i form af slides og praktiske øvelser om etiske spørgsmål i NLP, som primært er beregnet til at blive integreret i introducerende NLP- eller beregningslingvistiske kurser. Ved at gøre dette materiale frit tilgængeligt, sigter vi mod at sænke tærsklen til at tilføje etik til pensum. Vi håber, at øget bevidsthed vil gøre det muligt for eleverne at identificere potentielt uetisk adfærd.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_ko>자연언어처리(NLP) 분야에서 윤리는 어떤 과정에도 포함되어야 한다는 인식이 지배적이다.관련 핵심 개념을 이해하고 이해하는 것은 윤리 NLP 토론에 따르고 참여하는 선결 조건이다.우리는 여기에서 기존 교재와 NLP 윤리 문제의 실천 연습을 슬라이드 형식으로 보여주는데 주요 목적은 이를 NLP나 계산언어학 입문 과정에 통합시키는 것이다.이 자료들을 무료로 제공함으로써 우리의 목표는 과정에서 윤리의 문턱을 낮추는 것이다.우리는 의식을 높이면 학생들이 잠재적인 부도덕한 행위를 식별할 수 있기를 바란다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Jambo la kawaida imekubaliana katika jamii ya upasuaji wa lugha asilia (NLP) kwamba maadili yanapaswa kuunganishwa katika mfululizo wowote. Kutambua na kuelewa dhana za msingi zinazohusiana ni muhimu ya kufuatia na kushiriki mazungumzo kuhusu NLP ya kimaadili. We here present ready-made teaching material in the form of slides and practical exercises on ethical issues in NLP, which is primarily intended to be integrated into introductory NLP or computational linguistics courses.  Kwa kutengeneza vifaa hiki bure, tunakusudia kupunguza hatua hiyo kwa kuongeza maadili katika masomo. Tunatumaini kwamba ongezeko la uelewa utawasaidia wanafunzi kutambua tabia isiyo na uwezekano.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Adatça, tebigy diller işlemegi (NLP) jemgyýetinde etika islendikleri okuwçylara integral edilmelidir. Mazmunlyk esasy düşünjäniň habarynyň bolmagy we düşürmegiň ahlaky NLP diskusiýasynda gatnaşmagyň öňünden gerekli däldir. Bu ýerde NLP'da slaytlaryň we praktikalaryň etik meselelerinde taýýarlyk öwretmek materialyny görkezip taýýarlapdyk. Bu ilkinji gezek NLP ýa-da kompýuterlik lingwistiki kurslara integral edilmek üçin meýilleşdirilýär. Bu materiýa özgürläk ulaşarak, okuwçy programa etik goşmak üçin süýşini düşürmek üçin amaçladyk. Biziň bilinçylygyň köprüsi okuwçylara mümkin döwürmegi tanamak üçin mümkin däldir diýip umyt edýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Dit is algemeen ooreenkomstig in die natuurlike taal-prosessering (NLP) gemeenskap dat etika in enige onderwerp-program integreer moet word. Om bekend te wees van en te verstaan die relevante core konsepte is 'n voorspoediging vir volgende en deelnadering in die diskursie op etiese NLP. Ons het hier gereed gemaak onderwerpmaak in die vorm van skyf en praktiese oefeninge op etiese probleme in NLP voorstel, wat voorstel is om integreer te word in inligting van NLP of rekenaasjonale lingwisiese kurse. Deur hierdie materiaal vry beskikbaar te maak, doen ons om die drukklok te laat neer om etika te byvoeg aan die program. Ons hoop dat vergroot bevestigheid studente kan aktiveer om potensieel onetiese gedrag te identifiseer.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Në përgjithësi është dakord në komunitetin e përpunimit natyror të gjuhës (NLP) se etika duhet të integrohet në çdo program mësimi. Të jesh i vetëdijshëm dhe të kuptosh konceptet thelbësore të rëndësishme është një parakusht për ndjekjen dhe pjesëmarrjen në diskursin mbi NLP etike. We here present ready-made teaching material in the form of slides and practical exercises on ethical issues in NLP, which is primarily intended to be integrated into introductory NLP or computational linguistics courses.  Duke e bërë këtë material të disponueshëm lirisht, ne synojmë të ulim pragun për shtimin e etikës në programin e mësimit. Shpresojmë se ndërgjegjësimi i rritur do të lejojë studentët të identifikojnë sjellje potencialisht jo etike.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_id>Secara umum disetujui dalam komunitas proses bahasa alam (NLP) bahwa etika harus terintegrasi dalam kurikulum apapun. Mengetahui dan memahami konsep inti yang relevan adalah syarat untuk mengikuti dan berpartisipasi dalam pidato tentang NLP etika. Kami di sini mempersembahkan bahan pendidikan yang siap-siap dalam bentuk slide dan latihan praktis tentang masalah etika di NLP, yang utamanya dimaksud untuk diintegrasikan ke NLP penemuan atau kursus bahasa komputasi. Dengan membuat bahan ini tersedia secara bebas, kita bermaksud menurunkan ambang untuk menambahkan etika ke kurikulum. We hope that increased awareness will enable students to identify potentially unethical behavior.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_hy>Ընդհանուր առմամբ ընդունվում է, որ բնական լեզվի վերամշակում (ՆԼՊ) համայնքում էթիկան պետք է ինտեգրվի ցանկացած ուսումնական ծրագրի մեջ: Գիտելը և հասկանալը համապատասխանատու հիմնական գաղափարների մասին անհրաժեշտ է հետևելու և մասնակցելու էթիկական ՆԼՊ-ի մասին խոսակցության մեջ: Այստեղ մենք ներկայացնում ենք պատրաստ ուսուցման նյութ սլայդերի և պրակտիկ վարժությունների տեսքով ՆԼՊ-ում բարոյական հարցերի մասին, որոնք հիմնականում նշանակում են ինտեգրվել ՆԼՊ-ի ներկայացնող կամ հաշվարկման լեզվաբանական դասընթացների մեջ: Այս նյութը ազատ հասանելի դարձնելով, մենք նպատակում ենք նվազեցնել ուսումնական ծրագրերի էթիկայի ավելացման սահմանը: Մենք հույս ունենք, որ ավելի մեծ գիտակցությունը թույլ կտա ուսանողներին բացահայտել պոտենցիալ անէթիկ վարքագիծը:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_fa>معمولاً در جامعه پردازش زبان طبیعی (NLP) موافقت می‌شود که اخلاقی باید به هر برنامه آموزشی متصل شوند. از فهمیدن و درک کردن مفهوم اصلی مربوط به این مفهوم پیش از این است که برای تعقیب کردن و مشارکت در صحبت های NLP اخلاقی باشد. ما در اینجا ماده آموزش آماده آماده آماده را در شکل اسلاید ها و تمرین های عملی در مسائل اخلاقی NLP پیشنهاد می کنیم، که در اصل هدف دارد که به کلاس های زبان‌شناسی داخلی NLP یا محاسبه باشد. با اینکه این مواد را آزاد در دسترسی قرار دهیم، هدف می‌گیریم که سطح را کاهش دهیم تا اخلاقی را به برنامه آموزشی اضافه کنیم. ما امیدواریم که آگاهی افزایش دهد که دانش آموزان را اجازه دهند که احتمالاً رفتار غیر اخلاقی را شناسایی کنند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_az>Təbiətli dil işləməsi (NLP) ümmətinə etik hər bir təhsil programına qatılması lazımdır. Məhz məqsədilə məhz məqsədilərin nəticəsini biləcək və anlamaq etik NLP söhbətlərində olmaq və iştirak etmək üçün əvvəlcə münasibdir. Biz burada NLP'deki etik məsələlər haqqında müəyyən edilmiş təhsil maddələrini NLP və hesablama dilində birləşdirmək üçün hazırlanmış təhsil maddələrini göstəririk. Bu materyalı özgür olaraq müəyyən edərək, öyrənmək programına etik əlavə etmək üçün sütunu azaltmaq istəyirik. Bizim ümid edirik ki, artıq xəbərdarlığı tələbələrə mümkün olmayan davranışları tanımayacaq.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>It is generally agreed upon in the natural language processing (NLP) community that ethics should be integrated into any curriculum.  মূল ধারণা সম্পর্কে সচেতন এবং বুঝতে পারার প্রয়োজনীয় নৈতিক এনএলপির কথোপকথনে অংশগ্রহণের জন্য। এনএলপির নৈতিক বিষয়ের মাধ্যমে স্লাইড এবং বৈশিষ্ট্যিক প্রশিক্ষণের মাধ্যমে আমরা এখানে প্রস্তুত শিক্ষার উপাদান উপস্থাপন করছি, যা প্রধান উদ্দেশ্য হচ্ছে এনএল এই উপাদানের মুক্তি পাওয়ার মাধ্যমে আমরা কার্কুলে নৈতিক যোগ করার উদ্দেশ্য নীতি কমিয়ে দিয়েছি। আমরা আশা করি যে সচেতনতা বাড়িয়ে দেবে শিক্ষার্থীদের সম্ভাব্য অসম্ভব আচরণ চিহ্নিত করবে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>U prirodnoj zajednici obrade jezika (NLP) se općenito slaže da se etika treba integrirati u bilo koji nastavni program. Svjesno i razumijevanje relevantnih osnovnih koncepta je predviđenje za slijedeće i sudjelovanje u diskusiji o etičkom NLP-u. Ovdje predstavljamo pripremljeni učiteljski materijal u obliku slajdova i praktičnih vježbi o etičkim pitanjima u NLP-u, koji je primarno namjeren biti integrisan u unutrašnje NLP ili kompjuterske jezičke kurse. Uspoređenjem ovog materijala slobodno dostupnim, ciljamo se smanjiti prag dodavanja etike nastavnom programu. Nadamo se da će povećanje svijesti omogućiti studentima da identifikuju potencijalno neobično ponašanje.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>V komunitě zpracování přirozeného jazyka (NLP) se obecně shoduje, že etika by měla být integrována do jakéhokoliv učebního plánu. Vědomí a porozumění příslušným základním konceptům je nezbytným předpokladem pro následování a účast v diskurze o etické NLP. Představujeme připravené výukové materiály ve formě prezentací a praktických cvičení na etické otázky v NLP, které mají být primárně integrovány do úvodních kurzů NLP nebo výpočetní lingvistiky. Zpřístupněním těchto materiálů se snažíme snížit práh k přidání etiky do učebních osnov. Doufáme, že zvýšené povědomí umožní studentům identifikovat potenciálně neetické chování.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>En general, a la comunitat del processament natural de llenguatges (NLP) s'acorda que l'ètica hauria d'integrar-se en qualsevol currículum. Being aware of and understanding the relevant core concepts is a prerequisite for following and participating in the discourse on ethical NLP.  Aquí presentem material d'ensenyament preparat en forma de diapositives i exercicis pràctics sobre qüestions ètiques en NLP, que està destinat principalment a integrar-se en curss introductius de NLP o de lingüística computacional. Met aquest material lliurament a disposició, mirem a baixar el umbre d'afegir ètica al currículum. Esperem que un augment de la consciència permetrà als estudiants identificar comportaments potencialment desitòtics.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_am>በጥያቄ ቋንቋ ማቀናቀል (NLP) ማኅበረሰብ የሕግ ትምህርት ወደ ማንኛውም ትምህርት ማቀናቀል እንዲገባ ይስማማቸዋል፡፡ የአካባቢው አካባቢዎች ማስተዋል እና ማስተዋል የኢንተርናዊ NLP ንግግር ለመከተል እና ለመጋጠም ጉዳይ ነው፡፡ ወደዚህ በNLP የኢንተርናዊ ጉዳዮች ላይ በተዘጋጀ ሳላዳ እና የኢንተርኔት ትምህርት ትምህርት ማህበረሰብ አቀናብናለን፡፡ ይህንን ዕቃዎች ነፃነት በመፍታት፣ የመድረቡን መድረክ ለመምህርት ማቀናቀል እናስፈልጋለን፡፡ ማስታወቂያውን የሚጨምር ተማሪዎችን የስልጣን ሁኔታ ማግኘት እንዲችል ተስፋ እናደርጋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_et>Looduskeele töötlemise (NLP) kogukonnas on üldiselt kokku lepitud, et eetika tuleks integreerida igasse õppekavasse. Asjakohaste põhikontseptsioonide teadlikkus ja mõistmine on eeltingimus eetilise uue õppekava diskursuse jälgimiseks ja osalemiseks. Esitleme valmismaterjali slaidide ja praktiliste harjutuste kujul NLP eetilistel küsimustel, mis on eelkõige mõeldud integreerimiseks NLP sissejuhatavatesse või arvutusliku keeleteaduse kursustesse. Selle materjali vabalt kättesaadavaks tegemisega püüame vähendada eetika lisamise künnist õppekavasse. Loodame, et suurem teadlikkus võimaldab õpilastel tuvastada potentsiaalselt ebaeetilist käitumist.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Luonnonkielen käsittelyyhteisössä (NLP) sovitaan yleisesti, että etiikka tulisi sisällyttää mihin tahansa opetussuunnitelmaan. Asiaankuuluvien ydinkäsitteiden tunteminen ja ymmärtäminen on edellytys eettisestä NLP:stä käytävän keskustelun seuraamiselle ja osallistumiselle. Esitämme valmiin opetusmateriaalin dioina ja käytännön harjoituksina NLP:n eettisistä kysymyksistä, jotka on tarkoitettu ensisijaisesti integroitavaksi NLP:n johdantokursseihin tai laskennalliseen kielitieteeseen. Luomalla aineiston vapaasti saataville pyrimme alentamaan kynnystä lisätä etiikkaa opetussuunnitelmaan. Toivomme, että lisääntynyt tietoisuus antaa opiskelijoille mahdollisuuden tunnistaa mahdollisesti epäeettistä käyttäytymistä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ha>An yi yarda da shi a cikin jamii na aikatãwar harshe na natura (NLP) cẽwa kada a haɗa addinin zuwa wani kurs. Kusani kuma ka fahimta da gane idãnun muhimmada na muhimmada ne da za'a bi da kuma ta yi shirin da maganar NLP. Tuna halatar da takardar da aka samar da wa'ar da aka yi wa tsari kamar misalin lissafa da masu aikin muhimmada na NLP, wanda aka yi nufin a haɗa cikin shirin na NLP ko cikin linguistic na lissafa. Ina iya samar da wannan abu da aka buɗa, sai mu yi amfani da shi sai mu ƙara bangon na kafin da za'a ƙara tamkar karãtun. We hope that increased awareness will enable students to identify potentially unethical behavior.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>בדרך כלל מסכים בקהילה של עיבוד השפה הטבעית (NLP) שאתיקה צריכה להיות מושלמת בכל תוכנית לימודים. להיות מודע לרעיונות הליבודים הרלוונטיים והבנה הם התנאי הקדמי לעקוב אחריו ולהשתתף בהנחה על NLP אתית. אנו מציגים כאן חומר לימוד מוכן בצורה של גלישות ותרגילים מעשיים על עניינים אתיים ב-NLP, שמתכוון בעיקר להשתלב במדרגות NLP המרכזיות או לימודים שפתיים מחשבים. על ידי שהחומר הזה יהיה זמין בחינם, אנחנו מתכוונים להוריד את המגבל להוסיף אתיקה לתוכנית הלימודים. אנו מקווים שהמודעות הגבוהה תאפשר לסטודנטים לזהות התנהגות פוטנציאלית לא אתית.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>V skupnosti za obdelavo naravnega jezika (NLP) se na splošno dogovori, da je treba etiko vključiti v vsak učni načrt. Zavedanje in razumevanje relevantnih osnovnih konceptov je predpogoj za spremljanje in sodelovanje v diskurzu o etičnem NLP. Predstavljamo vam pripravljeno učno gradivo v obliki diapozitivov in praktičnih vaj o etičnih vprašanjih v NLP, ki je predvsem namenjeno vključevanju v uvodne NLP oziroma računalniške jezikoslovje. S prosto dostopnostjo tega gradiva želimo znižati prag dodajanja etike v učni načrt. Upamo, da bo večja ozaveščenost študentom omogočila prepoznavanje potencialno neetičnega vedenja.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Punika dipun ngomongke sampeyan ing sakjane kanggo nggawe lengkang pribadi (NLP) lan akeh etik kudu entekake nang program sing apik. Rasané awakdhéwé karo ngbagané kuwi tindakan piwong sing klêrung kuwi, kuwi arep mesthi awak dhéwé nggawe gerakan kelas ning kejahatan NLP etik. Awak dhéwé éntuk akeh nggawe mesthi, akeh-akeh wé nggawe geratan cara-cara nik nggawe pratiki iki ning NLP, iki dadi wis nguasai perusahaan seneng diputara NLP karo tiku kelompatistik. Ngawe jenis-jenis hukum sing wis arep liyo, awak dhéwé njaluk kanggo nambah etik kanggo nggawe program. Awak dhéwé éntuk sing katéwan awak dhéwé iso ngejaraké awak dhéwé kuwi mau, nik awak dhéwé kuwi kesempatan awak dhéwé.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>སྤྱིར་བཏང་ན། རང་རྒྱུན་གྱི་སྐད་ཡིག་ལས་སྦྱོར་བའི་ཚོགས་སྡེར་གྱི་ནང་དུ་བློ་གཏོང་ཡོད། Being aware of and understanding the relevant core concepts is a prerequisite for following and participating in the discourse on ethical NLP. We here present ready-made teaching material in the form of slides and practical exercises on ethical issues in NLP, which is primarily intended to be integrated into introductory NLP or computational linguistics courses. འུ་ཅག་གི་མི་མང་ཆེ་མཐོང་སྣང་བྱེད་ཐུབ་པ་ལས་མཐོང་གི་རྣམ་པ་ལྟར་གཞན་ཞིག་གནང་ཡོད་པ་ལས། ང་ཚོས་རྟོགས་པའི་ཆེད་དུ་རྒྱས་ཡོད་ཚད་གིས་ཤེས་པ་ཚོར་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་མེད་པའི་སྒེར་གྱི་རྒྱུ་དངོས།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>MiniVQA-A resource to build your tailored VQA competition<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>ini<fixed-case>VQA</fixed-case> - A resource to build your tailored <fixed-case>VQA</fixed-case> competition</title>
      <author><first>Jean-Benoit</first><last>Delbrouck</last></author>
      <pages>55–58</pages>
      <abstract>MiniVQA is a Jupyter notebook to build a tailored VQA competition for your students. The resource creates all the needed resources to create a classroom competition that engages and inspires your students on the free, self-service Kaggle platform. InClass competitions make <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning</a> fun ‘.</abstract>
      <url hash="50758ec6">2021.teachingnlp-1.8</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.8</doi>
      <bibkey>delbrouck-2021-minivqa</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/visual-question-answering">Visual Question Answering</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>A Balanced and Broadly Targeted Computational Linguistics Curriculum</title>
      <author><first>Emma</first><last>Manning</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathan</first><last>Schneider</last></author>
      <author><first>Amir</first><last>Zeldes</last></author>
      <pages>65–69</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the primarily-graduate computational linguistics and NLP curriculum at Georgetown University, a U.S. university that has seen significant growth in these areas in recent years. We reflect on the principles behind our curriculum choices, including recognizing the various academic backgrounds and goals of our students ; teaching a variety of skills with an emphasis on working directly with data ; encouraging collaboration and interdisciplinary work ; and including languages beyond English. We reflect on challenges we have encountered, such as the difficulty of teaching programming skills alongside NLP fundamentals, and discuss areas for future growth.</abstract>
      <url hash="a6dfe8c5">2021.teachingnlp-1.11</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.11</doi>
      <bibkey>manning-etal-2021-balanced</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>The Flipped Classroom model for teaching Conditional Random Fields in an NLP course<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> course</title>
      <author><first>Manex</first><last>Agirrezabal</last></author>
      <pages>80–86</pages>
      <abstract>In this article, we show and discuss our experience in applying the flipped classroom method for teaching <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conditional_random_field">Conditional Random Fields</a> in a Natural Language Processing course. We present the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Action_(philosophy)">activities</a> that we developed together with their relationship to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_complexity">cognitive complexity model</a> (Bloom’s taxonomy). After this, we provide our own reflections and expectations of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> itself. Based on the evaluation got from students, it seems that students learn about the topic and also that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> is rewarding for some students. Additionally, we discuss some shortcomings and we propose possible solutions to them. We conclude the paper with some possible future work.</abstract>
      <url hash="e50843ff">2021.teachingnlp-1.13</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="48a32274">2021.teachingnlp-1.13.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.pdf</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>agirrezabal-2021-flipped</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>An Immersive Computational Text Analysis Course for Non-Computer Science Students at Barnard College</title>
      <author><first>Adam</first><last>Poliak</last></author>
      <author><first>Jalisha</first><last>Jenifer</last></author>
      <pages>92–95</pages>
      <abstract>We provide an overview of a new Computational Text Analysis course that will be taught at Barnard College over a six week period in May and June 2021. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Course_(education)">course</a> is targeted to non Computer Science at a Liberal Arts college that wish to incorporate fundamental Natural Language Processing tools in their re- search and studies. During the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Course_(education)">course</a>, students will complete daily programming tutorials, read and review contemporary research papers, and propose and develop independent research projects.</abstract>
      <url hash="b1e5be1c">2021.teachingnlp-1.15</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.15</doi>
      <bibkey>poliak-jenifer-2021-immersive</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>Learning How To Learn NLP : Developing Introductory Concepts Through Scaffolded Discovery<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>: Developing Introductory Concepts Through Scaffolded Discovery</title>
      <author><first>Alexandra</first><last>Schofield</last></author>
      <author><first>Richard</first><last>Wicentowski</last></author>
      <author><first>Julie</first><last>Medero</last></author>
      <pages>131–137</pages>
      <abstract>We present a scaffolded discovery learning approach to introducing concepts in a Natural Language Processing course aimed at computer science students at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liberal_arts_colleges_in_the_United_States">liberal arts institutions</a>. We describe some of the objectives of this approach, as well as presenting specific ways that four of our discovery-based assignments combine specific natural language processing concepts with broader analytic skills. We argue this approach helps prepare students for many possible future paths involving both application and innovation of NLP technology by emphasizing experimental data navigation, experiment design, and awareness of the complexities and challenges of analysis.</abstract>
      <url hash="988d906c">2021.teachingnlp-1.23</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.23</doi>
      <bibkey>schofield-etal-2021-learning</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="25">
      <title>Teaching NLP outside <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistics">Linguistics</a> and Computer Science classrooms : Some challenges and some opportunities<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> outside Linguistics and Computer Science classrooms: Some challenges and some opportunities</title>
      <author><first>Sowmya</first><last>Vajjala</last></author>
      <pages>149–159</pages>
      <abstract>NLP’s sphere of influence went much beyond <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_science">computer science research</a> and the development of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software">software applications</a> in the past decade. We see people using NLP methods in a range of academic disciplines from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asian_studies">Asian Studies</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinical_Oncology">Clinical Oncology</a>. We also notice the presence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> as a module in most of the data science curricula within and outside of regular university setups. These <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Course_(education)">courses</a> are taken by students from very diverse backgrounds. This paper takes a closer look at some issues related to teaching <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP</a> to these diverse audiences based on my classroom experiences, and identifies some challenges the instructors face, particularly when there is no ecosystem of related courses for the students. In this process, it also identifies a few challenge areas for both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP researchers</a> and tool developers.</abstract>
      <url hash="e04207cb">2021.teachingnlp-1.25</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.teachingnlp-1.25</doi>
      <bibkey>vajjala-2021-teaching</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>