<collection id="2021.triton">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2022-01-11">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Translation and Interpreting Technology Online Conference</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ruslan</first><last>Mitkov</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Vilelmini</first><last>Sosoni</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Julie Christine</first><last>Gigu&#232;re</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elena</first><last>Murgolo</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Deysel</last></editor>
      <publisher>INCOMA Ltd.</publisher>
      <address>Held Online</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="26951116">2021.triton-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="df7cadab">2021.triton-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>triton-2021-translation</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Remote Interpreting: Platform Testing in a University Setting</title>
      <author><first>Francesco</first><last>Saina</last></author>
      <pages>57&#8211;67</pages>
      <abstract>This work is based on the testing of a remote interpreting (RI) delivery platform conducted a year before the disruptive COVID-19 pandemic outbreak, and aimed at assessing the use and experience of such systems in a university setting. A survey was administered to the different groups of users (interpreters, audience, and speakers) involved in two tests to collect their responses and remarks, and assess trends and perceptions in their experience. According to emerging findings of the research project, RI was already considered to be an indisputable yet burgeoning resource for conference settings with potential convenience and benefits for each group of users. However, participants&#8217; remarks early suggested that all the parties involved in the industry need to collaborate to effectively improve and enhance such services. Specific training on RI modalities would also appear to be increasingly necessary for interpreters to adapt to new raising working conditions and meet a thriving demand&#8212;and training institutions would ever more have to offer adequate solutions, while this technological shift also requires receptiveness and adaptability to an abruptly diversifying and evolving profession.</abstract>
      <url hash="5110b92c">2021.triton-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>saina-2021-remote</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title><fixed-case>S</fixed-case>mar<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>erp: A <fixed-case>CAI</fixed-case> System to Support Simultaneous Interpreters in Real-Time</title>
      <author><first>Susana</first><last>Rodriguez</last></author>
      <author><first>Roberto</first><last>Gretter</last></author>
      <author><first>Marco</first><last>Matassoni</last></author>
      <author><first>Alvaro</first><last>Alonso</last></author>
      <author><first>Oscar</first><last>Corcho</last></author>
      <author><first>Mariano</first><last>Rico</last></author>
      <author><first>Falavigna</first><last>Daniele</last></author>
      <pages>102&#8211;109</pages>
      <abstract>We present a system to support simultaneous interpreting in specific domains. The system is going to be developed through a strong synergy among technicians, mostly experts on both speech and text processing, and end-users, i.e. professional interpreters who define the requirements and will test the final product. Some preliminary encouraging results have been achieved on benchmark tests collected with the aim of measuring the performance of single components of the whole system, namely: automatic speech recognition (ASR) and named entity recognition.</abstract>
      <url hash="6cd7adf7">2021.triton-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>rodriguez-etal-2021-smarterp</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Sign Language Translation in a Healthcare Setting</title>
      <author><first>Floris</first><last>Roelofsen</last></author>
      <author><first>Lyke</first><last>Esselink</last></author>
      <author><first>Shani</first><last>Mende-Gillings</last></author>
      <author><first>Anika</first><last>Smeijers</last></author>
      <pages>110&#8211;124</pages>
      <abstract>Communication between healthcare professionals and deaf patients is challenging, and the current COVID-19 pandemic makes this issue even more acute. Sign language interpreters can often not enter hospitals and face masks make lipreading impossible. To address this urgent problem, we developed a system which allows healthcare professionals to translate sentences that are frequently used in the diagnosis and treatment of COVID-19 into Sign Language of the Netherlands (NGT). Translations are displayed by means of videos and avatar animations. The architecture of the system is such that it could be extended to other applications and other sign languages in a relatively straightforward way.</abstract>
      <url hash="4eecfce4">2021.triton-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>roelofsen-etal-2021-sign</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>What Makes a Concept Complex? Measuring Conceptual Complexity as a Precursor for Text Simplification</title>
      <author><first>Anne</first><last>Eschenbruecher</last></author>
      <pages>154&#8211;160</pages>
      <abstract>Advancements within the field of text simplification (TS) have primarily been within syntactic or lexical simplification. However, conceptual simplification has previously been identified as another field of TS that has the potential to significantly improve reading comprehension. A first step to measuring conceptual simplification is the classification of concepts as either complex or simple. This research-in-progress paper proposes a new definition of conceptual complexity alongside a simple machine-learning approach that performs a binary classification task to distinguish between simple and complex concepts. It is proposed that this be a first step when developing new text simplification models that operate on a conceptual level.</abstract>
      <url hash="2a4d4a75">2021.triton-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>eschenbruecher-2021-makes</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Feedback in Online Translation Courses and the Covid Era</title>
      <author><first>Miguel A.</first><last>Jimenez-Crespo</last></author>
      <pages>208&#8211;215</pages>
      <abstract>The Covid pandemic upended translation teaching globally. The forced move to online teaching represented a gargantuan challenge for anyone only experienced in face-to-face teaching. Online translation teaching requires distinct approaches to guarantee that students can reach the targeted learning goals. This paper presents a literature review on the provision of effective feedback in the light of these drastic changes in translation teaching as well as a description as how existing research on online feedback for translation training has been applied to the design of online courses at the translation program at Rutgers University.</abstract>
      <url hash="8461d671">2021.triton-1.24</url>
      <bibkey>jimenez-crespo-2021-feedback</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>