<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.isa">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-10-27">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 17th Joint ACL - ISO Workshop on Interoperable Semantic Annotation</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Harry</first><last>Bunt</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Groningen, The Netherlands (online)</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="c9238150">2021.isa-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="f6e3649b">2021.isa-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>isa-2021-joint</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Towards the ISO 24617-2-compliant Typology of Metacognitive Events<fixed-case>ISO</fixed-case> 24617-2-compliant Typology of Metacognitive Events</title>
      <author><first>Volha</first><last>Petukhova</last></author>
      <author><first>Hafiza</first><last>Erum Manzoor</last></author>
      <pages>14–19</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents ongoing efforts in design of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typology_(psychology)">typology</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metacognition">metacognitive events</a> observed in a multimodal dialogue. The typology will serve as a tool to identify relations between participants’ dispositions, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue">dialogue actions</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metacognition">metacognitive indicators</a>. It will be used to support an assessment of metacognitive knowledge, experiences and strategies of dialogue participants. Based on the mutidimensional dialogue model defined within the framework of Dynamic Interpretation Theory and ISO 24617-2 annotation standard, the proposed approach provides a systematic analysis of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metacognition">metacognitive events</a> in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue">dialogue acts</a>, i.e. concepts that dialogue research community is used to operate on in dialogue modelling and system design tasks.</abstract>
      <url hash="321c4619">2021.isa-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>petukhova-erum-manzoor-2021-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Annotating Quantified Phenomena in Complex Sentence Structures Using the Example of Generalising Statements in Literary Texts</title>
      <author><first>Tillmann</first><last>Dönicke</last></author>
      <author><first>Luisa</first><last>Gödeke</last></author>
      <author><first>Hanna</first><last>Varachkina</last></author>
      <pages>20–32</pages>
      <abstract>We present a tagset for the annotation of quantification which we currently use to annotate certain quantified statements in fictional works of literature. Literary texts feature a rich variety in expressing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantification_(linguistics)">quantification</a>, including a broad range of lexemes to express quantifiers and complex sentence structures to express the restrictor and the nuclear scope of a quantification. Our tagset consists of seven tags and covers all types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantifier_(linguistics)">quantification</a> that occur in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language">natural language</a>, including vague quantification and generic quantification. In the second part of the paper, we introduce our German corpus with annotations of generalising statements, which form a proper subset of quantified statements.</abstract>
      <url hash="dd0020c4">2021.isa-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>donicke-etal-2021-annotating</bibkey>
    <title_ar>شرح الظواهر الكمية في تراكيب الجمل المعقدة باستخدام مثال لتعميم العبارات في النصوص الأدبية</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Annotation de phénomènes quantifiés dans des structures de phrases complexes à l'aide de l'exemple de généralisation d'énoncés dans des textes littéraires</title_fr>
      <title_pt>Anotando Fenômenos Quantificados em Estruturas de Frases Complexas Usando o Exemplo de Generalizações em Textos Literários</title_pt>
      <title_zh>用文本大概陈示例注杂句结构之量化</title_zh>
      <title_es>Anotación de fenómenos cuantificados en estructuras de oraciones complejas utilizando el ejemplo de la generalización de declaraciones en textos literarios</title_es>
      <title_ja>文献テキストの一般化文の例を使用した複雑な文章構造における定量化された現象の注釈付け</title_ja>
      <title_hi>एनोटेटिंग जटिल वाक्य संरचनाओं में मात्रात्मक घटना साहित्यिक ग्रंथों में सामान्यीकृत कथनों के उदाहरण का उपयोग कर</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Аннотирование количественных явлений в сложных структурах предложений на примере обобщающих утверждений в литературных текстах</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Feiniméin Chainníochtaithe a Anótáil i Struchtúir Pianbhreithe Coimpléascacha ag Úsáid Sampla de Ráitis Ghinearálta i dTéacsanna Liteartha</title_ga>
      <title_ka>კვანტიფიკაციული ფინომენს კომპლექსი სიტყვების სტრუქტურაში გამოყენება სიტყვების ტექსტურაში</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Mennyiségi jelenségek megjegyzése komplex mondatszerkezetekben az állítások általánosításának példájával irodalmi szövegekben</title_hu>
      <title_el>Παρατήρηση ποσοτικών φαινομένων σε σύνθετες δομές φράσεων χρησιμοποιώντας το παράδειγμα γενικοποίησης δηλώσεων σε λογοτεχνικά κείμενα</title_el>
      <title_it>Annotazione di fenomeni quantificati in strutture di frasi complesse utilizzando l'esempio di generalizzazione di dichiarazioni nei testi letterari</title_it>
      <title_kk>Қосымша сөз құрылымындағы шектелген феноманы белгілеу</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Annotating Quantified Phenomena in Complex Sentence Structures Using the Example of Generalising Statements in Literary Texts</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Nurodomi kiekybiniai reiškiniai sudėtingų sakinių struktūrose naudojant literatūros tekstuose pateiktų bendrųjų pareiškimų pavyzdžią</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Menganotasi Fenomena Berkuantifikasi dalam Struktur Hukuman Kompleks Mengguna Contoh Pengumuman Perkataan dalam Teks Literari</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ലൈറ്ററി ടെക്സ്റ്റുകളിലെ പൊതുവാക്കുന്ന വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതിന്റെ ഉദാഹരണമായി കോമ്പ്ലക്സ് ശിക്ഷ ക്രമീകരണങ്ങളില</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Annotazzjoni ta’ fenomeni kwantifikati fi Strutturi ta’ Sentenza Komplessa bl-Użu ta’ Eżempju ta’ Dikjarazzjonijiet Ġeneralizzanti fit-Testi Litterarji</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Комплекс өгүүлбэр бүтээгдэхүүний хэмжээний феномын хэмжээний хэмжээний хэмжээний хэмжээний хэмжээний хэмжээний хэмжээний хэмжээний хэлбэрүүдийг ашиглаж</title_mn>
      <title_no>Merkar kvantifisert fenomen i komplekse setningsstruktur ved å bruka eksempel for generellisering av uttaler i literre tekstar</title_no>
      <title_pl>Annotacja zjawisk ilościowych w złożonych strukturach zdań na przykładzie uogólniania stwierdzeń w tekstach literackich</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Annotirajući kvantificiranu fenomenu u kompleksnoj strukturi kazne Koristeći primjer generalizacije izjava u literarnim tekstima</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Adnotarea fenomenelor cuantificate în structurile complexe de sentințe folosind exemplul de generalizare a declarațiilor în textele literare</title_ro>
      <title_ta>பொதுவான உரையில் பொதுவான விகிதத்தை பயன்படுத்தும் குறிப்பிட்ட பொருள்களை அறிவிக்கிறது</title_ta>
      <title_so>Annotation Quantified Phenomena in Complex Sentences Structures using the example of Generalising Statements in Literary Texts</title_so>
      <title_sv>Notera kvantifierade fenomen i komplexa meningsstrukturer med hjälp av exempel på generalisering av uttalanden i litterära texter</title_sv>
      <title_si>සම්පූර්ණ වාක්ය සංස්කරණයේ ක්‍රියාත්මක විශේෂ ප්‍රමාණය සඳහා ක්‍රියාත්මක ප්‍රමාණය සඳහා සාමාන්‍ය විශේෂ</title_si>
      <title_ur>مکمل سنت ساختاروں میں Quantified Phenomena کا انٹیٹ کیا جاتا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Thông tin người thường được phân tích trong cấu trúc án phức tạp Sử dụng ví dụ về các câu nói chung trong Văn học</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Анотиране на количествени феномени в сложни структури на изречения чрез пример за обобщаващи изявления в литературни текстове</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Annotatie van gekwantificeerde fenomenen in complexe zinsstructuren aan de hand van het voorbeeld van het generaliseren van uitspraken in literaire teksten</title_nl>
      <title_da>Anmærkning af kvantificerede fænomener i komplekse sætningsstrukturer ved hjælp af eksemplet på generalisering af udtalelser i litterære tekster</title_da>
      <title_hr>Annotirajući kvantificiranu fenomenu u kompleksnim strukturama kazne Koristeći primjer generalizacije izjava u književnim tekstima</title_hr>
      <title_de>Annotierung quantifizierter Phänomene in komplexen Satzstrukturen am Beispiel der Generalisierung von Aussagen in literarischen Texten</title_de>
      <title_ko>문학 텍스트 중의 범화 진술을 예로 삼아 복잡한 문장 구조 중의 양적 현상을 해석하다</title_ko>
      <title_id>Menganotasi fenomena berkwantifikasi dalam struktur kalimat kompleks menggunakan contoh pernyataan generalisasi dalam teks sastra</title_id>
      <title_tr>Kompliks söz yapılarında Quantified Fenomena duyurular</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Akitangaza Tamko zilizotolewa katika Miundombinu ya Hukumu ya Complex kwa kutumia mfano wa Maelezo ya Kijumla katika Maandishi ya Fasihi</title_sw>
      <title_fa>نویسندگی فینوم مقدار در ساختارهای کلمه پیچیده با استفاده از مثال توضیح عمومی در متن نوشته</title_fa>
      <title_af>Opmerking van Quantifiseerde Fenomena in Volledige Uitdrukking Struktures gebruik die Voorbeeld van Generalisering Opmerking in Literary Teks</title_af>
      <title_sq>Duke vënë në dukje fenomenet e kuantifikuara në strukturat e dënimeve komplekse duke përdorur shembullin e shprehjeve të gjeneralizuara në tekstet letërore</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Օգտագործելով գրական տեքստներում ընդհանուր հայտարարությունների օրինակը</title_hy>
      <title_az>Kompleksiz Sözü Quruluqlarında Quantified Fenomena İşaretlənir</title_az>
      <title_bs>Annotirajući kvantificiranu fenomenu u kompleksnim strukturama kazne Koristeći primjer generalizacije izjava u književnim tekstima</title_bs>
      <title_bn>সাহিত্য টেক্সটের সাধারণ বিবৃতির উদাহরণ ব্যবহার করে কমপ্লেক্স শাস্তি ক্ষেত্রে বৈশিষ্ট্যের বৈশিষ্ট্যের বিষয়বস্তুকে</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Anotar fenomens quantificats en estructures de sentença complexa utilitzant l'exemple de declaracions generalitzats en textos literaris</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Anotace kvantifikovaných jevů ve složitých větových strukturách na příkladu generalizace výroků v literárních textech</title_cs>
      <title_et>Kvantifitseeritud nähtuste annoteerimine keerukates lausestruktuurides, kasutades kirjandustekstides üldiste avalduste näidet</title_et>
      <title_fi>Kvantifioitujen ilmiöiden merkitseminen monimutkaisissa lauserakenteissa käyttäen esimerkkiä yleistävistä lausumista kirjallisuusteksteissä</title_fi>
      <title_am>Annotating Quantified Phenomena in Complex Sentence Structures Using the Example of Generalising Statements in Literary Texts</title_am>
      <title_jv>Ngawe</title_jv>
      <title_he>מצביעה על פנומנים מוגדרים במבנות גזרות מורכבות בשימוש בדוגמא של הצהרות הגנרליזציות בטקסטים הספריים</title_he>
      <title_sk>Anotiranje kvantificiranih pojavov v kompleksnih stavkovnih strukturah z uporabo primera splošnih izjav v literarnih besedilih</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>མཇུག་བསྡུ་ཡོད་པའི་ཚིག་རྩོམ་འབྲས་ལ་ཐོག་པའི་མིང་ལ་སྟོན་པའི་དཔེ་བརྗོད།</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم مجموعة علامات للتعليق التوضيحي للتقدير الكمي والتي نستخدمها حاليًا للتعليق على بعض العبارات المحددة الكمية في الأعمال الأدبية الخيالية. تتميز النصوص الأدبية بتنوع غني في التعبير عن القياس الكمي ، بما في ذلك مجموعة واسعة من المفردات للتعبير عن المحددات الكمية وهياكل الجمل المعقدة للتعبير عن المقيد والنطاق النووي للتقدير الكمي. تتكون مجموعة العلامات الخاصة بنا من سبع علامات وتغطي جميع أنواع القياس الكمي التي تحدث في اللغة الطبيعية ، بما في ذلك القياس الكمي الغامض والقياس الكمي العام. في الجزء الثاني من الورقة ، نقدم مجموعة النصوص الألمانية الخاصة بنا مع التعليقات التوضيحية لبيانات التعميم ، والتي تشكل مجموعة فرعية مناسبة من البيانات المحددة الكمية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos um conjunto de tags para a anotação de quantificação que usamos atualmente para anotar certas declarações quantificadas em obras literárias de ficção. Os textos literários apresentam uma rica variedade na expressão de quantificação, incluindo uma ampla gama de lexemas para expressar quantificadores e estruturas de sentenças complexas para expressar o restritor e o escopo nuclear de uma quantificação. Nosso conjunto de tags consiste em sete tags e abrange todos os tipos de quantificação que ocorrem em linguagem natural, incluindo quantificação vaga e quantificação genérica. Na segunda parte do artigo, apresentamos nosso corpus alemão com anotações de afirmações generalizantes, que formam um subconjunto próprio de afirmações quantificadas.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Nous présentons un jeu de balises pour l'annotation de quantification que nous utilisons actuellement pour annoter certaines déclarations quantifiées dans des œuvres littéraires fictives. Les textes littéraires présentent une grande variété d'expressions de quantification, y compris un large éventail de lexèmes pour exprimer des quantificateurs et des structures de phrases complexes pour exprimer le restricteur et la portée nucléaire d'une quantification. Notre jeu de balises se compose de sept étiquettes et couvre tous les types de quantification qui se produisent en langage naturel, y compris la quantification vague et la quantification générique. Dans la deuxième partie de l'article, nous présentons notre corpus allemand avec des annotations d'énoncés généralisants, qui constituent un sous-ensemble approprié d'énoncés quantifiés.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos un conjunto de etiquetas para la anotación de la cuantificación que utilizamos actualmente para anotar ciertas afirmaciones cuantificadas en obras literarias ficticias. Los textos literarios presentan una amplia variedad de expresiones de cuantificación, incluyendo una amplia gama de lexemas para expresar cuantificadores y estructuras de oraciones complejas para expresar el limitador y el alcance nuclear de una cuantificación. Nuestro conjunto de etiquetas consta de siete etiquetas y cubre todos los tipos de cuantificación que se producen en el lenguaje natural, incluida la cuantificación vaga y la cuantificación genérica. En la segunda parte del artículo, presentamos nuestro corpus alemán con anotaciones de declaraciones generalizadoras, que forman un subconjunto adecuado de declaraciones cuantificadas.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_zh>我们发出一个量化注的标签集,我们眼前用它注释虚构文学作品中的某些量化陈述。 夫文本乎表量化,多样性乎表量词,词素乎致量化,核范围乎杂句。 凡签集由七,涵盖自然语言之量化,模糊量化通用量化。 本文第二,引我德语料库,附概括性陈注,量化陈适子集。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम परिमाणीकरण के एनोटेशन के लिए एक टैगसेट प्रस्तुत करते हैं जिसका उपयोग हम वर्तमान में साहित्य के काल्पनिक कार्यों में कुछ मात्रात्मक कथनों को एनोटेट करने के लिए करते हैं। साहित्यिक ग्रंथों में परिमाणीकरण को व्यक्त करने में एक समृद्ध विविधता है, जिसमें क्वांटिफायर और जटिल वाक्य संरचनाओं को व्यक्त करने के लिए लेक्सेम्स की एक विस्तृत श्रृंखला शामिल है ताकि प्रतिबंधक और एक परिमाणीकरण के परमाणु दायरे को व्यक्त किया जा सके। हमारे टैगसेट में सात टैग होते हैं और प्राकृतिक भाषा में होने वाले सभी प्रकार के परिमाणीकरण को शामिल किया जाता है, जिसमें अस्पष्ट परिमाणीकरण और सामान्य परिमाणीकरण शामिल हैं। पेपर के दूसरे भाग में, हम अपने जर्मन कॉर्पस को सामान्यीकरण कथनों के एनोटेशन के साथ पेश करते हैं, जो परिमाणित कथनों का एक उचित सबसेट बनाते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ja>私たちは、現在、架空の文学作品における特定の定量化されたステートメントに注釈を付けるために使用している定量化の注釈のためのタグセットを提示します。文献テキストは、定量化を表現するための幅広い辞書と、定量化の制限者と核の範囲を表現するための複雑な文章構造を含む、定量化を表現するための豊富な多様性を特徴とする。当社のタグセットは7つのタグで構成されており、漠然とした定量化と一般的な定量化を含む、自然言語で発生するすべての種類の定量化をカバーしています。論文の第2部では、ドイツ語のコーパスと、定量化されたステートメントの適切なサブセットを形成する一般的なステートメントの注釈を紹介します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid clibeanna i láthair don nóta cainníochtaithe a úsáidimid faoi láthair chun ráitis chainníochtaithe áirithe a anótáil i saothair fhicseanúla litríochta. Tá éagsúlacht shaibhir sa chainníochtú léirithe i dtéacsanna liteartha, lena n-áirítear raon leathan de lexemí chun cainníochtaithe a chur in iúl agus struchtúir casta abairtí chun sriantóir agus scóip núicléach cainníochtaithe a chur in iúl. Seacht gclib atá inár dtata clibeanna agus clúdaíonn sé gach cineál cainníochtaithe a tharlaíonn i dteanga nádúrtha, lena n-áirítear cainníochtú doiléir agus cainníochtú cineálach. Sa dara cuid den pháipéar, tugaimid ár gcorpas Gearmánach isteach le nótaí ginearálaithe ráitis, atá mar fho-thacar ceart de ráitis chainníochtaithe.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ru>Мы представляем набор меток для аннотации количественного определения, который мы в настоящее время используем для аннотации определенных количественных утверждений в вымышленных произведениях литературы. Литературные тексты отличаются богатым разнообразием в выражении количественной оценки, включая широкий спектр лексем для выражения количественных показателей и сложных структур предложений для выражения ограничителя и ядерной сферы охвата количественной оценки. Наш набор тегов состоит из семи тегов и охватывает все типы количественного определения, которые происходят на естественном языке, включая расплывчатое количественное определение и общее количественное определение. Во второй части работы мы представляем наш немецкий корпус с аннотациями обобщающих высказываний, которые образуют надлежащее подмножество количественных высказываний.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε ένα σημειωματάριο για τον σχολιασμό της ποσοτικοποίησης που χρησιμοποιούμε σήμερα για να σχολιάσουμε ορισμένες ποσοτικοποιημένες δηλώσεις σε φανταστικά έργα λογοτεχνίας. Τα λογοτεχνικά κείμενα χαρακτηρίζουν μια πλούσια ποικιλία στην έκφραση ποσοτικού προσδιορισμού, συμπεριλαμβανομένου ενός ευρέος φάσματος λέξεων για την έκφραση ποσοτικών συντελεστών και σύνθετων δομών προτάσεων για την έκφραση του περιοριστή και του πυρηνικού πεδίου ενός ποσοτικού προσδιορισμού. Το σετ μας αποτελείται από επτά ετικέτες και καλύπτει όλους τους τύπους ποσοτικοποίησης που συμβαίνουν στη φυσική γλώσσα, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της αόριστης ποσοτικοποίησης και της γενικής ποσοτικοποίησης. Στο δεύτερο μέρος της εργασίας, εισάγουμε το γερμανικό σώμα μας με σχολιασμούς γενικευμένων δηλώσεων, οι οποίες αποτελούν ένα κατάλληλο υποσύνολο ποσοτικοποιημένων δηλώσεων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Bemutatjuk a számszerűsítés jegyzékének tagset-jét, amelyet jelenleg egyes számszerűsített állítások jegyzékezésére használunk fiktív irodalmi művekben. Az irodalmi szövegek gazdag változatossággal rendelkeznek a számszerűsítés kifejezésében, beleértve a számszerűsítők kifejezésére szolgáló lexemek széles skáláját, valamint a számszerűsítés korlátozójának és nukleáris hatályának kifejezésére szolgáló komplex mondatszerkezeteket. A tagszettünk hét címkéből áll, és lefedi a természetes nyelvben előforduló mennyiségi meghatározások minden típusát, beleértve a homályos mennyiségi meghatározást és az általános mennyiségi meghatározást. A tanulmány második részében bemutatjuk német korpuszunkat az általánosító állítások jegyzeteivel, amelyek számszerűsített állítások megfelelő részhalmazát képezik.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ ჩვენ კვანტაქტიფიკაციის ნიოტაციისთვის ნიოტაციის ნიოტაციას, რომელიც ჩვენ ახლა გამოყენებთ განსაკუთრებული კვანტაქტიფიკაციული განსაკუთრებების ნიოტაციას Literary texts feature a rich variety in expressing quantification, including a broad range of lexemes to express quantifiers and complex sentence structures to express the restrictor and the nuclear scope of a quantification. ჩვენი მონიშნულები შვიდი ჭდეების შეფარდება და ყველა ტიპის კვანტიფიკაციის შეფარდება, რომელიც მოხდება თავიდან ენერგიულ ენერგიში, შეფარდება გაგზავნილი კვანტიფიკაცია და გენერი ჩვენ გერმანეთის მეორე ნაწილში ჩვენი კაპოსს ჩვენ დავიტანოთ, რომელიც გერმანეთის განახლებების ანოტაციებით, რომელიც იქნება სწორი კვანტაციული განახლებების სპესტი.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo un tagset per l'annotazione della quantificazione che attualmente utilizziamo per annotare alcune affermazioni quantificate in opere letterarie fittizie. I testi letterari presentano una ricca varietà di espressioni di quantificazione, tra cui una vasta gamma di lessimi per esprimere quantificatori e complesse strutture di frase per esprimere il limitatore e la portata nucleare di una quantificazione. Il nostro tagset è composto da sette tag e copre tutti i tipi di quantificazione che si verificano nel linguaggio naturale, compresa la quantificazione vaga e la quantificazione generica. Nella seconda parte dell'articolo presentiamo il nostro corpus tedesco con annotazioni di affermazioni generalizzanti, che costituiscono un vero e proprio sottoinsieme di affermazioni quantificate.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Mes pateikiame žymenų rinkinį kiekybinio įvertinimo anotacijai, kurią šiuo metu naudojame tam tikriems kiekybiniams pareiškimams fiktyviuose literatūros kūriniuose anotuoti. Literatūriniuose tekstuose yra daug kiekybinio įvertinimo išraiškos, įskaitant platų lexemų, skirtų kiekybiniams įvertinimams išreikšti, ir sudėtingų sakinių struktūrų, skirtų kiekybinio įvertinimo ribotuvui išreikšti, ir branduolinės srities. Mūsų ženklų rinkinį sudaro septyni ženklai ir apima visų rūšių kiekybinį įvertinimą, kuris vyksta natūralia kalba, įskaitant neaiškų kiekybinį įvertinimą ir bendrą kiekybinį įvertinimą. In the second part of the paper, we introduce our German corpus with annotations of generalising statements, which form a proper subset of quantified statements.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Презентираме тагет за анотација на квантификација која моментно ја користиме за анотација на одредени квантификувани изјави во фантастични дела на литературата. Литерарните тексти имаат богата разлика во изразувањето на квантификацијата, вклучувајќи и широк опсег на лексеми за изразување на квантификации и комплексни структури на реченици за изразување на рестрикторот и нуклеарниот опсег на квантификацијата. Нашиот тагет се состои од седум тагети и ги покрива сите видови квантификација кои се случуваат на природен јазик, вклучувајќи ја и нејасната квантификација и генералната квантификација. In the second part of the paper, we introduce our German corpus with annotations of generalising statements, which form a proper subset of quantified statements.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami perkenalkan set tag untuk anotasi kuantifikasi yang kita gunakan untuk anotasi pernyataan kuantifikasi tertentu dalam kerja fiksi literatur. Teks literari mengandungi pelbagai yang kaya dalam mengekspresikan kuantifikasi, termasuk julat luas leksem untuk mengekspresikan kuantifikasi dan struktur kalimat kompleks untuk mengekspresikan pengendali dan skop nuklear kuantifikasi. Tagset kami terdiri dari tujuh tag dan meliputi semua jenis kuantifikasi yang berlaku dalam bahasa semulajadi, termasuk kuantifikasi yang tidak jelas dan kuantifikasi generik. Dalam bahagian kedua kertas, kami memperkenalkan korpus Jerman kami dengan anotasi pengumuman pernyataan, yang membentuk subset yang betul dari pernyataan kuantifikasi.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>സാഹിത്യത്തിന്റെ കൃത്രിമ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങളില്‍ നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കാന്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഇപ്പോള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന കുറച്ചു വിശദീകരിച്ച വാ സാഹിത്ര വാക്കുകള്‍ വ്യക്തമാക്കുന്നതില്‍ സമ്പത്തുള്ള വ്യത്യസ്ത വ്യത്യാസങ്ങള്‍ നല്‍കുന്നു. അതിനുള്ള പരിധികളും അണുവിക സ്കോപ്പും പ്രസ്താവിക്കാന്‍ വിശാ ഞങ്ങളുടെ ടാഗ്സെറ്റില്‍ ഏഴ് ടാഗുകളുണ്ട്. സ്വാഭാഷയില്‍ സംഭവിക്കുന്ന എല്ലാ തരം വിശേഷതകളും പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായ വ്യക്തിത്വങ്ങളും പൂര്‍ണ പത്രത്തിന്റെ രണ്ടാമത്തെ ഭാഗത്ത്, നമ്മുടെ ജര്‍മ്മന്‍ കോര്‍പ്പുസിനെ പരിചയപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു. പ്രസ്താനങ്ങള്‍ ജനറലൈസ് ചെയ്യുന്ന പ്ര</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nippreżentaw tag set għall-annotazzjoni tal-kwantifikazzjoni li bħalissa nużaw biex niannotaw ċerti dikjarazzjonijiet kwantifikati f’xogħlijiet fikzzjonali tal-letteratura. Literary texts feature a rich variety in expressing quantification, including a broad range of lexemes to express quantifiers and complex sentence structures to express the restrictor and the nuclear scope of a quantification.  It-tagset tagħna jikkonsisti f’seba’ tags u jkopri t-tipi kollha ta’ kwantifikazzjoni li jseħħu fil-lingwa naturali, inkluż kwantifikazzjoni vaga u kwantifikazzjoni ġenerika. Fit-tieni parti tad-dokument, a ħna nintroduċu l-korpus Ġermaniż tagħna b’annotazzjonijiet ta’ dikjarazzjonijiet ġeneralizzati, li jiffurmaw sottosett xieraq ta’ dikjarazzjonijiet kwantifikati.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer eit merkelapp for annotasjonen av kvantifikasjon som vi brukar for å merke nokre kvantifiserte uttrykk i fiksjonelle arbeidar av literatur. Literarte tekstar har ein rikk variasjon i uttrykket av kvantifikasjon, inkludert eit brett område lesar for å uttrykke kvantifikatorar og komplekse setningsstruktur for å uttrykke grensesnittet og kjerneområdet for kvantifikasjon. Merkelappsettet vårt inneheld av sju merker og dekkar alle typar kvantifikasjon som skjer i naturspråk, inkludert vaguelt kvantifikasjon og generelt kvantifikasjon. I den andre delen av papiret introduserer vi våre tyske korpus med annotasjonar av generellisering av uttrykk, som formar eit rett subgruppe av kvantifiserte uttrykk.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Przedstawiamy tagset do adnotacji kwantyfikacji, który obecnie używamy do adnotacji określonych ilościowych stwierdzeń w fikcyjnych dziełach literatury. Teksty literackie charakteryzują się bogatą różnorodnością wyrażania kwantyfikacji, w tym szeroką gamą leksemów do wyrażania kwantyfikatorów oraz złożonymi strukturami zdań do wyrażenia ograniczającego i jądrowego zakresu kwantyfikacji. Nasz tagset składa się z siedmiu tagów i obejmuje wszystkie rodzaje kwantyfikacji występujących w języku naturalnym, w tym niejasne kwantyfikacje i ogólne kwantyfikacje. W drugiej części artykułu przedstawiamy nasz niemiecki korpus z adnotacjami stwierdzeń uogólniających, które stanowią właściwy podzbiór stwierdzeń ilościowych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Бид одоо зохиолын бичиг баримтуудын хэмжээний хэмжээний өгүүлбэрүүдийг анзааруулахын тулд хэрэглэдэг хэмжээний хэмжээний өгүүлбэрийг тайлбарлаж байна. Шинэ бичсэн текстүүд хэмжээний тодорхойлолтыг илэрхийлж, хэмжээний тодорхойлолтын хязгаарлагч болон цөмийн тодорхойлолтын хэмжээг илэрхийлж, хэмжээний хэмжээний хэлбэрийг илэрхийлж, хэмжээний хэмжээний хэлбэрийг Бидний тэмдэглэл нь 7 тэмдэгт байдаг. Байгалийн хэл дээр тодорхойлж буй бүх төрлийн тодорхойлолт байдаг. Цагийн хоёр дахь хэсэгт бид Германы корпус-ыг хэмжээний тоон хэмжээний зөв хэлбэрүүдийг илтгэдэг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Prezentăm un tagset pentru adnotarea cuantificării pe care îl folosim în prezent pentru a adnota anumite afirmații cuantificate în operele fictive de literatură. Textele literare prezintă o varietate bogată în exprimarea cuantificării, inclusiv o gamă largă de lexeme pentru a exprima cuantificatori și structuri complexe de propoziții pentru a exprima restrictorul și domeniul nuclear al cuantificării. Tagsetul nostru este format din șapte etichete și acoperă toate tipurile de cuantificare care apar în limbajul natural, inclusiv cuantificarea vagă și cuantificarea generică. În a doua parte a lucrării, prezentăm corpul nostru german cu adnotări de declarații generalizate, care formează un subset propriu de declarații cuantificate.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>අපි දැන් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්නේ ක්‍රමාන්‍ය විශ්වාස කරන්න ටැග්සෙට් එකක් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා. අපි දැන් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා කියලා  ලිට්‍රේරි පාළුවන් සම්බන්ධ විශේෂයක් විශේෂය කරනවා ක්වාන්තිකරණය සහ ප්‍රමාණය සම්බන්ධ විශේෂයක් සම්බන්ධ විශේෂය කරනවා ක්වාන අපේ ටැග් සෙට් එක්ක ටැග් 7ක් තියෙනවා, ස්වභාවික භාෂාවට සිද්ධ වෙන්න හැම වර්ගයක්ම ආවරණය කරනවා. පත්තරේ දෙවෙනි කොටසේදී, අපි අපේ ජර්මාන් කොර්පුස් එක්ක සාමාන්‍ය වාර්තාවක් සමඟ ප්‍රතිචාරයක් තියෙනවා, ඒකෙන් ප්‍රති</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo oznaku za annotaciju kvantifikacije koju trenutno koristimo za annotaciju određenih kvantificiranih izjava u ficionalnim delovima literacije. Literijski teksti pokazuju bogatu raznolikost u izražavanju kvantifikacije, uključujući širok niz lexema kako bi izrazili kvantifikatore i kompleksne strukture rečenica kako bi izrazili ograničavanje i nuklearnu oblast kvantifikacije. Naša etiketa se sastoji od sedam etiketa i pokriva sve vrste kvantifikacije koje se dešavaju na prirodnom jeziku, uključujući nespretnu kvantifikaciju i generičnu kvantifikaciju. U drugom dijelu papira, predstavljamo naše njemačke korpuse sa annotacijom generalizacije izjava, koje formiraju odgovarajuću podskupu kvantificiranih izjava.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu soo bandhignaa bandhig, si aan u caddeyno qiyaastii aan haatan u isticmaalno si aan u caddeyno hadal cayiman oo ah shaqooyinka shahaadada farshaxanka ah. Qoraalka warqadda ah waxaa ku jira taajir kala duduwan oo ku qoran qiyaastii, kuwaas oo ku jira xeerar kala duduwan oo ay ku muujiyaan dhismaha qiyaastii iyo qalabka adag si ay u muujiyaan xadhiidka iyo qiyaastii nuurka. Our tagset consists of seven tags and covers all types of quantification that occur in natural language, including vague quantification and generic quantification.  Qaybta labaad ee warqadda, waxaynu ku soo bandhignaynaa qofkayada Jarmalka ah, taasoo ka mid ah qeyb aad u sahlan oo lagu qoro hadallo.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_kk>Біз қазіргі уақытта күнтізбелгілеу үшін кейбір күнтізбелгілеу мәліметтердің кейбір күнтізбелгілерін түсіндіру үшін қолданатын тегтерді таңдаймыз. Литералық мәтіндері көлемдеу кезінде баяны түрлі, көлемдеу кезінде көп лексемдер мен комплекс сөз құрылғыларын көрсету үшін шектеу және көлемдеу кезінде ядерлық масштабын көрсету үшін көптеген лексемдер Біздің тегтеріміз жеті тегтен тұрып, табиғи тілде болатын барлық түрлерді көлемдеу және жалпы көлемдеу тілде жазылады. Қағаздың екінші бөлігінде, біз неміс корпусымызды жалпы мәліметтерді жаңарту арқылы көрсетедік. Бұл көптеген мәліметтердің дұрыс бөлігі.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar ett tagset för anteckningen av kvantifiering som vi för närvarande använder för att kommentera vissa kvantifierade uttalanden i fiktiva litteraturverk. Litterära texter har en rik variation när det gäller att uttrycka kvantifiering, inklusive ett brett spektrum av lexem för att uttrycka kvantifierare och komplexa meningsstrukturer för att uttrycka restriktorn och kärnkraften i en kvantifiering. Vårt tagset består av sju taggar och täcker alla typer av kvantifiering som förekommer i naturligt språk, inklusive vag kvantifiering och generisk kvantifiering. I den andra delen av uppsatsen introducerar vi vår tyska korpus med anmärkningar av generaliserande uttalanden, som utgör en riktig undergrupp av kvantifierade uttalanden.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாம் தற்போது நாம் தற்போது குறிப்பிட்ட கூற்றுகளை அறிவிப்பதற்கான ஒரு ஒட்டு அமைப்பை கொண்டு வருகிறோம். இது நாம் நிரல் சி எழுத்து உரைகள் மதிப்பை கூறுவதற்கு பழைய மாறுபாடு உள்ளது, அதில் உள்ள அளவு மற்றும் சிக்கலான வாக்கு அமைப்புகளை கூற வேண்டும் மற்றும் அணு அளவை வெளிப்படுத்துவதற்க எங்கள் ஒட்டு ஏழு ஒட்டுகள் உள்ளது மற்றும் இயல்பான மொழியில் நடக்கும் அனைத்து வகையான அளவு மற்றும் குறிப்பிட்ட அளவு மற்றும் பொது அளவ காக்கியத்தின் இரண்டாவது பகுதியில், நாம் எங்கள் ஜெர்மன் கோர்ப்ஸை அறிவிக்கிறோம் பொதுவான கூற்றுகளை அறிவிக்கிறோம், அது சரியான க</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم ایک ٹاگنٹ کے لئے مقدار تعلیم کے علائم کے لئے پیش کرتے ہیں جسے ہم اکنون استعمال کررہے ہیں کہ ایک مقدار تعلیم تعلیم کے علائم کو ادبیات کی تصویر کریں۔ لیٹریریٹر ٹیکسٹ کی تعریف کے ساتھ بہترین مختلف فرق کرتا ہے، اور ایک مقدار تعریف کے مطابق مقدار اور پیچیدہ جماعت کی تعریف کرنے کے لئے ایک وسیع مختلف لکس کے شامل ہے۔ ہمارے ٹاگسٹ میں سات ٹاگ ہیں اور ہر قسم کی تعداد پوری کرتا ہے جو طبیعی زبان میں اتر رہی ہے، غیر تعداد اور عمومی تعداد کے ساتھ۔ کاغذ کے دوسرے حصہ میں، ہم نے اپنے جرمانی کورپوس کو معلوم کر دیتے ہیں جنرال کی تعریف کے مطابق مطابق کے مطابق مطابق مطابق بناتے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Биз ҳозир фойдаланадиган маълумотнинг маълумотларини маълумотларга эътибор беришга ишора этиб қўймоқдамиз. Matn matnlari taʼminlashni aniqlash uchun taʼminlovchi tarkibi mavjud. Koʻrsatish cheksiz va nuklik chegarasini koʻrsatish uchun katta chegara va murakkab maxfiy soʻzlar tugmasini koʻrsatish. Bizning taglarimiz yetti tagning birinchi bo'lgan va tabiiy tildagi hamma турли маълумотларни ўргатади, аниқ маълумот ва умумий маълумотларни ўргатади. Qogʻozning ikkinchi qismida, biz Olmoncha korpusni birinchi so'zlarni o'zgartirish natijasida o'zgarishni anglatamiz. Bu ma'lumotlar tashkilotlari haqiqida o'zgartiradi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi đưa ra một câu chú thích để định lượng số lượng người mà chúng tôi đang sử dụng để ghi chú vài tuyên bố định lượng trong tác phẩm văn học hư cấu. Văn bản văn học có nhiều dạng xác định lượng, bao gồm cả một loạt các từ điển để diễn tả lượng tử và cấu trúc chữ phức tạp để diễn tả giới hạn và phạm vi hạt nhân của một số lượng. Chúng tôi bao gồm bảy thẻ và bao gồm tất cả các loại định lượng xuất hiện trong ngôn ngữ tự nhiên, bao gồm cả phân tích mập mờ và phân tích chung. Trong phần thứ hai của tờ giấy, chúng tôi giới thiệu tập đoàn Đức của chúng tôi với ghi chú các phát biểu tổng hợp, chúng là một nhóm đầy đủ các tuyên bố định lượng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме тагсет за анотация на количествено определяне, който в момента използваме за анотация на определени количествено изразени твърдения в измислени литературни произведения. Литературните текстове имат богато разнообразие в изразяването на количествено определяне, включително широк спектър от лексеми за изразяване на количествено определяне и сложни структури на изречения за изразяване на ограничението и ядрения обхват на количествено определяне. Нашият тагсет се състои от седем тагове и обхваща всички видове количествено определяне, които се случват на естествен език, включително неясна количествено определяне и общо количествено определяне. Във втората част на доклада представяме нашия немски корпус с анотации на обобщаващи твърдения, които формират подходящ поднабор от количествени твърдения.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Predstavljamo oznaku za annotaciju kvantifikacije koje trenutno koristimo za annotaciju određenih kvantificiranih izjava u ficionalnim djelima književnosti. Literijski teksti pokazuju bogatu raznolikost izražavanja kvantifikacije, uključujući širok raspon lexema kako bi izrazili kvantifikatore i kompleksne strukture kazne kako bi izrazili ograničavanje i nuklearnu oblast kvantifikacije. Naša etiketa se sastoji od sedam etiketa i pokriva sve vrste kvantifikacije koje se događaju na prirodnom jeziku, uključujući nespretnu kvantifikaciju i generičku kvantifikaciju. U drugom dijelu papira, predstavljamo naš njemački korpus s annotacijom generalizacije izjava, koje formiraju odgovarajuću podskupu kvantificiranih izjava.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer et tagset for annotation af kvantificering, som vi i øjeblikket bruger til at annotere visse kvantificerede udsagn i fiktive værker af litteratur. Litterære tekster har en rig variation i udtryk for kvantificering, herunder en bred vifte af lexemes til at udtrykke kvantificatorer og komplekse sætningsstrukturer til at udtrykke begrænsningen og det nukleare omfang af en kvantificering. Vores tagset består af syv tags og dækker alle typer kvantificering, der forekommer i naturligt sprog, herunder vag kvantificering og generisk kvantificering. I anden del af artiklen introducerer vi vores tyske korpus med anmærkninger af generaliserende udsagn, som udgør en egentlig delmængde af kvantificerede udsagn.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren een tagset voor de annotatie van kwantificatie die we momenteel gebruiken om bepaalde gekwantificeerde uitspraken in fictieve literatuurwerken te annoteren. Literaire teksten hebben een rijke verscheidenheid in het uitdragen van kwantificatie, waaronder een breed scala aan lexemen om kwantificers uit te drukken en complexe zinsstructuren om de restrictor en de nucleaire reikwijdte van een kwantificatie uit te drukken. Onze tagset bestaat uit zeven tags en omvat alle soorten kwantificering die voorkomen in de natuurlijke taal, inclusief vage kwantificering en generieke kwantificering. In het tweede deel van het artikel introduceren we ons Duitse corpus met annotaties van generaliserende verklaringen, die een juiste subset van gekwantificeerde verklaringen vormen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Kami mempersembahkan tag set untuk anotasi kuantifikasi yang kita gunakan untuk anotasi pernyataan kuantifikasi tertentu dalam karya fiksi literatur. Teks literari memiliki berbagai jenis yang kaya dalam mengekspresikan kuantifikasi, termasuk jangkauan luas lexem untuk mengekspresikan kuantifikasi dan struktur kalimat kompleks untuk mengekspresikan penghalang dan jangkauan nuklir kuantifikasi. Tagset kami terdiri dari tujuh tag dan meliputi semua jenis kuantifikasi yang terjadi dalam bahasa alam, termasuk kuantifikasi yang tidak jelas dan kuantifikasi generik. Dalam bagian kedua dari koran, kami memperkenalkan korpus Jerman kami dengan anotasi dari generalisasi pernyataan, yang membentuk subset yang tepat dari pernyataan kuantifikasi.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Wir stellen ein Tagset für die Annotation von Quantifizierung vor, mit dem wir derzeit bestimmte quantifizierte Aussagen in fiktiven literarischen Werken annotieren. Literarische Texte zeichnen sich durch eine große Vielfalt an Ausdrucksquantifizierungen aus, einschließlich einer breiten Palette von Lexemen, um Quantifizierer auszudrücken, und komplexe Satzstrukturen, um den Restriktor und den nuklearen Umfang einer Quantifizierung auszudrücken. Unser Tagset besteht aus sieben Tags und deckt alle Arten von Quantifizierung ab, die in natürlicher Sprache vorkommen, einschließlich vage Quantifizierung und generische Quantifizierung. Im zweiten Teil der Arbeit stellen wir unser deutsches Korpus mit Annotationen generalisierender Aussagen vor, die eine angemessene Teilmenge quantifizierter Aussagen bilden.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>ما یک جعبه برای نویسندگی تعدادی که در حال حاضر از آن استفاده می‌کنیم برای نویسندگی تعدادی تعداد مقدار در کار های داستان‌شناسی را نشان می‌دهیم. texts literary feature a rich variety in expressing quantification, including a broad range of lexemes to express quantifiers and complex sentence structures to express the limiter and the nuclear scope of a quantification. نقاشی ما از هفت نقاشی است و همه نوع تعدادی که در زبان طبیعی اتفاق می‌افتد را پوشانده می‌کند، شامل تعداد تعداد و تعداد عمومی. در قسمت دوم کاغذ، شرکت آلمانی ما را با توضیح اعلام‌های ژنرال معرفی می‌کنیم، که یک قسمت مناسب از اعلام‌های مقدار معرفی می‌کنند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 양적 주석에 사용되는 표기집을 제시했는데, 우리는 현재 그것을 이용하여 문학 허구 작품 중의 일부 양적 문장을 주석하고 있다.문학 텍스트는 표현 양화에 있어 풍부한 다양성을 가지는데 표현 양화의 광범위한 어소와 표현 양화의 제한어와 핵심 범위의 복잡한 문장 구조를 포함한다.우리의 표지집은 7개의 표지로 구성되어 있으며 자연 언어에 나타난 모든 유형의 양화를 포함하고 모호 양화와 범형 양화를 포함한다.논문의 두 번째 부분에서 우리는 우리의 독일어 어료 라이브러리를 소개했는데 그 중에서 범화어구의 주석을 포함하는데 이런 주석은 양적어구의 적당한 서브집을 구성한다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaweza kuweka alama ya kutangaza kiwango ambacho kwa sasa tunatumia kutangaza tamko fulani katika kazi za fasihi. Maandishi ya fasihi yanahusisha tofauti zenye utajiri katika kuonyesha uhakika, ikiwa ni pamoja na mfululizo mkubwa wa lexesi wa kuonyesha miundombinu ya uhakika na hukumu tatizo ili kuonyesha vizuizi na kiwango cha nuklia. Our tagset consists of seven tags and covers all types of quantification that occur in natural language, including vague quantification and generic quantification.  Katika sehemu ya pili ya gazeti hilo, tunautambulisha viungo vyetu vya Ujerumani kwa matamko ya kutengeneza kauli, ambayo inatengeneza vigogo sahihi vya kauli zilizokadiriwa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Biz häzirki ulanýan hasaplanjaň beýleki hasaplamak üçin bir täg görkezýäris. Kelimeler, sayıları ifade etmek için zengin bir çeşit şeklinde değerli bir şekilde, sayıları ve karmaşık sözler yapılarını ifade etmek için nükleer boyutlu bir şekilde düzenlenerek değerli bir şekilde düzenlenebilir. Täglerimiz yeddi etiketlerden olup, tiýmit dilde bolan her hili ölçüleme diýipdir. Gazetyň ikinji böleginde, biz nemesçe korpuslarymyzy döredilik deklaratlar bilen tanyşdyrýarys. Bu şekilde quantifikadan düzgün bir bölümdir.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Ons stel 'n etiket voor die notasie van quantifikaasie wat ons huidiglik gebruik het om sekere quantifiseerde uitdrukkings in fiksielle werke van literature te annoteer. Literarie teks eienskap 'n ryk verskilligheid in die uitdrukking van kvantifikasie, insluitend 'n breide omvang van lexems om quantifiseerders en komplekse setstrukture te uitdruk om die beperkenaar en die nuwerskoop van 'n kvantifikasie te uitdruk. Ons etiketstel bestaan van sewe etikette en dekk alle tipes van kvantifikasie wat in natuurlike taal voorkom, insluitend vaguele kvantifikasie en generieke kvantifikasie. In die tweede deel van die papier, introduseer ons Duitse korpus met opmerking van generalisering uitdrukkings, wat 'n goeie subartikel van quantifiseerde uitdrukkings vorm.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>በጸሐፊው አካባቢ ሥራ እናሳውቃለን፡፡ የጸሐፊ ጽሑፎች ብዙዎችን ባለጠጎች እና የቁጥጥር እና የአካባቢ ስፋትን ለመግለጽ የሚችሉ ሰፊ ደረጃዎች እና ተጨማሪ የደብዳቤ ግንኙነት እና የአካባቢ ስፋትን ለመግለጥ ያስተካክላሉ፡፡ tagset ለባሕላዊ ቋንቋ የሚወስደውን ሁሉንም ዓይነት ማሰናከል እና የተለየ ማሰናከያ እና የብሔራዊ ቁጥር ነው፡፡ በደብዳቤው ሁለተኛ ክፍል፣ የጀርመን ቆርፓስ እናሳውቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք ներկայացնում ենք քվանտիվացման նշումների մի համակարգ, որը մենք ներկայումս օգտագործում ենք գրականության ֆանտաստիկ գործերում որոշ քվանտիվացված հայտարարությունների նշումների համար: Գրագրական տեքստերը բազմազանություն ունի չափչափման արտահայտության մեջ, ներառյալ լայն տեսակ լեքսեմերի, որպեսզի արտահայտեն չափչափողները և բարդ նախադասությունների կառուցվածքները, որպեսզի արտահայտեն չափչափման սահմանափակու Մեր նշանները կազմված են յոթ նշաններից և ծախսում են բնական լեզվով տեղի ունեցող բոլոր տեսակի չափման, ներառյալ անորոշ չափման և ընդհանուր չափման: Թղթի երկրորդ մասում մենք ներկայացնում ենք մեր գերմանացի մարմինը ընդհանուր հայտարարությունների նկարագրություններով, որոնք կազմում են քանակավորված հայտարարությունների ճիշտ ենթախումբ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Biz həmin vaxt yazılmış qiymətlərin bəzi qiymətli ifadələrini ifadə etmək üçün istifadə edirik. Qıymetlik mətnlərini ifadə etmək üçün çox geniş lexemlərin və kompleks cümləlik quruluşlarını ifadə etmək üçün qüvvətli və nükleer sahəsini ifade etmək üçün çox müxtəlif bir növ tərzini təşkil edir. Bizim etiketimiz yeddi etiketlərdən olub, təbiətli dildə olan hər cür kvantifikasyonu örtür, təbiətli kvantifikasyonu və generiki kvantifikasyonu da dahil edir. Kağıtın ikinci bölümündə Alman korpusu, genelləşdirilmiş ifadələr ilə təşkil edirik. Bu, kvantitatlı ifadələrin doğru bir subgrupu olur.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim një etiketë për anotimin e kuantifikimit që ne aktualisht përdorim për të anotuar disa deklarata kuantifikuar në punë fiktive të letërsisë. Tekstet literare paraqesin një varietet të pasur në shprehjen e kuantifikimit, duke përfshirë një gamë të gjerë lexemesh për të shprehur kuantifikuesit dhe strukturat komplekse të fjalëve për të shprehur kufizuesin dhe fushën bërthamore të një kuantifikimi. Tagset ynë përbëhet nga shtatë tag dhe mbulon të gjitha llojet e kuantifikimit që ndodhin në gjuhën natyrore, duke përfshirë kuantifikimin e paqartë dhe kuantifikimin gjeneral. Në pjesën e dytë të gazetës, ne prezantojmë korpusin tonë gjerman me anotacione të deklaratave të gjeneralizuara, të cilat formojnë një nëngrup të përshtatshëm të deklaratave të kuantifikuara.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা সাহিত্যের কল্যাণের কাজে বিশেষ বিবৃতি প্রকাশ করার জন্য একটি ট্যাগসেট উপস্থাপন করি। সাহিত্য লেখাগুলো সমৃদ্ধ বৈশিষ্ট্য প্রকাশ করে, যার মধ্যে রয়েছে ব্যাপক লেক্সিমের সংখ্যা এবং জটিল বাক্যের কাঠামো প্রকাশ করার জন্য সীমাবদ্ধ এবং পারমাণব আমাদের ট্যাগেটের মধ্যে সাত ট্যাগ রয়েছে এবং প্রাকৃতিক ভাষায় যে সমস্ত ধরনের পরিমাণ সংক্রান্ত সংক্রান্ত হয়, যার মধ্যে রয়েছে বি কাগজপত্রের দ্বিতীয় অংশে আমরা আমাদের জার্মান কোর্পাসের সাথে পরিচয় করিয়ে দিচ্ছি বিবৃতি সংক্রান্ত বিবৃতি প্রদান করার জন্য, যা</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo oznaku za annotaciju kvantifikacije koju trenutno koristimo za annotaciju određenih kvantificiranih izjava u ficionalnim djelima literature. Literijski teksti pokazuju bogatu raznolikost izražavanja kvantifikacije, uključujući širok niz lexema kako bi izrazili kvantifikatore i kompleksne strukture kazne kako bi izrazili ograničavanje i nuklearni oblast kvantifikacije. Naša etiketa se sastoji od sedam etiketa i pokriva sve vrste kvantifikacije koje se dešavaju na prirodnom jeziku, uključujući nespretnu kvantifikaciju i generičnu kvantifikaciju. U drugom dijelu papira, predstavljamo naš njemački korpus sa annotacijom generalizacije izjava, koje formiraju odgovarajuću podskupu kvantificiranih izjava.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Presentam un conjunt d'etiquetes per anotar la quantificació que actualment utilitzem per anotar certes declaracions quantificades en obres ficcionals de literatura. Els textos literaris tenen una gran varietat en expressar la quantificació, incloent una amplia gama de lexemes per expressar quantificadors i estructures complexes de frases per expressar el restriccionador i l'àmbit nuclear d'una quantificació. La nostra etiqueta consisteix en set etiquetes i cobre tots els tipus de quantificació que ocorren en llenguatge natural, incloent quantificació vaga i quantificació genèrica. En la segona part del paper, introduïm el nostre cos alemany amb anotacions de declaracions generalitzats, que formen un subconjunt adequat de declaracions quantificades.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme tagset pro anotaci kvantifikace, který v současnosti používáme k anotaci určitých kvantifikovaných výroků ve fiktivních literaturách. Literární texty se vyznačují bohatou různorodostí v vyjadřování kvantifikace, včetně široké škály lexemů pro vyjádření kvantifikátorů a složitých struktur vět pro vyjádření omezovače a jaderného rozsahu kvantifikace. Náš tagset se skládá ze sedmi tagů a pokrývá všechny typy kvantifikace, které se vyskytují v přirozeném jazyce, včetně vágní kvantifikace a obecné kvantifikace. V druhé části příspěvku představujeme náš německý korpus s anotacemi zobecňujících výroků, které tvoří vlastní podmnožinu kvantifikovaných výroků.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Esitame kvantifitseerimise annotatsiooni tagset, mida me praegu kasutame teatud kvantifitseeritud avalduste annoteerimiseks väljamõeldud kirjanduses. Kirjandustekstidel on suur valik kvantifitseerimise väljendamisel, sealhulgas mitmesuguseid lekseeme kvantifitseerijate väljendamiseks ja keerukaid lausestruktuure kvantifitseerimise piiraja ja tuumaulatuse väljendamiseks. Meie tagset koosneb seitsmest sildist ja hõlmab kõiki looduskeeles esinevaid kvantifitseerimisviise, sealhulgas ebamääraseid kvantifitseerimisi ja üldisi kvantifitseerimisi. Artikli teises osas tutvustame meie saksa korpust üldiste avalduste annotatsioonidega, mis moodustavad kvantifitseeritud avalduste õige alamhulga.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esitämme kvantifioinnin annotoinnille tagsetin, jota käytämme tällä hetkellä tiettyjen kvantifioitujen lausuntojen annotointiin fiktiivisissä kirjallisuustuoksissa. Kirjallisissa teksteissä on runsaasti erilaisia kvantifiointia ilmaisevia tekstejä, mukaan lukien laaja valikoima kvantifiointia ilmaisevia lekseemejä ja monimutkaisia lauserakenteita kvantifioinnin rajoittimen ja ydinalan laajuuden ilmaisemiseksi. Tunnistimme koostuu seitsemästä tunnisteesta ja kattaa kaikki luonnollisella kielellä esiintyvät kvantifioinnit, mukaan lukien epämääräinen kvantifiointi ja yleinen kvantifiointi. Artikkelin toisessa osassa esittelemme saksankielisen korpusemme, jossa on huomautuksia yleistävistä lausumista, jotka muodostavat asianmukaisen osajoukon kvantifioituja lausumia.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>@title: window texts string" in "context_BAR_stringWrap Ndheke segala sing wis kelas nang leter, awak dhéwé nggawe barang kelas telu babagan kelas telu kotak dhéwé, kuwi sawar-awak dhéwé, iso nguasai perusahaan kelas nggawe tarjamahan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo tagset za označevanje kvantifikacije, ki ga trenutno uporabljamo za označevanje določenih kvantifikacijskih izjav v fiktivnih literarnih delih. Literarna besedila so zelo raznolika pri izražanju količinske opredelitve, vključno s širokim naborom leksemov za izražanje količinskih opredelitev in kompleksnimi stavkovnimi strukturami za izražanje omejitve in jedrskega obsega količinske opredelitve. Naš slog je sestavljen iz sedmih oznak in zajema vse vrste kvantifikacije, ki se pojavijo v naravnem jeziku, vključno z nejasno kvantifikacijo in splošno kvantifikacijo. V drugem delu prispevka predstavljamo nemški korpus z opombami posploševalnih izjav, ki tvorijo ustrezen podsklop kvantificiranih izjav.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna gabatar da wani tagset wa mai sanar da tsarin littafin da ake amfani da shi a yanzu, dõmin mu sanar da wasu ayukan da aka ƙayyade cikin aikin littafan. KCharselect unicode block name @ info: whatsthis Ga rabin na ƙari na takarda, za mu introduce makalinmu na jerumani da taƙaitãwa ga bakwai da bakwai, wanda ke sami wani rabon da aka ƙayyade.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་ད་ལྟ་བུའི་རྣམ་གྲངས་འབེབས་སྐུལ་ལ་མཚོན་རྟགས་བཀོད་པ་ཡིན། Literary texts feature a rich variety in expressing quantification, including a broad range of lexemes to express quantifiers and complex sentence structures to express the restrictor and the nuclear scope of a quantification. ང་ཚོའི་ཤོག་བྱང་ནང་དུ་ཤོག་བྱང་༧་ཡིན་ལས་སྤྱིར་བཏང་བའི་རྣམ་པ་སྒྲིག་ཡོད། དེའི་ཤོག་བྱང་གི་ཆ་ཤས་གཉིས་པ་དེ་ལ་ང་ཚོའི་སྒེར་གྱི་རྣམ་པ་ཚོར་ཡང་བསྒྲགས་སྲིད་གཏོང་།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו מציגים קבוצת תגים עבור הערות של כיוון שאנחנו משתמשים כרגע כדי להציג הצהרות מסוימות מכוונות בעבודות בדיוניות של ספרות. טקסטים ספרתיים מאפיינים מגוון עשיר בבטא כיוון, כולל מגוון רחב של לקסמים כדי לבטא כיוונים ומבני משפטים מורכבים התג שלנו כולל שבעה תגים וכסה את כל סוגי הכוונה שמתרחשים בשפה טבעית, כולל הכוונה מוחלטת וכוונטית כללית. בחלק השני של העיתון, אנו מכירים את הקורפוס הגרמני שלנו עם ציונים של הצהרות הגנרליזציות, אשר יוצרים תת-קבוצה נכונה של הצהרות המזוודות.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Discourse-based Argument Segmentation and Annotation</title>
      <author><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Saveleva</last></author>
      <author><first>Volha</first><last>Petukhova</last></author>
      <author><first>Marius</first><last>Mosbach</last></author>
      <author><first>Dietrich</first><last>Klakow</last></author>
      <pages>41–53</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents a discourse-based approach to the analysis of argumentative texts departing from the assumption that the coherence of a text should capture argumentation structure as well and, therefore, existing discourse analysis tools can be successfully applied for argument segmentation and annotation tasks. We tested the widely used Penn Discourse Tree Bank full parser (Lin et al., 2010) and the state-of-the-art neural network NeuralEDUSeg (Wang et al., 2018) and XLNet (Yang et al., 2019) models on the two-stage discourse segmentation and discourse relation recognition. The two-stage approach outperformed the PDTB parser by broad margin, i.e. the best achieved F1 scores of 21.2 % for PDTB parser vs 66.37 % for NeuralEDUSeg and XLNet models. Neural network models were fine-tuned and evaluated on the argumentative corpus showing a promising <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of 60.22 %. The complete <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argument_(linguistics)">argument structures</a> were reconstructed for further argumentation mining tasks. The reference Dagstuhl argumentative corpus containing 2,222 elementary discourse unit pairs annotated with the top-level and fine-grained PDTB relations will be released to the research community.</abstract>
      <url hash="80f26743">2021.isa-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>saveleva-etal-2021-discourse</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Converting Multilayer Glosses into Semantic and Pragmatic forms with GENLIS<fixed-case>GENLIS</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Rodolfo</first><last>Delmonte</last></author>
      <author><first>Serena</first><last>Trolvi</last></author>
      <author><first>Francesco</first><last>Stiffoni</last></author>
      <pages>54–64</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents work carried out to transform glosses of a fable in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italian_Sign_Language">Italian Sign Language (LIS)</a> into a text which is then read by a TTS synthesizer from an SSML modified version of the same text. Whereas many systems exist that generate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_language">sign language</a> from a text, we decided to do the reverse operation and generate text from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp_(programming_language)">LIS</a>. For that purpose we used a version of the fable The Tortoise and the Hare, signed and made available on Youtube by ALBA cooperativa sociale, which was annotated manually by second author for her master’s thesis. In order to achieve our goal, we converted the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gloss_(annotation)">multilayer glosses</a> into linear Prolog terms to be fed to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generator_(mathematics)">generator</a>. In the paper we focus on the main problems encountered in the transformation of the glosses into a semantically and pragmatically consistent representation. The main problems have been caused by the complexities of a text like a fable which requires <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coreference">coreference mechanisms</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_act">speech acts</a> to be implemented in the representation which are often unexpressed and constitute implicit information.</abstract>
      <url hash="b54770d8">2021.isa-1.6</url>
      <attachment type="Attachment" hash="1fda60f2">2021.isa-1.6.Attachment.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>delmonte-etal-2021-converting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>