<collection id="2021.hcinlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-04-19">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Bridging Human&#8211;Computer Interaction and Natural Language Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Su Lin</first><last>Blodgett</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Michael</first><last>Madaio</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Brendan</first><last>O'Connor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Hanna</first><last>Wallach</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Qian</first><last>Yang</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9060d684">2021.hcinlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>hcinlp-2021-bridging</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Towards Human-Centered Summarization: A Case Study on Financial News</title>
      <author><first>Tatiana</first><last>Passali</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexios</first><last>Gidiotis</last></author>
      <author><first>Efstathios</first><last>Chatzikyriakidis</last></author>
      <author><first>Grigorios</first><last>Tsoumakas</last></author>
      <pages>21&#8211;27</pages>
      <abstract>Recent Deep Learning (DL) summarization models greatly outperform traditional summarization methodologies, generating high-quality summaries. Despite their success, there are still important open issues, such as the limited engagement and trust of users in the whole process. In order to overcome these issues, we reconsider the task of summarization from a human-centered perspective. We propose to integrate a user interface with an underlying DL model, instead of tackling summarization as an isolated task from the end user. We present a novel system, where the user can actively participate in the whole summarization process. We also enable the user to gather insights into the causative factors that drive the model&#8217;s behavior, exploiting the self-attention mechanism. We focus on the financial domain, in order to demonstrate the efficiency of generic DL models for domain-specific applications. Our work takes a first step towards a model-interface co-design approach, where DL models evolve along user needs, paving the way towards human-computer text summarization interfaces.</abstract>
      <url hash="c0c3ef39">2021.hcinlp-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>passali-etal-2021-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Methods for the Design and Evaluation of <fixed-case>HCI</fixed-case>+<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> Systems</title>
      <author><first>Hendrik</first><last>Heuer</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Buschek</last></author>
      <pages>28&#8211;33</pages>
      <abstract>HCI and NLP traditionally focus on different evaluation methods. While HCI involves a small number of people directly and deeply, NLP traditionally relies on standardized benchmark evaluations that involve a larger number of people indirectly. We present five methodological proposals at the intersection of HCI and NLP and situate them in the context of ML-based NLP models. Our goal is to foster interdisciplinary collaboration and progress in both fields by emphasizing what the fields can learn from each other.</abstract>
      <url hash="d4a6277b">2021.hcinlp-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>heuer-buschek-2021-methods</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Challenges in Designing Natural Language Interfaces for Complex Visual Models</title>
      <author><first>Henrik</first><last>Voigt</last></author>
      <author><first>Monique</first><last>Meuschke</last></author>
      <author><first>Kai</first><last>Lawonn</last></author>
      <author><first>Sina</first><last>Zarrie&#223;</last></author>
      <pages>66&#8211;73</pages>
      <abstract>Intuitive interaction with visual models becomes an increasingly important task in the field of Visualization (VIS) and verbal interaction represents a significant aspect of it. Vice versa, modeling verbal interaction in visual environments is a major trend in ongoing research in NLP. To date, research on Language &amp; Vision, however, mostly happens at the intersection of NLP and Computer Vision (CV), and much less at the intersection of NLP and Visualization, which is an important area in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI). This paper presents a brief survey of recent work on interactive tasks and set-ups in NLP and Visualization. We discuss the respective methods, show interesting gaps, and conclude by suggesting neural, visually grounded dialogue modeling as a promising potential for NLIs for visual models.</abstract>
      <url hash="fb2e8946">2021.hcinlp-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>voigt-etal-2021-challenges</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/visual-question-answering">Visual Question Answering</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title><fixed-case>RE</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>AIM</fixed-case>ing Predictive Text</title>
      <author><first>Matthew</first><last>Higgs</last></author>
      <author><first>Claire</first><last>McCallum</last></author>
      <author><first>Selina</first><last>Sutton</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Warner</last></author>
      <pages>109&#8211;115</pages>
      <abstract>Our increasing reliance on mobile applications means much of our communication is mediated with the support of predictive text systems. How do these systems impact interpersonal communication and broader society? In what ways are predictive text systems harmful, to whom, and why? In this paper, we focus on predictive text systems on mobile devices and attempt to answer these questions. We introduce the concept of a &#8216;text entry intervention&#8217; as a way to evaluate predictive text systems through an interventional lens, and consider the Reach, Effectiveness, Adoption, Implementation, and Maintenance (RE-AIM) of predictive text systems. We finish with a discussion of opportunities for NLP.</abstract>
      <url hash="ed2bcacc">2021.hcinlp-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>higgs-etal-2021-aiming</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>How do people interact with biased text prediction models while writing?</title>
      <author><first>Advait</first><last>Bhat</last></author>
      <author><first>Saaket</first><last>Agashe</last></author>
      <author><first>Anirudha</first><last>Joshi</last></author>
      <pages>116&#8211;121</pages>
      <abstract>Recent studies have shown that a bias in thetext suggestions system can percolate in theuser&#8217;s writing. In this pilot study, we ask thequestion: How do people interact with text pre-diction models, in an inline next phrase sugges-tion interface and how does introducing senti-ment bias in the text prediction model affecttheir writing? We present a pilot study as afirst step to answer this question.</abstract>
      <url hash="a8177809">2021.hcinlp-1.18</url>
      <bibkey>bhat-etal-2021-people</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>