<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.socialnlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Ninth International Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Lun-Wei</first><last>Ku</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Cheng-Te</first><last>Li</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.socialnlp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="d0f89066">2021.socialnlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>socialnlp-2021-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>A Case Study of In-House Competition for Ranking Constructive Comments in a News Service</title>
      <author><first>Hayato</first><last>Kobayashi</last></author>
      <author><first>Hiroaki</first><last>Taguchi</last></author>
      <author><first>Yoshimune</first><last>Tabuchi</last></author>
      <author><first>Chahine</first><last>Koleejan</last></author>
      <author><first>Ken</first><last>Kobayashi</last></author>
      <author><first>Soichiro</first><last>Fujita</last></author>
      <author><first>Kazuma</first><last>Murao</last></author>
      <author><first>Takeshi</first><last>Masuyama</last></author>
      <author><first>Taichi</first><last>Yatsuka</last></author>
      <author><first>Manabu</first><last>Okumura</last></author>
      <author><first>Satoshi</first><last>Sekine</last></author>
      <pages>24–35</pages>
      <abstract>Ranking the user comments posted on a news article is important for online news services because comment visibility directly affects the user experience. Research on ranking comments with different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metrics</a> to measure the comment quality has shown constructiveness used in argument analysis is promising from a practical standpoint. In this paper, we report a case study in which this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constructivism_(philosophy_of_education)">constructiveness</a> is examined in the real world. Specifically, we examine an in-house competition to improve the performance of ranking constructive comments and demonstrate the effectiveness of the best obtained <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> for a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Service_(economics)">commercial service</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="973a90ae">2021.socialnlp-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.socialnlp-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>kobayashi-etal-2021-case</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Quantifying the Effects of COVID-19 on Restaurant Reviews<fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 on Restaurant Reviews</title>
      <author><first>Ivy</first><last>Cao</last></author>
      <author><first>Zizhou</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Giannis</first><last>Karamanolakis</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Hsu</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis</first><last>Gravano</last></author>
      <pages>36–60</pages>
      <abstract>The COVID-19 pandemic has implications beyond <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Health">physical health</a>, affecting society and economies. Government efforts to slow down the spread of the virus have had a severe impact on many businesses, including restaurants. Mandatory policies such as restaurant closures, bans on social gatherings, and social distancing restrictions have affected restaurant operations as well as customer preferences (e.g., prompting a demand of stricter hygiene standards). As of now, however, it is not clear how and to what extent the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandemic">pandemic</a> has affected restaurant reviews, an analysis of which could potentially inform policies for addressing this ongoing situation. In this work, we present our efforts to understand the effects of COVID-19 on restaurant reviews, with a focus on Yelp reviews produced during the pandemic for New York City and Los Angeles County restaurants. Overall, we make the following contributions. First, we assemble a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> of 600 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Review">reviews</a> with manual annotations of fine-grained COVID-19 aspects related to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Restaurant">restaurants</a> (e.g., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hygiene">hygiene practices</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Service_(economics)">service changes</a>, sympathy and support for local businesses). Second, we address COVID-19 aspect detection using supervised classifiers, weakly-supervised approaches based on keywords, and unsupervised topic modeling approaches, and experimentally show that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifiers</a> based on pre-trained BERT representations achieve the best performance (F1=0.79). Third, we analyze the number and evolution of COVID-related aspects over time and show that the resulting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_series">time series</a> have substantial correlation (Spearman’s = 0.84) with critical statistics related to the COVID-19 pandemic, including the number of new COVID-19 cases.<tex-math>\rho</tex-math>=0.84) with critical statistics related to the COVID-19 pandemic, including the number of new COVID-19 cases. To our knowledge, this is the first work analyzing the effects of COVID-19 on Yelp restaurant reviews and could potentially inform policies by public health departments, for example, to cover resource utilization.</abstract>
      <url hash="71f3d389">2021.socialnlp-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.socialnlp-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>cao-etal-2021-quantifying</bibkey>
    <title_ar>تحديد تأثيرات COVID-19 على تقييمات المطاعم</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Quantifier les effets de la COVID-19 sur les avis des restaurants</title_fr>
      <title_es>Cuantificación de los efectos del COVID-19 en las reseñas de restaurantes</title_es>
      <title_pt>Quantificando os efeitos do COVID-19 nas avaliações de restaurantes</title_pt>
      <title_ja>レストランのレビューに対する新型コロナウイルス感染症(COVID -19)の影響の定量化</title_ja>
      <title_zh>量化COVID-19于餐厅论之</title_zh>
      <title_hi>रेस्तरां समीक्षाओं पर कोविड -19 के प्रभावों को परिमाणित करना</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Количественная оценка влияния COVID-19 на отзывы ресторанов</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Éifeachtaí COVID-19 ar Athbhreithnithe Bialainne a Chainníochtú</title_ga>
      <title_ka>COVID-19 ეფექტის რესტოპანტის შესახებ</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A COVID-19 hatásainak számszerűsítése az éttermek értékelésére</title_hu>
      <title_el>Ποσοτικός προσδιορισμός των επιπτώσεων του στις κριτικές εστιατορίων</title_el>
      <title_it>Quantificare gli effetti del COVID-19 sulle recensioni dei ristoranti</title_it>
      <title_lt>COVID-19 poveikio restoranų peržiūroms kiekybiškumas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Quantifying the Effects of COVID-19 on Restaurant Reviews</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Quantifying the Effects of COVID-19 on Restaurant Reviews</title_ms>
      <title_ml>റിസ്റ്ററര്‍നാറ് റിവിവിയുകളില്‍ കോവിഡി- 19 പ്രഭാവങ്ങളുടെ പ്രഭാവങ്ങള്‍ സ്വീകരിക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Il-kwantifikazzjoni tal-Effetti tal-COVID-19 fuq ir-Reviżjonijiet tar-Restoranti</title_mt>
      <title_pl>Ilościowe wpływy COVID-19 na recenzje restauracji</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Cuantificarea efectelor COVID-19 asupra recenziilor restaurantelor</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Quantizacija učinka COVID-19 na restoranske preglede</title_sr>
      <title_si>රෙස්ටෝරාන්ට් පරීක්ෂණයේ COVID-19 ප්‍රභාව ක්‍රමාණය කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Quantification Effects of COVID-19 on Restaurant Reviews</title_so>
      <title_sv>Kvantifiera effekterna av COVID-19 på restaurangens omdömen</title_sv>
      <title_ta>COVID- 19 விளைவுகளை மறுபடியும் முன்னோட்டம்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>رستوران رستوران پر COVID-19 کے اثرات کی تعداد کرتا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_mn>COVID-19-ын үр дүнг ресторант шалгалтуудад</title_mn>
      <title_no>Kvantering av effekten av COVID-19 på restaurantpārskat</title_no>
      <title_kk>Ресторан редакцияларында COVID- 19 эффекттерін шектеу</title_kk>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Cách phân tích hiệu ứng của COVID-19 trên nhà hàng.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Количествено определяне на ефектите от КОВИД-19 върху ревютата на ресторантите</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Kwantificeren van de effecten van COVID-19 op restaurantbeoordelingen</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Quantizacija učinka COVID-19 na preglede restorana</title_hr>
      <title_da>Kvantificering af virkningerne af COVID-19 på restaurantanmeldelser</title_da>
      <title_ko>코로나가 음식점 리뷰에 미친 영향 계량화</title_ko>
      <title_de>Quantifizierung der Auswirkungen von COVID-19 auf Restaurantbewertungen</title_de>
      <title_fa>تعداد اثرات COVID-19 روی تحقیقات رستوران</title_fa>
      <title_id>Mengkuantifikasi Efek COVID-19 pada Review Restaurant</title_id>
      <title_tr>COVID-19 faýllary restoran pārskatlarynda barlaýar</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Akipinga madhara ya COVID-19 kwenye Mapitio ya Kubuni</title_sw>
      <title_af>Kwantifikasie van die Effekte van COVID- 19 op Restaurant Review</title_af>
      <title_sq>Përcaktimi i efekteve të COVID-19 në shqyrtimet e restauranteve</title_sq>
      <title_am>የCOVID-19 ውጤቶች በRestaurant Reviews በማስተካከል</title_am>
      <title_hy>COVID-19-ի ազդեցությունները ռեստորանների վերլուծումների վրա</title_hy>
      <title_bn>রিস্ট্রেন্ট রিভিউ সম্পর্কে কভিড-১৯ এর প্রভাব সম্পর্কিত করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_az>Restoran G√∂zl…ôri √ºz…ôrind…ô COVID-19 Effects Quantification</title_az>
      <title_ca>Quantifying the Effects of COVID-19 on Restaurant Reviews</title_ca>
      <title_bs>Quantizacija učinka COVID-19 na restoranske preglede</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Kvantifikace účinků COVID-19 na recenze restaurací</title_cs>
      <title_et>COVID-19 mõju hindamine restoranide arvustustele</title_et>
      <title_fi>COVID-19:n vaikutus ravintoloiden arvosteluihin</title_fi>
      <title_jv>text-tool-action</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Količina učinkov COVID-19 na ocene restavracij</title_sk>
      <title_he>Quantifying the Effects of COVID-19 on Restaurant Reviews</title_he>
      <title_bo>བསྐྱར་གསོ་ལ་བསླབས་སྐབས་ཀྱི་གནོད་འཚོལ་ཞིབ་ཚད་བཟོ་བཞིན་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_pt>A pandemia do COVID-19 tem implicações além da saúde física, afetando a sociedade e as economias. Os esforços do governo para retardar a propagação do vírus tiveram um impacto severo em muitas empresas, incluindo restaurantes. Políticas obrigatórias, como fechamento de restaurantes, proibições de reuniões sociais e restrições de distanciamento social, afetaram as operações dos restaurantes, bem como as preferências dos clientes (por exemplo, exigindo padrões de higiene mais rigorosos). A partir de agora, no entanto, não está claro como e até que ponto a pandemia afetou as avaliações de restaurantes, cuja análise poderia informar as políticas para lidar com essa situação em andamento. Neste trabalho, apresentamos nossos esforços para entender os efeitos do COVID-19 nas avaliações de restaurantes, com foco nas avaliações do Yelp produzidas durante a pandemia para os restaurantes da cidade de Nova York e do condado de Los Angeles. No geral, fazemos as seguintes contribuições. Primeiro, reunimos um conjunto de dados de 600 avaliações com anotações manuais de aspectos refinados do COVID-19 relacionados a restaurantes (por exemplo, práticas de higiene, mudanças de serviço, simpatia e apoio a empresas locais). Em segundo lugar, abordamos a detecção de aspectos do COVID-19 usando classificadores supervisionados, abordagens fracamente supervisionadas com base em palavras-chave e abordagens de modelagem de tópicos não supervisionados e mostramos experimentalmente que classificadores baseados em representações BERT pré-treinadas alcançam o melhor desempenho (F1 = 0,79). Terceiro, analisamos o número e a evolução dos aspectos relacionados ao COVID ao longo do tempo e mostramos
que as séries temporais resultantes têm correlação substancial (ρ de Spearman = 0,84) com estatísticas críticas relacionadas à pandemia de COVID-19, incluindo o número de novos casos de COVID-19. Até onde sabemos, este é o primeiro trabalho analisando os efeitos do COVID-19 nas avaliações de restaurantes do Yelp e pode potencialmente informar as políticas dos departamentos de saúde pública, por exemplo, para cobrir a utilização de recursos.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>COVID -19のパンデミックは、身体的健康を超えて社会や経済に影響を与えます。 ウイルスの拡散を遅らせるための政府の取り組みは、レストランを含む多くのビジネスに深刻な影響を与えています。 レストランの閉店、懇親会の禁止、ソーシャルディスタンスの制限などの強制的なポリシーは、レストランの運営や顧客の好みに影響を与えます（例えば、より厳格な衛生基準の要求を促す）。 しかし、現在のところ、パンデミックがレストランのレビューにどのように影響を与え、どの程度影響を及ぼしているかは明らかではありません。レストランのレビューの分析は、この進行中の状況に対処するための政策に役立つ可能性があります。 本作では、ニューヨーク市およびロサンゼルス郡のレストランで新型コロナウイルス感染症(COVID -19)が流行した際に生じたYelpレビューを中心に、レストランのレビューに対する影響を理解するための取り組みを紹介します。 全体的に、次のような貢献をしています。 まず、600件のレビューのデータセットを組み立て、レストランに関連する細かいCOVID -19の側面（衛生慣行、サービスの変更、地元企業へのお見舞いやサポートなど）を手動でアノテーションします。 第二に、監視された分類子、キーワードに基づく弱監視アプローチ、監視されていないトピックモデリングアプローチを使用してCOVID -19のアスペクト検出に対処し、事前に訓練されたBERT表現に基づく分類子が最高のパフォーマンスを達成することを実験的に示します（ F 1 = 0.79 ）。 第三に、新型コロナウイルスに関連する側面の数と進化を分析し、
結果として得られた時系列は、新型コロナウイルス感染症（ COVID -19 ）の新規症例数を含むCOVID -19パンデミックに関連する重要な統計と実質的な相関がある（ Spearman 's ρ = 0.84 ）。私たちの知る限りでは、これは新型コロナウイルスによるYelpレストランのレビューへの影響を分析した最初の仕事であり、例えばリソースの利用をカバーするために、公衆衛生部門による政策に情報を提供する可能性があります。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ar>لوباء COVID-19 آثار تتجاوز الصحة البدنية ، حيث يؤثر على المجتمع والاقتصاد. كان للجهود الحكومية لإبطاء انتشار الفيروس تأثير شديد على العديد من الشركات ، بما في ذلك المطاعم. السياسات الإلزامية مثل إغلاق المطاعم ، وحظر التجمعات الاجتماعية ، وقيود التباعد الاجتماعي أثرت على عمليات المطاعم وكذلك على تفضيلات العملاء (على سبيل المثال ، المطالبة بمعايير نظافة أكثر صرامة). حتى الآن ، ومع ذلك ، ليس من الواضح كيف وإلى أي مدى أثر الوباء على مراجعات المطاعم ، ويمكن لتحليلها أن يوجه السياسات لمعالجة هذا الوضع المستمر. في هذا العمل ، نقدم جهودنا لفهم تأثيرات COVID-19 على تقييمات المطاعم ، مع التركيز على تقييمات Yelp التي تم إنتاجها أثناء الجائحة لمطاعم مدينة نيويورك ومقاطعة لوس أنجلوس. بشكل عام ، نقدم المساهمات التالية. أولاً ، نقوم بتجميع مجموعة بيانات من 600 مراجعة مع التعليقات التوضيحية اليدوية لجوانب COVID-19 الدقيقة المتعلقة بالمطاعم (على سبيل المثال ، ممارسات النظافة وتغييرات الخدمة والتعاطف ودعم الشركات المحلية). ثانيًا ، نتعامل مع اكتشاف جوانب COVID-19 باستخدام المصنفات الخاضعة للإشراف ، والأساليب الخاضعة للإشراف الضعيف استنادًا إلى الكلمات الرئيسية ، وأساليب نمذجة الموضوعات غير الخاضعة للإشراف ، ونبين بشكل تجريبي أن المصنفات القائمة على تمثيلات BERT المدربة مسبقًا تحقق أفضل أداء (F1 = 0.79). ثالثًا ، نقوم بتحليل عدد وتطور الجوانب المتعلقة بـ COVID بمرور الوقت والعرض
أن السلسلة الزمنية الناتجة لها علاقة كبيرة (سبيرمان ρ = 0.84) بالإحصائيات الهامة المتعلقة بجائحة COVID-19 ، بما في ذلك عدد حالات COVID-19 الجديدة. على حد علمنا ، هذا هو العمل الأول الذي يحلل آثار COVID-19 على تقييمات مطاعم Yelp ويمكن أن يوجه السياسات من قبل إدارات الصحة العامة ، على سبيل المثال ، لتغطية استخدام الموارد.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>La pandemia de COVID-19 tiene implicaciones más allá de la salud física y afecta a la sociedad y la economía. Los esfuerzos del gobierno para frenar la propagación del virus han tenido un grave impacto en muchas empresas, incluidos los restaurantes. Las políticas obligatorias, como el cierre de restaurantes, la prohibición de reuniones sociales y las restricciones de distanciamiento social, han afectado las operaciones de los restaurantes y las preferencias de los clientes (por ejemplo, han provocado una demanda de normas de higiene más estrictas). Sin embargo, hasta ahora no está claro cómo y en qué medida la pandemia ha afectado las reseñas de restaurantes, un análisis que podría informar las políticas para abordar esta situación actual. En este trabajo, presentamos nuestros esfuerzos para comprender los efectos del COVID-19 en las reseñas de restaurantes, con un enfoque en las reseñas de Yelp producidas durante la pandemia para los restaurantes de la ciudad de Nueva York y el condado de Los Ángeles. En general, realizamos las siguientes contribuciones. Primero, reunimos un conjunto de datos de 600 revisiones con anotaciones manuales de aspectos detallados de la COVID-19 relacionados con los restaurantes (por ejemplo, prácticas de higiene, cambios en el servicio, simpatía y apoyo a las empresas locales). En segundo lugar, abordamos la detección de aspectos de COVID-19 mediante clasificadores supervisados, enfoques débilmente supervisados basados en palabras clave y enfoques de modelado de temas no supervisados, y demostramos experimentalmente que los clasificadores basados en representaciones BERT previamente entrenadas logran el mejor rendimiento (F1 = 0,79). En tercer lugar, analizamos el número y la evolución de los aspectos relacionados con COVID a lo largo del tiempo y mostramos
que las series temporales resultantes tienen una correlación sustancial (ρ=0,84 de Spearman) con las estadísticas críticas relacionadas con la pandemia de COVID-19, incluido el número de nuevos casos de COVID-19. Hasta donde sabemos, este es el primer trabajo que analiza los efectos del COVID-19 en las reseñas de restaurantes de Yelp y podría informar las políticas de los departamentos de salud pública, por ejemplo, para cubrir la utilización de recursos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_fr>La pandémie de COVID-19 a des répercussions au-delà de la santé physique, affectant la société et les économies. Les efforts déployés par le gouvernement pour ralentir la propagation du virus ont eu de graves répercussions sur de nombreuses entreprises, y compris les restaurants. Les politiques obligatoires telles que les fermetures de restaurants, les interdictions de rassemblements sociaux et les restrictions de distanciation sociale ont affecté les activités des restaurants ainsi que les préférences des clients (par exemple, incitant à exiger des normes d'hygiène plus strictes). À ce jour, cependant, on ne sait pas exactement comment et dans quelle mesure la pandémie a affecté les critiques de restaurants, dont une analyse pourrait potentiellement éclairer les politiques visant à faire face à cette situation actuelle. Dans ce travail, nous présentons nos efforts pour comprendre les effets de la COVID-19 sur les avis de restaurants, en mettant l'accent sur les avis Yelp produits pendant la pandémie pour les restaurants de New York et du comté de Los Angeles. Dans l'ensemble, nous apportons les contributions suivantes. Tout d'abord, nous assemblons un ensemble de données de 600 avis avec des annotations manuelles sur les aspects précis de la COVID-19 liés aux restaurants (par exemple, les pratiques d'hygiène, les changements de service, la sympathie et le soutien aux entreprises locales). Deuxièmement, nous abordons la détection de l'aspect COVID-19 à l'aide de classificateurs supervisés, d'approches faiblement supervisées basées sur des mots-clés et d'approches de modélisation de sujets non supervisées, et montrons expérimentalement que les classificateurs basés sur des représentations BERT pré-entraînées obtiennent les meilleures performances (F1 = 0,79). Troisièmement, nous analysons le nombre et l'évolution des aspects liés à la COVID au fil du temps et montrons
que les séries chronologiques qui en résultent présentent une corrélation substantielle (ρ=0,84 de Spearman) avec les statistiques critiques liées à la pandémie de COVID-19, y compris le nombre de nouveaux cas de COVID-19. À notre connaissance, il s'agit du premier travail analysant les effets de la COVID-19 sur les avis des restaurants Yelp et pourrait potentiellement éclairer les politiques des services de santé publique, par exemple, pour couvrir l'utilisation des ressources.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_zh>COVID-19大流超出身体,感动世间经济。 政府缓疾传所行餐馆在内多企业。 餐厅闭社交会禁社交去限强制性政妨餐厅运营顾客偏好(如趣卫生标准)。 然截至目前,未详大行所以及多大程度之餐厅,或餐厅论以为信。 吾言吾曹勉知COVID-19餐厅论,大为纽约市、洛杉矶县餐厅作Yelp论也。 要之,我为下献。 首总一包600条论数集,手动注餐馆之细粒度COVID-19(如,卫生习惯事变更,矜企业之)。 其次用监分类器、基于关键字之弱监、无监之主建模以COVID-19检之,以实验明之,以先练之BERT,以至善(F1=0.79)。 其三曰,论COVID之数,与时变而示之
由是序COVID-19大行之要统计数据(包新COVID-19病例数)有实质性相关性(Spearman之ρ= 0.84)。 以臣所知,此论COVID-19论Yelp餐厅之第一项,而信公共卫生部门之政,如涵盖资用。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>कोविड-19 महामारी के शारीरिक स्वास्थ्य से परे निहितार्थ हैं, जो समाज और अर्थव्यवस्थाओं को प्रभावित करते हैं। वायरस के प्रसार को धीमा करने के सरकारी प्रयासों का रेस्तरां सहित कई व्यवसायों पर गंभीर प्रभाव पड़ा है। रेस्तरां बंद होने, सामाजिक समारोहों पर प्रतिबंध और सोशल डिस्टेंसिंग प्रतिबंधों जैसी अनिवार्य नीतियों ने रेस्तरां संचालन के साथ-साथ ग्राहकों की प्राथमिकताओं को भी प्रभावित किया है (उदाहरण के लिए, सख्त स्वच्छता मानकों की मांग को प्रेरित करना)। अभी तक, हालांकि, यह स्पष्ट नहीं है कि महामारी ने रेस्तरां समीक्षाओं को कैसे और किस हद तक प्रभावित किया है, जिसका एक विश्लेषण संभावित रूप से इस चल रही स्थिति को संबोधित करने के लिए नीतियों को सूचित कर सकता है। इस काम में, हम न्यूयॉर्क शहर और लॉस एंजिल्स काउंटी रेस्तरां के लिए महामारी के दौरान उत्पादित येल्प समीक्षाओं पर ध्यान केंद्रित करने के साथ, रेस्तरां की समीक्षाओं पर कोविड -19 के प्रभावों को समझने के लिए अपने प्रयासों को प्रस्तुत करते हैं। कुल मिलाकर, हम निम्नलिखित योगदान करते हैं। सबसे पहले, हम रेस्तरां से संबंधित ठीक-ठीक कोविड -19 पहलुओं (उदाहरण के लिए, स्वच्छता प्रथाओं, सेवा परिवर्तन, सहानुभूति और स्थानीय व्यवसायों के लिए समर्थन) के मैनुअल एनोटेशन के साथ 600 समीक्षाओं के डेटासेट को इकट्ठा करते हैं। दूसरा, हम पर्यवेक्षित क्लासिफायर, कीवर्ड के आधार पर कमजोर रूप से पर्यवेक्षित दृष्टिकोण, और असुरक्षित विषय मॉडलिंग दृष्टिकोण का उपयोग करके कोविड -19 पहलू का पता लगाने को संबोधित करते हैं, और प्रयोगात्मक रूप से दिखाते हैं कि पूर्व-प्रशिक्षित BERT प्रतिनिधित्व के आधार पर क्लासिफायर्स सर्वश्रेष्ठ प्रदर्शन (F1 = 0.79) प्राप्त करते हैं। तीसरा, हम समय के साथ कोविड से संबंधित पहलुओं की संख्या और विकास का विश्लेषण करते हैं और दिखाते हैं
कि परिणामी समय श्रृंखला में कोविड -19 महामारी से संबंधित महत्वपूर्ण आंकड़ों के साथ पर्याप्त सहसंबंध (स्पीयरमैन का π = 0.84) है, जिसमें नए कोविड -19 मामलों की संख्या भी शामिल है। हमारी जानकारी के लिए, यह येल्प रेस्तरां समीक्षाओं पर कोविड -19 के प्रभावों का विश्लेषण करने वाला पहला काम है और संभावित रूप से सार्वजनिक स्वास्थ्य विभागों द्वारा नीतियों को सूचित कर सकता है, उदाहरण के लिए, संसाधन उपयोग को कवर करने के लिए।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ru>Пандемия COVID-19 имеет последствия не только для физического здоровья, но и для общества и экономики. Усилия правительства по замедлению распространения вируса оказали серьезное воздействие на многие предприятия, включая рестораны. Обязательные правила, такие как закрытие ресторанов, запрет на общественные собрания и ограничения социального дистанцирования, повлияли на работу ресторанов, а также на предпочтения клиентов (например, потребовали более строгих гигиенических стандартов). Однако в настоящее время неясно, каким образом и в какой степени пандемия повлияла на отзывы ресторанов, анализ которых потенциально мог бы послужить основой для разработки политики по преодолению этой текущей ситуации. В этой работе мы рассказываем о том, как коронавирус повлиял на отзывы о ресторанах. Особое внимание уделяется отзывам Yelp, подготовленным во время пандемии для ресторанов в Нью-Йорке и Лос-Анджелесе. В целом мы вносим следующий вклад. Во-первых, мы собрали набор данных из 600 обзоров с ручными аннотациями о мелкозернистых аспектах COVID-19, связанных с ресторанами (например, правила гигиены, изменения в обслуживании, симпатия и поддержка местного бизнеса). Во-вторых, мы рассматриваем выявление аспектов COVID-19 с использованием контролируемых классификаторов, слабо контролируемых подходов, основанных на ключевых словах, и неконтролируемых подходов к моделированию тем, и экспериментально показываем, что классификаторы, основанные на предварительно подготовленных представлениях BERT, достигают наилучшей производительности (F1=0,79). В-третьих, мы анализируем количество и эволюцию аспектов, связанных с COVID, с течением времени и показываем
что результирующие временные ряды имеют существенную корреляцию (ρ=0,84 Спирмена) с критической статистикой, связанной с пандемией COVID-19, включая количество новых случаев COVID-19. Насколько нам известно, это первая работа по анализу влияния COVID-19 на отзывы ресторанов Yelp, которая может потенциально повлиять на политику отделов общественного здравоохранения, например, чтобы охватить использование ресурсов.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>Tá impleachtaí ag paindéim COVID-19 lasmuigh den tsláinte fhisiciúil, rud a chuireann isteach ar an tsochaí agus ar an ngeilleagar. Bhí tionchar mór ag iarrachtaí an rialtais chun scaipeadh an víris a mhoilliú ar go leor gnólachtaí, bialanna san áireamh. Chuir beartais éigeantacha ar nós dúnadh bialann, toirmisc ar chruinnithe sóisialta, agus srianta ar chianchar sóisialta isteach ar oibríochtaí bialainne chomh maith le roghanna custaiméirí (m.sh., éileamh ar chaighdeáin sláinteachais níos déine a spreagadh). Go dtí seo, áfach, níl sé soiléir conas agus cé chomh mór agus a chuaigh an phaindéim i bhfeidhm ar athbhreithnithe ar bhialanna, agus d’fhéadfadh anailís a dhéanamh air sin eolas a chur ar fáil do bheartais chun aghaidh a thabhairt ar an gcás leanúnach seo. San obair seo, cuirimid i láthair ár n-iarrachtaí chun éifeachtaí COVID-19 ar léirmheasanna bialainne a thuiscint, le fócas ar athbhreithnithe Yelp a tháirgtear le linn na paindéime do bhialanna i gCathair Nua-Eabhrac agus i gContae Los Angeles. Tríd is tríd, déanaimid na ranníocaíochtaí seo a leanas. Ar an gcéad dul síos, bailímid tacar sonraí de 600 léirmheas le nótaí láimhe ar ghnéithe mínghlanta COVID-19 a bhaineann le bialanna (m.sh. cleachtais sláinteachais, athruithe ar sheirbhísí, comhbhá agus tacaíocht do ghnólachtaí áitiúla). Ar an dara dul síos, tugaimid aghaidh ar bhrath gné COVID-19 ag baint úsáide as aicmitheoirí maoirsithe, cuir chuige lag-mhaoirsithe bunaithe ar eochairfhocail, agus cineálacha cur chuige samhaltaithe topaicí gan mhaoirseacht, agus léirímid go turgnamhach go mbaineann aicmitheoirí atá bunaithe ar uiríll réamhoilte BERT an fheidhmíocht is fearr amach (F1 = 0.79). Ar an tríú dul síos, déanaimid anailís ar líon agus ar éabhlóid na ngnéithe a bhaineann le COVID le himeacht ama agus le seó
go bhfuil comhghaol suntasach idir an tsraith ama a d’eascair as sin (Spearman’s ρ=0.84) le staitisticí criticiúla a bhaineann leis an bpaindéim COVID-19, lena n-áirítear líon na gcásanna nua COVID-19. Go bhfios dúinn, is é seo an chéad obair a dhéanann anailís ar éifeachtaí COVID-19 ar athbhreithnithe ar bhialanna Yelp agus d’fhéadfadh sé a bheith mar bhonn eolais do bheartais na ranna sláinte poiblí, mar shampla, chun úsáid acmhainní a chlúdach.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>COVID-19 პანდემიკაში ფიზიკური ჯანმრთის გარეშე იქნება, საზოგადოებას და ეკონომიკაზე გააკეთება. სამყარო ძალიან, რომელიც ვირუსის გაფართლებას დახმარებას, უფრო ძალიან გავაკეთებული ბიზნესების შესახებ, включая რესტორანტები. მანძილური პოლიტიკები, როგორც რესტოპანტის დახურება, საზოგადომი სოციალური კონფიგურაციების დაბრუნება, და საზოგადომი განმავლობაში განმავლობაში რესტოპანტის პროგრაციები და კლიენტის პროგრაციები მაგრამ ახლა არ არის წარმოიდგინე თუ როგორ და რამდენი განმავლობა პენდემიკაში რესტორანტის განახლებები, რომელის ანალიზაცია შეიძლება პოლიტიკის შესახებ, რომელიც შეუძლება შეუძლებელია გა ამ სამუშაოში ჩვენ ჩვენი წარმოდგენება COVID-19-ის რესტორანტის რეცენციების ეფექტის გაგრძნობისთვის, რომელიც ივლო რეცენციების განახლებისთვის, რომელიც აღმოქმედება ნუ იორკის და ლოს ჩვენ გავაკეთებთ შემდეგი დამატება. პირველად, ჩვენ 600 განახლების მონაცემები დავყენებთ მონაცემები, რომელიც მანძილურად მონაცემები COVID-19 აპექტიკების შესახებ რესტორანტებით (მაგალითად, ჰიგენეტიური პრაქტიკები, სერვისური ც მეორე, ჩვენ ვაკეთებთ COVID-19 ადექტის განახლებას, რომელიც გამოყენებული კლასიფიკაციების გამოყენებათ, ძალიან დანარწმუნებული კლასიფიკაციების გამოყენებაში, კლასიფიკაციების გამოყენებაში, და არაფერიმენტირებული ტემების მოდელების გამოყენებაში, და ე მესამე, ჩვენ ვაანალიზებთ COVID-ის განმავლობათა აპექტიკების რიცხვა და ევოლუცია დროში და ჩვენ ჩვენებთ
რომელიც შემდეგ დროს სერიოში იქნება მნიშვნელოვანი კორელაცია (სპერმანის = 0.84) რომელიც კრიტიკური სტატისტიკები, რომელიც COVID-19 პანდემიკის შესახებ, რომელიც ახალი COVID-19 ფასების რა ჩვენი მეცნიერებისთვის, ეს არის პირველი სამუშაო, რომელიც COVID-19-ის ეფექტები ივლო რესტორანში გადაწყენებაში და შეიძლება პოლიტიკის ინფორმაცია საზოგადო ჯანმრთელო განყოფილებების</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η πανδημία έχει επιπτώσεις πέρα από τη φυσική υγεία, επηρεάζοντας την κοινωνία και τις οικονομίες. Οι κυβερνητικές προσπάθειες για την επιβράδυνση της εξάπλωσης του ιού είχαν σοβαρές επιπτώσεις σε πολλές επιχειρήσεις, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των εστιατορίων. Υποχρεωτικές πολιτικές όπως το κλείσιμο εστιατορίων, η απαγόρευση κοινωνικών συγκεντρώσεων και οι περιορισμοί κοινωνικής απόστασης έχουν επηρεάσει τις λειτουργίες των εστιατορίων καθώς και τις προτιμήσεις των πελατών (π.χ., προκαλώντας απαίτηση αυστηρότερων προτύπων υγιεινής). Προς το παρόν, ωστόσο, δεν είναι σαφές πώς και σε ποιο βαθμό η πανδημία επηρέασε τις κριτικές εστιατορίων, μια ανάλυση των οποίων θα μπορούσε ενδεχομένως να ενημερώσει τις πολιτικές για την αντιμετώπιση αυτής της τρέχουσας κατάστασης. Σε αυτή την εργασία, παρουσιάζουμε τις προσπάθειές μας να κατανοήσουμε τις επιπτώσεις του στις κριτικές εστιατορίων, με έμφαση στις κριτικές που παράγονται κατά τη διάρκεια της πανδημίας για εστιατόρια της Νέας Υόρκης και της Κομητείας του Λος Άντζελες. Συνολικά, κάνουμε τις ακόλουθες συνεισφορές. Πρώτον, συγκεντρώνουμε ένα σύνολο δεδομένων από 600 αναθεωρήσεις με χειροκίνητες σχολιάσεις λεπτόκοκκων πτυχών που σχετίζονται με τα εστιατόρια (π.χ. πρακτικές υγιεινής, αλλαγές υπηρεσιών, συμπάθεια και υποστήριξη των τοπικών επιχειρήσεων). Δεύτερον, εξετάζουμε την ανίχνευση πτυχών χρησιμοποιώντας εποπτευόμενους ταξινομητές, ασθενώς εποπτευόμενες προσεγγίσεις βασισμένες σε λέξεις-κλειδιά και προσεγγίσεις μοντελοποίησης χωρίς επίβλεψη θεμάτων, και πειραματικά δείχνουν ότι οι ταξινομητές που βασίζονται σε προ-εκπαιδευμένες αναπαραστάσεις επιτυγχάνουν την καλύτερη απόδοση (F1=0.79). Τρίτον, αναλύουμε τον αριθμό και την εξέλιξη των πτυχών που σχετίζονται με το COVID με την πάροδο του χρόνου και δείχνουμε
ότι οι προκύπτουσες χρονικές σειρές έχουν ουσιαστική συσχέτιση (Spearman =0.84) με κρίσιμες στατιστικές που σχετίζονται με την πανδημία συμπεριλαμβανομένου του αριθμού των νέων περιπτώσεων COVID-19. Από όσο γνωρίζουμε, αυτή είναι η πρώτη εργασία που αναλύει τις επιπτώσεις του στις κριτικές εστιατορίων και μπορεί ενδεχομένως να ενημερώσει τις πολιτικές των υπηρεσιών δημόσιας υγείας, για παράδειγμα, για να καλύψει τη χρήση πόρων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A COVID-19 járványnak a fizikai egészségen túlmutató következményei vannak, amelyek hatással vannak a társadalomra és a gazdaságra. A vírus terjedésének lelassítására irányuló kormányzati erőfeszítések komoly hatást gyakoroltak számos vállalkozásra, köztük az éttermekre is. A kötelező szabályzatok, mint például az éttermek bezárása, a társadalmi összejövetelek tilalma és a társadalmi távolságra vonatkozó korlátozások befolyásolták az éttermek működését, valamint az ügyfelek preferenciáit (például szigorúbb higiéniai előírások iránti igényt). Jelenleg azonban nem világos, hogy a világjárvány hogyan és milyen mértékben befolyásolta az éttermek értékelését, amelyek elemzése potenciálisan támogathatja a jelenlegi helyzet kezelésére irányuló politikákat. Ebben a munkában bemutatjuk erőfeszítéseinket annak érdekében, hogy megértsük a COVID-19 hatását az éttermek értékeléseire, különös tekintettel a járvány alatt New York City és Los Angeles megyei éttermekben készült Yelp értékelésekre. Összességében a következő hozzájárulásokat teszünk: Először is 600 értékelésből álló adatkészletet állítunk össze az éttermekhez kapcsolódó finomszemcsés COVID-19 szempontok manuális jegyzéseivel (pl. higiéniai gyakorlatok, szolgáltatásváltozások, együttérzés és a helyi vállalkozások támogatása). Másodszor, felügyelt osztályozókkal, gyengén felügyelt kulcsszavakon alapuló megközelítésekkel és felügyelet nélküli téma modellezési megközelítésekkel foglalkozunk, és kísérleti módon megmutatjuk, hogy az előre képzett BERT reprezentációkon alapuló osztályozók a legjobb teljesítményt érik el (F1=0,79). Harmadszor elemezzük a COVID-kapcsolatos szempontok számát és evolúcióját az idő során, és bemutatjuk
a kapott idősorok jelentős összefüggésben állnak (Spearman = 0,84) a COVID-19 járványhoz kapcsolódó kritikus statisztikákkal, beleértve az új COVID-19 esetek számát is. Tudomásunk szerint ez az első munka, amely elemzi a COVID-19 hatását a Yelp éttermi értékelésekre, és potenciálisan tájékoztathatja a közegészségügyi osztályok politikáit, például az erőforrások felhasználására vonatkozóan.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>La pandemia COVID-19 ha implicazioni oltre la salute fisica, colpendo la società e le economie. Gli sforzi del governo per rallentare la diffusione del virus hanno avuto un grave impatto su molte imprese, tra cui ristoranti. Politiche obbligatorie come la chiusura dei ristoranti, il divieto di riunioni sociali e le restrizioni di distanziamento sociale hanno influenzato le operazioni dei ristoranti e le preferenze dei clienti (ad esempio, spingendo la richiesta di norme igieniche più severe). Ad oggi, tuttavia, non è chiaro in che modo e in quale misura la pandemia abbia influenzato le recensioni dei ristoranti, un'analisi della quale potrebbe potenzialmente informare le politiche per affrontare questa situazione in corso. In questo lavoro presentiamo i nostri sforzi per comprendere gli effetti del COVID-19 sulle recensioni dei ristoranti, con particolare attenzione alle recensioni Yelp prodotte durante la pandemia per i ristoranti di New York e Los Angeles County. Nel complesso, forniamo i seguenti contributi. In primo luogo, assembliamo un set di dati di 600 recensioni con annotazioni manuali di aspetti COVID-19 a grana fine relativi ai ristoranti (ad esempio, pratiche igieniche, cambiamenti di servizio, simpatia e supporto per le aziende locali). In secondo luogo, affrontiamo il rilevamento degli aspetti COVID-19 utilizzando classificatori supervisionati, approcci debolmente supervisionati basati su parole chiave e approcci di modellazione degli argomenti non supervisionati, e mostriamo sperimentalmente che i classificatori basati su rappresentazioni BERT pre-addestrate raggiungono le migliori prestazioni (F1=0,79). In terzo luogo, analizziamo il numero e l'evoluzione degli aspetti correlati al COVID nel tempo e mostriamo
che le serie temporali risultanti hanno una correlazione sostanziale (Spearman = 0,84) con le statistiche critiche relative alla pandemia COVID-19, incluso il numero di nuovi casi COVID-19. Per quanto ci risulta, questo è il primo lavoro che analizza gli effetti del COVID-19 sulle recensioni dei ristoranti Yelp e potrebbe potenzialmente informare le politiche dei dipartimenti di sanità pubblica, ad esempio, per coprire l'utilizzo delle risorse.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>COVID-19 pandemija daro poveikį ne tik fizinei sveikatai, bet ir visuomenei ir ekonomikai. Vyriausybės pastangos sulėtinti viruso plitimą turėjo didelį poveikį daugeliui įmonių, įskaitant restoranus. Privaloma politika, pavyzdžiui, restoranų uždarymas, socialinių susitikimų draudimas ir socialinių atstumų apribojimai, turėjo įtakos restoranų operacijoms ir vartotojų pageidavimams (pvz., skatina griežtesnių higienos standartų poreikį). Tačiau dabar neaišku, kaip ir kokiu mastu pandemija turėjo įtakos restoranų peržiūroms, kurios analizė galėtų suteikti galimybę informuoti politikos kryptis šiai dabartinei padėčiai spręsti. Šiame darbe mes dedame pastangas suprasti COVID-19 poveikį restoranų apžvalgoms, daugiausia dėmesio skiriant Yelp apžvalgoms, parengtoms per Niujorko ir Los Andželo apygardos restoranų pandemiją. Overall, we make the following contributions.  First, we assemble a dataset of 600 reviews with manual annotations of fine-grained COVID-19 aspects related to restaurants (e.g., hygiene practices, service changes, sympathy and support for local businesses).  Antra, sprendžiame COVID-19 aspektų nustatymą naudojant prižiūrėtus klasifikatorius, silpnai prižiūrėtus metodus, grindžiamus pagrindiniais žodžiais, ir nepažiūrėtus teminių modeliavimo metodus, ir eksperimentiniu būdu parodoma, kad klasifikatoriai, grindžiami iš anksto parengtais BERT atstovais, pasiekia geriausių rezultatų (F1=0,79). Trečia, mes analizuojame su COVID susijusių aspektų skaičių ir raidą laikui bėgant ir rodome,
kad gautos laiko eilutės turi didelę koreliaciją (Spearman =0,84) su kritiniais statistiniais duomenimis, susijusiais su COVID-19 pandemija, įskaitant naujų COVID-19 atvejų skaičių. To our knowledge, this is the first work analyzing the effects of COVID-19 on Yelp restaurant reviews and could potentially inform policies by public health departments, for example, to cover resource utilization.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>The COVID-19 pandemic has implications beyond physical health, affecting society and economies.  Usaha kerajaan untuk memperlambat penyebaran virus telah mempunyai kesan yang berat pada banyak perniagaan, termasuk restoran. Polisi yang wajib seperti penutupan restoran, melarang pertemuan sosial, dan keterangan jarak sosial telah mempengaruhi operasi restoran serta keutamaan pelanggan (cth., menyebabkan permintaan standar kesehatan yang lebih ketat). Sejak sekarang, bagaimanapun, tidak jelas bagaimana dan ke mana jumlah pandemia telah mempengaruhi ulasan restoran, analisis yang mana mungkin boleh memberitahu polisi untuk mengatasi situasi yang sedang berlangsung. Dalam kerja ini, kami memperkenalkan usaha kami untuk memahami kesan COVID-19 pada ulasan restoran, dengan fokus pada ulasan Yelp yang dihasilkan semasa pandemia untuk restoran New York dan Los Angeles County. Secara keseluruhan, kita membuat kontribusi berikut. Pertama, kita mengumpulkan set data 600 ulasan dengan anotasi manual aspek COVID-19 berkaitan dengan restoran (cth., praktek higiene, perubahan perkhidmatan, simpati dan sokongan untuk perniagaan tempatan). Kedua, kami alami pengesan aspek COVID-19 menggunakan pengendali terkawal, pendekatan terkawal lemah berdasarkan kata kunci, dan pendekatan pemodelan topik tidak terkawal, dan secara eksperimen menunjukkan bahawa pengendali berdasarkan perwakilan BERT terlatih mencapai prestasi terbaik (F1=0.79). Third, we analyze the number and evolution of COVID-related aspects over time and show
bahawa siri masa yang berasal mempunyai korelasi yang besar (Spearman =0.84) dengan statistik kritik berkaitan dengan pandemi COVID-19, termasuk bilangan kes COVID-19 baru. To our knowledge, this is the first work analyzing the effects of COVID-19 on Yelp restaurant reviews and could potentially inform policies by public health departments, for example, to cover resource utilization.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Пандемијата КоВИД-19 има импликации надвор од физичкото здравје, влијаејќи на општеството и економијата. Government efforts to slow down the spread of the virus have had a severe impact on many businesses, including restaurants.  Обврзувачките политики, како што се затворањето на рестораните, забраните за социјални собири и ограничувањата на социјалното оддалечување, влијаат врз ресторанските операции, како и на преференциите на клиентите (на пример, предизвикувањето на побаруваое на строги Сепак, од сега не е јасно како и во каков степен пандемијата влијаеше врз рецензиите на рестораните, за кои анализа може потенцијално да ги информира политиките за решавање на оваа тековна ситуација. Во оваа работа, ги претставуваме нашите напори за разбирање на ефектите на COVID-19 на рецензиите на рестораните, со фокус на рецензиите на Јелп произведени за време на пандемијата за рестораните во Њујорк и округот Лос Анџелес. Вкупно, ние даваме следни придонеси. Прво, собираме податоци од 600 рецензии со рачни анотации на фино растените аспекти на COVID-19 поврзани со рестораните (на пример, хигиенски практики, промени на услугите, симпатија и поддршка за локалните бизниси). Второ, ние се обраќаме на детекцијата на аспектот COVID-19 користејќи надгледувани класификатори, слабо надгледувани пристапи базирани на клучни зборови, и ненадгледувани пристапи на моделирање на теми, и експериментално покажуваме дека класификаторите базирани на предобучени претставувања на BERT постигнуваат најдобра резу Third, we analyze the number and evolution of COVID-related aspects over time and show
дека резултатите на временската серија имаат значителна корелација (на Сперман =0,84) со критичките статистики поврзани со пандемијата COVID-19, вклучително и бројот на нови случаи COVID-19. To our knowledge, this is the first work analyzing the effects of COVID-19 on Yelp restaurant reviews and could potentially inform policies by public health departments, for example, to cover resource utilization.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>കോവിഡി-19 പാന്‍ഡെമിക്ക് ശാരീരിക സ്വാഭാവിക്കും സമൂഹത്തിനും സാമ്പത്തികവും പ്രയോജനപ്പെടുന്നു. ഈ വൈറസിന്റെ വിതരണം കുറച്ച് ബിസിനസ്സുകളിലും റെസ്റ്ററേന്റുകളിലും കൂടുതല്‍ വലിയ പ്രഭാവം ഉണ്ടായിരുന്നു. Mandatory policies such as restaurant closures, bans on social gatherings, and social distancing restrictions have affected restaurant operations as well as customer preferences (e.g., prompting a demand of stricter hygiene standards).  As of now, however, it is not clear how and to what extent the pandemic has affected restaurant reviews, an analysis of which could potentially inform policies for addressing this ongoing situation.  ഈ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനത്തില്‍, നമ്മള്‍ കോവിഡി-19 ന്റെ പ്രഭാവങ്ങള്‍ മനസ്സിലാക്കാന്‍ നമ്മുടെ ശ്രമിച്ചുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. ന്യൂയോര്‍ക്ക് സിറ്റിയും ലോസ് ആഞ്ച എല്ലായിടത്തും നമ്മള്‍ താഴെയുള്ള പങ്കുകള്‍ ചെയ്യുന്നു. ആദ്യം, നമ്മള്‍ 600 റിവിയറുകളുടെ ഒരു ഡാറ്റാസെറ്റ് കൂട്ടിച്ചേര്‍ക്കുന്നു. കൊവിഡി-19 പ്രഖ്യാപിക്കപ്പെട്ട കോവിഡി-19 വിവരങ്ങളുമായി കൈകാര്യം കൊണ്ട് ക രണ്ടാമത്, നമ്മള്‍ കോവിഡി-19 പാര്‍ട്ട് കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നത് കീവോര്‍ഡുകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ച്, ദുര്‍ബലമായി നിരീക്ഷിക്കപ്പെട്ട വഴികള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു, സൂക്ഷിക്കപ്പെടാത്ത പ്രമേയത്തിന്റെ മാതൃക മൂന്നാമത്, നമ്മള്‍ കോവിഡിയുടെ സംഖ്യയും വികസിപ്പിക്കുന്നതും സമയത്തിനു മുമ്പ് കാണിക്കുന്നു
പുതിയ കോവിഡി-19 കേസുകളുടെ എണ്ണം കൊണ്ട് സംബന്ധിച്ചുള്ള പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട സമയത്തിന്റെ കൂട്ടത്തിലുള്ള ബന്ധമുണ്ടെന്ന് വരുത്തുന്നു. നമ്മുടെ അറിവിന് ഇതാണ് ആദ്യത്തെ ജോലി യെല്‍ഫ് റെസ്റ്റോറണ്ടിന്റെ പ്രഭാവങ്ങള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നത്. പൊതു ആരോഗ്യത്തിന്റെ വിഭവങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കാന</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-pandemija COVID-19 għandha implikazzjonijiet lil hinn mis-saħħa fiżika, li jaffettwaw is-soċjetà u l-ekonomiji. L-isforzi tal-gvern biex inaqqsu t-tixrid tal-virus kellhom impatt qawwi fuq ħafna negozji, inklużi r-ristoranti. Mandatory policies such as restaurant closures, bans on social gatherings, and social distancing restrictions have affected restaurant operations as well as customer preferences (e.g., prompting a demand of stricter hygiene standards).  Minn issa, madankollu, mhuwiex ċar kif u sa liema punt il-pandemija affettwat ir-reviżjonijiet tar-ristoranti, li analiżi tagħhom tista’ potenzjalment tinforma politiki biex tiġi indirizzata din is-sitwazzjoni attwali. In this work, we present our efforts to understand the effects of COVID-19 on restaurant reviews, with a focus on Yelp reviews produced during the pandemic for New York City and Los Angeles County restaurants.  Overall, we make the following contributions.  L-ewwel nett, a ħna nġabru sett ta’ dejta ta’ 600 reviżjoni b’annotazzjonijiet manwali ta’ aspetti COVID-19 imdewba fin relatati mar-ristoranti (pereżempju prattiki ta’ iġjene, bidliet fis-servizzi, simpatija u appoġġ g ħan-negozji lokali). Second, we address COVID-19 aspect detection using supervised classifiers, weakly-supervised approaches based on keywords, and unsupervised topic modeling approaches, and experimentally show that classifiers based on pre-trained BERT representations achieve the best performance (F1=0.79).  It-tielet, nagħmlu analiżi tan-numru u l-evoluzzjoni tal-aspetti relatati mal-COVID maż-żmien u nuru
li s-serje taż-żmien li tirriżulta għandha korrelazzjoni sostanzjali (Spearman’s =0.84) ma’ statistika kritika relatata mal-pandemija COVID-19, inkluż in-numru ta’ każijiet ġodda COVID-19. Għall-għarfien tagħna, din hija l-ewwel ħidma li tanalizza l-effetti tal-COVID-19 fuq ir-reviżjonijiet tar-ristoranti Yelp u tista’ potenzjalment tinforma l-politiki mid-dipartimenti tas-saħħa pubblika, pereżempju, biex tkopri l-użu tar-riżorsi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>COVID-19 салбарт физикийн эрүүл мэндийн гадаад нийгэм болон эдийн засгийн нөлөөлдөг нөлөөтэй. Засгийн газрын вирусын тархалтыг багасгах хичээл олон бизнес, ресторанууд ч бас маш их нөлөө үзүүлсэн. Рестораны хаалга, нийгмийн цуглуулалт, нийгмийн холбоотой хязгаарлалт нь рестораны үйл ажиллагаанд нөлөөлдөг, хэрэглэгчийн сонголтууд (жишээ нь, илүү хатуу эрүүл мэндийн стандарт шаардлагатай). Гэвч одоогийн хугацаанд энд хэрхэн, хэр хэмжээнд рестораны шинжилгээнд нөлөөлдөг вэ гэвэл, энэ шинжилгээ дамжуулж байгаа нөхцөл байдлыг зохицуулахын тулд бодлого хэрхэн мэдэх боломжгүй. Энэ ажил дээр бид Нью-Йорк хотод, Лос Анжелес хотод хотын ресторанууд дэлгэцэнд гарсан Yelp шинжилгээний нөлөөг ойлгохын тулд хичээл үзүүлсэн. Ихэнхдээ бид дараагийн нөлөөлөлт хийдэг. Эхлээд бид 600 шалгалтын өгөгдлийн санг холбоотой хоолны COVID-19 асуудлуудтай холбоотой холбоотой холбоотой мэдээллийн сангуудыг цуглуулдаг. Хоёрдугаар, бид COVID-19 асуудлыг удирдаж буй ангилалтуудыг ашиглаж, хамгийн чухал үг дээр суурилуулсан арга барилгуудыг удирдаж, шалгалтгүй сэдвийн загварын загварын арга барилгуудыг удирдаж, мөн туршилтын арга барилгуудын өмнө сургалтын BERT төлөвлөгөөнд суурилсан ан Гурав дахь, бид COVID-тэй холбоотой асуудлын тоо болон хувьсалыг цаг хугацаанд судалж,
Үүний үр дүнд цаг хугацааны хэлбэрээс маш чухал холбоотой (Спеарманын =0.84) байдаг. COVID-19 пандемиктэй хамааралтай чухал статистик, шинэ COVID-19 тохиолдолд хамааралтай. Бидний мэдэхэд, энэ нь Ельп рестораны шалгалтын нөлөөг COVID-19-ын анхны ажлыг шинжилж, нийгмийн эрүүл мэндийн departamentүүдийн бодлого, жишээлбэл эдийн засгийн хэрэглээ ашиглах боломжтой болно.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Pandemia COVID-19 ma konsekwencje wykraczające poza zdrowie fizyczne, wpływające na społeczeństwo i gospodarkę. Wysiłki rządu mające na celu spowolnienie rozprzestrzeniania się wirusa miały poważny wpływ na wiele przedsiębiorstw, w tym restauracje. Obowiązkowe zasady, takie jak zamknięcie restauracji, zakaz spotkań towarzyskich i ograniczenia dystansowania społecznego, wpłynęły na działalność restauracji i preferencje klientów (np. wywołując żądanie surowszych norm higieny). Na razie jednak nie jest jasne, w jaki sposób i w jakim stopniu pandemia wpłynęła na recenzje restauracji, których analiza mogłaby potencjalnie przyczynić się do polityki rozwiązywania tej bieżącej sytuacji. W niniejszej pracy przedstawiamy nasze wysiłki na rzecz zrozumienia wpływu COVID-19 na recenzje restauracji, ze szczególnym uwzględnieniem recenzji Yelp wyprodukowanych w czasie pandemii dla restauracji Nowy Jork i Los Angeles County. Ogólnie rzecz biorąc, wnosimy następujący wkład. Po pierwsze, składamy zestaw danych 600 recenzji z ręcznymi adnotacjami drobnoziarnistych aspektów COVID-19 związanych z restauracjami (np. praktyki higieny, zmiany serwisowe, sympatia i wsparcie dla lokalnych firm). Po drugie, zajmujemy się wykrywaniem aspektów COVID-19 przy użyciu nadzorowanych klasyfikatorów, słabo nadzorowanych podejść opartych na słowach kluczowych oraz nienadzorowanych podejść do modelowania tematów i eksperymentalnie pokazujemy, że klasyfikatory oparte na wstępnie przeszkolonych reprezentacjach BERT osiągają najlepszą wydajność (F1=0,79). Po trzecie, analizujemy liczbę i ewolucję aspektów związanych z COVID w czasie i pokazujemy
że powstałe szeregi czasowe mają istotną korelację (Spearmana =0,84) z krytycznymi statystykami związanymi z pandemią COVID-19, w tym liczbą nowych przypadków COVID-19. Z naszej wiedzy jest to pierwsza praca analizująca wpływ COVID-19 na recenzje restauracji Yelp i mogłaby potencjalnie informować o polityce działów zdrowia publicznego, na przykład w celu obejmowania wykorzystania zasobów.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>pandemia COVID-19 are implicații dincolo de sănătatea fizică, afectând societatea și economiile. Eforturile guvernului de a încetini răspândirea virusului au avut un impact sever asupra multor întreprinderi, inclusiv asupra restaurantelor. Politicile obligatorii, cum ar fi închiderea restaurantelor, interzicerea reuniunilor sociale și restricțiile de distanțare socială, au afectat operațiunile restaurantelor, precum și preferințele clienților (de exemplu, determinând o cerere de standarde mai stricte de igienă). În prezent, totuși, nu este clar cum și în ce măsură pandemia a afectat recenziile restaurantelor, o analiză a cărei analiză ar putea informa politicile de abordare a acestei situații actuale. În această lucrare, prezentăm eforturile noastre de a înțelege efectele COVID-19 asupra recenziilor restaurantelor, cu accent pe recenziile Yelp produse în timpul pandemiei pentru restaurantele din New York și Los Angeles County. În general, aducem următoarele contribuții. În primul rând, asamblăm un set de date de 600 de recenzii cu adnotări manuale ale aspectelor COVID-19 cu granule fine legate de restaurante (de exemplu, practici de igienă, schimbări de servicii, simpatie și sprijin pentru afacerile locale). În al doilea rând, abordăm detectarea aspectelor COVID-19 folosind clasificatori supravegheați, abordări slab supravegheate bazate pe cuvinte cheie și abordări de modelare a subiectelor nesupravegheate și demonstrăm experimental că clasificatorii bazați pe reprezentări BERT pre-instruite obțin cea mai bună performanță (F1=0,79). În al treilea rând, analizăm numărul și evoluția aspectelor legate de COVID în timp și arătăm
că seriile temporale rezultate au o corelație substanțială (Spearman = 0,84) cu statisticile critice legate de pandemia COVID-19, inclusiv numărul de noi cazuri COVID-19. Din câte știm, aceasta este prima lucrare care analizează efectele COVID-19 asupra recenziilor restaurantelor Yelp și ar putea informa politicile departamentelor de sănătate publică, de exemplu, pentru a acoperi utilizarea resurselor.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>COVID-19 පැන්ඩේමික් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂ ආරෝධයෙන් ප්‍රතිකාරයක් තියෙනවා, සමාජය සහ අධ්‍යාත්මක ව රජාධාර ප්‍රයෝජනය වික්‍රමයක් පහලට පහලට පහලට දාන්න ප්‍රයෝජනයක් ගොඩක් ව්‍යාපාර වලට ගොඩක් ප්‍රය අවශ්‍ය ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රතිස්ථානයක් වගේ, සාමාජික සංවිධානයක් සහ සාමාජික ප්‍රතිස්ථානයක් සහ ග්‍රාහකයෝ ප්‍රතිස්ථානයක් වගේම ප්‍රතිස් ඒත් දැන් විශ්ලේෂණයක් නැහැ කොහොමද කියලා, කොහොමද ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්නේ නැහැ කියලා, ඒ විශ්ලේෂ මේ වැඩේ අපි අපේ උත්සාහ කරනවා නිව්යෝර්ක් නගරය සහ ලොස් ඇන්ජෙල්ස් කොන්ටිස් රෙස්ටෝර්ට් එක්ක ප්‍රශ්නයක් තේරුම් ගන්න COVID-19 ගැන, ජ සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම, අපි පස්සේ පාලනය කරනවා. මුලින්ම, අපි සම්බන්ධ කරන්නේ ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක 600 ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක සමග ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක COVID-19 ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක සම්බන් දෙවනිය, අපි COVID-19 ප්‍රශ්නයක් පරීක්ෂණය කළා පරීක්ෂණය කළා, දුර්වලින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් පරීක්ෂණය කරලා ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා යතුරු වචන වලින් පරීක්ෂණය කරනවා, සහ අපරීක්ෂණ තුන්වෙනි දෙයක්, අපි COVID සම්බන්ධ අංකය සහ විකෘතිය විශ්ලේෂ කරනවා වෙලාවෙන් පෙන්වන්න
ප්‍රතිචාර වෙලාව සිරීස් එක්ක ප්‍රමාණය සම්බන්ධයක් තියෙනවා කියලා (ස්පීරමාන්ගේ =0.84) COVID-19 පැන්ඩීමික් සම්බන්ධයි, අළුත් COVID-19 අපේ දැනගන්න, මේක තමයි පළමු වැඩේ COVID-19 ගේ ප්‍රතිකාර විශ්ලේෂණය කරනවා යෙල්ප් රෙස්ටෝරෑන්ට් පරීක්ෂණයේ ප්‍රතිකාර පරීක්ෂණය සහ ස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Cudurada COVID-19 waxay saameyn ku leedahay wax ka badan caafimaadka caafimaadka, saameyn ku leh bulshada iyo dhaqaalaha. Xukuumadu wuxuu ku dadaalay in ay ka raadsato taraajinta viruska ay saameyn weyn ku leeyihiin shirkado badan, including restaurants. Siyaarada heshiiska, tusaale ahaan shirkadda sooshaalka, shirkadda bulshada iyo xadhka sooshaalka ah e e ay ku leedahay waxay saameyn ku leeyihiin shuruudaha restaurant a iyo daryeelka macaamiisha (tusaale ahaan u baahan tahay 标准yada caafimaadka ee adag). Si kastaba ha ahaatee ma caddayn sida cudurku u saameyso baaritaanka restaurada, baaritaankaas oo si suurtagal ah u wargelin karo siyaasadaha xaaladan soo socda. Shaqadan, waxaynu soo bandhignaa hawlahayaga aan garanayno saamaynta COVID-19 ee ka fiirsashada restauranteeda, kaas oo focus ku leh baaritaanka Yelp ee laga sameeyo waqtiga cudurada magaalada New York iyo restaurants Los Angeles County. Dhammaan, waxaynu bixinnaa qeybo soo socda. Marka ugu horeysa, waxaynu soo ururinaynaa sawirada 600 baaritaanka oo lagu qorayo macluumaad dhaqan oo la xiriira restaurants (tusaale ahaan qalabka caafimaadka, isbedelka adeegga, raxmad iyo caawimaad ganacsiga degmada ah). Second, waxaannu kula macaamiloonaa COVID-19 dhinac sida loo isticmaalayo fasaxyada la ilaaliyey, qalabka la ilaaliyey oo ku saleysan hadallada, iyo qaababka sameynta mada la ilaaliyo, waxaana si tijaab ah u muuqanaynaa in fasaxyada ku saleysan kooxaha horay loo tababaray BERT ay dhamaadaan dhamaadka ugu wanaagsan (F1=0.79). Saddex, waxaynu analyshannaa lambarka iyo horumarinta arrimaha la xiriira COVID waqtiga oo aan tusno
in tirada xilliga soo socda ay leeyihiin xiriir aad u weyn (Spearman =0.84) oo ku saabsan takhasusyo muhiim ah oo la xiriira cudurada COVID-19, including tirada cusub ee COVID-19. To our knowledge, this is the first work analyzing the effects of COVID-19 on Yelp restaurant reviews and could potentially inform policies by public health departments, for example, to cover resource utilization.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>COVID-19-pandemin har konsekvenser utöver fysisk hälsa och påverkar samhället och ekonomierna. Regeringens insatser för att bromsa spridningen av viruset har haft en allvarlig inverkan på många företag, inklusive restauranger. Obligatoriska policyer som stängningar av restauranger, förbud mot sociala sammankomster och restriktioner för social distansering har påverkat restaurangens verksamhet och kundpreferenser (t.ex. lett till krav på strängare hygiennormer). Från och med nu är det dock inte klart hur och i vilken utsträckning pandemin har påverkat restaurangrecensioner, och en analys av dessa skulle kunna ge underlag för strategier för att hantera denna pågående situation. I detta arbete presenterar vi våra insatser för att förstå effekterna av COVID-19 på restaurangrecensioner, med fokus på Yelp-recensioner producerade under pandemin för restauranger i New York City och Los Angeles County. Sammantaget lämnar vi följande bidrag. Först sammanställer vi en dataset med 600 recensioner med manuella anteckningar av finkorniga COVID-19-aspekter relaterade till restauranger (t.ex. hygienrutiner, serviceförändringar, sympati och stöd för lokala företag). För det andra behandlar vi COVID-19-aspektdetektering med hjälp av övervakade klassificerare, svagt övervakade tillvägagångssätt baserade på nyckelord och icke-övervakade ämnesmodelleringsmetoder, och experimentellt visar vi att klassificerare baserade på förutbildade BERT-representationer uppnår bästa prestanda (F1=0,79). För det tredje analyserar vi antalet och utvecklingen av COVID-relaterade aspekter över tid och visar
att de resulterande tidsserierna har betydande korrelation (Spearmans =0,84) med kritisk statistik relaterad till COVID-19-pandemin, inklusive antalet nya COVID-19-fall. Såvitt vi vet är detta det första arbetet som analyserar effekterna av COVID-19 på Yelp restaurangrecensioner och kan potentiellt informera folkhälsodepartementens policyer, till exempel för att täcka resursutnyttjande.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>The COVID-19 pandemic has implications beyond physical health, affecting society and economies.  இந்த வைரஸ் விரிவுகளை குறைத்து அரசாங்க முயற்சி பல வியாபாரத்தில், மற்றும் restaurants சேர்ந்து பல வியாபாரத்தில் கடு ரெஸ்டாரென்ட் மூடும், சமூக கூட்டத்தில் தடை செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது போன்ற கொள்கைகள் மற்றும் சமூகத்திற்கு தொடர்ந்து வரும் தடைப்புகள் மற்றும் நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளத இப்போது, இப்போது, தெளிவாக இல்லை எப்படி மற்றும் எப்படி துன்பம் மற்றும் என்று தெளிவாக இருக்கிறது என்று, இந்த நடக்கும் நிலையில் செயல்படுத்தும் பொ இந்த வேலையில், நாங்கள் COVID-19 விளைவுகளை புரிந்து கொள்ள எங்கள் முயற்சிகளை காண்பிக்கிறோம், நியூயார்க் நகரத்தில் மற்றும் லாஸ் ஏஞ்செல்ஸ் காண்டி  பொதுவாக, நாம் பின்வரும் பங்களை செய்கிறோம். முதலில், நாம் 600 முன்னோட்டங்களில் ஒரு தகவல் அமைப்பை கைமுறையாக சேகரிக்கிறோம் சிறப்பு கிடைக்கப்பட்ட COVID-19 விளக்கங்களின் கைமுறையாக அறிவிப்புகள் (உ. ம். ச Second, we address COVID-19 aspect detection using supervised classifiers, weakly-supervised approaches based on keywords, and unsupervised topic modeling approaches, and experimentally show that classifiers based on pre-trained BERT representations achieve the best performance (F1=0.79).  மூன்றாவது,
முடிவு நேர தொடர்களில் பெரிய இணைப்பு இருக்கிறது (ஸ்பெர்மானின்  =0. 84) COVID- 19 புதிய COVID- 19 வழக்கங்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை சேர் எங்கள் அறிவிற்கு, இது தான் முதல் வேலை யெல்ப் ரெச்சான்ட் மீது COVID-19 விளைவுகளை ஆய்வு செய்ய முடியும் மற்றும் பொது சுகாதாரசால துறைகள் மூலம் பயன்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_no>The COVID-19 pandemic has implications beyond physical health, affecting society and economies. Regjeringsforsøk for å halde ned spreidinga av virusen har fått stor effekt på mange virksomhetar, inkludert restaurantar. Mandatory policies such as restaurant closures, banning on social gatherings, and social distancing restrictions have affected restaurant operations as well as customer preferences (e.g. prompting a demand for stricter hygiene standards). Det er imidlertid ikkje klart korleis og kor mykje pandemikken har påvirka restorasjonsgjennomsikt, en analyse av som kan potensielt informere politikk for å handtera denne situasjonen. I denne arbeida presenterer vi forsøkene våre for å forstå effekten av COVID-19 på restoransregisjonar, med fokus på Yelp reviews produsert under pandemikk for New York City og Los Angeles County restoranar. I alt gjør vi dei følgjande bidraga. Først samler vi eit dataset med 600 gjennomsikt med manuelt oppmerking av fin-korn COVID-19-aspektar relaterte til restoranar (f.eks. hygiene-praksis, endringar av tenester, simpati og støtte for lokale forretningar). Andre, vi adresserer COVID-19-aspektoppdaging ved hjelp av superviserte klassifikatorar, svakt overvåking av tilnærmingar basert på nøkkelord, og ikkje oppretta temamodellende tilnærmingar, og eksperimentelt viser at klassifikatorar basert på føretrainerte BERT-representasjonar oppnår den beste utviklinga (F1=0,79). Tredje analyserer vi talet og evolusjonen av COVID-relaterte aspektar over tid og viser
at resultatet tidserien har substantiell korrelasjon (Spearman's =0,84) med kritiske statistikk relatert til COVID-19 pandemikk, inkludert talet på nye COVID-19 tilfeller. Dette er det første arbeidet som analyserer effekten av COVID-19 på gjeldande restorasjonar i Yelp, og kan potensielt informere politikk av offentlige helsedepartementar for eksempel for å dekka ressursbruk.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_kk>COVID-19 пандемиясы физикалық саулық, қоғам мен экономикаға әсер етеді. Үкіметтің вирус таратуды баяу үшін көп бизнес, ресторанттарды қоса, көпшілікті әсер етеді. Ресторантың жабылуы, әлеуметтік жинақтау қатесі және әлеуметтік шектеу қатесі ресторантық операцияларына және клиенттердің қасиеттеріне әсер етеді (мысалы, қарапайым гигиентің стандарттарының талап сұрауы). Бірақ қазір пандемияның ресторанттардың қалай және қаншалыққа әсер етілгенін анықтамайды. Бұл анализ бұл жағдайды қалай жасау үшін саясаттарды түсініп бере алады. Бұл жұмыс ішінде біз COVID-19 ресторанттың редакцияларының эффекттерін түсініп, Нью-Йорк қаласының пандемиясында және Лос-Анджелес күйінің ресторантарының пандемиясында жасалған Yelp редакцияларына Жалпы, біз келесі қосымшаларды жасаймыз. Біріншіден, біз 600 редакциялардың деректер жинағын ресторанттар (мысалы, гигиена практикасы, қызметтер өзгерістері, симпатия және жергілікті бизнестерге қолдау үшін қолмен жазылған COVID-19 аспекттерінің қолмен жазылған жа Екіншіден, біз COVID-19 аспекттерді бақылау классификаторларды, кілттердің негізінде бақылау тәртібін қолдануға және бақылау тәртібінде тәртібінде тәртібін табу және тәртібінде бақылау тәртібінде тәртібінде BERT тәртібінде негізінде клас Үшіншіден, біз COVID-мен қатынастық аспекттердің санын және эволюциясын уақытта анализ және
Сондағы уақыт сериясының COVID-19 пандемиясына сәйкес келген критикалық статистикасы (Спеармандың  =0,84) сипаттамасы бар, жаңа COVID-19 жағдайлардың саны бар. Біздің біліміміз үшін, бұл COVID-19 ресторанттың ефектерін Ельп ресторанттарының редакцияларына анализ жұмыс істейді. Мысалы, көпшілік саулық бөлімдерінің саясаттарын, ресурстар пайдала</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ur>COVID-19 pandemic has implications beyond physical health, affecting society and economies. ویروس کے پھیلانے کے لئے حکومت کی کوشش بہت سی تجارت پر سخت اثر نازل ہوئی ہے۔ مجبور طریقے ہیں جیسے رستورن قطعے، سوسیال جمع کرنے کے لئے منع کرتے ہیں، اور سوسیال دور کرنے کے منع کرنے کے لئے رستورن کی عملیات اور مشترک ترجیح کے تاثیر دیتے ہیں لیکن اب سے یہ واضح نہیں ہے کہ کیسے اور کیسی اندازہ تک رنج رستورانٹ رستورانٹ رستورانٹ کی تحقیق کرتی ہے، جس کا تحقیق اس موقع پر قابل ہے کہ یہ موقعیت کے بارے میں پولیس کی اطلاع کرے۔ اس کام میں ہم نے اپنے کوشش کو پہچان لیا ہے کہ رستوران رستوران پر COVID-19 کے اثرات سمجھ سکیں اور نیویورک سیتی اور لوس آنجلس کنٹرونٹ کے رستوران کے بارے میں ایلپ رستوران پر تمرکز کریں۔ ہم سب سے نیچے اضافہ کرتے ہیں۔ پہلے، ہم 600 رستوران کے ایک ڈیٹ سٹ کو مجموعہ کررہے ہیں جو مصنوعی دانے COVID-19 کے مطابق رستوران کے ساتھ متعلق ہیں (جیسا: ہیجنیز طریقے، سرویس تغییر، شفاعت اور مدد کے ساتھ). دوسرا، ہم COVID-19 اسپٹ شناسیٹ کے استعمال کرتے ہیں، سرپرست کلاسیٹر، کمزور تحت نظر کیویورڈ پر بنیاد رکھے ہوئے تقریبیں، اور غیر سرپرست ٹوپ موڈلینگ کے تقریبیں، اور آزمائش کے طور پر دکھاتے ہیں کہ پہلے تحت تعلیم کی BERT روشنی پر بنیاد رکھے ہوئے کلاسیٹر بہترین عملکرد حاصل تیسری، ہم COVID کے معاملہ کی تعداد اور تکامل کو وقت پر تحقیق کرتے ہیں اور دکھاتے ہیں
کہ نتیجۂ تایمہ سیریریوں میں بہت بڑی تعلق ہے (اسپیرمن کی = = 0.84)، جو COVID-19 pandemic کے معاملہ میں موجود ہے، نو COVID-19 کیس کی تعداد کے ساتھ۔ ہمارے علم کے لئے یہ سب سے پہلے کام ہے جو COVID-19 کے اثرات کو یلپ رستورانٹ روشنی پر تحقیق کرتا ہے اور ممکن ہوتا ہے کہ پولیسی روشنی بخش کے ذریعے پولیسی بتائی جاتی ہے، مثال، سرمایہ استعمال کے لئے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_sr>Pandemija COVID-19 ima implikacije izvan fizičkog zdravlja, koji utiču na društvo i ekonomiju. Vladni napori da usporimo širenje virus a imaju težak uticaj na mnoge poduzeće, uključujući restorane. Obvezne politike kao što su zatvaranje restorana, zabrane na socijalne skupljanje i ograničenje za društvo udaljenje uticale su na operacije restorana, kao i preferencije klijenta (npr. zahteva strogih higijenskih standarda). Međutim, od sada nije jasno kako i do kakve mjere je pandemija utjecala na preglede restorana, analiza kojih bi potencijalno mogla obavijestiti politiku za rješavanje ovog trenutnog situacije. U ovom poslu predstavljamo naše napore da razumemo efekte COVID-19 na restoranske preglede, sa fokusom na Yelp preglede proizvođene tokom pandemije za restorane u okrugu Njujork i Los Angeles. Uglavnom, mi donosimo sljedeće doprinose. Prvo, skupljamo set podataka od 600 pregleda sa ručnim annotacijom finog zrnca COVID-19 aspekta povezanih sa restoranima (npr. higijenske prakse, promjene usluga, saosjećanje i podrška lokalnim poduzećima). Drugo, obraćamo se na detekciju aspekta COVID-19 koristeći nadzorne klasifikatore, slabe nadzorne pristupe na temelju ključnih reči, i neodređene pristupe modeliranja tema, i eksperimentalno pokazujemo da klasifikatori bazirani na predobučenim predstavljanjima BERT ostvaruju najbolju funkciju (F1=0,79). Treće, analiziramo broj i evoluciju aspekta povezanih sa COVID tokom vremena i pokazujemo
da rezultatna serija vremena ima značajnu korelaciju (Spearman =0,84) sa kritičnim statistikom povezanom sa pandemijom COVID-19, uključujući broj novih slučajeva COVID-19. Za naše znanje, ovo je prvi rad koji analizira učinak COVID-19 na preglede Yelp restorana i može potencijalno obavijestiti politiku javnih zdravstvenih odjela, na primer, da pokrije korištenje resursa.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_vi>Đại dịch COVID-19 có tác động lớn hơn cả sức khỏe thể chất, tác động đến xã hội và kinh tế. Nỗ lực của chính phủ nhằm ngăn chặn lây lan của virus đã ảnh hưởng nghiêm trọng đến nhiều doanh nghiệp, kể cả nhà hàng. Các chính sách ràng buộc như việc đóng cửa nhà hàng, cấm tiệc họp xã hội, và giới hạn cách biệt xã hội đã ảnh hưởng đến hoạt động nhà hàng cũng như ưu tiên khách hàng (v.d., thúc đẩy yêu cầu nghiêm ngặt chuẩn mực vệ sinh). Hiện tại, tuy nhiên, chưa rõ rõ bệnh dịch đã ảnh hưởng thế nào và đến mức nào đến kiểm tra nhà hàng, một bài phân tích có thể cung cấp cho chính sách để giải quyết tình trạng hiện tại này. Trong công việc này, chúng tôi giới thiệu nỗ lực để hiểu hiệu quả của COVID-19 trên báo cáo nhà hàng, cùng với sự tập trung vào các bài phát hành của Yelp trong thời đại dịch đối với New York City và nhà hàng Los Angeles. Nói chung, chúng tôi có đóng góp như sau đây. Đầu tiên, chúng tôi tập hợp dữ liệu của 600 bình luận với biên bản ghi chú về các khía cạnh Tốt nhất của COVID-19 liên quan tới nhà hàng (v.v. như: thói quen vệ sinh, thay đổi dịch vụ, thông cảm và hỗ trợ cho doanh địa phương). Thứ hai, chúng tôi xử lý việc phát hiện khía cạnh COVID-19 bằng các phân loại giám sát viên giám sát, theo trình tự từ khoá, và theo phương pháp mẫu về chủ đề không được giám sát, và thử nghiệm cho thấy các phân loại dựa trên các biểu tượng thiếu sót sót đạt kết quả tốt nhất (F1=0.97). Thứ ba, chúng tôi phân tích số lượng và tiến hóa các khía cạnh của COVID qua thời gian và cho thấy
rằng chuỗi thời gian kết quả có mối tương quan lớn với s ố liệu quan trọng liên quan đến đại dịch COVID-19, kể cả số trường hợp mới của COVID-19. Theo chúng tôi được biết, đây là công việc đầu tiên phân tích tác động của COVID-19 trên báo cáo nhà hàng Yelp và có thể cung cấp chính sách cho các bộ phận y tế cộng đồng, ví dụ như, về việc sử dụng tài nguyên.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>COVID-19 pandemik, shaxsiy sog'lom va kompyuterga tashkilotlar bor. Buyruqning virus tezligini kamaytirishga harakat qilishda ko'pchilik tashkilotlari va restauranter kabi ko'pchilik ishlatadi. Name Hozirda, bu holatni boshqarish uchun qanday va qanday darajada pandemik restaurantni qanday ko'rsatish mumkin emas, analyzer bu holatni boshqarish uchun qoidalarni ko'rsatish mumkin. Bu ishda, biz COVID-19 Restaurantning tashkilotlarini o'rganishga harakat qilamiz, New York City va Los Angeles County restauranteri davomida Yelp tajribalarini o'rganishga fokus qilamiz. Umumiy, biz quyidagi paydo qilamiz. Birinchisi, biz restaurants bilan bog'liq qo'llangan COVID-19 qo'lbola taʼminlovchilar bilan 600 ta'minlovchi maʼlumotlar tarkibini birlashtiramiz (m.eks. bog'liq qo'llanmalar, xizmatni o'zgarishlar, sympati va lokal vazifalar uchun qoʻllanmalar). Ikkinchi so'zda, biz boshqaruvchi darajalar bilan COVID-19 ta'limni aniqlash mumkin, kalitlar asosida qo'llangan qo'llanmalar va xavfsiz mavzu model usullarini ishlatish mumkin, va taʼminlovchi bo'lgan BERT tashkilotlariga asoslangan darajalar eng yaxshi bajarish imkoniyatini bajaradi (F1=0.79). Uchinchi, biz COVID bilan bog'liq bo'lgan sonlarning soni va evolyutsiyatini analyzeriz va vaqt bilan ko'rsatumiz
Keyin vaqt seriyasi (Spearman =0. 84) bilan bog'liq (COVID-19 pandemik bilan muhim statistikasi), yangi COVID-19 holatlarning soni. Bu bizning bilganimizga, bu Yelp restaurantening effektlarini aniqlash uchun birinchi ish, va masalan, ma'lum resource foydalanishni qarashga ega bo'ladi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Пандемията има последици отвъд физическото здраве и засяга обществото и икономиките. Правителствените усилия за забавяне на разпространението на вируса оказаха сериозно въздействие върху много предприятия, включително ресторанти. Задължителните политики като закриване на ресторанти, забрани за социални събирания и ограничения за социално дистанциране засегнаха дейността на ресторантите, както и предпочитанията на клиентите (напр. предизвикаха изискване за по-строги хигиенни стандарти). Засега обаче не е ясно как и до каква степен пандемията е засегнала прегледите на ресторантите, чийто анализ би могъл потенциално да информира политиките за справяне с настоящата ситуация. В тази работа представяме усилията си да разберем ефектите на КОВИД-19 върху ревютата на ресторантите, с акцент върху ревютата на Йелп, произведени по време на пандемията за ресторантите в Ню Йорк и окръг Лос Анджелис. Като цяло, ние правим следния принос. Първо, събираме набор от данни от 600 рецензии с ръчни анотации на фино зърнести аспекти, свързани с ресторантите (например хигиенни практики, промени в услугите, симпатия и подкрепа за местния бизнес). Второ, разглеждаме откриването на аспекти, използвайки надзорни класификатори, слабо надзорни подходи, базирани на ключови думи, и ненадзорни подходи за моделиране на темата, и експериментално показваме, че класификаторите, базирани на предварително обучени представи постигат най-добри резултати (Ф1=0.79). Трето, анализираме броя и еволюцията на свързаните с COVID аспекти във времето и показваме</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>COVID-19 pandemien har konsekvenser ud over fysisk sundhed og påvirker samfundet og økonomierne. Regeringens bestræbelser på at bremse spredningen af virussen har haft en alvorlig indvirkning på mange virksomheder, herunder restauranter. Obligatoriske politikker såsom lukning af restauranter, forbud mod sociale sammenkomster og restriktioner for social afstand har påvirket restaurantens drift såvel som kundernes præferencer (f.eks. medført et krav om strengere hygiejnestandarder). Fra nu af er det imidlertid ikke klart, hvordan og i hvilket omfang pandemien har påvirket restaurantanmeldelser, hvis analyse potentielt kunne danne grundlag for politikker til at håndtere denne nuværende situation. I dette arbejde præsenterer vi vores bestræbelser på at forstå virkningerne af COVID-19 på restaurantanmeldelser med fokus på Yelp-anmeldelser produceret under pandemien for restauranter i New York City og Los Angeles County. Samlet set yder vi følgende bidrag. Først samler vi et datasæt på 600 anmeldelser med manuelle noteringer af finkornede COVID-19 aspekter relateret til restauranter (f.eks. hygiejneprocesser, serviceændringer, sympati og støtte til lokale virksomheder). For det andet behandler vi COVID-19 aspekt detektering ved hjælp af overvågede klassificeringsmetoder, svagt overvågede tilgange baseret på søgeord og ikke-overvågede emnemodelleringstilgange og eksperimentelt viser, at klassificeringsmetoder baseret på forududdannede BERT-repræsentationer opnår den bedste ydeevne (F1=0,79). For det tredje analyserer vi antallet og udviklingen af COVID-relaterede aspekter over tid og viser</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>De COVID-19-pandemie heeft gevolgen die verder gaan dan fysieke gezondheid, en heeft gevolgen voor de samenleving en economieën. Overheidsinspanningen om de verspreiding van het virus te vertragen hebben ernstige gevolgen gehad voor veel bedrijven, waaronder restaurants. Verplichte beleidsmaatregelen zoals restaurantsluitingen, verbod op sociale bijeenkomsten en beperkingen op sociale afstand hebben invloed gehad op de restaurantactiviteiten en de voorkeuren van klanten (bijvoorbeeld door strengere hygiënenormen te eisen). Op dit moment is het echter niet duidelijk hoe en in hoeverre de pandemie de beoordelingen van restaurants heeft beïnvloed, waarvan een analyse mogelijk kan leiden tot beleidsmaatregelen om deze huidige situatie aan te pakken. In dit werk presenteren we onze inspanningen om de effecten van COVID-19 op restaurantbeoordelingen te begrijpen, met een focus op Yelp reviews die tijdens de pandemie zijn geproduceerd voor restaurants in New York City en Los Angeles County. Over het algemeen leveren wij de volgende bijdragen. Eerst verzamelen we een dataset van 600 reviews met handmatige annotaties van fijnkorrelige COVID-19 aspecten met betrekking tot restaurants (bijv. hygiënepraktijken, servicewijzigingen, sympathie en ondersteuning voor lokale bedrijven). Ten tweede behandelen we COVID-19 aspect detectie met behulp van begeleide classificatoren, zwak begeleide benaderingen op basis van trefwoorden en niet-begeleide topic modelling benaderingen en laten we experimenteel zien dat classificatoren op basis van vooraf getrainde BERT representaties de beste prestaties behalen (F1=0.79). Ten derde analyseren we het aantal en de evolutie van COVID-gerelateerde aspecten in de loop van de tijd en tonen we</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Die COVID-19-Pandemie hat über die körperliche Gesundheit hinaus Auswirkungen auf Gesellschaft und Wirtschaft. Die Bemühungen der Regierung, die Ausbreitung des Virus zu verlangsamen, hatten erhebliche Auswirkungen auf viele Unternehmen, einschließlich Restaurants. Obligatorische Richtlinien wie Restaurantschließungen, Verbote von gesellschaftlichen Zusammenkünften und Beschränkungen der sozialen Distanzierung haben sowohl den Restaurantbetrieb als auch die Kundenpräferenzen beeinflusst (z.B. die Forderung nach strengeren Hygienestandards). Bisher ist jedoch nicht klar, wie und inwieweit sich die Pandemie auf Restaurantbewertungen ausgewirkt hat, deren Analyse möglicherweise als Grundlage für Maßnahmen zur Bewältigung dieser aktuellen Situation dienen könnte. In dieser Arbeit stellen wir unsere Bemühungen vor, die Auswirkungen von COVID-19 auf Restaurantbewertungen zu verstehen, mit einem Schwerpunkt auf Yelp-Bewertungen, die während der Pandemie für Restaurants in New York City und Los Angeles County erstellt wurden. Insgesamt leisten wir folgende Beiträge: Zunächst erstellen wir einen Datensatz von 600-Bewertungen mit manuellen Anmerkungen zu feinkörnigen COVID-19-Aspekten im Zusammenhang mit Restaurants (z.B. Hygienepraktiken, Serviceänderungen, Sympathie und Unterstützung für lokale Unternehmen). Zweitens befassen wir uns mit der COVID-19-Aspekterkennung mit überwachten Klassifikatoren, schwach überwachten Ansätzen basierend auf Schlüsselwörtern und unbeaufsichtigten Themenmodellierungsansätzen und zeigen experimentell, dass Klassifikatoren, die auf vortrainierten BERT-Darstellungen basieren, die beste Leistung erzielen (F1=0.79). Drittens analysieren wir die Anzahl und Entwicklung von COVID-bezogenen Aspekten im Laufe der Zeit und zeigen</abstract_de>
      <abstract_hr>Pandemija COVID-19 ima implikacije izvan fizičkog zdravlja, utječu na društvo i gospodarstvo. Vladni napori na usporiti širenje virus a imali su teški utjecaj na mnoge poduzeća, uključujući restorane. Obvezne politike poput zatvaranja restorana, zabrani na socijalne skupljanje i ograničenja za društveno distanciranje utjecaju na operacije restorana, kao i preferencije klijenata (npr. zahtjev težih higijenskih standarda). Međutim, od sada nije jasno kako i do kakve mjere je pandemija utjecala na preglede restorana, analiza kojih bi potencijalno mogla obavijestiti politiku za rješavanje ovog trenutnog situacije. U ovom poslu predstavljamo svoje napore da razumijemo učinak COVID-19 na restoranske preglede, s fokusom na Yelp preglede proizvođene tijekom pandemije za restorane u okrugu New York i Los Angeles. Uglavnom, mi donosimo sljedeće doprinose. Prvo, skupljamo skup podataka od 600 pregleda s ručnim annotacijom finog zrnca COVID-19 aspekta povezanih s restoranima (npr. higijenske prakse, promjene usluga, simpatija i podrška lokalnim poduzećima). Drugo, obraćamo se na otkrivanje aspekta COVID-19 koristeći nadzorne klasifikatore, slabe nadzorne pristupe na temelju ključnih riječi, i nepotrebne pristupe modeliranja teme, te eksperimentalno pokazujemo da klasifikatori na temelju predobučenih predstavljanja BERT postignu najbolju učinku (F1=0,79). Treće, analiziramo broj i evoluciju aspekta povezanih s COVID-om tijekom vremena i pokazujemo</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_id>Pandemi COVID-19 memiliki implikasi selain kesehatan fisik, mempengaruhi masyarakat dan ekonomi. Perusahaan pemerintah untuk memperlambat penyebaran virus telah memiliki dampak berat pada banyak bisnis, termasuk restoran. Mandatory policies such as restaurant closures, bans on social gatherings, and social distancing restrictions have affected restaurant operations as well as customer preferences (e.g., prompting a demand of stricter hygiene standards).  Sejak sekarang, bagaimanapun, tidak jelas bagaimana dan seberapa besar pandemia telah mempengaruhi resensi restoran, analisis yang potensial dapat memberitahu kebijakan untuk mengatasi situasi yang sedang berlangsung. Dalam pekerjaan ini, kami mempersembahkan usaha kami untuk memahami efek COVID-19 pada resensi restoran, dengan fokus pada resensi Yelp yang diproduksi selama pandemia untuk restoran kota New York dan Los Angeles County. Secara umum, kita membuat kontribusi berikutnya. Pertama, kami mengumpulkan dataset dari 600 ulasan dengan anotasi manual dari aspek COVID-19 yang baik berkaitan dengan restoran (contohnya praktek higiene, perubahan layanan, simpati dan dukungan untuk bisnis lokal). Kedua, kami mengatasi deteksi aspek COVID-19 menggunakan klasifikasi yang diawasi, pendekatan yang diawasi lemah berdasarkan kata kunci, dan pendekatan model topik yang tidak diawasi, dan secara eksperimental menunjukkan bahwa klasifikasi berdasarkan represensi BERT yang terlatih mencapai prestasi terbaik (F1=0,79). Ketiga, kita menganalisa jumlah dan evolusi aspek terkait dengan COVID melalui waktu dan menunjukkan</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Ugonjwa wa COVID-19 una madhara zaidi ya afya ya kimwili, yanaathiri jamii na uchumi. Serikali inajitahidi kupunguza usambazaji wa virusi umekuwa na athari kubwa kwa biashara nyingi, ikiwa ni pamoja na migahawa. Sera za viwanda kama vile kufungiwa kwa mgahawa, vikwazo vya vikosi vya kijamii, na vizuizi vinavyoendelea na kijamii vimeathiri shughuli za mgahawa pamoja na vipaumbele vya wateja (kwa mfano, kutaka kiwango cha huduma za afya kali). Mpaka sasa, hata hivyo, haijaeleweka wazi jinsi na kwa kiasi gani ugonjwa huu umeathiri matokeo ya mgahawa, uchambuzi ambao unaweza kutoa taarifa za sera kwa kuhusiana na hali hii inayoendelea. Katika kazi hii, tunaweka juhudi zetu za kuelewa madhara ya COVID-19 kwenye matokeo ya mgahawa, yenye lengo la kutafiti za Yelp zilizotengenezwa wakati wa janga la jiji la New York na migahawa ya Los Angeles County. Kwa ujumla, tunafanya michango yafuatayo. Kwanza, tunakusanya seti ya taarifa ya tathmini 600 kwa kutumia matangazo ya vifaa vya COVID-19 yanayohusiana na migahawa (kwa mfano, mazoea ya afya, mabadiliko ya huduma, huruma na kuunga mkono biashara za wenyeji). Pili, tunazungumzia vipande vya COVID-19 kwa kutumia wataalamu waliokuwa wakifuatiliwa, mbinu zisizo na udhaifu zinazofuatiliwa kwa kutumia maneno ya ufundi, na mbinu za kutengeneza mada zisizo na uhakika, na kwa mtihani unaonyesha kuwa wataalamu wanaotengenezwa na wawakilishi wa BERT wanafanya kazi bora zaidi (F1=0.79). Tatu, tunachambua idadi na mabadiliko ya mambo yanayohusiana na COVID kwa muda na kuonyesha</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_ko>코로나의 영향은 건강뿐 아니라 사회·경제에도 영향을 미친다.정부의 바이러스 전파 완화 노력은 식당을 비롯한 많은 기업에 심각한 영향을 미쳤다.식당 폐쇄, 사교 모임 금지령과 사회적 거리 제한 등 강제적인 정책은 식당 운영과 고객 선호(예를 들어 더욱 엄격한 위생 기준을 요구하도록 하는 것)에 영향을 미쳤다.그러나 아직까지 팬데믹이 어떻게 식당 심사에 얼마나 영향을 미쳤는지는 알려지지 않았으며, 이를 분석하면 현재 이런 상황을 해결하는 정책에 정보를 제공할 수 있을 것으로 보인다.이 사업에서 코로나가 음식점 리뷰에 미치는 영향을 알아보기 위한 노력을 소개했는데, 코로나 사태 기간 뉴욕시와 로스앤젤레스 카운티 음식점에 대한 Yelp 리뷰에 초점을 맞췄다.전반적으로 말하면, 우리는 다음과 같은 공헌을 한다.우선 식당과 관련된 세립도 코로나에 대한 수동 주석(예를 들어 위생 습관, 서비스 변화, 현지 기업에 대한 동정과 지원)을 담은 600편의 리뷰가 담긴 데이터집을 수집했다.그 다음으로 우리는 감독 분류기, 키워드 기반의 약한 감독 방법과 무감독 주제 모델링 방법을 사용하여 코로나 측의 검측 문제를 해결했고, 예비 훈련을 바탕으로 하는 버트가 표시한 분류기가 최적 성능(F1=0.79)을 실현했다는 실험 결과가 나왔다.셋째, 우리는 코로나 관련 분야의 수량과 변화를 분석하고</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>پاندمیک COVID-19 اثرات غیر از سلامت فیزیکی، اثر اجتماعی و اقتصادی است. تلاش دولتی برای آهسته کردن گسترش ویروس بر بسیاری از تجارت، شامل رستوران، تأثیر سختی داشته است. سیاست‌های مجبور مانند بستن رستوران، بازداشت‌های جمع‌آوری اجتماعی و محدودیت‌های پرتاب اجتماعی به عملیات رستوران و ترجیح‌های مشتری تأثیر داده‌اند (مثلاً درخواست استانداردهای استانداردهای استانداردهای استانداردهای زیادی). ولی از این لحظه، مشخص نیست که چگونه و به چه اندازه پاندوم تحقیقات رستوران تاثیر داده است، یک تحلیل از آن ممکن است سیاست‌ها را برای حل این موقعیت در حال حاضر اطلاع دهد. در این کار، ما تلاش‌هایمان را برای درک اثرات COVID-19 بر رستوران نشان می‌دهیم، با تمرکز روی تحقیقات یلپ تولید شده در طول پاندمیک برای رستوران شهر نیویورک و کنترل لوس آنجلس. در کل، ما این شرکت ها را انجام می دهیم. اول، ما یک مجموعه داده‌های ۶۰۰ امتحان را با توضیح دستی از نقطه‌های COVID-۱۹ مربوط به رستوران جمع می‌کنیم (مثلاً تمرین سلامتی، تغییرات خدمت، همدلی و حمایت تجارت محلی). دوم، ما با استفاده از بررسی‌های مختصر نظارت شده، روش‌های ضعیف بر اساس کلمات‌های کلید، و روش‌های مدل‌سازی موضوع ناپذیر و آزمایشی نشان می‌دهیم که بررسی‌کنندگان بر اساس نمایش‌های BERT پیش آموزش‌شده بهترین کاربرد (F1=0.79) می‌رسند. سوم، ما تعداد و تکامل مربوط به COVID را در طول زمان تحلیل می کنیم و نشان می دهیم</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Die pandemiek van COVID-19 het implikasies buite fisiese gesondheid, wat gemeenskap en ekonomie beïnvloor. Regering versoeke om die verspreiding van die virus te stadig het 'n swaar invloek op baie besigheide, insluitend restaurante. Mandatory beleid soos restaurant toesluitings, verbans op sosiale versameling en sosiale afstand beperking het die restaurant operasies en kliëntevoorkeure afgevloek (bv. die versoek van stringere hygienstandaardes). As nou af, is dit nie duidelik hoe en tot hoe exten die pandemiek die restaurante oorskoue het, die analisie waarvan potensieel beleide kan informasie om hierdie voortgaande situasie te raak nie. In hierdie werk stel ons versoek om die effekte van COVID-19 te verstaan op restaurant resensies, met 'n fokus op Yelp resensies wat produseer gedurende die pandemiek vir New York City en Los Angeles County restaurante. Ons maak die volgende bydraai. Eerste, ons versamel 'n datastel van 600 hersienings met manuele aankennings van fyn-graad COVID-19 aspekte wat verwante met die restaurante (bv. hygienispraksies, diens veranderinge, simpatie en ondersteun vir plaaslike besighede). Tweede, ons adres COVID-19 aspektopdekking met die gebruik van superviseerde klassifiseerders, swak-superviseerde toegang wat op sleutelwoorde gebaseer is, en ononderwerp onderwerp onderwerp modellering toegang, en eksperimenteel vertoon dat klassifiseerders gebaseer op voor-onderwerp BERT voorstellings die beste prestasie bereik (F1=0.79). Derde, ons analyseer die nommer en evolusie van COVID-verwante aspekte oor tyd en wys</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Pandemia COVID-19 ka pasoja përtej shëndetit fizik, duke prekur shoqërinë dhe ekonomitë. Përpjekjet e qeverisë për të ngadalësuar shpërndarjen e virusit kanë patur një ndikim të rëndë në shumë biznese, duke përfshirë restorante. Politikat e detyrueshme të tilla si mbyllja e restauranteve, ndalimet e mbledhjeve shoqërore dhe kufizimet e distancës shoqërore kanë prekur operacionet e restauranteve si dhe preferencat e klientëve (për shembull, nxitja e kërkesës për standarde më të ashpra higjene). As of now, however, it is not clear how and to what extent the pandemic has affected restaurant reviews, an analysis of which could potentially inform policies for addressing this ongoing situation.  Në këtë punë, ne paraqesim përpjekjet tona për të kuptuar efektet e COVID-19 në revistat e restauranteve, me një përqëndrim në revistat e Yelp të prodhuara gjatë pandemisë për restaurantet e Nju Jorkut dhe Los Anxhelosit. Overall, we make the following contributions.  Së pari, ne mbledhim një grup të dhënash prej 600 shqyrtimeve me anotacione manual e të aspekteve COVID-19 të hollësishme lidhur me restorantet (për shembull, praktikat higjenike, ndryshimet e shërbimeve, simpati dhe mbështetje për bizneset lokale). Së dyti, ne trajtojmë zbulimin e aspekteve COVID-19 duke përdorur klasifikuesit e mbikqyrur, qasjet e mbikqyrur dobësisht bazuar në fjalët kyçe dhe qasjet e modelimit të temave të pa mbikqyrur dhe eksperimentalisht tregojmë se klasifikuesit bazuar në përfaqësimet e paratrajnuara BERT arrijnë performancën më të mirë (F1=0.79). Së treti, ne analizojmë numrin dhe evolucionin e aspekteve të lidhura me COVID gjatë kohës dhe tregojmë</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>COVID-19 pandemiýasy fiziksel saglyklaryň daşyndan täsirleýär, jemgyýeti we ekonomileriň täsirine täsirleýär. Hökümet virüsüniň ýuwaşyrlygyny azaltmak üçin köp biznislere, restoranlary hem gaty bir täsiri ýok etdi. Restoran ýapmaklary ýaly meýdany politikalar, sosyal ýygnamalary we sosyal taýýarlanmaky çykarmaklary restoran işlerine we müşterileriň tercihleri (meseläm, has diň gysga hygiene standartlaryna g özlemek üçin) täsirleýär. Şu wagtdan hem pandemiýanyň restoran çözümleriniň nähili täsirini we nähili näçe näçe täsirini bolup bilenokdygyny düşünemokdir. Bu çözümleri bu durumda çözmek üçin politikalary biljek bolup biler. Bu işde, biz COVID-19 restoran resumileriniň täsirini düşünmek üçin çabalarymyzy görkeýäris, New York şäheriniň pandemiýasynda we Los Angeles şäheriniň restoranlarynda ýerleşýän Yelp reviewlerine üns berýäris. Hemme zatda, biz indiki täsirlerimizi goýýarys. Ilkinji gezek, biz 600 sany çykyş bilen el tapylýan COVID-19 restoranlaryň (meselâ, hygiene praktika, häsiýet üýtgewleri, sympatiýa we ýerli biznisleriň destegi) golaýlaşdyrylyp bilen çykýarys. Ikinjisi, biz COVID-19 aspekt tanyşyny üstlenen klasifikatçylara ullanýarys, azajyk-üstlenen açarlar we suytlanmaýan tem modelleme ýakynlamalaryny we eksperimentel şeklinde BERT öňünden bilinmeli terjimelerinde daýanýan klasifikatçylara iñ gowy hereket edip bilen tanyşdyrýarys (F1=0.79). Üçüncüsü, COVID'iň zamanla ilgili aspektlerin sanyny we evrimini çözümleýäris we görkez</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>የCOVID-19 ደዌብ ማኅበራዊ እና ኢኮኖሚካ በሚያስጨንቁበት አካባቢ ጤና ውጤት በላይ ነው፡፡ መንግሥት የቪሮሽን ስፋት ለማዘጋጀት ጥቃት በብዙ ንግድ፣ ሰራትሮቶች ላይ እጅግ የበረቱ ጉዳይ አግኝቷል፡፡ እንደማረፊያው ፖለቲካዎች፣ ማኅበራዊ ጉባኤ ላይ የሚከለክሉ እና ማኅበራዊ ግንኙነት የግንኙነት ግንኙነት የአራሲቱን ሥራ እና የአጋራጆች ምርጫዎች አስጨንቋል (ምሳሌ ብርቱ የጤና ድጋፍ ጥቅም እንዲያስፈልጋቸው)፡ አሁን ግን፣ የደዌው እንዴት እና እንዴት በሬሽሮንት ላይ የወሰነ ግልፅ አይገልጽም፣ ማንኛውም አስተያየት የዚህን ሁኔታ ለመቆጣጠር የፖሊሲቶችን ማሳየት ይችላል፡፡ በዚህ ሥራ፣ የCOVID-19 ውጤቶች በሬስቶሮንቲ ክፍተቶችን ለማስተዋል ስልጣናችንን እናሳውቃለን፡፡ በሙሉ፣ የሚከተሉትን አዋጅ እናደርጋለን፡፡ በመጀመሪያው፣ 600 የዳታ ዘጠኝ ቁጥጥር፣ ከኮቪD-19 ጋር የተደረገውን አካባቢዎች (ምሳሌ የጤና ሥራ፣ የአገልግሎት ለውጥ፣ ስህተት፣ እህረት እና የቅርብ ነጋዴዎችን ለመደጋገም እናስባለን፡፡ Second, we address COVID-19 aspect detection using supervised classifiers, weakly-supervised approaches based on keywords, and unsupervised topic modeling approaches, and experimentally show that classifiers based on pre-trained BERT representations achieve the best performance (F1=0.79).  ሦስተኛ፣ ከCOVID ጋር ያሉትን ቁጥርና ውጤት በጊዜው እና ለማሳየት እናሳያልን</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>কোভিড-১৯ প্যানেডিমের শারীরিক স্বাস্থ্যের বাইরে, সমাজ ও অর্থনীতির উপর প্রভাব ফেলেছে। সরকার এই ভাইরাসের ছড়িয়ে পড়ার প্রচেষ্টা কমিয়ে দিয়েছে অনেক ব্যবসায়ী, যার মধ্যে রেস্তুরেন্ট রয়েছে। রেস্তুরেন্ট বন্ধ, সামাজিক সমাবেশে নিষিদ্ধ এবং সামাজিক বিপর্যয়ের নীতিগুলো রেস্তুরেন্টের কার্যকলাপ এবং কাস্টমারের পছন্দের প্রভাব ফেলেছে (যেমন কঠো তবে এখন পর্যন্ত এটা পরিষ্কার নয় কিভাবে এবং কি ভাবে এই বিপর্যয় রেস্তুরেন্ট পর্যবেক্ষণের প্রভাব ফেলেছে, যার বিশ্লেষণ সম্ভবত এই পরিস্থিতি নিয়ে নীতিকে জ In this work, we present our efforts to understand the effects of COVID-19 on restaurant reviews, with a focus on Yelp reviews produced during the pandemic for New York City and Los Angeles County restaurants.  সাধারণত, আমরা নিম্নলিখিত অংশগ্রহণ করি। প্রথমত, আমরা ৬০০ তথ্য পর্যবেক্ষণের একটি ডাটাসেট সংগ্রহ করেছি যেখানে স্থানীয় ব্যবসায়ীদের জন্য সুন্দর কোভিড-১৯ বিষয়ের সাথে সম্পর্কিত ভালো কোভিড-১৯ বিষয়ের দ্বিতীয়, আমরা কভিড-১৯ দিকের আবিষ্কারের সাথে কথা বলি, পর্যবেক্ষণ করা শ্রেণীবিদ, কীওয়ার্ডের ভিত্তিতে দুর্বল পর্যবেক্ষণের উপায় এবং সংরক্ষিত বিষয়ের মডেলিং পদ্ধতি এবং পরীক্ষায় দেখাচ্ছি যে পূর তৃতীয়, আমরা কোভিডি সম্পর্কিত বিষয়ের সংখ্যা এবং বিবর্তন বিশ্লেষণ করি সময় এবং দেখানোর জন্য</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>COVID-19 համաճարակը ունի ազդեցություններ ֆիզիկական առողջությունից դուրս, ազդեցություններ հասարակության և տնտեսության վրա: Կառավարության ջանքերը վարակի տարածումը դանդաղելու համար շատ բիզնեսների, ներառյալ ռեստորանների վրա լուրջ ազդեցություն ունեցան: Պարտավորական քաղաքականությունը, ինչպիսիք են ռեստորանների փակումները, սոցիալական հավաքածուների արգելքները և սոցիալական հեռավորության սահմանափակումները, ազդել են ռեստորանների գործողություններին, ինչպես նաև հաճախորդների նախընտրություններին (օրինակ, ավելի խիստ հիգենեն ստա Այնուամենայնիվ, հիմա պարզ չէ, թե ինչպես և ինչքանով է պանդեմիան ազդել ռեստորանների վերանայման վրա, որի վերլուծությունը կարող է պոտենցիալ տեղեկացնել քաղաքականությունը այս ընթացքում գտնվող իրավիճակի լուծման համար: In this work, we present our efforts to understand the effects of COVID-19 on restaurant reviews, with a focus on Yelp reviews produced during the pandemic for New York City and Los Angeles County restaurants.  Ընդհանուր առմամբ, մենք ներդրում ենք հետևյալ ներդրումները: Նախ և առաջ, մենք հավաքում ենք 600 վերլուծությունների տվյալների համակարգ, որի ձեռքով նկարագրված են COVID-19 տեսանկյունները, որոնք կապված են ռեստորանների հետ (օրինակ, հիգենային գործողություններ, ծառայությունների փոփոխություններ, սիմպատիա և աջակցություն տեղական բիզնեսների Երկրորդ, մենք դիտարկում ենք COVID-19 ասպեկտների հայտնաբերումը օգտագործելով վերահսկված դասակարգողներ, թույլ վերահսկված մոտեցումներ, հիմնված բառերի վրա, և անվերահսկված թեմային մոդելներ, և փորձարկումներ ցույց են տալիս, որ BER-ի նախապատրաստված ներկայացումների հիմնված դասակարգողները հասնում են լավագույն Երրորդ, մենք վերլուծում ենք COVID-ի հետ կապված ասպեկտների թիվը և էվոլյուցիան ժամանակի ընթացքում և ցույց ենք տալիս,</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>COVID-19 pandemik fizik sağlığından, toplum və ekonomilərə təsir edir. Hökumət virüsünün yayılmasını yavaşlaşdırmaq üçün çoxlu işlər, restoranlar da dahil olmaqla, şiddətli etkisi vardır. Restoran qapılması, sosyal toplantılara qadağan edilməsi və sosyal uzaqlaşma müəyyənləşdirmələri restoran işlərinə və müşterilərin seçimlərinə təsir etdilər (məsələn, daha şiddətli hygiene standartlarına tələb edir). Halbuki şimdilik pandemik restoran tərzlərinə nə qədər və nə qədər təsir etdiyini açıq deyildir, bu analizi mümkün olaraq bu durumu çəkmək üçün politikaları xəbər verə bilər. Bu işdə, New York şəhəri və Los Angeles County restoranların pandemiyası sırasında ürəklənmiş Yelp reviewlərinə məxsus olaraq COVID-19 təsirlərini anlamaq üçün çabalarımızı göstəririk. Əlbəttə, biz də aşağıdaki qismətlər edərik. İlk dəfə, restoranlarla bağlı COVID-19 g örüntüləri ilə birlikdə 600 dəyişiklik dəyişiklikləri toplayırıq. İkincisi, biz COVID-19 aspekt keşfini təsdiqlənmiş klasifikatçılar, anahtar sözlərinə dayanan zəif təsdiqlənmiş metodlar vasitəsilə, təsdiqlənmiş məsələlər modellik metodlarını təsdiqləyirik, və təcrübə olaraq təhsil edilmiş BERT təsdiqlənmələrinə dayanan klasifikatçıların ən yaxşı performans yetişdirməsini göstəririk (F1=0 Üçüncüsü, biz COVID-ə bağlı aspektlərin sayını və dəyişikliyini zaman boyunca analiz edirik və göstəririk</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Pandemija COVID-19 ima implikacije izvan fizičkog zdravlja, utječu na društvo i ekonomiju. Vladni napori na usporiti širenje virus a imali su teški utjecaj na mnoge poduzeće, uključujući restorane. Obvezne politike poput zatvaranja restorana, zabrani na socijalne skupljanje i ograničenja na društveno distanciranje utjecaju na operacije restorana, kao i preferencije klijenta (npr. zahtjev težih higijenskih standarda). Međutim, od sada nije jasno kako i do kakve mjere je pandemija utjecala na preglede restorana, analiza kojih bi potencijalno mogla obavijestiti politiku za rješavanje ovog trenutnog situacije. U ovom poslu predstavljamo naše napore da razumijemo učinak COVID-19 na restoranske preglede, s fokusom na Yelp preglede proizvođene tokom pandemije za restorane u okrugu New York i Los Angeles. Uglavnom, mi donosimo sljedeće doprinose. Prvo, skupljamo skup podataka od 600 pregleda sa ručnim annotacijom finog zrnca COVID-19 aspekta povezanih sa restoranima (npr. higijenske prakse, promjene usluga, simpatija i podrška lokalnim poduzećima). Drugo, obraćamo se otkrivanju aspekta COVID-19 koristeći nadzorne klasifikatore, slabe nadzorne pristupe na temelju ključnih riječi, i neodređene pristupe modeliranja tema, i eksperimentalno pokazujemo da klasifikatori bazirani na predobučenim predstavljanjima BERT postignu najbolje učinke (F1=0,79). Treće, analiziramo broj i evoluciju aspekta povezanih s COVID-om tijekom vremena i pokazujemo</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Pandemie COVID-19 má důsledky mimo fyzické zdraví a ovlivňuje společnost a ekonomiky. Úsilí vlády o zpomalení šíření viru mělo vážný dopad na mnoho podniků, včetně restaurací. Povinné zásady, jako jsou uzavření restaurací, zákaz společenských setkání a omezení sociálního vzdálenosti, ovlivnily provoz restaurací i preference zákazníků (např. vyvolávají požadavek na přísnější hygienické normy). V současnosti však není jasné, jak a do jaké míry pandemie ovlivnila recenze restaurací, jejichž analýza by mohla potenciálně informovat politiky pro řešení této probíhající situace. V této práci představujeme naše snahy porozumět účinkům COVID-19 na recenze restaurací, se zaměřením na recenze Yelp vytvořené během pandemie pro restaurace New York City a Los Angeles County. Celkově přispíváme k následujícím příspěvkům. Nejprve sestavíme datovou sadu 600 recenzí s manuálními anotacemi jemnozrnných aspektů COVID-19 souvisejících s restauracemi (např. hygienické postupy, změny služeb, sympatie a podpora místním podnikům). Za druhé se zabýváme detekcí aspektů COVID-19 pomocí dozorovaných klasifikátorů, slabě dozorovaných přístupů založených na klíčových slovech a bez dozoru modelováním témat a experimentálně ukazujeme, že klasifikátory založené na předškolených reprezentacích BERT dosahují nejlepšího výkonu (F1=0,79). Za třetí analyzujeme počet a vývoj aspektů souvisejících s COVID v průběhu času a ukazujeme</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>COVID-19 pandeemia mõjutab ka füüsilist tervist, mõjutades ühiskonda ja majandust. Valitsuse jõupingutused viiruse leviku aeglustamiseks on avaldanud tõsist mõju paljudele ettevõtetele, sealhulgas restoranidele. Kohustuslikud põhimõtted, nagu restoranide sulgemine, sotsiaalsete koosolekute keeld ja sotsiaalse kauguse piirangud, on mõjutanud restoranide tegevust ja klientide eelistusi (nt nõudmine rangemate hügieenistandardite järele). Praeguseks ei ole aga selge, kuidas ja mil määral on pandeemia mõjutanud restoranide ülevaateid, mille analüüs võiks potentsiaalselt anda teavet praeguse olukorra lahendamiseks. Selles töös tutvustame oma jõupingutusi mõista COVID-19 mõju restoranide arvustustele, keskendudes pandeemia ajal New Yorgi ja Los Angelese maakonna restoranide Yelpi arvustustele. Kokkuvõttes anname järgmised panused. Esiteks koostame 600 ülevaatest koosneva andmekogumi, milles on käsitsi märgitud restoranidega seotud peeneteraliste COVID-19 aspektide kohta (nt hügieenitavad, teenusemuutused, kaastunne ja toetus kohalikele ettevõtetele). Teiseks käsitleme COVID-19 aspektide tuvastamist järelevalvega klassifitseerijate, märksõnadel põhinevate nõrga järelevalvega lähenemisviiside ja järelevalveta teemamodelleerimisega seotud lähenemisviiside abil ning näitame eksperimentaalselt, et eelkoolitud BERTi esitustel põhinevad klassifitseerijad saavutavad parima tulemuse (F1=0,79). Kolmandaks analüüsime COVIDiga seotud aspektide arvu ja arengut aja jooksul ning näitame</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>COVID-19-pandemia vaikuttaa fyysisen terveyden lisäksi yhteiskuntaan ja talouteen. Hallituksen pyrkimyksillä hidastaa viruksen leviämistä on ollut vakavia vaikutuksia moniin yrityksiin, myös ravintoloihin. Pakolliset käytännöt, kuten ravintoloiden sulkeminen, kokoontumiskiellot ja sosiaaliset etäisyysrajoitukset, ovat vaikuttaneet ravintoloiden toimintaan ja asiakkaiden mieltymyksiin (esimerkiksi vaatineet tiukempia hygieniastandardeja). Toistaiseksi ei kuitenkaan ole selvää, miten ja missä määrin pandemia on vaikuttanut ravintoloiden arvosteluihin. Analyysi siitä voisi mahdollisesti olla pohjana tämänhetkiseen tilanteeseen. Tässä työssä esittelemme pyrkimyksiämme ymmärtää COVID-19:n vaikutuksia ravintoloiden arvosteluihin keskittyen pandemian aikana tuotettuihin Yelp-arvosteluihin New Yorkin ja Los Angelesin piirikunnan ravintoloille. Kaiken kaikkiaan esitämme seuraavat kannanotot. Ensin kokoamme 600 arvostelun aineiston, jossa on manuaalisia merkintöjä ravintoloihin liittyvistä hienorakeisista COVID-19-näkökohdista (esim. hygieniakäytännöistä, palvelumuutoksista, sympatiasta ja paikallisten yritysten tuesta). Toiseksi käsittelemme COVID-19-aspektintunnistusta valvotuilla luokittelijoilla, heikosti valvotuilla avainsanoihin perustuvilla lähestymistavoilla ja valvomattomilla teemamallinnusmenetelmillä. Kokeellisesti osoitamme, että esikoulutettuihin BERT-esityksiin perustuvat luokittelijat saavuttavat parhaan suorituskyvyn (F1=0,79). Kolmanneksi analysoimme COVIDiin liittyvien näkökohtien lukumäärää ja kehitystä ajan mittaan ja näytämme</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>La pandèmia COVID-19 té implicacions més enllà de la salut física, afectant la societat i les economies. Els esforços del govern per ralentizar la difusió del virus han tingut un gran impacte en moltes empreses, incloent restaurants. Mandatory policies such as restaurant closures, bans on social gatherings, and social distancing restrictions have affected restaurant operations as well as customer preferences (e.g., prompting a demand of stricter hygiene standards).  Però a partir d'ara, no és clar com i en quin punt la pandèmia ha afectat les revisions dels restaurants, una an àlisi de la qual podria potencialment informar les polítiques per abordar aquesta situació en curs. In this work, we present our efforts to understand the effects of COVID-19 on restaurant reviews, with a focus on Yelp reviews produced during the pandemic for New York City and Los Angeles County restaurants.  En general, fem les següents contribucions. Primer, assemblem un conjunt de dades de 600 revisions amb anotacions manuals d'aspectes COVID-19 fins grains relacionats amb restaurants (per exemple, pràctiques d'higiene, canvis de servei, simpatia i suport per a les empreses locals). Segon, ens ocupem de la detecció d'aspectes COVID-19 fent servir classificadors supervisats, enfocaments debidament supervisats basats en paraules clau i enfocaments no supervisats de modelació de temes, i experimentalment mostren que classificadors basats en representacions BERT pré-entrenats aconsegueixen el millor rendiment (F1=0,79). En tercer lloc, analitzem el nombre i l'evolució dels aspectes relacionats amb COVID amb el temps i demostrem</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_he>לפנדמיה COVID-19 יש השלכות מעבר לבריאות פיזית, משפיעות על החברה והכלכליות. המאמצים של הממשלה להאט את התפשטות של הוירוס היו השפעה רצינית על עסקים רבים, כולל מסעדות. מדיניות חובה כמו סגירת מסעדות, אסורים על אסיפות חברתיות, ומגבלות מרחקים חברתיים השפיעו על פעולות המסעדות, כמו גם על עדיפות לקוחות (לדוגמא, לגרום לדריש של סטנדרטי היגינה קשים יותר). ועכשיו, עם זאת, לא ברור איך ולמה המידה הפנדמיה השפיעה על ביקורי מסעדות, ניתוח שיכול להודיע על מדיניות להתמודד עם המצב הממשיך הזה. בעבודה הזו, אנחנו מציגים את המאמצים שלנו להבין את השפעות של COVID-19 על ביקורות מסעדות, עם מרכז על ביקורות Yelp שנוצרו במהלך הפנדמיה למסעדות של ניו יורק ומחוז לוס אנג'לס. באופן כללי, אנחנו עושים את התרומות הבאות. ראשית, אנו אוספים קבוצת נתונים של 600 ביקורות עם ציונים ידניים של אפקטים COVID-19 מעורפלים בקשר למסעדות (למשל מערכות היגינה, שינויים שירות, סימפטיה ותמיכה לעסקים מקומיים). שנית, אנו מתייחסים לזיהוי איכות COVID-19 באמצעות מסווגים מבוקשים, גישות מבוקשות בחולשה מבוססות על מילים מפתחות, ובגישות דגמניות נושאים לא מבוקשות, ולהראות ניסויים כי מסווגים מבוססים על מייצגים BERT מאומנים מראש להשיג את ההופעה הטובה ביותר (F1=0.79). שלישית, אנו מנתחים את מספר ואבולוציה של היבטים הקשורים ל COVID במהלך הזמן
that the resulting time series have substantial correlation (Spearman's  =0.84) with critical statistics related to the COVID-19 pandemic, including the number of new COVID-19 cases.  לדעתנו, זו העבודה הראשונה שנבחנה את השפעות של COVID-19 על ביקורי מסעדה Yelp ויכולה לפרסם פוטנציאליות על ידי מחלקות בריאות הציבורית, לדוגמה, כדי לכסות את השימוש משאבים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Cuduran COKID-19 yana da amfani masu ƙaranci ga afya, mai shagala ga jami da aikin. Government's aikin yin kashẽwa ga tarakin wannan misalin ya shagala mai tsanani a kan businesses mãsu yawa, kamar musamman. Policy na daidai kamar rufe restaurant, an hana mutane a samuran sosia, da hanyoyin sauri da jamii, sun yi shawara ga aikin kafahan da kuma misãlai ga matafiya (misali da aka sabar da umarni masu kallo mai tsanani). Aka yanzu, bã ya bayyana a yanzu yadda da kafin nan ya yi amfani da ma'anar matsayin restaurant, an yi anayyar da wanda zai iya gaya wa lissafar da za'a yi mataimaki ga wannan halin da ke tafiya. Daga wannan aikin, Munã gaura aikinmu dõmin ka fahimta matsayin COV-19 a kan rabo-rayuwar restaurant, da makini a kan jarrabin Yelf wanda aka samu a lokacin garin New York da Los Engls County restaurants. Kayya da shi, munã sami rabon da waɗannan. Kayyan da, muna samun wani danne na takarda 600 ana samu da kunnuwa na manual da aka nuna masu takarda kofi-COKID-19 masu husũna da restaurant (misali, mazaɓa na aikin muhimmada, musanyawa, rahamar da kuma taimakon businessa na lokaci). Piki, za'a yi amfani da shiryoyin kowace COV-19 da aka yi tsaron fasafa masu tsari, masu rauni da wato-tsari a kan maganar maɓallin, kuma da hanyoyin misãlai da ba'a tsare su ba, kuma ke nuna, a kan jarrabo, musamman, su sami da musamman, a kan karatun masu tsari da ke gaba-wa'anar BERT, su sami mafi kyawi (F1=0.79). na ukun, Munã anayya naman da uzalisar masu da aka yi na alkawari a lokacin da za'a nũna
Shiryar lokaci da ke ƙara yana da muhimmi mai husũma (Spearman =0.84) da statistics na muhimmi da ke haɗi da COKID-19 ɗin agogon, da kuma ƙidãyar kasuka na s ãbuwa COV-19. Ga saninmu, wannan ne aikin na farko, yana analyza matsayin COV-19 a kan kurejai na Yelfi kuma yana iya yiwuwa ya sanar da lissafar da idanun afura, misali, dõmin su tsare matuƙar na amfani da resource.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>(Video) Goberno-wong kanggo nyeleh ngerasakno ujian winih ning karo perbudhakan anyar tentang karo akeh pengguna nêmên, lan restoran. Siji sing perusahaan lagi kaya ngono kapan restoran, nggalaksi urip nggawe perusahaan ara, lan ngêptahan sing beraksi hukum sing nggawe restoran lan ngêptahan sing berarti Perintah Pancenan (isih sabên, njuk sabên ngentèh kejahatan kanggo ngilangno urip sing beraksi kapan). Nanging saiki, ora klêran piye nganggep kuwi, nganggep sampeyan kawane karo hal bandem nggawe resmi restoran, kedhélané sing bisa yengan akeh iso nggawe poliki sing iso nggawe gerakan urip nggawe durung iki. Nang gunggo iki, kita mulai nggawe perbudhakan kanggo ngerasakno efek nggo resmi cor-19 kanggo resmi restoran, karo ndelok sing nggawe barang yelp sing bisa ngelarang Panem kanggo langlangkung dolanan sing paling maneh kanggo New Yok lan restoran LA. Lah kok, kéné lagi nganggo kontribusi sing takon Awak dhéwé, ngêmên beraksi akeh dataset karo 6 atum sing beraksi karo nganggo manual sing dibutungane soko corid-19 sing ngregani soko restoran (isul. Perintah sing Hyensi, njujayakno, senjatahan lan ndhukung nggo keamanan empresa lokal). Sikonde, kita ngarasakno OPML-19 Aspect detection nggambar kelas kucasar Genjer-Genjer, kita diwerlilungi perusahaan lan jeweluran linepakan karo ngono nggambar
Perintah sing dibutuhke nggawe Perintah dumadhi Lansing berarti (Kasunyatan EspeArman =0.04)karo akeh barang nggawe barang nggawe barang kelas ntasun cara-19 Panjenengan awak dhéwé, iki sing perusahaan kanggo nyedihake perusahaan kanggo nyedihake perusahaan coro-19 lan mbukaké restoran yelp kuwi iso nggawe politik sing diputara perusahaan kanggo dimulaan sing wérti ngêdol, sampek, iso nggawe nguasakno perusahaan resuran.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་ནད་དོན་གནད་དོན་ཡོད་པའི་(COVID-19)ནུས་པ་དབུགས་ཀྱི་འཕྲོད་བསྟེན་དང་། སྤྱི་ཚོགས་དང་། སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ གཞུང་གིས་སྒོ་བརྙན་གྱི་རྒྱ་ཚད་དུ་འགྱུར་བར་གནོད་འགྲུལ་བའི་སྣེ་ཚོགས་རྣམས་བརྩིས་ཤུགས་ཏེ། དངོས འོན་ཀྱང་། ད་ལྟ་བུའི་ཆེན་དུ་ཅི་ཞིག འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་ལྟ་བ་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་COVID-19 ཡོད་པའི་འཐབ་ཚུལ་གྱི་རྐྱེན་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་གླེང་སྒྲུང་ལ་བསླབ་ནི་ ཡོངས་རྫོགས་ན། འོག་གི་གཤམ་གྱི་གུས་འཆར་བྱེད་དགོས་པ་དེ་ཡིན། First, we assemble a dataset of 600 reviews with manual annotations of fine-grained COVID-19 aspects related to restaurants (e.g. hygiene practices, service changes, sympathy and support for local businesses). Second, we address COVID-19 aspect detection using supervised classifiers, weakly-supervised approaches based on keywords, and unsupervised topic modeling approaches, and experimentally show that classifiers based on pre-trained BERT representations achieve the best performance (F1=0.79). གསུམ་པ་བརྗོད། ང་ཚོས་COVID དང་འབྲེལ་བའི་аспект་ ཀྱི་ཨང་གྲངས་དང་ཡར་རྒྱས་ལྗངས་དེ་དུས་དང་འཆར་བརྟན་ན།
resulting time series have substantial correlation (Spearman's  =0.84) with critical statistics related to the COVID-19 pandemic, including the number of new COVID-19 cases. ང་ཚོའི་གནས་ཚུལ་ལ། འདི་ནི་COVID-19 ཡོད་པའི་འཛམ་གླིང་སྣོད་ཀྱི་ལྟ་ཞིབ་དཔྱད་ཞིབ་བྱེད་པའི་ལས་འགན་སྐྱོན་དང་། དཔེར་ན། རྒྱུ་ཆས་ལག་ལེན་འཐབ་ནི་འགྲེ</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_sk>Pandemija COVID-19 ima posledice zunaj fizičnega zdravja in vpliva na družbo in gospodarstva. Prizadevanja vlade za upočasnitev širjenja virusa so močno vplivala na številna podjetja, vključno z restavracijami. Obvezne politike, kot so zaprtje restavracij, prepovedi družabnih srečanj in omejitve socialnega oddaljenosti, so vplivale na delovanje restavracij in na želje strank (npr. zahteve po strožjih higienskih standardih). Vendar od zdaj ni jasno, kako in v kolikšni meri je pandemija vplivala na preglede restavracij, analiza katerih bi lahko utegnila upoštevati politike za obravnavanje teh trenutnih razmer. V tem delu predstavljamo naša prizadevanja za razumevanje učinkov COVID-19 na ocene restavracij, s poudarkom na Yelpovih ocenah, pripravljenih med pandemijo za restavracije New York City in Los Angeles County. Na splošno dajemo naslednje prispevke. Najprej zberemo podatkovni niz 600 pregledov z ročnimi opombami o drobnozrnatih vidikih COVID-19, povezanih z restavracijami (npr. higienske prakse, spremembe storitev, sočutje in podpora lokalnim podjetjem). Drugič, odkrivanje vidikov COVID-19 obravnavamo z uporabo nadzorovanih klasifikatorjev, šibko nadzorovanih pristopov, ki temeljijo na ključnih besedah, in nenadzorovanih pristopov modeliranja teme, eksperimentalno pa pokažemo, da klasifikatorji, ki temeljijo na predhodno usposobljenih predstavitvah BERT, dosegajo najboljšo učinkovitost (F1=0,79). Tretjič, analiziramo število in razvoj vidikov, povezanih s COVID, skozi čas in prikažemo
da imajo nastale časovne vrste znatno korelacijo (Spearmanov = 0,84) s kritičnimi statističnimi podatki, povezanimi s pandemijo COVID-19, vključno s številom novih primerov COVID-19. Kolikor vemo, je to prvo delo, ki analizira učinke COVID-19 na preglede restavracij Yelp in bi lahko potencialno vplivalo na politike javnega zdravstvenega oddelka, na primer za kritje uporabe virov.</abstract_sk>
      </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Assessing Cognitive Linguistic Influences in the Assignment of Blame</title>
      <author><first>Karen</first><last>Zhou</last></author>
      <author><first>Ana</first><last>Smith</last></author>
      <author><first>Lillian</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <pages>61–69</pages>
      <abstract>Lab studies in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognition">cognition</a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychology_of_morality">psychology of morality</a> have proposed some thematic and linguistic factors that influence <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moral_reasoning">moral reasoning</a>. This paper assesses how well the findings of these studies generalize to a large corpus of over 22,000 descriptions of fraught situations posted to a dedicated forum. At this social-media site, users judge whether or not an author is in the wrong with respect to the event that the author described. We find that, consistent with lab studies, there are statistically significant differences in uses of first-person passive voice, as well as first-person agents and patients, between descriptions of situations that receive different blame judgments. These <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> also aid performance in the task of predicting the eventual collective verdicts.</abstract>
      <url hash="1364306e">2021.socialnlp-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.socialnlp-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>zhou-etal-2021-assessing</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/scruples">Scruples</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Evaluating Deception Detection Model Robustness To <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variation_(linguistics)">Linguistic Variation</a></title>
      <author><first>Maria</first><last>Glenski</last></author>
      <author><first>Ellyn</first><last>Ayton</last></author>
      <author><first>Robin</first><last>Cosbey</last></author>
      <author><first>Dustin</first><last>Arendt</last></author>
      <author><first>Svitlana</first><last>Volkova</last></author>
      <pages>70–80</pages>
      <abstract>With the increasing use of machine-learning driven algorithmic judgements, it is critical to develop <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> that are robust to evolving or manipulated inputs. We propose an extensive analysis of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robust_statistics">model robustness</a> against <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variation_(linguistics)">linguistic variation</a> in the setting of deceptive news detection, an important task in the context of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misinformation">misinformation spread online</a>. We consider two prediction tasks and compare three state-of-the-art embeddings to highlight consistent trends in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> performance, high confidence misclassifications, and high impact failures. By measuring the effectiveness of adversarial defense strategies and evaluating model susceptibility to adversarial attacks using character- and word-perturbed text, we find that character or mixed ensemble models are the most effective defenses and that character perturbation-based attack tactics are more successful.</abstract>
      <url hash="725f36c6">2021.socialnlp-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.socialnlp-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>glenski-etal-2021-evaluating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Using Noisy Self-Reports to Predict Twitter User Demographics<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter User Demographics</title>
      <author><first>Zach</first><last>Wood-Doughty</last></author>
      <author><first>Paiheng</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <author><first>Xiao</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Dredze</last></author>
      <pages>123–137</pages>
      <abstract>Computational social science studies often contextualize <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_analysis">content analysis</a> within standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demography">demographics</a>. Since <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demography">demographics</a> are unavailable on many <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media platforms</a> (e.g. Twitter), numerous studies have inferred <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demography">demographics</a> automatically. Despite many studies presenting proof-of-concept inference of race and ethnicity, training of practical systems remains elusive since there are few annotated datasets. Existing datasets are small, inaccurate, or fail to cover the four most common <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Race_and_ethnicity_in_the_United_States">racial and ethnic groups</a> in the United States. We present a method to identify self-reports of race and ethnicity from Twitter profile descriptions. Despite the noise of automated supervision, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-report_study">self-report datasets</a> enable improvements in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a> performance on gold standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-report_study">self-report survey data</a>. The result is a reproducible method for creating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training_and_development">large-scale training resources</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Race_and_ethnicity_in_the_United_States">race and ethnicity</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="c7fca580">2021.socialnlp-1.11</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.socialnlp-1.11</doi>
      <bibkey>wood-doughty-etal-2021-using</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://bitbucket.org/mdredze/demographer" additional="false">mdredze/demographer</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>PANDORA Talks : Personality and Demographics on Reddit<fixed-case>PANDORA</fixed-case> Talks: Personality and Demographics on <fixed-case>R</fixed-case>eddit</title>
      <author><first>Matej</first><last>Gjurković</last></author>
      <author><first>Mladen</first><last>Karan</last></author>
      <author><first>Iva</first><last>Vukojević</last></author>
      <author><first>Mihaela</first><last>Bošnjak</last></author>
      <author><first>Jan</first><last>Snajder</last></author>
      <pages>138–152</pages>
      <abstract>Personality and demographics are important variables in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_science">social sciences</a> and computational sociolinguistics. However, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> with both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personality_type">personality and demographic labels</a> are scarce. To address this, we present <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PANDORA">PANDORA</a>, the first dataset of Reddit comments of 10k users partially labeled with three personality models and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demography">demographics</a> (age, gender, and location), including 1.6k users labeled with the well-established Big 5 personality model. We showcase the usefulness of this dataset on three experiments, where we leverage the more readily available data from other personality models to predict the Big 5 traits, analyze gender classification biases arising from psycho-demographic variables, and carry out a confirmatory and exploratory analysis based on psychological theories. Finally, we present benchmark prediction models for all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personality_type">personality and demographic variables</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="05dfea1b">2021.socialnlp-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.socialnlp-1.12</doi>
      <bibkey>gjurkovic-etal-2021-pandora</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/pandora">PANDORA</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Room to Grow : Understanding Personal Characteristics Behind Self Improvement Using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">Social Media</a></title>
      <author><first>MeiXing</first><last>Dong</last></author>
      <author><first>Xueming</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <author><first>Yiwei</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Ian</first><last>Stewart</last></author>
      <author><first>Rada</first><last>Mihalcea</last></author>
      <pages>153–162</pages>
      <abstract>Many people aim for change, but not everyone succeeds. While there are a number of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_psychology">social psychology theories</a> that propose motivation-related characteristics of those who persist with change, few <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_psychology">computational studies</a> have explored the motivational stage of personal change. In this paper, we investigate a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> consisting of the writings of people who manifest intention to change, some of whom persist while others do not. Using a variety of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">linguistic analysis techniques</a>, we first examine the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writing_style">writing patterns</a> that distinguish the two groups of people. Persistent people tend to reference more topics related to long-term self-improvement and use a more complicated writing style. Drawing on these consistent differences, we build a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classifier_(linguistics)">classifier</a> that can reliably identify the people more likely to persist, based on their language. Our experiments provide new insights into the motivation-related behavior of people who persist with their intention to change.</abstract>
      <url hash="b1cfcb24">2021.socialnlp-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.socialnlp-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>dong-etal-2021-room</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Jujeop : Korean Puns for K-pop Stars on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">Social Media</a><fixed-case>K</fixed-case>orean Puns for K-pop Stars on Social Media</title>
      <author><first>Soyoung</first><last>Oh</last></author>
      <author><first>Jisu</first><last>Kim</last></author>
      <author><first>Seungpeel</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Eunil</first><last>Park</last></author>
      <pages>170–177</pages>
      <abstract>Jujeop is a type of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pun">pun</a> and a unique way for fans to express their love for the K-pop stars they follow using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Korean_language">Korean</a>. One of the unique characteristics of Jujeop is its use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exaggeration">exaggerated expressions</a> to compliment <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K-pop">K-pop stars</a>, which contain or lead to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humour">humor</a>. Based on this characteristic, Jujeop can be separated into four distinct types, with their own lexical collocations : (1) Fragmenting words to create a twist, (2) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homophone">Homophones</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homograph">homographs</a>, (3) Repetition, and (4) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonsense">Nonsense</a>. Thus, the current study first defines the concept of Jujeop in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Korean_language">Korean</a>, manually labels 8.6 K comments and annotates the comments to one of the four Jujeop types. With the given annotated corpus, this study presents distinctive characteristics of Jujeop comments compared to the other comments by classification task. Moreover, with the clustering approach, we proposed a structural dependency within each Jujeop type. We have made our dataset publicly available for future research of Jujeop expressions.</abstract>
      <url hash="2bd866e7">2021.socialnlp-1.15</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.socialnlp-1.15</doi>
      <bibkey>oh-etal-2021-jujeop</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/merry555/jujeop" additional="false">merry555/jujeop</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>