<collection id="2021.nlp4posimpact">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on NLP for Positive Impact</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Anjalie</first><last>Field</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Shrimai</first><last>Prabhumoye</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Maarten</first><last>Sap</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Zhijing</first><last>Jin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jieyu</first><last>Zhao</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Chris</first><last>Brockett</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="2a2e6a54">2021.nlp4posimpact-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="4789defb">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp4posimpact-2021-nlp</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>The Climate Change Debate and Natural Language Processing</title>
      <author><first>Manfred</first><last>Stede</last></author>
      <author><first>Ronny</first><last>Patz</last></author>
      <pages>8&#8211;18</pages>
      <abstract>The debate around climate change (CC)&#8212;its extent, its causes, and the necessary responses&#8212;is intense and of global importance. Yet, in the natural language processing (NLP) community, this domain has so far received little attention. In contrast, it is of enormous prominence in various social science disciplines, and some of that work follows the &#8221;text-as-data&#8221; paradigm, seeking to employ quantitative methods for analyzing large amounts of CC-related text. Other research is qualitative in nature and studies details, nuances, actors, and motivations within CC discourses. Coming from both NLP and Political Science, and reviewing key works in both disciplines, we discuss how social science approaches to CC debates can inform advances in text-mining/NLP, and how, in return, NLP can support policy-makers and activists in making sense of large-scale and complex CC discourses across multiple genres, channels, topics, and communities. This is paramount for their ability to make rapid and meaningful impact on the discourse, and for shaping the necessary policy change.</abstract>
      <url hash="a348fc77">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4posimpact-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>stede-patz-2021-climate</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Dialogue Act Classification for Augmentative and Alternative Communication</title>
      <author><first>E. Margaret</first><last>Perkoff</last></author>
      <pages>107&#8211;114</pages>
      <abstract>Augmentative and Alternative Communication (AAC) devices and applications are intended to make it easier for individuals with complex communication needs to participate in conversations. However, these devices have low adoption and retention rates. We review prior work with text recommendation systems that have not been successful in mitigating these problems. To address these gaps, we propose applying Dialogue Act classification to AAC conversations. We evaluated the performance of a state of the art model on a limited AAC dataset that was trained on both AAC and non-AAC datasets. The one trained on AAC (accuracy = 38.6%) achieved better performance than that trained on a non-AAC corpus (accuracy = 34.1%). These results reflect the need to incorporate representative datasets in later experiments. We discuss the need to collect more labeled AAC datasets and propose areas of future work.</abstract>
      <url hash="7dedea7a">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4posimpact-1.12</doi>
      <bibkey>perkoff-2021-dialogue</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Improving Policing with Natural Language Processing</title>
      <author><first>Anthony</first><last>Dixon</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Birks</last></author>
      <pages>115&#8211;124</pages>
      <abstract>This article explores the potential for Natural Language Processing (NLP) to enable a more effective, prevention focused and less confrontational policing model that has hitherto been too resource consuming to implement at scale. Problem-Oriented Policing (POP) is a potential replacement, at least in part, for traditional policing which adopts a reactive approach, relying heavily on the criminal justice system. By contrast, POP seeks to prevent crime by manipulating the underlying conditions that allow crimes to be committed. Identifying these underlying conditions requires a detailed understanding of crime events - tacit knowledge that is often held by police officers but which can be challenging to derive from structured police data. One potential source of insight exists in unstructured free text data commonly collected by police for the purposes of investigation or administration. Yet police agencies do not typically have the skills or resources to analyse these data at scale. In this article we argue that NLP offers the potential to unlock these unstructured data and by doing so allow police to implement more POP initiatives. However we caution that using NLP models without adequate knowledge may either allow or perpetuate bias within the data potentially leading to unfavourable outcomes.</abstract>
      <url hash="3387a444">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4posimpact-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>dixon-birks-2021-improving</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>A Speech-enabled Fixed-phrase Translator for Healthcare Accessibility</title>
      <author><first>Pierrette</first><last>Bouillon</last></author>
      <author><first>Johanna</first><last>Gerlach</last></author>
      <author><first>Jonathan</first><last>Mutal</last></author>
      <author><first>Nikos</first><last>Tsourakis</last></author>
      <author><first>Herv&#233;</first><last>Spechbach</last></author>
      <pages>135&#8211;142</pages>
      <abstract>In this overview article we describe an application designed to enable communication between health practitioners and patients who do not share a common language, in situations where professional interpreters are not available. Built on the principle of a fixed phrase translator, the application implements different natural language processing (NLP) technologies, such as speech recognition, neural machine translation and text-to-speech to improve usability. Its design allows easy portability to new domains and integration of different types of output for multiple target audiences. Even though BabelDr is far from solving the problem of miscommunication between patients and doctors, it is a clear example of NLP in a real world application designed to help minority groups to communicate in a medical context. It also gives some insights into the relevant criteria for the development of such an application.</abstract>
      <url hash="7830b960">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.15</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4posimpact-1.15</doi>
      <bibkey>bouillon-etal-2021-speech</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>