<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.econlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-10-28">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Economics and Natural Language Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Udo</first><last>Hahn</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Veronique</first><last>Hoste</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Amanda</first><last>Stent</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Punta Cana, Dominican Republic</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="4e91a557">2021.econlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>econlp-2021-economics</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>A Fine-Grained Annotated Corpus for Target-Based Opinion Analysis of Economic and Financial Narratives</title>
      <author><first>Jiahui</first><last>Hu</last></author>
      <author><first>Patrick</first><last>Paroubek</last></author>
      <pages>1–12</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper about aspect-based sentiment analysis (ABSA), we present the first version of a fine-grained annotated corpus for target-based opinion analysis (TBOA) to analyze <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economy">economic activities</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_market">financial markets</a>. We have annotated, at an intra-sentential level, a corpus of sentences extracted from documents representative of financial analysts’ most-read materials by considering how financial actors communicate about the evolution of event trends and analyze related publications (news, official communications, etc.). Since we focus on identifying the expressions of opinions related to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economy">economy</a> and financial markets, we annotated the sentences that contain at least one subjective expression about a domain-specific term. Candidate sentences for annotations were randomly chosen from texts of specialized press and professional information channels over a period ranging from 1986 to 2021. Our annotation scheme relies on various linguistic markers like domain-specific vocabulary, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax">syntactic structures</a>, and rhetorical relations to explicitly describe the author’s subjective stance. We investigated and evaluated the recourse to automatic pre-annotation with existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing technologies</a> to alleviate the annotation workload. Our aim is to propose a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> usable on the one hand as training material for the automatic detection of the opinions expressed on an extensive range of domain-specific aspects and on the other hand as a gold standard for evaluation TBOA. In this paper, we present our pre-annotation models and evaluations of their performance, introduce our annotation scheme and report on the main characteristics of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="06570a64">2021.econlp-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>hu-paroubek-2021-fine</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.econlp-1.1</doi>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/conll-2003">CoNLL-2003</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>EDGAR-CORPUS : Billions of Tokens Make The World Go Round<fixed-case>EDGAR</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>CORPUS</fixed-case>: Billions of Tokens Make The World Go Round</title>
      <author><first>Lefteris</first><last>Loukas</last></author>
      <author><first>Manos</first><last>Fergadiotis</last></author>
      <author><first>Ion</first><last>Androutsopoulos</last></author>
      <author><first>Prodromos</first><last>Malakasiotis</last></author>
      <pages>13–18</pages>
      <abstract>We release EDGAR-CORPUS, a novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> comprising annual reports from all the publicly traded companies in the US spanning a period of more than 25 years. To the best of our knowledge, EDGAR-CORPUS is the largest financial NLP corpus available to date. All the reports are downloaded, split into their corresponding items (sections), and provided in a clean, easy-to-use JSON format. We use EDGAR-CORPUS to train and release EDGAR-W2V, which are WORD2VEC embeddings for the financial domain. We employ these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embedding">embeddings</a> in a battery of financial NLP tasks and showcase their superiority over generic GloVe embeddings and other existing financial word embeddings. We also open-source EDGAR-CRAWLER, a toolkit that facilitates downloading and extracting future <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annual_report">annual reports</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="7cc0391b">2021.econlp-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>loukas-etal-2021-edgar</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.econlp-1.2</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/nlpaueb/edgar-crawler" additional="false">nlpaueb/edgar-crawler</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/edgar-corpus">EDGAR-CORPUS</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>EDGAR-CORPUS: مليارات من الرموز تجعل العالم يدور</title_ar>
      <title_es>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miles de millones de fichas hacen girar al mundo</title_es>
      <title_pt>EDGAR-CORPUS: Bilhões de tokens fazem o mundo girar</title_pt>
      <title_ja>EDGAR - CORPUS ：数十億のトークンが世界を丸くする</title_ja>
      <title_zh>EDGAR-CORPUS:数十亿代币运世界</title_zh>
      <title_hi>EDGAR-CORPUS: टोकन के अरबों दुनिया को गोल करते हैं</title_hi>
      <title_ga>EDGAR-CORPUS: Na Billiúin Comharthaí a Dhéanann an Domhan Téigh Babhta</title_ga>
      <title_el>Έντγκαρ-Κόρπους: Δισεκατομμύρια μάρκες κάνουν τον κόσμο να γυρίζει</title_el>
      <title_hu>EDGAR-CORPUS: Több milliárd zseton forog a világ</title_hu>
      <title_it>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miliardi di gettoni fanno girare il mondo</title_it>
      <title_lt>EDGAR-CORPUS: milijardai tokenų sukuria pasaulį</title_lt>
      <title_ka>EDGAR-CORPUS: მილიარდი ტოკენები მსოფლიოს გადატანა</title_ka>
      <title_mk>EDGAR-CORPUS: Billions of Tokens Make The World Go Round</title_mk>
      <title_kk>EDGAR- CORPUS: Миллиардық Токен Дүйрейді жүгірту</title_kk>
      <title_ml>ബില്ല്യണ്‍ ടോക്കന്‍സുകള്‍ ലോകത്തിന്‍റെ ചുറ്റും ഉണ്ടാക്കുക</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Billion Token Membuat Dunia Berputar</title_ms>
      <title_pl>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miliardy żetonów sprawiają, że świat się toczy</title_pl>
      <title_mn>EDGAR-CORPUS: Сая тэрбум Токен Дэлхийн Go Round Make The World Go Round</title_mn>
      <title_ro>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miliarde de jetoane fac lumea să se învârtească</title_ro>
      <title_sr>EDGAR-CORPUS: Milijarde Tokena pravi krug svijeta</title_sr>
      <title_si>EDGAR-CORPUS: බිලියන් ටොකෙන්ස් වලින් ලෝකය යන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>EDGAR-CORPUS: Billions of Tokens Make The World Go Round</title_so>
      <title_sv>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miljarder Tokens får världen att gå runt</title_sv>
      <title_ta>EDGAR- CORPUS: பில்லியன் டோகென்ஸ் உலக சுற்று</title_ta>
      <title_no>EDGAR-CORPUS: millioner av Tokens Make the World Go Round</title_no>
      <title_mt>EDGAR-CORPUS: Biljuni ta' Tokens jagħmlu d-dinja tonda</title_mt>
      <title_ur>EDGAR-CORPUS: Billions of Tokens Make the World Go Round</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Hàng tỉ Tokens Make The World Go Round</title_vi>
      <title_uz>EDGAR-CORPUS: Billardardan Tokenlar Dunyo Goya burish</title_uz>
      <title_hr>EDGAR-CORPUS: Milijarde Tokena pravi krug svijeta</title_hr>
      <title_nl>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miljarden munten maken de wereld draaiend</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Милиарди жетони карат света да се върти</title_bg>
      <title_de>EDGAR-CORPUS: Milliarden von Token machen die Welt rund</title_de>
      <title_id>Billion Token Membuat Dunia Berputar</title_id>
      <title_da>EDGAR-CORPUS: Milliarder af poletter får verden til at gå rundt</title_da>
      <title_ko>EDGAR-CORPUS: 수십억 기호화폐로 세계를 움직인다</title_ko>
      <title_sw>EDGAR-CORPUS: mabilioni ya Tokens Make The World Go</title_sw>
      <title_tr>EDGAR-CORPUS</title_tr>
      <title_fa>EDGAR-CORPUS: میلیاردها توکنها مسیر جهانی را انجام می دهند</title_fa>
      <title_sq>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miliarda tokenash e bëjnë botën të rrotullohet</title_sq>
      <title_am>EDGAR-CORPUS: Billions of Tokens Make the World Go Round</title_am>
      <title_af>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miliardes van Tokens Maak die Wêreld Gaan rond</title_af>
      <title_hy>EDGAR-CORPUS: Billions of Tokens Make The World Go Round</title_hy>
      <title_az>EDGAR-CORPUS: Milyarlarca Token Dünya Geçmə Dönüşü</title_az>
      <title_bs>EDGAR-CORPUS: Milijarde Tokena pravi krug svijeta</title_bs>
      <title_bn>বিলিয়ন টোকেন্স বানান বিশ্ব গ্যার রাউন্ড</title_bn>
      <title_cs>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miliardy žetonů dělají svět kolem</title_cs>
      <title_ca>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miliards de tòkenes fan el món girar</title_ca>
      <title_et>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miljardid tokenid panevad maailma ringi liikuma</title_et>
      <title_fi>EDGAR-CORPUS: Miljardeja poletteja saa maailman pyörimään</title_fi>
      <title_jv>eDga R-corpus: Bilian de Token gawe barang Mundu Go Rond</title_jv>
      <title_he>מיליארדי טוקנים גורמים לעולם להסתובב</title_he>
      <title_sk>EDGAR-CORPUS: Na milijarde žetonov se svet obrne</title_sk>
      <title_ha>EDGAR-CORPUS: Billions of Tokens Make The World Go Round</title_ha>
      <title_bo>EDGAR-CORPUS: Tokens ཐེངས་འབུམ་ཅིག་Make The World Go Round</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>أصدرنا EDGAR-CORPUS ، وهي مجموعة جديدة تضم تقارير سنوية من جميع الشركات المتداولة علنًا في الولايات المتحدة والتي تمتد لأكثر من 25 عامًا. على حد علمنا ، تعد EDGAR-CORPUS أكبر مجموعة مالية متاحة حتى الآن في مجال البرمجة اللغوية العصبية. يتم تنزيل جميع التقارير وتقسيمها إلى العناصر (الأقسام) المقابلة لها ، ويتم توفيرها بتنسيق JSON نظيف وسهل الاستخدام. نستخدم EDGAR-CORPUS لتدريب وإصدار EDGAR-W2V ، وهي عبارة عن حفلات زفاف WORD2VEC للمجال المالي. نحن نوظف حفلات الزفاف هذه في مجموعة من مهام البرمجة اللغوية العصبية المالية ونظهر تفوقها على حفلات الزفاف العامة من GloVe وغيرها من حفلات الزفاف المالية الحالية. نحن أيضًا EDGAR-CRAWLER مفتوحة المصدر ، وهي مجموعة أدوات تسهل تنزيل واستخراج التقارير السنوية المستقبلية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Publicamos EDGAR-CORPUS, un corpus novedoso que incluye informes anuales de todas las empresas que cotizan en bolsa en los EE. UU. que abarcan un período de más de 25 años. Hasta donde sabemos, EDGAR-CORPUS es el mayor corpus financiero de PNL disponible hasta la fecha. Todos los informes se descargan, se dividen en sus elementos (secciones) correspondientes y se proporcionan en un formato JSON limpio y fácil de usar. Usamos EDGAR-CORPUS para entrenar y lanzar EDGAR-W2V, que son incrustaciones de WORD2VEC para el dominio financiero. Empleamos estas incorporaciones en una batería de tareas financieras de PNL y mostramos su superioridad sobre las incrustaciones genéricas de GloVe y otras incrustaciones de palabras financieras existentes. También tenemos EDGAR-CRAWLER de código abierto, un kit de herramientas que facilita la descarga y extracción de futuros informes anuales.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Lançamos o EDGAR-CORPUS, um novo corpus composto por relatórios anuais de todas as empresas de capital aberto nos EUA, abrangendo um período de mais de 25 anos. Até onde sabemos, EDGAR-CORPUS é o maior corpus financeiro de PNL disponível até hoje. Todos os relatórios são baixados, divididos em seus itens (seções) correspondentes e fornecidos em um formato JSON limpo e fácil de usar. Usamos EDGAR-CORPUS para treinar e liberar EDGAR-W2V, que são embeddings WORD2VEC para o domínio financeiro. Empregamos esses embeddings em uma bateria de tarefas de PNL financeira e mostramos sua superioridade sobre os embeddings genéricos da GloVe e outros embeddings de palavras financeiras existentes. Também disponibilizamos o EDGAR-CRAWLER de código aberto, um kit de ferramentas que facilita o download e a extração de relatórios anuais futuros.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>EDGAR - CORPUSは、25年以上にわたる米国のすべての上場企業の年次報告書を含む新規コーパスです。私たちの知る限りでは、EDGAR - CORPUSはこれまでに利用可能な最大の財務NLPコーパスです。すべてのレポートはダウンロードされ、対応する項目（セクション）に分割され、クリーンで使いやすいJSON形式で提供されます。当社は、EDGAR - CORPUSを使用して、金融ドメインのためのWORD 2 VEC埋め込みであるEDGAR - W 2 Vのトレーニングとリリースを行います。私たちは、これらの埋め込みを一連の財務NLPタスクに採用し、一般的なGloVe埋め込みやその他の既存の財務単語埋め込みよりも優れていることを示します。また、将来の年次報告書のダウンロードと抽出を容易にするツールキットであるオープンソースのEDGAR - CRAWLERも提供しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>发EDGAR-CORPUS,此一新语料库也,凡美国诸上市公司之年度报告,时间跨度过25年。 以吾所知,EDGAR-CORPUS迄今为止最大金融NLP语料库也。 凡告皆下载,拆分其目(),洁净易用者JSON式。 吾以EDGAR-CORPUS教发EDGAR-W2V,此金融域之WORD2VEC嵌也。 用此嵌金融NLP,示其对通用GloVe嵌及他现金融词嵌优越性。 开源而EDGAR-CRAWLER之,便下载取未来年度报告之工具包也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम EDGAR-CORPUS जारी करते हैं, एक उपन्यास कॉर्पस जिसमें अमेरिका में सभी सार्वजनिक रूप से कारोबार करने वाली कंपनियों की वार्षिक रिपोर्ट शामिल है, जो 25 से अधिक वर्षों की अवधि में फैली हुई है। हमारे ज्ञान का सबसे अच्छा करने के लिए, EDGAR-CORPUS आज तक उपलब्ध सबसे बड़ा वित्तीय NLP कॉर्पस है। सभी रिपोर्ट डाउनलोड की जाती हैं, उनके संबंधित आइटम (अनुभागों) में विभाजित होती हैं, और एक साफ, आसानी से उपयोग किए जाने वाले JSON प्रारूप में प्रदान की जाती हैं। हम EDGAR-CORPUS का उपयोग EDGAR-W2V को प्रशिक्षित करने और जारी करने के लिए करते हैं, जो वित्तीय डोमेन के लिए WORD2VEC एम्बेडिंग हैं। हम वित्तीय एनएलपी कार्यों की एक बैटरी में इन embeddings रोजगार और जेनेरिक GloVe embeddings और अन्य मौजूदा वित्तीय शब्द embeddings पर अपनी श्रेष्ठता का प्रदर्शन. हम भी खुला स्रोत EDGAR-CRAWLER, एक टूलकिट है कि डाउनलोड करने और भविष्य की वार्षिक रिपोर्ट निकालने की सुविधा देता है.</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Eisímid EDGAR-CORPUS, corpas nua ina bhfuil tuarascálacha bliantúla ó na cuideachtaí a thrádáiltear go poiblí sna SA thar thréimhse níos mó ná 25 bliain. Chomh fada agus is eol dúinn, is é EDGAR-CORPUS an corpas NLP airgeadais is mó atá ar fáil go dtí seo. Íoslódáltar na tuarascálacha go léir, roinntear iad ina míreanna comhfhreagracha (rannóga), agus soláthraítear iad i bhformáid JSON atá glan agus éasca le húsáid. Bainimid úsáid as EDGAR-CORPUS chun EDGAR-W2V a thraenáil agus a scaoileadh, ar leabaithe WORD2VEC iad don fhearann airgeadais. Bainimid úsáid as na leabaithe seo i gcadhnra de thascanna airgeadais NLP agus taispeánaimid a fheabhas atá siad thar leabú cineálach GloVe agus leabú focal airgeadais eile atá ann cheana féin. Tá foinse oscailte againn freisin EDGAR-CRAWLER, foireann uirlisí a éascaíonn tuarascálacha bliantúla amach anseo a íoslódáil agus a bhaint amach.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ EDGAR-CORPUS-ს გახსნა, რომელსაც კორპუს, რომელსაც წლის შესახებ ყველა ადამიანურად სამუშაო კომპანიაზე, რომელსაც უფრო 25 წლის პერიოდის გადასვლა. EDGAR-CORPUS არის უფრო დიდი ფინანსური NLP კოპპუსი, რომელიც ახლა ხელხილდება. ყველა შეტყობინებები ჩატვირთვალია, გაყოფილი შესაძლებელი ელემენტებში (პექციონებში) და გამოყენებული ფრთხი, ადვილი გამოყენებელი JSON ფორმატში. ჩვენ EDGAR-CORPUS გამოყენებთ, რომ EDGAR-W2V-ს გაგრძელებთ და გამოგრძელებთ, რომლებიც WORD2VEC ფანსონალური დიომინის გაგრძელება. ჩვენ გამოყენებთ ეს ინტებიზიციები ფინანსური NLP დავალების ბატრიაში და ჩვენ ჩვენებთ მათი უფრო მეტი სიმართლეების გარეშე და სხვა ფინანსური სიტყვების გარეშე. ჩვენ ასევე გახსნა ფორმა EDGAR-CRAWLER, ხელსაწყოთა კიტი, რომელიც მომავალე წლის შეტყობინება და გამოყენება.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Απελευθερώνουμε την EDGAR-CORPUS, ένα νέο σώμα που περιλαμβάνει ετήσιες εκθέσεις από όλες τις εισηγμένες στο χρηματιστήριο εταιρείες στις ΗΠΑ για περίοδο περισσότερο από 25 ετών. Από ό,τι γνωρίζουμε, η EDGAR-CORPUS είναι το μεγαλύτερο οικονομικό σώμα που διατίθεται μέχρι σήμερα. Όλες οι αναφορές μεταφορτώνονται, χωρίζονται σε αντίστοιχα στοιχεία (ενότητες) και παρέχονται σε καθαρή, εύχρηστη μορφή. Χρησιμοποιούμε το EDGAR-CORPUS για να εκπαιδεύσουμε και να απελευθερώσουμε το EDGAR-W2V, τα οποία είναι ενσωμάτωση WORD2VEC για τον οικονομικό τομέα. Χρησιμοποιούμε αυτές τις ενσωματώσεις σε μια σειρά οικονομικών εργασιών και επιδεικνύουμε την ανωτερότητά τους έναντι των γενικών ενσωματώσεων και άλλων υφιστάμενων χρηματοοικονομικών ενσωματώσεων λέξεων. Επίσης, χρησιμοποιούμε ένα πακέτο εργαλείων που διευκολύνει τη λήψη και εξαγωγή μελλοντικών ετήσιων εκθέσεων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Megjelenítjük az EDGAR-CORPUS-t, egy új korpuszt, amely több mint 25 éves időszakot tartalmaz az Egyesült Államok összes részvényes társaságának éves jelentéseiből. Legjobb tudásunk szerint az EDGAR-CORPUS az eddigi legnagyobb pénzügyi NLP korpusz. Az összes jelentés letöltésre kerül, megfelelő elemekre (szakaszokra) osztva, és tiszta, könnyen használható JSON formátumban rendelkezésre áll. Az EDGAR-CORPUS-t használjuk az EDGAR-W2V képzésére és kiadására, amely WORD2VEC beágyazások a pénzügyi területen. Ezeket a beágyazásokat egy sor pénzügyi NLP feladatba alkalmazzuk, és bemutatjuk, hogy felsőbbrendűek az általános GloVe beágyazásokkal és más meglévő pénzügyi szóbeágyazásokkal szemben. Nyílt forráskódú EDGAR-CRAWLER eszköztárunk is, amely megkönnyíti a jövőbeli éves jelentések letöltését és kibontását.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Pubblichiamo EDGAR-CORPUS, un nuovo corpus che comprende relazioni annuali di tutte le società quotate in borsa negli Stati Uniti per un periodo di oltre 25 anni. Per quanto ci risulta, EDGAR-CORPUS è il più grande corpus di PNL finanziario finora disponibile. Tutti i report vengono scaricati, suddivisi in elementi corrispondenti (sezioni) e forniti in un formato JSON pulito e facile da usare. Utilizziamo EDGAR-CORPUS per formare e rilasciare EDGAR-W2V, che sono incorporazioni WORD2VEC per il settore finanziario. Impieghiamo questi embedding in una serie di attività finanziarie NLP e mostriamo la loro superiorità rispetto agli embedding GloVe generici e ad altri embedding di parole finanziarie esistenti. Abbiamo anche EDGAR-CRAWLER open source, un toolkit che facilita il download e l'estrazione dei futuri report annuali.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Mes paskelbiame EDGAR-CORPUS, naują korpusą, kuriame pateikiamos metinės ataskaitos iš visų JAV viešai prekiaujamų bendrovių, apimančios daugiau kaip 25 metus. Kaip žinome, EDGAR-CORPUS yra didžiausias iki šiol turimas NLP korpusas. Visos ataskaitos parsisiųstos, suskirstomos į atitinkamus straipsnius (skirsnius) ir pateikiamos švariu, lengvai naudojamu JSON formatu. Naudojame EDGAR-CORPUS mokymui ir išleidimui EDGAR-W2V, kuris yra WORD2VEC įranga finansų srityje. Šie įdėjimai naudojami finansinių NLP užduočių rinkinyje ir parodomi, kad jie yra viršesni už bendruosius GloVe įdėjimus ir kitus esamus finansinius žodžius įdėjimus. Taip pat esame atvirojo kodo EDGAR-CRAWLER, priemonių rinkinys, kuris palengvina būsimų metinių ataskaitų atsiuntimą ir gavimą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Ние го ослободуваме ЕДГАР-КОРПУС, нов корпус кој сочинува годишни извештаи од сите јавно трговски претпријатија во САД кои траат повеќе од 25 години. Според нашето знаење, ЕДГАР-КОРПУС е најголемиот финансиски корпус на НЛП досега. Сите извештаи се симнуваат, поделени на нивните соодветни елементи (секции), и се обезбедуваат во чист, лесно користлив формат JSON. Користиме EDGAR-CORPUS за обука и ослободување EDGAR-W2V, кои се WORD2VEC вгради за финансискиот домен. Ние ги употребуваме овие вложувања во батерија финансиски NLP задачи и ја покажуваме нивната супериорност над генералните вложувања на GloVe и други постојни финансиски зборови вложувања. Ние, исто така, отворени извори ЕДГАР-Краулер, алатки кои го олеснуваат симнувањето и извлекувањето на идните годишни извештаи.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Біз EDGAR-CORPUS-ді, 25 жылдан артық жылдық тұратын компаниялардың жұмыс хабарламалары бар романдық корпус шығардық. Біздің біліміміздің ең жақсы жағдай, EDGAR-CORPUS қазіргі үлкен қаржылық NLP корпус. Барлық хабарламаларды жүктеп, сәйкес элементтеріне (бөлімдеріне бөліп) жүктеп, JSON пішіміне жеткілікті, оңай қолдану үшін келтіріледі. Біз EDGAR-CORPUS дегенді денежні доменге WORD2VEC ендіру үшін EDGAR-W2V жұмыс істеу және шығару үшін қолданамыз. Біз бұл құрылғыларды батарея NLP тапсырмаларының батареясында жұмыс істейміз және олардың көпшілігін жалпы Glove ендіру және басқа қаржылық сөздерді ендіру үшін көрсетейміз Біз сонымен қатар ашық көзі EDGAR-CRAWLER, болашақ жылдық хабарламаларды жүктеп алу және тарқату мүмкіндігін көмектеседі.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami melepaskan EDGAR-CORPUS, sebuah korpus novel yang mengandungi laporan tahunan dari semua syarikat yang ditukar secara awam di Amerika Syarikat yang berlangsung lebih dari 25 tahun. Menurut pengetahuan kita, EDGAR-CORPUS adalah korpus NLP keuangan terbesar yang tersedia hingga sekarang. Semua laporan dimuat turun, dibahagi ke item yang sepadan (seksyen), dan disediakan dalam format JSON yang bersih, mudah digunakan. Kami menggunakan EDGAR-CORPUS untuk melatih dan melepaskan EDGAR-W2V, yang merupakan penyembedding WORD2VEC untuk domain kewangan. Kami menggunakan penyembedding ini dalam bateri tugas NLP kewangan dan menunjukkan kelebihan mereka atas penyembedding GloVe generik dan penyembedding perkataan kewangan yang ada. Kami juga EDGAR-CRAWLER sumber terbuka, alat yang memudahkan muat turun dan mengekstrak laporan tahunan masa depan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഞങ്ങള്‍ എഡ്ജാര്‍-കോര്‍പ്പ്യൂസിനെ വിടുന്നു. ഒരു നോവല്‍ കോര്‍പ്പുസ്, അമേരിക്കയിലെ എല്ലാ പ്രസിദ്ധകമാക്കുന്ന കമ്പനികങ്ങളില്‍ നിന്നും വര്‍ഷ To the best of our knowledge, EDGAR-CORPUS is the largest financial NLP corpus available to date.  @ info: status ഞങ്ങള്‍ EDGAR-CORPUS ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത് EDGAR-W2V പരിശീലിപ്പിക്കുകയും വിടുകയും ചെയ്യുന്നു. അത് വോര്‍ഡ്2VEC സാമ്പത്തിക ഡോമെയിന്‍റെ പ നമ്മള്‍ ഈ അഭിപ്രായത്തിന്റെ പണിയില്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കുന്ന ഒരു ബാറ്ററിയില്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കുന്നു. പിന്നെ നമ്മള്‍ അവരുടെ മേല്‍നോട്ടത്തെ പ്രധാനപ നമ്മള്‍ തുറന്ന സ്രോതസ്സ് എഡ്ജാര്‍-ക്രോവ്ലറിനെയും തുറന്നുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. അത് ഭാവിയാലാവധി റിപ്പോര്‍ട്ടു</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>We release EDGAR-CORPUS, a novel corpus comprising annual reports from all the publicly traded companies in the US spanning a period of more than 25 years.  Għall-aħjar għarfien tagħna, EDGAR-CORPUS huwa l-akbar korpus finanzjarju tal-NLP disponibbli s’issa. Ir-rapporti kollha jitniżżlu, jinqasmu fl-oġġetti korrispondenti tagħhom (sezzjonijiet), u jiġu pprovduti f’format JSON nadif u faċli biex jintuża. Aħna nużaw EDGAR-CORPUS biex inħarrġu u nħarrġu EDGAR-W2V, li huma inkorporazzjonijiet WORD2VEC għall-qasam finanzjarju. Aħna nużaw dawn l-inkorporazzjonijiet f’batterija ta’ kompiti finanzjarji tal-NLP u nirriżultaw fis-superjorità tagħhom fuq inkorporazzjonijiet ġeneriċi tal-GloVe u inkorporazzjonijiet finanzjarji eżistenti oħrajn. Aħna wkoll EDGAR-CRAWLER b’sors miftuħ, sett ta’ għodod li jiffaċilita t-tniżżil u l-estrazzjoni tar-rapporti annwali futuri.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Бид EDGAR-CORPUS, АНУ-ын олон нийтийн худалдааны компаниудаас 25 жилээс илүү хугацааны цаг хугацаанд ирсэн бүх жилийн мэдээллийг бүрдүүлсэн шинэ корпус гаргасан. Хамгийн сайн мэдлэгтэй нь, EDGAR-CORPUS бол өнөөдрийн хамгийн том санхүүгийн NLP корпус юм. Бүх мэдээллүүд хадгалагдаж, харилцааны зүйлсийг (хэсэгт) хувааж, цэвэр, амархан ашиглах JSON форматаар хангагдаж байна. Бид EDGAR-CORPUS-г санхүүгийн сүлжээнд WORD2VEC-г суралцах, гаргах зорилго ашигладаг. Бид эдгээр хөрөнгө оруулалтыг санхүүгийн NLP ажлын батареар ашиглаж, тэдний өндөр өндөр байдлыг Glove-ын хөрөнгө оруулалт болон бусад эдийн засгийн үгийг оруулж үзүүлдэг. Бид бас нээлттэй эх үүсвэртэй EDGAR-CRAWLER, ирээдүйн жилийн мэдээллийг авах болон хадгалах хэрэгслийн систем юм.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Wydajemy EDGAR-CORPUS, nowatorski korpus składający się z raportów rocznych wszystkich spółek giełdowych w Stanach Zjednoczonych w okresie ponad 25-letnim. Z naszej najlepszej wiedzy EDGAR-CORPUS jest największym dostępnym do tej pory korpusem finansowym NLP. Wszystkie raporty są pobierane, podzielone na odpowiednie elementy (sekcje) i dostarczane w czystym, łatwym w użyciu formacie JSON. Używamy EDGAR-CORPUS do szkolenia i wydania EDGAR-W2V, które są osadzeniami WORD2VEC dla domeny finansowej. Wykorzystujemy te osadzenia w serii zadań finansowych NLP i pokazujemy ich przewagę nad ogólnymi osadzeniami GloVe i innymi istniejącymi osadzeniami słów finansowych. Posiadamy również open source EDGAR-CRAWLER, zestaw narzędzi ułatwiający pobieranie i ekstrakcję przyszłych raportów rocznych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Vi løyser EDGAR-CORPUS, eit nytt korpus som inkluderer årlige rapporter frå alle offentlig trådte selskapene i USA som utgår eit periode med fleire enn 25 år. For det beste av vårt kunnskap er EDGAR-CORPUS den største finansielle NLP corpus tilgjengelege til dag. Alle rapportene vert lasta ned, delt inn i dei tilsvarande elementa (deler) og oppgjeven i ein rein, enkel å bruka JSON- format. Vi bruker EDGAR-CORPUS for å trenga og sletta EDGAR-W2V, som er WORD2VEC-innbygging for den finansielle domenet. Vi bruker desse innbyggingane i ein batteriet med finansielle NLP- oppgåver og viser deres overhøgd over generelle innbygging av Glove og andre finansielle ordinnbygging. Vi har også åpen-kjelde EDGAR-CRAWLER, eit verktøykassett som lettar nedlasting og utpakking av framtidige årsrapporter.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Publicăm EDGAR-CORPUS, un corpus nou care cuprinde rapoarte anuale ale tuturor companiilor tranzacționate la bursă din SUA pe o perioadă de peste 25 de ani. Din câte ştim, EDGAR-CORPUS este cel mai mare corpus financiar PNL disponibil până în prezent. Toate rapoartele sunt descărcate, împărțite în elementele corespunzătoare (secțiuni) și furnizate într-un format JSON curat, ușor de utilizat. Folosim EDGAR-CORPUS pentru a instrui și lansa EDGAR-W2V, care sunt încorporări WORD2VEC pentru domeniul financiar. Utilizăm aceste încorporări într-o baterie de sarcini financiare NLP și demonstrăm superioritatea lor față de încorporările generice GloVe și alte încorporări financiare existente. De asemenea, EDGAR-CRAWLER cu sursă deschisă, un set de instrumente care facilitează descărcarea și extragerea rapoartelor anuale viitoare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Oslobađamo EDGAR-CORPUS, novog korpusa koji sadrži godišnje izveštaje od svih javno trgovačkih kompanija u SAD-u koje traje više od 25 godina. Za najbolje od našeg znanja, EDGAR-CORPUS je najveći finansijski korpus NLP koji je dostupan do sada. Svi izveštaji su skinuti, podeljeni u njihove odgovarajuće predmete (sekcije) i pruženi u čistom, lakom korištenju JSON format a. Koristimo EDGAR-CORPUS kako bi obučili i oslobodili EDGAR-W2V, što su WORD2VEC integracije za finansijsku domenu. Upotrebljavamo ove uloge u bateriju finansijskih zadataka NLP-a i pokazujemo njihovu nadmoć nad generičnim uloženjima Glove i drugim postojećim finansijskim rečima. Također smo otvoreni izvor EDGAR-CRAWLER, alatkit koji olakšava skidanje i izvlačenje budućih godišnjih izveštaja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>ADGAR-CORPUS waa warqad warqadeed oo ku qoran warqado sanad ah oo ka soo baxaya shirkadaha ganacsiga oo dalka Mareykanka ah oo ka badan 25 sano. Tan ugu wanaagsan aqoontayada, EDGAR-CORPUS waa dhamaan dhaqaalaha dhaqaalaha NLP ee ugu weyn ilaa maanta. Wargelinta oo dhan waxaa la soo dejiyey oo loo kala qeybiyaa alaabtooda wax u eg (qeybaha), waxaana lagu sameeyaa foomka JSON oo daahir ah oo si sahlan loo isticmaalo. We use EDGAR-CORPUS to train and release EDGAR-W2V, which are WORD2VEC embeddings for the financial domain.  Waxaannu ku shaqaynaynaa qashinka dhaqaalaha NLP, waxaana muujinnaa sarkaalkooda ku saabsan bangiyada geneeral GloVe iyo hadal kale oo dhaqaale ah oo ku jira. Waxaynu sidoo kale furan nahay EDGAR-CRAWLER, qalabka qalabka ah oo ka caawinaya download iyo soo bixinta wargelinta sanadkii dambe.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Vi släpper EDGAR-CORPUS, en ny korpus bestående av årsredovisningar från alla börsnoterade företag i USA över en period på mer än 25 år. Så vitt vi vet är EDGAR-CORPUS den största finansiella NLP-korpus som finns tillgänglig hittills. Alla rapporter laddas ner, delas upp i motsvarande objekt (avsnitt) och tillhandahålls i ett rent, lättanvänt JSON-format. Vi använder EDGAR-CORPUS för att träna och släppa EDGAR-W2V, som är WORD2VEC-inbäddningar för den finansiella domänen. Vi använder dessa inbäddningar i ett batteri av finansiella NLP-uppgifter och visar upp deras överlägsenhet över generiska GloVe-inbäddningar och andra befintliga finansiella ord inbäddningar. Vi har även öppen källkod EDGAR-CRAWLER, en verktygslåda som underlättar nedladdning och utvinning av framtida årsredovisningar.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>අපි EDGAR-CORPUS නිදහස් කරනවා, අවුරුදු 25 වඩා වඩා වැඩි අවස්ථාවක් වලින් සාමාජික ව්‍යාපාර කරුණාවල් වලින් අවස්ථාවක් ති අපේ දැනගන්න හොඳම දේවල්, EDGAR-CORPUS තමයි දැනටමත් ලොකු විශාල විශාල ආර්ථික NLP කොර්පුස්. ඔක්කොම වාර්තාව දාලා ගන්න, ඔවුන්ගේ සම්බන්ධ අයිති අයිති අයිති අයිති වලට විතරයි (කොටස්), සහ පිරිසිදුම, ල අපි EDGAR-CORPUS පාවිච්චි කරනවා EDGAR-W2V ක්‍රියානය කරන්න සහ නිදහස් කරන්න, ඒක WORD2VEC සම්බන්ධතාවක් වෙනුවෙන්. අපි මේ ඇම්බෙන්ඩින්ග්ව භාවිතා කරනවා අර්ථික NLP වැඩේ බැටරියාවක් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රධානය පෙන්වන්න සාමාන්‍ය Glove ඇම්බෙන් අපි තියෙන්නේ ප්‍රවෘත්තිය EDGAR-CRAWLER, අනාගතයේ වාර්තාව ප්‍රවෘත්ති කරන්න සහ අනාගතයේ වාර්තාව ප්‍රවෘත්තියක</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>நாங்கள் EDGAR-CORPUS வெளியேற்றுகிறோம், ஒரு புத்தகக் குறிப்பு, அமெரிக்காவில் உள்ள அனைத்து பொது விற்பனை நிறுவனங்களிலிருந்தும் வரு எங்கள் அறிவு சிறந்ததுக்கு, EDGAR-CORPUS இன்று கிடைக்கும் பெரிய நிதி NLP கார்ப்ஸ் ஆகும். All the reports are downloaded, split into their corresponding items (sections), and provided in a clean, easy-to-use JSON format.  நாங்கள் EDGAR-CORPUS பயன்படுத்தி EDGAR-W2V பயிற்சி வெளியேற்ற பயன்படுத்துகிறோம், அது தொழில்நுட்பம் தளத்திற்காக உள்ளிடுகிறது. நாங்கள் இந்த உள்ளீடுகளை நிதி NLP பணிகளின் பாட்டரில் வேலை செய்து மற்றும் அவர்களுடைய மேன்மையைக் காட்டுகிறோம் பொதுவான கிளோவி பொருள்கள் மற் நாம் திறந்த மூலம் EDGAR-CRAWLER, ஒரு கருவிப்பெட்டி, எதிர்காலத்தின் வருடம் அறிக்கை</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم EDGAR-CORPUS کو چھوڑ دیتے ہیں، ایک نئی کورپوس، جو سال کی راپوروں میں سے تمام امریکا کے سارے عمومی تجارت کی کمپنیوں سے ملتی ہے جو 25 سال سے زیادہ گزر رہے ہیں۔ ہمارے سب سے بہترین علم کے لئے، EDGAR-CORPUS بہترین مالی NLP کورپوس ہے جو اس وقت موجود ہے. تمام راپوروٹ ڈونلڈ کیے جاتے ہیں، ان کے متعلق آئٹوں میں تقسیم کیے جاتے ہیں، اور ایک پاکیزہ, آسان استعمال کرنے کے لئے JSON فرمود میں پیش کیے جاتے ہیں. ہم EDGAR-CORPUS کو استعمال کرتے ہیں کہ EDGAR-W2V کو ٹرین کریں اور آزاد کریں، جو مالی دامین کے لئے WORD2VEC ایمبڈینگ ہیں۔ ہم ان ایمبڈینگ کو فنانسی NLP کے کاموں کی باتری میں استعمال کرتے ہیں اور ان کی زیادتی کو گلووی ایمبڈینگ اور دوسری موجود فنانسی کلمات ایمبڈینگ پر دکھاتے ہیں. ہم نے اپنا اوپن سورس EDGAR-CRAWLER، ایک تولیک کیٹ جو آگے سال کی راپوروٹوں کو ڈونلوڈ اور اخراج کرتا ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi phát hành Eddie Garcia-COTMS, một tập đoàn mới gồm các báo cáo hàng năm từ tất cả các công ty được trao đổi công khai ở Mỹ đang kéo dài hơn 25 năm. Theo kiến thức tốt nhất của chúng tôi, EDGarcia-COPPS là tập đoàn tài chính lớn nhất từng có. Tất cả các báo cáo được tải về, chia thành các mục tương ứng (các mục) và được cung cấp theo dạng chuẩn chuẩn chuẩn xác, dễ dùng. Chúng tôi sử dụng DGAR-COPPS để huấn luyện và phóng thích EDGAR-W2V, những tổ chức WOOD cho lĩnh vực tài chính. Chúng tôi tuyển dụng những tổ chức này trong một loạt các công việc tài chính của Đảng Nchọc và phô bày khả năng ưu việt của họ hơn GloVee tổng hợp và những từ vốn đã có. Chúng tôi cũng nguồn mở, một bộ hỗ trợ giúp tải về và thu hồi các báo cáo năm tới.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Biz EDGAR-CORPUS, 25 yildan ko'p davomida davom etilgan har yil davomida AQSHdagi barcha jamiyatlar kompaniyalaridan hisoblanadi. Bizning eng eng yaxshi aniqligimizga, EDGAR-CORPUS bu hozir uchun eng katta narsa NLP korpusi. @ info Biz EDGAR-CORPUSdan foydalanamiz EDGAR-W2V'ni o'rganish va ruxsat qilamiz. Bu DWD2VEC financiy domen uchun qo'llanmalar. Biz shu tashkilotlarni NLP tashkilotlarida ishlayapmiz va ularning o'zlarini geneziy GloVe kabi boshqa murakkablarini ko'rsatdik. Biz kelajakdagi yil haqida yozib olish va yozib olish imkoniyatini ochamiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Издаваме нов корпус, включващ годишни отчети на всички публично търгувани компании в САЩ за период от повече от 25 години. Доколкото знаем, ЕДГАР-КОРПУС е най-големият финансов корпус на НЛП, достъпен до момента. Всички отчети се изтеглят, разделят на съответните им елементи (раздели) и се предоставят в чист, лесен за използване формат. Използваме ЕДГАР-КОРПУС, за да обучаваме и пускаме ЕДГАР-W2V, които са вградени във финансовата област. Ние използваме тези вграждания в батерия от финансови задачи за НЛП и демонстрираме тяхното превъзходство пред общите вграждания и други съществуващи финансови думи вграждания. Ние също така предлагаме набор от инструменти с отворен код, който улеснява изтеглянето и извличането на бъдещи годишни отчети.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Oslobodimo EDGAR-CORPUS, novog korpusa koji sadrži godišnje izvješće od svih javno trgovačkih kompanija u SAD-u koji spaja više od 25 godina. Najbolje od naših znanja, EDGAR-CORPUS je najveći financijski korpus NLP-a koji je dostupan do sada. Svi izvještaji se skidaju, podele u njihove odgovarajuće predmete (dijelove) i pružaju se u čistom, lakom korištenju JSON format a. Koristimo EDGAR-CORPUS kako bi obučili i oslobodili EDGAR-W2V, što su WORD2VEC integracije za financijsku domenu. Upotrebili smo ove uloge u bateriju financijskih zadataka NLP-a i pokazujemo njihovu superiornost nad generičnim uloženjem Glove-a i drugim postojećim financijskim riječima. Također smo otvoreni izvor EDGAR-CRAWLER, toolkit koji olakšava snimanje i izvlačenje budućih godišnjih izvješća.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi udgiver EDGAR-CORPUS, et nyt korpus bestående af årsrapporter fra alle børsnoterede selskaber i USA over en periode på mere end 25 år. Så vidt vi ved, er EDGAR-CORPUS det hidtil største finansielle NLP-korpus. Alle rapporter downloades, opdeles i deres tilsvarende elementer (sektioner), og leveres i et rent, brugervenligt JSON-format. Vi bruger EDGAR-CORPUS til at træne og frigive EDGAR-W2V, som er WORD2VEC-indlejringer til det finansielle område. Vi anvender disse indlejringer i et batteri af finansielle NLP-opgaver og viser deres overlegenhed over generiske GloVe-indlejringer og andre eksisterende finansielle ord indlejringer. Vi har også open source EDGAR-CRAWLER, et værktøjssæt, der gør det lettere at downloade og udtrække fremtidige årsrapporter.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>We brengen EDGAR-CORPUS uit, een nieuw corpus bestaande uit jaarverslagen van alle beursgenoteerde bedrijven in de VS over een periode van meer dan 25 jaar. Voor zover wij weten is EDGAR-CORPUS het grootste financiële NLP corpus dat tot nu toe beschikbaar is. Alle rapporten worden gedownload, opgesplitst in de bijbehorende items (secties) en geleverd in een schoon, gebruiksvriendelijk JSON-formaat. We gebruiken EDGAR-CORPUS om EDGAR-W2V te trainen en uit te brengen, wat WORD2VEC embeddings zijn voor het financiële domein. We gebruiken deze embeddings in een reeks financiële NLP taken en tonen hun superioriteit ten opzichte van generieke GloVe embeddings en andere bestaande financiële word embeddings. We maken ook open source EDGAR-CRAWLER, een toolkit die het downloaden en extraheren van toekomstige jaarverslagen vergemakkelijkt.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Wir veröffentlichen EDGAR-CORPUS, ein neuartiges Korpus, das Jahresberichte aller börsennotierten Unternehmen in den USA über einen Zeitraum von mehr als 25-Jahren umfasst. EDGAR-CORPUS ist nach bestem Wissen das bisher größte Finanz-NLP-Korpus. Alle Berichte werden heruntergeladen, in die entsprechenden Elemente (Abschnitte) aufgeteilt und in einem sauberen, benutzerfreundlichen JSON-Format bereitgestellt. Wir verwenden EDGAR-CORPUS, um EDGAR-W2V zu trainieren und zu veröffentlichen, die WORD2VEC Einbettungen für den Finanzbereich sind. Wir setzen diese Einbettungen in eine Reihe finanzieller NLP-Aufgaben ein und zeigen ihre Überlegenheit gegenüber generischen GloVe-Einbettungen und anderen bestehenden Finanzworteinbettungen. Wir nutzen auch EDGAR-CRAWLER, ein Toolkit, das das Herunterladen und Extrahieren zukünftiger Geschäftsberichte erleichtert.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 EDGAR-CORPUS를 발표했는데 이것은 미국의 모든 상장회사의 25년 동안의 연간 보고서를 포함하는 참신한 자료 라이브러리이다.EDGAR-CORPUS는 지금까지 가장 큰 금융 NLP 자료 라이브러리로 알고 있습니다.모든 보고서는 다운로드되어 해당 항목(부분)으로 나뉘어 깨끗하고 사용하기 쉬운 JSON 형식으로 제공된다.우리는 EDGAR-CORPUS를 이용하여 EDGAR-W2V를 훈련하고 발표하는데 이것은 금융 분야의 WORD2VEC 삽입이다.우리는 일련의 금융 NLP 임무에서 이러한 삽입을 사용했고 유니버설 장갑 삽입과 다른 기존 금융 단어 삽입에 비해 장점을 보여 주었다.우리는 또한 기원된 EDGAR-CRAWLER 패키지를 개발했는데 이것은 미래 연도 보고서를 다운로드하고 추출하는 데 편리한 패키지이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaachia huru EDGAR-CORPUS, makampuni ya riwaya yenye taarifa za kila mwaka kutoka kwa makampuni yote yanayobadilika hadharani nchini Marekani kwa zaidi ya miaka 25. Kwa ufahamu mzuri zaidi, EDGAR-CORPUS ni makampuni makubwa zaidi ya kifedha yanayopatikana mpaka sasa. All the reports are downloaded, split into their corresponding items (sections), and provided in a clean, easy-to-use JSON format.  Tunatumia EDGAR-CORPUS kufundisha na kuachia huru EDGAR-W2V, ambayo ni WORD2VEC kwa ajili ya maeneo ya fedha. Tunaitumia shughuli hizi katika betri ya kazi za NLP za fedha na kuonyesha utawala wao juu ya mabadiliko ya kijamii ya GloVe na maneno mengine ya kifedha yanayoendelea. Pia tunafungua chanzo cha EDGAR-CRAWLER, kituo ambacho kinawezesha kupandisha na kutoa taarifa za mwaka ujao.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>ما EDGAR-CORPUS را آزاد می‌کنیم، یک شرکت نویسی که از تمام شرکت‌های تجارت عمومی در آمریکا در طول بیش از ۲۵ سال طول می‌کشد. برای بهترین دانش ما، EDGAR-CORPUS بزرگترین شرکت NLP مالی است که در حال حاضر موجود است. تمام گزارش‌ها بارگیری می‌شوند، به عنوان عناصر (بخش‌ها) متصل می‌شوند و در یک قالب پاک و آسان استفاده از JSON داده می‌شوند. ما از EDGAR-CORPUS استفاده می کنیم تا EDGAR-W2V را آموزش دهیم و آزاد کنیم، که برای دامنۀ مالی WORD2VEC است. ما این وسیله‌ها را در یک باتری از کارهای NLP مالی استفاده می‌کنیم و بزرگی‌شان را بر اساس وسیله‌های کلوو و دیگر کلمه‌های مالی موجود نشان می‌دهیم. ما همچنین منبع باز EDGAR-CRAWLER هستیم، یک کیت ابزار که به بارگیری و اخراج گزارش های سال آینده آسان می دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Biz EDGAR-CORPUS-y 25 ýyldan gowurak ýyldan gowurak kompaniýalaryň ýylykly raporlaryny ýazyp kabul etdik. Bilgimiziň iň gowy bolsa, EDGAR-CORPUS häzirki wagtda ulaşan iň uly mali NLP korpusdyr. Hemme hasaplar ýüklenilýär, ýerleri baglaýyşlary (bölmeler) bilen böldi we ýene-de ýeňil JSON biçiminde berilýär.friendly time" string for the current day, strftime format. like "Today 12:34 am EDGAR-CORPUS EDGAR-W2V otlamak we çykarmak üçin ullanýarys. Bu finans domynyň WORD2VEC kömekleri. Biz bu içerikleri mali NLP zadalarynyň bateriýasynda işleýäris we olaryň üstünliklerini Glove içeriklerinden we beýleki mali sözleriň içine görkez. Biz hem a çyk çeşme EDGAR-CRAWLER, gelejek ýylyň raportlaryny indirmek we çykarmak üçin bir alet kiti.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>We release EDGAR-CORPUS, a novel corpus comprising annual reports from all the publicly traded companies in the US spanning a period of more than 25 years.  To the best of our knowledge, EDGAR-CORPUS is the largest financial NLP corpus available to date.  Të gjitha raportet janë shkarkuar, ndarë në elementet e tyre korrispondente (seksione) dhe furnizuar në një format të pastër, të lehtë për përdorim JSON. Ne përdorim EDGAR-CORPUS për të stërvitur dhe lëshuar EDGAR-W2V, që janë përfshirje WORD2VEC për domenin financiar. Ne i përdorim këto përfshirje në një bateri detyrash financiare NLP dhe tregojmë superioritetin e tyre ndaj përfshirjeve gjenerale Glove dhe përfshirjeve të tjera financiare ekzistuese. Ne gjithashtu kemi burim të hapur EDGAR-CRAWLER, një paketë mjete që lehtëson shkarkimin dhe nxjerrjen e raporteve vjetore të ardhshme.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_af>Ons verlos EDGAR-CORPUS, 'n nuwe korpus wat jaarlike raporte bevat uit al die openbaar verhandede maatskappye in die VSA wat 'n tyd van meer as 25 jaar afspraak het. Op die beste van ons kennis is EDGAR-CORPUS die grootste finansiële NLP corpus wat tot nou beskikbaar is. Alle die raporte word afgelaai, deel in hul ooreenstemmende items (seksies), en verskaf in 'n rein, maklik na- gebruik JSON formaat. Ons gebruik EDGAR-CORPUS om EDGAR-W2V te trein en verlos, wat word WORD2VEC inbettings vir die finansiële domein. Ons gebruik hierdie inbêdings in 'n batterie van finansiÃ«le NLP taak en wys hulle hoogheid oor generieke Glove inbêdings en ander bestaande finansiÃ«le woord inbêdings. Ons het ook oop-bron EDGAR-CRAWLER, 'n nutsbalkit wat toekomstige jaarlike raporte laat aflaai en uitpak.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>አሜሪካ-ኮርፕዩስን የዓመቱ ወራት ከ25 ዓመታት በላይ የተለወጠውን የአሜሪካ መንግስታት ካምፓርቲዎች ሁሉ የሚወስደውን የረኀብ ኮርፓስ እናስወግዳለን፡፡ ከውቀታችን ሁሉ በላጭ፣ EDGAR-CORPUS እስከ ዛሬ የተገኘው የሀብት የNLP ኮርፓስ ትልቁ ነው፡፡ የሪፖርት ሁሉ ዝርዝሮች ላይ ይወርዳሉ፣ እየተለያዩ ዕቃ (ክፍሎች) ክፍልፍሎች፣ የJSON ፎርማት በተለየ ቀላል እና በመጠቀም ይደረጋሉ፡፡ ኤድጋርክ-ኮርፕዩስስ ለመማር እና ለመፈታት እና ለመፈታት እናስጠጋለን፡፡ እነዚህን አካባቢዎች የNLP ስራ ባርቲ ላይ እናስገራለን እና የግንኙነት የግንኙነት ግንኙነት እና ሌሎችን የሀብት ቃላት አካባቢ እናሳያቸዋለን፡፡ We also open-source EDGAR-CRAWLER, a toolkit that facilitates downloading and extracting future annual reports.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_id>Kami melepaskan EDGAR-CORPUS, sebuah korpus novel yang mengandung laporan tahunan dari semua perusahaan perdagangan publik di Amerika Serikat yang berlangsung lebih dari 25 tahun. To the best of our knowledge, EDGAR-CORPUS is the largest financial NLP corpus available to date.  All the reports are downloaded, split into their corresponding items (sections), and provided in a clean, easy-to-use JSON format.  Kami menggunakan EDGAR-CORPUS untuk melatih dan melepaskan EDGAR-W2V, yang merupakan penerbangan WORD2VEC untuk domain keuangan. Kami menggunakan penerbangan ini dalam baterai tugas NLP keuangan dan menunjukkan superioritas mereka atas penerbangan GloVe generik dan penerbangan kata keuangan lainnya yang ada. Kami juga EDGAR-CRAWLER sumber terbuka, sebuah set alat yang memudahkan mengunduh dan mengekstraksi laporan tahunan masa depan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা ইডিগার-কোর্পাসের মুক্তি দিচ্ছি, যা আমেরিকার সকল প্রকাশ্য ব্যবসা কোম্পানির বার্ষিক রিপোর্ট থেকে বার্ষিক রিপোর্ট দিয়েছে, য আমাদের জ্ঞানের সবচেয়ে ভালোর জন্য, এডগার-কোর্পাস এখন পর্যন্ত সবচেয়ে বড় অর্থনৈতিক এনএলপি কর্পাস। সকল রিপোর্ট ডাউনলোড করা হয়েছে, তাদের সাথে সংশ্লিষ্ট বস্তুগুলোর মধ্যে বিভক্ত হয়েছে এবং পরিষ্কার, সহজে ব্যবহার করা হয়েছে জে আমরা EDGAR-CORPUS ব্যবহার করি এDGAR-W2V প্রশিক্ষণ ও মুক্তি দেয়ার জন্য, যা অর্থনৈতিক ডোমেইনের জন্য ওয়ার্ড২ভিস। আমরা এনএলপি অর্থনৈতিক কাজের একটি ব্যাটারি ব্যাটারি চাকরি এবং সাধারণ গ্লোভির প্রবেশাধিকার এবং অন্যান্য অর্থনৈতিক শব্দের ব্যাপারে তাদের শ্ আমরা উন্মুক্ত সূত্র EDGAR-CRAWLER, একটি টুলবিট, যা ভবিষ্যতের বার্ষিক রিপোর্ট ডাউনলোড করা ও বের করে আনার সুযোগ প্রদান করে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք հրապարակում ենք ԷԴԳԱR-Կորպուս, մի նոր կորպուս, որը կազմում է ամբողջ ԱՄՆ հանրային առևտրային ընկերությունների տարեկան զեկույցներ, որոնք տևում են ավելի քան 25 տարի: Ըստ մեր լավագույն գիտելիքների, ԷԴԳԱR-Կորպուսը մինչ հիմա ամենամեծ ֆինանսական ՆԼՊ կորպուսն է: Բոլոր զեկույցները ներբեռնվում են, բաժանում են իրենց համապատասխան առարկաների (հատվածների) վրա և տրամադրվում են մաքուր, հեշտ օգտագործվող JSON ֆորմատով: Մենք օգտագործում ենք Edger-CORPus-ը, որպեսզի վարժեցնենք և հրապարակենք Edger-World 2V-ը, որը ֆինանսական ոլորտի համար է աշխատում: Մենք օգտագործում ենք այս ներդրումները ֆինանսական ՆԼՊ-ի առաջադրանքների շարքում և ցույց ենք տալիս նրանց գերակայությունը գերակայության վերաբերյալ ընդհանուր Գլովի ներդրումներին և այլ գոյություն ունեցող ֆինանսական բառերի ներդրումներին: Մենք նաև բաց աղբյուր ունեցող ԷԴԳԱR-ՔՌԱՈւլեր ենք, մի գործիքների շարք, որը հնարավորություն է տալիս ներբեռնել և դուրս բերել ապագա տարեկան զեկույցները:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Biz EDGAR-CORPUS, 25 il ərzində olan bütün ABŞ-deki halda ticarət edən şirketlərdən ilk raporları olan yeni bir korpus yayındırırıq. Bizim elmimizin ən yaxşısına görə, EDGAR-CORPUS günümüzdə bulunan ən böyük malik NLP korpusu. Bütün xəbərlər indirilir, müqayisədə olanlar (bölümlər) ilə bölünər və təmiz, asanlıqla istifadə edilən JSON format ında təyin edilir. Biz EDGAR-CORPUS'ı mali domenin WORD2VEC inşallarını təhsil etmək və təhsil etmək üçün istifadə edirik. Biz bu məlumatları mali NLP işlərinin bateriyada istifadə edirik və onların üstünlüyünü Glove in şallarına və başqa mali sözlərin inşallarına göstəririk. Biz də a çıq-kaynaklı EDGAR-CRAWLER, gələcək il raporlarını indirəcək və çıxartmaq üçün istifadə edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_cs>Vydáváme EDGAR-CORPUS, nový korpus obsahující výroční zprávy všech veřejně obchodovaných společností v USA po dobu více než 25 let. Podle našich nejlepších znalostí je EDGAR-CORPUS největším dostupným finančním korpusem NLP. Všechny sestavy jsou staženy, rozděleny do odpovídajících položek (sekcí) a poskytovány v čistém a snadno použitelném formátu JSON. EDGAR-CORPUS používáme k tréninku a uvolnění EDGAR-W2V, což jsou WORD2VEC embeddings pro finanční doménu. Tyto vložení využíváme v řadě finančních NLP úkolů a ukazujeme jejich nadřazenost nad obecnými GloVe vloženími a dalšími stávajícími finančními slovy vložení. Rovněž využíváme open source EDGAR-CRAWLER, sadu nástrojů, která usnadňuje stahování a extrahování budoucích výročních zpráv.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_bs>Oslobodimo EDGAR-CORPUS, novog korpusa koji sadrži godišnje izvješće od svih javno trgovačkih kompanija u SAD-u koji spaja više od 25 godina. Za najbolje od našeg znanja, EDGAR-CORPUS je najveći financijski korpus NLP koji je dostupan do sada. Svi izvještaji se skidaju, podele u odgovarajuće predmete (dijelove) i pružaju u čistom, lakom korištenju JSON format a. Koristimo EDGAR-CORPUS kako bi obučili i oslobodili EDGAR-W2V, što su WORD2VEC integracije za financijsku domenu. Upotrijebimo ove uloge u bateriju financijskih zadataka NLP-a i pokazujemo njihovu superiornost nad generičnim uloženjima Glove i drugim postojećim financijskim riječima. Također smo otvoreni izvor EDGAR-CRAWLER, toolkit koji olakšava snimanje i izvlačenje budućih godišnjih izvješća.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Avaldame EDGAR-CORPUS-i, uudse korpuse, mis sisaldab kõikide USA börsil noteeritud ettevõtete aastaaruandeid üle 25 aasta. Meie parimate teadmiste kohaselt on EDGAR-CORPUS seni suurim finantsprogrammi korpus. Kõik aruanded laaditakse alla, jagatakse vastavateks üksusteks (jaotisteks) ja esitatakse puhas ja lihtsalt kasutatav JSON-vormingus. Me kasutame EDGAR-CORPUS-t, et koolitada ja vabastada EDGAR-W2V, mis on WORD2VEC põimitud finantsvaldkonna jaoks. Me kasutame neid manustamisi mitmetes finantsprogrammiülesannetes ja näitame nende paremust üldiste GloVe manustamiste ja muude olemasolevate finantssõnade manustamise ees. Samuti on meil avatud lähtekoodiga EDGAR-CRAWLER, tööriistakomplekt, mis hõlbustab tulevaste aastaaruannete allalaadimist ja väljavõtmist.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Julkaisemme EDGAR-CORPUSin, uuden korpusen, joka sisältää kaikkien yhdysvaltalaisten pörssiyhtiöiden vuosikertomukset yli 25 vuoden ajalta. Tietojemme mukaan EDGAR-CORPUS on tähän mennessä suurin saatavilla oleva NLP-corpus. Kaikki raportit ladataan, jaetaan vastaaviin kohteisiin (osioihin) ja toimitetaan puhtaassa ja helppokäyttöisessä JSON-muodossa. EDGAR-CORPUS kouluttaa ja vapauttaa EDGAR-W2V:tä, jotka ovat WORD2VEC-upotuksia rahoitusalalle. Käytämme näitä upotuksia lukuisissa taloudellisissa NLP-tehtävissä ja näytämme niiden ylivoimaisuuden yleisiin GloVe-upotuksiin ja muihin olemassa oleviin taloussanaupotuksiin verrattuna. Tarjoamme myös avoimen lähdekoodin EDGAR-CRAWLER, työkalupakin, joka helpottaa tulevien vuosikertomusten lataamista ja poimimista.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>Vam publicar EDGAR-CORPUS, un nou cos compost d'informes anuals de totes les empreses comercials als Estats Units que duraven més de 25 anys. Segons el nostre coneixement, EDGAR-CORPUS és el cos financer més gran del NLP disponible fins ara. Tots els informes es descarreguen, es dividen en els seus articles correspondents (seccions), i es proporcionen en un format JSON net i fàcil d'utilitzar. Utilitzem EDGAR-CORPUS per entrenar i alliberar EDGAR-W2V, que són integracions de WORD2VEC per al domini financer. Empreguem aquestes incorporacions en una pila de tasques financeres de NLP i demostram la seva superioritat sobre les incorporacions genèriques de GloVe i altres incorporacions financeres existents. També tenim EDGAR-CRAWLER de codi obert, un conjunt d'eines que facilita la descarga i l'extracció de futurs informes anuals.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé nambah, perusahaan kelompok sing sampeyan anyar nggawe barang-barang kanggo nganggo kuwi kompanie sing nganggo barang-barang kanggo Kemerdekaan kanggo ngerasahan luwih apik sing katêpakan karo awak dhéwé. Panjenengan langkung saé awakdhéwé, eDGaR-corpus kuwi nggawe barang pengguna NLP sing gak dhéwé nggawe ngulinggo. politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Awak dhéwé nggunakake eDga R-COMRUSO nggawe lan mbukakipun eDGaR-W2V, sing iki WorD2veC embedding kanggo token pengaturan Awak dhéwé éntuk embedding iki ning batir tentang NLP dadi nggawe lan padha biasane supoyo nggawe barang nggawe barang kelas Global embedding lan gambar barang dolanan sing wis ana. Awak dhéwé mengko buksan-pernik, iso nggawe barang-pernik, iso nggawe barang nggawe lan ijol-ijol barang bersatu.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו משחררים EDGAR-CORPUS, קורפוס רומן שמכיל דוחות שנתיים מכל החברות המסחרות בפומבי בארה"ב במשך תקופה של יותר מ-25 שנים. To the best of our knowledge, EDGAR-CORPUS is the largest financial NLP corpus available to date.  כל הדו"חות מוורידים, מתחלקים לאפריטים (חלקים) המתאימים שלהם, ומספקים בצורה נקייה, קלה להשתמש JSON. אנחנו משתמשים באדגר-קורפוס כדי לאמן ולשחרר את אדגר-W2V, אשר הם תוכניות WORD2VEC לתחום הפיננסי. אנחנו משתמשים בתכניות אלה בסוללה של משימות NLP פיננסיות ולהראות את העליון שלהם על התכניות גלובה גנרליות ותכניות מילים פיננסיות קיימות אחרות. אנחנו גם EDGAR-CRAWLER מקור פתוח, ערכת כלים שמקלה להוריד ולחטיף דוחות שנתיים עתידים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་EDGAR-CORPUS ་སྐྱེས་ཆེན་པོ་ཞིག་ཡོད། རྣམ་གྲངས་ཀ་འདིས་མི་མང་གི་སྡོམ་ཁང་ཆེན་མཁན་ལས་རྒྱལ་སྤྱིར་བཏང་བ་ཡོད། ང་ཚོའི་ཤེས་ཚད་དགའ་ཤོས་ཡོད། EDGAR-CORPUS་ནི་དུས་ཚོད་ཀྱིས་བཏོན་པའི་རྒྱུ་ནོར་ཆེ་ཤོས་རེད། ཡར་ཞུ་ཡོངས We use EDGAR-CORPUS to train and release EDGAR-W2V, which are WORD2VEC embeddings for the financial domain. ང་ཚོས་གཞུང་གི་NLP བྱ་འགུལ་གྱི་ཨ་རིམ་ནང་དུ་སྒྲིག་འཛུགས་འདི་དག་གི་ལས་རྒན་ཏུ་འཇུག་སྤྱོད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་EDGAR-CRAWLER(open-source)ཁ་ཕྱེས་ཀྱི་ལག་ཆ་ཞིག</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna sakar EDGR-CORPUS, wata bangon noveli wanda ke samun littattafai yearli daga duk makampuni da aka saɓa da mabuwãyi cikin Marekani na ƙari shekara 25. Ga mafi kyaun saninmu, EDGAN-CORPU ne mafi girma na kamufi na NLP wanda ke iya haɗuwa a yanzu. An sassautar da duk ajalinsu, kuma aka raba su cikin abubuwan da suke daidai (rabo-rabo), kuma aka bãyar da shi cikin tsarin JSSon mai sauƙi da amfani da shi. Tuna amfani da EDGR-CORPUS ga yin shirin da kuma za'a saka EDGR-W2V, waɗanda ke shiga kowace kasuka na dũkiyar. Munã aiki waɗannan da ke cikin batarin na NLP masu aikin dũkiya da ke nuna sarrafarsu a kowace ta ga matsayin GoV da wasu kalmõmi da ke cikin kashi. Mu samu masu buɗe-zane EDGR-CRAWLER, wata taska mai sauƙi da download da samu'in da ake samun littattafan sanauka baka.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Izdajamo EDGAR-CORPUS, nov korpus, ki vsebuje letna poročila vseh javnih družb v ZDA za obdobje več kot 25 let. Kolikor vemo, je EDGAR-CORPUS največji korpus finančnega NLP, ki je doslej na voljo. Vsa poročila so prenesena, razdeljena na ustrezne elemente (odseke) in zagotovljena v čisti in enostavni obliki JSON. EDGAR-CORPUS uporabljamo za usposabljanje in izdajo EDGAR-W2V, ki so WORD2VEC vgradnje za finančno področje. Te vdelave uporabljamo v naboru finančnih nalog NLP in prikazujemo njihovo superiornost pred generičnimi vdelavami GloVe in drugimi obstoječimi vdelavami finančnih besed. Prav tako imamo odprtokodno orodje EDGAR-CRAWLER, ki omogoča prenos in pridobivanje prihodnjih letnih poročil.</abstract_sk>
      </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>The Global Banking Standards QA Dataset (GBS-QA)<fixed-case>QA</fixed-case> Dataset (<fixed-case>GBS</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>QA</fixed-case>)</title>
      <author><first>Kyunghwan</first><last>Sohn</last></author>
      <author><first>Sunjae</first><last>Kwon</last></author>
      <author><first>Jaesik</first><last>Choi</last></author>
      <pages>19–25</pages>
      <abstract>A domain specific question answering (QA) dataset dramatically improves the machine comprehension performance. This paper presents a new Global Banking Standards QA dataset (GBS-QA) in the banking regulation domain. The GBS-QA has three values. First, it contains actual questions from market players and answers from global rule setter, the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (BCBS) in the middle of creating and revising banking regulations. Second, financial regulation experts analyze and verify pairs of questions and answers in the annotation process. Lastly, the GBS-QA is a totally different dataset with existing datasets in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finance">finance</a> and is applicable to stimulate transfer learning research in the banking regulation domain.</abstract>
      <url hash="cc80d688">2021.econlp-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>sohn-etal-2021-global</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.econlp-1.3</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Corporate Bankruptcy Prediction with Domain-Adapted BERT<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Alex Gunwoo</first><last>Kim</last></author>
      <author><first>Sangwon</first><last>Yoon</last></author>
      <pages>26–36</pages>
      <abstract>This study performs BERT-based analysis, which is a representative contextualized language model, on corporate disclosure data to predict impending bankruptcies. Prior literature on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bankruptcy_prediction">bankruptcy prediction</a> mainly focuses on developing more sophisticated prediction methodologies with financial variables. However, in our study, we focus on improving the quality of input dataset. Specifically, we employ BERT model to perform <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> on MD&amp;A disclosures. We show that BERT outperforms dictionary-based predictions and Word2Vec-based predictions in terms of adjusted R-square in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_regression">logistic regression</a>, k-nearest neighbor (kNN-5), and linear kernel support vector machine (SVM). Further, instead of pre-training the BERT model from scratch, we apply <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autodidacticism">self-learning</a> with confidence-based filtering to corporate disclosure data (10-K). We achieve the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy rate</a> of 91.56 % and demonstrate that the domain adaptation procedure brings a significant improvement in prediction accuracy.</abstract>
      <url hash="570b9d58">2021.econlp-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>kim-yoon-2021-corporate</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.econlp-1.4</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>To What Extent Can English-as-a-Second Language Learners Read Economic News Texts?<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish-as-a-Second Language Learners Read Economic News Texts?</title>
      <author><first>Yo</first><last>Ehara</last></author>
      <pages>62–68</pages>
      <abstract>In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision-making">decision making</a> in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economy">economic field</a>, an especially important requirement is to rapidly understand news to absorb ever-changing economic situations. Given that most economic news is written in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, the ability to read such information without waiting for a translation is particularly valuable in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economics">economics</a> in contrast to other fields. In consideration of this issue, this research investigated the extent to which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreign_language">non-native English speakers</a> are able to read economic news to make decisions accordingly   an issue that has been rarely addressed in previous studies. Using an existing standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> as training data, we created a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> that automatically evaluates the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readability">readability</a> of text with high <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> for English learners. Our assessment of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readability">readability</a> of an economic news corpus revealed that most news texts can be read by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_as_a_second_or_foreign_language">intermediate English learners</a>. We also found that in some cases, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readability">readability</a> varies considerably depending on the knowledge of certain words specific to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economics">economic field</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="fd7d735f">2021.econlp-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>ehara-2021-extent</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.econlp-1.9</doi>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/onestopenglish">OneStopEnglish</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>