<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.insights">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-11-02">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Insights from Negative Results in NLP</booktitle>
      <editor><first>João</first><last>Sedoc</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Rogers</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Rumshisky</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Shabnam</first><last>Tafreshi</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online and Punta Cana, Dominican Republic</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="18678a7a">2021.insights-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>insights-2021-insights</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Corrected CBOW Performs as well as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skip-gram">Skip-gram</a><fixed-case>CBOW</fixed-case> Performs as well as Skip-gram</title>
      <author><first>Ozan</first><last>İrsoy</last></author>
      <author><first>Adrian</first><last>Benton</last></author>
      <author><first>Karl</first><last>Stratos</last></author>
      <pages>1–8</pages>
      <abstract>Mikolov et al. (2013a) observed that continuous bag-of-words (CBOW) word embeddings tend to underperform Skip-gram (SG) embeddings, and this finding has been reported in subsequent works. We find that these observations are driven not by fundamental differences in their training objectives, but more likely on faulty negative sampling CBOW implementations in popular <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_(computing)">libraries</a> such as the official implementation, word2vec.c, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gensim">Gensim</a>. We show that after correcting a bug in the CBOW gradient update, one can learn CBOW word embeddings that are fully competitive with SG on various intrinsic and extrinsic tasks, while being many times faster to train.</abstract>
      <url hash="aeb2d85a">2021.insights-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>irsoy-etal-2021-corrected</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.insights-1.1</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/bloomberg/koan" additional="false">bloomberg/koan</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/c4">C4</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/glue">GLUE</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/qnli">QNLI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>BERT Can not Align Characters<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> Cannot Align Characters</title>
      <author><first>Antonis</first><last>Maronikolakis</last></author>
      <author><first>Philipp</first><last>Dufter</last></author>
      <author><first>Hinrich</first><last>Schütze</last></author>
      <pages>16–22</pages>
      <abstract>In previous work, it has been shown that BERT can adequately align cross-lingual sentences on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax">word level</a>. Here we investigate whether BERT can also operate as a char-level aligner. The languages examined are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, Fake <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greek_language">Greek</a>. We show that the closer two languages are, the better BERT can align them on the character level. BERT indeed works well in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> to Fake English alignment, but this does not generalize to natural languages to the same extent. Nevertheless, the proximity of two languages does seem to be a factor. English is more related to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a> than to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greek_language">Greek</a> and this is reflected in how well BERT aligns them ; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a> is better than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greek_language">Greek</a>. We examine multiple setups and show that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Similarity_matrix">similarity matrices</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language">natural languages</a> show weaker relations the further apart two languages are.</abstract>
      <url hash="993e58e5">2021.insights-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>maronikolakis-etal-2021-bert</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.insights-1.3</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Two Heads are Better than One? Verification of Ensemble Effect in Neural Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Chanjun</first><last>Park</last></author>
      <author><first>Sungjin</first><last>Park</last></author>
      <author><first>Seolhwa</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Taesun</first><last>Whang</last></author>
      <author><first>Heuiseok</first><last>Lim</last></author>
      <pages>23–28</pages>
      <abstract>In the field of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Musical_ensemble">ensembles</a> are broadly known to be effective in improving performance. This paper analyzes how ensemble of neural machine translation (NMT) models affect performance improvement by designing various experimental setups (i.e., intra-, inter-ensemble, and non-convergence ensemble). To an in-depth examination, we analyze each ensemble method with respect to several aspects such as different attention models and vocab strategies. Experimental results show that ensembling is not always resulting in performance increases and give noteworthy negative findings.</abstract>
      <url hash="507d99cc">2021.insights-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>park-etal-2021-two</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.insights-1.4</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Comparing Euclidean and Hyperbolic Embeddings on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a> Nouns Hypernymy Graph<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>uclidean and Hyperbolic Embeddings on the <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et Nouns Hypernymy Graph</title>
      <author><first>Sameer</first><last>Bansal</last></author>
      <author><first>Adrian</first><last>Benton</last></author>
      <pages>49–53</pages>
      <abstract>Nickel and Kiela (2017) present a new method for embedding tree nodes in the Poincare ball, and suggest that these hyperbolic embeddings are far more effective than Euclidean embeddings at embedding nodes in large, hierarchically structured graphs like the WordNet nouns hypernymy tree. This is especially true in low dimensions (Nickel and Kiela, 2017, Table 1). In this work, we seek to reproduce their experiments on embedding and reconstructing the WordNet nouns hypernymy graph. Counter to what they report, we find that Euclidean embeddings are able to represent this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tree_(graph_theory)">tree</a> at least as well as Poincare embeddings, when allowed at least 50 dimensions. We note that this does not diminish the significance of their work given the impressive performance of hyperbolic embeddings in very low-dimensional settings. However, given the wide influence of their work, our aim here is to present an updated and more accurate comparison between the Euclidean and hyperbolic embeddings.</abstract>
      <url hash="fa0346b5">2021.insights-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>bansal-benton-2021-comparing</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.insights-1.8</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>The Highs and Lows of Simple Lexical Domain Adaptation Approaches for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_machine_translation">Neural Machine Translation</a></title>
      <author><first>Nikolay</first><last>Bogoychev</last></author>
      <author><first>Pinzhen</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <pages>74–80</pages>
      <abstract>Machine translation systems are vulnerable to domain mismatch, especially in a low-resource scenario. Out-of-domain translations are often of poor quality and prone to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallucination">hallucinations</a>, due to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exposure_bias">exposure bias</a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translator_(computing)">decoder</a> acting as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language model</a>. We adopt two approaches to alleviate this problem : lexical shortlisting restricted by IBM statistical alignments, and hypothesis reranking based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Similarity_measure">similarity</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Method_(computer_programming)">methods</a> are computationally cheap and show success on low-resource out-of-domain test sets. However, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Method_(computer_programming)">methods</a> lose advantage when there is sufficient data or too great domain mismatch. This is due to both the IBM model losing its advantage over the implicitly learned neural alignment, and issues with subword segmentation of unseen words.</abstract>
      <url hash="93b16635">2021.insights-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>bogoychev-chen-2021-highs</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.insights-1.12</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/marian-nmt/marian" additional="false">marian-nmt/marian</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Backtranslation in Neural Morphological Inflection</title>
      <author><first>Ling</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Mans</first><last>Hulden</last></author>
      <pages>81–88</pages>
      <abstract>Backtranslation is a common technique for leveraging unlabeled data in low-resource scenarios in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a>. The method is directly applicable to morphological inflection generation if unlabeled word forms are available. This paper evaluates the potential of backtranslation for morphological inflection using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a> from six languages with labeled data drawn from the SIGMORPHON shared task resource and unlabeled data from different sources. Our core finding is that backtranslation can offer modest improvements in low-resource scenarios, but only if the unlabeled data is very clean and has been filtered by the same annotation standards as the labeled data.</abstract>
      <url hash="f560fdcd">2021.insights-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>liu-hulden-2021-backtranslation</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.insights-1.13</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>Challenging the Semi-Supervised VAE Framework for Text Classification<fixed-case>VAE</fixed-case> Framework for Text Classification</title>
      <author><first>Ghazi</first><last>Felhi</last></author>
      <author><first>Joseph</first><last>Le Roux</last></author>
      <author><first>Djamé</first><last>Seddah</last></author>
      <pages>136–143</pages>
      <abstract>Semi-Supervised Variational Autoencoders (SSVAEs) are widely used models for data efficient learning. In this paper, we question the adequacy of the standard design of sequence SSVAEs for the task of text classification as we exhibit two sources of overcomplexity for which we provide simplifications. These simplifications to SSVAEs preserve their theoretical soundness while providing a number of practical advantages in the semi-supervised setup where the result of training is a text classifier. These simplifications are the removal of (i) the Kullback-Liebler divergence from its objective and (ii) the fully unobserved latent variable from its probabilistic model. These changes relieve users from choosing a prior for their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latent_variable">latent variables</a>, make the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> smaller and faster, and allow for a better flow of information into the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latent_variable">latent variables</a>. We compare the simplified versions to standard SSVAEs on 4 text classification tasks. On top of the above-mentioned simplification, experiments show a speed-up of 26 %, while keeping equivalent classification scores. The code to reproduce our experiments is public.</abstract>
      <url hash="f94e6d7d">2021.insights-1.19</url>
      <bibkey>felhi-etal-2021-challenging</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.insights-1.19</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ghazi-f/challenging-ssvaes" additional="false">ghazi-f/challenging-ssvaes</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ag-news">AG News</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/imdb-movie-reviews">IMDb Movie Reviews</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Active Learning for Argument Strength Estimation</title>
      <author><first>Nataliia</first><last>Kees</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Fromm</last></author>
      <author><first>Evgeniy</first><last>Faerman</last></author>
      <author><first>Thomas</first><last>Seidl</last></author>
      <pages>144–150</pages>
      <abstract>High-quality arguments are an essential part of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision-making">decision-making</a>. Automatically predicting the quality of an argument is a complex task that recently got much attention in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argument_mining">argument mining</a>. However, the annotation effort for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> is exceptionally high. Therefore, we test uncertainty-based active learning (AL) methods on two popular argument-strength data sets to estimate whether sample-efficient learning can be enabled. Our extensive empirical evaluation shows that uncertainty-based acquisition functions can not surpass the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> reached with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_variable">random acquisition</a> on these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">data sets</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="8e0ea365">2021.insights-1.20</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="a1fb3587">2021.insights-1.20.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>kees-etal-2021-active</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.insights-1.20</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/nkees/active-learning-argument-strength" additional="false">nkees/active-learning-argument-strength</pwccode>
    <title_ar>التعلم النشط لتقدير قوة الحجة</title_ar>
      <title_es>Aprendizaje activo para estimar la fuerza argumental</title_es>
      <title_pt>Aprendizado Ativo para Estimativa de Força de Argumento</title_pt>
      <title_ja>引数強度推定のアクティブラーニング</title_ja>
      <title_zh>以参数度者自学</title_zh>
      <title_hi>तर्क शक्ति अनुमान के लिए सक्रिय सीखना</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Foghlaim Ghníomhach don Argóint Meastachán Neart</title_ga>
      <title_el>Ενεργή μάθηση για την εκτίμηση της δύναμης επιχειρημάτων</title_el>
      <title_hu>Aktív tanulás az érvek erősségének becsléséhez</title_hu>
      <title_ka>არგემენტის ძალიან განსაზღვრება</title_ka>
      <title_kk>Аргументтің күш оқу үшін белсенді оқу</title_kk>
      <title_it>Apprendimento attivo per la stima della forza dell'argomento</title_it>
      <title_lt>Veiklus mokymasis argumentų stiprumo vertinimui</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Активно учење за проценка на силата на аргументот</title_mk>
      <title_ml>Active Learning for Argument Strength Estimation</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Pelajaran Aktif untuk Estimasi Kekuatan Argumen</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Tagħlim Attiv għal Stima tas-Saħħa tal-Argument</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Аргументийн хүчтэй тооцооллын актив суралцах</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Aktywne uczenie się dla oszacowania siły argumentów</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Învățare activă pentru estimarea forței argumentelor</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Aktivno učenje za procjenu snage argumenta</title_sr>
      <title_no>Aktiv læring for sterkte estimating av argument</title_no>
      <title_si>සක්‍රිය ඉගෙනගන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Waxbarashada Active Learning for Argument Strength Estimation</title_so>
      <title_sv>Aktivt lärande för bedömning av argumentstyrka</title_sv>
      <title_ta>ஆரம்ப வலிமை கணக்கீட்டிற்கான செயல்படுத்தல்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Argument Strength Estimation for Active Learning</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Học hành cho Đối số Độ mạnh</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_hr>Aktivno učenje za procjenu snage argumenta</title_hr>
      <title_da>Aktiv læring til vurdering af argumentstyrke</title_da>
      <title_id>Pelajaran Aktif untuk Penghargaan Kekuatan Argumen</title_id>
      <title_bg>Активно обучение за оценка на силата на аргументите</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Actief leren voor de schatting van argumentsterkte</title_nl>
      <title_ko>논원 강도 추정의 주동 학습</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Kiongozi cha harakati cha Kushinikiza Uhisabu</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Argument Güç Hesablamak üçin janlaş öwrenme</title_tr>
      <title_fa>یادگیری فعال برای ارزیابی قوت ارزیابی</title_fa>
      <title_de>Aktives Lernen zur Schätzung der Argumentstärke</title_de>
      <title_am>Active Learning for Argument Strength Estimation</title_am>
      <title_af>Aktiewe leer vir Argument Sterkte Estimasie</title_af>
      <title_sq>Mësimi aktiv për vlerësimin e forcës së argumentit</title_sq>
      <title_bn>আর্গামেন্ট শক্তি গণনার জন্য সক্রিয় শিক্ষা শিক্ষা</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Ակտիվ սովորելը բանավեճի ուժի գնահատման համար</title_hy>
      <title_ca>Active Learning for Argument Strength Estimation</title_ca>
      <title_bs>Aktivno učenje za procjenu snage argumenta</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Aktivní učení pro odhad síly argumentů</title_cs>
      <title_az>Argument Q칲vv톛tli N칬mr톛si 칲칞칲n Fayl 칐yr톛nm톛</title_az>
      <title_et>Aktiivne õpe argumentide tugevuse hindamiseks</title_et>
      <title_fi>Aktiivinen oppiminen argumentin vahvuuden arviointiin</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Attribute</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Aktivno učenje za oceno moči argumentov</title_sk>
      <title_he>לימוד פעיל עבור הערכת כוח הטיעון</title_he>
      <title_bo>སྒྲུབ་རྟགས་ཀྱི་སྟོབས་ཤུགས་ཚད་ལ་སྤྱོད་སྦྱོར་བ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تعتبر الحجج عالية الجودة جزءًا أساسيًا من عملية صنع القرار. إن التنبؤ تلقائيًا بجودة الحجة هو مهمة معقدة حظيت مؤخرًا باهتمام كبير في التنقيب عن الجدل. ومع ذلك ، فإن جهد التعليقات التوضيحية لهذه المهمة مرتفع بشكل استثنائي. لذلك ، نقوم باختبار طرق التعلم النشط القائمة على عدم اليقين على مجموعتين شائعتين من بيانات قوة الحجة لتقدير ما إذا كان يمكن تمكين التعلم الفعال في العينة. يُظهر تقييمنا التجريبي الشامل أن وظائف الاستحواذ القائمة على عدم اليقين لا يمكنها تجاوز الدقة التي تم الوصول إليها من خلال الاستحواذ العشوائي على مجموعات البيانات هذه.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Argumentos de alta qualidade são uma parte essencial da tomada de decisão. Prever automaticamente a qualidade de um argumento é uma tarefa complexa que recentemente recebeu muita atenção na mineração de argumentos. No entanto, o esforço de anotação para esta tarefa é excepcionalmente alto. Portanto, testamos métodos de aprendizado ativo (AL) baseado em incerteza em dois conjuntos de dados de força de argumento populares para estimar se o aprendizado com eficiência de amostra pode ser ativado. Nossa extensa avaliação empírica mostra que as funções de aquisição baseadas em incerteza não podem superar a precisão alcançada com a aquisição aleatória nesses conjuntos de dados.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Los argumentos de alta calidad son parte esencial de la toma de decisiones. Predecir automáticamente la calidad de un argumento es una tarea compleja que recientemente ha recibido mucha atención en la minería de argumentos. Sin embargo, el esfuerzo de anotación para esta tarea es excepcionalmente alto. Por lo tanto, probamos los métodos de aprendizaje activo (AL) basados en la incertidumbre en dos conjuntos de datos populares de solidez de argumentos para estimar si se puede habilitar el aprendizaje eficiente de la muestra. Nuestra amplia evaluación empírica muestra que las funciones de adquisición basadas en la incertidumbre no pueden superar la precisión alcanzada con la adquisición aleatoria de estos conjuntos de datos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>質の高い議論は意思決定に不可欠な部分です。引数の品質を自動的に予測することは、最近引数マイニングで注目されている複雑なタスクです。しかしながら、このタスクの注釈の労力は非常に高い。したがって、不確実性ベースのアクティブラーニング（ AL ）方法を2つの人気のある引数強度データセットでテストして、サンプル効率の高い学習が有効になるかどうかを推定します。私たちの広範な実証的評価は、不確実性に基づく取得関数が、これらのデータセット上のランダム取得で到達した精度を上回ることはできないことを示しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>उच्च गुणवत्ता वाले तर्क निर्णय लेने का एक अनिवार्य हिस्सा हैं। स्वचालित रूप से एक तर्क की गुणवत्ता की भविष्यवाणी करना एक जटिल कार्य है जिसे हाल ही में तर्क खनन में बहुत ध्यान दिया गया है। हालांकि, इस कार्य के लिए एनोटेशन प्रयास असाधारण रूप से उच्च है। इसलिए, हम दो लोकप्रिय तर्क-शक्ति डेटा सेट पर अनिश्चितता-आधारित सक्रिय सीखने (एएल) विधियों का परीक्षण करते हैं ताकि यह अनुमान लगाया जा सके कि नमूना-कुशल सीखने को सक्षम किया जा सकता है या नहीं। हमारे व्यापक अनुभवजन्य मूल्यांकन से पता चलता है कि अनिश्चितता-आधारित अधिग्रहण कार्य इन डेटा सेटों पर यादृच्छिक अधिग्रहण के साथ पहुंची सटीकता को पार नहीं कर सकते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>高质量之论,决策之要组成部分。 自料论点质是一项复杂的事务,近在论点发掘中很多关注。 然此注甚高。 是以两行之参数,度数集上试于不确定性之自学(AL)法,以度可用样本高效学否。 臣等博实质明,基于不确定性采函数无以过此集上随机采致之精度。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Is cuid riachtanach den chinnteoireacht iad argóintí ardchaighdeáin. Is tasc casta é cáilíocht argóinte a thuar go huathoibríoch ar tugadh go leor airde air le déanaí i mianadóireacht argóintí. Mar sin féin, tá an iarracht nótaí don tasc seo thar a bheith ard. Dá bhrí sin, déanaimid tástáil ar mhodhanna foghlama gníomhaí atá bunaithe ar éiginnteacht (AL) ar dhá thacar sonraí a bhfuil neart argóinte acu chun a mheas an féidir foghlaim atá tíosach ar shamplaí a chumasú. Léiríonn ár meastóireacht eimpíreach fhairsing nach féidir le feidhmeanna fála atá bunaithe ar éiginnteacht an cruinneas a baineadh amach leis an bhfáil randamach ar na tacair sonraí seo a shárú.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Τα επιχειρήματα υψηλής ποιότητας αποτελούν ουσιαστικό μέρος της λήψης αποφάσεων. Η αυτόματη πρόβλεψη της ποιότητας ενός επιχειρήματος είναι μια πολύπλοκη εργασία που πρόσφατα έλαβε μεγάλη προσοχή στην εξόρυξη επιχειρημάτων. Ωστόσο, η προσπάθεια σχολιασμού για αυτό το έργο είναι εξαιρετικά υψηλή. Ως εκ τούτου, δοκιμάζουμε μεθόδους ενεργού μάθησης βασισμένης στην αβεβαιότητα σε δύο δημοφιλή σύνολα δεδομένων δύναμης επιχειρημάτων για να εκτιμήσουμε αν μπορεί να ενεργοποιηθεί η αποτελεσματική μάθηση δειγμάτων. Η εκτενής εμπειρική μας αξιολόγηση δείχνει ότι οι λειτουργίες απόκτησης βάσει αβεβαιότητας δεν μπορούν να υπερβούν την ακρίβεια που επιτυγχάνεται με την τυχαία απόκτηση σε αυτά τα σύνολα δεδομένων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A kiváló minőségű érvek a döntéshozatal alapvető részét képezik. Az argumentumok minőségének automatikus előrejelzése komplex feladat, amely nemrégiben nagy figyelmet kapott az argumentumbányászatban. Ennek ellenére a feladatnak a jegyzetelési erőfeszítése rendkívül magas. Ezért a bizonytalanságon alapuló aktív tanulási (AL) módszereket két népszerű argumentum-erősség adatkészleten teszteljük annak megállapítására, hogy a mintahatékony tanulás engedélyezhető-e. Kiterjedt empirikus értékelésünk azt mutatja, hogy a bizonytalanságon alapuló beszerzési funkciók nem haladhatják meg az ezen adatkészletek véletlenszerű beszerzésével elért pontosságot.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>უფრო კანგალიტიური არგუმენტები უფრო მნიშვნელოვანი გადაწყვეტილების ნაწილი. ავტომატურად აპორმენტის კალიონტის წინასწარმოდგენა კომპლექსი რაოდენობა, რომელიც ახლა აპორმენტის წინასწარმოდგენა. მაგრამ, ამ დავალებისთვის ამოცანების ძალიან ძალიან დიდი. ამიტომ, ჩვენ შევცვალობთ არჩეულობის აკტივი სწავლების (AL) მეტოვებზე ორი პოლიპური არგუმენტის ძალადობის მონაცემების შესახებ, რომელიც შეიძლება გავამწონოთ თუ ჩვენი უფრო დიდი ემპერიკალური განსაზღვრება აჩვენებს, რომ უცნობიერებული მიღება ფუნქციები არ შეუძლიათ გადავადგინოთ მართლა, რომელიც მიღებულია ამ მონაცემების სე</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_kk>Жоғары сапатты аргументтер - шешімдеу үшін негізгі бөлігі. Аргументтің сапасын автоматты түрде таңдау - жаңа уақытта аргументтің бағыттауында көп қызық тапсырмасы. Бірақ бұл тапсырманың жаңарту әрекеті өте жоғары. Сондықтан, біз белсенді үйрену (AL) әдістерін тексереміз екі мәліметтік аргумент- күштік деректер бағдарламасы үшін мәліметтің оқыту мүмкіндігін бағалау үшін. Біздің кеңейтілген импирикалық оқиғамыз бұл деректер жиындарындағы кездейсоқ қабылдау функцияларына негізделген тәуелсіздік қабылдау функцияларына арналмайды.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_it>Argomenti di alta qualità sono una parte essenziale del processo decisionale. Prevedere automaticamente la qualità di un argomento è un compito complesso che recentemente ha ricevuto molta attenzione nel mining degli argomenti. Tuttavia, lo sforzo di annotazione per questo compito è eccezionalmente elevato. Pertanto, testiamo metodi di apprendimento attivo basato sull'incertezza (AL) su due insiemi di dati popolari per valutare se l'apprendimento efficiente del campione può essere abilitato. La nostra ampia valutazione empirica mostra che le funzioni di acquisizione basate sull'incertezza non possono superare l'accuratezza raggiunta con l'acquisizione casuale su questi set di dati.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Aukštos kokybės argumentai yra esminė sprendimų priėmimo dalis. Automatinis argumento kokybės prognozavimas yra sudėtinga užduotis, kuri neseniai daug dėmesio skyrė argument ų gavybai. Tačiau pastangos užrašyti šią užduotį yra išskirtinai didelės. Todėl bandome neapibrėžtumu pagrįstus aktyvaus mokymosi (angl. uncertainty-based active learning (AL) metodus naudojant du populiarius argument ų stiprumo duomenų rinkinius, kad įvertintume, ar galima įdiegti mėginių naudojimo efektyvų mokymąsi. Išsamus empirinis vertinimas rodo, kad netikrumo pagrindu pagrįstos įsigijimo funkcijos negali viršyti tikslumo, pasiekto atsitiktiniu šių duomenų rinkinių įsigijimu.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Високиквалитетните аргументи се суштински дел од донесувањето одлуки. Автоматски предвидување на квалитетот на аргументот е комплексна задача која неодамна доби многу внимание во рудањето аргументи. Сепак, напорите за анотација за оваа задача се исклучително високи. Затоа, ги тестираме методите на активно учење (АЛ) базирано на несигурноста на два популарни групи податоци за сила на аргументите за да процениме дали може да се овозможи учење ефикасно на примероци. Our extensive empirical evaluation shows that uncertainty-based acquisition functions can not surpass the accuracy reached with the random acquisition on these data sets.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>ഉയര്‍ന്ന വിവരങ്ങള്‍ തീരുമാനിക്കുന്നതിന്റെ പ്രധാന ഭാഗമാണ്. ഒരു ആര്‍ഗ്യുമെന്റെ സ്വാഭാവികമായി പ്രവചിക്കുന്നത് ഒരു ചികിത്രമായ ജോലിയാണ്. അതിന്റെ അടുത്തുതന്നെ വാദ്യ എന്നാലും, ഈ ജോലിയുടെ പ്രശ്നം വ്യക്തമായി ഉയര്‍ന്നിരിക്കുന്നു. അതുകൊണ്ട്, നമ്മള്‍ പരീക്ഷിക്കുന്നത് പരിശോധിക്കുന്നത് രണ്ട് പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട ആര്‍ഗ്യുമെന്‍റ് ശക്തിയുള്ള വിവരങ്ങളുടെ സെറ്റുകളില നമ്മുടെ വിശാലമായ എക്മീരിക്കല്‍ വിലാസങ്ങള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നുവെങ്കില്‍ ഈ ഡേറ്റാ സജ്ജീകരണങ്ങളില്‍ എത്തുന്നതിന്റെ കൃത്യമായ വി</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Өндөр чанартай аргументууд бол шийдвэр гаргах үндсэн хэсэг юм. Аргументийн сайн чанарыг автоматаар таамаглах нь аргументын хөрөнгө оруулахад маш их анхаарлын ажил юм. Гэхдээ энэ ажил дээрх анхаарлаа хандуулах чадвар маш өндөр. Тиймээс, бид алдартай аргумент-хүчтэй өгөгдлийн хоёр аргумент дээр тодорхойлж чадахгүй эсэхийг тооцоолж чадна. Бидний өргөн эзэмшигийн үнэлгээ нь тодорхойгүй байдлын худалдааны функцүүд эдгээр өгөгдлийн санамсаргүй худалдааны тодорхойлолтой тодорхойлж чадахгүй гэдгийг харуулж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ms>Argumen kualiti tinggi adalah bahagian penting dalam pembuat keputusan. Automatik meramalkan kualiti argumen adalah tugas kompleks yang baru-baru ini mendapat banyak perhatian dalam perlombongan argumen. Namun, usaha anotasi untuk tugas ini sangat tinggi. Oleh itu, kami menguji kaedah pembelajaran aktif berdasarkan ketidakpastian (AL) pada dua set data kekuatan argumen populer untuk menghargai sama ada pembelajaran efisien sampel boleh dibenarkan. Evaluasi empirik luas kami menunjukkan bahawa fungsi penemuan berdasarkan ketidakpastian tidak boleh melebihi ketepatan yang dicapai dengan penemuan rawak pada set data ini.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Argumenti ta’ kwalità għolja huma parti essenzjali mit-teħid tad-deċiżjonijiet. Il-previżjoni awtomatika tal-kwalità ta’ argument hija kompitu kumpless li reċentement irċeviet ħafna attenzjoni fil-minjieri tal-argumenti. However, the annotation effort for this task is exceptionally high.  Għalhekk, nistestjaw il-metodi tat-tagħlim attiv ibbażat fuq l-inċertezza (AL) fuq żewġ settijiet ta’ dejta popolari dwar is-saħħa tal-argument biex nistmaw jekk it-tagħlim effiċjenti fil-kampjuni jistax ikun possibbli. L-evalwazzjoni empirika estensiva tagħna turi li l-funzjonijiet ta’ akkwist ibbażati fuq l-inċertezza ma jistgħux jaqbżu l-preċiżjoni milħuqa bl-akkwist aleatorju fuq dawn is-settijiet ta’ dejta.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Wysokiej jakości argumenty są istotną częścią podejmowania decyzji. Automatyczne przewidywanie jakości argumentu jest złożonym zadaniem, które ostatnio zyskało dużą uwagę w eksploracji argumentów. Jednak nakład adnotacyjny dla tego zadania jest wyjątkowo wysoki. W związku z tym testujemy metody aktywnego uczenia się oparte na niepewności (AL) na dwóch popularnych zbiorach danych dotyczących siły argumentów, aby oszacować, czy można włączyć naukę efektywną próbkę. Nasza szeroka ocena empiryczna pokazuje, że funkcje pozyskiwania oparte na niepewności nie mogą przekroczyć dokładności osiągniętej przy losowym pozyskiwaniu na tych zbiorach danych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Høgkvalitetssargumenter er ein viktig del av avgjøring av beslutningar. Automatisk forhåndsvising av kvaliteten til eit argument er ein kompleks oppgåve som nyleg fikk mykje oppmerksomhet i argument-mining. Dette er imidlertid uttrykket for annotasjonen for denne oppgåva ekstra høg. Det er derfor vi tester ulike aktive læringsmetodar (AL) på to populære argumentstyrkedata for å vurdere om prøveeffektiv læring kan slå på. Vårt utvida empirisk evaluering viser at uavhengige opptak-funksjonar kan ikkje overføre nøyaktigheten som er nådd med tilfeldig opptak på desse datasettene.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Argumentele de înaltă calitate reprezintă o parte esențială a luării deciziilor. Prezicerea automată a calității unui argument este o sarcină complexă care a primit recent multă atenție în mineritul argumentelor. Cu toate acestea, efortul de adnotare pentru această sarcină este excepțional de mare. Prin urmare, testăm metodele de învățare activă bazată pe incertitudine (AL) pe două seturi de date populare pentru a estima dacă învățarea eficientă prin eșantioane poate fi activată. Evaluarea noastră empirică extinsă arată că funcțiile de achiziție bazate pe incertitudine nu pot depăși acuratețea atinsă cu achiziția aleatorie a acestor seturi de date.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Visokokvalitetni argumenti su ključni deo donošenja odluka. Automatski predviđanje kvalitete argument a je kompleksan zadatak koji je nedavno dobio mnogo pažnje u rudarstvu argumenta. Međutim, napor za annotaciju ovog zadatka je izuzetno visok. Stoga, testiramo metode aktivnog učenja (AL) na temelju nejasnosti na dva popularna seta podataka o snazi argumentacija kako bi procenili može li omogućiti učenje uzorka efikasnog učenja. Naša široka empirička procjena pokazuje da funkcije na osnovu prikupljanja na osnovu nesigurnosti ne mogu preći tačnost koja je postignuta slučajnim prikupljanjem na ovim podacima.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Högkvalitativa argument är en viktig del av beslutsfattandet. Att automatiskt förutsäga kvaliteten på ett argument är en komplex uppgift som nyligen fick mycket uppmärksamhet i argumentmining. Annotationsinsatsen för denna uppgift är dock exceptionellt stor. Därför testar vi osäkerhetsbaserade aktiva inlärningsmetoder (AL) på två populära argumentstyrkedata för att uppskatta om proveffektivt lärande kan aktiveras. Vår omfattande empiriska utvärdering visar att osäkerhetsbaserade förvärvsfunktioner inte kan överträffa den noggrannhet som uppnåtts med slumpmässiga förvärv på dessa datauppsättningar.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>උත්සත් ප්‍රශ්ණතාවය ප්‍රශ්ණත්වයක් තීරණය කරන්න අවශ්‍ය කොටසක්. ස්වයංක්‍රියාවිතයෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ස්වයංක්‍රියාවිතයෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්නේ සංක්‍රිය වැ නමුත්, මේ වැඩක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් විශේෂයෙන් ඉහළයි. ඉතින්, අපි අනිශ්චිතත්වයක් අධාරිත්වය සක්‍රිය ඉගෙනීම (AL) විධානයක් පරීක්ෂා කරනවා ප්‍රජාතිකාරිය සඳහා ප්‍රත අපේ විශාල සාමාන්‍ය විශ්ලේෂණය පෙන්වන්නේ අනිශ්වාසිත විශ්ලේෂණය සඳහා මේ තොරතුරු සෙට් එක්ක සාමාන්‍ය විශ්ලේෂණය ස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Qiimaha takhasuska sare waa qayb muhiim ah go’aanka. Sida dhaqso ah ka hor dhigidda qiimaha doodu waa shaqo adag oo ugu dhowaad aad aad u fiirsatay qoraalka arrimaha. Si kastaba ha ahaatee hawlgabka la xiriiro waa mid si gaar ah. Sidaa darteed waxaynu ku imtixaannaa qaababka waxbarashada waxqabadka ah oo ku qoran labada kooban ee macluumaadka arrimaha bulshada, si aan u qiimeyno in waxbarashada faa’iido leh ay awoodi karto. Qiimeynta faa'iidada aad u dheer waxay muuqataa in qabashada aqoonta la'aanta aysan ka hor marin karin saxda la heli karo koritaanka kooxdaas.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>உயர்தரமான தருமதிப்புகள் முடிவு செய்ய முக்கியமான பகுதியாகும். ஒரு தருமதிப்பின் தரம் தானாகவே முன்வாக்குவது ஒரு சிக்கலான செயல் ஆனால், இந்த பணிக்கான அறிவிப்பு முயற்சி வித்தியாசமாக உயர்ந்தது. ஆகையால், நாம் சோதிக்க வேண்டும் இரண்டு பிரபலமான தருமதிப்பு-சக்தி தரவு அமைப்புகளில் தெரியாத செயல்பாடு கற்றல் செயல்படுத்த முடியுமா  நம்முடைய விரிவான உச்சரிப்பு காண்பிக்கப்படுகிறது நம்பிக்கை அடிப்படையான பெறுதல் செயல்பாடுகள் இந்த தரவு அமைப்புகளில் குறிப்ப</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>اچھی کیفیت کے ارائے فیصلہ کرنے کے ایک ضروری حصہ ہیں. آروم کی کیفیت کی آگاہ کرنا ایک پیچیدہ کام ہے جو اچھے سے بہت سی توجه حاصل کیا گیا ہے۔ لیکن اس کام کے لئے اظہار کی کوشش بہت بلند ہے۔ لہٰذا، ہم نے ان دو مشرکین آرکیم-قوت ڈیٹ سٹوں پر غیر یقین کی بنیاد پر فعال یادہانی (AL) طریقے کی آزمائش کی تاکید کی کہ نمونہ-فعال یادہانی قابل ہو سکتی ہے. ہماری گھیری عمومی ارزیابی دکھاتی ہے کہ غیر قطعی بنیاد رکھنے والی غیر قطعی فعالیتیں ان ڈیٹ سٹوں پر پہنچ جانے والی صحیح کے ساتھ غیر قطعی غیر قابل ہے</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Buyuk qiymati argumentlari xabar qilish muhim qismi. @ info: whatsthis Lekin, bu vazifa uchun taʼminlovchi harakat oddiy juda yuqori. Shunday qilib, biz ko'pchilik asosiy aktiv o'rganish (AL) usullarini o'rganish mumkin, masalan o'rganishni foydalanishiga imkoniyat qilamiz. Bizning kengaytirilgan muvaffaqiyatlarimizni ko'rsatadi, bu maʼlumotlar sonlarida tasdiqlash muvaffaqiyatlarni aniqlab boʻlmaydi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tài liệu chất lượng cao là yếu tố quyết định. Tự động dự đoán chất lượng của một cuộc tranh luận là một nhiệm vụ phức tạp mà gần đây đã được chú ý nhiều trong việc khai thác tranh luận. Tuy nhiên, ghi chú dành cho nhiệm vụ này cực kỳ cao. Do đó, chúng tôi thử các phương pháp nghiên cứu hoạt động dựa trên sự mơ hồ (Al) dựa trên hai nhóm dữ liệu dựa trên các cuộc tranh luận để ước lượng liệu hiệu quả mẫu có khả năng học hay không. Sự nghiên cứu đầy đủ của chúng tôi cho thấy các chức năng mua sắm dựa trên sự rủi ro không thể vượt qua độ chính xác đạt được với việc mua ngẫu nhiên trên các bộ dữ liệu này.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>Vjerojatno kvalitetni argumenti su ključni dio donošenja odluka. Automatski predviđanje kvalitete argument a je kompleksan zadatak koji je nedavno dobio mnogo pažnje u rudarstvu argumenta. Međutim, napor za annotaciju ovog zadatka je izuzetno visok. Stoga testiramo metode aktivnog učenja (AL) na temelju nejasnosti na dva popularna seta podataka o snazi argument-a kako bi procijenili može li se omogućiti učenje učinkovitosti uzorka. Naša široka empirička procjena pokazuje da funkcije na osnovu prikupljanja na temelju nesigurnosti ne mogu preći točnost dostignuta slučajnim prikupljanjem na ovim podacima.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Argumenter af høj kvalitet er en væsentlig del af beslutningstagningen. Automatisk forudsigelse af kvaliteten af et argument er en kompleks opgave, der for nylig fik meget opmærksomhed i argument mining. Anmærkningsindsatsen for denne opgave er dog usædvanlig stor. Derfor tester vi usikkerhedsbaserede aktive læringsmetoder (AL) på to populære argumentstyrkedatasæt for at vurdere, om prøveeffektiv læring kan aktiveres. Vores omfattende empiriske evaluering viser, at usikkerhedsbaserede anskaffelsesfunktioner ikke kan overgå den nøjagtighed, der opnås med tilfældig anskaffelse af disse datasæt.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>Висококачествените аргументи са съществена част от вземането на решения. Автоматичното предсказване на качеството на аргумент е сложна задача, която наскоро привлече много внимание в добива на аргументи. Въпреки това усилията за анотация за тази задача са изключително високи. Ето защо тестваме методи за активно учене, базирани на неопределеност (АЛ), върху два популярни набора от данни за силата на аргументите, за да преценим дали може да се даде възможност за ефективно учене на извадката. Нашата обширна емпирична оценка показва, че функциите за придобиване, базирани на неопределеност, не могат да надминат точността, постигната при случайното придобиване на тези набори от данни.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_ko>고품질의 논거는 정책 결정의 중요한 구성 부분이다.논점의 질을 자동으로 예측하는 것은 복잡한 임무로 최근 몇 년 동안 논점 발굴에서 광범위한 관심을 받았다.그러나 이 임무의 주석 작업량은 매우 높다.따라서 우리는 두 가지 유행하는 매개 변수 강도 데이터 집합에서 불확실성에 기반한 능동 학습(AL) 방법을 테스트하여 샘플의 효과적인 학습을 사용할 수 있는지를 평가한다.우리의 광범위한 경험 평가에 따르면 불확실성을 바탕으로 하는 채집 함수는 무작위 채집이 달성한 정밀도를 초과할 수 없다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_nl>Hoogwaardige argumenten zijn een essentieel onderdeel van de besluitvorming. Het automatisch voorspellen van de kwaliteit van een argument is een complexe taak die onlangs veel aandacht kreeg in argument mining. De annotatie-inspanning voor deze taak is echter uitzonderlijk hoog. Daarom testen we op onzekerheid gebaseerde actieve leermethoden (AL) op twee populaire gegevenssets met argumentsterkte om te schatten of steekproefefficiënt leren mogelijk is. Onze uitgebreide empirische evaluatie toont aan dat onzekerheidsgebaseerde acquisitiefuncties de nauwkeurigheid die bereikt wordt met de willekeurige acquisitie op deze datasets niet kunnen overtreffen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Argumen kualitas tinggi adalah bagian penting dalam pembuat keputusan. Otomatis memprediksi kualitas argumen adalah tugas kompleks yang baru-baru ini mendapat banyak perhatian dalam pertambangan argumen. Namun, usaha anotasi untuk tugas ini sangat tinggi. Oleh karena itu, kami menguji metode pembelajaran aktif berdasarkan ketidakpastian (AL) pada dua set data kekuatan argumen populer untuk memperkirakan apakah pembelajaran efisien sampel dapat diaktifkan. Evaluasi empirik ekstensif kami menunjukkan bahwa fungsi akvizi berdasarkan ketidakpastian tidak dapat melebihi akurasi yang dicapai dengan akvizi acak pada set data ini.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>ارائه‌های کیفیت بالا بخشی از تصمیم گرفتن ضروری هستند. خودکار پیش‌بینی کیفیت یک حجت یک کار پیچیده است که اخیراً توجه زیادی در ذخیره کردن حجت داشته است. ولی تلاش اظهار این کار بسیار بالاست. بنابراین، ما روش‌های یادگیری فعالی (AL) بر بنیاد غیر مطمئنی را آزمایش می‌کنیم بر دو مجموعه‌های داده‌های قوت arguments-قوت محبوب برای تخمین کردن که آیا یادگیری‌های مثبت نمونه‌ای تواند فعال ارزیابی عمومی ما نشان می دهد که عملکرد گرفتن غیر مستقیم نمی توانند دقیقاتی که با گرفتن تصادفی در این مجموعه داده ها رسیده شده را تغییر دهند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Majadiliano ya juu ni sehemu muhimu ya uamuzi. Kutabiri mwenyewe kiwango cha mjadala ni kazi tata ambayo hivi karibuni ilijikuta makini sana katika uchimbaji wa mijadala. Hata hivyo, jitihada za kutangaza kwa kazi hii ni kubwa zaidi. Kwa hiyo, tunajaribu njia za kujifunza kwa usio na uhakika (AL) za takwimu mbili maarufu za hoja zinazohitimisha kama elimu yenye ufanisi unaweza uwezekano. Utafiti wetu wa kipekee unaonyesha kuwa kazi za kupatikana kwa usio na uhakika hauwezi kupitisha ukweli uliofanywa na upatikanaji wa taarifa hizi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Yüksek kalitede argümanlar karar bermegiň esasy bölegi. Argumentyň kalitesini otomatik çaklamak üçin gaty bir täblikdir. Soňra argüment taýýarlamakda köp üns berilýär. Yöne şu işiň üçin duýdurma çalygy ýok. Şol sebäpli, biz ynamlykdan daşary aktiw öwrenmek (AL) yöntemlerini iki popüler argum güýçli maglumat düzümleriniň örän-täsirli öwrenmek mümkin edip biljegini takyklaýarys. Biziň golaý empirik deňleşmerimiz bu maglumat düzümlerinde gatnaşykly gazanýan fonksiyonlaryň dogrylygyny üstünde tutup bilmeýändigini görkez.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_de>Qualitativ hochwertige Argumente sind ein wesentlicher Bestandteil der Entscheidungsfindung. Die automatische Vorhersage der Qualität eines Arguments ist eine komplexe Aufgabe, die kürzlich im Argument Mining viel Aufmerksamkeit erregte. Der Annotationsaufwand für diese Aufgabe ist jedoch außergewöhnlich hoch. Daher testen wir unsicherheitsbasierte aktive Lernmethoden (AL) an zwei gängigen Argumentstärke-Datensätzen, um abzuschätzen, ob sample-efficient learning aktiviert werden kann. Unsere umfangreiche empirische Auswertung zeigt, dass unsicherheitsbasierte Erfassungsfunktionen die Genauigkeit der Zufallserfassung auf diesen Datensätzen nicht überschreiten können.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_sq>Argumentet e cilësisë së lartë janë një pjesë thelbësore të vendimit. Parashikimi automatik i cilësisë së një argument është një detyrë komplekse që kohët e fundit mori shumë vëmendje në minierën e argumenteve. Megjithatë, përpjekja e anotacionit për këtë detyrë është jashtëzakonisht e lartë. Therefore, we test uncertainty-based active learning (AL) methods on two popular argument-strength data sets to estimate whether sample-efficient learning can be enabled.  Vlerësimi ynë i gjerë empirik tregon se funksionet e blerjes bazuar në pasiguri nuk mund të kapërcejnë saktësinë e arritur me blerjen e rastësishme në këto grupe të dhënash.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>ከፍተኛ ውጤት ክርክሮች የውሳኔ ውሳኔ ናቸው፡፡ የአውራጅ ግንኙነት ውጤትን በመቀበል በአሁኑ ጊዜ ብዙ ትኩረትን በመቀበል የደረሰበት ትክክለኛ ስራ ነው፡፡ ምንም እንኳን ለዚህ ስራ የሚደረገው አካባቢ ትልቅ ነው፡፡ ስለዚህም የምናስፈልገውን የፀሐይ ትምህርት (AL) ሥርዓት በሁለት የሆኑት የአውራሲ-የኃይል ዳታዎችን በመጠቀም ምሳሌ-ፍቃድ ትምህርት መቻለኛ እንዲችል እንደሆነ እናስታውቃለን፡፡ የስፋት ማነሳያ ግንኙነታችን በማይታወቅ በአካባቢው የሥርዓት ግንኙነታችን በዚህ የዳታ ሰርቨሮች ላይ በተደረገው እርግጠኛ ማግኘት አይችልም፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Yüksek kaliteli argumentlər karar verməyin əsas bir parçasıdır. Argumentin keyfiyyətini avtomatik olaraq təxminə etmək müxtəlif bir işdir ki, az öncə Argument qurmasında çox dikkat alırdı. Ancaq bu işin məcburiyyətinin məcburiyyəti çox yüksəkdir. Buna görə də, nümunə-effektiv öyrənmə qabiliyyəti qabiliyyəti qabiliyyəti ilə müəyyən etmək üçün iki məşhur argument-qüvvət verilən dəyişiklik qurunun istifadə etdik. Bizim genişliyimiz empirik değerlendirmələrimiz belə göstərir ki, bu məlumatlar qurduğu istisna qəbul etmə fəaliyyətlərinin istisnadır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_hy>Բավական որակի բանավեճերը որոշումների կայացման կարևոր մասն են: Ավելի բարդ խնդիր է, որը վերջերս շատ ուշադրություն դարձրեց բանավեճերի հանքահանման մեջ: Այնուամենայնիվ, այս խնդրի նկարագրման ջանքը բացառությամբ բարձր է: Այսպիսով, մենք փորձում ենք անորոշությամբ հիմնված ակտիվ ուսումնասիրության (ԱԲ) մեթոդները երկու հայտնի բանավեճի ուժի տվյալների համակարգերի վրա, որպեսզի հաշվարկենք, արդյոք նմուշներ արդյունավետ ուսում Մեր էքսպենսիվ էմպրիկական գնահատումը ցույց է տալիս, որ անորոշությամբ հիմնված գնումների ֆունկցիաները չեն կարող գերազանցել ճշգրտությունը, որը հասել է այս տվյալների համակարգերի պատահական գնումների հետ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_af>Hoog-kwaliteit argumente is 'n nuwe deel van besluit-making. Outomaties voorskou die kwaliteit van 'n argument is 'n kompleks taak wat onlangs baie aandag het in argument mining. Maar, die annotasie versoek vir hierdie taak is uitsonderlik hoog. Daarom, ons probeer onbevestigheid-gebaseerde aktiewe leer (AL) metodes op twee populêre argument-sterkte data stelle om te estimereer of voorbeeld-effektief leer geaktiveer kan word. Ons uitbreidige empiriese evaluering vertoon dat onbevestigheid-gebaseerde akseptasie funksies kan nie oorvloei die presisie wat bereik is met die willekeurige akseptasie op hierdie data stel.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_ca>Els arguments d'alta qualitat són una part essencial de la toma de decisions. Predir automàticament la qualitat d'un argument és una tasca complex a que fa poc va rebre molta atenció en la mineria d'arguments. Però l'esforç d'anotació d'aquesta tasca és excepcionalment alt. Per tant, testem mètodes d'aprenentatge actiu basat en incertituds (AL) en dos conjunts populars de dades d'argument-strength per estimar si es pot activar aprenentatge eficient en mostra. Our extensive empirical evaluation shows that uncertainty-based acquisition functions can not surpass the accuracy reached with the random acquisition on these data sets.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Vysoce kvalitní argumenty jsou nezbytnou součástí rozhodování. Automatické předpovídání kvality argumentu je složitý úkol, který v poslední době získal velkou pozornost při dolování argumentů. Avšak úsilí o anotaci pro tento úkol je mimořádně vysoké. Proto testujeme metody aktivního učení založené na nejistotě na dvou populárních datových sadách argumentů, abychom odhadli, zda lze povolit efektivní učení vzorků. Naše rozsáhlé empirické hodnocení ukazuje, že akviziční funkce založené na nejistotě nemohou překonat přesnost dosaženou náhodným získáváním na těchto datových sadách.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_bn>উচ্চমানের যুক্তি সিদ্ধান্ত নির্ধারণের একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ অংশ। স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে একটি যুক্তির মানের ভবিষ্যদ্বাণী হচ্ছে একটি জটিল কাজ যা সম্প্রতি যুক্তি মিনিটে বেশী মনোযো তবে এই কাজের প্রচেষ্টা ব্যতিক্রমে বেশী উচ্চ। তাই আমরা দুই জনপ্রিয় যুক্তি-শক্তিশালী তথ্যের উপর নিশ্চিতভিত্তিক সক্রিয় শিক্ষা শিক্ষার পদ্ধতি পরীক্ষা করছি যাতে আমরা ধারণা করি নমুনা আমাদের বিস্তৃত ক্ষমতার মূল্য দেখাচ্ছে যে নিশ্চিতভিত্তিক অনুসন্ধানের ক্ষেত্রে এই তথ্য সংক্রান্ত তথ্য পাওয়ার ক্ষেত্রে</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_et>Kvaliteetsed argumendid on otsuste tegemise oluline osa. Argumenti kvaliteedi automaatne prognoosimine on keeruline ülesanne, mis sai hiljuti argumentide kaevandamisel palju tähelepanu. Selle ülesande märgistamise jõupingutused on siiski erakordselt suured. Seetõttu testime ebakindlusel põhinevat aktiivse õppe (AL) meetodeid kahe populaarse argumentide tugevuse andmekogumi põhjal, et hinnata, kas valimitõhusat õppimist on võimalik lubada. Meie ulatuslik empiiriline hindamine näitab, et määramatusel põhinevad omandamise funktsioonid ei saa ületada nende andmekogumite juhusliku omandamise täpsust.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>Argumenti visoke kvalitete su ključni dio donošenja odluka. Automatski predviđanje kvalitete argument a je kompleksan zadatak koji je nedavno dobio mnogo pažnje u rudarstvu argumenta. Međutim, napor za annotaciju ovog zadatka je izuzetno visok. Stoga testiramo metode aktivnog učenja (AL) na temelju nesigurnosti na dva popularna seta podataka snage argumentacija kako bi procijenili može li se omogućiti učenje učinkovitosti uzorka. Naša široka empirička procjena pokazuje da funkcije na osnovu prikupljanja na osnovu nesigurnosti ne mogu preći tačnost ostvarena slučajnim prikupljanjem na ovim podacima.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_fi>Laadukkaat perustelut ovat olennainen osa päätöksentekoa. Argumentin laadun automaattinen ennustaminen on monimutkainen tehtävä, joka on viime aikoina saanut paljon huomiota argumenttien louhintaan. Tähän tehtävään liittyvät huomautukset ovat kuitenkin poikkeuksellisen suuria. Tämän vuoksi testaamme epävarmuuteen perustuvaa aktiivista oppimista kahdella suositulla argumenttivahvuusaineistolla arvioidaksemme, voidaanko otokseen perustuva oppiminen mahdollistaa. Laaja empiirinen arviointimme osoittaa, että epävarmuuteen perustuvat hankintatoiminnot eivät voi ylittää satunnaishankinnalla saavutettua tarkkuutta.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Delokan sawar luwih-kaliwat sing dibenakno ning kebijakan dockable-action politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertive Nanging, kéné ujian seneng pisan-pakan mulai akses nggambar (AL) gambar ditambah populer Awak dhéwé éntuk empirhik sing ngomong nik akeh perusahaan-perusahaan karo pakem gak dhéwé, kuwi mau kuwi kesempatan kanggo ngerasah</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Visokokakovostni argumenti so bistveni del odločanja. Samodejno napovedovanje kakovosti argumenta je kompleksno opravilo, ki je v zadnjem času pridobilo veliko pozornosti pri rudarjenju argumentov. Vendar pa je prizadevanje za opombe za to nalogo izjemno visoko. Zato preizkusimo metode aktivnega učenja na podlagi negotovosti na dveh priljubljenih naborih podatkov o moči argumentov, da ocenimo, ali je mogoče učenje z učinkovitim vzorcem omogočiti. Naša obsežna empirična ocena kaže, da funkcije pridobivanja, ki temeljijo na negotovosti, ne morejo preseči natančnosti, dosežene z naključnim pridobivanjem na teh naborih podatkov.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Argumen da sifawa ya fi girma yana da muhimu rabo ga yin hukunci. @ info: whatsthis A lokacin da, aikin zartar da wannan aikin na sarki. Saboda haka, Munã jarraba hanyõyi masu tsari da aka sani a bakin da ba'a sani ba (AI) a kan data masu jama'a biyu na argument-ƙarfi, dõmin ka ƙaddara ko an iya iya iya karatar da karatun masu amfani da kwamfyuta. Our extensive empirical evaluation shows that uncertainty-based acquisition functions can not surpass the accuracy reached with the random acquisition on these data sets.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>הטיעונים באיכות גבוהה הם חלק חיוני של קיבלת החלטות. חיזוי אוטומטי של איכות טיעון הוא משימה מורכבת שקיבלה לאחרונה תשומת לב רבה במכריית טיעונים. עם זאת, מאמץ הערות למשימה הזאת גבוה באופן יוצא דופן. לכן, אנחנו בודקים שיטות לימוד פעיל מבוססת על אי-בטוחות (AL) על שני קבוצות נתונים פופולריים של כוח טיעון כדי להעריך אם לימוד יעיל בדגימה יכול להיות אפשרי. הערכה האמפרית המורחבת שלנו מראה שמפעילות רכישה מבוססת בלתי בטוחות לא יכולות להתגבר על הדיוקת שנהגעה עם הרישוי האקראי על קבוצות הנתונים האלה.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>High-quality arguments are an essential part of decision-making. Automatically predicting the quality of an argument is a complex task that recently got much attention in argument mining. ཡིན་ནའང་། བྱ་འགུལ་འདིའི་དོན་ལ་གསལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་སྒུལ་ཤུགས་ནི་ཁྱད་དུ་འཕགས་པ་ཞིག་རེད། Therefore, we test uncertainty-based active learning (AL) methods on two popular argument-strength data sets to estimate whether sample-efficient learning can be enabled. ང་ཚོའི་འཛམ་གླིང་གི་empirical evaluation་ནི་གསལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་ལས་འཚོལ་བ་གཞི་རྟེན་ནས་ཉར་ཞིབ་ཀྱི་རྩིས་འབྲེལ་འདི་ཚོའི་གནས་སྟངས་འདི་ཚོར</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>