<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.alvr">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-06-07">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Advances in Language and Vision Research</booktitle>
      <editor><first /><last>Xin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ronghang</first><last>Hu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Drew</first><last>Hudson</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Tsu-Jui</first><last>Fu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Marcus</first><last>Rohrbach</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Daniel</first><last>Fried</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="95670c66">2021.alvr-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="eef9d62d">2021.alvr-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>alvr-2021-advances</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Leveraging Partial Dependency Trees to Control Image Captions</title>
      <author><first>Wenjie</first><last>Zhong</last></author>
      <author><first>Yusuke</first><last>Miyao</last></author>
      <pages>16–21</pages>
      <abstract>Controlling the generation of image captions attracts lots of attention recently. In this paper, we propose a framework leveraging partial syntactic dependency trees as control signals to make image captions include specified words and their syntactic structures. To achieve this purpose, we propose a Syntactic Dependency Structure Aware Model (SDSAM), which explicitly learns to generate the syntactic structures of image captions to include given partial dependency trees. In addition, we come up with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metric</a> to evaluate how many specified words and their syntactic dependencies are included in generated captions. We carry out experiments on two standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> : Microsoft COCO and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flickr">Flickr30k</a>. Empirical results show that image captions generated by our model are effectively controlled in terms of specified words and their syntactic structures. The code is available on GitHub.</abstract>
      <url hash="c9112d4c">2021.alvr-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.alvr-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>zhong-miyao-2021-leveraging</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/flickr30k">Flickr30k</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Grounding Plural Phrases : Countering Evaluation Biases by Individuation</title>
      <author><first>Julia</first><last>Suter</last></author>
      <author><first>Letitia</first><last>Parcalabescu</last></author>
      <author><first>Anette</first><last>Frank</last></author>
      <pages>22–28</pages>
      <abstract>Phrase grounding (PG) is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multimodal_interaction">multimodal task</a> that grounds language in images. PG systems are evaluated on well-known <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benchmark_(computing)">benchmarks</a>, using Intersection over Union (IoU) as evaluation metric. This work highlights a disconcerting bias in the evaluation of grounded plural phrases, which arises from representing sets of objects as a union box covering all component bounding boxes, in conjunction with the IoU metric. We detect, analyze and quantify an evaluation bias in the grounding of plural phrases and define a novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metric</a>, c-IoU, based on a union box’s component boxes. We experimentally show that our new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metric</a> greatly alleviates this bias and recommend using it for fairer evaluation of plural phrases in PG tasks.</abstract>
      <url hash="a92f2c3a">2021.alvr-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.alvr-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>suter-etal-2021-grounding</bibkey>
    <title_es>Fundamentando las frases en plural: contrarrestar los sesgos de evaluación mediante la individuación</title_es>
      <title_pt>Fundamentos de frases plurais: combatendo vieses de avaliação por individuação</title_pt>
      <title_ar>عبارات الجمع الأساسية: مواجهة تحيزات التقييم عن طريق الفردية</title_ar>
      <title_ja>グラウンディングの複数のフレーズ：個別化による評価バイアスの対策</title_ja>
      <title_zh>接地气复数短语:以个性化抗估偏差</title_zh>
      <title_hi>ग्राउंडिंग बहुवचन वाक्यांश: Individuation द्वारा मूल्यांकन पूर्वाग्रहों का मुकाबला करना</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Frásaí Iolra a Thaisceadh: Claonadh Meastóireachta a Chomhrac de réir Aonair</title_ga>
      <title_ka>მრავალური ფრაზები</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Többszörös kifejezések földelése: Az értékelési hibák ellensúlyozása egyénileg</title_hu>
      <title_el>Grounding Plural Phrases: Αντιμετώπιση των προκαταλήψεων αξιολόγησης με την ατομικοποίηση</title_el>
      <title_it>Frasi plurali di messa a terra: contrastare i biasi di valutazione per individualizzazione</title_it>
      <title_kk>Төменгі бірнеше фразлар: Бірлектіру бойынша есептеу үлкендері</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Grounding Plural Phrases: Countering Evaluation Biases by Individuation</title_mk>
      <title_ml>ഗ്രൂഡിങ്ങ് പ്ലാറല്‍ വാക്കുകള്‍: സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യത്തില്‍ എണ്ണുന്നതിന്റെ ബൈസുകള്‍ കണക്കാക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Grounding Plural Phrases: Countering Evaluation Biases by Individuation</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Үндсэн нэмэлт хэлбэрүүд: Хувь хүн төрөлхтний тооцоололтын өсөлт</title_mn>
      <title_no>Grunnleggjande fleire uttrykk: Teljingsverdiar ved individuering</title_no>
      <title_pl>Uziemianie zwrotów wieloralnych: przeciwdziałanie uprzedzeniom oceny poprzez indywiduację</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Expresii multiple de împământare: Contracarea erorilor de evaluare prin individualizare</title_ro>
      <title_lt>Pagrindinės daugialypės frazės</title_lt>
      <title_sr>Pod osnovnim višestrukim frazama: brojanje procjene pojedinaca</title_sr>
      <title_ms>Frasa Plural Grounding: Menghadapi Bias Evaluasi Oleh Individuasi</title_ms>
      <title_so>Heerarka kooxo badan: Heyminta qashinka</title_so>
      <title_sv>Jordning av flerfaldiga fraser: motverka utvärderingssjukdomar genom individuell bedömning</title_sv>
      <title_si>ප්‍රධාන විශේෂය: විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂණය</title_si>
      <title_ur>گرونڈنگ پلرول فریز: گرانڈینگ ارزیابی زیادہ وابستگی کے ذریعہ</title_ur>
      <title_ta>குழுவில் சேர்க்கப்பட்ட சொற்கள்:</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Koò£proq soò£zlar:</title_uz>
      <title_vi>KCharselect unicode block name</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Заземяване на многобройни фрази: противодействие на предразсъдъците за оценка по индивидуализация</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Najvažnije višestruke izraze: brojanje procjene pojedinačnosti</title_hr>
      <title_da>Grundlægning af flere sætninger: Modvirkning af evalueringsfejl ved individuel vurdering</title_da>
      <title_nl>Grounding Plural Phrases: het tegengaan van evaluatievooroordelen door individuatie</title_nl>
      <title_de>Grounding Plural Phrases: Gegenüberstellung von Bewertungsverzerrungen durch Individuation</title_de>
      <title_id>Berdasarkan Frasa Plural: Menghadapi Kesalahan Evaluasi oleh Individuasi</title_id>
      <title_fa>جمله‌های زیادی: افزایش ارزیابی با فرد</title_fa>
      <title_ko>복수 기반 단어: 개성화된 대항 평가를 통해 편견</title_ko>
      <title_af>Grounding Plurale Frase: Telling Evaluering Biases deur Individuasie</title_af>
      <title_am>Grounding Plural Phrases: Countering Evaluation Biases by Individuation</title_am>
      <title_sw>Kundi la Maneno mengine: Kuhesabu Uchunguzi unaotolewa na Uwekezaji</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Adalat köp sanlary:</title_tr>
      <title_hy>Բազմաթիվ արտահայտություններ. հակառակ գնահատման խնդիրները անհատականության կողմից</title_hy>
      <title_az>Bütün çoxlu Frazlar: İnsanlıqların sayısı</title_az>
      <title_bn>গ্রুপিং প্লাগারেল শব্দগুলো: বিভিন্ন পরিসংখ্যানের বায়াস গণনা করছে</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Frases pluralistes fundamentals: Contratar els obstáculos d'evaluació per individu</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Uzemnění plurálních frází: Odstranění předsudků hodnocení individuací</title_cs>
      <title_bs>Najvažnije višestruke izraze: brojanje procjene povećanja po individuaciji</title_bs>
      <title_et>Mitmekordsete fraaside maandamine: hindamise kalduvuste vastu individuatsiooni järgi</title_et>
      <title_fi>Monipuoliset lauseet: Arvioinnin vinoutumien vastainen yksilöinnin mukaan</title_fi>
      <title_sq>Fazat shumëfishe të themeluara: Kundërshtimi i dëmeve të vlerësimit nga individimi</title_sq>
      <title_jv>Global</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>פרסמות רבות מרביעות: נגד הפרעות הערכה על ידי האישיות</title_he>
      <title_sk>Ozemljanje večkratnih fraz: proti pristranskosti ocenjevanja po individuaciji</title_sk>
      <title_bo>རྨང་གཞུང་ཚབ་ཀྱི་ཚིག་བརྗོད།རྩིས་འབྲི་ནི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་ཀྱི་འགྱུར་ལྡན་ཤིག་གི་སྐྱེས་ཚད།</title_bo>
      <abstract_es>La conexión a tierra de frases (PG) es una tarea multimodal que basa el lenguaje en las imágenes. Los sistemas PG se evalúan en puntos de referencia bien conocidos, utilizando Intersección sobre Unión (IoU) como métrica de evaluación. Este trabajo destaca un sesgo desconcertante en la evaluación de frases plurales fundamentadas, que surge de la representación de conjuntos de objetos como una caja de unión que cubre todos los cuadros delimitadores de componentes, junto con la métrica de IoU. Detectamos, analizamos y cuantificamos un sesgo de evaluación en la base de frases plurales y definimos una métrica novedosa, c-IOU, basada en las cajas de componentes de una caja de unión. Demostramos experimentalmente que nuestra nueva métrica alivia en gran medida este sesgo y recomendamos usarla para una evaluación más justa de las frases en plural en las tareas de PG.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Phrase grounding (PG) é uma tarefa multimodal que fundamenta a linguagem em imagens. Os sistemas PG são avaliados em benchmarks bem conhecidos, usando Intersection over Union (IoU) como métrica de avaliação. Este trabalho destaca um viés desconcertante na avaliação de frases plurais fundamentadas, que surge da representação de conjuntos de objetos como uma caixa de união cobrindo todas as caixas delimitadoras de componentes, em conjunto com a métrica IoU. Detectamos, analisamos e quantificamos um viés de avaliação na fundamentação de frases plurais e definimos uma nova métrica, c-IoU, com base nas caixas componentes de uma caixa de união. Mostramos experimentalmente que nossa nova métrica alivia bastante esse viés e recomendamos usá-la para uma avaliação mais justa de frases no plural em tarefas de PG.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>تأريض العبارة (PG) هي مهمة متعددة الوسائط تؤسس اللغة في الصور. يتم تقييم أنظمة PG وفقًا لمعايير معروفة ، باستخدام Intersection over Union (IoU) كمقياس للتقييم. يسلط هذا العمل الضوء على التحيز المثير للقلق في تقييم عبارات الجمع المؤرضة ، والذي ينشأ من تمثيل مجموعات من الكائنات كمربع اتحاد يغطي جميع المربعات المحيطة بالمكون ، بالاقتران مع مقياس IoU. نحن نكتشف ونحلل ونحدد كميًا تحيز التقييم في تأريض عبارات الجمع ونحدد مقياسًا جديدًا ، c-IoU ، استنادًا إلى مربعات مكونات صندوق الاتحاد. لقد أظهرنا بشكل تجريبي أن مقياسنا الجديد يخفف إلى حد كبير هذا التحيز ونوصي باستخدامه لإجراء تقييم أكثر إنصافًا لعبارات الجمع في مهام PG.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_zh>短语接地(PG)者,多模样之务,所以立于图像之基也。 PG统于众所周知准试上为评估,以交集(IoU)为指标。 显于评估接地复数短语令人不安之偏见,盖以所集为覆组件界框之合框及IoU指标所生也。 臣等检量,量化复数短语接地中评估偏差,并据合框组件框定义一新指标c-IoU。 吾实验以明之,吾新指标大纾其差,而议用之以平PG复数短语。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ja>フレーズ接地（ PG ）は、言語を画像に基礎づけるマルチモーダルタスクです。PGシステムは、評価指標としてIntersection over Union (IoU)を使用して、周知のベンチマークで評価されます。この研究は、接地された複数のフレーズの評価における不安定なバイアスを強調しています。これは、IoUメトリックと併せて、すべてのコンポーネント境界ボックスをカバーするユニオンボックスとしてオブジェクトのセットを表現することから生じます。私たちは、複数のフレーズの接地における評価バイアスを検出、分析、定量化し、ユニオンボックスのコンポーネントボックスに基づいて新規のメトリックであるc - IoUを定義します。新しい指標がこのバイアスを大幅に軽減することを実験的に示し、PGタスクで複数のフレーズをより公正に評価するために使用することをお勧めします。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>वाक्यांश ग्राउंडिंग (पीजी) एक बहुआयामी कार्य है जो छवियों में भाषा को आधार बनाता है। पीजी सिस्टम का मूल्यांकन अच्छी तरह से ज्ञात बेंचमार्क पर किया जाता है, मूल्यांकन मीट्रिक के रूप में यूनियन (आईओयू) पर चौराहे का उपयोग करके। यह काम ग्राउंडेड बहुवचन वाक्यांशों के मूल्यांकन में एक निराशाजनक पूर्वाग्रह पर प्रकाश डालता है, जो आईओयू मीट्रिक के साथ संयोजन के रूप में सभी घटक बाउंडिंग बक्से को कवर करने वाले यूनियन बॉक्स के रूप में वस्तुओं के सेट का प्रतिनिधित्व करने से उत्पन्न होता है। हम बहुवचन वाक्यांशों के ग्राउंडिंग में एक मूल्यांकन पूर्वाग्रह का पता लगाते हैं, विश्लेषण करते हैं और मात्रा निर्धारित करते हैं और एक संघ बॉक्स के घटक बक्से के आधार पर एक उपन्यास मीट्रिक, सी-आईओयू को परिभाषित करते हैं। हम प्रयोगात्मक रूप से दिखाते हैं कि हमारा नया मीट्रिक इस पूर्वाग्रह को बहुत कम करता है और पीजी कार्यों में बहुवचन वाक्यांशों के निष्पक्ष मूल्यांकन के लिए इसका उपयोग करने की सलाह देता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Is tasc ilmhódach é bunús frásaí (PG) a fhorálann teanga in íomhánna. Déantar córais PG a mheas ar thagarmharcanna aitheanta, ag baint úsáide as Intersection over Union (IoU) mar mhéadracht meastóireachta. Leagann an obair seo béim ar chlaonadh neamhchonspóideach sa mheastóireacht ar fhrásaí iolra bunaithe, a eascraíonn as tacair réad a léiriú mar bhosca aontais a chlúdaíonn gach bosca teorannaithe comhpháirte, i gcomhar leis an méadrach IoU. Brathaimid, déanaimid anailís agus cainníochtúil ar chlaonadh meastóireachta i mbunús frásaí iolra agus sainímid méadrach nua, c-IoU, bunaithe ar bhoscaí comhpháirte an bhosca aontais. Léirímid go turgnamhach go maolaíonn ár méadrach nua an claonadh seo go mór agus molaimid é a úsáid chun frásaí iolra i dtascanna PG a mheas níos cothroime.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η γείωση φράσεων (PG) είναι μια πολυμορφική εργασία που θεμελιώνει τη γλώσσα σε εικόνες. Τα συστήματα ΠΓ αξιολογούνται βάσει γνωστών κριτηρίων αναφοράς, χρησιμοποιώντας ως μετρική αξιολόγηση τη διατομή πάνω από την Ένωση. Η παρούσα εργασία υπογραμμίζει μια ανησυχητική προκατάληψη στην αξιολόγηση των θεμελιωμένων πληθυντικών φράσεων, η οποία προκύπτει από την αναπαράσταση συνόλων αντικειμένων ως ενωσιακού πλαισίου που καλύπτει όλα τα οριακά πλαίσια συστατικών, σε συνδυασμό με τη μετρική. Εντοπίζουμε, αναλύουμε και ποσοτικοποιούμε μια προκατάληψη αξιολόγησης στη γείωση των πληθυντικών φράσεων και καθορίζουμε μια νέα μετρική, βασισμένη στα συστατικά κουτιά ενός ενωσιακού κουτιού. Δείχνουμε πειραματικά ότι η νέα μας μέτρηση μετριάζει σημαντικά αυτή την προκατάληψη και συστήνουμε τη χρήση της για πιο δίκαιη αξιολόγηση των πληθυντικών φράσεων σε εργασίες ΠΓ.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A kifejezések földelése (PG) egy multimodális feladat, amely a nyelvet a képekbe alapozza. A PG-rendszerek értékelése jól ismert referenciaértékek alapján történik, az Intersection over Union (IoU) mint értékelési metrika alkalmazásával. Ez a munka a földelt többszámú kifejezések értékelésében megdöbbentő elfogultságot mutat ki, amely abból ered, hogy az objektumhalmazokat egy uniós dobozként ábrázolja, amely az összes komponens határolódobozát lefedi, az IoU metriával együtt. Észleljük, elemezzük és számszerűsítjük az értékelési elfogultságot a többszámú kifejezések alapozásában, és definiálunk egy új metrikát, c-IoU-t egy uniós doboz komponensei alapján. Kísérleti módon megmutatjuk, hogy az új metrika nagymértékben enyhíti ezt az elfogultságot, és azt javasoljuk, hogy használja a PG feladatok többszámú kifejezéseinek tisztességesebb értékeléséhez.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ფრაზის დაფერები (PG) არის მულტიმოდიალური რაოდენობა, რომელიც გამოსახულებში ენის ფონტურაცია. PG სისტემები ძალიან უცნობილი ბენქმარკებით გამოიყენება, როგორც ინტერსექციონის მეტრიკის გამოყენება სამყაროს (IoU). ეს სამუშაო ახალგაზრდება, რომელიც ახალგაზრდება სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო ფრაზების განსაზღვრებაში, რომელიც იქნება სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშა ჩვენ განვიცნობით, ანალიზებით და კვანტაქტირებთ მრავალური ფრაზების ფონტაქტის ფონტაქტის ფონტაქტის ფონტაქტის ფონტაქტის ფონტაქტის ფონტაქტის ფონტაქტის ფონტაქტის ფ ჩვენ ექსპერიმენტიურად გამოჩვენებთ, რომ ჩვენი ახალი მეტრიკი ძალიან გამოყენებს ეს წარმოდგენება და ამას უფრო მარტივია გამოყენება მრავალური ფრაზების გაუმუშაობის</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_kk>Суреттердің түсіндіру (PG) көп модельді тапсырмасы кескіндерде тілді түсіндіреді. PG жүйелері мәліметтер ретінде білетін бағдарламалар бойынша, Union (IoU) жүйесінің интерфейсін қолдану метрикалық ретінде тең алады. Бұл жұмыс IoU метрикалық компоненттердің шектеу өрістерін біріктіру керек нысандардың біріктіру өрістерінен біріктірілген біріктіру өрістерін шектеу өрістерін шектеу үшін бұл көмегімен белсендіруді бояулады. Біз көпшілікті сөздерді зерттеу, анализ және саналдыру керектігін анықтап, біріктіру өрісінің компоненттер өрісіне негізделген романдық метрикалық, c- IoU- ды анықтаймыз. Біз тәжірибеде жаңа метрикалық бұл тәжірибесін көтеріп, PG тапсырмаларындағы көптеген сөздерді дұрыс оқу үшін қолдануға болады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Frazės pagrindimas (PG) yra daugiarūšio pobūdžio užduotis, kuria grindžiama kalba vaizduose. PG sistemos vertinamos pagal gerai žinomus lyginamuosius rodiklius, naudojant sąsają su Sąjunga (IoU) kaip vertinimo metriją. Šiame darbe pabrėžiama nerimą kelianti pusiausvyra vertinant grindžiamas daugiašales frazes, atsirandanti dėl objektų rinkinių reprezentavimo kaip sąjungos langelio, apimančio visus komponentų ribojimo langelius, kartu su IoU metriku. Nustatome, analizuojame ir kiekybiškai vertiname vertinimo pusiausvyrą daugialypių frazių pagrindu ir apibrėžiame naują metrinį, c-IoU, pagrįstą s ąjungos dėžutės komponentais. Eksperimentiškai parodome, kad mūsų nauja metrija labai palengvina šią pusiausvyrą ir rekomenduojame ją naudoti sąžiningesniam daugialypių frazių PG užduočių vertinimui.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>La messa a terra delle frasi (PG) è un compito multimodale che fonda il linguaggio nelle immagini. I sistemi PG sono valutati su parametri di riferimento ben noti, utilizzando Intersection over Union (IoU) come metrica di valutazione. Questo lavoro evidenzia una distorsione sconcertante nella valutazione delle frasi plurale a terra, che deriva dalla rappresentazione di insiemi di oggetti come una scatola di unione che copre tutte le caselle di confine dei componenti, in combinazione con la metrica IoU. Rilevamo, analizziamo e quantificamo un bias di valutazione nella messa a terra delle frasi plurale e definiamo una metrica nuova, c-IoU, basata sulle scatole componenti di una scatola di unione. Mostriamo sperimentalmente che la nostra nuova metrica allevia notevolmente questo bias e raccomandiamo di usarlo per una valutazione più equa delle frasi plurale nelle attività PG.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Градењето на фразите (PG) е мултимодилна задача која го основа јазикот во сликите. ПГ системите се проценуваат на добро познати споредби, користејќи го Интерсекционот над Унијата (ЈУ) како проценка метрика. Оваа работа ја истакнува вознемирувачката пристрасност во проценката на основаните мнозински фрази, која се појавува од претставувањето на сетови на објекти како кутија за унија која ги покрива сите гранични кутии на компонентите, заедно со метриката IoU. We detect, analyze and quantify an evaluation bias in the grounding of plural phrases and define a novel metric, c-IoU, based on a union box's component boxes.  Експериментално покажуваме дека нашата нова метрика значително го олеснува ова предрасудување и препорачуваме да се користи за пофер проценка на мнозинските фрази во PG задачите.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Pemasangan frasa (PG) adalah tugas multimodal yang mengasaskan bahasa dalam imej. PG systems are evaluated on well-known benchmarks, using Intersection over Union (IoU) as evaluation metric.  Kerja ini menyatakan bias yang mengganggu dalam penilaian frasa berbilang berdasar, yang muncul dari mewakili set objek sebagai kotak kesatuan yang meliputi semua kotak pembatasan komponen, bersama dengan metrik IoU. Kami mengesan, menganalisis dan kuantifikasikan bias penilaian dalam dasar frasa berbilang dan takrifkan metrik novel, c-IoU, berdasarkan kotak komponen kotak persatuan. Kami secara eksperimen menunjukkan bahawa metrik baru kami sangat mengurangkan bias ini dan menyarankan menggunakannya untuk penilaian yang lebih adil frasa-frasa dalam tugas PG.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>L-grounding tal-frażi (PG) huwa kompitu multimodali li jibbaża l-lingwa fl-immaġni. Is-sistemi tal-PG huma evalwati fuq punti ta’ riferiment magħrufa sew, bl-użu tal-Intersezzjoni fuq l-Unjoni (IoU) bħala metrika ta’ evalwazzjoni. Dan ix-xogħol jenfasizza preġudizzju inkoncertanti fl-evalwazzjoni ta’ frażijiet plurali bbażati fuq l-art, li jirriżulta mir-rappreżentazzjoni ta’ settijiet ta’ oġġetti bħala kaxxa tal-unjoni li tkopri l-kaxxi tal-konfini kollha tal-komponenti, flimkien mal-metrika IoU. Aħna nidentifikaw, janalizzaw u kkwantifikaw preġudizzju ta’ evalwazzjoni fl-għeruq ta’ frażijiet plurali u niddefinixxu metrika ġdida, c-IoU, ibbażata fuq kaxxi komponenti ta’ kaxxa tal-unjoni. Aħna nuru b’mod sperimentali li l-metrika l-ġdida tagħna tnaqqas ħafna dan il-preġudizzju u nirrakkomandawha għall-evalwazzjoni aktar ġusta tal-frażijiet plurali fil-kompiti tal-PG.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Хүснэгтийн суурь (PG) бол зурагт хэлэг үндсэн олон загвар юм. PG систем нь тодорхойлолтын метрик хэлбэрээр тодорхойлогдож байдаг. Энэ ажиллагаар олон хэлбэрүүдийн дүгнэлтийн тухайд бүх компонентын хязгаарлалтын хайрцаг, IoU метрикийн холбоотой бүх хэлбэрүүдийн хайрцаг гэх хайрцаг болж буй объектуудыг нэг хайрцаг гэж үзүүлэхээс илэрхийлж буй зайлсхий Бид олон хэлбэрүүдийг суурилуулж, үнэлгээ судалж, хэмжээгээр тодорхойлж, холбоотой хайрцаг хайрцаг дээр суурилсан соёл метрик, c-IoU-г тодорхойлж байна. Бид туршилтын хувьд шинэ метрик нь энэ өрөөсгөлийг маш багасгаж, PG ажиллагаанд олон хэлбэрүүдийг илүү шударга дүгнэхэд ашиглаж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ml>ചിത്രങ്ങളില്‍ ഭാഷ ക്രമീകരിക്കുന്ന വാക്കുകളുടെ ഗ്രൂണ്‍ടി (പിജി) ഒരു പലിമോഡല്‍ ജോലിയാണ്. പിജി സിസ്റ്റത്തെ പരിചയപ്പെട്ട ബെന്‍മാര്‍ക്കുകളില്‍ വിലാസപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു. യൂണിയനിലെ ഇന്റര്‍സെക്ഷന്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ച് യ ഈ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിക്കുന്നത് ഭൂമിയിലുള്ള പല വാക്കുകളുടെ വിലാസങ്ങളുടെ വിലാസത്തിന്റെ നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കുന്നതില്‍ നിന്നും അസംബന്ധിച്ചിടത്തോളം ഒരു യൂണിയന്‍ ബോക്സ്  പൂര്‍ണ്ണവാക്കുകളുടെ കൂട്ടത്തില്‍ ഒരു വിലാസങ്ങള്‍ നാം കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുകയും, പരിശോധിക്കുകയും, നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കുകയും, ഒരു യൂണിയന്‍ പെട്ടിയുടെ പെട്ടികള്‍ അടിസ്ഥ ഞങ്ങള്‍ പരീക്ഷണത്തില്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു നമ്മുടെ പുതിയ മെട്രിക്ക് ഈ പ്രശ്നത്തെ വളരെ ലളിതമാക്കുന്നു പിജിയുടെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങളില്‍</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_pl>Uziemienie fraz (PG) jest zadaniem multimodalnym, które uziemia język w obrazach. Systemy PG oceniane są na podstawie znanych wskaźników referencyjnych, wykorzystując jako wskaźnik oceny Intersection over Union (IoU). W niniejszej pracy podkreślono niepokojącą stronniczość w ocenie uziemionych zwrotów liczby mnogiej, która wynika z reprezentowania zestawów obiektów jako pudełka unijnego obejmującego wszystkie składniki graniczące, w połączeniu z metryką IoU. Wykrywamy, analizujemy i ilościowo stronnicze oceny w uziemieniu zwrotów mnogich i definiujemy nową metrykę, c-IoU, opartą na skrzynkach składowych skrzynki unijnej. Eksperymentalnie pokazujemy, że nasza nowa metryka znacznie łagodzi tę stronniczość i zalecamy stosowanie jej do sprawiedliwszej oceny zwrotów mnogich w zadaniach PG.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Frasergrunnlegging (PG) er ein multimodal oppgåve som bakgrunner språk i bilete. PG- systemet blir evaluert på godt kjende benchmarker ved bruk av Interseksjon over Union (IoU) som evalueringsmetrisk. Dette arbeidet markerer ein avkortingsfarge i evalueringa av bakgrunnsfarge fleire frasar, som oppstår frå å representeringa av sett av objekt som eit union- boks som dekkar alle komponente grenseboksar saman med IoU- metrikken. Vi oppdager, analyser og kvantifiserer ein evalueringsforsikt i grunnlegginga av fleire frasar og definerer ein novel metrisk, c- IoU, basert på komponentboksane for ein union- boks. Vi viser eksperimentelt at det nye metriske vårt gjer stort å redusere denne forsvinninga og anbefaler å bruka det for rettere evaluering av fleire frasar i PG-oppgåver.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Fraza osnova (PG) je multimodalni zadatak koji osnova jezik na slikama. PG sistemi se procjenjuju na poznatim kriterijama, koristeći Intersekciju preko Unije (IoU) kao metričku procjenu. Ovaj rad naglašava nepristojnu pristrasnost u procjeni osnovanih pluralnih fraza, koji se pojavljuje od predstavljanja seta objekata kao kutija unije koja pokriva sve kutije za ograničenje komponenta, zajedno sa IoU metrikom. Otkrivamo, analiziramo i kvantificiramo predrasude za procjenu na osnovu pluralnih fraza i definiramo novu metriku, c-IoU, baziranu na kutijama komponentnih kutija sindikata. Eksperimentalno pokazujemo da naša nova metrika veoma smanjuje ovu predrasude i preporučuje ga koristiti za fer procjenu pluralnih fraza u PG zadatkima.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ro>Împământarea frazelor (PG) este o sarcină multimodală care bazează limbajul în imagini. Sistemele PG sunt evaluate pe criterii de referință bine cunoscute, utilizând Intersecțiune peste Uniune (IOU) ca metrică de evaluare. Această lucrare evidențiază o părtinire tulburătoare în evaluarea frazelor plurale împământate, care rezultă din reprezentarea seturilor de obiecte ca o cutie de uniune care acoperă toate casetele de limitare a componentelor, în combinație cu metrica IoU. Detectăm, analizăm și cuantificăm o părtinire de evaluare în baza frazelor plurale și definim o metrică nouă, c-IoU, bazată pe casetele componente ale unei cutii de uniune. Noi arătăm experimental că noua noastră metrică atenuează foarte mult această părtinire și recomandăm utilizarea acesteia pentru o evaluare mai corectă a frazelor plurale în sarcinile PG.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>පින්තූරයේ භාෂාව පිළිබඳින් භාෂාව පිළිබඳින්න බොහොමෝඩාල් වැඩක්. Name මේ වැඩේ ප්‍රතිශීල විශ්වාසයෙන් ප්‍රතිශීල විශ්වාසයෙන් ප්‍රතිශීල කරනවා, මෙයා ඔක්කොම සම්පූර්ණය බොක්ස් වල සංවිධානය බොක්ස් වල සිර අපි හොයාගන්න, විශ්ලේෂණය කරන්න, විශේෂණය කරන්න සහ ක්‍රියාත්මක කරන්න, විශ්ලේෂණය කරන්න, විශේෂණය කරන්න, විශේෂණය කරන්න, විශේෂණය පැත්ත අපි පරීක්ෂණයෙන් පෙන්වන්නේ අපේ අලුත් මෙට්‍රික් ගොඩක් විශේෂයෙන් මේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් අඩු කරනවා කියලා ඒක ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න PG</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Phrase Grounding (PG) är en multimodal uppgift som grundar språk i bilder. PG-system utvärderas på välkända riktmärken, med hjälp av Intersection over Union (IoU) som utvärderingsmått. Detta arbete belyser en förvirrande bias i utvärderingen av jordade pluralfraser, som uppstår genom att representera uppsättningar av objekt som en union box som täcker alla komponentgränser, i kombination med IoU-metrin. Vi detekterar, analyserar och kvantifierar en utvärderingsskapande i grunden av flertalsfraser och definierar en ny metrik, c-IoU, baserad på en fackbox komponentboxar. Vi visar experimentellt att vårt nya mått avsevärt lindrar denna bias och rekommenderar att du använder det för en rättvisare utvärdering av pluralfraser i PG-uppgifter.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalka rasmiga (PG) waa shaqo badan oo ku saleysan luqada sawirada. Tirada PG waxaa lagu qiimeeyaa meelaha lagu aqoonsan yahay, waxaana lagu isticmaalaa Intersection over Midowga (IoU) sida qiimeynta. Shaqodanku wuxuu ka muuqanayaa qiimeynta hadallada rasmiga ah oo lagu qoray, kaas oo ka soo baxa mid ka mid ah mid ka mid ah alaabta midowga ah oo ku qarinaya dhamaan kooxo boxeedka ku qoran karta IoU. Waxaynu ogaanaynaa, baaritaannaa, baaritaanka qiimeynta oo ku qoran hadallada kala duduwan, waxaana ku sawirannaa metric c-IoU oo ku saleysan karta boxeedka isku xiran. We experimentally show that our new metric greatly alleviates this bias and recommend using it for fairer evaluation of plural phrases in PG tasks.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ur>Phrase grounding (PG) ایک multimodal task ہے جس نے تصاویروں میں زبان پاؤں رکھی ہے. پی جی سیسٹم کو خوب معلوم بنچم مارک پر مطالعہ کیا جاتا ہے، یونیون (یویو) کے ذریعے انٹرسکٹ کے مطالعہ سے مطالعہ میٹریک کے طور پر استعمال کیا جاتا ہے. یہ کام آئوئو متریک کے ساتھ تمام قسمتوں کے بانڈ بوکس کو پورے پورے پورے کنٹ بوکس کے ساتھ آئوئو کے ساتھ آئوئن کے سٹوں کو دکھانے سے آئوئن بوکس کے طور پر نازل کرتا ہے. ہم نے بہت سی فریزوں کی بنیادی میں ایک ارزیابی غرض کو پہچان لیا، تحلیل اور مقدار کرلیا اور ایک نوم میٹریک، سی-یو، ایک یونیون بوکس کی رشتہ بوکس پر بنیاد رکھا ہے. ہم آزمائش کے طور پر دکھاتے ہیں کہ ہماری نوی میٹریک نے اس بحث کو بہت کمزور کر دیا ہے اور اس کا استعمال کرنا PG کے کاموں میں بہت سی بحث کا ارزش کرنا ہے</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>சொற்றொடர் குழு (PG) பிம்பங்களில் மொழியை அடிப்படையாக்கும் பல வேலையாகும். பிஜி முறைமைகள் நன்றாக அறியப்பட்ட benchmarks யில் மதிப்பிடப்படுகிறது, யூனியன் மேல் இடைவெளியீடு (IoU) மேல் மதிப்பிடும் மெட்ர இந்த வேலை நிலையில் உள்ள பல்வேறு சொற்களை மதிப்பில் குறிப்பிடும் பொருட்களை குறிப்பிடும் ஒரு union பெட்டியிலிருந்து வரும், IoU மெட்ரிக்குடன் இணைக்கும் அனை ஒரு யூனியன் பெட்டியின் பெட்டி We experimentally show that our new metric greatly alleviates this bias and recommend using it for fairer evaluation of plural phrases in PG tasks.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Name @ info Bu ishni ajratilgan bir qatlam so'zlarni qiymatlashni anglatadi. Bu bir bir narsa narsalarni birlashtirishda, IoU metrikida hamma komponentlarni birlashtirish quyidagi bir bir bir qismi bo'lgan bir qismlarni ko'rsatadi. Biz bir necha so'zlar guruhida qiymatni aniqlab, aniqlash va qiymatni aniqlash va union qutisining qiymatlari qutisini asosida yangi metrik c-IoU aniqlash. Biz tajriba qilamiz, yangi metrikiz buni juda ko'paytirishni ko'rganamiz va bizni PG vazifalarida ko'plab bir so'zlarni qiymatish uchun ishlatishni talab qilamiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Đoạn ẩn (PG) là một nhiệm vụ đa phương để tạo nên ngôn ngữ trong ảnh. Hệ thống PG được đánh giá dựa trên những tiêu chuẩn nổi tiếng, dùng Intersection over Union (IoU) làm hệ thống đo lường. Việc này làm nổi bật một khuynh hướng rối loạn trong việc đánh giá các cụm từ đa dạng giáo, xuất phát từ việc đại diện các bộ vật thể như một cái hộp liên kết bao gồm tất cả các hộp đựng các thành phần, kết hợp với dữ liệu nhị phân. Chúng tôi phát hiện, phân tích và định lượng thiên kiến đánh giá từ nhiều c ụm từ... và xác định một s ố mét mới, c-Iou, dựa trên các hộp thành phần của một hộp liên hợp. Chúng tôi thí nghiệm cho thấy hệ thống đo lường mới của chúng tôi giúp giảm bớt ưu thế này và khuyên sử dụng nó để đánh giá đúng số nhiều từ trong các nhiệm vụ PG.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_da>Sætningsgrundning (PG) er en multimodal opgave, der baserer sprog i billeder. PG-systemer evalueres på kendte benchmarks ved hjælp af Intersection over Union (IoU) som evalueringsmetric. Dette arbejde fremhæver en foruroligende skævhed i evalueringen af jordbaserede flertalssætninger, som opstår ved at repræsentere sæt af objekter som en union boks, der dækker alle komponentgrænsefelter, sammen med IoU-metrikken. Vi opdager, analyserer og kvantificerer en evalueringsskævhed i grundlæggelsen af flertalssætninger og definerer en ny metric, c-IoU, baseret på en union bokss komponentbokse. Vi viser eksperimentelt, at vores nye metric i høj grad lindrer denne bias og anbefaler at bruge det til en mere retfærdig evaluering af flertalssætninger i PG-opgaver.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Phrase aarding (PG) is een multimodale taak die taal in afbeeldingen grondt. PG-systemen worden geëvalueerd op basis van bekende benchmarks, met behulp van Intersection over Union (IoU) als evaluatiemetric. Dit werk benadrukt een verontrustende vooringenomenheid in de evaluatie van geaard meervoud zinnen, die voortkomt uit het weergeven van verzamelingen van objecten als een uniekast die alle componenten begrenzende vakken bestrijkt, in combinatie met de IoU metric. We detecteren, analyseren en kwantificeren een evaluatiebias in de grondslag van meervoud zinnen en definiëren een nieuwe metric, c-IoU, gebaseerd op de componentdozen van een uniebox. We laten experimenteel zien dat onze nieuwe metric deze bias sterk verlicht en raden aan om het te gebruiken voor een eerlijkere evaluatie van meervoud zinnen in PG taken.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Заземяването на фразите (ПГ) е мултимодална задача, която основава езика в изображенията. Системите за ПГ се оценяват въз основа на добре известни показатели, като като измервателен показател се използва Интерсеction over Union (IoU). Тази работа подчертава обезпокоително отклонение при оценката на обосновани множествени фрази, които възникват от представянето на множество обекти като обединителна кутия, покриваща всички компоненти ограничителни кутии, във връзка с метриката. Ние откриваме, анализираме и количествено определяме отклонения в оценката при заземяването на множествени фрази и дефинираме нов метрик, базиран на компонентните кутии на обединителната кутия. Експериментално показваме, че нашият нов показател значително облекчава това отклонение и препоръчваме използването му за по-справедлива оценка на множествените фрази в задачите на ПГ.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Primjena fraze (PG) je multimodalni zadatak koji temelji jezik na slikama. PG sustavi se procjenjuju na poznatim kriterijama, koristeći Intersection preko Unije (IoU) kao metričku procjenu. Ovaj rad ukazuje na prekršavajuće pristrasnosti u procjeni osnovanih pluralnih fraza, koji se pojavljuje od predstavljanja seta objekata kao kutija za sindikat koja pokriva sve kutije granica komponenta, zajedno s metrikom IoU. Otkrivamo, analiziramo i kvantificiramo predrasude za procjenu na osnovu pluralnih fraza i definiramo novu metričku, c-IoU-u, temeljenu na kutiji komponentnih kutija sindikata. Eksperimentalno pokazujemo da naša nova metrika veoma smanjuje tu pristrasnost i preporučuje ga koristiti za ispravniju procjenu pluralnih fraza u PG zadatkima.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Phrase Grounding (PG) ist eine multimodale Aufgabe, die Sprache in Bildern gründet. PG-Systeme werden anhand bekannter Benchmarks bewertet, wobei Intersection over Union (IoU) als Bewertungsmetrik verwendet wird. Diese Arbeit hebt eine beunruhigende Verzerrung bei der Bewertung von geerdeten Pluralphrasen hervor, die sich aus der Darstellung von Objektsätzen als Union-Box ergibt, die alle Komponenten-Bounding-Boxen abdeckt, in Verbindung mit der IoU-Metrik. Wir erkennen, analysieren und quantifizieren einen Bewertungsbias in der Erdung von Pluralphrasen und definieren eine neue Metrik, c-IoU, basierend auf den Komponentenboxen einer Union Box. Wir zeigen experimentell, dass unsere neue Metrik diese Verzerrung stark lindert und empfehlen, sie für eine gerechtere Bewertung von Pluralphrasen in PG-Aufgaben zu verwenden.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>구 접지(PG)는 언어를 이미지에 배치하는 다중모드 작업입니다.PG시스템은 유명한 기준에서 평가를 하고 연합교집(IoU)을 평가 지표로 사용한다.이 작업은 고정 복수 단어를 평가할 때 불안한 편차를 강조한다. 이것은 대상 집합을 모든 구성 요소의 경계 상자를 포함하는 병렬 상자로 표시하고 IoU 도량을 결합시켜 발생한 것이다.우리는 복수 단어의 기초에서 평가 편차를 검측하고 분석하며, 콤보 상자의 구성 요소 상자를 바탕으로 새로운 도량, c-IoU를 정의합니다.우리의 실험은 우리의 새로운 지표가 이러한 편견을 크게 경감시켰다는 것을 보여 주었고, 이를 사용하여 PG 임무의 복수 단어를 더욱 공평하게 평가할 것을 건의했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>زمینۀ عبارت (PG) یک کار بسیار متحده است که زبان را در تصاویر پایه می‌دهد. سیستم‌های PG به عنوان متریک ارزیابی با استفاده از قطعه‌ای در اتحادیه (IoU) بر روی برچسب‌های شناخته شده ارزیابی می‌شوند. این کار یک تغییر ناپذیر در ارزیابی جمله‌های بسیاری زیر پایه را نشان می‌دهد که از نمایش مجموعه‌های شیء به عنوان یک جعبه اتحادیه که تمام جعبه‌های محدوده‌ای را پوشش می‌دهد، در کنار متریک یو است. ما تشخیص، تحلیل و مقدار ارزیابی را در زمینه‌های عبارت‌های زیادی شناسایی می‌کنیم و یک مقدار متریک C-IoU روشن می‌کنیم، بر اساس جعبه‌های بخش‌های جعبه اتحادیه. ما به طور آزمایشی نشان می دهیم که متریک جدید ما این قضیه را بسیار کم می کند و از آن برای ارزیابی عدل‌تر از جمله‌های متعدد در کار PG پیشنهاد می‌دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Kundi la maneno (PG) ni kazi ya kidunia inayotumia lugha katika picha. Mfumo wa PG unapitiwa kwenye benchmark maarufu, kwa kutumia Intersection over Union (IoU) kama njia ya uchunguzi. Kazi hii inaonyesha upendeleo wa kusikitisha katika tathmini ya maneno mengi yaliyozinduliwa, ambayo yanatokana na kuwakilisha vitu kama sanduku la muungano unaoandika vifaa vyote vinavyozungumzia boksi, pamoja na miti ya IoU. Tunagundua, uchambuzi na kuhakikisha upendeleo wa uchunguzi katika msingi wa maneno mengi na kuelezea mtiririko wa riwaya, c-IoU, kwa kutumia vifaa vya vifaa vya ushirikiano. Tunaonyesha kwa majaribio kwamba mtindo wetu mpya unapunguza upendeleo huu na kupendekeza kutumia matumizi yake kwa ajili ya kutathmini maneno mengi katika kazi za PG.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Resimlerde ýerleşýän bir multimodal täblikdir. PG sistemleri bilýän kalamlarda deňlenýär. Uniýa (IoU) arasyndaky Interkesiýa metriýa görkezilýär. Bu işe yer alan plural frazlerin değerlendirmesinde bozgunç bir suçsuzluğu ýagtylaýar. Bu, IoU metrik ile birlikte bütün komponent çubuklarını ören bir birlik kutu olarak gelen nesneleri temizlemekten geler. Biz plural frazlerin arkasynda değerlenme virgülini detektip, analiz edip, çözümleme virgülini analiz edip, bir birlik kutusunun komponent kutularına dayanan bir roman metrik, c-IoU'yu tanımlarız. Biz deneysel olarak yeni metrimizin bu bias ını daha az azalttığını ve PG görevlerinde plural frazlerin düzgün değerlendirmesini tavsiye ediyoruz.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Frase agtergrond (PG) is 'n multimodaal taak wat agtergrond taal in beelde. Pg stelsels word geevalueer op goed bekend benchmarke, gebruik Interseksie oor Unie (IoU) as evaluering metriek. Hierdie werk verlig 'n afsonderde bias in die evaluering van agtergrond plurale frase, wat opkom van voorstel stelle van objekte as 'n union boks wat oordek alle komponente grense bokse, in saam met die IoU metrie. Ons ontdek, analyseer en quantifiseer 'n evaluasie voorspoedige in die grond van plurale frase en definieer 'n roman metrie, c- IoU, gebaseer op 'n union boks se komponent bokse. Ons eksperimenteel wys dat ons nuwe metrie baie verklein hierdie voorbeeld en aanbeveel dit gebruik vir egter evaluering van plurale frase in PG-taak.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>የፊደል ቅርጽ ምርጫዎች በዩኒቨርስቲ (IoU) በተጠቃሚ ሚትሪክ የPG ስርዓቶች በሚታወቁ benchmarks እንደተሸክሙ ነው። This work highlights a disconcerting bias in the evaluation of grounded plural phrases, which arises from representing sets of objects as a union box covering all component bounding boxes, in conjunction with the IoU metric.  የብዛት አካላት አካላትን በመፍጠር እናሳውቃለን፣ አስተያይተን እናስታውቃለን፡፡ በተፈተና እናሳየዋለን አዲስ ሚትሪክ ይህንን ትግባር እጅግ ያሳርፋል እና በPG ስራቶች ውስጥ የብዙ ቃላትን ማስታወቂያ ለመሻል እናመክራለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Krijimi i frazës (PG) është një detyrë multimodale që bazon gjuhën në imazhe. Sistemet PG vlerësohen në pika të njohura, duke përdorur Intersection mbi Union (IoU) si metrik vlerësimi. Ky punë thekson një paragjykim shqetësues në vlerësimin e frazave plurale të bazuara, që vjen nga përfaqësimi i grupeve të objekteve si një kuti bashkimi që mbulon të gjitha kutitë kufitare të komponenteve, në lidhje me metrikën IoU. Ne zbulojmë, analizojmë dhe kuantifikojmë një paragjykim të vlerësimit në bazën e frazave shumëfishe dhe përcaktojmë një metrik të ri, c-IoU, bazuar në kutitë e komponenteve të një kutie bashkimi. We experimentally show that our new metric greatly alleviates this bias and recommend using it for fairer evaluation of plural phrases in PG tasks.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Ֆրանսի հիմնավորումը (PD) բազմամոդալ խնդիր է, որը հիմնավորում է լեզուն պատկերներում: ԳԳ համակարգերը գնահատվում են լավ հայտնի համեմատային նպատակների վրա, օգտագործելով ԱՄՆ-ի (IU) հատվածը որպես գնահատման մետրիկ: Այս աշխատանքը ներկայացնում է անհանգստացնող կողմնականությունը հիմնված բազմաթիվ արտահայտությունների գնահատման մեջ, որը առաջանում է առարկաների համակարգերի ներկայացումից որպես միավորման արկղ, որը ներառում է բոլոր բաղադրիչների սահմանափակումները, միասին IU մետրիկայի հետ: Մենք հայտնաբերում ենք, վերլուծում և չափեցնում ենք գնահատման կողմնականությունը բազմաթիվ արտահայտությունների հիմնադրման մեջ և սահմանում ենք նոր մետրիկ, c-IU, հիմնված համայնքի արկղի բաղադրիչների արկղի վրա: Մենք փորձարկումներով ցույց ենք տալիս, որ մեր նոր մետրիկը մեծապես նվազեցնում է այս կողմնականությունը և խորհուրդ է տալիս այն օգտագործել ԳԳ խնդիրների բազմաթիվ արտահայտությունների ավելի արդարացի գնահատման համար:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Fraz yerl…ôŇüdirm…ôsi (PG) Ňü…ôkill…ôrd…ô dili yerl…ôŇüdir…ôn √ßoxlu modal iŇüdir. PG sisteml…ôri tanńĪdńĪqlarńĪ benchmarklarda deńüerlendirilir, Union (IoU) arasńĪndakńĪ Intersection il…ô deńüerlendirm…ô metrik olaraq istifad…ô edir. Bu iŇüin IoU metrik il…ô birlikd…ô b√ľt√ľn komponentl…ôrin qutuqlarńĪnńĪ √∂rt√ľy…ôn birlikd…ô, yerli √ßoxlu s√∂zl…ôrin deńüerlendirm…ôsind…ô d…ôyiŇüiklik bir bias ńĪ iŇüńĪqlandńĪrńĪr. Biz √ßoxlu s √∂zl…ôrin t…ôr…ôfind…ô deńüerlendirm…ô bias ńĪnńĪ tanńĪyńĪrńĪq, analiz edirik v…ô kvantitat edirik v…ô yeni metrik, c-IoU, birlikl…ôrin komponent qutularńĪna dayanan bir m…ôlumat qutusu bel…ô tanńĪyńĪrńĪq. Biz t…ôcr√ľb…ôl…ôr…ô g√∂st…ôririk ki, yeni metrik bu bias ńĪnńĪ √ßox azaldńĪr v…ô PG iŇüind…ô √ßoxlu frazl…ôrin d√ľzg√ľn deńüerlendirm…ôsin…ô istifad…ô edir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_id>Pemasangan frasa (PG) adalah tugas multimodal yang membangun bahasa dalam gambar. Sistem PG diteliti pada benchmarks yang dikenal, menggunakan Intersection over Union (IoU) sebagai metrik evaluasi. Pekerjaan ini mempertimbangkan bias yang mengganggu dalam evaluasi frasa plural berdasarkan dasar, yang muncul dari mewakili set objek sebagai kotak union yang meliputi semua kotak pembatasan komponen, bersama dengan metrik IoU. We detect, analyze and quantify an evaluation bias in the grounding of plural phrases and define a novel metric, c-IoU, based on a union box's component boxes.  Kami secara eksperimen menunjukkan bahwa metrik baru kami sangat mengurangi bias ini dan merekomendasikan menggunakannya untuk evaluasi lebih adil frasa plural dalam tugas PG.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_bn>বাক্য গ্রুউন্ডিং (পিজি) একটি বহুটিমোডাল কাজ যা ছবিতে ভাষার ভাষা কার্যক্রম করে। পিজি সিস্টেম পরিচিত বেনম্যার্কে মূল্যায়নের মেট্রিক হিসেবে ব্যবহার করা হচ্ছে। এই কাজটি ভূমিকম্পের বাক্সের মূল্যের মাধ্যমে বিস্মিত বাক্সের বিষয়টিকে উদ্বিগ্ন করে, যা ইওইউ মেট্রিকের সাথে সংযুক্ত বস্তুকে প্রতিনিধিত্ব করে একটি ইউনিয়ন বা আমরা একটি ইউনিয়ন বাক্সের কম্পোনেন্ট বাক্সের ভিত্তিতে একটি নোভেল মেট্রিক, c-IoU ব্যবহারের মূল্য বিশ্লেষণ এবং পরিমাণ পরিমাপ করি। আমরা পরীক্ষামূলক ভাবে দেখাচ্ছি যে আমাদের নতুন মেট্রিক এই বিভ্রান্তিকে বেশী কমিয়ে দেয় এবং পিজির কাজে প্রবল বাক্যের মূল্যের জন</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Phrase uzemnění (PG) je multimodální úloha, která uzemní jazyk v obrázkech. PG systémy jsou hodnoceny na základě známých referenčních měřítek, pomocí hodnotící metriky Intersection over Union (IoU). Tato práce zdůrazňuje znepokojující zaujatost v hodnocení uzemněných množných frází, která vzniká z reprezentace množin objektů jako sjednocovací rámeček pokrývající všechny součásti ohraničující rámečky, ve spojení s metrikou IoU. Detekujeme, analyzujeme a kvantifikujeme zkreslení hodnocení v uzemnění množných frází a definujeme novou metriku, c-IoU, založenou na komponentních boxech sjednocovacího boxu. Experimentálně ukazujeme, že naše nová metrika výrazně zmírňuje tuto zkreslenost a doporučujeme ji použít pro spravedlivější hodnocení množných frází v PG úkolech.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>La base de frases (PG) és una tasca multimodal que basa el llenguatge en imatges. Els sistemes PG s'evaluen amb punts de referència coneguts, utilitzant Intersection over Union (IoU) com a mesura d'evaluació. Aquesta feina destaca un bias desconcertant en l'evaluació de frases plurals fundamentades, que surt de representar conjunts d'objectes com una caixa de unió que cobreix totes les caixes de límits de components, en conjunt amb la mètrica IoU. Detectem, analitzem i quantifiquem un bias d'evaluació en la base de frases plural s i definim una nova mètrica, c-IoU, basada en les caixes de components d'una caixa de sindicats. Ens demostram experimentalment que la nostra nova mètrica allevia molt aquest bias i li recomanem d'utilitzar-lo per a una evaluació més justa de frases plurals en tasques de PG.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Fraase grounding (PG) on mitmeliigiline ülesanne, mis põhjendab keelt piltides. PG süsteeme hinnatakse tuntud võrdlusnäitajate alusel, kasutades hindamismeetodina liidu üle lõikumist. Käesolev töö tõstab esile häirivat eelarvamust põhjendatud mitmusfraaside hindamisel, mis tuleneb objektide komplektide esindamisest kõiki komponente piiravaid kastisid hõlmava liidukastina koos IoU meetrikuga. Me tuvastame, analüüsime ja kvantifitseerime hindamispiirangut mitmusfraaside alusel ning määratleme uue meetriku c-IoU, mis põhineb liidukasti komponentkastidel. Eksperimentaalselt näitame, et meie uus mõõdik leevendab oluliselt seda eelarvamust ja soovitame seda kasutada mitmusfraaside õiglasemaks hindamiseks PG ülesannetes.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>Fraza osnova (PG) je multimodalni zadatak koji temelji jezik na slikama. PG sistemi se procjenjuju na poznatim kriterijama, koristeći Intersekciju iznad Unije (IoU) kao metričku procjenu. Ovaj rad naglašava nepristojnu pristrasnost u procjeni osnovanih pluralnih fraza, koja se pojavljuje od predstavljanja seta objekata kao kutija za sindikat koja pokriva sve kutije granica komponenta, zajedno sa metrikom IoU. Otkrivamo, analiziramo i kvantificiramo predrasude za procjenu na osnovu pluralnih fraza i definiramo novu metričku, c-IoU, baziranu na kutijama komponentnih kutija sindikata. Eksperimentalno pokazujemo da naša nova metrika veoma smanjuje ovu predrasude i preporučuje ga koristiti za fer procjenu pluralnih fraza u PG zadatkima.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_fi>Fraase grounding (PG) on multimodaalinen tehtävä, joka pohjaa kielen kuviin. PG-järjestelmiä arvioidaan tunnettujen vertailuarvojen perusteella käyttäen arviointimetrinä Intersection over Union (IoU). Tämä työ korostaa hämmentävää harhaa pohjautuvien monikon lauseiden arvioinnissa, joka syntyy esineiden esittämisestä liitoslaatikkona, joka kattaa kaikki komponentit rajaavat laatikot yhdessä IoU-metriikan kanssa. Havaitsemme, analysoimme ja kvantifioimme arviointivääristymän monikon lauseiden pohjautumisessa ja määrittelemme uuden metriikan, c-IoU, joka perustuu liitoslaatikon komponenttiraatikoihin. Kokeellisesti osoitamme, että uusi metriikkamme lievittää tätä vääristymää huomattavasti, ja suosittelemme sen käyttöä monikon lauseiden oikeudenmukaisempaan arviointiin PG-tehtävissä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Alternate Language Digawe Awak dh챕w챕 Awak dh챕w챕 챕ntuk 챕ntuk dh챕w챕 ngerasakno karo hal-hal ujaran karo perusahaan karo nggawe barang plural kanggo didasakno plural</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Ozemljanje fraz (PG) je multimodalna naloga, ki utemeljuje jezik v slikah. Sistemi PG se ocenjujejo na podlagi znanih referenčnih vrednosti, pri čemer se kot merilo ocenjevanja uporablja presekanje preko Unije (IoU). To delo poudarja zaskrbljujočo pristranskost pri ocenjevanju označenih množinskih stavkov, ki izhaja iz predstavljanja nizov objektov kot unijskega polja, ki pokriva vse komponentne mejne polje, v povezavi z metriko IoU. Zaznavamo, analiziramo in kvantificiramo vrednotenjsko pristranskost pri označevanju množinskih stavkov in opredelimo novo metriko, c-IoU, ki temelji na sestavnih poljih unijske škatle. Eksperimentalno pokažemo, da naša nova metrika močno ublaži to pristranskost in jo priporočamo za pravičnejše ocenjevanje množinskih stavkov v nalogah PG.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Kunna maganar magana (PG) shi ne wani aikin multi-doda wanda ke baka harshen cikin zane. Ana ƙaddara tsarin PG kan salon da aka sani, don a yi amfani da shirin Ciki a kan Union (IoU) kamar metric evaluation. Wannan aikin ya ƙayyade wani rabo mai ƙyacẽwa cikin evaluation of old-ƙunsa, wanda ke ƙara daga wakilishi daidaita abubuwa kamar botsun union wanda ke rufe duk ƙanshi na sami da metrikin IoU. Kana gane, Ana ƙayyade kuma an a ƙayyade kimar cikin salon maganar mulki kuma Mu bayyana wani metriki na sauri, c-IoU, a kan salon da boxen cikin fanikin faniki na haɗi. Tuna nũna cewa, metric in nan yanzu zai sauƙaƙara wannan tabaranci kuma ana shauri ka yi amfani da shi dõmin ka ƙaddara sauri masu ƙari cikin aikin PG.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ཡིག་ཆ་རྒྱབ་ལྗོངས་པ(PG)ནི་བརྙན་རིས་ནང་དུ་རྒྱབ་ལྗོངས་ཀྱི་སྐད་རིགས་ཤིག་རེད PG systems are evaluated on well-known benchmarks, using Intersection over Union (IoU) as evaluation metric. This work highlights a disconcerting bias in the evaluation of grounded plural phrases, which arises from representing sets of objects as a union box covering all component bounding boxes, in conjunction with the IoU metric. We detect, analyze and quantify an evaluation bias in the grounding of plural phrases and define a novel metric, c-IoU, based on a union box's component boxes. We experimentally show that our new metric greatly alleviates this bias and recommend using it for fairer evaluation of plural phrases in PG tasks.</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>קישור פרזים (PG) הוא משימה רבות מודלית שמקמת שפה בתמונות. מערכות PG מוערכות על נקודות רמז ידועות היטב, בשימוש של מחצית מעל יוניון (IoU) כמטרית הערכה. העבודה הזאת מזכירה חיווה מדאיגת בהערכה של ביטויים רבים מקורקעים, אשר נוצרת מייצג קבוצות של אובייקטים כקופסת איגוד מכסה את כל קופסות הגבול של המרכיבים, יחד עם המטרית IoU. אנו מגלים, מנתחים ומכירים את ההתמחות הערכתית בקרקע של ביטויים רבים ומגדרים מטריקה חדשה, c-IoU, מבוססת על קופסאות המרכיבים של קופסת איגוד. אנו מראים מבחינה ניסיונית שהמטריקה החדשה שלנו משקלת מאוד את ההתמחות הזו וממלצה להשתמש בה לערכה הוגנת יותר של ביטויים רבים במשימות PG.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Learning to Learn Semantic Factors in Heterogeneous Image Classification</title>
      <author><first>Boyue</first><last>Fan</last></author>
      <author><first>Zhenting</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <pages>34–38</pages>
      <abstract>Few-shot learning is to recognize novel classes with a few labeled samples per class. Although numerous meta-learning methods have made significant progress, they struggle to directly address the heterogeneity of training and evaluating task distributions, resulting in the domain shift problem when transitioning to new tasks with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disjoint_sets">disjoint spaces</a>. In this paper, we propose a novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> to deal with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homogeneity_and_heterogeneity">heterogeneity</a>. Specifically, by simulating class-difference domain shift during the meta-train phase, a bilevel optimization procedure is applied to learn a transferable representation space that can rapidly adapt to heterogeneous tasks. Experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of our proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="0f741cf6">2021.alvr-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.alvr-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>fan-liu-2021-learning</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/cub-200-2011">CUB-200-2011</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>