<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.louhi">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-04-19">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 12th International Workshop on Health Text Mining and Information Analysis</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Eben</first><last>Holderness</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Antonio</first><last>Jimeno Yepes</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alberto</first><last>Lavelli</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anne-Lyse</first><last>Minard</last></editor>
      <editor><first>James</first><last>Pustejovsky</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Fabio</first><last>Rinaldi</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>online</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="082c1a45">2021.louhi-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>louhi-2021-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Understanding Social Support Expressed in a COVID-19 Online Forum<fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 Online Forum</title>
      <author><first>Anietie</first><last>Andy</last></author>
      <author><first>Brian</first><last>Chu</last></author>
      <author><first>Ramie</first><last>Fathy</last></author>
      <author><first>Barrington</first><last>Bennett</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Stokes</last></author>
      <author><first>Sharath Chandra</first><last>Guntuku</last></author>
      <pages>19–27</pages>
      <abstract>In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_forum">online forums</a> focused on health and wellbeing, individuals tend to seek and give the following <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_support">social support</a> : emotional and informational support. Understanding the expressions of these social supports in an online COVID- 19 forum is important for : (a) the forum and its members to provide the right type of support to individuals and (b) determining the long term effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on the well-being of the public, thereby informing interventions. In this work, we build four machine learning models to measure the extent of the following social supports expressed in each post in a COVID-19 online forum : (a) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional_support">emotional support</a> given (b) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional_support">emotional support</a> sought (c) informational support given, and (d) informational support sought. Using these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a>, we aim to : (i) determine if there is a correlation between the different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_support">social supports</a> expressed in posts e.g. when members of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_forum">forum</a> give emotional support in posts, do they also tend to give or seek informational support in the same post? (ii) determine how these social supports sought and given changes over time in published posts. We find that (i) there is a positive correlation between the informational support given in posts and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional_support">emotional support</a> given and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional_support">emotional support</a> sought, respectively, in these posts and (ii) over time, users tended to seek more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional_support">emotional support</a> and give less <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional_support">emotional support</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="61bb3c59">2021.louhi-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>andy-etal-2021-understanding</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Integrating Higher-Level Semantics into Robust Biomedical Name Representations</title>
      <author><first>Pieter</first><last>Fivez</last></author>
      <author><first>Simon</first><last>Suster</last></author>
      <author><first>Walter</first><last>Daelemans</last></author>
      <pages>49–58</pages>
      <abstract>Neural encoders of biomedical names are typically considered robust if representations can be effectively exploited for various downstream NLP tasks. To achieve this, encoders need to model domain-specific biomedical semantics while rivaling the universal applicability of pretrained self-supervised representations. Previous work on robust representations has focused on learning low-level distinctions between names of fine-grained biomedical concepts. These fine-grained concepts can also be clustered together to reflect higher-level, more general semantic distinctions, such as grouping the names nettle sting and tick-borne fever together under the description puncture wound of skin. It has not yet been empirically confirmed that training biomedical name encoders on fine-grained distinctions automatically leads to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top-down_and_bottom-up_design">bottom-up encoding</a> of such higher-level semantics. In this paper, we show that this bottom-up effect exists, but that it is still relatively limited. As a solution, we propose a scalable multi-task training regime for biomedical name encoders which can also learn robust representations using only higher-level semantic classes. These representations can generalise both bottom-up as well as top-down among various semantic hierarchies. Moreover, we show how they can be used out-of-the-box for improved unsupervised detection of hypernyms, while retaining robust performance on various semantic relatedness benchmarks.</abstract>
      <url hash="729dc25a">2021.louhi-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>fivez-etal-2021-integrating</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/clips/higherlevelsemantics" additional="false">clips/higherlevelsemantics</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/is-a">IS-A</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/semeval-2018-task-9-hypernym-discovery">SemEval-2018 Task 9: Hypernym Discovery</pwcdataset>
    <title_pt>Integrando Semântica de Nível Superior em Representações de Nomes Biomédicos Robustas</title_pt>
      <title_es>Integración de la semántica de nivel superior en representaciones sólidas de nombres biomédicos</title_es>
      <title_fr>Intégrer une sémantique de haut niveau dans des représentations de noms biomédicaux robustes</title_fr>
      <title_ja>高レベルの意味論を堅牢な生物医学的名称表現に統合する</title_ja>
      <title_ar>دمج دلالات المستوى الأعلى في تمثيلات قوية لأسماء الطب الحيوي</title_ar>
      <title_zh>集高语义于强大生物医学名</title_zh>
      <title_hi>मजबूत जैव चिकित्सा नाम प्रतिनिधित्व में उच्च स्तर के शब्दार्थ को एकीकृत करना</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Интеграция семантики более высокого уровня в надежные биомедицинские представления имен</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Séimeantaic Ardleibhéil a chomhtháthú le Léirithe Ainmneacha Bithleighis Láidir</title_ga>
      <title_el>Ενσωμάτωση ανώτερου επιπέδου σημασιολογίας σε ισχυρές βιοιατρικές αναπαραστάσεις ονομάτων</title_el>
      <title_hu>A magasabb szintű szemantika integrálása robusztus biomedicini névképviseletekbe</title_hu>
      <title_ka>რობსტის ბიომედიციული სახელის გამოსახულებაში</title_ka>
      <title_it>Integrazione della semantica di livello superiore in robuste rappresentazioni biomediche dei nomi</title_it>
      <title_lt>Aukštesnio lygio seminarų integravimas į patikimas biomedicinos pavadinimų atstovavimas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Интегрирање на семантите на високо ниво во силни биомедицински имиња</title_mk>
      <title_ml>കൂടുതല്‍ നില സെമാന്റിക്സുകള്‍ റോബസ്റ്റ് ബിയോമിഡിക്കല്‍ പേരിലേക്ക് ചേര്‍ക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Integrasikan Semantik Aras Tinggi ke Perwakilan Nama Biomedik yang Kuat</title_ms>
      <title_mt>L-integrazzjoni ta’ Semanti ta’ Livell Għoli f’Rappreżentazzjonijiet b’Ismijiet Bijomediċiċi b’Saħħithom</title_mt>
      <title_pl>Integracja semantyki wyższego szczebla z solidnymi reprezentacjami nazw biomedycznych</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Integrarea semanticii de nivel superior în reprezentări biomedicale solide de nume</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Integrujući semantike na višem nivou u robotno biomedicinsko ime predstavljanje</title_sr>
      <title_mn>Хамгийн өндөр хэмжээний Semantics руу биологийн нэр төлөвлөгөөнд нэгтгэх</title_mn>
      <title_no>Integrering av høgrenivåsemiantikk i robust biomedisk namn</title_no>
      <title_si>උපරිම ස්ථානය සෙමාන්ටික්ස් එක්කරණය කරන්නේ රොබ්ස්ට් බියෝබියෝඩික් නාම ප්‍රධානය</title_si>
      <title_so>Ku qabsashada heerka sare Semantics into Robust Biomedical magac Representations</title_so>
      <title_kk>Жоғары деңгейіндегі семантикаларды Робуст биомедикалық атауларына біріктіру</title_kk>
      <title_sv>Integrering av semantik på högre nivå i robusta biomedicinska namnrepresentationer</title_sv>
      <title_ta>அதிக மட்டத்தில் சேமிப்புகளை சுழற்சி பையோமிடிக் பெயரில் சேர்க்கவும்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>روبوسٹ بیولوڈیسی نام نمائندس میں Higher-Level Semantics کو ترکیب کیا جاتا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Nhập loại kỳ tích cao cấp vào KCharselect unicode block name</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Интегриране на семантиката на по-високо ниво в здрави биомедицински представяния на имената</title_bg>
      <title_da>Integrering af semantik på højere niveau i robuste biomedicinske navneopræsentationer</title_da>
      <title_nl>Het integreren van semantica op hoger niveau in robuuste biomedische naamvertegenwoordigingen</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Integracija semantika na višem nivou u robotne predstave biomedicinskog imena</title_hr>
      <title_de>Integration von übergeordneter Semantik in robuste biomedizinische Namensvertretungen</title_de>
      <title_ko>고급 의미를 건장한 생물의학 명칭 표시에 집적하다</title_ko>
      <title_fa>جمع کردن سیمانتیک سطح بالاتر به نمایش نام زیست پزشکی</title_fa>
      <title_id>Integrating Higher-Level Semantics into Robust Biomedical Name Representations</title_id>
      <title_sw>Kuunganisha Semantiki za kiwango cha juu katika majina ya Biomedical ya Robust</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Robust Biomedical Name Representations</title_tr>
      <title_af>Integrasie van Hoogvlak Semantieke in Robust Biomedical Name Representations</title_af>
      <title_sq>Integrimi i Semantikëve të nivelit të lartë në përfaqësime të forta të emrave biomjekësore</title_sq>
      <title_am>ቦታ</title_am>
      <title_az>쿮n y칲ks톛k s톛viyy톛 Semantika Robust Biomedical Name Representations Integrating HighLevel Semantics into Robust Biomedical Name Representations</title_az>
      <title_hy>Ինտեգրելով բարձր մակարդակի սեմանտիկները ուժեղ կենսաբիոբժշկական անունների ներկայացումների մեջ</title_hy>
      <title_bn>সর্বোচ্চ স্তরের সেমান্টিক্স রোবাস্ট বিয়োমিক্যাল নামে যুক্ত করো</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Integracija semantika na višem nivou u robotne predstave biomedicinskog imena</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Integrar Semàtics de Alt Nivel en Robustes Representacions de Noms Biomèdics</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Integrace sémantiky na vyšší úrovni do robustních biomedicínských reprezentací názvů</title_cs>
      <title_et>Kõrgema taseme semantika integreerimine tugevatesse biomeditsiinilistesse nimede esindustesse</title_et>
      <title_fi>Korkeamman tason semantiikan integrointi kestäviin biolääketieteellisiin nimiedustuksiin</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Name</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Vključevanje semantike na višji ravni v robustne biomedicinske predstavitve imen</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>שילוב סמנטיקה ברמה גבוהה לתוך מייצגי שם ביורפואי חזקים</title_he>
      <title_bo>Integrating Higher-Level Semantics into Robust Biomedical Name Representations</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>عادةً ما تُعتبر الترميز العصبي للأسماء الطبية الحيوية قوية إذا كان من الممكن استغلال التمثيلات بفعالية في مهام معالجة اللغات الطبيعية المختلفة. لتحقيق ذلك ، تحتاج أجهزة التشفير إلى تصميم دلالات طبية حيوية خاصة بالمجال مع منافسة التطبيق العالمي للتمثيلات الخاضعة للإشراف الذاتي التي تم تدريبها مسبقًا. ركز العمل السابق على التمثيلات القوية على تعلم الفروق منخفضة المستوى بين أسماء المفاهيم الطبية الحيوية الدقيقة. يمكن أيضًا تجميع هذه المفاهيم الدقيقة معًا لتعكس الفروق الدلالية ذات المستوى الأعلى والأكثر عمومية ، مثل تجميع أسماء لدغة نبات القراص والحمى المنقولة بالقراد معًا تحت وصف جرح ثقب الجلد. لم يتم التأكد بعد من الناحية التجريبية من أن تدريب مشفرات الأسماء الطبية الحيوية على تمييز دقيق الحبيبات يؤدي تلقائيًا إلى ترميز من أسفل إلى أعلى لمثل هذه الدلالات عالية المستوى. في هذه الورقة ، نوضح أن هذا التأثير التصاعدي موجود ، لكنه لا يزال محدودًا نسبيًا. كحل ، نقترح نظام تدريب متعدد المهام قابل للتطوير لمشفرات الأسماء الطبية الحيوية والتي يمكنها أيضًا تعلم تمثيلات قوية باستخدام الفصول الدلالية عالية المستوى فقط. يمكن لهذه التمثيلات أن تعمم على حد سواء من أسفل إلى أعلى وكذلك من أعلى إلى أسفل بين التدرجات الهرمية الدلالية المختلفة. علاوة على ذلك ، نوضح كيف يمكن استخدامها خارج الصندوق لتحسين الكشف غير الخاضع للرقابة عن التشعبات المفرطة ، مع الحفاظ على الأداء القوي في مختلف معايير الارتباط الدلالي.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Codificadores neurais de nomes biomédicos são normalmente considerados robustos se as representações puderem ser exploradas de forma eficaz para várias tarefas de PNL a jusante. Para conseguir isso, os codificadores precisam modelar a semântica biomédica específica do domínio enquanto rivalizam com a aplicabilidade universal de representações auto-supervisionadas pré-treinadas. Trabalhos anteriores sobre representações robustas se concentraram em aprender distinções de baixo nível entre nomes de conceitos biomédicos refinados. Esses conceitos refinados também podem ser agrupados para refletir distinções semânticas de nível mais alto e mais gerais, como agrupar os nomes picada de urtiga e febre transmitida por carrapato sob a descrição ferimento por punção da pele. Ainda não foi empiricamente confirmado que o treinamento de codificadores de nomes biomédicos em distinções refinadas leva automaticamente à codificação de baixo para cima de tal semântica de nível superior. Neste artigo, mostramos que esse efeito bottom-up existe, mas ainda é relativamente limitado. Como solução, propomos um regime de treinamento multitarefa escalável para codificadores de nomes biomédicos que também podem aprender representações robustas usando apenas classes semânticas de nível superior. Essas representações podem generalizar tanto de baixo para cima quanto de cima para baixo entre várias hierarquias semânticas. Além disso, mostramos como eles podem ser usados imediatamente para melhorar a detecção não supervisionada de hiperônimos, mantendo um desempenho robusto em vários benchmarks de relação semântica.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Les codeurs neuronaux de noms biomédicaux sont généralement considérés comme robustes si les représentations peuvent être exploitées efficacement pour diverses tâches de PNL en aval. Pour y parvenir, les codeurs doivent modéliser la sémantique biomédicale spécifique au domaine tout en rivalisant avec l'applicabilité universelle des représentations auto-supervisées préentraînées. Les travaux antérieurs sur les représentations robustes se sont concentrés sur l'apprentissage de distinctions de bas niveau entre les noms de concepts biomédicaux précis. Ces concepts à grain fin peuvent également être regroupés pour refléter des distinctions sémantiques plus générales de niveau supérieur, telles que le regroupement des noms piqûre d'ortie et fièvre transmise par les tiques sous la description plaie perforante de la peau. Il n'a pas encore été confirmé empiriquement que l'entraînement de codeurs de noms biomédicaux sur des distinctions fines conduit automatiquement à un codage ascendant de cette sémantique de niveau supérieur. Dans cet article, nous montrons que cet effet ascendant existe, mais qu'il est encore relativement limité. En guise de solution, nous proposons un programme de formation multitâche évolutif pour les encodeurs de noms biomédicaux qui peuvent également apprendre des représentations robustes en utilisant uniquement des classes sémantiques de niveau supérieur. Ces représentations peuvent généraliser à la fois de bas en haut et de haut en bas entre différentes hiérarchies sémantiques. De plus, nous montrons comment ils peuvent être utilisés prêts à l'emploi pour améliorer la détection non supervisée des hyperonymes, tout en conservant des performances robustes sur divers tests de relation sémantique.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Los codificadores neuronales de nombres biomédicos generalmente se consideran robustos si las representaciones pueden explotarse eficazmente para diversas tareas posteriores de la PNL. Para lograr esto, los codificadores necesitan modelar la semántica biomédica específica del dominio y, al mismo tiempo, rivalizar con la aplicabilidad universal de las representaciones autosupervisadas preentrenadas. El trabajo anterior sobre representaciones sólidas se ha centrado en aprender distinciones de bajo nivel entre los nombres de conceptos biomédicos detallados. Estos conceptos detallados también pueden agruparse para reflejar distinciones semánticas más generales y de alto nivel, como agrupar los nombres picadura de ortiga y fiebre transmitida por garrapatas bajo la descripción herida punzante de la piel. Todavía no se ha confirmado empíricamente que el entrenamiento de codificadores de nombres biomédicos en distinciones precisas conduzca automáticamente a una codificación ascendente de tal semántica de nivel superior. En este artículo, mostramos que este efecto de abajo hacia arriba existe, pero que sigue siendo relativamente limitado. Como solución, proponemos un régimen de capacitación multitarea escalable para codificadores de nombres biomédicos que también pueden aprender representaciones sólidas utilizando solo clases semánticas de nivel superior. Estas representaciones pueden generalizar tanto de abajo hacia arriba como de arriba hacia abajo entre varias jerarquías semánticas. Además, mostramos cómo se pueden usar de forma inmediata para mejorar la detección no supervisada de hiperónimos, al tiempo que se mantiene un rendimiento sólido en varios puntos de referencia de relación semántica.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_zh>生物医学名者神经编码器常以为壮,若示以下流NLP务。 为此者,编码器建模特定于领域之生物医学语义,而比于先训之自监适用性也。 前鲁棒之事,集于学细粒度生物医学名之差也。 此细粒度大概相聚,以见更高层次,更语义分别,如合荨麻刺痛与蜱传热之名,皮肤穿伤。 未证于经验,练生物医学名于细粒度编码器则自下而上编码此更高层次之语义也。 本文中,证其自下之效有在,然犹相对有限。 为解决方案者,吾为生物医学名编码器设可广之多任务训练方略,其制度犹可以高等语义类来学鲁棒。 此文可推诸语义层次结构自下而上,自上而下。 此外展示如何开箱即以地用之,改进超名词者无监督检测,兼于诸语义相关基准。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>बायोमेडिकल नामों के तंत्रिका एनकोडर को आमतौर पर मजबूत माना जाता है यदि विभिन्न डाउनस्ट्रीम एनएलपी कार्यों के लिए प्रतिनिधित्व को प्रभावी ढंग से शोषण किया जा सकता है। इसे प्राप्त करने के लिए, एनकोडर को डोमेन-विशिष्ट बायोमेडिकल शब्दार्थ को मॉडल करने की आवश्यकता होती है, जबकि पूर्व-प्रशिक्षित आत्म-पर्यवेक्षित अभ्यावेदन की सार्वभौमिक प्रयोज्यता को प्रतिद्वंद्वी किया जाता है। मजबूत प्रतिनिधित्व पर पिछले काम ने ठीक-ठाक बायोमेडिकल अवधारणाओं के नामों के बीच निम्न-स्तरीय अंतर सीखने पर ध्यान केंद्रित किया है। इन ठीक-दाने वाली अवधारणाओं को उच्च-स्तरीय, अधिक सामान्य शब्दार्थ भेदों को प्रतिबिंबित करने के लिए एक साथ क्लस्टर किया जा सकता है, जैसे कि त्वचा के विवरण पंचर घाव के तहत बिछुआ डंक और टिक-जनित बुखार नामों को एक साथ समूहीकृत करना। यह अभी तक अनुभवजन्य रूप से पुष्टि नहीं की गई है कि ठीक-दाने वाले भेदों पर बायोमेडिकल नाम एन्कोडर का प्रशिक्षण स्वचालित रूप से इस तरह के उच्च-स्तरीय शब्दार्थ के नीचे-ऊपर एन्कोडिंग की ओर जाता है। इस पेपर में, हम दिखाते हैं कि यह बॉटम-अप प्रभाव मौजूद है, लेकिन यह अभी भी अपेक्षाकृत सीमित है। एक समाधान के रूप में, हम बायोमेडिकल नाम एन्कोडर के लिए एक स्केलेबल मल्टी-टास्क प्रशिक्षण व्यवस्था का प्रस्ताव करते हैं जो केवल उच्च-स्तरीय शब्दार्थ वर्गों का उपयोग करके मजबूत प्रतिनिधित्व भी सीख सकता है। ये अभ्यावेदन विभिन्न शब्दार्थ पदानुक्रमों के बीच नीचे-ऊपर और ऊपर-नीचे दोनों को सामान्यीकृत कर सकते हैं। इसके अलावा, हम दिखाते हैं कि हाइपरनिम्स के बेहतर असुरक्षित पता लगाने के लिए आउट-ऑफ-द-बॉक्स का उपयोग कैसे किया जा सकता है, जबकि विभिन्न शब्दार्थ संबंधितता बेंचमार्क पर मजबूत प्रदर्शन को बनाए रखा जा सकता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Is gnách go meastar ionchódóirí néaracha ainmneacha bithleighis a bheith láidir más féidir leas a bhaint as léiriúcháin go héifeachtach le haghaidh tascanna NLP éagsúla iartheachtacha. Chun é seo a bhaint amach, ní mór d’ionchódóirí múnla a dhéanamh ar shéimeantaic bhithleighis a bhaineann go sonrach leis an bhfearann agus ag an am céanna a bheith in iomaíocht le hinfheidhmeacht uilíoch léiriúcháin féinmhaoirsithe réamhoilte. Dhírigh obair a rinneadh roimhe seo ar léiriúcháin láidre ar idirdhealú leibhéal íseal a fhoghlaim idir ainmneacha coincheapa bithleighis mínghlana. Is féidir na coincheapa mínghrámhara seo a bhraisliú le chéile freisin chun idirdhealú shéimeantach ardleibhéil, níos ginearálta a léiriú, mar shampla na hainmneacha nettle sting agus sceartán-iompartha a ghrúpáil le chéile faoin gcur síos ar chréacht puncture an chraicinn. Níor deimhníodh go heimpíreach go fóill go n-eascródh ionchódú shéimeantach ardleibhéil dá leithéid as oiliúint a chur ar ionchódóirí ainmneacha bithleighis ar idirdhealuithe míne. Sa pháipéar seo, léirímid go bhfuil an éifeacht bun-aníos seo ann, ach go bhfuil sé fós sách teoranta. Mar réiteach, molaimid réimeas oiliúna inscálaithe il-tasc le haghaidh ionchódóirí ainmneacha bithleighis ar féidir leo léirithe láidre a fhoghlaim agus úsáid á baint as aicmí séimeantaice ardleibhéil amháin. Is féidir leis na huiríll seo ginearálú ón mbun aníos agus ón mbarr anuas i measc ordlathas shéimeantach éagsúla. Ina theannta sin, léirímid conas is féidir iad a úsáid lasmuigh den bhosca chun hipirneamanna a bhrath níos fearr gan mhaoirseacht, agus feidhmíocht láidir á choinneáil ar thagarmharcanna éagsúla a bhaineann le séimeantach.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ja>生物医学的名称のニューラルエンコーダは、典型的には、表現が様々な下流NLPタスクのために効果的に利用され得る場合、堅牢であると見なされる。 これを達成するために、エンコーダは、事前に訓練された自己監視表現の普遍的な適用性と競合しながら、ドメイン固有の生物医学的意味論をモデル化する必要がある。 堅牢な表現に関するこれまでの研究は、細粒生物医学的概念の名前間の低レベルの区別を学習することに焦点を当てている。 これらの細かい概念は、皮膚穿刺創の記述の下でネッタチ刺しとダニ媒介熱の名前を一緒にグループ化するなど、よりレベルの高い、より一般的な意味論的な区別を反映するために集約することもできる。 細かい区別に関するバイオメディカルネームエンコーダーのトレーニングが、そのようなより高いレベルの意味論のボトムアップのエンコードに自動的につながることは、まだ経験的に確認されていない。 本稿では、このボトムアップ効果が存在するが、それでも比較的限定的であることを示す。 解決策として、高レベルのセマンティッククラスのみを使用して堅牢な表現を学習することもできるバイオメディカルネームエンコーダーのためのスケーラブルなマルチタスクトレーニングレジームを提案します。 これらの表現は、様々な意味論的階層の間でボトムアップとトップダウンの両方を一般化することができる。 さらに、さまざまなセマンティック関連性ベンチマークで堅牢なパフォーマンスを維持しながら、ハイパーニーミスの監視されていない検出を改善するためにどのようにそれらをすぐに使用できるかを示します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ru>Нейронные кодеры биомедицинских названий обычно считаются надежными, если представления могут быть эффективно использованы для различных последующих задач NLP. Для достижения этой цели кодировщикам необходимо моделировать биомедицинскую семантику, ориентируясь при этом на универсальную применимость предварительно подготовленных самоконтролируемых представлений. Предыдущая работа над надежными представлениями была сосредоточена на изучении различий на низком уровне между названиями мелкозернистых биомедицинских концепций. Эти мелкозернистые концепции также могут быть сгруппированы вместе, чтобы отразить более высокие, более общие семантические различия, такие как группировка названий крапивница жала и клещевой лихорадки вместе под описанием прокола раны кожи. Эмпирически еще не подтверждено, что обучение кодировщиков биомедицинских названий на тонкозернистых различиях автоматически приводит к кодированию такой семантики более высокого уровня снизу вверх. В этом документе мы показываем, что этот эффект "снизу вверх" существует, но что он все еще относительно ограничен. В качестве решения мы предлагаем масштабируемый многозадачный режим обучения для кодировщиков биомедицинских имен, который также может изучать надежные представления, используя только семантические классы более высокого уровня. Эти представления могут обобщать как восходящие, так и нисходящие среди различных семантических иерархий. Кроме того, мы показываем, как их можно использовать из коробки для улучшенного неконтролируемого обнаружения гипернимов, сохраняя при этом надежную производительность по различным критериям семантической родственности.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_hu>Az orvosbiológiai nevek idegkódolóit általában robusztusnak tekintik, ha a reprezentációk hatékonyan használhatók különböző downstream NLP feladatokhoz. Ennek eléréséhez a kódolóknak tartományspecifikus biomedikai szemantikát kell modellezniük, miközben versengnek az előkészített önfelügyelt reprezentációk univerzális alkalmazhatóságával. A robusztus reprezentációkkal kapcsolatos korábbi munkák a finom szemű orvosbiológiai fogalmak nevei közötti alacsony szintű különbségek tanulására összpontosítottak. Ezek a finomszemű fogalmak is összekapcsolhatók, hogy a magasabb szintű, általánosabb szemantikai megkülönböztetéseket tükrözzék, mint például a csaláncsípés és kullancs okozta láz elnevezések csoportosítása a bőr szúrási sebe alatt. Még nem igazolták empirikusan, hogy az orvosbiológiai névkódolók finomszemcsés megkülönböztetésekre való képzése automatikusan alulról felfelé irányuló kódolásához vezet. Ebben a tanulmányban megmutatjuk, hogy ez az alulról felfelé irányuló hatás létezik, de még mindig viszonylag korlátozott. Megoldásként egy skálázható, többfeladatos képzési rendszert javasolunk az orvosbiológiai névkódolók számára, amely csak magasabb szintű szemantikai osztályok segítségével képes robusztus reprezentációkat tanulni. Ezek az ábrázolások mind alulról felfelé, mind felülről lefelé általánosíthatják a különböző szemantikai hierarchiák között. Ezenkívül bemutatjuk, hogyan használhatók azok a hipernímek felügyelet nélküli felismerésére, miközben stabil teljesítményt tartanak fenn különböző szemantikai kapcsolattartási referenciaértékeken.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Οι νευρωνικοί κωδικοποιητές των βιοϊατρικών ονομάτων θεωρούνται συνήθως ισχυροί εάν οι αναπαραστάσεις μπορούν να αξιοποιηθούν αποτελεσματικά για διάφορες μεταγενέστερες εργασίες NLP. Για να επιτευχθεί αυτό, οι κωδικοποιητές πρέπει να μοντελοποιήσουν τη βιοϊατρική σημασιολογία συγκεκριμένου τομέα, ενώ παράλληλα να ανταγωνίζονται την καθολική εφαρμογή των προκαθορισμένων αυτοεποπτευόμενων αναπαραστάσεων. Προηγούμενες εργασίες σχετικά με ισχυρές αναπαραστάσεις έχουν επικεντρωθεί στην εκμάθηση χαμηλού επιπέδου διακρίσεων μεταξύ ονομάτων λεπτόκοκκων βιοϊατρικών εννοιών. Αυτές οι λεπτόκοκκες έννοιες μπορούν επίσης να ομαδοποιηθούν μαζί για να αντικατοπτρίζουν υψηλότερα επίπεδα, πιο γενικές σημασιολογικές διακρίσεις, όπως η ομαδοποίηση των ονομάτων τσίμπημα τσουκνίδας και πυρετός που μεταδίδεται από τσιμπούρια μαζί κάτω από την περιγραφή πληγής από διάτρηση του δέρματος. Δεν έχει ακόμη επιβεβαιωθεί εμπειρικά ότι η εκπαίδευση βιοϊατρικών κωδικοποιητών ονομάτων σε λεπτόκοκκες διακρίσεις οδηγεί αυτόματα σε κωδικοποίηση από κάτω προς τα πάνω μιας τέτοιας σημασιολογίας ανώτερου επιπέδου. Στην παρούσα εργασία, αποδεικνύουμε ότι αυτό το αποτέλεσμα από κάτω προς τα πάνω υπάρχει, αλλά ότι εξακολουθεί να είναι σχετικά περιορισμένο. Ως λύση, προτείνουμε ένα κλιμακώσιμο πρόγραμμα κατάρτισης πολλαπλών εργασιών για βιοϊατρικούς κωδικοποιητές ονομάτων που μπορούν επίσης να μάθουν ισχυρές αναπαραστάσεις χρησιμοποιώντας μόνο υψηλότερου επιπέδου σημασιολογικές τάξεις. Αυτές οι αναπαραστάσεις μπορούν να γενικεύσουν τόσο από κάτω προς τα πάνω όσο και από πάνω προς τα κάτω μεταξύ διαφόρων σημασιολογικών ιεραρχίων. Επιπλέον, δείχνουμε πώς μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για βελτιωμένη ανίχνευση υπερνύμων χωρίς επίβλεψη, διατηρώντας παράλληλα ισχυρή απόδοση σε διάφορα σημεία αναφοράς σημασιολογικής συσχέτισης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Gli encoder neurali di nomi biomedici sono generalmente considerati robusti se le rappresentazioni possono essere efficacemente sfruttate per varie attività NLP a valle. Per raggiungere questo obiettivo, gli encoder devono modellare la semantica biomedica specifica per un dominio rivaleggiando con l'applicabilità universale delle rappresentazioni pre-addestrate auto-supervisionate. I lavori precedenti su rappresentazioni robuste si sono concentrati sull'apprendimento di distinzioni di basso livello tra nomi di concetti biomedici a grana fine. Questi concetti a grana fine possono anche essere raggruppati insieme per riflettere distinzioni semantiche più generali e di livello superiore, come raggruppare i nomi di ortica puntura e febbre trasmessa da zecche insieme sotto la descrizione della ferita da puntura della pelle. Non è ancora stato empiricamente confermato che la formazione di codificatori biomedici di nomi su distinzioni a grana fine porta automaticamente alla codifica bottom-up di tale semantica di livello superiore. In questo articolo, mostriamo che questo effetto bottom-up esiste, ma che è ancora relativamente limitato. Come soluzione, proponiamo un regime di formazione multi-task scalabile per encoder biomedici che possono anche imparare rappresentazioni robuste utilizzando solo classi semantiche di livello superiore. Queste rappresentazioni possono generalizzare sia bottom-up che top-down tra varie gerarchie semantiche. Inoltre, mostriamo come possono essere utilizzati out-of-the-box per migliorare il rilevamento non supervisionato degli ipernimi, mantenendo prestazioni robuste su vari benchmark di relazione semantica.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ka>ბიომედიციო სახელების ნეიროლური კოდერები ტიპულად იყვნენ ძალიან, თუ გამოსახულებები შეიძლება ეფექტიურად გამოიყენება განსხვავებული NLP დავალებისთვის. რომელიც ამის გავაკეთებთ, კოდერებები უნდა მოდელუროთ სპეციფიკალური ბიომედიციური სმენტიკის მოდელური, როცა უნდა გავაკეთოთ უნივერსალური პროგრამებელობა, რომელი პირველი სამუშაო ძალიან გამოსახულებების სამუშაო მუშაო სამუშაო განსხვავებაზე გააკეთებული ბიო მედიციო კონცექტების სახელს. ეს კონფიგური კონფიგურები შეიძლება შეიძლება იყოს ერთად კონსტერებული, რომ გააჩვენოთ უფრო მეტი სიმენტიკური განსხვავებები, როგორც სახელის სახელის სახელის სურაცია და დარჩენილი სიმრცე ერთად, როგორც სა ამას არ იყო ემპერიკურად დარწმუნებული, რომ ბიომედიციური სახელის კოდერების განსხვავებაში ავტომატურად იქნება ასეთი უფრო მეტიკური სიმენტიკის კოდერების კოდირებაში. ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ აჩვენებთ, რომ ეს ქვემოთ ეფექტი არსებობს, მაგრამ ეს კონტაქტიურად დავუდგენა. როგორც გარეშე, ჩვენ მრავალური მრავალური სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო რეზიმის გარეშე, რომელიც შეიძლება ასევე ვისწავლოთ ძალიან გამოსახულებული რეზიმი, რომელიც მხ ეს გამოსახულებები შეიძლება ორივე ქვემო და ზემო ქვემოთ განსხვავებული სიმენტიკური ჰიერაქტიების შორის გენერალიზაცია. დამატებით, ჩვენ აჩვენებთ, როგორ ისინი შეიძლება გამოიყენება საკუთარი გარეშე ჰიპერნიმების განახლებისთვის, როგორც მუშაობელი გამოყენება განსხვავებული სმენტიკური განახლებისთვის.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_lt>Biomedicininių pavadinimų neurologiniai kodai paprastai laikomi patikimais, jei gali būti veiksmingai naudojami įvairioms tolesnėms NLP užduotims atlikti. Norint tai pasiekti, koduotojai turi modeliuoti konkrečiai sričiai būdingą biomedicinę semantiką, lyginant su visuotiniu iš anksto parengtų savarankiškai prižiūrimų atstovų taikymu. Ankstesniame patikimo atstovavimo darbe daugiausia dėmesio buvo skiriama mažo lygio skirtumui tarp smulkių grūdų biomedicinos koncepcijų pavadinimų. These fine-grained concepts can also be clustered together to reflect higher-level, more general semantic distinctions, such as grouping the names nettle sting and tick-borne fever together under the description puncture wound of skin.  Iki šiol empiriniu požiūriu nebuvo patvirtinta, kad mokymas biomedicinio pavadinimo koduojant smulkių grūdų skirtumus automatiškai lemia tokių aukštesnio lygio semantikos kodavimą iš apačios į viršų. Šiame dokumente parodomi, kad šis poveikis iš apačios į viršų egzistuoja, tačiau jis vis dar yra palyginti ribotas. Kaip sprendimą siūlome skaliuojamą daugiafunkcinį mokymo režimą biomedicinių pavadinimų koduotojams, kurie taip pat gali pasimokyti patikimų atstovavimų naudojant tik aukštesnio lygio semantines klases. Šie atstovai gali generalizuoti įvairias semantines hierarchijas iš apačios į viršų ir iš viršaus į apačią. Moreover, we show how they can be used out-of-the-box for improved unsupervised detection of hypernyms, while retaining robust performance on various semantic relatedness benchmarks.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Neural encoders of biomedical names are typically considered robust if representations can be effectively exploited for various downstream NLP tasks.  За да го постигнат ова, кодерите мора да моделираат биомедициска семантика специфична за домените, истовремено ривалирајќи со универзалната апликабилност на предобучените самонадгледувани претставувања. Претходната работа на силни претставувања се фокусираше на учењето на разлики на ниско ниво помеѓу имињата на фини биомедициски концепти. Овие фино-зелени концепти, исто така, можат да се групираат заедно за да се одразат повисоко ниво, поопшта семантични разлики, како што е групирањето на имињата мрежна болка и температура пренесена со кликови заедно под описот пунктурна рана на кожата. Уште не е емпирички потврдено дека обуката на кодерите на биомедицинските имиња за финозерни разлики автоматски води до кодерање од долу нагоре на ваква семантика на високо ниво. Во оваа весник покажуваме дека овој ефект постои долу горе, но дека е сé уште релативно ограничен. Како решение, предложуваме скалиран режим за обука на мултизадачи за биомедицински кодери на името, кој исто така може да научи силни претставувања користејќи само семантични класи на повисоко ниво. Овие претставувања можат да ги генерализираат и од дното горе, како и од горе долу меѓу различните семантични хиерархии. Покрај тоа, покажуваме како може да се искористат надвор од кутијата за подобрено ненадгледувано детекција на хипернимите, при што се задржуваат силни резултати на различни семантични релативни значки.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Neural encoders of biomedical names are typically considered robust if representations can be effectively exploited for various downstream NLP tasks.  Untuk mencapai ini, pengekod perlu model semantik biomedikal spesifik domain sementara bertentangan dengan aplikabiliti universal bagi perwakilan yang diawasi oleh diri. Kerja terdahulu mengenai perwakilan yang kuat telah fokus pada belajar perbezaan aras rendah antara nama konsep biomedikal berwarna gandum. Koncep-konsep-benih halus ini juga boleh dikumpulkan bersama-sama untuk mencerminkan perbezaan semantik tinggi, yang lebih umum, seperti mengumpulkan nama-nama penyakit jaring dan demam yang dilakukan tiket bersama-sama di bawah luka puncture deskripsi kulit. Ia belum dikonfirmasi secara empirik bahawa pelatihan pengekod nama biomedikal pada perbezaan berwarna gandum secara automatik membawa kepada pengekodan bawah-atas semantik tinggi seperti ini. In this paper, we show that this bottom-up effect exists, but that it is still relatively limited.  Sebagai penyelesaian, kami cadangkan režim latihan berbilang-tugas yang boleh dipandang untuk pengekod nama biomedis yang juga boleh belajar perwakilan yang kuat menggunakan hanya kelas semantik tahap tinggi. Perwakilan ini boleh menyeluruhkan kedua-dua bawah-atas dan atas-bawah diantara pelbagai hierarki semantik. Selain itu, kita menunjukkan bagaimana mereka boleh digunakan keluar dari kotak untuk meningkatkan pengesan hipernim yang tidak diawasi, sementara menjaga prestasi yang kuat pada berbagai tanda referensi hubungan semantik.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ജീവിയ മെഡിക്കല്‍ പേരുകളുടെ നെയൂറല്‍ കോഡോര്‍ഡുകള്‍ സാധാരണയായി റോബ്സ്റ്റ് ചെയ്യപ്പെടുന്നു ഇത് പ്രാപിക്കാന്‍, ഡൊമെയിന്‍ - പ്രത്യേക ജീവിയ മെഡിക്കല്‍ സെമാന്റിക്കുകള്‍ മാതൃകയാക്കേണ്ടതുണ്ട്, പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട സ്വയം നിരീ റോബോസ്റ്റ് പ്രതിനിധികളുടെ മുമ്പുള്ള ജോലിയാണ് കുറഞ്ഞ നിലയിലെ വ്യത്യാസങ്ങള്‍ പഠിക്കുന്നത് എന്ന് ശ്രദ്ധിച് ഉയരത്തില്‍ നിന്നും കൂടുതല്‍ സെമാന്റിക്ക് വ്യത്യാസങ്ങള്‍ പ്രതിഫലിപ്പിക്കാനും, നെറ്റില്‍ കടിക്കുന്ന പേരുകള്‍ ഗ്രൂപ്പ് ചെയ്യുന്നതും തൊലിയുടെ മുറി സുന്ദരിതമായ വ്യത്യാസങ്ങളുടെ പേരിന്റെ പരിശീലിപ്പിക്കുന്നത് സ്വയമായി ഉയര്‍ന്ന നിലയിലെ സെമാന്റിക്കുകളുടെ അടിത്തടിയിലേക്ക്  ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു, ഈ താഴ്വരയുടെ പ്രഭാവം നിലനില്‍ക്കുന്നു എന്ന്, പക്ഷെ അത് ഇപ്പോഴും പരിധി ഒരു പരിഹാരത്തിനായി ഞങ്ങള്‍ ബയോമെഡിക്കല്‍ പേരിന്റെ പേരിന്റെ പ്രതിനിധികള്‍ക്ക് വേണ്ടിയുള്ള ഒരു മില്ല്യൂട്ട് ജോലി പരിശീലിക്ക ഈ പ്രതിനിധികള്‍ക്ക് താഴെയും താഴെയും സെമാന്റിക് ഹീരാര്‍ക്കികള്‍ക്കിടയില്‍ ഉയര്‍ന്നുകൊടുക്കാന്‍ കഴിയും. Moreover, we show how they can be used out-of-the-box for improved unsupervised detection of hypernyms, while retaining robust performance on various semantic relatedness benchmarks.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-kodifikaturi newrali tal-ismijiet bijomediċi tipikament jitqiesu robusti jekk ir-rappreżentazzjonijiet jistgħu jiġu sfruttati b’mod effettiv għal diversi kompiti downstream tal-NLP. Biex dan jinkiseb, jeħtieġ li l-kodifikaturi jimmudellaw semantika bijomedika speċifika għad-dominju filwaqt li jikkorrispondu mal-applikabbiltà universali tar-rappreżentazzjonijiet awtosorveljati mħarrġa minn qabel. Xogħol preċedenti fuq rappreżentazzjonijiet robusti ffoka fuq it-tagħlim ta’ distinzjonijiet ta’ livell baxx bejn ismijiet ta’ kunċetti bijomediċi ta’ ħbub fin. Dawn il-kunċetti ta’ ħbub fin jistgħu wkoll jiġu raggruppati flimkien biex jirriflettu distinzjonijiet semantiċi ta’ livell ogħla u aktar ġenerali, bħall-raggruppament tal-ismijiet għaż-żaqq tan-netwerk u d-deni tal-qurdien flimkien taħt il-ferita tat-titqib tad-deskrizzjoni tal-ġilda. Għad ma ġiex ikkonfermat empirikament li t-taħriġ tal-kodifikaturi tal-ismijiet bijomediċi dwar distinzjonijiet ta’ ħbub fin iwassal awtomatikament għall-kodifikazzjoni minn isfel għal fuq ta’ tali semantiċi ta’ livell ogħla. F’dan id-dokument, naraw li dan l-effett minn isfel għal fuq jeżisti, iżda li għadu relattivament limitat. Bħala soluzzjoni, nipproponu reġim ta' taħriġ b'ħafna kompiti skalabbli għall-kodifikaturi tal-ismijiet bijomediċi li jistgħu wkoll jitgħallmu rappreżentazzjonijiet robusti bl-użu ta' klassijiet semantiċi ta' livell ogħla biss. Dawn ir-rappreżentazzjonijiet jistgħu jiġġeneralizzaw kemm minn isfel għal fuq kif ukoll minn fuq għal isfel fost diversi ġerarkiji semantiċi. Barra minn hekk, naraw kif jistgħu jintużaw barra mill-kaxxa għal detezzjoni mtejba mhux sorveljata ta’ iperinimi, filwaqt li nżammu prestazzjoni robusta fuq diversi punti ta’ riferiment ta’ rabta semantika.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_kk>Биомедицина атауларының нейрондық кодері әдетте, егер кескіндер әртүрлі NLP тапсырмаларының көмегімен жұмыс істеуге мүмкін болса, қалыпты сияқты деп ойлайды. Бұны жеткізу үшін кодерлер доменге бөлек биомедикалық семантика үлгілеу керек, бірақ өзіңізді бақылау үшін әлемдік қолданбалардың әлемділігіне қарсы болып тұрады. Алдыңғы жұмыс құпты түсіндіру үшін төмен деңгейіндегі биомедикалық концепциялардың атаулары арасындағы түсіндірілген. Бұл тұтас тұтас концепциялары да жоғары деңгейінде, ең жалпы семантикалық түрлерді көрсетуге болады, мысалы, жалпы тұтас атауларын топтастыру және тұтас тұтас тұтас арқылы тұтас тұтас арқылы түсіні Бірақ бұл биомедикалық атау кодтарының автоматты түрде бұл ең жоғары деңгейіндегі семантикалық кодтарының төмендегі кодтамасын қолдану мүмкін емес. Бұл қағаздың төмендегі эффекті бар екенін көрсетеді, бірақ ол әлі қарапайым шектелген. Бұл шешім ретінде біз биомедикалық атау кодерлерінің көп тапсырмаларды оқыту режимін ұсынамыз. Бұл әрі тек жоғары деңгейіндегі семантикалық класстарды қолдануға болады. Бұл таңбалар екеуі төмендегі және жоғары және төмендегі әртүрлі семантикалық иерархиялардың арасында жалпы болады. Сонымен қатар, оларды гипернимдерді қалай қолдануға болады дегенді көрсету үшін, бірақ әртүрлі семантикалық қатынастығы бақылау үшін қалай қолдануға болады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mn>Биологийн эмнэлгийн нэрийн мэдрэлийн коддогчид ихэвчлэн үнэхээр хүчтэй гэж үздэг. Хэрвээ харилцаа нь олон нийтлэг NLP ажиллагаанд үр дүнтэй ашиглаж болох юм. Үүнийг хүртэхийн тулд коддогчид өөрийгөө удирдлагатай үзүүлэлтийн универсал хэрэгжүүлэх боломжтой биологийн эмнэлгийн хэмжээсүүдийг загварчлах хэрэгтэй. Өмнөх ажил нь бага түвшинд бага хэмжээний биологийн эмнэлгийн ойлголтын нэр хоорондын ялгааг сурах юм. Эдгээр сайхан тарианы ойлголт мөн хамтдаа өндөр түвшинд, илүү ерөнхий семантийн ялгааг харуулахын тулд хамтдаа хамтдаа байж болно. Биологийн эрүүл мэндийн нэр коддогчид бага зэрэг тодорхойлолтын тулд автоматаар бага зэрэг өндөр хэмжээний семантикийн коддогч байдаг гэдгийг батлаагүй. Энэ цаасан дээр бид энэ доорх нөлөө байдаг гэхдээ энэ нь харьцангуй хязгаарлагддаг гэдгийг харуулж байна. Харин шийдэл гэхээр бид биологийн эмнэлгийн нэр кодеруудын хэмжээний олон ажлын сургалтын төлөвлөгөөг суралцах боломжтой. Энэ нь зөвхөн өндөр төвшин semantic хичээлийг ашиглаж чадна. Эдгээр үзүүлэлт нь хоёр доор болон дээд доор нь олон төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн төрлийн Мөн бид тэднийг хипернимд сайжруулахад хэрхэн ашиглаж болох вэ гэдгийг харуулж байна. Хипернимд сайжруулагдаагүй олон төрлийн семантийн харилцааны сайжруулалт дээр шинэ үйл ажиллагааг сайжруулж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Kodery neuronowe nazw biomedycznych są zazwyczaj uważane za solidne, jeśli reprezentacje mogą być skutecznie wykorzystywane do różnych dalszych zadań NLP. Aby to osiągnąć, kodery muszą modelować specyficzną semantykę biomedyczną dla domeny, konkurując jednocześnie z uniwersalnym zastosowaniem wstępnie przeszkolonych reprezentacji samodzielnie nadzorowanych. Poprzednie prace nad solidnymi reprezentacjami koncentrowały się na nauce niskiego poziomu różnic między nazwami drobnoziarnistych koncepcji biomedycznych. Te drobnoziarniste koncepcje mogą być również skupione razem w celu odzwierciedlenia wyższego poziomu, bardziej ogólnych różnic semantycznych, takich jak grupowanie nazw użądlenia pokrzywy i gorączki przenoszonej kleszczem razem pod opisem rany kłute skóry. Nie zostało jeszcze empirycznie potwierdzone, że szkolenie biomedycznych koderów nazw na drobnoziarnistych rozróżnieniach automatycznie prowadzi do oddolnego kodowania takiej semantyki wyższego poziomu. W niniejszym artykule pokazujemy, że efekt oddolny istnieje, ale nadal jest stosunkowo ograniczony. Jako rozwiązanie proponujemy skalowalny wielozadaniowy system szkoleniowy dla biomedycznych koderów nazw, który może również uczyć się solidnych reprezentacji wykorzystując tylko wyższe klasy semantyczne. Reprezentacje te mogą uogólniać zarówno oddolne, jak i odgórne wśród różnych hierarchii semantycznych. Ponadto pokazujemy, w jaki sposób można je wykorzystać gotowo do lepszego wykrywania hipernimów bez nadzoru, przy jednoczesnym zachowaniu solidnej wydajności w różnych wskaźnikach odniesienia związków semantycznych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Nøyrale kodar av biomedisinske namn vert vanlegvis kalla som robust dersom representasjonar kan brukast for ulike nedstrekke NLP-oppgåver. For å oppnå dette må kodarar modellera biomediske semantikk for domenespesifikke domenespesifikke, mens det gjer mot den universelle tilgjengelege tilgjengelege representasjonane som er sjølvovervåka. Førre arbeid på robust representasjonar har fokusert på læring av låg nivå skilnader mellom namn på fyrste biomediske konseptar. Desse fine-grained konseptene kan også bli kopla saman for å refleksera høgare nivå, meir generelle semantiske distikasjonar, slik som grupperer namnene på nettstrek og fjerne feil saman under beskrivelsespunktursjøden av tema. Det er ikkje noko empirisk stadfesting at opplæring av biomedisinske namnkoder på fine-grained skilnader automatisk fører til nedtrekkkoding av slike høgare nivå semantikk. I denne papiret viser vi at denne nederste effekten finst, men at det er fortsatt relativt begrenset. Som løysing, fører vi ein skalerbar fleire oppgåver- treningsregime for biomedisinske namnkodingar som også kan lære robust representasjonar med berre høgare nivå semantiske klasser. Desse representasjonane kan generellisere både nedover og topp nedover blant ulike semantiske hierarki. I tillegg viser vi korleis dei kan brukast ut av boksen for å forbetra utrekninga av hypernymar, mens det beholder robust utvikling på ulike semantiske relatede benchmarker.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Encoderele neurale ale denumirilor biomedicale sunt de obicei considerate robuste dacă reprezentările pot fi exploatate în mod eficient pentru diferite sarcini din aval ale PNL. Pentru a realiza acest lucru, codificatorii trebuie să modeleze semantica biomedicală specifică domeniului, rivalizând în același timp cu aplicabilitatea universală a reprezentărilor pre-instruite auto-supravegheate. Lucrările anterioare privind reprezentările solide s-au axat pe învățarea distincțiilor la nivel scăzut între numele conceptelor biomedicale cu granulație fină. Aceste concepte cu granulație fină pot fi, de asemenea, grupate împreună pentru a reflecta distincții semantice de nivel mai înalt, mai generale, cum ar fi gruparea numelor înțepături de urzică și febră purtată de căpușe sub descrierea plănii perforate a pielii. Nu a fost încă confirmat empiric faptul că instruirea codificatoarelor biomedicale de nume pe distincții fine duce automat la codificarea de jos în sus a unor astfel de semantice de nivel superior. În această lucrare, arătăm că acest efect de jos în sus există, dar că este încă relativ limitat. Ca soluție, propunem un regim scalabil de formare multi-sarcină pentru codificatoarele biomedicale de nume, care pot învăța, de asemenea, reprezentări robuste folosind doar clase semantice de nivel superior. Aceste reprezentări pot generaliza atât de jos în sus, cât și de sus în jos în rândul diverselor ierarhii semantice. Mai mult decât atât, arătăm modul în care acestea pot fi utilizate din nou pentru o detectare îmbunătățită nesupravegheată a hipernimelor, menținând în același timp performanțe robuste pe diferite criterii de referință de relație semantică.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sv>Neurala kodare av biomedicinska namn anses vanligtvis vara robusta om representationer kan utnyttjas effektivt för olika NLP-uppgifter nedströms. För att uppnå detta måste kodare modellera domänspecifik biomedicinsk semantik samtidigt som de konkurrerar med universell tillämplighet av förkränade självövervakade representationer. Tidigare arbete med robusta representationer har fokuserat på att lära sig lågnivåskillnader mellan namn på finkorniga biomedicinska begrepp. Dessa finkorniga begrepp kan också grupperas tillsammans för att återspegla högre nivå, mer allmänna semantiska distinktioner, såsom gruppering av namnen nässelstick och fästingburen feber tillsammans under beskrivningen punkteringssår på huden. Det har ännu inte empiriskt bekräftats att utbildning av biomedicinska namnkodare på finkorniga distinktioner automatiskt leder till nedifrån-och-upp-kodning av sådan semantik på högre nivå. I denna uppsats visar vi att denna bottom-up effekt existerar, men att den fortfarande är relativt begränsad. Som en lösning föreslår vi en skalbar flerfunktionsutbildning för biomedicinska namnkodare som också kan lära sig robusta representationer med hjälp av endast högre semantiska klasser. Dessa representationer kan generalisera både nedifrån och upp samt uppifrån och ner bland olika semantiska hierarkier. Dessutom visar vi hur de kan användas direkt för förbättrad oövervakad upptäckt av hypernymer, samtidigt som vi behåller robust prestanda på olika semantiska referensvärden.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Neuralni koderi biomedicinskih imena obično se smatraju robnim ako se predstavljanja mogu efektivno iskoristiti za različite zadatke NLP. Da bi to ostvarili, koderi moraju da modele biomedicinske semantike posebne domene, dok se suprotstavljaju univerzalnoj primjenljivosti predviđenih autonadzornih predstavljanja. Prethodni rad na robnim predstavljanjima fokusirao se na učenje razlike niskog nivoa između imena finog biomedicinskog koncepta. Ovi koncepti od finog zrnca mogu biti skupljeni zajedno kako bi odrazili visoke nivoe, opće semantičke razlike, kao što su skupljanje imena punjenja mreže i groznica koja se pojavljuje ispod rane kože punkcije opisa. Još nije empirički potvrđeno da obuka kodera biomedicinskih imena na finog zrnca automatski vodi do kodiranja takvih semantika na visokom nivou. U ovom papiru pokazujemo da ovaj efekt dole postoji, ali da je i dalje relativno ograničen. Kao rešenje, predlažemo mjerljiv režim vežbanja multizadataka za kodere biomedicinskih imena koji takođe mogu naučiti robne predstave koristeći samo semantičke klase višeg nivoa. Ovi predstavnici mogu generalizovati i dole, kao i dole među različitim semantičkim hijerarhijama. Osim toga, pokazujemo kako se mogu iskoristiti izvan kutije za poboljšanje neodređenog otkrivanja hipernima, dok zadržavamo jaku predstavu na različitim semantičkim standardima veze.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Qoryaha naafada ah ee magaca dhakhaatiirta ah waxaa sida caadiga ah loo tiriyaa karo tuug, haddii qofka xuquuqda ah lagu faa’iido karo shaqaalaha NLP oo kala duduwan. Si uu u gaadho, qodaxda waxaa u baahan in ay u sameynaan dawooyinka cayiman ee dhakhaatiirta dabeecada ee gaarka ah, iyadoo la sameynayo habka caalamiga ah ee qofka iska ilaalinaya. Shaqo hore oo ku saabsan qofka lagu soo bandhigay waxyaabaha lagu soo bandhigay wuxuu ku kalsoonaaday barashada kala duwan heerka hoose ee magacyada fikrada dhakhaatiirta. Sidoo kale waxaa la wada qabsan karaa fikradan si ay u fiiriyaan heerka sare, kala duwanaanshaha caadiga ah, tusaale ahaan kooxa magaca boosaska shabakadda iyo qandhada lagu xambaaro oo ku qoran karo dhaawaca jidhka. Waxaa weli loo xaqiijiyey in waxbarashada magaca caafimaadka ee biofimaadka ah oo ku qoran kala duwan oo si fiican loo qoray ay ay automatic u leedahay kodeynta hoose ee heerka sare. Warqadan waxan ka muujinaynaa in saamaynta hoose ee ay jiraan, laakiin weli waa xad daranyahay. Sida xal ah, waxaynu u soo jeedaynaa nidaamka waxbarashada shaqada oo kala duduwan ee magaca caafimaadka ah, kuwaas oo sidoo kale baran kara kooxaha robotiga ee lagu isticmaali karo fasalka semantika sare oo kaliya. These representations can generalise both bottom-up as well as top-down among various semantic hierarchies.  Sidoo kale waxaynu tusnaa sidoo kale looga isticmaali karo sanduuqiga si loo hagaajiyo aqoonta badnaanta, iyadoo lagu sii haysto tababarida dhimirka oo ku saabsan xariirka kala duduwan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>ජීවිත වෛද්‍ය නාමයේ නිර්මාණික කෝඩර්ස් සාමාන්‍ය විශ්වාසයෙන් නිර්මාණය වෙන්න පුළුවන් නම් සාමාන්‍ය විශ මේක ප්‍රමාණය කරන්න, කෝඩාර්ටර්ට ඩොමේන් විශේෂ ජීවිත වෛද්‍ය සෙමැන්ටික් මද්ද්‍ය කරන්න ඕනි වගේම, ප්‍රමාණය ස්වාම්ප මුලින් වැඩේ සාධාරණ ප්‍රතිශ්නයක් ගැන ප්‍රතිශ්නයක් ඉගෙන ගන්න පුළුවන් ප්‍රතිශ්නයක් තියෙනවා. මේ සාමාන්‍ය ක්‍රීන්ඩ් අදහස් සමහර වෙන්න පුළුවන් විතරයි, වඩා සාමාන්‍ය සෙමැන්ටික් විශේෂ විශේෂය, වගේම නම් නැට්ල් ස්ටින්ට් සහ ටික් බෝර ඒක තවමත් ප්‍රශ්නයක් නැහැ කියලා තියෙන්නේ නැහැ ජීවිත වෛද්‍යාත්මක නාම කෝඩාර්ඩ් වලට ස්වයංක්‍රීය විශේෂයෙන් ස්ව මේ පත්තරේ අපි පෙන්වන්නේ මේ පහළ ප්‍රභාව තියෙනවා කියලා, ඒත් ඒක තවමත් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සීමාවිත වෙනවා. ප්‍රතිශ්නයක් විදිහට, අපි ප්‍රතිශ්නයක් කරන්න පුළුවන් වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි වැඩි  මේ ප්‍රතිනිධානයට පුළුවන් පහළ අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අඩු අ තවත්, අපි පෙන්වන්නේ ඔවුන්ට කොහොමද ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න පුළුවන් කියලා, හායිපර්නිම්ස් ගැන හොයාගන්න විශේෂ නිර්මාණය සඳහා විශේෂ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>ஜையோமருத்துவப் பெயர்களின் நெயுரல் குறியீடுகள் பிரதிநிதிகள் NLP பணிகளுக்கு பயன்படுத்தப்படும் என்றால் பொதுவாக துண்டு To achieve this, encoders need to model domain-specific biomedical semantics while rivaling the universal applicability of pretrained self-supervised representations.  முந்தைய வேலை முன்பு ரோப்ட் குறைந்த மட்டத்திற்கும் வேறுபாடுகளை கற்றுக் கொள்ள முடியும். நன்றாக்கப்பட்ட ஜியோ இந்த நன்றாக்கப்பட்ட கருத்துக்கள் உயர்நிலையில் சேர்க்க முடியும், அதிக பொதுவான பாதுகாப்பு வேறுபாடுகளை பிரிப்பதற்காகவும் ஒன்றாக சேர்க்கப்படும், அதா இது இன்னும் வெறுமையாக உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டிருக்கவில்லை என்றால் பிடிக்கப்பட்ட வேறுபாடுகளில் உயிரியல் பெயர் குறியீடுகளை பயிற்ச இந்த காகிதத்தில், இந்த கீழ் மேல் விளைவு இருக்கிறது என்பதை நாம் காட்டுகிறோம், ஆனால் அது இன்னும் சுற்றில்  ஒரு தீர்வாக இருந்தால், நாம் ஒரு பல பணி பயிற்சி விதிமுறைமையை பரிந்துரைக்கிறோம். ஜையோமரிக்கல் பெயர் குறியீட்டுகளுக்கு இது மேலு இந்த குறிப்புகள் இருவரும் கீழ் மேல் மற்றும் மேல் கீழே உருவாக்க முடியும். மேலும், நாம் எவ்வாறு அவர்கள் உபயோகிக்க முடியும் பெட்டி வெளிப்பெட்டியிலிருந்து உபயோகிக்க முடியும் என்பதை காட்டுகிறோம், பாதுகாப்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>بیوڈیسٹریک ناموں کے نیورال اکڈر عمدہ طور پر مضبوط سمجھے جاتے ہیں اگر نمایش مختلف NLP کاموں کے لئے اثرات کے ساتھ استعمال کر سکتے ہیں۔ اس پر پہنچانے کے لئے کوڈروں کو ڈومین کے مطابق مخصوص بیولوڈیسی سیمانٹیکوں کی مدل کی ضرورت ہے جب کہ ان کے سارے سارے سارے نظارت کی عمومی کاربردی سے مخالف ہوتی ہے. مضبوط نمایش کے بارے میں پہلے کام کم سطح کے ناموں کے درمیان پاکیزہ دانے بیوڈیسی نظریں کی تفریق کا ذریعہ دکھائی گیا ہے. یہ نیک دانے کی نظریں بھی ایک دوسرے کے ساتھ جمع کئے جائیں گے کہ اس سے زیادہ بلند سطح، زیادہ عمومی سیمنٹی اختلاف کریں، جیسے کہ اسم کے نام جمع کئے جائیں جو نیٹ سینٹ سینٹ اور چک بورنے والی جہنم کی جہنم کے ذریعہ ایک دوسرے کے ساتھ جمع کئے جائیں اب تک مضبوط طور پر ثابت نہیں کی گئی کہ زیاترین پزشکی نام کی تعلیم کے ذریعہ سیمانٹیکوں کے ذریعہ سیمانٹیکوں کے نیچے سیمنٹیکوں کی کوڈر کی جاتی ہے. ہم اس کاغذ میں دکھاتے ہیں کہ یہ نیچے پاؤں کے اثر موجود ہے، لیکن یہ اب بھی نسبتا محدود ہے۔ ہم ایک حل کے طور پر ایک مقدار قابل multi-task ترینیسی ریجیم کی پیشنهاد کرتے ہیں جو بیولوڈیسی نام کوڈر کے لئے ہے جو صرف بلند سطح سیمنٹی کلاس کے مطابق استعمال کر رہے ہیں۔ یہ نشانیاں دونوں نیچے اوپر اور ٹوپ نیچے مختلف سمantic hierarchies میں عام کر سکتے ہیں. اور ہم نشان دیتے ہیں کہ ان کو کس طرح بیرون بوکس سے استعمال کیا جاتا ہے کہ ان کی آزمائش کو اضافہ نہیں کی جاتی اور مختلف سیمانٹی رابطہ سنچروں پر ثابت قدم رکھتے ہیں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Buni amalga oshirish uchun kodlash qoidalari domen-specific biomediya semantika modelini modellashi kerak, balki o'zgarishni o'zgartirib tasavvur qilish uchun umumiy qobiliyatni rivojlantirish kerak. Oldingi robot tashkilotlari bilan birinchi ish qo'shilgan biotika g'oyalari orasidagi eng darajada o'rganishga qaramadi. Bu ajoyib fikrlarni eng yuqori darajaga, ko'proq semantik o'zgarishga birlashtirish mumkin. Masalan, shamol suv va suhbat qog'ozida qog'ozni guruhlash mumkin. Hech qachon tasavvur qilmagan emas, yaxshi qo'llangan ajoyib tibbiy kodlash qoidalarini avtomatik yuqori darajaga kodlash imkoniyatini bajaradi. Bu qogʻozda biz bu pastki effekti mavjud, lekin bu juda qisqarli. Bu yo'l qilib, biz bir necha vazifa taʼminlovchi tizimni biomedical nom kodlash qoidalari uchun taʼminlovchi qilamiz. Bu qoidalar faqat eng darajada semantik sinflari yordamida robot representarini o'rganadi. Bu tashkilotlar har xil semantik hierarchalarning orasidagi ikkita pastga va eng yuqoriga yaratishi mumkin. Moreover, we show how they can be used out-of-the-box for improved unsupervised detection of hypernyms, while retaining robust performance on various semantic relatedness benchmarks.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Mã hóa thần kinh của tên sinh học thường được xem là mạnh mẽ nếu các biểu tượng có thể được khai thác thực tế cho các công việc sục sạo xuôi dòng. Để đạt được điều này, các bộ mã hóa cần mô hình... ngữ pháp sinh học quy mô đặc trưng miền, trong khi sánh được với sử dụng chung của các biểu tượng tự giám sát. Trước đây, các biểu tượng mạnh mẽ đã tập trung vào việc học sự khác biệt cấp thấp giữa các tên của các định nghĩa sinh học. Những ý niệm sắc màu này cũng có thể được ráp lại với nhau để phản ánh những sự khác biệt theo cấp độ cao, theo khái niệm thì đơn giản hơn, như kết hợp những cái tên đốt cháy cây và các con bọ chét với nhau dưới vết thương đào tạo trên da. Chưa có kinh nghiệm xác nhận rằng việc huấn luyện mã hóa chữ ký sinh học trên các sự khác biệt sắc màu tự động dẫn đến việc mã hóa nền ngữ học cao cấp. Trong tờ giấy này, chúng ta cho thấy hiệu ứng từ dưới lên tồn tại, nhưng nó vẫn còn khá hạn chế. Như một giải pháp, chúng tôi đề xuất một chế độ đào tạo đa nhiệm vụ đáng chú ý cho bộ mã hóa tên sinh học cũng có thể học được những biểu hiện mạnh mẽ chỉ dựa trên lớp ngữ pháp cao cấp. Các biểu tượng này có thể tổng hợp cả hai từ trên cùng cũng như từ trên xuống trong các thứ phân biệt. Hơn nữa, chúng tôi cho thấy làm thế nào để họ có thể sử dụng ngoài lề hộp để phát hiện các siêu năng động không giám sát, đồng thời giữ vững hiệu suất dựa trên các điểm liên quan.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Невронните кодери на биомедицински имена обикновено се считат за стабилни, ако изображенията могат ефективно да бъдат експлоатирани за различни задачи по НЛП надолу по веригата. За да се постигне това, кодерите трябва да моделират специфична за домейн биомедицинска семантика, като същевременно съперничат на универсалната приложимост на предварително обучените самостоятелно контролирани представи. Предишната работа по солидни представи се фокусира върху изучаването на разграничения на ниско ниво между имената на фините биомедицински концепции. Тези финозърнести концепции също могат да бъдат обединени заедно, за да отразяват по-високо ниво, по-общи семантични различия, като например групиране на имената коприва жило и кърлежова треска заедно под описанието на прободната рана на кожата. Все още не е емпирично потвърдено, че обучението на биомедицински кодери за имена на фино-зърнести разграничения автоматично води до кодиране отдолу нагоре на такава семантика от по-високо ниво. В тази статия показваме, че този ефект отдолу нагоре съществува, но все още е сравнително ограничен. Като решение предлагаме мащабируем режим на обучение с многозадачи за биомедицински кодери на имена, който също може да научи надеждни изображения, използвайки само семантични класове на по-високо ниво. Тези представяния могат да обобщават както отдолу нагоре, така и отгоре надолу сред различни семантични йерархии. Освен това, ние показваме как те могат да бъдат използвани извън кутията за подобрено ненадзорно откриване на хиперними, като същевременно се запазва солидна производителност на различни семантични показатели за свързаност.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Neurale kodere af biomedicinske navne betragtes typisk som robuste, hvis repræsentationer effektivt kan udnyttes til forskellige downstreams NLP-opgaver. For at opnå dette skal kodere modellere domænespecifik biomedicinsk semantik samtidig med at konkurrere med den universelle anvendelighed af forudtrænede selvovervågede repræsentationer. Tidligere arbejde med robuste repræsentationer har fokuseret på at lære lav niveau skelnen mellem navne på finkornede biomedicinske begreber. Disse finkornede begreber kan også klynges sammen for at afspejle højere niveau, mere generelle semantiske forskelle, såsom gruppering af navnene nældestik og flåter-båret feber sammen under beskrivelsen punkteringssår på huden. Det er endnu ikke empirisk bekræftet, at uddannelse af biomedicinske navnekodere på finkornede skelninger automatisk fører til bottom-up kodning af en sådan semantik på højere niveau. I denne artikel viser vi, at denne bottom-up effekt eksisterer, men at den stadig er relativt begrænset. Som en løsning foreslår vi en skalerbar multi-task træningsordning for biomedicinske navnekodere, som også kan lære robuste repræsentationer ved hjælp af kun højere niveau semantiske klasser. Disse repræsentationer kan generalisere både bottom-up og top-down blandt forskellige semantiske hierarkier. Desuden viser vi, hvordan de kan bruges ud af boksen til forbedret uautoriseret detektion af hypernymer, samtidig med at de bevarer robust ydeevne på forskellige semantiske relaterethedsbenchmarks.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Neuralni koderi biomedicinskih imena obično se smatraju jakim ako se predstavljanja mogu učinkovito iskoristiti za različite zadatke NLP-a. Da bi to ostvarili, koderi moraju modelirati biomedicinske semantike posebne domene dok se suprotstavljaju univerzalnoj primjenljivosti predviđenih autonadzornih predstavljanja. Prethodni rad na snažnim predstavljanjima usredotočio se na učenje razlika niskog nivoa između imena lijepog biomedicinskog koncepta. Također se mogu skupljati i ovi zglobljeni koncepti kako bi razmišljali o višem nivou, općem semantičkim razlikama, kao što su skupljanje imena oštećenja mreže i groznica koja se pojavljuje pod ozljedem kože. Još nije empirički potvrđeno da obuka kodera biomedicinskih imena na fino zrno razlike automatski vodi do gornjeg kodiranja takvih semantika na višem nivou. U ovom papiru pokazujemo da ovaj efekt dolje postoji, ali da je i dalje relativno ograničen. Kao rješenje, predlažemo mjerljiv režim multizadatačnog obuke za kodere biomedicinskih imena koji također mogu naučiti jak predstavljanja koristeći samo semantičke klase višeg nivoa. Ovi predstavnici mogu generalizirati i dolje, kao i dolje među različitim semantičkim hijerarhijama. Osim toga, pokazujemo kako se mogu koristiti izvan kutije za poboljšanje neodređenog otkrivanja hipernima, dok zadržavamo jače učinke na različitim semantičkim kriterijama veze s odnosima.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Neurale encoders van biomedische namen worden meestal als robuust beschouwd als representaties effectief kunnen worden benut voor verschillende downstream NLP taken. Om dit te bereiken, moeten encoders domeinspecifieke biomedische semantiek modelleren, terwijl ze concurreren met de universele toepasbaarheid van vooraf getrainde zelfbegeleide representaties. Eerder werk aan robuuste representaties heeft zich toegespitst op het leren van onderscheid op laag niveau tussen namen van fijnkorrelige biomedische concepten. Deze fijnkorrelige concepten kunnen ook worden geclusterd om hogere, meer algemene semantische onderscheidingen te weerspiegelen, zoals het groeperen van de namen brandnetelsteek en teken-overgedragen koorts samen onder de beschrijving punctiewond van de huid. Het is nog niet empirisch bevestigd dat het trainen van biomedische naamcoders op fijnkorrelige onderscheidingen automatisch leidt tot bottom-up codering van dergelijke semantiek op hoger niveau. In dit artikel laten we zien dat dit bottom-up effect bestaat, maar dat het nog relatief beperkt is. Als oplossing stellen we een schaalbaar multi-task trainingsregime voor biomedische naamencoders voor die ook robuuste representaties kunnen leren met alleen hogere semantische klassen. Deze representaties kunnen zowel bottom-up als top-down generaliseren tussen verschillende semantische hiërarchieën. Bovendien laten we zien hoe ze out-of-the-box kunnen worden gebruikt voor een verbeterde onbeheerde detectie van hyperniemen, met behoud van robuuste prestaties op verschillende semantische relatedness benchmarks.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Neural encoders of biomedical names are typically considered robust if representations can be effectively exploited for various downstream NLP tasks.  Untuk mencapai ini, pengekoder perlu model semantik biomedis spesifik domain sementara bertentangan dengan aplikabilitas universal dari represensi yang diawasi oleh diri sendiri. Pekerjaan sebelumnya pada represisi yang kuat telah fokus pada belajar perbedaan tingkat rendah antara nama konsep biomedis berkulit gandum. Koncep-konsep fine grained ini juga dapat berkumpul bersama-sama untuk merefleksi perbedaan semantis tinggi, lebih umum, seperti mengumpulkan nama-nama netle sting dan demam yang dilahirkan tick bersama-sama di bawah deskripsi luka puncture kulit. Belum dikonfirmasi secara empirik bahwa pelatihan pengekode nama biomedis pada perbedaan berwarna gandum secara otomatis menyebabkan pengekodan bawah-atas dari semantik tingkat lebih tinggi. Dalam kertas ini, kami menunjukkan bahwa efek bawah-atas ini ada, tapi bahwa efek tersebut masih relatif terbatas. Sebagai solusi, kami mengusulkan skema pelatihan multi-tugas yang dapat diperbaiki untuk pengekoder nama biomedis yang juga dapat belajar representation yang kuat menggunakan hanya kelas semantis tingkat tinggi. Perwakilan ini dapat menggeneralisasi baik dari bawah ke atas dan dari atas ke bawah di antara berbagai hierarki semantis. Selain itu, kami menunjukkan bagaimana mereka dapat digunakan keluar dari kotak untuk meningkatkan deteksi tidak diawasi hipernim, sementara mempertahankan prestasi yang kuat pada berbagai benchmark hubungan semantis.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Neuronale Encoder biomedizinischer Namen gelten typischerweise als robust, wenn Repräsentationen effektiv für verschiedene nachgelagerte NLP-Aufgaben genutzt werden können. Um dies zu erreichen, müssen Encoder domänenspezifische biomedizinische Semantik modellieren und gleichzeitig die universelle Anwendbarkeit vortrainierter selbstüberwachter Repräsentationen konkurrieren. Bisherige Arbeiten zu robusten Repräsentationen konzentrierten sich auf das Erlernen von Unterscheidungen auf niedriger Ebene zwischen Namen feinkörniger biomedizinischer Konzepte. Diese feinkörnigen Konzepte können auch gruppiert werden, um übergeordnete, allgemeinere semantische Unterscheidungen widerzuspiegeln, wie die Gruppierung der Namen Brennnesselstich und Zeckenfieber zusammen unter der Bezeichnung Stichwunde der Haut. Es ist bisher nicht empirisch bestätigt, dass das Training biomedizinischer Namenscoder auf feinkörnigen Unterscheidungen automatisch zur Bottom-up-Kodierung solcher übergeordneten Semantik führt. In diesem Beitrag zeigen wir, dass dieser Bottom-up-Effekt existiert, aber noch relativ begrenzt ist. Als Lösung schlagen wir ein skalierbares Multi-Task-Trainingsregime für biomedizinische Namenscoder vor, das auch robuste Repräsentationen mit nur übergeordneten semantischen Klassen erlernen kann. Diese Darstellungen können sowohl bottom-up als auch top-down in verschiedenen semantischen Hierarchien verallgemeinern. Darüber hinaus zeigen wir, wie sie out-of-the-box für eine verbesserte unüberwachte Erkennung von Hypernymen verwendet werden können, während gleichzeitig eine robuste Performance auf verschiedenen semantischen Relatedness Benchmarks beibehalten wird.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>هنگامی که نمایش‌دهندگان برای کار های NLP پایین‌ترین پایین‌ترین استفاده می‌شوند، معمولاً نام‌های بیولوژیک‌ها استفاده می‌کنند. برای رسیدن به این، رمزگاران نیاز به مدل سیمانتیک بیولوژیکی ویژه‌ای دارند در حالی که در مقابل کاربردی جهانی از نمایش‌های خودکنترل شده‌اند رقابت کنند. کارهای قبلی که روی نمایش های قوی تمرکز می کنند روی تعلیم تفاوت سطح پایین بین اسم مفهوم های بیولوپزشکی خوب دانه شده تمرکز می کنند. این مفهوم‌های خوشمزه‌ای همچنین می‌توانند با هم جمع شوند تا تفاوت‌های طبقه بالاتر، طبقه‌های semantic بیشتری را توضیح دهند، مانند جمع کردن نام‌هایی که جرقه‌های زنجیره‌ها و جرقه‌های غذایی با هم در زیر زخم‌های تفسیر پوست است. هنوز تایید نشده است که تعلیم نام بیوپزشکی زیستی در تفاوت‌های دانه‌های نیکو به طور خودکار به رمزبندی زیر بالا از چنین سیمانتیک‌های سطح بالا می‌رسد. در این کاغذ، نشان می دهیم که این اثر پایین بالا وجود دارد، ولی هنوز نسبتا محدود است. به عنوان یک راه حل، ما یک režiم آموزش چندین کاری قابل مقدار برای اسم زیست پزشکی پیشنهاد می کنیم که همچنین می توانند نمایش های قوی را یاد بگیرند با استفاده از فقط کلاس های semantic سطح بالاتر. این نمایش‌دهندگان می‌توانند هر دو پایین‌بالا و بالا‌پایین را در میان آفرینش‌های سنتی‌های مختلف عمومی گردانند. علاوه بر این، ما نشان می دهیم که چگونه می توانند از بیرون جعبه استفاده شوند برای شناسایی غیرقابل توجه از هیپرنیم، در حالی که عملکرد استثنایی قوی در مقدار مختلف نقطه‌های آرامش سیمانتی نگه دارند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>다양한 다운스트림 NLP 임무에 효과적으로 활용할 수 있다고 밝히면 생물의학적 이름의 신경 인코더는 일반적으로 건장하다고 여겨진다.이를 실현하기 위해 인코더는 특정 분야의 생물의학적 의미 모델링을 하고 예비 훈련 자체 감독이 표시하는 보편적인 적용성과 맞물려야 한다.앞서 루팡에 대한 작업은 세립도 생물의학 개념 명칭 간의 저급한 차이에 집중됐다.이런 섬세한 입도의 개념도 한데 모여 더욱 높은 차원, 더욱 일반적인 의미 차이를 나타낼 수 있다. 예를 들어 심마침과 진드기 전열병이라는 두 명칭을 피부자상 묘사로 분류할 수 있다.경험에 의하면 생물의학 명칭 인코더에 대해 세립도 구분 훈련을 하면 이런 더 높은 의미의 밑바닥 인코딩을 자동으로 초래할 수 있다.본고에서 우리는 이러한 아래에서 위로의 효과가 존재한다는 것을 증명했지만, 그것은 여전히 상대적으로 유한하다.해결 방안으로서 우리는 확장 가능한 다중 임무 생물의학 명칭 인코더 훈련 메커니즘을 제시했다. 이 메커니즘은 더욱 높은 등급의 의미류만 사용하여 루팡의 표시를 배울 수 있다.이러한 표시는 각종 의미 차원 구조에서 아래에서 위로, 위에서 아래로 요약할 수 있다.그 밖에 우리는 각종 의미 관련성 기준 테스트에서 양호한 성능을 유지하는 동시에 초어를 개선하는 무감독 검측에 사용할 수 있는 상자를 열어 놓았다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sq>Koduesit nervorë të emrave biomedikë zakonisht konsiderohen të fortë në qoftë se përfaqësimet mund të shfrytëzohen efektivisht për detyra të ndryshme të NLP. Për ta arritur këtë, koduesit duhet të modelojnë semantikën biomedikale specifike në domeni ndërsa rivalizojnë aplikabilitetin universal të përfaqësimeve të mbikqyrura nga përpara. Puna e mëparshme mbi përfaqësime të forta është përqëndruar në mësimin e dallimeve të nivelit të ulët midis emrave të koncepteve biomedikë të hollë. Këto koncepte me kokrra të holla mund të mblidhen së bashku për të pasqyruar dallime më të larta, më të përgjithshme semantike, të tilla si grupimi i emrave rrjeti pikë dhe temperatura me kuti së bashku nën përshkrimin e plagës pikë të lëkurës. It has not yet been empirically confirmed that training biomedical name encoders on fine-grained distinctions automatically leads to bottom-up encoding of such higher-level semantics.  Në këtë letër, ne tregojmë se ky efekt nga poshtë lart ekziston, por që është ende relativisht i kufizuar. Si zgjidhje, ne propozojmë një regjim trajnimi të shkallëzueshëm me shumë detyra për koduesit e emrave biomedikë që gjithashtu mund të mësojnë përfaqësime të forta duke përdorur vetëm klasa semantike të nivelit të lartë. Këto përfaqësime mund të gjeneralizojnë si poshtë-lart si poshtë-poshtë midis hierarkive të ndryshme semantike. Përveç kësaj, ne tregojmë se si mund të përdoren jashtë kutisë për zbulimin e përmirësuar të hiperinimeve pa mbikqyrje, duke mbajtur performancë të fortë në pika të ndryshme të lidhjes semantike.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Biýolar медицинскi adlaryň nädogry ködlemeleri, eger täsirler NLP täzelikleri üçin ulanyp biljek bolsa, adatça ködlemeler güýçli diýip kabul edilýär. Bunu başarmak için kodlayıcılar, domun özellikle biyolojik tıbbi semantik örneklerini örtmek zorunda, önünsel özel gözlemlerinin evrensel uygulama uygulanması gerekiyor. Ýagyrky temsiller barada öňki işiň iň düşük derejä biomedical düşünjeleriniň adynyň tapawutlaryny öwrenmek üçin üns berdi. Bu ýokary çyzgyly düşünjeler bilelikde ýokary derejesi, semantik üýtgeşmeleri ýaly adlary toparlamak we çyzgylan atly hasaplamak üçin bile birleştirilebilir. Häli hem beýik dereje semantika üçin biomedical ady kodçularynyň düzümlenmesiniň üstünde kodlemesiniň ködlemesine mümkin edilmedi. Bu kagyzda, biz bu aşak etki bar diýip görkeýäris ýöne ol heniz görä ýigrendik. Çözüm bolsa, biomedical ady kodçylar üçin ölçekli bir çoklu işgärli eğitim rejimini teklip edip bilýäris. Diňe ýokary dereje semantik klaslary ulanarak robust temsilleri öwrenip biler. Bu temsiller her iki aşağı ve üst aşağı farklı semantik hiyerarşilerin arasynda generalize biler. Munuň üçin hipernimleriň ýüze garşylanmadyk tanamak üçin nähili ýüze-daşaryk ýüze ullanılabilirler diýip görkezip otyrýarys. Çeşitli semantik saklap çykyşlygyň düzümlerini ýok edip barýarys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Kadiri za kijamii za majina ya kitabibu huchukuliwa kama wabaguzi kama wawakilishi wanaweza kutumiwa kwa ufanisi kwa kazi mbalimbali za NLP. Ili kufikia hili, idadi zinahitaji kutengeneza dawa maalum za kitabibu wakati wakipinga matumizi ya ulimwengu wa uwakilishi wa kujitazama. Kazi iliyopita kuhusu uwakilishi wa ubaguzi imejikita kujifunza tofauti za kiwango cha chini kati ya majina ya dhana nzuri ya kitabibu. Wazo hizi vizuri vinaweza kuwa na pamoja ili kutafakari tofauti za kiwango kikubwa, tofauti zaidi za kimapenzi, kama vile makundi ya majina ya vurugu za mitandao na kofi zilizobeba kwa pamoja chini ya majeraha ya ngozi. Bado haijathibitishwa kwa msisitizo kwamba mafunzo ya jina la kitabibu kuhusu utofauti mzuri unaoendelea kuongezeka kwa upande wa chini wa mfumo wa aina hii ya sekta ya juu. Katika gazeti hili, tunaonyesha kwamba athari hii ya chini imepo, lakini bado ni vigumu. Kama suluhisho, tunapendekeza utawala wa mafunzo ya kazi mbalimbali kwa ajili ya kodi za majina ya kitabibu ambazo pia wanaweza kujifunza wakiwakilisha ubaguzi kwa kutumia darasa la sekunde za juu tu. Wawakilishaji hawa wanaweza kuitengeneza viwili vya chini na pia chini ya juu miongoni mwa makundi mbalimbali ya kigaidi. Zaidi ya hayo, tunaonyesha jinsi wanavyoweza kutumika nje ya kisanduku kwa ajili ya kuboresha uchunguzi wa umeme usio na usalama, wakati wakiendelea kufanya kazi za ubakaji katika misingi mbalimbali ya mahusiano ya kimapenzi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_am>የሕያዊ መድኃኒት ስም የሚቆጠሩ የነዌብ ኮድዶችን በተለያዩ የNLP ስርዓቶች እንዲጠቀም የሚችል እንደሆነ በጥቅረት ይቆጥራሉ፡፡ ይህንን ለማግኘት፣ የኮድዶችን አካባቢ የዳሜን የተለየ የbiomedical semantics ማሳየት ያስፈልጋል፡፡ የቀድሞው የሮቦት መልዕክቶች ላይ የሚደረገውን ሥራ በጥሩ የbiomedical አካሄድ ስሞች በጥሩ ጥሩ ልዩነት በማስተማር ላይ አስማርቷል፡፡ እነዚህ ጥሩ አካባቢዎች ከፍተኛ ደረጃዎች፣ የጠቅላላ ስሜት መለያየት እንዲያስተካክሉ ይችላሉ፡፡ እንደተጨማሪም የቆዳ ጥቁር እና በቁርባን ቍስል ውስጥ የተሸከሙትን ንዳት በአንድነት ይቆማሉ፡፡ It has not yet been empirically confirmed that training biomedical name encoders on fine-grained distinctions automatically leads to bottom-up encoding of such higher-level semantics.  በዚህ ገጾች ውስጥ ይህ የመታጠቢያ ፍቃድ እንዳለ እናሳያቸዋለን ግን ገና ይታያል፡፡ እንደምናልባት፣ ለብዙ ስራ ማህበረሰብ ሥርዓት የbiomedical name encodings እናስተማራለን፡፡ እነዚህ መልዕክቶች ከታች እና በላይ እና ከታች በተለያዩ የsemantic hierarchy መካከል መፍጠር ይችላሉ፡፡ እንደዚህም፣ የኤፍሬኒም ማሳየት እንዴት እንደሚጠቀሙ እናሳያቸዋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>Neurale koders van biomediese naams word tipies aangesien robust as voorstellings effektief kan gebruik word vir verskeie onderstreem NLP-taak. Om dit te bereik, moet enkoders domein-spesifieke biomediese semantieke model maak terwyl die universele toepassingbaarheid van voorgeskryfde self-ondersoekte verteenwoordelings teenstel. Vorige werk op kragtige voorstellings het gefokus op die leer van lae vlak verskilte tussen die name van fyn-graad biomediese konsepte. Hierdie fyn-graad konsepte kan ook saam gesluit word om hoër vlak te reflekteer, meer algemene semantiese verskilinge, soos groepeer van die naams van die nett-slag en geteker-borne feur saam onder die beskrywing punktuurwonde van vel. Dit is nog nie empiriese bevestig dat onderwerking biomediese naam enkoderers op fyn-graan uitdelings outomaties na ondersteunde enkodering van sodanige hoër vlak semantieke lei nie. In hierdie papier, wys ons dat hierdie onderkant effek bestaan, maar dat dit nog relativief beperk is. As 'n oplossing, voorstel ons 'n skaalbaar multi-taak opvoeringsreëm vir biomediese naam koders wat ook kragtige voorstellings kan leer met net hoër vlak semantiese klasse. Hierdie voorstellings kan genereer beide onderkant en bo-onderkant onder verskillende semantiese hierarkies. Ook, ons wys hoe hulle kan gebruik word uit-die-boks vir verbeter ononderwerpende opdecking van hypernyme, terwyl hulle sterk prestasie hou op verskeie semantiese verhouding benchmarke.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_az>Əgər göstəricilər müxtəlif NLP işləri üçün dəyişiklik olaraq istifadə edilə bilərsə, biomedical adlarının nöral kodlayıcıları çox qüvvətli hesab edilir. Bunu başa düşmək üçün kodlayıcıların domain-specific biomedical semantika modeli olması lazımdır. Özünün gözləyirlənmiş nümunələrinin universal uyğulaması ilə müqayisədə. Qüvvətli göstəricilər barəsindəki əvvəlki işin düşük seviyyətli biomedicin fikirlərin adlarının arasında fərqlənmələrə odaqlanmışdır. Bu gözəl dənələr həmçinin yüksək seviyyəti, daha genel semantik fərqlənmələri ilə birlikdə birlikdə birlikdə toplanıla bilər, çünki adları çəkilmək və dərinin qaranlığı altındakı təfsirlənmək yarası altında bir yerə toplanıla bilər. Henüz təhsil edilməmişdir ki, bu yüksək seviyyətli semantik kodlamalarının üstünlük kodlamasına yol açar. Bu kağızda, biz bu aşağı təsirin mövcud olduğunu göstəririk, amma bu hələ relativi sınırlı olduğunu göstəririk. Biz bir çətinlik olaraq, biomedical adlı kodlayıcılar üçün çoxlu iş təhsil rejimini təklif edirik ki, sadəcə yüksək səviyyə semantik sınıflarını istifadə edərək qüvvətli təhsil öyrənə bilər. Bu göstəricilər hər ikisinin alt üstünü və üstünü müxtəlif semantik hiyerarhiyatların arasında generalizə bilər. Daha sonra, biz onların müxtəlif semantik bağlantılıq benchmarklərində möhkəm performansı saxlayaraq, hipernimlərin yaxşılaşdırılması üçün necə qutudan istifadə ediləcəklərini göstəririk.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_hy>Բիոբժշկական անունների նյարդային կոդերները սովորաբար համարվում են ուժեղ, եթե ներկայացումները կարող են արդյունավետ օգտագործվել տարբեր հետագա ՆԼՊ խնդիրների համար: Սա հասնելու համար կոդերները պետք է մոդելավորեն բիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիոբիո Անցյալ աշխատանքը ուժեղ ներկայացումների վրա կենտրոնացել է ցածր մակարդակի տարբերությունների ուսումնասիրելուն նրբագեղ կենսաբժշկական հասկացությունների անունների միջև: Այս նրբագեղ գաղափարները կարող են նաև համախմբվել, որպեսզի արտացոլում են ավելի բարձր մակարդակի, ավելի ընդհանուր սեմանտիկ տարբերակներ, ինչպիսիք են օրինակ ցանցաթաղանթի անունների խմբավորումը և կետիկների տառապող ջերմաստիճանը համախմբում մաշկի նկա Դեռ էմպիրիկապես չի հաստատվել, որ կենսաբժշկական անունների կոդավորման ուսումնասիրությունը նրբագեղ տարբերակների վրա ինքնաբերաբար հանգեցնում է նման բարձր մակարդակի սեմանտիկայի ներքևի կոդավորման: Այս թղթի մեջ մենք ցույց ենք տալիս, որ այս ներքևի էֆեկտը գոյություն ունի, բայց այն դեռ համեմատաբար սահմանափակ է: Որպես լուծում, մենք առաջարկում ենք, որ կենսաբժշկական անունների կոդերների համար բազմախնդիրներ սովորեցնենք, որոնք կարող են սովորել ուժեղ ներկայացումներ միայն օգտագործելով բարձր մակարդակի սեմանտիկ դասեր: Այս ներկայացումները կարող են ընդհանրացնել նաև ներքև և ներքև տարբեր սեմանտիկ հիերարխիաների միջև: Ավելին, մենք ցույց ենք տալիս, թե ինչպես դրանք կարող են օգտագործվել արկղից դուրս հիպերնիմների բարելավման համար, առանց վերահսկման, մինչդեռ պահպանվում են ուժեղ արտադրողություններ տարբեր սեմանտիկ հարաբերակցության հարաբերականների վրա:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ca>Els codificadors neurològics de noms biomèdics són típicament considerats robustos si les representacions poden ser explotades efectivament per diverses tasques de NLP avall. Per aconseguir això, els codificadors han de modelar la semàntica biomèdica específica per domini al mateix temps que competeixen amb l'aplicabilitat universal de representacions autosupervisades. La feina anterior en representacions robustes s'ha centrat en aprendre distincions de baix nivell entre noms de conceptes biomèdics fines. Aquests conceptes de grans fins també es poden agrupar per reflexionar distincions semàntiques de nivell més alt i més general, com agrupar els noms col·laboració de la xarxa i la febre carregada pels marxos sota la descripció de la ferida de puntura de la pell. Encara no s'ha confirmat empíricament que formar codificadors de noms biomèdics en distincions fines condueix automàticament a codificar de baix a dalt d'aquesta semàntica de nivell superior. En aquest article demostram que existeix aquest efecte de baix a dalt, però que encara està relativament limitat. Com a solució, proposem un règim de capacitació multitasca escalable per codificadors de noms biomèdics que també poden aprendre representacions robustes fent servir només classes semàntiques de nivell superior. Aquestes representacions poden generalitzar tant de baix a dalt com de dalt a baix entre diverses jerarquies semàntiques. A més, demostram com es poden utilitzar fora de la caixa per a millorar la detecció sense supervisió de hipernims, mantenint un rendiment robust en diversos punts de referència de relació semàntica.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>Neuralni koderi biomedicinskih imena obično se smatraju robnim ako se predstavljanja mogu učinkovito iskoristiti za različite zadatke NLP. Da bi to ostvarili, koderi moraju modelovati biomedicinske semantike specifične domene dok se suprotstavljaju univerzalnoj primjennosti predviđenih predstavljanja samopouzdanja. Prethodni rad na robnim predstavljanjima fokusirao se na učenje razlika niskog nivoa između imena finog biomedicinskog koncepta. Također se mogu skupljati i ovi zgodni koncepti da odraže višu nivou, opće semantičke razlike, kao što su skupljanje imena štampanja mreže i groznica koja se pojavljuje pod ozljedem kože. Još nije empirički potvrđeno da obuka kodera biomedicinskih imena na fino zrno razlike automatski vodi do donjeg kodiranja takvih semantika na višem nivou. U ovom papiru pokazujemo da ovaj efekt dolje postoji, ali da je i dalje relativno ograničen. Kao rješenje, predlažemo mjerljiv režim vežbanja multizadataka za kodere biomedicinskih imena koji također mogu naučiti robne predstave koristeći samo semantičke klase višeg nivoa. Ove predstave mogu generalizirati i dolje, kao i dolje među različitim semantičkim hijerarhijama. Osim toga, pokazujemo kako se mogu koristiti izvan kutije za poboljšanje neodređenog otkrivanja hipernima, dok zadržavamo jake učinke na različitim semantičkim standardima veze.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_bn>বায়োমেডিকেল নামের নিউরেল কোডার সাধারণত রোবট বিবেচনা করা হচ্ছে যদি প্রতিনিধিত্বের প্রতিনিধিত্ব কার্যকর কাজে এনএল To achieve this, encoders need to model domain-specific biomedical semantics while rivaling the universal applicability of pretrained self-supervised representations.  রোবট প্রতিনিধিত্বের পূর্ববর্তী কাজ সুন্দর বায়োমেডিকেল ধারণার নামের মধ্যে নিম্ন স্তরের পার্থক্য শিখতে মনোযোগ এই চমৎকার ধারণাগুলো একসাথে একত্রিত হতে পারে উচ্চপর্যায়, আরো সাধারণ সেমেন্টিক বিভাগের প্রতিক্রিয়া প্রতিফলিত করার জন্য, যেমন নেটেল টিস্টিং এবং তালিকার আ এটা এখনো ক্ষমতার সাথে নিশ্চিত করা হয়নি যে বায়োমেডিকেল নামের প্রশিক্ষণ সুন্দর ভিন্ন বিভিন্ন বিভিন্ন বিভেদের প্রশিক্ষণ স্বয়ংক্রি এই পত্রিকায় আমরা দেখাচ্ছি যে এই নীচের প্রভাব আছে, কিন্তু এটা এখনো পরিমাণ সীমাবদ্ধ। একটি সমাধান হিসেবে আমরা বায়োমেডিকেল নাম এনকোডারের জন্য একটি মাল্টিক কাজের প্রশিক্ষণ শাসকদের প্রস্তাব করি যা শুধুমাত্র উচ্চমাত্র সে এই প্রতিনিধিগুলো বিভিন্ন সেম্যান্টিক হিয়ারার্কির মধ্যে দুটো নীচের সাথে সাধারণ করে দিতে পারে। এছাড়াও আমরা দেখাচ্ছি কিভাবে তারা হাইপার্নিমের উন্নতির জন্য ব্যবহার করতে পারে বিভিন্ন সেম্পেন্টিক সম্পর্কের বিভিন্ন মেন্টিক সম্পর্কে রোবট</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Neurální snímače biomedicínských názvů jsou obvykle považovány za robustní, pokud lze reprezentace efektivně využít pro různé následné NLP úlohy. K dosažení tohoto cíle musí kodéry modelovat doménově specifickou biomedicínskou sémantiku a současně konkurovat univerzální použitelnosti předem trénovaných samovládaných reprezentací. Předchozí práce na robustních reprezentacích se zaměřila na naučení nízké úrovně rozlišování názvů jemnozrnných biomedicínských konceptů. Tyto jemnozrnné koncepty mohou být také shlukovány dohromady, aby odrážely vyšší úrovně, obecnější sémantické rozlišení, jako je seskupení názvů kopřivy bodnutí a klíšťová horečka dohromady pod popisem bodné rány kůže. Ještě nebylo empiricky potvrzeno, že trénink biomedicínských kodérů názvů na jemných rozlišeních automaticky vede k kódování zdola nahoru takové vyšší úrovně sémantiky. V tomto článku ukazujeme, že tento efekt zdola nahoru existuje, ale že je stále relativně omezený. Jako řešení navrhujeme škálovatelný víceúlohový tréninkový režim pro biomedicínské kodéry názvů, který se také naučí robustní reprezentace pouze pomocí vyšší úrovně sémantických tříd. Tyto reprezentace mohou generalizovat jak zdola nahoru, tak shora dolů mezi různými sémantickými hierarchiemi. Navíc ukazujeme, jak je lze použít out-of-the-box pro lepší detekci hypernymů bez dohledu, při zachování robustního výkonu na různých sémantických referenčních hodnotách.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Biomeditsiiniliste nimetuste neurokodeerijaid peetakse tavaliselt tugevaks, kui esitusi saab tõhusalt ära kasutada mitmesuguste järgnevate uue tööprogrammi ülesannete jaoks. Selle saavutamiseks peavad kodeerijad modelleerima domeenispetsiifilist biomeditsiinilist semantikat, samal ajal konkureerides eelnevalt treenitud isejärelevalve all olevate representatsioonide universaalse rakendatavusega. Varasemad tööd tugevate representatsioonide alal on keskendunud madalate eristuste õppimisele peeneteraliste biomeditsiinikontseptsioonide nimede vahel. Neid peeneteralisi kontseptsioone võib kokku koondada, et kajastada kõrgema taseme ja üldisemaid semantilisi eristusi, näiteks nõgese nõelamise ja puugist põhjustatud palaviku nimetuste rühmitamine naha punktsioonihava alla. Empiiriliselt ei ole veel kinnitatud, et biomeditsiiniliste nimekodeerijate koolitamine peenete eristuste alal viib automaatselt sellise kõrgema taseme semantika alt üles kodeerimiseni. Käesolevas dokumendis näitame, et see alt-üles mõju on olemas, kuid see on endiselt suhteliselt piiratud. Lahendusena pakume välja skaleeritava mitmeülesandelise koolituse režiimi biomeditsiinilistele nimekodeerijatele, mis suudab õppida ka tugevaid esitusi, kasutades ainult kõrgema taseme semantilisi klasse. Need esitused võivad üldistada nii alt üles- kui ka ülalt-alla erinevate semantiliste hierarhiate hulgas. Lisaks näitame, kuidas neid saab kasutada koheselt hüpernüümide järelevalveta tuvastamiseks, säilitades samas tugeva jõudluse erinevate semantiliste seoste võrdlusnäitajate puhul.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Biolääketieteellisten nimien hermokoodereita pidetään yleensä vahvoina, jos esityksiä voidaan tehokkaasti hyödyntää erilaisissa jatkojalostuksen tehtävissä. Saavuttaakseen tämän koodaajien on mallinnettava verkkotunnuskohtaista biomedikaalista semantiikkaa samalla kun verrataan ennalta harjoitettujen itsevalvottujen representaatioiden yleismaailmallista sovellettavuutta. Aiempi vankkoja esityksiä käsittelevä työ on keskittynyt matalatasoisten erottelujen oppimiseen hienorakeisten biolääketieteen käsitteiden nimien välillä. Nämä hienorakeiset käsitteet voidaan myös koota yhteen heijastamaan korkeampia, yleisempiä semanttisia eroja, kuten nokkospiston ja punkkien aiheuttaman kuumeen nimien ryhmittelyä ihon pistohaavan alla. Empiirisesti ei ole vielä varmistettu, että biolääketieteellisten nimikoodaajien kouluttaminen hienojakoisiin erotteluihin johtaisi automaattisesti tällaisen korkeamman tason semantiikan alhaalta ylöspäin koodaukseen. Tässä asiakirjassa osoitamme, että tämä alhaalta ylöspäin suuntautuva vaikutus on olemassa, mutta se on edelleen suhteellisen rajallinen. Ratkaisuna ehdotamme skaalautuvaa monitehtäväkoulutusta biolääketieteellisille nimikoodereille, jotka voivat myös oppia vankkoja esityksiä käyttämällä vain korkeamman tason semanttisia luokkia. Nämä esitykset voivat yleistää sekä alhaalta ylös että ylhäältä alas erilaisten semanttisten hierarkioiden kesken. Lisäksi näytämme, miten niitä voidaan käyttää välittömästi hypernyymien valvomattoman tunnistamisen parantamiseen säilyttäen samalla vahvan suorituskyvyn erilaisissa semanttisissa yhteyksissä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Poker To success this, decoders have to model domain-special Biwotherapist semanti when contrasting the universal apliitude of preshined Self-super Vised representations. Awak dhéwé éntuk sing beraksi kanggo ngerasahan kelas kuwi nggawe gerarané gambar nganggep gambaran sing larang ngregani ora bisa pasar biya. Perintah sing dibunangé punika dipunangé katêpakan uwong gawe nguasai luwih-luwih, ulih semanti kuwi ngêngé kesempatan, ngono ngêngé nambarang tuyata mên lan ujol-ujol ngêngé. Ora durung ono wektu nggunakake bener tentang kanggo nggawe Panjenengan pangan Biyamik, koyo nggawe barang nggawe barang kelas etek dhuwur, kuwi iso nguasai akeh tho Nanging mapur iki, kita ngomatke punika teras-teras iki dadi, njuk dadi iki dadi apik dadi apik. Ana sampeyan, kita supoyo sistem multi-task gawe ngubah sistem dadi kapan kanggo koder pangan biyoten sing bisa nggawe ngubah sistem sing gawe ngubah sistem sing wis jawisan kelas semanti kuwi etik dhéwé. Rasalah sing dipunangke dipunangke dipunangke dipunangke lan mulalah sing sampeyan kelas semanti. Label</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>קודדים נוירוניים של שמות ביו-רפואים בדרך כלל נחשבים חזקים אם ניתן לנצל היציגות באופן יעיל עבור משימות NLP מתקדמות שונות. כדי להשיג את זה, הקודנים צריכים לדוגמא סמנטיקה ביורפואית ספציפית לתחום בזמן שיתוף היחידה באוניברסלית של מייצגות משומדות על עצמם. Previous work on robust representations has focused on learning low-level distinctions between names of fine-grained biomedical concepts.  These fine-grained concepts can also be clustered together to reflect higher-level, more general semantic distinctions, such as grouping the names nettle sting and tick-borne fever together under the description puncture wound of skin.  עדיין לא הואשר אמפירית שהאימון קודם שם ביו-רפואי על הבדיקות צפופונות מוביל באופן אוטומטי לקוד מתחת למעלה של סמנטיקה ברמה גבוהה כזו. בעיתון הזה, אנחנו מראים שהאפקט הזה מתחת למעלה קיים, אבל שהוא עדיין מוגבל יחסית. כפתרון, אנו מציעים מערכת אימון ממשימות רבות אפשרית לקודים בשמות ביו-רפואיים שיכולים גם ללמוד מייצגים חזקים באמצעות שיעורים סמנטיים ברמה גבוהה בלבד. הייצגות האלה יכולות לגנרליזציה גם מלמטה למעלה וגם מלמעלה למטה בין הייררכיות סמנטיות שונות. חוץ מזה, אנו מראים איך הם יכולים להשתמש מחוץ לקופסא כדי לשפר את גילוי היפרנימות ללא השגחה, בזמן שמירה ביצועים חזקים על נקודות רמזים של קשר סמנטי שונים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Živčni kodirniki biomedicinskih imen se običajno štejejo za robustne, če je mogoče predstavitve učinkovito izkoristiti za različne nadaljnje naloge NLP. Za dosego tega morajo kodirniki modelirati domensko specifično biomedicinsko semantiko, hkrati pa konkurirati univerzalni uporabnosti predtreniranih samonadzorovanih reprezentacij. Predhodno delo o robustnih reprezentacijah se je osredotočilo na učenje nizkih razlik med imeni drobnozrnatih biomedicinskih konceptov. Ti drobnozrnati koncepti se lahko združijo tudi tako, da odražajo višje stopnje, splošnejše semantične razlike, kot je združevanje imen pikljenja koprive in vročine, prenesenih s klopi, skupaj pod opisom vbodne rane kože. Empirično še ni bilo potrjeno, da usposabljanje biomedicinskih kodirjev imen na drobnozrnatih razlikah samodejno vodi v kodiranje takšne semantike višje ravni od spodaj navzgor. V tem članku pokažemo, da ta učinek od spodaj navzgor obstaja, vendar je še vedno relativno omejen. Kot rešitev predlagamo razširljiv režim večopravilnega usposabljanja za biomedicinske kodirnike imen, ki se lahko učijo tudi robustnih predstavitev z uporabo samo semantičnih razredov višje ravni. Te predstavitve lahko posplošijo tako od spodaj navzgor kot od zgoraj navzdol med različnimi semantičnimi hierarhijami. Poleg tega smo pokazali, kako jih je mogoče uporabiti za izboljšanje nenadzorovanega odkrivanja hipernimov, hkrati pa ohraniti robustno delovanje na različnih semantičnih referenčnih merilih povezanosti.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Kodi na neural na sunayen bajirada aka ƙaddara a yi kodi a rana ko kuma idan an iya amfani da masu sharri cikin aikin NLP guda. To, domin su isa wannan, kode za'a buƙata misãlai masu cikin dawwamar da aka ƙayyade shi a lokacin da ya yi motsari ga abubuwa masu tsari da kuma a sami kwamfyuta. Yin aikin da ya gabãta a kan masu tsari da aka goge ya fokus, yana zura fahimtar da rarrabai masu ƙasƙanci a tsakanin sunayen sunayen da aka fi-grafi na hanyoyin kimada. Ana iya samun wannan zafi mai kyau zuwa tsakanin da za'a yi tunãni game da tsofanin sarki, da kuma masu ƙaranci da tsakanin mutane, kamar misãlin sunayen sunayen mitel da kwamfyuta mai kifi da kuma a samu a cikin kwamfyutan zarar kwamfyutan tebur. Ba a riga an tabbatar da shi ba, ya zama mai amfani da kodi na sunan ɗima da aka haife su farat ɗaya yana ƙara kodi na ƙari da ke cikin wannan semantiki na sarrafa. Ga wannan takardan, Munã nũna cewa wannan mai ƙara-baka yana da, kuma amma yana da gwargwadon. Kayya da rabon, Munã goyyar da wani matsayi mai ƙidãya na aikin aiki mai ƙidãya wa kodi na aikin da za'a iya amfani da matsayin maɓalli, da kuma za'a iya sanar da masu karatun matsayin maɓalli da ke yi amfani da fasalar-na-daraja kawai. Wannan hotunan suna iya ƙiƙiro dukkan ƙasa da ƙasa da kuma da sama daga tsakanin hirarori masu sakanti. Za kuma, Munã nuna yadda za a yi amfani da su daga-box dõmin an improve canza gandin surori na Hyernym, da kuma Muke riƙe rabon jerobiyar a kan misãlai masu husũma na semanti.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་སྨན་ཐོག་གི་མིང་ཡོད་པའི་ནུས་བའི་སྒེར་གྱི་ཨིན་ཀོ་ཌིས་རྣམས་ནད་ཡོད་ཚད་ཡོད་པ་དང་། གལ་སྲིད་རྟོགས་ནི་ཕར To achieve this, encoders need to model domain-specific biomedical semantics while rivaling the universal application of pretrained self-supervised representations. སྔོན་གྱི་ལས་འགན་བློ་བརྟན་དགོས་པ་ཞིག་ནི་ཆེད་དུ་ཉུང་བའི་རྐྱེན་གྱིས་མཐོང་བ་དང་། ཞེས་པ་གཟུགས་པའི་ལྟ་བ་འདི་ཚོ་ཡང་མཐོ་རྣམས་མཐོ་བྱེད་སྣང་ཚུལ་མཐོ་ཁག་ཆེ་མཐོ་རྣམས་མཐོ་རྣམས། ད་ལྟ་བུའི་སྨན་ཐོག་གི་མིང་གསལ་པོ་ཞིག་གི་གོ་སྐབས་ཀྱིས་རང་འགུལ་གྱིས་རྨན་ཐོག་ཏུ་གཏོང་བ་དང་། འོག ཐབས་ཤེས་དེ་ལྟར། ང་ཚོས་རྨས་གཞུང་གི་མིང་གསལ་པོ་ཞིག་ལས་སྒྲིག་སྟངས་མང་ཙམ་བྱེད་པའི་གྲངས་སྒྲིག་འཛིན་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་སྟོན་ཐུབ། རྣམ་པ་འདི་དག་གི་སྐྱེས་ཆེན་གཉིས་ཀྱིས་མགོ་རིང་དང་མགོ་རིང་ནང་ཕར་ཆེན་འབད་ཆོག འུ་ཅག་གིས་འདི་ཚོ་ཕྱི་ཁར་ནས་གྲངས་སུ་མཐོང་མེད་པའི་རྣམ་པ་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་གྱིས་ཇི་ལྟར་བློ་གཏོང་ནི་མེད་པའི་ཚེ།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>FuzzyBIO : A Proposal for Fuzzy Representation of Discontinuous Entities<fixed-case>F</fixed-case>uzzy<fixed-case>BIO</fixed-case>: A Proposal for Fuzzy Representation of Discontinuous Entities</title>
      <author><first>Anne</first><last>Dirkson</last></author>
      <author><first>Suzan</first><last>Verberne</last></author>
      <author><first>Wessel</first><last>Kraaij</last></author>
      <pages>77–82</pages>
      <abstract>Discontinuous entities pose a challenge to named entity recognition (NER). These phenomena occur commonly in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biomedicine">biomedical domain</a>. As a solution, expansions of the BIO representation scheme that can handle these entity types are commonly used (i.e. BIOHD). However, the extra tag types make the NER task more difficult to learn. In this paper we propose an alternative ; a fuzzy continuous BIO scheme (FuzzyBIO). We focus on the task of Adverse Drug Response extraction and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normalization_(statistics)">normalization</a> to compare FuzzyBIO to BIOHD. We find that FuzzyBIO improves <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a> of NER for two of three data sets and results in a higher percentage of correctly identified disjoint and composite entities for all data sets. Using FuzzyBIO also improves end-to-end performance for continuous and composite entities in two of three data sets. Since FuzzyBIO improves performance for some data sets and the conversion from BIOHD to FuzzyBIO is straightforward, we recommend investigating which is more effective for any data set containing discontinuous entities.</abstract>
      <url hash="044aa9b1">2021.louhi-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>dirkson-etal-2021-fuzzybio</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/AnneDirkson/FuzzyBIO" additional="false">AnneDirkson/FuzzyBIO</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Scientific Claim Verification with VerT5erini<fixed-case>V</fixed-case>er<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>5erini</title>
      <author><first>Ronak</first><last>Pradeep</last></author>
      <author><first>Xueguang</first><last>Ma</last></author>
      <author><first>Rodrigo</first><last>Nogueira</last></author>
      <author><first>Jimmy</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <pages>94–103</pages>
      <abstract>This work describes the adaptation of a pretrained sequence-to-sequence model to the task of scientific claim verification in the biomedical domain. We propose a system called VerT5erini that exploits T5 for abstract retrieval, sentence selection, and label prediction, which are three critical sub-tasks of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verification_and_validation">claim verification</a>. We evaluate our pipeline on SciFACT, a newly curated dataset that requires models to not just predict the veracity of claims but also provide relevant sentences from a corpus of scientific literature that support the prediction. Empirically, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> outperforms a strong <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline</a> in each of the three sub-tasks. We further show VerT5erini’s ability to generalize to two new datasets of COVID-19 claims using evidence from the CORD-19 corpus.</abstract>
      <url hash="daec55f2">2021.louhi-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>pradeep-etal-2021-scientific</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/fever">FEVER</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/liar">LIAR</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ms-marco">MS MARCO</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>