<collection id="2021.reinact">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-09-27">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Reasoning and Interaction Conference (ReInAct 2021)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Christine</first><last>Howes</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Simon</first><last>Dobnik</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ellen</first><last>Breitholtz</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Stergios</first><last>Chatzikyriakidis</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Gothenburg, Sweden</address>
      <month>October</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ca7d93c2">2021.reinact-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>reinact-2021-reasoning</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Dogwhistles as Inferences in Interaction</title>
      <author><first>Ellen</first><last>Breitholtz</last></author>
      <author><first>Robin</first><last>Cooper</last></author>
      <pages>40&#8211;46</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we will argue that the nature of dogwhistle communication is essentially dialogical, and that to account for dogwhistle meaning we must consider dialogical events in which dialogue partners can draw different conclusions based on communicative events. This leads us to a theory based on inference. However, as identified by Khoo (2017) and emphasised by Henderson &amp; McCready (2018), a problematic aspect of this approach is that expressions that have a similar meaning are analysed as generating the same dogwhistle inferences, which appears not always to be the case. By modelling meaning in terms of intensional types in TTR, we avoid this problem.</abstract>
      <url hash="d5fa8ab4">2021.reinact-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>breitholtz-cooper-2021-dogwhistles</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Decoupling Pragmatics: Discriminative Decoding for Referring Expression Generation</title>
      <author><first>Simeon</first><last>Sch&#252;z</last></author>
      <author><first>Sina</first><last>Zarrie&#223;</last></author>
      <pages>47&#8211;52</pages>
      <abstract>The shift to neural models in Referring Expression Generation (REG) has enabled more natural set-ups, but at the cost of interpretability. We argue that integrating pragmatic reasoning into the inference of context-agnostic generation models could reconcile traits of traditional and neural REG, as this offers a separation between context-independent, literal information and pragmatic adaptation to context. With this in mind, we apply existing decoding strategies from discriminative image captioning to REG and evaluate them in terms of pragmatic informativity, likelihood to ground-truth annotations and linguistic diversity. Our results show general effectiveness, but a relatively small gain in informativity, raising important questions for REG in general.</abstract>
      <url hash="1efa35a1">2021.reinact-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>schuz-zarriess-2021-decoupling</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/coco">COCO</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/refcoco">RefCOCO</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Generating Justifications in a Spatial Question-Answering Dialogue System for a Blocks World</title>
      <author><first>Georgiy</first><last>Platonov</last></author>
      <author><first>Benjamin</first><last>Kane</last></author>
      <author><first>Lenhart</first><last>Schubert</last></author>
      <pages>53&#8211;57</pages>
      <abstract>As AI reaches wider adoption, designing systems that are explainable and interpretable becomes a critical necessity. In particular, when it comes to dialogue systems, their reasoning must be transparent and must comply with human intuitions in order for them to be integrated seamlessly into day-to-day collaborative human-machine activities. Here, we describe our ongoing work on a (general purpose) dialogue system equipped with a spatial specialist with explanatory capabilities. We applied this system to a particular task of characterizing spatial configurations of blocks in a simple physical Blocks World (BW) domain using natural locative expressions, as well as generating justifications for the proposed spatial descriptions by indicating the factors that the system used to arrive at a particular conclusion.</abstract>
      <url hash="9cfafd85">2021.reinact-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>platonov-etal-2021-generating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Why Should <fixed-case>I</fixed-case> Turn Left? Towards Active Explainability for Spoken Dialogue Systems.</title>
      <author><first>Vladislav</first><last>Maraev</last></author>
      <author><first>Ellen</first><last>Breitholtz</last></author>
      <author><first>Christine</first><last>Howes</last></author>
      <author><first>Jean-Philippe</first><last>Bernardy</last></author>
      <pages>58&#8211;64</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we argue that to make dialogue systems able to actively explain their decisions they can make use of enthymematic reasoning. We motivate why this is an appropriate strategy and integrate it within our own proof-theoretic dialogue manager framework based on linear logic. In particular, this enables a dialogue system to provide reasonable answers to why-questions that query information previously given by the system.</abstract>
      <url hash="de99a229">2021.reinact-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>maraev-2021-turn</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>