<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.bucc">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-11-09">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 14th Workshop on Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC 2021)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Reinhard</first><last>Rapp</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Serge</first><last>Sharoff</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Pierre</first><last>Zweigenbaum</last></editor>
      <publisher>INCOMA Ltd.</publisher>
      <address>Online (Virtual Mode)</address>
      <month>September</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="f525bf72">2021.bucc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>bucc-2021-building</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Syntax-aware Transformers for Neural Machine Translation : The Case of Text to Sign Gloss Translation</title>
      <author><first>Santiago</first><last>Egea Gómez</last></author>
      <author><first>Euan</first><last>McGill</last></author>
      <author><first>Horacio</first><last>Saggion</last></author>
      <pages>18–27</pages>
      <abstract>It is well-established that the preferred mode of communication of the deaf and hard of hearing (DHH) community are Sign Languages (SLs), but they are considered low resource languages where natural language processing technologies are of concern. In this paper we study the problem of text to SL gloss Machine Translation (MT) using Transformer-based architectures. Despite the significant advances of MT for spoken languages in the recent couple of decades, MT is in its infancy when it comes to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_language">SLs</a>. We enrich a Transformer-based architecture aggregating syntactic information extracted from a dependency parser to word-embeddings. We test our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> on a well-known dataset showing that the syntax-aware model obtains performance gains in terms of MT evaluation metrics.</abstract>
      <url hash="2ddf419a">2021.bucc-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>egea-gomez-etal-2021-syntax</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/lastus-taln-upf/syntax-aware-transformer-text2gloss" additional="false">lastus-taln-upf/syntax-aware-transformer-text2gloss</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Employing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia">Wikipedia</a> as a resource for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named-entity_recognition">Named Entity Recognition</a> in Morphologically complex under-resourced languages<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ikipedia as a resource for Named Entity Recognition in Morphologically complex under-resourced languages</title>
      <author><first>Aravind</first><last>Krishnan</last></author>
      <author><first>Stefan</first><last>Ziehe</last></author>
      <author><first>Franziska</first><last>Pannach</last></author>
      <author><first>Caroline</first><last>Sporleder</last></author>
      <pages>28–39</pages>
      <abstract>We propose a novel approach for rapid prototyping of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named-entity_recognition">named entity recognisers</a> through the development of semi-automatically annotated datasets. We demonstrate the proposed pipeline on two under-resourced agglutinating languages : the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Dravidian language Malayalam</a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zulu_language">Bantu language isiZulu</a>. Our approach is weakly supervised and bootstraps training data from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia">Wikipedia</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Knowledge_Graph">Google Knowledge Graph</a>. Moreover, our approach is relatively language independent and can consequently be ported quickly (and hence cost-effectively) from one language to another, requiring only minor language-specific tailoring.</abstract>
      <url hash="949c0b5b">2021.bucc-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>krishnan-etal-2021-employing</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Empregando a Wikipedia como um recurso para reconhecimento de entidades nomeadas em linguagens morfologicamente complexas com poucos recursos</title_pt>
      <title_es>Emplear Wikipedia como recurso para el reconocimiento de entidades nombradas en idiomas morfológicamente complejos y de escasos recursos</title_es>
      <title_ja>形態学的に複雑でリソース不足の言語での名前付きエンティティ認識のリソースとしてのウィキペディアの採用</title_ja>
      <title_ar>استخدام ويكيبيديا كمصدر للتعرف على الكيان المحدد في اللغات المعقدة شكليًا قليلة الموارد</title_ar>
      <title_hi>रूपात्मक रूप से जटिल कम संसाधन वाली भाषाओं में नामित इकाई मान्यता के लिए एक संसाधन के रूप में विकिपीडिया को नियोजित करना</title_hi>
      <title_fr>Utilisation de Wikipédia comme ressource pour la reconnaissance d'entités nommées dans les langues morphologiquement complexes et sous-ressources</title_fr>
      <title_ga>Vicipéid a úsáid mar acmhainn le haghaidh Aitheantas Aonán Ainmnithe i dteangacha atá casta go leor de na hacmhainní nach bhfuil mórán acmhainní acu</title_ga>
      <title_ru>Использование Википедии в качестве ресурса для распознавания именованных сущностей в морфологически сложных языках с недостаточным объемом ресурсов</title_ru>
      <title_zh>以维基百科为形之不足者,名曰实体</title_zh>
      <title_ka>ვიკიპედიას როგორც რესურსის გამოყენება მოპოლოგიურად კომპლექსიურად გამოყენებული ინტერტის განახლებისთვის</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A Wikipédia használata forrásként a nevezett entitások felismeréséhez morfológiailag összetett alacsony erőforrásokkal rendelkező nyelveken</title_hu>
      <title_el>Χρήση της Βικιπαίδειας ως πόρου για την Αναγνώριση Οντότητας σε Μορφολογικά σύνθετες γλώσσες που δεν διαθέτουν πόρους</title_el>
      <title_it>Utilizzare Wikipedia come risorsa per il riconoscimento delle entità nominate in linguaggi morfologicamente complessi con risorse insufficienti</title_it>
      <title_kk>Википедияға Марфологиялық көптеген тілдерде аталған нысандарды анықтау ресурсы ретінде қолдану</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Wikipedia naudojimas kaip vardinio subjekto pripažinimo šaltinis morfologiškai sudėtingomis nepakankamai išteklių turinčiomis kalbomis</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Користење на Википедија како ресурс за препознавање на именувани ентитети на морфолошки комплексни јазици со недоволни ресурси</title_mk>
      <title_ml>വിക്കിപിഡിയ വിഭവങ്ങളായി മോര്‍ഫോളോഗിക്കല്‍ വിഭവങ്ങളില്‍ പേരുള്ള എന്റിറ്റി തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നതിനുള്ള വിഭവങ്</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Menggunakan Wikipedia sebagai sumber untuk Pengenalan Entiti bernama dalam bahasa yang kompleks secara morfologik dibawah sumber-sumber</title_ms>
      <title_mt>L-użu tal-Wikipedia bħala riżorsa għar-Rikonoxximent tal-Entità Ismija f’lingwi morfoloġikament kumplessi b’riżorsi baxxi</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Википедийг Морфологик хэл дээр нэрлэгдсэн Нэгтийн Recognition болон</title_mn>
      <title_no>Bruk Wikipedia som ressurs for gjenkjenning av namnet entitet i morfologisk komplekse underressurserte språk</title_no>
      <title_ro>Utilizarea Wikipedia ca resursă pentru recunoașterea entităților denumite în limbi morfologic complexe sub-resurse</title_ro>
      <title_pl>Wykorzystanie Wikipedii jako zasobu do rozpoznawania nazwanych podmiotów w językach morfologicznie złożonych niedostatecznie zasobów</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Zaposlenje Wikipedije kao resursa za priznanje imenovanih entiteta na morfološki kompleksnom jeziku pod resursima</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>Shaqaalaha Wikipedia sida resource for Named Entity Recognition in Morphologically complex under-resourced languages</title_so>
      <title_sv>Använda Wikipedia som resurs för Named Entity Recognition i morfologiskt komplexa underresursspråk</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>ویکیپیڈیا کو نام رکھا ہوا انٹیٹی شناسی کے لئے ایک سرمایہ کے طور پر استعمال کرتا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Việc áp dụng Wikipedia như một tài nguyên cho Việc nhận dạng người có tên bằng ngôn ngữ phức tạp, thiếu nguồn lực.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Използване на Уикипедия като ресурс за разпознаване на имена на лица в морфологически сложни езици с недостатъчно ресурси</title_bg>
      <title_da>Anvendelse af Wikipedia som ressource til anerkendelse af navngivne enheder på morfologisk komplekse sprog med underressourcer</title_da>
      <title_nl>Wikipedia gebruiken als bron voor naamsbekendheid in morfologisch complexe talen met weinig middelen</title_nl>
      <title_de>Verwendung von Wikipedia als Ressource für Named Entity Recognition in morphologisch komplexen Unterressourcensprachen</title_de>
      <title_id>Menggunakan Wikipedia sebagai sumber daya untuk Pengenalan Entitas bernama dalam bahasa yang rumit secara morfologis</title_id>
      <title_ko>위키백과를 자원으로 삼아 형태가 복잡하고 자원이 부족한 언어에서 명명된 실체 식별을 하다</title_ko>
      <title_hr>Zaposlenje Wikipedia kao resursa priznanja imenovanih područja na morfološki složenim jezicima pod resursima</title_hr>
      <title_sw>Kutumia Wikipedia kama rasilimali kwa ajili ya Kutambua Ujumbe wa Jinai katika lugha za Kimorphologically complex under-resource</title_sw>
      <title_tr>횥첵tgedi첵any Marfologiki 첵체ze arkalanylan dillerde Ady Entity Tany힊ma 체챌in 챌e힊me h철km체nde ullan첵arlar</title_tr>
      <title_am>Wikipedia as a source for Named Entity Recognition in Morphologically complex under-resourced languages</title_am>
      <title_fa>با استفاده از ویکیپدیا به عنوان منابع برای شناسایی عنوان واحدی در زبانهای زیر منابع مرفولژی پیچیده</title_fa>
      <title_hy>Վիքիփեդիայի օգտագործումը որպես ռեսուրս Մորֆոլոգիապես բարդ լեզուներում կոչված անհատականության ճանաչման համար</title_hy>
      <title_af>Die werking van Wikipedia as 'n hulpbron vir genoemde Entity-herkenning in Morphologically kompleks onder-hulpbron taals</title_af>
      <title_bn>Name</title_bn>
      <title_sq>Duke përdorur Wikipedian si një burim për njohjen e njësisë së emëruar në gjuhë të ndërlikuara nga ana morfologjike</title_sq>
      <title_ca>Empregar la Wikipedia com un recurso per a la reconeixement d'entitats anomenades en llengües morfològicament complexes amb menys recursos</title_ca>
      <title_az>İsmim Entity Recognition üçün Wikipedia'yi Morphologically complex under resource dillərində istifadə edir.</title_az>
      <title_bs>Zaposlenje Wikipedia kao resursa za priznanje imenovanih entiteta na morfološki kompleksnom jeziku pod resursima</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Využití Wikipedie jako zdroje pro rozpoznávání jmenovaných entit v morfologicky složitých jazycích s nedostatečnými zdroji</title_cs>
      <title_et>Vikipeedia kasutamine nimetatud isikute tuvastamise ressursina morfoloogiliselt keerukates, alaressurssidega keeltes</title_et>
      <title_fi>Wikipedian käyttäminen resurssina nimettyjen entiteettien tunnistamiseen morfologisesti monimutkaisilla aliresursseilla varustetuilla kielillä</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Ngawe</title_jv>
      <title_he>משתמש בויקיפדיה כמשאב לזהות איכות בשם בשפות מורפולוגית מורכבות</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Uporaba Wikipedije kot vira za prepoznavanje imenovanih subjektov v morfološko kompleksnih jezikih s premalo virov</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Name</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقترح نهجًا جديدًا للنماذج الأولية السريعة لأدوات التعرف على الكيانات المسماة من خلال تطوير مجموعات البيانات المشروحة بشكل شبه تلقائي. نعرض خط الأنابيب المقترح على لغتين من لغات التراص قليلة الموارد: لغة درافيدية المالايالامية ولغة البانتو إيزولو. يخضع نهجنا للإشراف الضعيف ويقوم بتمهيد بيانات التدريب من ويكيبيديا و Google Knowledge Graph. علاوة على ذلك ، فإن نهجنا مستقل نسبيًا عن اللغة ويمكن بالتالي نقله بسرعة (ومن ثم فعاليته من حيث التكلفة) من لغة إلى أخرى ، مما لا يتطلب سوى خياطة ثانوية خاصة بلغة معينة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_fr>Nous proposons une nouvelle approche pour le prototypage rapide de dispositifs de reconnaissance d'entités nommées grâce au développement d'ensembles de données annotés semi-automatiquement. Nous démontrons le pipeline proposé sur deux langues agglutinantes sous-dotées : la langue dravidienne malayalam et la langue bantoue isiZulu. Notre approche est faiblement supervisée et amorce les données de formation de Wikipédia et de Google Knowledge Graph. De plus, notre approche est relativement indépendante de la langue et peut donc être portée rapidement (et donc de manière rentable) d'une langue à une autre, ne nécessitant qu'une adaptation mineure spécifique à la langue.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Proponemos un enfoque novedoso para la creación rápida de prototipos de reconocedores de entidades nombradas mediante el desarrollo de conjuntos de datos anotados semiautomáticamente. Demostramos el proyecto propuesto en dos lenguas aglutinantes de escasos recursos: el idioma dravídico malayalam y el idioma bantú es el zulú. Nuestro enfoque es débilmente supervisado y arranca datos de entrenamiento de Wikipedia y Google Knowledge Graph. Además, nuestro enfoque es relativamente independiente del idioma y, por lo tanto, se puede trasladar rápidamente (y por lo tanto de forma rentable) de un idioma a otro, lo que requiere solo una pequeña adaptación específica del idioma.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Propomos uma nova abordagem para prototipagem rápida de reconhecedores de entidades nomeadas através do desenvolvimento de conjuntos de dados anotados semiautomaticamente. Demonstramos o pipeline proposto em duas línguas aglutinantes com poucos recursos: a língua dravidiana malaiala e a língua bantu isiZulu. Nossa abordagem é fracamente supervisionada e utiliza dados de treinamento da Wikipedia e do Google Knowledge Graph. Além disso, nossa abordagem é relativamente independente do idioma e, consequentemente, pode ser portada rapidamente (e, portanto, de forma econômica) de um idioma para outro, exigindo apenas pequenas adaptações específicas do idioma.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>私たちは、半自動的にアノテーションされたデータセットの開発を通じて、名前付きエンティティレグナイザーの迅速なプロトタイピングのための新しいアプローチを提案します。提案されているパイプラインは、資源不足のマラヤーラム語のドラヴィダ語とバントゥー語のisiZuluという2つのアグルティン言語で実演しています。当社のアプローチは弱く監督されており、ウィキペディアやGoogleナレッジグラフからのトレーニングデータをブートストラップします。さらに、私たちのアプローチは比較的言語に依存しないため、ある言語から別の言語に素早く（したがって費用対効果の高い）移植することができ、わずかな言語固有のテーラリングしか必要としません。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ru>Мы предлагаем новый подход к быстрому прототипированию именованных распознавателей сущностей посредством разработки полуавтоматически аннотированных наборов данных. Мы демонстрируем предлагаемый конвейер на двух агглютинирующих языках, не обеспеченных достаточными ресурсами: на малаяламском языке дравидия и на языке банту isiZulu. Наш подход слабо контролируется и загружает обучающие данные из Википедии и Google Knowledge Graph. Кроме того, наш подход относительно независим от языка и, следовательно, может быть быстро (и, следовательно, экономически эффективно) перенесен с одного языка на другой, требуя лишь незначительной адаптации к конкретному языку.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_hi>हम अर्ध-स्वचालित रूप से एनोटेट किए गए डेटासेट के विकास के माध्यम से नामित इकाई पहचानकर्ताओं के तेजी से प्रोटोटाइप िंग के लिए एक उपन्यास दृष्टिकोण का प्रस्ताव करते हैं। हम दो कम संसाधन वाली एग्लूटीनेटिंग भाषाओं पर प्रस्तावित पाइपलाइन का प्रदर्शन करते हैं: द्रविड़ भाषा मलयालम और बंटू भाषा isiZulu। हमारा दृष्टिकोण कमजोर रूप से पर्यवेक्षित है और विकिपीडिया और Google ज्ञान ग्राफ़ से डेटा प्रशिक्षण के लिए बूटस्ट्रैप्स है। इसके अलावा, हमारा दृष्टिकोण अपेक्षाकृत भाषा स्वतंत्र है और परिणामस्वरूप एक भाषा से दूसरी भाषा में जल्दी से (और इसलिए लागत प्रभावी ढंग से) पोर्ट किया जा सकता है, जिसके लिए केवल मामूली भाषा-विशिष्ट सिलाई की आवश्यकता होती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>发半自动注数集来速原型化名实体识别器新法。 两资贫乏凝言拟议管道:达罗毗荼语马拉雅拉姆语班图语isiZulu。 吾法受弱监督,导自维基百科Google图谱训练数。 此可以速言(故有成本效地)从一言而移一语,但须特定言少定。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Molaimid cur chuige nua chun fréamhshamhaltú tapa a dhéanamh ar lucht aitheantais aonáin ainmnithe trí thacair sonraí leath-uathoibríoch anótáilte a fhorbairt. Léirímid an phíblíne atá beartaithe maidir le dhá theanga agglutinating gann-acmhainní: an teanga Dravidian Mailéalaimis agus an teanga Bantu isiZulu. Tá maoirsiú lag ar ár gcur chuige agus cuirtear bac ar shonraí oiliúna ó Vicipéid agus ó Google Knowledge Graph. Ina theannta sin, tá ár gcur chuige sách neamhspleách ó thaobh teanga de agus is féidir é a aistriú go tapa (agus dá réir sin go cost-éifeachtach) ó theanga amháin go teanga eile, rud nach dteastaíonn ach mion-oiriúnú teanga-shonrach.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ მინდა პრომენტის პროტიპის გამოყენება, რომელიც სახელ ინტერტიკის მოცნობილის პროტოტიპის გავაკეთებას, სახელ ავტომატურად მონატანტირებული მონატანების განვითა ჩვენ გამოჩვენებთ საზოგადომის გარეშე ორი რესუპორციური ადგლუტინაციის ენაზე: დირავიდიური ენაში მალაიალამ და ბანტუ ენაში isiZulu. ჩვენი პროგრამა უბრალოდ მონაცემულია და დაბუტურებული სკიპედია და Google Knowledge Graph-ის განათლების მონაცემულია. დამატებით, ჩვენი წარმოდგენა relatively language independent და შემდეგ შეიძლება ბრალოდ (და ამიტომ გამოიყენება-ეფექტიურად) ერთი ენაზე მეორე, რომელიც მხოლოდ მცირე ენათის განსაზღვრული კონფიგურაცი</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Προτείνουμε μια νέα προσέγγιση για την ταχεία δημιουργία πρωτοτύπων ονομάτων αναγνωριστών οντοτήτων μέσω της ανάπτυξης ημιαυτόματα σχολιασμένων συνόλων δεδομένων. Επιδεικνύουμε τον προτεινόμενο αγωγό για δύο ελλιπείς συγκολλητικές γλώσσες: τη δραβιδική γλώσσα Μαλαγιάλαμ και τη γλώσσα Μπαντού είναι Ζουλού. Η προσέγγισή μας είναι ανεπαρκώς εποπτευμένη και χρησιμοποιεί δεδομένα εκπαίδευσης από τη Βικιπαίδεια και το Γνωσιακό Γράφημα της Google. Επιπλέον, η προσέγγισή μας είναι σχετικά γλωσσική ανεξάρτητη και κατά συνέπεια μπορεί να μεταφερθεί γρήγορα (και επομένως οικονομικά αποδοτικά) από τη μία γλώσσα στην άλλη, απαιτώντας μόνο μικρή γλωσσική προσαρμογή.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Új megközelítést javasolunk a nevezett entitás felismerők gyors prototípusának gyártására félautomatikusan jegyzetelt adathalmazok fejlesztésével. Bemutatjuk a javasolt csővezetéket két nem erőforrásokkal rendelkező agglutináló nyelven: a dravidi Malayalam és a bantu nyelven isizulu. Megközelítésünk gyengén felügyelt és bootstraps képzési adatok a Wikipédiából és a Google Knowledge Graphból. Ezen túlmenően a megközelítésünk viszonylag nyelvfüggetlen, következésképpen gyorsan (és így költséghatékonyan) hordozható egyik nyelvről a másikra, és csak kisebb nyelvspecifikus szabást igényel.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Proponiamo un nuovo approccio per la prototipazione rapida di identificatori di entità nominate attraverso lo sviluppo di set di dati annotati semi-automaticamente. Dimostriamo la pipeline proposta su due lingue agglutinanti sottorisorse: la lingua dravidiana Malayalam e la lingua bantu isiZulu. Il nostro approccio è debolmente supervisionato e bootstraps training dati da Wikipedia e Google Knowledge Graph. Inoltre, il nostro approccio è relativamente indipendente dalla lingua e può quindi essere trasportato rapidamente (e quindi economicamente) da una lingua all'altra, richiedendo solo una piccola personalizzazione linguistica specifica.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>We propose a novel approach for rapid prototyping of named entity recognisers through the development of semi-automatically annotated datasets.  Ние го демонстрираме предложениот гасовод на два јазици со недостаток на ресурси: дравидскиот јазик Малајајалам и јазикот Банту изулу. Нашиот пристап е слабо надгледуван и ги обучува податоците од Википедија и Google Knowledge Graph. Покрај тоа, нашиот пристап е релативно независен од јазикот и со тоа може да се пренесе брзо (и со тоа е ефикасно) од еден јазик до друг, барајќи само мало приспособување специфично на јазикот.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Siūlome naują metodą greitam pavadintų subjektų pripažintojų prototipų nustatymui plėtojant pusautomatiškai anotuotus duomenų rinkinius. Mes parodome siūlomą vamzdyną dviem nepakankamai išteklių turinčiomis agglutinuojančiomis kalbomis: dravidijos kalba Malayalam ir Bantu kalba isiZulu. Mūsų požiūris yra silpnai prižiūrimas ir įjungia Wikipedia ir Google Knowledge Graph mokymo duomenis. Be to, mūsų požiūris yra palyginti nepriklausomas nuo kalbos ir todėl gali būti greitai (ir todėl ekonomiškai efektyviai) perkeltas iš vienos kalbos į kitą, reikalaujant tik nedidelio kalbos pritaikymo.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Біз жарты автоматты түрде белгіленген деректер жинақтарын жасау арқылы аталған нысандардың тез прототиптерін жаңа түрде жасау арқылы жаңа тәртібін ұсынамыз. Біз қолданыстағы қосымша қосымша қосымша қосымша қосымша қосымша қосымша қосымша тілдерді көрсетедік: Дравидия тілі Малайям және Банту тілі isiZulu. Біздің қасиетіміз Википедия және Google Knowledge графикасындағы деректерді бақылау және жүктеуді бақылау. Сонымен қатар, біздің тәсілдігіміз сәйкес тілді тәуелсіз, сондықтан бір тілден бір тілден бір тілде тәуелсіз (және бұл үшін бұл тілден бір тілде тәуелсіз) жібере алады, тек кішк</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ml>പേരിട്ട വസ്തുവിന്റെ തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നവരുടെ പേരില്‍ പെട്ടെന്ന് പ്രോട്ടോട്ടിപ്പിനുള്ള നോവല്‍ പ്രോട്ടോട്ടോപ്റ നമ്മള്‍ നിര്‍ദ്ദേശിക്കപ്പെട്ട രണ്ട് വിഭവങ്ങളുടെ ഭാഷകളില്‍ പൈപ്പെലൈന്‍ പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്നു; ഡ്രാവിഡിയന്‍ ഭാഷ മലായാലാമ ഞങ്ങളുടെ സമ്പാദം ദുര്‍ബലമായി നിരീക്ഷിക്കപ്പെടുന്നതും വിക്കിപിഡിയയില്‍ നിന്നും ഗൂഗിള്‍ അറിവ് ഗ്രാഫില അതുകൊണ്ടും, നമ്മുടെ സമ്പ്രദായം വളരെ സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യമായ ഭാഷയാണ്. അതുകൊണ്ട് ഒരു ഭാഷയില്‍ നിന്നും മറ്റൊരു ഭാഷയിലേക്കും വേഗം പോര്‍ട്ട് ചെയ്യാന്‍ സ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_ms>Kami cadangkan pendekatan baru untuk prototip cepat pengenalpasti entiti bernama melalui pembangunan set data semi-automatik anotasi. Kami menunjukkan saluran paip yang diusulkan pada dua bahasa yang kurang sumber: bahasa Dravidia Malayalam dan bahasa Bantu isiZulu. Pendekatan kami adalah mengawasi lemah dan bootstraps latihan data dari Wikipedia dan Google Knowledge Graph. Moreover, our approach is relatively language independent and can consequently be ported quickly (and hence cost-effectively) from one language to another, requiring only minor language-specific tailoring.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nipproponu approċċ ġdid għall-prototip rapidu ta’ rikonoxxituri ta’ entitajiet imsemmija permezz tal-iżvilupp ta’ settijiet ta’ dejta semiawtomatikament annotati. Aħna nuru l-pipeline propost dwar żewġ lingwi agglutinanti b’riżorsi baxxi: il-lingwa Dravidjana Malayalam u l-lingwa Bantu isiZulu. L-approċċ tagħna huwa sorveljat b’mod dgħajjef u jnaqqas id-dejta tat-taħriġ mill-Wikipedia u l-Google Knowledge Graph. Barra minn hekk, l-approċċ tagħna huwa relattivament indipendenti mil-lingwa u konsegwentement jista’ jinġabar malajr (u għalhekk b’mod kosteffettiv) minn lingwa għal oħra, li jeħtieġ biss tfassil minuri speċifiku għall-lingwa.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Vi foreslår eit nytt tilnærming for rask prototyping av gjenkjente entitet gjennom utviklinga av semiautomatisk oppmerkte datasett. Vi viser foreslått røyrlinje på to underressurserte aggluteringsspråk: Dravidisk språk Malayalam og Bantu-språket isiZulu. Tilnærminga vårt er viktig oversikt og oppstartslag opplæringsdata frå Wikipedia og Google Knowledge Graph. I tillegg er tilnærming vårt relativt språk uavhengig, og derfor kan bli portert raskt (og derfor kostnadseffektivt) frå ein språk til ein annan, derfor krev berre mindre språk-spesifikke tillegg.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Proponujemy nowatorskie podejście do szybkiego prototypowania nazwanych identyfikatorów podmiotów poprzez opracowanie półautomatycznie adnotacyjnych zbiorów danych. Przedstawiamy proponowany rurociąg dotyczący dwóch niedostatecznie zasobów języków aglutynujących: języka drawidyjskiego Malayalam i języka Bantu jest Zulu. Nasze podejście jest słabo nadzorowane i bootstraps dane szkoleniowe z Wikipedii i Google Knowledge Graph. Ponadto nasze podejście jest stosunkowo niezależne od języka i w konsekwencji może być szybko (a tym samym opłacalnie) przeniesione z jednego języka do drugiego, wymagając jedynie niewielkiego dopasowania specyficznego języka.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Бид нэрлэгдсэн бүтээгдэхүүний хурдан прототипчлэх шинэ арга замыг автоматжуулсан өгөгдлийн санг хөгжүүлэхээр сануулдаг. Бид хоёр төвөгтэй аглуутайн хэл дээр тайлбарласан хоолойн шугам нь Дравидийн хэл Малайалам, Банту хэл isiZulu гэдгийг харуулж байна. Бидний арга зам нь Wikipedia болон Google Knowledge Graph-ын сургалтын өгөгдлийг багасгаж байдаг. Мөн бидний арга зам нь харьцангуй хэл тус хамааралтай. Үүнээс хурдан (үүнээс үнэ цэнэтэй) нэг хэлээс нөгөө хэлээс нөгөө хэлээс нөгөө хэлээс нь бага хэл тодорхойлох шаардлагатай.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Propunem o abordare nouă pentru prototiparea rapidă a recunoașterilor entităților denumite prin dezvoltarea seturilor de date adnotate semi-automat. Demonstrăm conducta propusă pe două limbi aglutinante insuficient de resurse: limba dravidiană Malayalam și limba bantu isiZulu. Abordarea noastră este slab supravegheată și datele de instruire bootstraps din Wikipedia și Google Knowledge Graph. Mai mult decât atât, abordarea noastră este relativ independentă de limbă și, prin urmare, poate fi transportată rapid (și, prin urmare, rentabil) de la o limbă la alta, necesitând doar o personalizare minoră specifică limbii.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා නාමක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් නිර්මාණය කරලා තියෙන්නේ  අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා පායිප්ලයින් දෙන්නෙක් අඩු සම්පූර්ණ භාෂාවක් වල: ඩ්‍රාවිඩියාන් භාෂාව මලායාලාම් සහ අපේ පරීක්ෂණය විකිපිඩියා සහ ගුගුල් දන්න ග්‍රාෆ් වලින් දුර්වලින් පරීක්ෂණය කරලා බටස්ට්‍රෑප් කරල තවත්, අපේ භාෂාව සාමාන්‍ය භාෂාව ස්ථායිත වෙන්න පුළුවන්, ඒ වගේම ඉක්මනින් ඉක්මනින් ඉක්මනින් (ඒ වගේම ක්‍රියාත්මක ව</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu horumarinaynaa qaab warqad ah sameynta dhaqso oo lagu magacaabay qofka loo aqoonsaday marka loo horumariyo sawirada macluumaadka si bilowga ah. Waxaannu muujinnaa pipeline la soo jeeday oo ku qoran laba luqadood oo aan la isticmaali karin: luqada Drawiyan Malayalam iyo luqada isizulu. Dhaqdhaqaalahayaga waxaa la ilaaliyaa itaal daryeel iyo macluumaad waxbarasho oo lagu tababarayo ee Wikipedia iyo Graf aqoonta Googley. Sidoo kale dhaqdhaqaalahayagu waa luqadeena mid u xor ah, markaasna waxaa loo bandhigi karaa si dhaqso ah (sababtaas darteed kharash-faa’iido leh) oo af ilaa af kale looga baahan yahay mid ku qoran luqad yar oo kaliya.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>Predlažemo nov pristup brzom prototipiranju priznatih entiteta kroz razvoj polu-automatski notiranih podataka. Pokazali smo predloženu cijevinu na dva pod resursima agluticiranja jezika: Dravidski jezik Malayalam i Bantu jezik isiZulu. Naš pristup je slab nadzor i obuka podataka iz Wikipedia i Google Knowledge Grafa. Osim toga, naš pristup je relativno nezavisan jezik i stoga se može brzo prijaviti (i stoga se koštaju efikasno) od jednog jezika na drugog jezika, zahtevajući samo manje specifične praćenje jezika.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Vi föreslår ett nytt tillvägagångssätt för snabb prototyp av namngivna entitetsigenkännare genom utveckling av halvautomatiskt kommenterade datauppsättningar. Vi visar den föreslagna pipeline på två underresourcerade agglutinerande språk: dravidiska språket Malayalam och bantu språket isizulu. Vårt tillvägagångssätt är svagt övervakat och bootstraps träningsdata från Wikipedia och Google Knowledge Graph. Dessutom är vårt tillvägagångssätt relativt språkoberoende och kan följaktligen snabbt (och därmed kostnadseffektivt) överföras från ett språk till ett annat, vilket endast kräver mindre språkspecifik skräddarsy.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாம் பெயர் பொருள் அடையாளங்களின் வேகமான முறைமையை உருவாக்குவதற்கு ஒரு புதிய செயல்பாட்டை பரிந்துரைக்கிறோம். We demonstrate the proposed pipeline on two under-resourced agglutinating languages: the Dravidian language Malayalam and the Bantu language isiZulu.  விகிபிடியா மற்றும் கூகுல் அறிவு வரைப்படத்திலிருந்து தகவல் பயிற்சியை கண்காணிக்கப்படுகிறது. மேலும், எங்கள் நெருக்கம் சுருக்கமான மொழி சுதந்திரமாக இருக்கும் மற்றும் அதனால் விரைவில் (மற்றும் அதனால் விலை செலவு செயல்படுத்தப்படும்) ஒரு ம</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم نے ایک نئی طریقہ پیش کرتا ہے جس کا نام اتنی پہچان کرنے والوں کے لئے سریع پروٹوٹیپینگ کا ذریعہ ہے نصف-اٹوٹیٹ ڈیٹ سٹ کی توسعہ سے۔ ہم نے پیغمبر کی پیشنهاد کی پیپ لین کو دکھایا ہے دو کم رسسورٹی زبانوں میں: ڈراویڈی زبان مالایالم اور بانٹو زبان ایزیزولو۔ ہمارا طریقہ کمزور تحقیق ہے اور بوٹ سٹرپ ویکیپیڈیا اور گوگل علم گراف سے آموزش دادہ کی آموزش کرتا ہے. اور اس کے بعد ہماری طریقہ مقابلہ میں زبان کی بے نیاز ہے اور اس کے نتیجہ میں ایک زبان سے دوسرے زبان سے سریع (اور اس کے نتیجہ میں) لے کر آ سکتا ہے، صرف تھوڑی زبان کے مطابق تدبیر کرنے کی ضرورت ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Biz quyidagi obʼektlarni avtomatik avtomatik taʼminlovchi maʼlumotlar tarkibini tahlash orqali tez qilish uchun novel usulini tahlil qilamiz. Biz tasavvur qilingan pipelin ikkita tashkilotlar tilida ko'rsatdik: Dravidian tili Malayalam va Bantu tili isizulu. Bizning murojaatiyatlarimiz juda tez taʼminlovchi va Wikipedia va Google Fan Grafikdan taʼminlovchi maʼlumotni boshqarishdir. Ko'pchilik, bizning tilimiz o'xshash tilda o'xshash bo'ladi va keyin bir tildan bir tildan foydalanish mumkin, faqat kichkina tilni qo'shish kerak.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi đề xuất một phương pháp mới cho việc xử lý nhanh những người nhận diện thực thể tên bằng cách phát triển các tập tin đã được ghi chú gần tự động. Chúng tôi chứng minh khả năng cung cấp cho hai ngôn ngữ đậm đặc thiếu nguồn: ngôn ngữ của người Đức Malayaham và ngôn ngữ Banu isiZulu. Cách tiếp cận của chúng tôi được giám sát thiếu sót và khởi động dữ liệu tập luyện trên Wikipedia và Google knowledge Graph. Hơn nữa, cách tiếp cận của chúng ta là tương đối độc lập ngôn ngữ và do đó có thể được áp dụng nhanh chóng (và do đó có giá trị kinh tế) từ ngôn ngữ này sang ngôn ngữ khác, chỉ cần chỉnh sửa nhỏ.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>We stellen een nieuwe aanpak voor voor snelle prototyping van benoemde entiteitsherkenners door de ontwikkeling van semi-automatisch geannoteerde datasets. We demonstreren de voorgestelde pijplijn op twee onvoldoende beschikbare agglutinerende talen: de Dravidische taal Malayalam en de Bantu taal isiZulu. Onze aanpak wordt zwak begeleid en bootstraps trainingsgegevens uit Wikipedia en Google Knowledge Graph. Bovendien is onze aanpak relatief taalonafhankelijk en kan daardoor snel (en dus kosteneffectief) van de ene naar de andere taal worden overgezet, waarbij slechts een kleine taalspecifieke aanpassing vereist is.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Predlažemo nov pristup brzom prototipiranju priznatih subjekta kroz razvoj polu-automatski notiranih podataka. Pokazali smo predloženu cijevinu na dva pod resursima aglutirajućih jezika: Dravidski jezik Malayalam i Bantu jezik isiZulu. Naš pristup je slab nadzor i podaci obuke iz Wikipedia i Google Knowledge Grafa. Osim toga, naš pristup je relativno nezavisan jezik i stoga se može brzo (i stoga se koštati učinkovito) prijaviti od jednog jezika na drugog jezika, zahtijevajući samo manje praćenje jezika specifičnog.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi foreslår en ny tilgang til hurtig prototype af navngivne entitetsgenkendere gennem udvikling af halvautomatisk annoterede datasæt. Vi demonstrerer den foreslåede pipeline på to underresourcerede agglutinerende sprog: det dravidiske sprog Malayalam og Bantu sproget isizulu. Vores tilgang er svagt overvåget og bootstraps træningsdata fra Wikipedia og Google Knowledge Graph. Desuden er vores tilgang relativt sproguafhængig og kan derfor hurtigt (og dermed omkostningseffektivt) overføres fra et sprog til et andet, hvilket kun kræver mindre sprogspecifik skræddersyelse.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Kami mengusulkan pendekatan baru untuk prototip cepat dari pengenal entitas bernama melalui pengembangan set data semi-otomatis anotasi. Kami menunjukkan saluran pipa yang diusulkan pada dua bahasa yang kurang sumber daya: bahasa Dravidia Malayalam dan bahasa Bantu isiZulu. pendekatan kita terlihat lemah dan bootstraps data latihan dari Wikipedia dan Google Knowledge Graph. Selain itu, pendekatan kita relatif bahasa independen dan konsekuensinya dapat dibawa dengan cepat (dan oleh itu rental-efektif) dari satu bahasa ke bahasa lainnya, yang membutuhkan hanya sedikit penyesuaian spesifik bahasa.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_bg>Предлагаме нов подход за бързо прототипиране на наименовани разпознаватели на обекти чрез разработване на полуавтоматично анотирани набори от данни. Представяме предложения тръбопровод на два аглутиниращи езика с недостатъчен ресурс: дравидски език малаялам и бантуски език исулу. Нашият подход е слабо контролиран и събира данни за обучение от Уикипедия и Гугъл графика на знанието. Нещо повече, нашият подход е относително независим от езика и следователно може да бъде пренесен бързо (и следователно икономически ефективно) от един език на друг, изисквайки само незначителна езикова специфика.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_fa>ما پیشنهاد می‌کنیم روش نویسی برای پیش‌نویسی سریع پیش‌نویسی پیش‌نویسی از طریق توسعه‌ی مجموعه‌های داده‌های استفاده‌شده‌ی نیم‌خودکار. ما این لوله پیشنهاد را در دو زبان زیر منطقه‌ای نشان می‌دهیم: زبان دروادیه مالایالم و زبان بانتو isiZulu. دسترسی ما ضعیف تحت نظر قرار گرفته و داده های آموزشی از ویکیپدیا و گراف دانش Google است. در ضمن، دسترسی ما نسبتاً زبان مستقل است و به نتیجه می تواند سریع (و از این نتیجه با تأثیر قیمت) از یک زبان به یک زبان حمل شود، و تنها اندازه‌گیری به زبان خاص کوچک نیاز دارد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 반자동 주석 데이터 집합을 개발하여 신속하게 원형화된 명명 실체 식별기를 개발하는 새로운 방법을 제시했다.우리는 두 가지 자원이 부족한 접합 언어에서 제안된 파이프라인: 델라위어 말레이시아어와 반투어 이시조루어를 보여 주었다.우리의 방법은 위키백과와 구글 지식도에서 나온 훈련 데이터를 약하게 감독하고 유도하는 것이다.그 밖에 우리의 방법은 언어에 상대적으로 독립되어 있기 때문에 한 언어에서 다른 언어로 빠르게 (경제적으로) 이식할 수 있고 소량의 특정한 언어의 재단만 필요하다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>Wir schlagen einen neuartigen Ansatz für das Rapid Prototyping benannter Entitätenerkennungen durch die Entwicklung semiautomatisch annotierter Datensätze vor. Wir demonstrieren die vorgeschlagene Pipeline auf zwei unzureichenden Agglutinierungssprachen: der dravidischen Sprache Malayalam und der Bantu-Sprache isiZulu. Unser Ansatz ist schwach überwacht und bootstraps Trainingsdaten aus Wikipedia und Google Knowledge Graph. Darüber hinaus ist unser Ansatz relativ sprachunabhängig und kann daher schnell (und damit kostengünstig) von einer Sprache in eine andere portiert werden, wobei nur geringe sprachspezifische Anpassungen erforderlich sind.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_af>Ons voorstel 'n nuwe toegang vir vinnige prototipering van genoem entiteit herkenaars deur die ontwikkeling van semi- automaties opgemerkte datastelle. Ons wys die voorgestelde pyplyn op twee onder-hulpbronne agluteerde tale: die Dravidiëse taal Malayalam en die Bantu taal isiZulu. Ons toegang is swak ondersoek en opstarp onderwerp data van Wikipedia en Google Knowledge Graph. Ook, ons toegang is relativief taal onveilig en kan daarom vinnig (en daarom koste-effektief) van een taal na 'n ander ondersteun word, en net klein taal-spesifieke sterking vereis.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>አካባቢው የሚታወቁትን የፍጥነት ፕሮግራም ለመፍጠር የረኀብ ጉዳይ አካባቢ አካባቢ አካባቢ አካባቢ አካባቢ መፍጠር እናስጀምራለን፡፡ We demonstrate the proposed pipeline on two under-resourced agglutinating languages: the Dravidian language Malayalam and the Bantu language isiZulu.  የጎግል እውቀት ግንኙነታችን ደካማ ነው፡፡ ደግሞም የቋንቋችን ነፃ ነጻ ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sw>Tunazipendekeza mbinu ya riwaya kwa ajili ya mifano ya haraka ya kutengeneza jina la entity kutambua kwa kupitia maendeleo ya seti za taarifa zinazovutiwa kwa mara mbili. Tunaonyesha pipeline inayopendekezwa kwenye lugha mbili isiyo na rasmi: lugha ya KiDravidi ya Malayalam na lugha ya Bantu isiZulu. Matokeo yetu ni dhaifu yanafuatiliwa na mafunzo ya taarifa kutoka Wikipedia na Graph ya Ujuzi wa Google. Zaidi ya hayo, mbinu yetu ni lugha yenye uhuru na kwa hiyo inaweza kuchukuliwa haraka (na hivyo gharama za gharama) kutoka lugha moja hadi nyingine, inayohitaji kufuatilia lugha madogo tu.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք առաջարկում ենք նոր մոտեցում անվանված էակների ճանաչողների արագ նախատիպ ստեղծելու համար, կիսաավտոմատ գրված տվյալների համակարգերի զարգացման միջոցով: Մենք ցույց ենք տալիս առաջարկած խողովակաշարը երկու թերռեսուրսներով խեղճող լեզուների վրա՝ Դրավիդիայի լեզուն՝ մալայալամը և Բանտու լեզուն՝ իսյուլուն: Մեր մոտեցումը թույլ է վերահսկվում և սկսում է վարժեցնել Վիքիփեդիայի և Google Knowledge Graf-ի տվյալները: Ավելին, մեր մոտեցումը հարաբերականորեն անկախ է լեզվից, և հետևաբար կարող է արագ (և հետևաբար գնահատականորեն) տեղափոխվել մեկ լեզվից մյուսին, որն անհրաժեշտ է միայն փոքր լեզվի մասնավորման:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_tr>Biz "entitet" diýilip tanyşanlarynyň çalt prototik taýýarlamagyny ýarym-otomatik tanyşan veri setirlerini geliştirmegini teklip edýäris. Biz golaýlanmış iki golaý altynda teklip eden pipelini: Drawiýat dili Malayalam we Bantu dilinde isiZulu görkezilýäris. Biziň ýaryşymyz Wikipediýanyň we Google Bilgi Grafiýasyndan azajyk gözleýän we göçüp biljek maglumatlarymyz bar. Munuň ýagdaýymyz görä görä dilimiz täsirli ýuwaşsyz bolýar we şonuň üçin bir dilden täsirli ýuwaşlyk bilen (onuň üçin kän-täsirli bolmagy üçin) bir dile taýýarlanabilir. Diňe kiçi dillerden aýratyn taýýarlamak gerek</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে বিরক্তিকর তথ্যের উন্নয়নের মাধ্যমে দ্রুত প্রোটোটোটাইপের জন্য একটি উপন্যাস প্রস্তাব করি। আমরা প্রস্তাবিত পাইপেলাইন দুটি নিম্নলিখিত ভাষায় প্রদর্শন করছি: ড্রাভিডিয়ার ভাষা মালায়ালাম এবং বাংটু ভাষা ইজুলুর উপর। উইকিপিডিয়া এবং গুগল জ্ঞান গ্রাফ থেকে বুটস্ট্র্যাপ প্রশিক্ষণের তথ্য দুর্বল পর্যবেক্ষণ করা হয়েছে। এছাড়াও, আমাদের পদক্ষেপ হচ্ছে আকর্ষণীয় ভাষার স্বাধীন এবং এর ফলে দ্রুত পোর্ট করা যাবে (এবং এর ফলে এক ভাষা থেকে এক ভাষা থেকে কার্যকর ভাষায়) যার জন</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_sq>Ne propozojmë një qasje të re për prototipin e shpejtë të njohësve të emëruar të njësive nëpërmjet zhvillimit të grupeve të dhënash gjysmë-automatike të anotuara. Ne demonstrojmë tubacionin e propozuar në dy gjuhë të pakufishme të aglutinuara: gjuhën dravidiane Malayalam dhe gjuhën Bantu isiZulu. Our approach is weakly supervised and bootstraps training data from Wikipedia and Google Knowledge Graph.  Përveç kësaj, qasja jonë është relativisht e pavarur nga gjuha dhe mund të sillet shpejt (dhe kështu me kosto-efektivitet) nga një gjuhë në tjetrën, duke kërkuar vetëm përshtatje të vogla specifike për gjuhën.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_az>Biz, yarńĪ-avtomatik t…ôŇükil veril…ôn qurmaqlarńĪn t…ôŇükil etm…ôsi vasit…ôsil…ô adlńĪ entit…ô tanńĪyńĪcńĪlarńĪn tez prototipi √ľ√ß√ľn yeni bir yol t…ôklif edirik. Biz t…ôklif etdiyimiz bor √ßizgisini iki qonaqlarńĪn altńĪndakńĪ agglutinasyon dilind…ô g√∂st…ôririk: Dravid dili Malayalam v…ô Bantu dili isiZulu. Bizim t…ôrzimiz Wikipedia v…ô Google Knowledge Graph t…ôhsil edil…ôn m…ôlumatlarńĪ z…ôif g√∂zl…ôyir. Daha sonra, bizim t…ôr…ôfimiz relativ dil bańüńĪmsńĪzdńĪr v…ô buna g√∂r…ô d…ô d…ôrhal (v…ô buna g√∂r…ô d…ô qiym…ôtli olaraq) bir dild…ôn baŇüqa dil…ô t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ôf t…ôr…ô</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Predlažemo nov pristup brzom prototipiranju priznatih entiteta kroz razvoj polu-automatski notiranih podataka. Pokazali smo predloženu cijevinu na dva pod resursima aglutirajućih jezika: Dravidski jezik Malayalam i Bantu jezik isiZulu. Naš pristup je slab nadzor i podaci obuke iz Wikipedia i Google Knowledge Grafa. Osim toga, naš pristup je relativno nezavisan jezik i stoga se može brzo (i stoga se koštati efikasno) prijaviti od jednog jezika na drugog jezika, zahtijevajući samo manje praćenje jezika specifičnog.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Pakume välja uudse lähenemisviisi nimetatud olemitunnistajate kiireks prototüüpimiseks poolautomaatsete annoteeritud andmekogumite arendamise kaudu. Tutvustame kavandatud juhtmestikku kahel alaressursiga aglutineerival keelel: draviidi keel malayalam ja bantu keel isizulu. Meie lähenemine on nõrgalt jälgitav ja bootstraps treeningu andmed Wikipediast ja Google Knowledge Graphist. Lisaks on meie lähenemisviis suhteliselt keelesõltumatu ja seetõttu saab seda kiiresti (ja seega kulutõhusalt) ühest keelest teise transportida, nõudes vaid väikest keelelist kohandamist.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ca>Proposem un enfocament nou per a prototipar ràpidament els reconeixents d'entitats anotats mitjançant el desenvolupament de conjunts de dades semi-automàticament anotats. Demonstrem el pipeline proposat en dues llengües aglutinants amb pocs recursos: el llenguatge dravídic malàyal i el llenguatge Bantu isZulu. El nostre enfocament està debidament supervisat i treina les dades de Wikipedia i Google Knowledge Graph. A més, el nostre enfocament és relativament independent del llenguatge i, per tant, pot ser portat ràpidament (i, per tant, rentablement) d'una llengua a l'altra, només necessitant una adaptació minor específica del llenguatge.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Navrhujeme nový přístup pro rychlé prototypování pojmenovaných rozpoznávačů entit prostřednictvím vývoje poloautomaticky anotovaných datových sad. Ukážeme navrhovaný plynovod na dvou nedostatečně vybavených aglutinačních jazycích: dravidském jazyce malajálam a bantuském jazyce isZulu. Náš přístup je slabě dohlížený a bootstrapuje tréninková data z Wikipedie a Google Knowledge Graph. Navíc je náš přístup relativně jazykově nezávislý a může být proto přenášen rychle (a tedy cenově efektivně) z jednoho jazyka do druhého, což vyžaduje pouze menší jazykové přizpůsobení.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Ehdotamme uutta lähestymistapaa nimettyjen entiteettitunnistimien nopeaan prototyyppiin kehittämällä puoliautomaattisia annotoituja datakokonaisuuksia. Esittelemme ehdotetun putkiston kahdella aliresurssisella agglutinaatiokielellä: dravidian kielellä malayalam ja bantun kielellä isizulu. Lähestymistapamme on heikosti valvottu ja bootstraps harjoitusdataa Wikipediasta ja Google Knowledge Graphista. Lisäksi lähestymistapamme on suhteellisen kieliriippumaton, ja sen vuoksi se voidaan siirtää nopeasti (ja siten kustannustehokkaasti) kieleltä toiselle, mikä edellyttää vain vähäistä kielikohtaista räätälöintiä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>Predlagamo nov pristop za hitro prototipiranje imenovanih prepoznavalcev entitet z razvojem polavtomatsko označenih naborov podatkov. Predlagani plinovod predstavljamo na dveh aglutinacijskih jezikih s premalo virov: dravidskem jeziku malajalam in bantujem izzulu. Naš pristop je slabo nadzorovan in zajema podatke o usposabljanju iz Wikipedije in Google Knowledge Graph. Poleg tega je naš pristop relativno jezikovno neodvisen in ga je zato mogoče hitro (in s tem stroškovno učinkovito) prenesti iz enega jezika v drugega, kar zahteva le manjše jezikovno specifično prilagajanje.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Munã goyyade wani matsayi na nowaya wa misalin abun da aka faɗa abun da aka sani game da the Development of data set by semi-farat-inganci. Tuna nuna da aka goyaye piilein a kan lugha biyu masu ƙaranci: lugha na Dandiyan Malayalam da harshen isiZulu. Mataimakinmu yana ƙaranci kuma an tsare data daga Taurar Sann na Wikimedia da Google. Kayya, hanyarmu na kamfata harshe, yana da huru kuma ana iya karatun da haraka (kuma dõmin haka masu kifi mai amfani da shi) daga harshen guda zuwa wani harshe, kuma yana tambayar ku da danganta masu ƙarami kawai.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé nggunakake sistem sing rawuh akeh kanggo ngilangno prototype anyir tentang karo nganggo sistem sing dadi iki dadi sing nguasakno Awak dhéwé éntuk ngéwangi tanggal sing nyeangké ning langa sing luwih banter: lenga Drawian, malayam lan lenga Bantu isiGulu. Ndoleh awak dhéwé kuwi nglanggar-sistem luwih nguasai karo mulasai kuwi nggawe dadi Wipediya karo Google knowness Graph. Lalika bener, akeh sing nglanga luwih dumateng lan akeh iso nglanggar bantuan (kaya nguasai njaluk-njaluk) sak sabên langa sampeyan liyane wis nguasai, akeh iso nglanggar langa sing nesaturan pur.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>אנו מציעים גישה חדשה לאבטיפוס מהיר של מזהה ישויות בשם דרך הפיתוח של קבוצות נתונים חצי-אוטומטיות. אנחנו מציגים את הצינור המוצע בשתי שפות מתעצבנות מתחת למשאלות: שפת דראבידית מליאלאם ושפת בנטו איזיזולו. הגישה שלנו מפקחת בחולשה ומעטפת מידע אימון מוויקיפדיה וגוגל גרף ידע. חוץ מזה, הגישה שלנו היא יחסית עצמאית לשפה, ולכן אפשר להעביר אותה מהר (ולכן יעיל במחיר) משפה אחת לשפה אחרת, דורשת רק תצוגה קטנה ספציפית לשפה.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་མིང་དང་འཛིན་པའི་དབུལ་གྱི་ཕྱོགས་སྐོར་ལ་རང་འགུལ་གྱིས་ཟིན་བྲིས་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་གསར་གཏོང་ཞིག་དང་། ང་ཚོས་རྗེས་སུ་འབྱུང་བའི་སྐད་རིགས་གཙང་འབོད་པའི་མ་གཟུགས་འབྲེལ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་སྔོན་འཆར་བྱས་པའི་རྒྱུད་དུ་བཀོད་པ་ཡིན། ང་ཚོའི་གཟུགས་སྐོར་ནི་Wikipedia དང Google Knowledge Graph ཡིས་བརྗོད་མཁན་གྱི་རྩོལ་མེད་སྟོན་པ་དང་འགོ་འཁྱེར་གྱི་ཐབས་ཤེས་ཡོད། འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོའི་ཐབས་ལམ་དེ་ཆུང་མཐའ་ནས་སྐད་ཡིག་ནི་སྟེང་ནས་མཐའ་འགྱུར་བ་ཞིག་ཏུ་འཇུག</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Majority Voting with Bidirectional Pre-translation For Bitext Retrieval</title>
      <author><first>Alexander</first><last>Jones</last></author>
      <author><first>Derry Tanti</first><last>Wijaya</last></author>
      <pages>46–59</pages>
      <abstract>Obtaining high-quality parallel corpora is of paramount importance for training NMT systems. However, as many language pairs lack adequate gold-standard training data, a popular approach has been to mine so-called pseudo-parallel sentences from paired documents in two languages. In this paper, we outline some drawbacks with current methods that rely on an embedding similarity threshold, and propose a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuristic_(computer_science)">heuristic method</a> in its place. Our method involves translating both halves of a paired corpus before mining, and then performing a majority vote on sentence pairs mined in three ways : after translating documents in language x to language y, after translating language y to x, and using the original documents in languages x and y. We demonstrate success with this novel approach on the Tatoeba similarity search benchmark in 64 low-resource languages, and on NMT in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kazakh_language">Kazakh</a> and Gujarati. We also uncover the effect of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_(biology)">resource-related factors</a> (i.e. how much monolingual / bilingual data is available for a given language) on the optimal choice of bitext mining method, demonstrating that there is currently no one-size-fits-all approach for this task. We make the code and data used in our experiments publicly available.</abstract>
      <url hash="9e9ffbc4">2021.bucc-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>jones-wijaya-2021-majority</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/AlexJonesNLP/alt-bitexts" additional="false">AlexJonesNLP/alt-bitexts</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/bucc">BUCC</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/tatoeba">Tatoeba</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>EM Corpus : a comparable corpus for a less-resourced language pair Manipuri-English<fixed-case>EM</fixed-case> Corpus: a comparable corpus for a less-resourced language pair <fixed-case>M</fixed-case>anipuri-<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish</title>
      <author><first>Rudali</first><last>Huidrom</last></author>
      <author><first>Yves</first><last>Lepage</last></author>
      <author><first>Khogendra</first><last>Khomdram</last></author>
      <pages>60–67</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we introduce a sentence-level comparable text corpus crawled and created for the less-resourced language pair, Manipuri(mni) and English (eng). Our monolingual corpora comprise 1.88 million Manipuri sentences and 1.45 million English sentences, and our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_corpus">parallel corpus</a> comprises 124,975 Manipuri-English sentence pairs. These data were crawled and collected over a year from August 2020 to March 2021 from a local newspaper website called ‘The Sangai Express.’ The resources reported in this paper are made available to help the low-resourced languages community for MT / NLP tasks.</abstract>
      <url hash="a4e1b714">2021.bucc-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>huidrom-etal-2021-em</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/pmindia">PMIndia</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>On Pronunciations in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wiktionary">Wiktionary</a> : Extraction and Experiments on Multilingual Syllabification and Stress Prediction<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>iktionary: Extraction and Experiments on Multilingual Syllabification and Stress Prediction</title>
      <author><first>Winston</first><last>Wu</last></author>
      <author><first>David</first><last>Yarowsky</last></author>
      <pages>68–74</pages>
      <abstract>We constructed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parsers</a> for five non-English editions of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wiktionary">Wiktionary</a>, which combined with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pronunciation">pronunciations</a> from the English edition, comprises over 5.3 million IPA pronunciations, the largest pronunciation lexicon of its kind. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> is a unique comparable corpus of IPA pronunciations annotated from multiple sources. We analyze the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>, noting the presence of machine-generated pronunciations. We develop a novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visualization_(graphics)">visualization method</a> to quantify <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syllabification">syllabification</a>. We experiment on the new combined task of multilingual IPA syllabification and stress prediction, finding that training a massively multilingual neural sequence-to-sequence model with copy attention can improve performance on both high- and low-resource languages, and multi-task training on stress prediction helps with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syllabification">syllabification</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="0a8e6918">2021.bucc-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>wu-yarowsky-2021-pronunciations</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>A Dutch Dataset for Cross-lingual Multilabel Toxicity Detection<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>utch Dataset for Cross-lingual Multilabel Toxicity Detection</title>
      <author><first>Ben</first><last>Burtenshaw</last></author>
      <author><first>Mike</first><last>Kestemont</last></author>
      <pages>75–79</pages>
      <abstract>Multi-label toxicity detection is highly prominent, with many research groups, companies, and individuals engaging with it through shared tasks and dedicated venues. This paper describes a cross-lingual approach to annotating multi-label text classification on a newly developed Dutch language dataset, using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> trained on English data. We present an ensemble model of one Transformer model and an LSTM using Multilingual embeddings. The combination of multilingual embeddings and the Transformer model improves performance in a cross-lingual setting.</abstract>
      <url hash="ae0ef078">2021.bucc-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>burtenshaw-kestemont-2021-dutch</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>