<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.lchange">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Computational Approaches to Historical Language Change 2021</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Nina</first><last>Tahmasebi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Adam</first><last>Jatowt</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yang</first><last>Xu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Simon</first><last>Hengchen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Syrielle</first><last>Montariol</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Haim</first><last>Dubossarsky</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="4d61727a">2021.lchange-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="05788371">2021.lchange-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>lchange-2021-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Time-Aware Ancient Chinese Text Translation and Inference<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>ncient <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese Text Translation and Inference</title>
      <author><first>Ernie</first><last>Chang</last></author>
      <author><first>Yow-Ting</first><last>Shiue</last></author>
      <author><first>Hui-Syuan</first><last>Yeh</last></author>
      <author><first>Vera</first><last>Demberg</last></author>
      <pages>1–6</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we aim to address the challenges surrounding the translation of ancient Chinese text : (1) The linguistic gap due to the difference in eras results in translations that are poor in quality, and (2) most translations are missing the contextual information that is often very crucial to understanding the text. To this end, we improve upon past translation techniques by proposing the following : We reframe the task as a multi-label prediction task where the model predicts both the translation and its particular era. We observe that this helps to bridge the linguistic gap as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context_(language_use)">chronological context</a> is also used as auxiliary information. We validate our framework on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_text">parallel corpus</a> annotated with chronology information and show experimentally its efficacy in producing quality translation outputs. We release both the code and the data for future research.</abstract>
      <url hash="9e9830a9">2021.lchange-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.lchange-1.1</doi>
      <bibkey>chang-etal-2021-time</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/orina1123/time-aware-ancient-text-translation" additional="false">orina1123/time-aware-ancient-text-translation</pwccode>
    <title_ar>ترجمة النصوص الصينية القديمة المدركة للوقت والاستدلال</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Tradução e Inferência de Textos Chineses Antigos Conscientes do Tempo</title_pt>
      <title_es>Traducción e inferencia de textos en chino antiguo con conciencia del tiempo</title_es>
      <title_ja>時を意識した古代中国のテキスト翻訳と推論</title_ja>
      <title_hi>समय-जागरूक प्राचीन चीनी पाठ अनुवाद और अनुमान</title_hi>
      <title_zh>所感古语文本译推理</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Aistriúchán Téacs Sean-Síneach agus Tátal</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Időtudatos ősi kínai szövegfordítás és fertőzés</title_hu>
      <title_el>Μετάφραση και συμπέρασμα αρχαίου κινεζικού κειμένου με επίγνωση του χρόνου</title_el>
      <title_kk>Қытай мәтінді аудару мен қатынас</title_kk>
      <title_it>Traduzione e inferenza del testo cinese antico consapevole del tempo</title_it>
      <title_lt>Laikas žinomas senovinis kinų teksto vertimas ir kalba</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Time-Aware Ancient Chinese Text Translation and Inference</title_mk>
      <title_ml>സമയം അറിയുന്ന വൃദ്ധനായ ചൈനീസ് പദാവലിയുടെ പരിഭാഷവും തടസ്സവും</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Traduzzjoni u Inferenza tat-Test Ċiniż Anzjani Konxji taż-Żmien</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Хятад хугацааны хугацааны Текст хөрөнгө оруулалт болон үнэ цэнэтэй</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Tłumaczenie i wnioski tekstu starożytnego chińskiego świadomego czasu</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Traducerea și inferența textului chinezesc antic conștient de timp</title_ro>
      <title_ms>Name</title_ms>
      <title_sr>Vremenski prevod drevnog kineskog teksta</title_sr>
      <title_so>Turjumista iyo Interference</title_so>
      <title_no>Comment</title_no>
      <title_sv>Tidsbevidgad antik kinesisk textöversättning och inferens</title_sv>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_ta>நேரம் அறிந்த பழைய சீனா உரை மொழிபெயர்ப்பு மற்றும் தடுப்பு</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Time-Aware Ancient Chinese Text Translation and Inference</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Time-Aware Ancient Chinese Text Translation and Inference</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Dịch và liên minh văn bản Trung Quốc</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Превод и извод на древен китайски текстов превод и извод</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Prijevod i privlačenje drevnog kineskog teksta</title_hr>
      <title_da>Tidsbevidst gammel kinesisk tekstoversættelse og inferens</title_da>
      <title_nl>Tijdbewust Oude Chinese Tekst Vertaling en Inferentie</title_nl>
      <title_de>Zeitbewusste Übersetzung und Schlussfolgerung alter chinesischer Texte</title_de>
      <title_fa>Name</title_fa>
      <title_ko>시간 감지의 고대 중국어 텍스트 번역과 추리</title_ko>
      <title_id>Time-Aware Kuno Teks Cina Terjemahan dan Inferensi</title_id>
      <title_sw>Tafsiri na Ushirikiano</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Wagtlaýyn Garry Çinçe Metin Terjime we Görnüş</title_tr>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_sq>Përkthimi dhe përkthimi i tekstit të lashtë kinez të njohur me kohën</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Comment</title_hy>
      <title_am>የቻይንኛ ጽሑፍ ትርጉም እና ማቀናጃ</title_am>
      <title_az>Vaxt-Aware Ancient Chinese Text Translation and Inference</title_az>
      <title_bn>সময়- অবগত প্রাচীন চীনা টেক্সট অনুবাদ এবং প্রভাব</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Prijevod i privlačenje drevnog kineskog teksta</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Traducció i inferència del text xinès antics conscients del temps</title_ca>
      <title_et>Ajateadlik iidse hiina teksti tõlge ja järeldus</title_et>
      <title_cs>Překlad a závěr starověkých čínských textů v čase</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Aikatietoinen muinaisen kiinan tekstin kääntäminen ja päätelmä</title_fi>
      <title_ha>@ item Text character set</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Časovno ozaveščen starodavni kitajski prevod in sklepanje besedila</title_sk>
      <title_jv>Peringatan-Awar Teks Anyar Terjamahan lan Peringatan</title_jv>
      <title_bo>Time-Aware Ancient Chinese Text Translation and Inference</title_bo>
      <title_he>תורגם וסונכרן ע"י QFontDatabase</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>في هذه الورقة ، نهدف إلى معالجة التحديات المحيطة بترجمة النص الصيني القديم: (1) الفجوة اللغوية بسبب الاختلاف في العصور تؤدي إلى ترجمات رديئة الجودة ، و (2) تفتقد معظم الترجمات إلى المعلومات السياقية هذا غالبًا ما يكون بالغ الأهمية لفهم النص. تحقيقًا لهذه الغاية ، نقوم بتحسين تقنيات الترجمة السابقة من خلال اقتراح ما يلي: نعيد صياغة المهمة كمهمة تنبؤ متعددة العلامات حيث يتنبأ النموذج بكل من الترجمة وعصرها الخاص. نلاحظ أن هذا يساعد على سد الفجوة اللغوية حيث يتم استخدام السياق الزمني أيضًا كمعلومات مساعدة. نحن نتحقق من صحة إطار العمل الخاص بنا على مجموعة موازية مشروحة بمعلومات التسلسل الزمني ونبين بشكل تجريبي فعاليتها في إنتاج مخرجات ترجمة عالية الجودة. نصدر كل من الكود والبيانات للبحث في المستقبل.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>En este artículo, nuestro objetivo es abordar los desafíos que rodean la traducción de textos chinos antiguos: (1) La brecha lingüística debido a la diferencia de épocas da como resultado traducciones de mala calidad, y (2) la mayoría de las traducciones pierden la información contextual que a menudo es muy crucial para la comprensión el texto. Con este fin, mejoramos las técnicas de traducción anteriores proponiendo lo siguiente: Reformulamos la tarea como una tarea de predicción multietiqueta en la que el modelo predice tanto la traducción como su época particular. Observamos que esto ayuda a cerrar la brecha lingüística, ya que el contexto cronológico también se utiliza como información auxiliar. Validamos nuestro marco en un corpus paralelo anotado con información cronológica y demostramos experimentalmente su eficacia en la producción de resultados de traducción de calidad. Publicamos tanto el código como los datos para futuras investigaciones.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Neste artigo, pretendemos abordar os desafios que cercam a tradução de texto chinês antigo: (1) a lacuna linguística devido à diferença de eras resulta em traduções de baixa qualidade e (2) a maioria das traduções não possui as informações contextuais que muitas vezes é muito crucial para a compreensão do texto. Para isso, aprimoramos as técnicas de tradução anteriores, propondo o seguinte: Reestruturamos a tarefa como uma tarefa de previsão multirrótulo, na qual o modelo prevê tanto a tradução quanto sua era específica. Observamos que isso ajuda a preencher a lacuna linguística, pois o contexto cronológico também é usado como informação auxiliar. Validamos nossa estrutura em um corpus paralelo anotado com informações cronológicas e mostramos experimentalmente sua eficácia na produção de resultados de tradução de qualidade. Liberamos o código e os dados para pesquisas futuras.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、中国古文の翻訳をめぐる課題に取り組むことを目指している。（ 1 ） ERASの違いによる言語的ギャップにより、翻訳の品質が低い。（ 2 ）ほとんどの翻訳は、文章を理解するために非常に重要な文脈情報を欠いている。そのために、過去の翻訳テクニックを次のように提案することで改善します。モデルが翻訳とその特定の時代の両方を予測するマルチラベル予測タスクとしてタスクを再フレーム化します。時系列的な文脈も補助的な情報として使用されるため、これは言語的なギャップを埋めるのに役立つことが観察されます。私たちは、年表情報が注釈された平行コーパスでフレームワークを検証し、品質の高い翻訳出力を生成する効果を実験的に示します。今後の研究のために、コードとデータの両方をリリースします。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>इस पत्र में, हम प्राचीन चीनी पाठ के अनुवाद के आसपास की चुनौतियों को संबोधित करने का लक्ष्य रखते हैं: (1) युगों में अंतर के कारण भाषाई अंतर के परिणामस्वरूप अनुवाद में परिणाम होता है जो गुणवत्ता में खराब हैं, और (2) अधिकांश अनुवाद प्रासंगिक जानकारी को याद कर रहे हैं जो अक्सर पाठ को समझने के लिए बहुत महत्वपूर्ण होता है। इस अंत में, हम निम्नलिखित का प्रस्ताव करके पिछली अनुवाद तकनीकों में सुधार करते हैं: हम कार्य को एक बहु-लेबल पूर्वानुमान कार्य के रूप में फिर से तैयार करते हैं जहां मॉडल अनुवाद और इसके विशेष युग दोनों की भविष्यवाणी करता है। हम देखते हैं कि यह भाषाई अंतर को पाटने में मदद करता है क्योंकि कालानुक्रमिक संदर्भ का उपयोग सहायक जानकारी के रूप में भी किया जाता है। हम कालक्रम जानकारी के साथ एनोटेट किए गए समानांतर कॉर्पस पर अपने ढांचे को मान्य करते हैं और गुणवत्ता अनुवाद आउटपुट के उत्पादन में प्रयोगात्मक रूप से इसकी प्रभावकारिता दिखाते हैं। हम भविष्य के शोध के लिए कोड और डेटा दोनों जारी करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>在本文中,我们旨在解释古代汉语文本译的挑战:(1)由于时代差异所致的话差距致译质量差,及(2)大多译都缺常对解文本至重的上下文信息。 因建议改旧译术:重构为多标签占候,其模测译及特定时。 观其有助于弥合语言鸿沟者,以其时背景亦所以辅信也。 以次信注并行语料库验吾框架,因实验展其高质量译输之功。 发代码、数据以备将来。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Sa pháipéar seo, tá sé mar aidhm againn aghaidh a thabhairt ar na dúshláin a bhaineann le haistriú téacs na Síne ársa: (1) Tá an bhearna theangeolaíoch mar gheall ar an difríocht i réanna mar thoradh ar aistriúcháin atá lag i gcáilíocht, agus (2) tá an fhaisnéis chomhthéacsúil in easnamh ar fhormhór na n-aistriúchán. is minic a bhíonn sé sin ríthábhachtach chun an téacs a thuiscint. Chuige sin, cuirimid feabhas ar theicnící aistriúcháin san am a chuaigh thart trí na nithe seo a leanas a mholadh: Déanaimid an tasc a athfhrámú mar thasc tuar illipéid ina ndéanann an tsamhail réamhinsint ar an aistriúchán agus ar a ré faoi leith. Tugaimid faoi deara go gcabhraíonn sé seo leis an mbearna teanga a líonadh toisc go n-úsáidtear comhthéacs croineolaíoch mar fhaisnéis chúnta freisin. Déanaimid ár gcreat a bhailíochtú ar chorpas comhthreomhar atá anótáilte le heolas croineolaíochta agus léirímid go turgnamhach a éifeachtúlacht maidir le haschuir aistriúcháin ardchaighdeáin a tháirgeadh. Eisímid an cód agus na sonraí le haghaidh taighde amach anseo.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ამ წიგნაში ჩვენ მინდა გავაკეთოთ წინასწორი ჩინეთი ტექსტის გარგულისხმების განცვლის განცვლების შემთხვევაში სისტემისტიკური განცვლების განცვლების შემთხვევაში, რომელიც უფრო ცოტა წიგნის განცვლების შემთხვევაში, და (2) უფრო მეტი ამ მიზეზით, ჩვენ წინასწარმოქმედების ტექნოგიების შესახებ გადავიწყებთ: ჩვენ დავაწყებთ რაოდენობას როგორც მრავალური წინასწინასწინასწინასწინასწინასწინასწინასწინასწინასწ ჩვენ დავხედავთ, რომ ეს დახმარებს ლიგნოლოგიური განსხვავებას, როგორც კრონოლოგიური კონტექსტი გამოყენება როგორც დახმარებელი ინფორმაცია. ჩვენ ჩვენი პარალელი კორპუსზე გავაკეთებთ კრონოლოგიური ინფორმაციის შესახებ და ექსპერიმენტიკურად ჩვენი ეფექციურობას გამოიყენებთ კალექტური გადაწყვეტილების ჩვენ კოდის და მომავალური შესწავლობისთვის მონაცემებისთვის გამოუშვებით.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>In questo articolo, ci proponiamo di affrontare le sfide che circondano la traduzione di testi antichi cinesi: (1) Il divario linguistico dovuto alle differenze nelle epoche si traduce in traduzioni di scarsa qualità, e (2) la maggior parte delle traduzioni manca di informazioni contestuali che sono spesso molto cruciali per la comprensione del testo. A tal fine, miglioriamo le tecniche di traduzione passate proponendo quanto segue: Reframe il compito come un compito di previsione multi-etichetta in cui il modello predice sia la traduzione che la sua epoca particolare. Osserviamo che questo aiuta a colmare il divario linguistico in quanto il contesto cronologico viene utilizzato anche come informazione ausiliaria. Validiamo il nostro framework su un corpus parallelo annotato con informazioni cronologiche e mostriamo sperimentalmente la sua efficacia nella produzione di output di traduzione di qualità. Rilasciamo sia il codice che i dati per la ricerca futura.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente siekiame spręsti senovinio Kinijos teksto vertimo problemas: 1) kalbų spraga dėl skirtingų amžių lemia kokybiškus vertimus, o 2) daugeliui vertimų trūksta kontekstinės informacijos, kuri dažnai labai svarbi tekstui suprasti. To this end, we improve upon past translation techniques by proposing the following: We reframe the task as a multi-label prediction task where the model predicts both the translation and its particular era.  Pastebėjome, kad tai padeda pašalinti kalbinę spragą, nes chronologinė aplinkybė taip pat naudojama kaip pagalbinė informacija. Patvirtiname savo sistemą dėl lygiagretaus korpuso, pažymėto chronologine informacija, ir eksperimentiškai parodomi, kad ji veiksmingai gamina kokybiškus vertimo rezultatus. Mes paskelbiame tiek kodą, tiek būsimų mokslinių tyrimų duomenis.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағазда, біз дұрыс қытайша мәтіннің аудармасының айырмашылығын өшіруге мақсат береміз: (1) Лингистикалық аудармасының айырмашылығы сапалы аудармасының айырмашылығын өшіруге болады, және (2) көпшілігі мәтінні түсіні Бұл үшін, өткен аудармалар техникаларын жақсартып келеді: Біз тапсырманы бірнеше жарлық тапсырманы аудармаларды және оның ерекше уақытын алдын алатын көп жарлық тапсырмасы ретінде қайта жасап Бұл лингвистикалық аралығын көмектесу үшін хронологиялық контексті де көмектесу мәліметі ретінде қолданылады. Біз хронология мәліметімен белгіленген параллелі корпустың бағдарламасын тексеріп, сапатты аудармалардың шығысын жасау үшін тәжірибесін көрсетедік. Келесі зерттеулер үшін код мен деректерді жібереміз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>In this paper, we aim to address the challenges surrounding the translation of ancient Chinese text: (1) The linguistic gap due to the difference in eras results in translations that are poor in quality, and (2) most translations are missing the contextual information that is often very crucial to understanding the text.  За оваа цел, ние ги подобруваме минатите техники на превод со предложување на следното: ја реформираме задачата како задача со мултиетички предвидувања каде моделот предвидува превод и негова конкретна ера. Ние забележуваме дека ова помага да се премине јазичната празнина бидејќи хронолошкиот контекст исто така се користи како помошна информација. Ние ја валидираме нашата рамка за паралелен корпус анотиран со хронолошки информации и експериментално ја покажуваме нејзината ефикасност во производството на квалитетни преводни излези. Ги објавуваме кодовите и податоците за идното истражување.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_hu>Jelen tanulmányban az ókori kínai szöveg fordításával kapcsolatos kihívásokat kívánjuk foglalkozni: (1) A korkülönbségek miatti nyelvi hiányosságok eredményeképpen rossz minőségű fordításokat eredményeznek, és (2) a legtöbb fordítás hiányzik a kontextuális információk, amelyek gyakran nagyon fontosak a szöveg megértéséhez. Ennek érdekében javítjuk a múltbeli fordítási technikákat azzal, hogy a következőket javasoljuk: A feladatot többcímkés előrejelzési feladatként alakítjuk át, ahol a modell előrejelzi mind a fordítást, mind annak korszakát. Megfigyeljük, hogy ez segít áthidalni a nyelvi szakadékot, mivel a kronológiai kontextust kiegészítő információként is használják. Keretrendszerünket kronológiai információkkal megjegyzett párhuzamos korpuszon validáljuk, és kísérleti úton mutatjuk meg hatékonyságát a minőségi fordítási kimenetek előállításában. Mind a kódot, mind az adatokat kiadjuk a jövőbeli kutatáshoz.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Στην παρούσα εργασία, στοχεύουμε να αντιμετωπίσουμε τις προκλήσεις που περιβάλλουν τη μετάφραση αρχαίου κινεζικού κειμένου: (1) Το γλωσσικό χάσμα που οφείλεται στη διαφορά των εποχών οδηγεί σε μεταφράσεις χαμηλής ποιότητας και (2) στις περισσότερες μεταφράσεις λείπουν οι πληροφορίες που είναι συχνά πολύ κρίσιμες για την κατανόηση του κειμένου. Για το σκοπό αυτό, βελτιώνουμε τις προηγούμενες τεχνικές μετάφρασης προτείνοντας τα εξής: Αναπλαισιώνουμε την εργασία ως εργασία πρόβλεψης πολλαπλών ετικετών όπου το μοντέλο προβλέπει τόσο τη μετάφραση όσο και τη συγκεκριμένη εποχή της. Παρατηρούμε ότι αυτό συμβάλλει στη γεφύρωση του γλωσσικού χάσματος καθώς το χρονολογικό πλαίσιο χρησιμοποιείται επίσης ως βοηθητική πληροφορία. Επιβεβαιώνουμε το πλαίσιο μας σε ένα παράλληλο σώμα σχολιασμένο με χρονολογικές πληροφορίες και δείχνουμε πειραματικά την αποτελεσματικότητά του στην παραγωγή ποιοτικών μεταφραστικών αποτελεσμάτων. Απελευθερώνουμε τόσο τον κώδικα όσο και τα δεδομένα για μελλοντική έρευνα.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаасан дээр бид эртний Хятадын текст орших сорилтуудыг зохицуулахын тулд зориулсан: (1) Хятадын текст орших сорилтуудын ялгааг устгахын тулд хэлний ялгаа нь сайн чанарын ядуу оршилтуудын үр дүнд гаргасан ба (2) ихэнх оршилтууд текст ойлгохын тулд маш чуха Үүний тулд бид өнгөрсөн орчуулах технологийг сайжруулж, дараагийн орчуулах технологийг санал болгож байна: Бид үүнийг олон загварын таамаглах үйл ажиллагаа болгож, загвар нь орчуулах болон түүний тодорхой үеийг таам Бид үүнийг хэлний ялгааг хронологик нөхцөлд мөн тусламжтай мэдээллийн хувьд ашигладаг гэдгийг анзаарсан. Бид хронологийн мэдээллээр дүгнэгдсэн параллел корпус дээр баталж, жишээлбэл чанартай орчуулалтын үр дүнг бүтээж чадварыг харуулж байна. Бид ирээдүйн судалгааны код болон өгөгдлийг ашиглаж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ms>Dalam kertas ini, kami bertujuan untuk mengatasi cabaran yang mengelilingi terjemahan teks Cina kuno: (1) Lubang bahasa disebabkan perbezaan dalam era mengakibatkan terjemahan yang kurang kualiti, dan (2) kebanyakan terjemahan hilang maklumat kontekstual yang sering sangat penting untuk memahami teks. Untuk tujuan ini, kami memperbaiki teknik terjemahan masa lalu dengan melaporkan ini: kami menamakan semula tugas sebagai tugas ramalan label berbilang di mana model meramalkan kedua-dua terjemahan dan era tertentunya. Kami memperhatikan bahawa ini membantu untuk memecahkan ruang bahasa sebagai konteks kronologi juga digunakan sebagai maklumat bantuan. Kami sahkan kerangka kami pada korpus selari yang dicatat dengan maklumat kronologi dan menunjukkan secara eksperimen kegunaannya dalam menghasilkan output terjemahan kualiti. Kami melepaskan kedua-dua kod dan data untuk kajian masa depan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍, പഴയ ചൈനീസ് ടെക്സ്റ്റിന്റെ പരിഭാഷണത്തിന് ചുറ്റുമുള്ള വിലാസങ്ങള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കാന്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഉദ്ദേശിക്കുന്നു: (1) ലേഖനം മനസ്സിലാക്കാന്‍ ഏറെ പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട ഈ അവസാനത്തിനു വേണ്ടി, കഴിഞ്ഞ പരിഭാഷയുടെ സാങ്കേതികവിദ്യകളില്‍ നാം മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു: ക്രോണോളജിക്കല്‍ കെന്‍സ്റ്റെക്സ്റ്റെക്സ്റ്റെന്‍റിലും കൂടുതല്‍ വിവരങ്ങളായി ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതിനാല്‍ ഇത് ഭാഷകങ് ക്രോണോളജിയുടെ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ കൊണ്ട് പാരാളല്‍ കോര്‍പ്പുസിന്‍റെ മേല്‍ നമ്മുടെ ഫ്രെയിമെക്ക് ഞങ്ങള്‍ വിവരിച്ചുകൊടുക്കുന്നു. അത നമ്മള്‍ കോഡും വിവരങ്ങളും ഭാവിയുടെ പഠനത്തിനുള്ള വിവരങ്ങളും വിടുന്നു.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>F’dan id-dokument, għandna l-għan li nindirizzaw l-isfidi madwar it-traduzzjoni tat-test Ċiniż antik: (1) Id-diskrepanza lingwistika minħabba d-differenza fl-era tirriżulta fi traduzzjonijiet li mhumiex ta’ kwalità tajba, u (2) il-biċċa l-kbira tat-traduzzjonijiet huma nieqsa mill-informazzjoni kuntestwali li ħafna drabi hija kruċjali ħafna għall-fehim tat-test. To this end, we improve upon past translation techniques by proposing the following: We reframe the task as a multi-label prediction task where the model predicts both the translation and its particular era.  Aħna nużaw li dan jgħin biex jitnaqqas id-distakk lingwistiku peress li l-kuntest kronoloġiku jintuża wkoll bħala informazzjoni awżiljari. Aħna jivvalidaw il-qafas tagħna dwar korpus parallel annotat b’informazzjoni kronoloġika u juru b’mod sperimentali l-effikaċja tiegħu fil-produzzjoni ta’ riżultati ta’ traduzzjoni ta’ kwalità. Aħna nħelsu kemm il-kodiċi kif ukoll id-dejta għar-riċerka futura.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ro>În această lucrare, ne propunem să abordăm provocările legate de traducerea textului chinezesc antic: (1) Diferența lingvistică datorată diferențelor dintre ere duce la traduceri care sunt slabe în calitate, și (2) majoritatea traducerilor lipsesc informațiile contextuale care sunt adesea foarte cruciale pentru înțelegerea textului. În acest scop, îmbunătățim tehnicile de traducere din trecut propunând următoarele: Reframăm sarcina ca o sarcină de predicție multi-etichetă în care modelul prezice atât traducerea, cât și era sa particulară. Observăm că acest lucru ajută la depășirea decalajului lingvistic, deoarece contextul cronologic este folosit și ca informație auxiliară. Validăm cadrul nostru pe un corpus paralel adnotat cu informații cronologice și demonstrăm experimental eficacitatea acestuia în producerea rezultatelor traducerii de calitate. Eliberăm atât codul, cât și datele pentru cercetările viitoare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>මේ පත්තරේ අපි අදහස් කරනවා පරණ චීනි පාළුවේ වාර්තාව සම්බන්ධ වෙනුවෙන් අභ්‍යාසය සම්බන්ධ කරනවා: (1) භාෂාවික අභ්‍යාසය විශේෂයෙන් අභ්‍යාසය සඳහා අභ මේ අවසානයෙන්, අපි පස්සේ වාර්තාව ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් පස්සේ වාර්තාව ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් පස්සේ වාර්තාව ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙ අපි බලාපොරොත්තු කරනවා මේක භාෂාවික විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විදිහට උදව් කරනවා කියලා  අපි සාමාන්‍ය කෝර්පුස් එකේ අපේ පරීක්ෂණයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා ක්‍රොනෝලෝජික තොරතුරු සඳහා ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා ඒ අපි අනාගතයේ පරීක්ෂණය සහ තොරතුරු දෙන්නම පුළුවන් කරනවා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalkan waxaynu ku talo galaynaa dhibaatooyinka ku wareegsan turjumidda qoraalka hore ee Shiino: (1) kala duwanaashada luuqada ah sababtoo ah kala duwanaashada hooyada waxaa ka soo baxa turjumaadda u baahan sida qiimo u baahan, iyo (2) turjumaadda badankood waa ka baahan yihiin macluumaadka joogtada ah oo inta badan muhiim u ah in aad u fahanto qoraalka. To this end, we improve upon past translation techniques by proposing the following: We reframe the task as a multi-label prediction task where the model predicts both the translation and its particular era.  Waxaynu aragnaa in taasu ay caawinaysaa in ay isduleexeeyo kala duwan luqada, sida xittaa lagu isticmaalo macluumaad dheeraad ah. Waxaynu xaqiijinnaa firaaqadeena ku qoran korpus lambarka ah oo la taabsaday macluumaadka chronology, waxaana tusnaa saameyntiisa ku saabsan sameynta soo saarista turjumista takhasuska. Waxaynu siinnaa sumadda iyo macluumaadka waxbarashada mustaqbalka ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_no>I denne papiret må vi handsama utfordringane som omkriver omsetjinga av gamle kinesisk tekst: (1) Lingsmellomrommet på grunn av forskjellen i sletting av resultatet i omsetjingar som er fattige i kvalitet, og (2) dei fleste omsetjingane manglar kontekstinformasjonen som ofte er veldig viktig for å forstå teksten. I denne slutten forbedrar vi på siste omsetjingstekningar ved å foreslå følgjande: Vi reframerer oppgåva som eit forhåndsvising av fleire merkelappar der modellen foreslår både omsetjinga og den spesifikke tida. Vi observerer at denne hjelper til å bryta linguistiske mellomrom som kronologisk kontekst blir også brukt som hjelpeinformasjon. Vi bestemmer rammeverket vårt på eit parallell korpus merkt med kronologiske informasjon og viser eksperimentelt effektiviteten i å produsera kvalitetsverktøy. Vi løyser både koden og data for framtidige forskning.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sv>I denna uppsats syftar vi till att ta itu med utmaningarna kring översättning av gammal kinesisk text: (1) Den språkliga klyftan på grund av skillnader i epoker resulterar i översättningar som är dålig i kvalitet, och (2) de flesta översättningar saknar kontextuell information som ofta är mycket avgörande för att förstå texten. För detta ändamål förbättrar vi tidigare översättningstekniker genom att föreslå följande: Vi omformar uppgiften som en multi-label förutsägelseuppgift där modellen förutspår både översättningen och dess speciella era. Vi konstaterar att detta bidrar till att överbrygga den språkliga klyftan eftersom kronologisk kontext också används som hjälpinformation. Vi validerar vårt ramverk på en parallell korpus kommenterad med kronologisk information och visar experimentellt dess effektivitet när det gäller att producera högkvalitativa översättningar. Vi släpper både koden och data för framtida forskning.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தில், நாம் பழைய சீனா உரையை மொழிபெயர்ப்பில் சுற்றிய சவால்பங்களை விளக்க வேண்டும்: (1) மொழிபெயர்ப்பில் மொழிபெயர்ப்புகளின் வித்தியாசமான மொழிபெயர்ப்ப இந்த முடிவிற்கு, முந்தைய மொழிபெயர்ப்பு தொழில்நுட்பத்தில் நாம் மேம்படுத்துகிறோம் பின்வரும் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு தொழில்நுட்பத்தை  நாம் பார்க்கிறோம் இது மொழி இடைவெளியை பிரித்து உதவும் என்பதை காண்கிறோம். கிரோனோலியல் சூழல் மூலம் அதிக தகவலாக பயன்பட @ info நாம் எதிர்கால ஆய்வுக்கான குறியீடு மற்றும் தகவல்களை வெளியிடுகிறோம்.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_pl>W niniejszym artykule chcemy poradzić sobie z wyzwaniami związanymi z tłumaczeniem starożytnego tekstu chińskiego: (1) Luka językowa spowodowana różnicą epok powoduje tłumaczenia słabej jakości, a (2) większości tłumaczeń brakuje informacji kontekstowych, które często są bardzo istotne dla zrozumienia tekstu. W tym celu poprawiamy wcześniejsze techniki tłumaczenia, proponując następujące: Przekształcamy zadanie jako wieloznakowe zadanie prognozowania, w którym model przewiduje zarówno tłumaczenie, jak i jego konkretną epokę. Obserwujemy, że pomaga to wypełnić lukę językową, ponieważ kontekst chronologiczny jest również wykorzystywany jako informacja pomocnicza. Weryfikujemy nasze ramy na równoległym korpusie opartym na informacjach chronologicznych i eksperymentalnie pokazujemy jego skuteczność w tworzeniu wysokiej jakości wyników tłumaczeniowych. Udostępniamy zarówno kod, jak i dane do przyszłych badań.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>U ovom papiru imamo cilj da riješimo izazove koje okružuju prevod drevnog kineskog teksta: (1) jezički praznik zbog razlike u izbrisanju rezultata prevoda koje su siromašne u kvaliteti, a (2) većina prevoda nedostaje kontekstualne informacije koje je često vrlo važne za razumevanje teksta. Za taj cilj, poboljšavamo prošle tehnike prevoda predložeći sljedeće: preobrađujemo zadatak kao predviđanje više etiketa u kojem model predviđa prevod i njegovu posebnu dobu. Primišljamo da ovo pomaže da se predstavi jezički praznik kao kronološki kontekst takođe koristi kao pomoćni informacije. Potvrđujemo naš okvir na paralelnom korpusu annotiranom kronološkom informacijom i pokazujemo eksperimentalno svoju efikasnost u proizvodnji rezultata kvalitetnog prevoda. Puštamo i kod i podatke za buduće istraživanje.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ur>اس کاغذ میں ہم نے پیچھے چین کے متن کی ترجمہ پر چلنے والی چالوں کا ارادہ کرنا چاہا ہے: (1) زبان کی فاصلہ مٹانے کی تفاوت کے باعث تفاوت کا نتیجہ ہے جو کیفیت میں کمزور ہیں، اور (2) اکثر ترجمہ کی ترجمہ اس متن کی اطلاعات کو ضائع کرتی ہے جو اکثر متن کی سمجھنے کے لئے اس کے لئے ہم اگلے ترجمہ ٹیکنالوجی پر زیادہ استعمال کرتے ہیں: ہم نے اس کام کو multi-label پیش بینی ٹیکنالوجی کے طور پر دفع کیا ہے جہاں مدل ترجمہ اور اس کی خاص عصر کی پیش بینی کرتا ہے. ہم دیکھ رہے ہیں کہ یہ زبان کی فاصلہ کو دھوپ دینے کے لئے مدد کرتا ہے جیسے کرونولوژیک متصلہ بھی مددگار معلومات کے طور پر استعمال کیا جاتا ہے۔ ہم ایک مشابہ کورپوس پر اپنی فرمود کی تصدیق کرتے ہیں جو کرونولوژی معلومات کے ذریعہ مشابہ کی گئی ہے اور اسے آزمائش کے ذریعہ اس کی فعالیت دکھاتے ہیں کیفیت ترجمہ نتائج پیدا کرنے کے لئے۔ ہم آگے کے تحقیقات کے لئے کوڈ اور ڈیٹا کو آزاد کرتے ہیں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu hujjatda, biz oldingi Xitoycha matnning tarjimalarini tarjima qilish uchun tarjima qilamiz:(1) chizillar tarjimasining o'zgarishlari darajasida o'zgarishlar darajasida o'zgarishga ega bo'ladi. va (2) ko'pchilik tarjimalar matnni o'rganish uchun juda muhim maʼlumot yoʻqoladi. Mana shunday qilib, biz keyingi tarjima teknologiyani yaxshi ko'proq qilamiz: Biz vazifani bir necha yordamchi vazifa sifatida qaytadan qaytamiz. Bu yerda model tarjima va xusus vaqt bilan oldin. Biz buni ko'rib turamiz, bu tillar gaplarini birlashtirishga yordam beradi, chunki kronologisk muktadha ham qo'llanilgan maʼlumot sifatida ishlatiladi. @ info Biz kelajakdagi qidirish uchun koda va maʼlumotni chiqaramiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Trong bài báo này, chúng tôi muốn giải quyết thử thách liên quan tới việc dịch thuật văn bản Trung Quốc cổ: 1) Sự thiếu hụt ngôn ngữ nhờ sự khác nhau trong thời gian, dẫn đến việc dịch chuyển chất lượng kém chất lượng, và (2) hầu hết dịch vụ thiếu các thông tin ngữ chung thường rất quan trọng để hiểu được văn bản. Vì vậy, chúng ta cải tiến kỹ thuật dịch chuyển trước đây bằng cách đề xuất như thế này: Chúng ta từ bỏ nhiệm vụ dự đoán đa nhãn nơi mà mô hình dự đoán cả thời đại và thời đại đặc biệt của nó. Chúng tôi nhận thấy rằng việc này giúp lấp liếm lỗ hổng ngôn ngữ trong thời gian, cũng được sử dụng như là thông tin phụ trợ. Chúng tôi xác nhận cơ sở của chúng tôi trên một tập thể song song song được ghi chú theo hồ sơ và cho thấy hiệu quả của nó trong việc sản xuất xuất xuất bản dịch chất lượng. Chúng tôi công bố cả mã và dữ liệu cho nghiên cứu tương lai.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>В настоящата статия се стремим да се справим с предизвикателствата, свързани с превода на древен китайски текст: (1) езиковата пропаст, дължаща се на разликата в епохите, води до преводи с лошо качество, и (2) повечето преводи липсва контекстната информация, която често е много важна за разбирането на текста. За тази цел ние подобряваме миналите техники за превод, като предлагаме следното: Преоформяме задачата като задача за прогнозиране с множество етикети, където моделът предвижда както превода, така и неговата конкретна ера. Наблюдаваме, че това помага за преодоляване на езиковата пропаст, тъй като хронологичният контекст се използва и като допълнителна информация. Ние валидираме нашата рамка върху паралелен корпус, анотиран с хронологична информация, и експериментално показваме нейната ефикасност при изготвянето на качествени преводни резултати. Пускаме кода и данните за бъдещи изследвания.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>In dit artikel willen we de uitdagingen aangaan rondom de vertaling van oude Chinese tekst: (1) De taalkloof als gevolg van het verschil in tijdperken resulteert in vertalingen die slecht van kwaliteit zijn, en (2) de meeste vertalingen missen de contextuele informatie die vaak cruciaal is voor het begrijpen van de tekst. Daartoe verbeteren we eerdere vertaaltechnieken door het volgende voor te stellen: We omschrijven de taak als een multi-label voorspellingstak waarbij het model zowel de vertaling als het specifieke tijdperk voorspelt. We zien dat dit helpt om de taalkloof te overbruggen, omdat chronologische context ook wordt gebruikt als hulpinformatie. We valideren ons framework op een parallel corpus dat geannoteerd is met chronologische informatie en tonen experimenteel de effectiviteit ervan aan bij het produceren van hoogwaardige vertaaloutputs. We geven zowel de code als de data vrij voor toekomstig onderzoek.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>I denne artikel har vi til formål at løse udfordringerne omkring oversættelsen af gammel kinesisk tekst: (1) Den sproglige kløft på grund af forskellen i tidsaldre resulterer i oversættelser, der er dårlig i kvalitet, og (2) de fleste oversættelser mangler kontekstuelle oplysninger, der ofte er meget afgørende for at forstå teksten. Til dette formål forbedrer vi tidligere oversættelsesteknikker ved at foreslå følgende: Vi omdanner opgaven som en multi-label forudsigelsesopgave, hvor modellen forudsiger både oversættelsen og dens særlige æra. Vi bemærker, at dette bidrager til at bygge bro over den sproglige kløft, da kronologisk kontekst også bruges som hjælpeinformation. Vi validerer vores ramme på et parallelt korpus annoteret med kronologiske oplysninger og viser eksperimentelt dets effektivitet i at producere kvalitetsoversættelsesudgange. Vi frigiver både koden og dataene til fremtidig forskning.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>U ovom papiru imamo cilj riješiti izazove oko prevoda drevnog kineskog teksta: (1) jezički praznik zbog razlike u izbrisanju rezultata prevoda koje su siromašne u kvaliteti, a (2) većina prevoda nedostaje kontekstualne informacije koje je često vrlo ključno za razumijevanje teksta. Za taj cilj, poboljšavamo prošle tehnike prevoda predložeći sljedeće: preobrađujemo zadatak kao predviđanje multietičkih mjera u kojem model predviđa prevod i njegovo određeno vrijeme. Primjećujemo da se to pomaže premostiti jezički praznik kao kronološki kontekst također koristi kao pomoćne informacije. Potvrđujemo naš okvir na paralelnom korpusu annotiranom kronološkom informacijom i pokazujemo eksperimentalno svoju djelotvornost u proizvodnji rezultata kvalitetnog prevoda. Puštamo i šifru i podatke za buduće istraživanje.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>In diesem Beitrag wollen wir die Herausforderungen im Zusammenhang mit der Übersetzung antiker chinesischer Texte adressieren: (1) Die sprachliche Lücke aufgrund der unterschiedlichen Epochen führt zu Übersetzungen mit schlechter Qualität und (2) den meisten Übersetzungen fehlen die Kontextinformationen, die oft sehr wichtig für das Verständnis des Textes sind. Zu diesem Zweck verbessern wir vergangene Übersetzungstechniken, indem wir Folgendes vorschlagen: Wir umrahmen die Aufgabe als Multi-Label-Vorhersageaufgabe, bei der das Modell sowohl die Übersetzung als auch ihre jeweilige Epoche vorhersagt. Wir beobachten, dass dies hilft, die sprachliche Lücke zu überbrücken, da auch der chronologische Kontext als Hilfsinformation verwendet wird. Wir validieren unser Framework auf einem parallelen Korpus mit chronologischen Informationen und zeigen experimentell seine Wirksamkeit bei der Erstellung qualitativ hochwertiger Übersetzungsausgaben. Wir geben sowohl den Code als auch die Daten für zukünftige Forschung frei.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Dalam kertas ini, kami bertujuan untuk mengatasi tantangan sekitar terjemahan teks Cina kuno: (1) Lubang bahasa karena perbedaan di era menghasilkan terjemahan yang tidak baik dalam kualitas, dan (2) kebanyakan terjemahan kehilangan informasi kontekstual yang sering sangat penting untuk memahami teks. Untuk tujuan ini, kami memperbaiki teknik terjemahan masa lalu dengan mengusulkan berikut: kami mengubah tugas sebagai tugas prediksi multi-label dimana model memprediksi terjemahan dan era tertentunya. Kami memperhatikan bahwa hal ini membantu untuk memecahkan ruang bahasa sebagai konteks kronologi juga digunakan sebagai informasi bantuan. We validate our framework on a parallel corpus annotated with chronology information and show experimentally its efficacy in producing quality translation outputs.  Kita melepaskan kode dan data untuk penelitian masa depan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>در این کاغذ، ما هدف داریم که چالش های محیط ترجمه متن چینی قدیمی را حل کنیم: (۱) فاصله زبان‌شناسی به دلیل تفاوت در پاک کردن نتیجه‌های ترجمه‌های ضعیف در کیفیت است و (۲) بیشتر ترجمه‌های ترجمه‌ها اطلاعات متوسط را که اغلب برای درک متن بسیار مهم برای این قسمت، ما بر تکنیک ترجمه گذشته با پیشنهاد کردن این تغییرات را بهتر می کنیم: ما این کار را به عنوان یک کار پیش‌بینی چندین برچسب تغییر می‌دهیم که مدل به ترجمه و زمان خاص آن پیش‌بینی می‌کند. ما مشاهده می‌کنیم که این کمک می‌کند که فاصله‌های زبان‌شناسی را به طور مربوط به عنوان اطلاعات کمک استفاده می‌کند. ما چهارچوب‌هایمان را روی یک کورپوس متفاوتی که با اطلاعات کرونولوژی مشخص شده و به طور آزمایشی عملکرد خود را در تولید نتیجه‌های ترجمه کیفیت نشان می‌دهیم. ما هر کد و اطلاعات را برای تحقیقات آینده آزاد می کنیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Katika karatasi hii, tunalenga kukabiliana na changamoto zinazozunguka tafsiri ya maandishi ya Kichina ya zamani: (1) Tofauti la lugha kwa sababu ya tofauti ya matokeo ya maandishi yanayotokana na tafsiri isiyo na kiwango cha usawa, na (2) tafsiri nyingi zinakosa taarifa za kisasa ambazo mara nyingi ni muhimu sana kuelewa maandishi. Kwa mwisho huu, tunaboresha mbinu za kutafsiri zilizopita kwa kupendekeza yafuatayo: Tunaweza kufanya kazi tena kama jukumu la kutabiri kwa mitandao mbalimbali ambapo modeli inatabiri tafsiri na kipindi chake maalum. Tunaona kuwa hii inasaidia kuingilia upande wa lugha kwa kuwa muktadha wa chronology pia unatumiwa kama taarifa za usalama. We validate our framework on a parallel corpus annotated with chronology information and show experimentally its efficacy in producing quality translation outputs.  Tunaachia sheria zote na taarifa kwa utafiti wa baadaye.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_ko>본고에서 우리의 목표는 고대 중국어 텍스트 번역을 둘러싼 도전을 해결하는 것이다. (1) 시대의 차이로 인해 발생한 언어 차이로 인해 번역의 질이 떨어지고 (2) 대부분의 번역은 텍스트를 이해하는 데 매우 중요한 상하문 정보가 부족하다.이를 위해 우리는 기존의 번역 기교를 개선하고 다음과 같은 건의를 제기했다. 우리는 임무를 다중 라벨 예측 임무로 재정립하고 그 중에서 모델 예측 번역과 특정한 시대를 제시한다.시간순으로 배열된 상하문도 보조정보로 사용되기 때문에 언어의 갭을 메우는 데 도움이 된다는 것을 우리는 관찰했다.우리는 시간 정보로 표시된 평행 어료 라이브러리에서 우리의 구조를 검증했고, 실험을 통해 고품질 번역 출력의 유효성을 증명했다.우리는 장래의 연구를 위해 코드와 데이터를 발표했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_af>In hierdie papier doen ons doel om die uitdrukkings oor die vertaling van ou Sjinese teks te adres: (1) Die lingwisiese afstand vanweë die verskil in die verwydering van resultate in vertalings wat arme is in kwaliteit, en (2) meeste vertalings ontbreek die onderwerp inligting wat dikwels baie belangrik is om die teks te verstaan. Na hierdie einde, ons verbeter op verlede vertaling teknike deur die volgende voorstel: Ons herstel die taak as 'n multi-label voorskou taak waar die model voorskou beide die vertaling en sy bepaalde era. Ons bewaar dat hierdie hulp om die lingvisse gap te brui as kroonologiese konteks ook as hulpinformasie gebruik word. Ons bevestig ons raamwerk op 'n parallele korpus aangeteken met kronologie inligting en vertoon eksperimenteel sy effektiviteit in die produksie van kwaliteit vertaling uitvoers. Ons verlos beide die kode en die data vir toekomstige ondersoek.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyzda, biz öňki Çin çe metiniň terjimesine golaýlaýan kynçylyklary çözmek üçin amaçlandyrýarys: (1) Dil gapysynyň mykdarlygynda nähili bagly terjime edeniň netijesi üçin netijesi ýok, we (2) iň köp terjime edilen teaksti düşünmek üçin örän möhüm bolan informasiýasyny ýok. Şu üçin, öňki terjime tekniklerini a şağıdaki terjime eden teknikleri geliştirip geliştirdik: bu zady multi-etiket tahmin eden zady bolup nusgala hem terjime edeni hem onuň häzirini tahmin edip durarak täze täze täze etýäris. Biz bu lingwistiki boşluklary kronolojik kontekst bolup kömekleýäris we kömekleyici maglumat hökmünde ulanylýar. Biz öz çerçevemizi kronoloji bilgileri ile ifade edilen paralel korpusda geçirip, howpsal terjime edilen çözümleri üretmek üçin etkinlik etkinliğini görüntüleriz. Biz hem ködi hem berüjileri hem gelejekde barlamak üçin seredip berýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>በዚህ ፕሮግራም፣ የቀድሞው ቻይና ጽሑፍ ማተርጓሜ በሚያዙት የቋንቋዊው ውጤት በጥሩ ውጤት ድሀ ነው፡፡ (2) ብዙዎቹ ትርጓሜዎች ጽሑፉን ለማስተዋል በጣም አስቸጋሪ የሆኑት የአሁኑን መረጃ ይጠፋሉ፡፡ ለዚህ መጨረሻ፣ ባለፉት ትርጉም ስክሮች በማሳመር እናሳድጋለን፡፡ ይህ የቋንቋ ቋንቋ ስፋትን ለመቀላቀል እንደሚረዳ እናደርጋለን፡፡ የክሮሎጂ መረጃዎች በተገኘው በተለያዩ የኮርፓስ ፍሬማችንን እናሳውቃለን፡፡ We release both the code and the data for future research.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Në këtë letër, ne synojmë të trajtojmë sfidat rreth përkthimit të tekstit të lashtë kinez: (1) Mungesa gjuhësore për shkak të ndryshimit në epokë rezulton në përkthime që janë të dobëta në cilësi dhe (2) shumica e përkthimeve mungon informacioni kontekstual që shpesh është shumë vendimtar për të kuptuar tekstin. Për këtë qëllim, ne përmirësojmë teknikat e përkthimit të kaluar duke propozuar këtë: ne e përsërisim detyrën si një detyrë parashikimi me shumë etiketa ku modeli parashikon si përkthimin ashtu edhe epokën e tij të veçantë. Ne vëzhgojmë se kjo ndihmon për të mbuluar çarjen gjuhësore pasi konteksti kronologjik përdoret gjithashtu si informacion ndihmës. Ne vlerësojmë kuadrin tonë në një korpus paralel të anotuar me informacion kronologjik dhe tregojmë eksperimentalisht efektshmërinë e tij në prodhimin e rezultateve të përkthimit të cilësisë. Ne lëshojmë si kodin ashtu edhe të dhënat për kërkimet e ardhshme.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Այս թղթի մեջ մենք նպատակում ենք լուծել հնագույն չինական տեքստի թարգմանման խնդիրները: (1) Լեզվաբանական բացառությունը դարաշրջանի տարբերության պատճառով հանգեցնում է թարգմանությունների, որոնք որակի մեջ վատ են, և (2) թարգմանությունների մեծ մասը բացակայում է կոնտեքստային տեղեկատվությունը,  Այս նպատակով մենք բարելավում ենք անցյալ թարգմանման տեխնիկաները առաջարկելով հետևյալը' մենք վերաձևավորում ենք խնդիրը որպես բազմաթիվ պիտակների կանխատեսման խնդիր, որտեղ մոդելը կանխատեսում է թարգմանությունը, ինչպես նաև այն հատուկ դարաշ Մենք նկատում ենք, որ սա օգնում է լեզվաբանական բացառությունը հաղթահարել, քանի որ քրոնոլոգիական կոնտեքստը օգտագործվում է նաև որպես օգնական տեղեկատվություն: Մենք ստուգում ենք մեր կառուցվածքը մի զուգահեռ կորպոսի վրա, որը գրված է քրոնոլոգիական տեղեկատվությամբ, և փորձարկումներով ցույց ենք տալիս դրա արդյունավետությունը որակի թարգմանման արտադրությունների Մենք հրապարակում ենք նաև կոդը, նաև ապագա հետազոտության տվյալները:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>এই কাগজটিতে আমরা প্রাচীন চীনা টেক্সটের অনুবাদের চারপাশে চ্যালেঞ্জের সাথে কথা বলতে চাই: (১) ভাষাগত ভাষার পার্থক্যের ফলে অনুবাদের মানে দারিদ্র এবং (২) অনুবাদের বেশীরভা এই শেষ পর্যন্ত আমরা অতীত অনুবাদের কৌশলের উপর উন্নতি প্রস্তাব করি নীচের প্রস্তাবের মাধ্যমে: আমরা এই কাজটিকে বহুল লেবেলের ভবিষ্যৎবাণী কাজ হিসেব আমরা দেখতে পাচ্ছি যে এটি ভাষাগত ভাষায় বিভ্রান্তিক বিভ্রান্তিতে সাহায্য করে যেহেতু ক্রোনোলজিক্যাল প্রেক্ষ আমরা ক্রোনোলজি তথ্য দিয়ে প্যারালেল কোর্পাসের উপর আমাদের ফ্রেমের কার্যক্রম বৈধ করি এবং মান অনুবাদের আউটপুট তৈরি করার পরীক্ষায় আমরা ভবিষ্যত গবেষণার জন্য কোড এবং তথ্য প্রকাশ করি।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağızda, əvvəlki Çin mətnlərin çeviriləcəyi çətinliklərdən çəkinmək istəyirik: (1) Dil boşluğu məlumatını təmizləmək üçün çətinliklərin müxtəlif təkrarlarının müxtəlif təkrarlarının sonuçlarına görə, və (2) çox təkrarların məlumatı anlamaq üçün çox mövcuddur. Bu səbəbdə, əvvəlki tercümə tekniklərini daha yaxşılaşdırırıq: Biz bu işi çoxlu etiketli tədbir törətməsi olaraq, modeli də tercümə ilə müəyyən vaxtı tədbir edir. Biz bu dil boşluğunu kömək etməyə kömək edirik ki, kronolojik məlumatı da kömək məlumatı olaraq istifadə edilir. Biz kronoloji məlumatları ilə bildirilmiş paralelə korpus üzərində çerçevemizi təsdiqləyirik və təcrübə olaraq özünü təşkil etmək üçün təşkil etdik. Biz hər ikisini və məlumatları gələcək araştırma üçün yayındırırıq.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>En aquest paper, busquem abordar els reptes que envolven la traducció del text xinès antic: (1) La diferència lingüística degut a la diferència en èpoces dóna lloc a traduccions que són poca qualitat, i (2) la majoria de traduccions falten la informació contextual que sovint és molt crucial per entendre el text. To this end, we improve upon past translation techniques by proposing the following: We reframe the task as a multi-label prediction task where the model predicts both the translation and its particular era.  Observem que això ajuda a superar la diferència lingüística mentre el context cronològic també s'utilitza com a informació auxiliar. Validim el nostre marc en un cos paral·lel anotat amb informació cronològica i mostram experimentalment la seva eficacia en produir productes de traducció de qualitat. Vam publicar tant el codi com les dades per a la recerca futura.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>V tomto článku se snažíme řešit výzvy spojené s překladem starověkého čínského textu: (1) Jazyková mezera způsobená rozdílem období vede k překladům špatné kvality a (2) většině překladů chybí kontextové informace, které jsou často velmi důležité pro porozumění textu. Za tímto účelem vylepšujeme předchozí překladové techniky navrhnutím následujícího: Úlohu přepravujeme jako víceštítkový predikční úkol, kde model předpovídá jak překlad, tak jeho konkrétní éru. Pozorujeme, že to pomáhá překlenut jazykovou propast, protože chronologický kontext je také používán jako pomocná informace. Ověřujeme náš rámec na paralelním korpusu anotovaném chronologickými informacemi a experimentálně ukazujeme jeho účinnost při produkci kvalitních překladových výstupů. Zveřejňujeme kód i data pro budoucí výzkum.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_bs>U ovom papiru imamo cilj da riješimo izazove oko prevoda drevnog kineskog teksta: (1) jezički praznik zbog razlike u izbrisanju rezultata prevoda siromašnih u kvaliteti, a (2) većina prevoda nedostaje kontekstualne informacije koje je često vrlo ključno za razumijevanje teksta. Za taj cilj, poboljšavamo prošle tehnike prevoda predložeći sljedeće: preobraćamo zadatak kao predviđanje multietiketa u kojem model predviđa prevod i njegovu određenu dobu. Primišljamo da ovo pomaže da se predstavlja jezički praznik kao kronološki kontekst također koristi kao pomoćni informacije. Potvrđujemo naš okvir na paralelnom korpusu annotiranom kronološkom informacijom i pokazujemo eksperimentalno svoju djelotvornost u proizvodnji rezultata kvalitetnog prevoda. Puštamo i kod i podatke za buduće istraživanje.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas töös püüame käsitleda iidse hiina teksti tõlkimisega seotud probleeme: (1) ajastute erinevusest tingitud keeleline lõhe toob kaasa tõlked, mis on halva kvaliteediga, ja (2) enamikul tõlketel puudub kontekstiteave, mis on sageli teksti mõistmiseks väga oluline. Selleks täiustame varasemaid tõlketeenikaid, pakkudes välja järgmist: Me kujundame ülesande ümber mitme märgisega ennustamisülesandeks, kus mudel prognoosib nii tõlke kui ka selle konkreetset ajastut. Märgime, et see aitab ületada keelelist lõhet, kuna lisainformatsioonina kasutatakse ka kronoloogilist konteksti. Valideerime oma raamistiku paralleelsel korpusel, mis on märgitud kronoloogilise informatsiooniga, ning näitame eksperimentaalselt selle efektiivsust kvaliteetsete tõlkeväljundite tootmisel. Me avaldame nii koodi kui ka andmed tulevaste uuringute jaoks.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa pyrimme vastaamaan antiikin kiinan tekstin kääntämiseen liittyviin haasteisiin: (1) aikakausien erilaisesta kielellisestä kuilusta johtuen käännökset ovat laadultaan huonoja ja (2) useimmilta käännöksiltä puuttuu kontekstitiedot, jotka ovat usein erittäin tärkeitä tekstin ymmärtämiseksi. Tätä varten kehitämme aikaisempia käännöstekniikoita ehdottamalla seuraavaa: Kehitämme tehtävän uudelleen monimerkkiseksi ennustustehtäväksi, jossa malli ennustaa sekä käännöksen että sen tietyn aikakauden. Havaitsemme, että tämä auttaa kuromaan kielellistä kuilua umpeen, koska kronologista kontekstia käytetään myös aputietona. Validoimme viitekehyksemme kronologisilla tiedoilla varustetulla rinnakkaiskorpusella ja osoitamme kokeellisesti sen tehokkuuden tuottaessa laadukkaita käännöstuotteita. Julkaisemme sekä koodin että datan tulevaa tutkimusta varten.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku želimo obravnavati izzive, povezane s prevajanjem starodavnih kitajskih besedil: (1) Jezikovna vrzel zaradi razlik v obdobjih povzroča slabo kakovost prevodov in (2) večini prevodov manjka kontekstualne informacije, ki so pogosto zelo ključne za razumevanje besedila. V ta namen izboljšujemo pretekle prevajalske tehnike tako, da predlagamo naslednje: Preoblikujemo nalogo kot nalogo napovedovanja z več oznakami, kjer model napoveduje prevod in njegovo določeno dobo. Ugotavljamo, da to pomaga premostiti jezikovno vrzel, saj se kronološki kontekst uporablja tudi kot pomožne informacije. Naš okvir potrjujemo na vzporednem korpusu, označenem s kronološkimi informacijami, in eksperimentalno dokazujemo njegovo učinkovitost pri izdelavi kakovostnih prevodov. Izdajamo tako kodo kot podatke za prihodnje raziskave.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Daga wannan takardan, Munã aimar mu yi magana ga masu murafa waɗanda ke kẽwaya a fassarar littãfin na China: (1) Kiɓallin harshen na gauraya da tsakanin sauri na fassarar da tarjifan su ne mafiya rauni ga nau'in, kuma (2) masu yawansa fassarar sunana ƙaranci ga maɓallin takarda da za'a iya amfani da matsayin. Ga wannan, Munã samar da mafarin fassarori masu gaba a gaba: Tuna riƙe aikin ka kama wani aikin abin da aka yi wa ɗabi'a multi-label, inda misalin ya yi bayani ga fassarar da tsofakinsa na ƙayyade. Munã ganin cewa wannan yana taimako da ya sami gaura cikin linguistic da aka yi amfani da shi kamar an yi amfani da maɓallin gaske. Tuna gaskata firam kanmu a kan wani korbas da aka yi wa haske da maɓallin chronogi kuma ke nuna aikin ta sami da jarrabo idan an sami fassarar masu tsari. Munã sakar da kodi da data ga littafan nan gaba ɗaya.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>בעיתון הזה, אנו מתכוונים להתמודד עם האתגרים שמסביבים את התרגום של טקסט סיני עתיק: (1) הפער השפתי בגלל ההבדל בתקופה תוביל לתרגומות שגרועות באיכות, ו (2) רוב התרגומות חסרות את המידע הקונקסטלי שבדרך כלל מאוד קריטי להבין את הטקסט. למטרה זו, אנחנו משתפרים על טכניקות התרגום בעבר על ידי הצעה הבאה: אנו מחדשים את המשימה בתור משימה חזיון multi-label שבו המודל חושף גם את התרגום ובעידן המיוחד שלה. אנו רואים שזה עוזר לכבוש את הפער השפתי, כיוון שקרנטקסט כרונולוגי משתמש גם בתור מידע נוסף. אנו מאשרים את המסגרת שלנו על קורפוס מקביל שנכתב עם מידע כרונולוגי ולהראות באופן ניסוי את היעילות שלה בייצור תוצאות התרגום איכותית. אנחנו משחררים את הקוד והנתונים למחקר עתיד.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Nang pewé iki, awak dhéwé iso nglanggar wigatining cara-wigatinipun sing nggawe tarjamahan kanggo teks sing Chinese sadha:1) Kasunyatan langkung wigatining tarjamahan kanggo ngilanggar tarjamahan sing bakal terus apik lan (2) terjamahan sing apik dhéwé informasi kapan-kapan sing beraksi yang cukup. Ngomongke iki, kita luwih ngrebut teknik sing dibutuhke tur angel nggawe geranggawe geranggawe lan nggawe barang multi-label prelimun nggawe geranggawe geranggawe tarjamahan karo perintah sing dumadhi. Awak dhéwé éntuk ngéwangé nggawe barang langgar tarjamahan kanggo nggawe tarjamahan kelas informasi. Awak dhéwé nggunakake sistem ning cara-cara sing dadi nggawe barang kelas informasi karo perknologi lan ngawe barang nggawe gerapakan seneng pisan jéwih apik dhéwé Awak dhéwé mbukaké kode lan data kanggo urêh barêng.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>འུ་ཅག་གི་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་གྱི་ཡིག་གེ་འགྲེལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་གནད་དོན་ལ་དམིགས་ཡུལ། To this end, we improve on past translation techniques by proposing the following: We reframe the task as a multi-label prediction task where the model predicts both the translation and its particular era. ངེད་ཚོས་སྐད་ཡིག་གི་བར་སྟོང་དག་ལ་མཐོ་རྐྱེན་བཟོ་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད་པ་བརྗོད་དགོས་བྱུང་། ང་ཚོས་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་རྩིས་གཞུང་འདི་མཐུན་སྒྲིག་གི་མཐུན་མཁན་གྱི་ཞལ་འཛུགས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་བཏོན་མཐུན་ཡོད་པ་དང་། ང་ཚོས་མ་འོངས་པར་ཞིབ་བཤེར་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་དང་གསལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་ཡོད་པ་རེད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Three-part diachronic semantic change dataset for Russian<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>ussian</title>
      <author><first>Andrey</first><last>Kutuzov</last></author>
      <author><first>Lidia</first><last>Pivovarova</last></author>
      <pages>7–13</pages>
      <abstract>We present a manually annotated lexical semantic change dataset for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_language">Russian</a> : RuShiftEval. Its novelty is ensured by a single set of target words annotated for their diachronic semantic shifts across three time periods, while the previous work either used only two time periods, or different sets of target words. The paper describes the composition and annotation procedure for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>. In addition, it is shown how the ternary nature of RuShiftEval allows to trace specific diachronic trajectories : ‘changed at a particular time period and stable afterwards’ or ‘was changing throughout all time periods’. Based on the analysis of the submissions to the recent shared task on semantic change detection for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_language">Russian</a>, we argue that correctly identifying such trajectories can be an interesting sub-task itself.</abstract>
      <url hash="6926ffc8">2021.lchange-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.lchange-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>kutuzov-pivovarova-2021-three</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/rushifteval">RuShiftEval</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>A diachronic evaluation of gender asymmetry in euphemism</title>
      <author><first>Anna</first><last>Kapron-King</last></author>
      <author><first>Yang</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <pages>28–38</pages>
      <abstract>The use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euphemism">euphemisms</a> is a known driver of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_change">language change</a>. It has been proposed that women use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euphemism">euphemisms</a> more than men. Although there have been several studies investigating gender differences in language, the claim about euphemism usage has not been tested comprehensively through time. If women do use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euphemism">euphemisms</a> more, this could mean that women also lead the formation of new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euphemism">euphemisms</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_change">language change</a> over time. Using four large diachronic text corpora of English, we evaluate the claim that women use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euphemism">euphemisms</a> more than men through a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantitative_research">quantitative analysis</a>. We assembled a list of 106 euphemism-taboo pairs to analyze their relative use through time by each gender in the corpora. Contrary to the existing belief, our results show that women do not use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euphemism">euphemisms</a> with a higher proportion than men. We repeated the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analysis">analysis</a> using different subsets of the euphemism-taboo pairs list and found that our result was robust. Our study indicates that in a broad range of settings involving both speech and writing, and with varying degrees of formality, women do not use or form <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euphemism">euphemisms</a> more than men.</abstract>
      <url hash="64074e62">2021.lchange-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.lchange-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>kapron-king-xu-2021-diachronic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Bhcitra : Visualising the dialect geography of South Asia<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>outh <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>sia</title>
      <author><first>Aryaman</first><last>Arora</last></author>
      <author><first>Adam</first><last>Farris</last></author>
      <author><first>Gopalakrishnan</first><last>R</last></author>
      <author><first>Samopriya</first><last>Basu</last></author>
      <pages>51–57</pages>
      <abstract>We present Bhcitra, a dialect mapping system for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Asia">South Asia</a> built on a database of linguistic studies of languages of the region annotated for topic and location data. We analyse language coverage and look towards applications to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typology_(linguistics)">typology</a> by visualising example datasets. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software">application</a> is not only meant to be useful for feature mapping, but also serves as a new kind of interactive bibliography for linguists of South Asian languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="8df779b2">2021.lchange-1.7</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.lchange-1.7</doi>
      <bibkey>arora-etal-2021-bhasacitra</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/aryamanarora/bhasacitra" additional="false">aryamanarora/bhasacitra</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Modeling the Evolution of Word Senses with Force-Directed Layouts of Co-occurrence Networks</title>
      <author><first>Tim</first><last>Reke</last></author>
      <author><first>Robert</first><last>Schwanhold</last></author>
      <author><first>Ralf</first><last>Krestel</last></author>
      <pages>58–63</pages>
      <abstract>Languages evolve over time and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meaning_(linguistics)">meaning of words</a> can shift. Furthermore, individual words can have multiple senses. However, existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> often only reflect one word sense per word and do not reflect <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_change">semantic changes</a> over time. While there are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> that can either model semantic change of words or multiple word senses, none of them cover both aspects simultaneously. We propose a novel force-directed graph layout algorithm to draw a network of frequently co-occurring words. In this way, we are able to use the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(discrete_mathematics)">drawn graph</a> to visualize the evolution of word senses. In addition, we hope that jointly modeling <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_change">semantic change</a> and multiple senses of words results in improvements for the individual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="31817be4">2021.lchange-1.8</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.lchange-1.8</doi>
      <bibkey>reke-etal-2021-modeling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>