<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.reinact">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-09-27">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Reasoning and Interaction Conference (ReInAct 2021)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Christine</first><last>Howes</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Simon</first><last>Dobnik</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ellen</first><last>Breitholtz</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Stergios</first><last>Chatzikyriakidis</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Gothenburg, Sweden</address>
      <month>October</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ca7d93c2">2021.reinact-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>reinact-2021-reasoning</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Dogwhistles as Inferences in Interaction</title>
      <author><first>Ellen</first><last>Breitholtz</last></author>
      <author><first>Robin</first><last>Cooper</last></author>
      <pages>40–46</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we will argue that the nature of dogwhistle communication is essentially dialogical, and that to account for dogwhistle meaning we must consider dialogical events in which dialogue partners can draw different conclusions based on communicative events. This leads us to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory">theory</a> based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inference">inference</a>. However, as identified by Khoo (2017) and emphasised by Henderson &amp; McCready (2018), a problematic aspect of this approach is that expressions that have a similar meaning are analysed as generating the same dogwhistle inferences, which appears not always to be the case. By modelling meaning in terms of intensional types in TTR, we avoid this problem.</abstract>
      <url hash="d5fa8ab4">2021.reinact-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>breitholtz-cooper-2021-dogwhistles</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Decoupling Pragmatics : Discriminative Decoding for Referring Expression Generation</title>
      <author><first>Simeon</first><last>Schüz</last></author>
      <author><first>Sina</first><last>Zarrieß</last></author>
      <pages>47–52</pages>
      <abstract>The shift to neural models in Referring Expression Generation (REG) has enabled more natural set-ups, but at the cost of interpretability. We argue that integrating pragmatic reasoning into the inference of context-agnostic generation models could reconcile traits of traditional and neural REG, as this offers a separation between context-independent, literal information and pragmatic adaptation to context. With this in mind, we apply existing decoding strategies from discriminative image captioning to REG and evaluate them in terms of pragmatic informativity, likelihood to ground-truth annotations and linguistic diversity. Our results show general effectiveness, but a relatively small gain in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Informatics">informativity</a>, raising important questions for REG in general.</abstract>
      <url hash="1efa35a1">2021.reinact-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>schuz-zarriess-2021-decoupling</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/coco">COCO</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/refcoco">RefCOCO</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Generating Justifications in a Spatial Question-Answering Dialogue System for a Blocks World</title>
      <author><first>Georgiy</first><last>Platonov</last></author>
      <author><first>Benjamin</first><last>Kane</last></author>
      <author><first>Lenhart</first><last>Schubert</last></author>
      <pages>53–57</pages>
      <abstract>As <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence">AI</a> reaches wider adoption, designing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> that are explainable and interpretable becomes a critical necessity. In particular, when it comes to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue_system">dialogue systems</a>, their reasoning must be transparent and must comply with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intuition">human intuitions</a> in order for them to be integrated seamlessly into day-to-day collaborative human-machine activities. Here, we describe our ongoing work on a (general purpose) dialogue system equipped with a spatial specialist with explanatory capabilities. We applied this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> to a particular task of characterizing spatial configurations of blocks in a simple physical Blocks World (BW) domain using natural locative expressions, as well as generating justifications for the proposed spatial descriptions by indicating the factors that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> used to arrive at a particular conclusion.</abstract>
      <url hash="9cfafd85">2021.reinact-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>platonov-etal-2021-generating</bibkey>
    <title_ar>توليد المبررات في نظام حوار الإجابة على الأسئلة المكانية لعالم الكتل</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Générer des justifications dans un système de dialogue spatial répondant à des questions pour un monde de blocs</title_fr>
      <title_es>Generar justificaciones en un sistema de diálogo espacial de preguntas y respuestas para un mundo de bloques</title_es>
      <title_pt>Gerando Justificativas em um Sistema de Diálogo Espacial de Respostas a Perguntas para um Mundo de Blocos</title_pt>
      <title_hi>एक ब्लॉक दुनिया के लिए एक स्थानिक प्रश्न-उत्तर संवाद प्रणाली में औचित्य उत्पन्न करना</title_hi>
      <title_zh>空中问答对话系统中为世界生理</title_zh>
      <title_ja>ブロック世界のための空間的な質問に答えるダイアログシステムでの正当性の生成</title_ja>
      <title_ru>Формирование обоснований в системе пространственного диалога «вопрос-ответ» для блочного мира</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Fírinnithe a Ghiniúint i gCóras Agallaimh Spáis Ceist-Freagartha do Dhomhan Bloic</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Δημιουργία αιτιολόγησης σε ένα σύστημα διαλόγου χωρικής απάντησης ερωτήσεων για έναν κόσμο μπλοκ</title_el>
      <title_hu>Indokolások generálása egy térbeli kérdésválaszadó párbeszédrendszerben egy blokkvilág számára</title_hu>
      <title_it>Generare giustificazioni in un sistema di dialogo spaziale per rispondere alle domande per un mondo di blocchi</title_it>
      <title_kk>Name</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Pagrindinių priežasčių sukūrimas erdvinių klausimų atsakymo dialogo sistemoje blokų pasauliui</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Генерирање на оправдувања во системот за дијалог за одговори на просторни прашања за блокиран свет</title_mk>
      <title_ml>സ്പെയില്‍ ചോദ്യങ്ങള്‍- ഉത്തരം നല്‍കുന്ന ഡയലോഗ് സിസ്റ്റമില്‍ ന്യായീകരണങ്ങള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Menjana Keadilan dalam Sistem Dialog Penjawapan-soalan Ruang untuk Dunia Blok</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Il-Ġenerazzjoni ta’ Ġustifikazzjonijiet f’Sistema ta’ Djalogu dwar it-Tweġibiet għall-Mistoqsijiet Spazjali għal Dinja Blokkjata</title_mt>
      <title_ro>Generarea justificărilor într-un sistem spațial de dialog de răspuns la întrebări pentru o lume blocuri</title_ro>
      <title_no>Lagar justeringar i eit dialogvindauge for spørsmål- svar for eit blokkeverd</title_no>
      <title_pl>Generowanie uzasadnienia w przestrzennym systemie dialogu odpowiedzi na pytania dla świata bloków</title_pl>
      <title_mn>Блокийн Дэлхийн орон зай асуулт-хариулт диалогын системд зөвлөгөө үүсгэх</title_mn>
      <title_sr>Generiranje opravdanja u svemirskom dijalogu za odgovor na pitanja za blokove sveta</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>Generating Justices in a Spatial Question-answering Dialog System for a Blocks World</title_so>
      <title_sv>Skapa motiveringar i ett rumsligt frågesvarsdialogsystem för en blockvärld</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Name</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Tạo lí do cho một hệ thống đối thoại Hỏi-đáp địa phương cho một thế giới Châu Âu</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Generating Justifications in a Spatial Question-Answering Dialogue System for a Blocks World</title_uz>
      <title_hr>Generiranje opravdanja u svemirskom dijalogu za odgovor na pitanja za blokove svijeta</title_hr>
      <title_de>Generierung von Rechtfertigungen in einem räumlichen Fragebeantworter Dialogsystem für eine Blockwelt</title_de>
      <title_bg>Генериране на обосновки в пространствена система за диалог за отговор на въпроси за един свят на блокове</title_bg>
      <title_da>Generation Justifications in a Spatial Spørgsmål-Besvarelse Dialogue System for a Blocks World</title_da>
      <title_id>Membuat Justifikasi dalam Sistem Dialog Jawab Pertanyaan Ruang untuk Dunia Blok</title_id>
      <title_ko>블록 세계의 공간 퀴즈 대화 시스템에서 이유를 생성합니다</title_ko>
      <title_fa>تولید دادگری در یک سیستم محاورۀ پاسخ پرسش فضایی برای جهان بلوک‌ها</title_fa>
      <title_nl>Het genereren van rechtvaardigingen in een ruimtelijk vragenbeantwoordingssysteem voor een blokwereld</title_nl>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_sw>Kutengeneza Haki katika mfumo wa maswali ya Spania kwa ajili ya Blocks World</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Blok Dünýä üçin Seleň Soragy-jogap sisteminde Ýarlanjak Jeşirmek</title_tr>
      <title_hy>Հարցքների պատասխանների տիեզերական համակարգում արդարադատություններ ստեղծելը</title_hy>
      <title_sq>Duke krijuar justifikime në një sistem dialog për përgjigjet hapësirore të pyetjeve për një botë bllokuese</title_sq>
      <title_bs>Generiranje opravdanja u svemirskom dijalogu za odgovor na pitanja za blokove svijeta</title_bs>
      <title_am>አዲስ ዶሴ ፍጠር</title_am>
      <title_ca>generar justificacions en un sistema de diàleg espacial de resposta a preguntes per a un món de blocs</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Generování odůvodnění v prostorovém dialogovém systému pro zodpovězení otázek pro blokový svět</title_cs>
      <title_bn>একটি ব্লক বিশ্বের জন্য স্পেশিয়াল প্রশ্ন- উত্তরাধিকারী ডায়ালগ সিস্টেমে বিচার তৈরি করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_az>Bir Blok Dünyası üçün yer soruşma-cavab Dönüş Dialooğu Sistemində Justifications Yapılandırılır</title_az>
      <title_fi>Perustelujen luominen alueellisessa kysymyksiin vastaamiseen liittyvĂ¤ssĂ¤ vuoropuhelujĂ¤rjestelmĂ¤ssĂ¤ lohkojen maailmassa</title_fi>
      <title_et>Põhjenduste loomine ruumilises küsimustele vastamise dialoogisüsteemis blokkide maailma jaoks</title_et>
      <title_sk>Ustvarjanje utemeljitev v prostorskem sistemu dialoga za odgovore na vprašanja za svet blokov</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_jv>Jejaring</title_jv>
      <title_he>יצירת צדקות במערכת דיאלוג לענות על שאלות מרחבית עבור עולם בלוקים</title_he>
      <title_bo>Blocks World ལ་སྤྱོད་པའི་བར་སྟོང་གླེང་སྒྲོམ་གྱི་ཕྱོགས་ལན་མོས་མཐུན་གླེང་སྒྲོམ་ཐོག་ཏུ་བཟོ་བཅོས་བཟོ་བ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>مع وصول الذكاء الاصطناعي إلى التبني على نطاق أوسع ، فإن تصميم الأنظمة القابلة للتفسير والتفسير يصبح ضرورة ملحة. على وجه الخصوص ، عندما يتعلق الأمر بأنظمة الحوار ، يجب أن يكون تفكيرهم شفافًا ويجب أن يتوافق مع الحدس البشري حتى يتم دمجهم بسلاسة في الأنشطة التعاونية اليومية بين الإنسان والآلة. هنا ، نصف عملنا المستمر على نظام حوار (للأغراض العامة) مزود بأخصائي مكاني بقدرات تفسيرية. طبقنا هذا النظام على مهمة معينة تتمثل في توصيف التكوينات المكانية للكتل في مجال بسيط للكتل المادية (BW) باستخدام التعبيرات الموضعية الطبيعية ، بالإضافة إلى إنشاء مبررات للأوصاف المكانية المقترحة من خلال الإشارة إلى العوامل التي استخدمها النظام للوصول إلى نتيجة معينة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_fr>Alors que l'IA gagne en adoption, concevoir des systèmes explicables et interprétables devient une nécessité cruciale. En particulier, lorsqu'il s'agit de systèmes de dialogue, leur raisonnement doit être transparent et respecter les intuitions humaines afin qu'ils puissent être intégrés de manière transparente dans les activités collaboratives homme-machine quotidiennes. Nous décrivons ici nos travaux en cours sur un système de dialogue (à usage général) équipé d'un spécialiste spatial doté de capacités explicatives. Nous avons appliqué ce système à une tâche particulière de caractérisation des configurations spatiales de blocs dans un domaine physique Blocks World (BW) simple à l'aide d'expressions locatives naturelles, ainsi que de génération de justifications pour les descriptions spatiales proposées en indiquant les facteurs utilisés par le système pour arriver à un conclusion particulière.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>A medida que la IA alcanza una adopción más amplia, diseñar sistemas que sean explicables e interpretables se convierte en una necesidad fundamental. En particular, cuando se trata de sistemas de diálogo, su razonamiento debe ser transparente y cumplir con las intuiciones humanas para que se integren sin problemas en las actividades colaborativas cotidianas entre humanos y máquinas. A continuación, describimos nuestro trabajo en curso sobre un sistema de diálogo (de propósito general) equipado con un especialista espacial con capacidades explicativas. Aplicamos este sistema a una tarea particular de caracterizar configuraciones espaciales de bloques en un dominio físico simple del Mundo de Bloques (BW) utilizando expresiones locativas naturales, así como generar justificaciones para las descripciones espaciales propuestas al indicar los factores que el sistema utilizó para llegar a un conclusión particular.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>À medida que a IA alcança uma adoção mais ampla, projetar sistemas que sejam explicáveis e interpretáveis torna-se uma necessidade crítica. Em particular, quando se trata de sistemas de diálogo, seus raciocínios devem ser transparentes e devem estar de acordo com as intuições humanas para que possam ser integrados perfeitamente às atividades colaborativas homem-máquina do dia-a-dia. Aqui, descrevemos nosso trabalho em andamento em um sistema de diálogo (propósito geral) equipado com um especialista espacial com recursos explicativos. Aplicamos este sistema a uma tarefa particular de caracterizar configurações espaciais de blocos em um domínio físico simples Blocks World (BW) usando expressões locativas naturais, bem como gerar justificativas para as descrições espaciais propostas, indicando os fatores que o sistema utilizou para chegar a uma determinada conclusão.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>AIがより広範囲に導入されるにつれて、説明可能で解釈可能なシステムを設計することが重要な必要性となります。特に、対話システムに関しては、それらの推論は透明でなければならず、日々の人間と機械の共同作業にシームレスに統合されるために、人間の直感に従わなければなりません。ここでは、説明能力を持つ空間専門家を備えた（汎用）対話システムに関する現在の取り組みについて述べる。このシステムを、自然な位置表現を使用して単純な物理ブロックワールド（ ＢＷ ）ドメイン内のブロックの空間構成を特徴付ける特定のタスクに適用し、また、システムが特定の結論を導き出すために使用した要因を示すことによって、提案された空間記述の正当性を生成した。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>जैसा कि एआई व्यापक गोद लेने तक पहुंचता है, उन प्रणालियों को डिजाइन करना जो व्याख्या योग्य और व्याख्यायोग्य हैं, एक महत्वपूर्ण आवश्यकता बन जाती है। विशेष रूप से, जब संवाद प्रणालियों की बात आती है, तो उनका तर्क पारदर्शी होना चाहिए और उन्हें दिन-प्रतिदिन की सहयोगी मानव-मशीन गतिविधियों में निर्बाध रूप से एकीकृत करने के लिए मानव अंतर्ज्ञान का पालन करना चाहिए। यहां, हम व्याख्यात्मक क्षमताओं के साथ एक स्थानिक विशेषज्ञ से सुसज्जित एक (सामान्य उद्देश्य) संवाद प्रणाली पर हमारे चल रहे काम का वर्णन करते हैं। हमने इस प्रणाली को प्राकृतिक लोकेटिव अभिव्यक्तियों का उपयोग करके एक साधारण भौतिक ब्लॉक्स वर्ल्ड (बीडब्ल्यू) डोमेन में ब्लॉकों के स्थानिक विन्यास की विशेषता के एक विशेष कार्य के लिए लागू किया, साथ ही साथ उन कारकों को इंगित करके प्रस्तावित स्थानिक विवरणों के लिए औचित्य उत्पन्न किया जो सिस्टम ने किसी विशेष निष्कर्ष पर पहुंचने के लिए उपयोग किया था।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>随人工智能得广用,设意为至必要条件。 当及言统,其理必明,必中人之直觉,以集于常人机活动之中。 述我方(),系统备空家。 吾将统用于一特定,虽以自然定位表达式表征物理(BW)宇宙之间,指示系统,特定结论者,因其成理。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ru>По мере того, как ИИ достигает более широкого принятия, разработка систем, которые объяснимы и интерпретируемы, становится критической необходимостью. В частности, когда речь идет о системах диалога, их рассуждения должны быть транспарентными и соответствовать человеческим интуициям, с тем чтобы они могли беспрепятственно интегрироваться в повседневную совместную деятельность человека и машины. Здесь мы описываем нашу текущую работу над диалоговой системой (общего назначения), оснащенной пространственным специалистом с пояснительными возможностями. Мы применили эту систему к конкретной задаче характеризации пространственных конфигураций блоков в простой физической области Blocks World (BW) с использованием естественных локативных выражений, а также генерации обоснований предлагаемых пространственных описаний с указанием факторов, которые использовались системой для достижения конкретного вывода.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_ga>De réir mar a shroicheann AI glacadh níos leithne, tá sé ríthábhachtach córais a dhearadh atá so-mhínithe agus inléirmhínithe. Go háirithe, maidir le córais idirphlé, ní mór a réasúnaíocht a bheith trédhearcach agus cloí le hintleachta daonna ionas gur féidir iad a chomhtháthú gan uaim i ngníomhaíochtaí comhoibritheacha laethúla an duine. Anseo, déanaimid cur síos ar ár n-obair leanúnach ar chóras idirphlé (cuspóir ginearálta) atá feistithe le speisialtóir spásúlachta le cumais mhíniúcháin. Chuireamar an córas seo i bhfeidhm ar thasc ar leith maidir le cumraíochtaí spásúla de bhloic a thréithriú i bhfearann simplí fisiciúil Blocks World (BW) ag baint úsáide as nathanna logánta nádúrtha, chomh maith le fírinnithe a ghiniúint do na tuairiscí spásúla molta trí na fachtóirí a d'úsáid an córas chun teacht orthu a léiriú. conclúid ar leith.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Ahogy a mesterséges intelligencia szélesebb körű bevezetésre kerül, a megmagyarázható és értelmezhető rendszerek kialakítása kritikus szükségessé válik. Különösen a párbeszédrendszerek érvelésének átláthatónak kell lennie, és meg kell felelnie az emberi intuícióknak annak érdekében, hogy zökkenőmentesen integrálhatók legyenek a mindennapi együttműködési ember-gép tevékenységekbe. Itt bemutatjuk a folyamatban lévő (általános célú) párbeszédrendszeren végzett, magyarázó képességekkel rendelkező térszakértővel felszerelt munkánkat. Ezt a rendszert egy egyszerű fizikai Blocks World (BW) tartományban lévő blokkok térbeli konfigurációinak természetes lokációs kifejezésekkel történő jellemzésére alkalmaztuk, valamint a javasolt térleírások indokolására azáltal, hogy megjelöltük azokat a tényezőket, amelyeket a rendszer egy adott következtetésre jutott.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Καθώς η τεχνητή νοημοσύνη φθάνει σε ευρύτερη υιοθέτηση, ο σχεδιασμός συστημάτων που είναι εξηγητά και ερμηνευτά γίνεται μια κρίσιμη αναγκαιότητα. Ειδικότερα, όσον αφορά τα συστήματα διαλόγου, η συλλογιστική τους πρέπει να είναι διαφανής και να συμμορφώνεται με τις ανθρώπινες διαισθήσεις προκειμένου να ενσωματωθούν απρόσκοπτα στις καθημερινές συνεργατικές δραστηριότητες ανθρώπου-μηχανής. Εδώ περιγράφουμε τη συνεχιζόμενη εργασία μας πάνω σε ένα σύστημα διαλόγου γενικού σκοπού εξοπλισμένο με έναν χωρικό ειδικό με επεξηγηματικές δυνατότητες. Εφαρμόσαμε αυτό το σύστημα σε ένα συγκεκριμένο έργο του χαρακτηρισμού χωρικών διαμορφώσεων μπλοκ σε έναν απλό φυσικό τομέα μπλοκ με τη χρήση φυσικών τοπογραφικών εκφράσεων, καθώς και της δημιουργίας δικαιολογιών για τις προτεινόμενες χωρικές περιγραφές υποδεικνύοντας τους παράγοντες που χρησιμοποίησε το σύστημα για να καταλήξει σε ένα συγκεκριμένο συμπέρασμα.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>როგორც AI უფრო დიდი მოვიღება, სისტემის განახსნა, რომლებიც უფრო განახსნა და განახსნა იქნება კრიტიკური მჭირდება. განსაკუთრებით, როდესაც დიალოგის სისტემის შესახებ, მათი არსება უნდა იყოს ცნობიერი და უნდა იყენებთ ადამიანის ინტეუციების შესახებ, რომ ისინი ყოველდღე სამუშაო ადამიანის მაქინის ევრატიგებ ჩვენ აღწერეთ ჩვენი მუშაობა (ყველა მიზეზი) დიალოგის სისტემაში, რომელიც განსაკუთრებული სპეციალური სპეციალური შესაძლებლობით აღწერა. ჩვენ ამ სისტემის განსაკუთრებულ დავაყენეთ კონფიგურაციის კონფიგურაციების კონფიგურაციების განსაკუთრებისთვის პირადი ფიზიკური ბლოკების მსოფლიოში (BW) დემომინის გამოყენებაში, რომელიც მიყენებული სისტემის განსაკუთრებისთვის განსაკუთ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Man mano che l'IA raggiunge un'adozione più ampia, progettare sistemi che siano spiegabili e interpretabili diventa una necessità critica. In particolare, quando si tratta di sistemi di dialogo, il loro ragionamento deve essere trasparente e conforme alle intuizioni umane per integrarli perfettamente nelle attività collaborative uomo-macchina quotidiane. Qui descriviamo il nostro lavoro in corso su un sistema di dialogo (generale purpose) dotato di uno specialista spaziale con capacità esplicative. Abbiamo applicato questo sistema ad un particolare compito di caratterizzare configurazioni spaziali di blocchi in un semplice dominio fisico Blocks World (BW) utilizzando espressioni localizzative naturali, oltre a generare giustificazioni per le descrizioni spaziali proposte indicando i fattori che il sistema ha utilizzato per arrivare a una particolare conclusione.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бағдарламаның көп қабылдауына жеткізгенде, түсінікті және түсінікті түсінікті жүйелерді құру қажет болады. Әсіресе, диалог жүйелеріне қатысты кезде, олардың тәсілдері мөлдір болу керек және адамдардың тәсілдеріне сәйкес істеу керек. Олар күнделік жүйелерді күнделікті біріктіру үшін адамдардың тәсілд Мұнда, біз жұмыс істегенімізді (жалпы мақсат) диалог жүйесінде түсініктеме мүмкіндіктері бар жергілікті специалистік жүйесінде таңдап береміз. Біз осы жүйені қарапайым физикалық блоктар Дүйесінде (BW) бойынша жергілікті өрнектерді қолданатын блоктардың бойынша баптауларын таңдау тапсырмасына қолдандық, сондай-ақ бұл жергілікті таңдау үшін қолданылатын жергілікті түсініктерді</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ml>AI വിശാലമായ പുത്രന്മാര്‍ക്ക് എത്തുമ്പോള്‍, വിശദീകരിക്കാനും വ്യക്തമാക്കാനും കഴിയുന്ന സിസ്റ്റമുകള്‍ പരിശോധ പ്രത്യേകിച്ച്, സംസാര സംവിധാനങ്ങളിലേക്ക് വരുമ്പോള്‍, അവരുടെ കാര്യങ്ങള്‍ സ്വകാര്യമായിരിക്കണം, മനുഷ്യരുടെ മനസ്സുകള്‍ അനുസരിക്കണം. അതിനാല്‍ അവരെ ദിവസത്തിലേക ഇവിടെ, നമ്മുടെ നടക്കുന്ന പണിയെക്കുറിച്ച് വിശദീകരിക്കുന്ന ഒരു സ്പാസ്റ്റിയൽ വിശേഷിപ്പുകാരനുമായ (സാധാരണ ഉദ്ദേശ ഈ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ സ്പെയില്‍ ബ്ലോക്കുകളുടെ സ്പെയിസ്റ്റിയേല്‍ ക്രമീകരണങ്ങള്‍ വ്യക്തമാക്കുന്നതിനായി ഞങ്ങള്‍ പ്രയോഗിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. സ്വാഭാവികമായ സ്ഥാനത്തിലെ പ്രകടനങ്ങള്‍</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mk>As AI reaches wider adoption, designing systems that are explainable and interpretable becomes a critical necessity.  Посебно, кога станува збор за дијалошките системи, нивното размислување мора да биде транспарентно и мора да се согласи со човечките интуиции со цел да се интегрираат безопасно во секојдневните заеднички активности на човек-машина. Овде ја опишуваме нашата тековна работа на (општиот) дијалог систем опремен со просториски специјалист со објаснувачки способности. Го применивме овој систем на одредена задача да се карактеризираат просторните конфигурации на блокови во едноставен физички домен Блокови свет (БВ) користејќи природни локационални изрази, како и да се генерираат оправдувања за предложените просторни описи со индикација на факторите кои системот ги користеше за да постигне</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Sebagaimana AI mencapai adopsi yang lebih luas, merancang sistem yang boleh dijelaskan dan diterangkan menjadi keperluan kritik. Secara khususnya, apabila ia berkaitan dengan sistem dialog, alasan mereka mesti transparan dan mesti sesuai dengan intuisi manusia supaya mereka disertai secara terus-menerus dalam aktiviti kerjasama manusia-mesin sehari-hari. Di sini, kita menggambarkan kerja kita yang sedang berlangsung pada sistem dialog (tujuan umum) yang dilengkapi dengan ahli ruang dengan kemampuan penjelasan. Kami melaksanakan sistem ini untuk tugas tertentu untuk mengukur konfigurasi ruang blok dalam domain Blok Fisik Dunia (BW) sederhana menggunakan ungkapan lokasi alami, serta menghasilkan alasan untuk deskripsi ruang yang diusulkan dengan menunjukkan faktor yang sistem digunakan untuk mencapai kesimpulan tertentu.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Hekk kif l-AI jilħaq adozzjoni usa’, it-tfassil ta’ sistemi li jistgħu jiġu spjegati u interpretati jsir neċessità kritika. B’mod partikolari, fir-rigward tas-sistemi ta’ djalogu, ir-raġunament tagħhom għandu jkun trasparenti u għandu jkun konformi mal-intwizzjonijiet umani sabiex ikunu integrati mingħajr xkiel fl-attivitajiet kollaborattivi ta’ kuljum bejn il-bniedem u l-magna. Hawnhekk, a ħna niddeskrivu l-ħidma kontinwa tagħna fuq sistema ta’ djalogu (bi skop ġenerali) mgħammra b’speċjalista ġeografiku b’kapaċitajiet ta’ spjegazzjoni. Applikajna din is-sistema għal kompitu partikolari li tikkaratterizza l-konfigurazzjonijiet ġeografiċi tal-blokki f’dominju sempliċi fiżiku tal-Blokkijiet Dinjija (BW) bl-użu ta’ espressjonijiet lokalizzati naturali, kif ukoll li tiġġenera ġustifikazzjonijiet għad-deskrizzjonijiet ġeografiċi proposti billi tindika l-fatturi li s-sistema użat biex tasal għal konklużjoni partikolari.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>ХАБ илүү өргөн хүлээн авах үед, тайлбарлаж болох боломжтой тогтоох системүүд нь чухал шаардлагатай болдог. Ялангуяа, диалог системийн тухай ярилцах үед, тэдний урам зорилго тодорхой байх ёстой. Тэднийг өдөр тутмын хамтрагч хүн-машины үйл ажиллагаанд гүйцэтгэл зорилготой болгохын тулд хүн төрөлхтний хариу бодлоор байх Энд бид үргэлжлүүлж байгаа (ерөнхий зорилго) диалог системийг тайлбарлах боломжтой орон зай мэргэжилтэн дээр тайлбарлаж байна. Бид энэ системийг энгийн физикийн Блок Дэлхийн (BW) хэлбэрээр байгалийн байрлал илэрхийллийг ашиглаж буй блокуудын загварын загварын тодорхойлолтын тулд ашиглаж, мөн санал өгсөн загварын тодорхойлолтын тулд тодорхойлолтын тулд тодорхойлдог.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Når AI når breier innføring, blir utforming av systemer som er forklarbare og tolkbar ein kritisk nødvendig. Særlig når det gjer dialogsystemet, må grunnen deres vera gjennomsiktig og må fullføra menneskelige intuisjonar for at dei skal integrerast såkalt i samarbeidsfunksjonar med menneskelige maskiner dagar. Her beskriver vi det gjeldande arbeidet vårt på eit (generell mål) dialogsystemet med ei mellomromspesialista med forklaringskapasiteter. Vi brukte denne systemet til eit spesielt oppgåve for å karakterisera mellomrom- oppsett av blokkar i ein enkel fysisk blokkar- domene (BW) ved bruk av naturlige lokasjonsuttrykk, og å laga justeringar for dei foreslåtte mellomromskildringane ved å vise faktorene som systemet bruka til å komme til ein bestemt konklusjon.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>W miarę szerszego przyjęcia sztucznej inteligencji projektowanie systemów, które są wytłumaczalne i interpretowalne, staje się krytyczną koniecznością. W szczególności, jeśli chodzi o systemy dialogu, ich rozumowanie musi być przejrzyste i zgodne z ludzką intuicją, aby mogły być bezproblemowo zintegrowane z codziennymi współpracującymi człowiek-maszyna działaniami. Opisujemy tutaj naszą bieżącą pracę nad systemem dialogu (ogólnego przeznaczenia) wyposażonym w specjalistę przestrzennego o możliwościach wyjaśniających. Zastosowaliśmy ten system do konkretnego zadania charakteryzowania konfiguracji przestrzennych bloków w prostej dziedzinie Świata Bloków fizycznych (BW) za pomocą naturalnych wyrażeń lokalizacyjnych, a także generowania uzasadnienia proponowanych opisów przestrzennych poprzez wskazanie czynników, które system użył do osiągnięcia konkretnego wniosku.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Pe măsură ce AI ajunge la o adoptare mai largă, proiectarea sistemelor care sunt explicabile și interpretabile devine o necesitate critică. În special, în ceea ce privește sistemele de dialog, raționamentul acestora trebuie să fie transparent și să respecte intuițiile umane pentru ca acestea să fie integrate fără probleme în activitățile de colaborare de zi cu zi om-mașină. Aici descriem lucrările noastre în curs de desfășurare asupra unui sistem de dialog (general purpose) echipat cu un specialist spațial cu capacități explicative. Am aplicat acest sistem la o sarcină particulară de caracterizare a configurațiilor spațiale ale blocurilor într-un domeniu fizic simplu Blocks World (BW) folosind expresii locative naturale, precum și generarea justificărilor pentru descrierile spațiale propuse prin indicarea factorilor pe care sistemul i-a folosit pentru a ajunge la o concluzie particulară.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_lt>Kadangi AI pasiekia platesnį įsisavinimą, aiškinamų ir aiškinamų sistemų kūrimas tampa labai svarbus. Visų pirma, kalbant apie dialogo sistemas, jų motyvavimas turi būti skaidrus ir turi atitikti žmogaus intuicijas, kad jie būtų visapusiškai integruoti į kasdienę žmogaus ir mašin ų bendradarbiavimo veiklą. Čia apibūdiname mūsų vykdomą darbą (bendrojo tikslo) dialogo sistemoje, kurioje yra erdvėspecialistas, turintis aiškinamųjų gebėjimų. Taikėme šią sistemą tam tikram uždaviniui apibūdinti erdvinius blokų konfigūracijas paprastose fizinėse blokų pasaulio (BW) srityse naudojant natūralias vietos išraiškas, taip pat sukurti pagrindimus siūlomiems erdviniams aprašymams, nurodant veiksnius, kuriuos sistema naudojo tam tikrai išvadai pasiekti.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_si>AI විශාල විශාල ප්‍රතිචාරයක් ලබාගන්න පුළුවන් විස්තර සහ අභිවාදයක් වෙන්න පුළුවන් පද්ධතිය විශේෂයෙන්, ඒක සංවාද පද්ධතියට ගැන, ඔවුන්ගේ හිතන්න පාරදේශ වෙන්න ඕනි ඒ වගේම මිනිස්සුන්ගේ ප්‍රතික්‍රියාවට සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න ඕන මෙන්න, අපි පැහැදිලි විශේෂ ක්‍රියාත්මක විශේෂකයෙක් සමග සාමාන්‍ය අරමුණ සංවාද පද්ධතියේ අපේ වැඩ කරන වැඩේ වි අපි මේ පද්ධතිය ප්‍රයෝජනය විශේෂයෙන් ප්‍රයෝජනය විශේෂයෙන් සාමාන්‍ය භාවිත බ්ලොක්ස් ලෝකය (BW) ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා ප්‍රයෝජනය ස්ථානය සඳහා ප්‍රයෝජනය විස්තරය ස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Markii AI gaadho korsashada korsashada ballaadhan, waxaa loo baahan yahay nidaamka loo qori karo oo lagu turjumi karo. Si gaar ah marka ay timaado nidaamka dialogka, waa in sababtoodu ay tahay mid muuqda, waana in ay addeecaan fikradda dadku si ay ugu wada qabsadaan waxqabadyo ka shaqeeya machine-ka dadka maalin-maalmeedka. Halkan, waxaynu ku qoraynaa shuqulkayaga ku soconaya nidaamka dialogue (caadiga) oo ay leedahay khabiir dhakhtar ah oo ay awoodo fasiri karto. Waxaan nidaamkan u qabannay shuqul gaar ah oo ku sawiranaya koonfureedyada bangiyada ah oo ka mid ah xafiiska jidhka dunida (BW) oo fudud isticmaalaya hadal degmada ah, sidoo kale waxaan sababnay garsoorid sawirada laga soo jeedo sawirida spatial, waxaana tusinayaa waxyaabaha ay nidaamka u isticmaali jirtay dhamaadka gaar ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>Dok AI postigne šire usvajanje, dizajnirajući sisteme koje su objašnjive i interpretabilne postaju kritična potreba. Posebno, kad se radi o sistemima dijaloga, njihovo razmišljanje mora biti transparentno i mora biti u skladu sa ljudskim intuicijama kako bi im se svakodnevno uključilo bezvezno u saradnju sa ljudskim mašinama. Ovdje opisujemo naš nastavljajući rad na (općem cilju) dijalogskom sistemu opremljenom prostornim specijalistom sa objašnjavajućim sposobnostima. Prijavili smo ovaj sistem na posebni zadatak karakteriziranja prostornih konfiguracija blokova u jednostavnom domenu fizičkih blokova svijeta (BW) koristeći prirodne lokativne izraze, kao i stvaranje opravdanja za predložene prostorne opise pokazivajući faktore koje je sistem koristio da stigne do određenog zaključka.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>I takt med att AI blir mer omfattande blir det nödvändigt att utforma system som är förklaringbara och tolkningsbara. Särskilt när det gäller dialogsystem måste deras resonemang vara transparenta och följa mänskliga intuitioner för att de ska integreras sömlöst i den dagliga samarbetsverksamheten mellan människa och maskin. Här beskriver vi vårt pågående arbete med ett (generellt) dialogsystem utrustat med en rumspecialist med förklarande förmåga. Vi tillämpade detta system på en särskild uppgift att karakterisera rumsliga konfigurationer av block i en enkel fysisk Blocks World-domän (BW) med hjälp av naturliga lokaliserade uttryck, samt generera motiveringar för de föreslagna rumsliga beskrivningarna genom att ange de faktorer som systemet använde för att komma fram till en viss slutsats.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>AI விரிவாக புதுப்பிக்கும் போது, வடிவமைப்பு அமைப்புகள் விளக்கமுடியாத மற்றும் விளக்கமுடியாது ஒரு முக்கி குறிப்பிட்டு, உரையாடல் முறைமைகளுக்கு வரும்போது, அவர்களுடைய காரணங்கள் தெளிவாக இருக்க வேண்டும் மற்றும் மனித உணர்வுகளை பின்பற்ற வேண்டும் என்றால்  இங்கு, நாம் எங்கள் நடப்பு பணியை விவரிக்கிறோம் விளக்கமான இயல்புகளுடன் ஒரு வெளிப்பாட்டு உரையாடல் முறைமையில். நாங்கள் இந்த கணினியை சிறப்பு பணிக்கு செயல்படுத்தி ஒரு எளிய இயல்பான தொகுதிகள் உலக (BW) களத்தில் உள்ள இடைவெளியீட்டு வடிவமைப்புகளை எழுதுவதற்கான சுலபமான செயல்பாடு</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>جب AI بہت وسیع منتخب ہوتا ہے، سیستموں کی طراحی کرتی ہے جو واضح کر سکتے ہیں اور تفسیر قابل ہیں، ایک ضروری ضرورت ہوتی ہے. مخصوصا، جب یہ بات ڈالیٹ سیسٹم کے بارے میں آتی ہے، ان کا منظور صریح ہونا چاہیے اور انسان کی نظریوں کے ساتھ پوری ہونا چاہیے تاکہ وہ روزہ کے دن کامیابی انسان-میشن کی فعالیتیں میں سیدھی طور پر جمع کئے جائیں. یہاں، ہم نے ایک (عمومی هدف) دیالوگ سیسٹم پر اپنا ادامه کررہا ہے جو کھول کھول کھول کھول کھول سکتا ہے۔ ہم نے اس سیسٹم کو ایک خاص کام پر لازم کیا تھا کہ ایک ساده فیزیکی بلاک (BW) ڈومین میں بلاک کی جگہ کی تنظیم کریں، اور اس طرح پیشنهاد کی جگہ کی توصیف کے لئے تعریف کریں کہ سیسٹم ایک خاص نتیجہ پر پہنچانے کے لئے استعمال کیا گیا تھا۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>AI tezligini tezlashtirishga ega bo'lganda, tezlashtirish mumkin va tarjima qiladigan tizimlar muhim kerak. Ko'pchilik tizimlariga kelganda, ularning g'oyalari transparent bo'lishi kerak va ular har kuni bir kuni qo'llash mashina harakatlariga birlashtirish kerak. Bu yerda, bizning davom etiladigan muloqat tizimimizni o'rganish imkoniyatlari bilan bog'liq muloqat tizimini anglatamiz. Biz bu tizimni oddiy fysik blocks (BW) domen (BW) domain (tabiiy lokal ifodalari) bilan bog'liq moslamalarini aniqlash uchun foydalanamiz va taʼminlovchi spatial taʼriflari uchun qoʻllanmalarni yaratish mumkin. Bu tizimning foydalanilgan maqsadlarni bir necha murakkab keladi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Khi AI phát triển rộng hơn, thiết kế các hệ thống có thể giải thích và giải thích trở thành một nhu cầu quan trọng. Đặc biệt, khi nói đến hệ thống đối thoại, lập luận của chúng phải là trong sáng suốt và phải tuân theo ý định của con người, để chúng có thể được hoà nhập hoàn hảo vào hoạt động hợp tác của máy móc. Ở đây, chúng tôi mô tả công việc của chúng tôi về một hệ thống đối thoại có mục đích chung, được trang bị một chuyên gia địa phương có khả năng giải thích. Chúng tôi áp dụng hệ thống này vào một nhiệm vụ đặc biệt của việc mô tả cấu hình địa phương của các khối bị trong một miền thể thao đơn giản (BW) sử dụng biểu thức định vị tự nhiên, cũng như tạo ra các lí do cho mô tả về vũ trụ đã đề nghị bằng cách chỉ ra các yếu tố mà hệ thống được dùng để đưa ra một kết luận cụ thể.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>Naarmate AI een bredere adoptie bereikt, wordt het ontwerpen van systemen die uitlegbaar en interpreteerbaar zijn een cruciale noodzaak. Met name als het gaat om dialoogsystemen moet hun redenering transparant zijn en voldoen aan menselijke intuïties, zodat ze naadloos kunnen worden geïntegreerd in de dagelijkse samenwerkingsactiviteiten tussen mens en machine. Hier beschrijven we onze lopende werkzaamheden aan een (algemeen) dialoogsysteem uitgerust met een ruimtelijke specialist met verklarende mogelijkheden. We pasten dit systeem toe op een specifieke taak van het karakteriseren van ruimtelijke configuraties van blokken in een eenvoudig fysiek Blocks World (BW) domein met behulp van natuurlijke locatieve expressies, evenals het genereren van rechtvaardigingen voor de voorgestelde ruimtelijke beschrijvingen door de factoren aan te geven die het systeem gebruikte om tot een bepaalde conclusie te komen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Efterhånden som AI når bredere anvendelse, bliver det en kritisk nødvendighed at designe systemer, der kan forklares og fortolkes. Navnlig når det gælder dialogsystemer, skal deres ræsonnement være gennemsigtige og overholde menneskelige intuitioner, så de kan integreres problemfrit i de daglige samarbejdsaktiviteter mellem mennesker og maskiner. Her beskriver vi vores igangværende arbejde med et (generelt) dialogsystem udstyret med en rumspecialist med forklarende evner. Vi anvendte dette system til en bestemt opgave at karakterisere rumlige konfigurationer af blokke i et simpelt fysisk Blocks World (BW) domæne ved hjælp af naturlige lokaliserede udtryk, samt generere begrundelser for de foreslåede rumlige beskrivelser ved at angive de faktorer, som systemet brugte til at nå frem til en bestemt konklusion.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Ketika AI mencapai adopsi yang lebih luas, desain sistem yang dapat dijelaskan dan diterjemahkan menjadi kebutuhan kritis. Khususnya, ketika hal itu tentang sistem dialog, alasan mereka harus transparan dan harus mematuhi intuisi manusia agar mereka bisa terintegrasi secara terus-menerus dalam aktivitas manusia-mesin kollaboratif sehari-hari. Di sini, kami menggambarkan pekerjaan kami yang sedang berlangsung pada sistem dialog (tujuan umum) yang disediakan dengan spesialis ruang dengan kemampuan penjelasan. Kami menerapkan sistem ini untuk tugas tertentu untuk mengkaraterisasi konfigurasi ruang blok dalam domain fisik Block World (BW) sederhana menggunakan ekspresi lokasi alami, serta menghasilkan alasan untuk deskripsi ruang yang diusulkan dengan menunjukkan faktor yang sistem digunakan untuk mencapai kesimpulan tertentu.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Mit zunehmender Akzeptanz von KI wird die Entwicklung von Systemen, die erklärbar und interpretierbar sind, zu einer kritischen Notwendigkeit. Insbesondere bei Dialogsystemen muss deren Argumentation transparent und menschlicher Intuition entsprechen, damit sie nahtlos in das alltägliche kollaborative Mensch-Maschine-Handeln integriert werden können. Hier beschreiben wir unsere laufende Arbeit an einem (universellen) Dialogsystem, das mit einem erklärenden Raumfachmann ausgestattet ist. Wir haben dieses System auf eine besondere Aufgabe angewendet, räumliche Konfigurationen von Blöcken in einer einfachen physikalischen Blockwelt (BW)-Domäne mittels natürlicher locativer Ausdrücke zu charakterisieren, sowie Begründungen für die vorgeschlagenen räumlichen Beschreibungen zu generieren, indem wir die Faktoren angeben, die das System verwendet hat, um zu einer bestimmten Schlussfolgerung zu gelangen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_bg>Тъй като изкуственият интелект достига по-широко приемане, проектирането на системи, които могат да бъдат обяснени и интерпретирани, става критична необходимост. По-специално, когато става въпрос за системи за диалог, техните разсъждения трябва да бъдат прозрачни и да съответстват на човешките интуиции, за да бъдат интегрирани безпроблемно в ежедневните съвместни дейности между човек и машина. Тук описваме текущата ни работа по система за диалог (общо предназначение), оборудвана с пространствен специалист с обяснителни възможности. Приложихме тази система към конкретна задача за характеризиране на пространствените конфигурации на блокове в прост физически блок свят (БВ) домейн, използвайки естествени локативни изрази, както и генериране на обосновки за предложените пространствени описания чрез посочване на факторите, които системата използва за постигане на конкретно заключение.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Dok AI postigne šire usvajanje, dizajnirajući sustave koje su objašnjive i interpretabilne postaju kritična potreba. Posebno, kad se radi o dijalogskim sustavima, njihovo razmišljanje mora biti transparentno i mora se ispunjavati ljudskim intuicijama kako bi se njih u svakodnevnim aktivnostima u suradnji ljudskih strojeva ne smiješno integrirali. Ovdje opisujemo nastavljajući rad na (općem svrhu) dijalogskom sustavu opremljenom prostornim specijalistom sa objašnjavajućim sposobnostima. Primijenili smo ovaj sustav na posebni zadatak karakteriziranja prostornih konfiguracija blokova u jednostavnom domenu fizičkih blokova svijeta (BW) koristeći prirodne lokativne izraze, kao i stvaranje opravdanja za predložene prostorne opise pokazujući činjenice koje je sustav koristio da dođe do određenog zaključka.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_fa>هنگامی که AI به فرزند فرزندی بیشتری رسید، سیستم‌های طراحی که قابل توضیح و تعبیر قابل توضیح هستند، نیازی مهم‌تر می‌شود. در خصوص، وقتی به سیستم‌های گفتگو رسیده باشد، دلیل‌هایشان باید شفاف باشد و باید به نظرهای انسان پیروی کنند تا آنها را به طور بی‌نظیر در فعالیت‌های انسان و دستگاه‌های همکاری روزی به طور مشکل جمع کنند. در اینجا، ما کارمون را توضیح می دهیم که در یک سیستم گفتگو (هدف عمومی) با یک متخصص فضایی با توانایی توضیح می دهد. ما این سیستم را به یک کار خاصی برای تعریف کردن پیکربندی های فضایی از بلوک های جهانی ساده از بلوک های فیزیکی (BW) با استفاده از توضیح محلی طبیعی استفاده کردیم، و برای توضیح محلی پیشنهاد توضیح دادیم، با نشان دادن faktورهایی که سیستم برای رسیدن به یک نتیجه خاصی استفاده می‌کرد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Wakati AI inapofikia kupitishwa kwa uasili mkubwa, kutengeneza mifumo ambayo inaelezea na kutafsiri inakuwa muhimu. Kwa hakika, inapokuja kwenye mifumo ya mazungumzo, maoni yao lazima iwe wazi na lazima zifuatilie hisia za binadamu ili kuwaunganisha kwa mara nyingi katika shughuli za ushirikiano wa mashine ya binadamu siku za mchana. Hapa, tunaelezea kazi yetu inayoendelea katika mfumo wa mazungumzo ya (kwa ujumla) ulioanzishwa na mtaalam wa anga wenye uwezo wa kuelezea. Tulitumia mfumo huu kwenye jukumu maalum la kuweka mabango ya angani katika eneo rahisi la Blogu Dunia (BW) kwa kutumia maoni ya asili ya asili, pamoja na kutengeneza haki kwa maelezo ya anga yanayopendekezwa kwa kuonyesha sababu ambazo mfumo ulitumika kufikia hitimisho maalum.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>Ndërsa AI arrin miratimin më të gjerë, dizajnimi i sistemeve që janë të shpjeguara dhe të interpretueshme bëhet një nevojë kritike. Në veçanti, kur bëhet fjalë për sistemet e dialogut, arsyetimi i tyre duhet të jetë transparent dhe duhet të përmbushë intuitat njerëzore në mënyrë që ato të integrohen në mënyrë të pandershme në veprimtaritë e përditshme bashkëpunimi njerëzor-makineri. Këtu, ne përshkruajmë punën tonë të vazhdueshme në një sistem dialog (qëllimi i përgjithshëm) të pajisur me një specialist hapësiror me aftësi shpjeguese. Kemi aplikuar këtë sistem në një detyrë të veçantë të karakterizimit të konfigurimeve hapësirore të blloqeve në një domeni të thjeshtë fizike të blloqeve botërore (BW) duke përdorur shprehjet vendndodhëse natyrore, si dhe duke krijuar justifikime për përshkrimet hapësirore të propozuara duke treguar faktorët që sistemi përdorej për të arritur në një përfundim të veçantë</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>AI uly bir adopteýä ulaşýan bolsa, düşündirilebilir we ýarymlanabilir sistemalary düzenlemek wajyp bir gerekli bolar. Adatça, dialoglar sistemalary barada, olaryň düşünseleri transparent bolmaly we adamlaryň düşünjelerini aýyrmaly we günde adam-maşynyň işbirlikçiliklerine garamazlyk bilen birleşmesi üçin. Bu ýerde, taýýarlanan işimizi (umumy maksady) dijalog sistemasynda aydınlaşyk ukyplary bilen birleştirilýäris. Biz bu sistemi bir basit fizikal bloklaryň dünýäde (BW) ýerli ifadeleri ullanýan bloklary taýýarlamak üçin bir taýýarlama taýýarlandyrdyk. we bu sistemi beýleki netijede gelen ýagdaýa golaýat taýýarlamak üçin deňleşdirilip başladyk.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Soos AI breideer aanvaar kom, ontwerp stelsels wat verduidelik is en uittelbare word, word 'n kritiese noodsaaklikheid. Spesifieke, wanneer dit tot dialoog stelsels kom, moet hulle redening deursigtig wees en moet voldoen met menslike intuisies, sodat hulle selfs in dag-totdag-samarbeidende menslike-masjien aktiviteit integreer moet word. Hier, ons beskryf ons voortgaande werk op 'n (algemene doel) dialoog stelsel beskikbaar met 'n spasiele spesialistig met uitduidelike kapasiteite. Ons het hierdie stelsel toegewend na 'n bepaalde taak van die karakterisering van spasiele konfigurasies van blokke in 'n eenvoudige fisiese blokke Wêreld (BW) domein wat natuurlike ligging uitdrukkings gebruik word, en ook die genereering van regverdighede vir die voorgestelde spasiele beskrywings deur die faktore wat die stelsel gebruik het om by 'n bepaalde konklusie te kom.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>As AI reaches wider adoption, designing systems that are explainable and interpretable becomes a critical necessity.  Հատկապես, երբ խոսակցական համակարգերի հետ կապված է, նրանց մտածելակերպը պետք է թափանցիկ լինի և պետք է համապատասխանի մարդկային ինտուիցիաներին, որպեսզի դրանք անընդհատ ներգրավվեն առօրյա համագործակցական մարդկային-մեքենային գործողությունների մեջ: Այստեղ մենք նկարագրում ենք մեր շարունակական աշխատանքը (ընդհանուր նպատակի) երկխոսային համակարգի վրա, որն ունի տարածական մասնագետ բացատրողական հնարավորություններով: Մենք կիրառեցինք այս համակարգը հատուկ խնդրի վրա' բլոկի բլոկի բլոկի համաշխարհի բլոկի բլոկի բլոկի բլոկի բլոկի բլոկի բլոկի բլոկի բնորոշ արտահայտությունների բնորոշ կառուցվածքների բնորոշ կառուցվածքների բնորոշ կառուցվածքների բնոր</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ko>인공지능이 광범위하게 응용됨에 따라 해석 가능하고 해석 가능한 시스템을 설계하는 것이 매우 중요하다.특히 대화 시스템에 있어 이들의 추리는 투명해야 하며, 이를 일상적인 인간과 기계의 협업 활동에 틈새 없이 집적할 수 있도록 인간의 직감에 부합해야 한다.여기서 우리는 우리가 (통용) 대화 시스템에서 진행하고 있는 일을 묘사했다. 이 시스템은 해석 능력을 갖춘 공간 전문가를 갖추고 있다.우리는 이 시스템을 단순 물리 블록 세계(BW) 영역에서 블록의 공간 설정을 자연 위치 표현식으로 설명하고 시스템이 특정한 결론을 얻는 데 사용하는 요소를 지적함으로써 제시된 공간 묘사에 이유를 생성하는 특정한 임무에 적용할 것이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_bn>যেহেতু AI ব্যাপকভাবে সন্তান পৌঁছায়, সেই সিস্টেম যা ব্যাখ্যা এবং ব্যাখ্যা করা যায় তা গুরুত্বপূর্ণ প্রয় বিশেষ করে, যখন এটা আলোচনা ব্যবস্থার কাছে আসে, তখন তাদের কারণ অবশ্যই স্বচ্ছতা এবং মানুষের অনুভূতির সাথে মেনে নিতে হবে, যাতে তাদেরকে দিন-দিনের সহযোগিতা মানব-মে এখানে আমরা আমাদের চলমান কাজের বর্ণনা করছি (সাধারণ উদ্দেশ্য) একটি ডায়ালগ সিস্টেমের উপর যা স্পেশিয়াল বিশেষজ্ঞের সাথে ব্যাখ প্রাকৃতিক স্থানীয় প্রকাশ ব্লক (বিডিউবি) ডোমেইন ব্যবহার করে ব্লকের স্পেশাল কনফিগারেশনের ক্ষেত্রে আমরা এই সিস্টেমের বিশেষ কাজের প্রয়োগ করেছি এবং প্রস্তাবিত স্পেশীয় বর্ণনার জন</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_am>AI ወደ ሰፊ ልጅነት ሲደርስ፣ የሚተረጉና የሚተረጉም ስርዓቶች የሚያስፈልግ ግድ ነው፡፡ በተለይም፣ ወደ ማኅበራዊ ስርዓቶች ሲመጣ አእምሮአቸው ግልፅ እንዲሆን እና ማሰናዊ ልቦችን ለቀኑ ለቀኑ ተጋሪዎች የሰው-machine ተግባር እንዲያስፈልጋቸው ይገባዋል፡፡ እዚህ፣ የሚሄደውን ሥራ (አቀናዊ ጉዳይ) በተቃውሞ የስፖስቲካዊ ባለስልጣናት ማኅበረሰብ ላይ እናሳውቃለን፡፡ ባሕላዊ ቦክቦች (BW) አካባቢ ቋንቋዎችን በመጠቀም እና በተዘጋጀው ስፖስቲካዊ ጽሑፎችን ለመግለጽ በተለየ ስፖስቲካዊ ግንኙነት አካባቢ አካባቢ አካባቢ (BW) አካባቢ አካባቢ አካላትን በመጠቀም እና በተዘጋጀው ስፖስቲካዊ ጽሑፎችን መግለጫ ማስረጃዎችን ለማድረግ እና</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>AI daha geniş adoptiya çatdığında, a çıq-aydın və yorumlayıcı sistemləri təşkil etmək mümkün olduğu qədər kritik ehtiyacı olur. Özellikle, dialoglar sistemlərinə gəldikdə, onların düşüncələri açıq olmalı və insanların düşüncələrinə uymalıdır ki, günlük istifadə edən insan makinesi fəaliyyətlərinə istifadə edilsinlər. Burada, müəyyən edilən işlərimizi a çıq-aydın qabiliyyətlərlə birlikdə uzay bir spesialisti ilə müəyyən edilən (genel məqsəd) dialog sistemində təsdiqləyirik. Biz bu sistemi təbiətli yerli ifadələr istifadə edən basit fizikal bloklar dünyanın (BW) səviyyəsində blokların yer konfigurasiyonlarını tanımlamaq üçün müəyyən bir işə istifadə etdik, həmçin in təklif edilmiş uzay tanımlamaları üçün də təklif etdik. Sistemin müəyyən bir sonuna gəlməsi üçün istifadə etdiyi faktorları göstərdik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>As AI reaches wider adoption, designing systems that are explainable and interpretable becomes a critical necessity.  En particular, quan es tracta dels sistemes de diàleg, el seu raonament ha de ser transparent i ha de conformar-se a les intuïcions humanes per integrar-les de manera incoherenta en activitats cotidianes de col·laboració humana-màquina. Aquí descrivim la nostra feina en curso en un sistema de diàleg (de propòsit general) dotat d'un especialista espacial amb capacitats explicatives. We applied this system to a particular task of characterizing spatial configurations of blocks in a simple physical Blocks World (BW) domain using natural locative expressions, as well as generating justifications for the proposed spatial descriptions by indicating the factors that the system used to arrive at a particular conclusion.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>Dok AI postigne šire usvajanje, dizajnirajući sisteme koje su objašnjive i interpretabilne postaju kritična potreba. Posebno, kad se radi o sistemima dijaloga, njihovo razumjanje mora biti transparentno i mora biti u skladu sa ljudskim intuicijama kako bi se u svakodnevnoj saradnji aktivnosti ljudskih strojeva bezvezno integrirali. Ovdje opisujemo naš nastavljajući rad na (općem cilju) dijalogskom sistemu opremljenom prostornim specijalistom sa objašnjavajućim sposobnostima. Prijavili smo ovaj sistem na određeni zadatak karakteriziranja prostornih konfiguracija blokova u jednostavnom domenu fizičkih blokova svijeta (BW) koristeći prirodne lokativne izraze, kao i stvaranje opravdanja za predložene prostorne opise pokazivajući faktore koje je sistem koristio da dođe do određenog zaključka.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Jak AI dosahuje širšího přijetí, navrhování systémů, které jsou vysvětlitelné a interpretovatelné, se stává kritickou nutností. Zejména pokud jde o systémy dialogu, musí být jejich uvažování transparentní a musí být v souladu s lidskými intuicemi, aby mohly být bezproblémově integrovány do každodenní spolupráce člověk-stroj činnosti. Zde popisujeme naši probíhající práci na (univerzálním) dialogovém systému vybaveném prostorovým specialistou s vysvětlujícími schopnostmi. Tento systém jsme aplikovali na konkrétní úkol charakterizování prostorových konfigurací bloků v jednoduché fyzické oblasti Blokového světa (BW) pomocí přirozených lokačních výrazů a generování odůvodnění navržených prostorových popisů označením faktorů, které systém použil k dosažení konkrétního závěru.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Kuna tehisintellekti kasutuselevõtt ulatub, muutub selgitatavate ja tõlgendatavate süsteemide projekteerimine kriitiliseks vajaduseks. Eelkõige dialoogisüsteemide puhul peavad nende arutlused olema läbipaistvad ja vastama inimese intuitsioonidele, et neid saaks sujuvalt integreerida inimese ja masina igapäevasesse koostöösse. Siin kirjeldame oma käimasolevat tööd (üldotstarbelise) dialoogisüsteemi kallal, mis on varustatud seletusvõimega ruumiaspetsialistiga. Rakendasime seda süsteemi konkreetsele ülesandele kirjeldada plokkide ruumilisi konfiguratsioone lihtsas füüsilises Blocks World (BW) domeenis, kasutades looduslikke lokaatorväljendeid, samuti põhjendada kavandatud ruumilisi kirjeldusi, näidates faktoreid, mida süsteem kasutas konkreetse järelduseni jõudmiseks.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tekoälyn yleistyessä selitettävien ja ymmärrettävien järjestelmien suunnittelusta tulee ratkaiseva tarve. Erityisesti vuoropuhelujärjestelmien perustelujen on oltava avoimia ja ihmisten intuitioiden mukaisia, jotta ne voidaan integroida saumattomasti ihmisen ja koneen päivittäiseen yhteistyöhön. Tässä kuvataan meneillään olevaa työtämme (yleiskäyttöisen) dialogijärjestelmän parissa, jossa on selittävä asiantuntija. Sovellimme tätä järjestelmää erityiseen tehtävään karakterisoida lohkojen spatiaalisia konfiguraatioita yksinkertaisella fyysisellä lohkomaailmauksella käyttäen luonnollisia paikannuslausekkeita sekä tuottaa perusteluja ehdotetuille paikkatietokuvauksille osoittamalla tekijät, joita järjestelmä käytti tietyn päätelmän tekemiseen.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Alé AI wis rampung nggunaké awak dhéwé, nggawe sistem sing bisa ditambah lan ijol-ijolan kuwi adir-ijolan kudu nggawe barang dhéwé. Awak dhéwé, pas kuwi nggo sistem dialog, akeh sabanjuré iki luwih kanggo ngerasakno karo titip-titip wong liyane, bisa mbelaké awak dhéwé beraksi iki ning acara awak dhéwé ning acara sampek liyane karo sistem sing beraksi barêng-barêng. (General goal) Awak dhéwé nggawe sistem iki ning kelas pengguna nggawe barang-barang nggawe barang nggawe barang blocks ning Ketok Munggo perusahaan (BWK), dadi akèh sistem sistem sing nyimpen macem gawe lan akeh nggawe justifications nggawe winih dhéwé, uga nggawe nyimpen winih sing berarti ujaran cara nggawe barang nggawe sistem sadurunggawe barang akeh ber</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Kama da AI ya kai koɗabi'in faɗi, za'a danne tsarin da za'a bayyana shi da za'a fassara, sai ya zama muhimu. Kuma da ƙayyadadde, idan za ta zo zuwa masu kallo na zauren akwatin bayani, sai ka buƙata masu bayyani kuma ya kamata su yi yarda da ma'anar mutane, dõmin a haɗa su a ƙidãya ko yau cikin aikin mutane na ƙarami. A nan, muna bayyana aikinmu wanda ke tafiya a kan wani na'urar zauren akwatin bayani na zauren (gabani) wanda yana da wani masu ƙayyade na spaitũ da abinci mai fassara. Mun applied wannan na'ura zuwa wani aikin da aka ƙayyade tsarin spaspaspati na block in a wuri mai sauƙi na Blocks World (BW) da ke amfani da magana masu lokaci, da kuma Mu ƙãga masu justifiɗa wa fassarar da aka buƙata da shi, ana nũna masu fakta da system ke amfani da su zuwa wani ƙarshen ƙayyade.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Ko umetna inteligenca doseže širšo sprejetje, postane oblikovanje sistemov, ki so razložljivi in razložljivi, ključna nuja. Zlasti ko gre za sisteme dialoga, mora biti njihovo razmišljanje pregledno in v skladu s človeškimi intuicijami, da se lahko brezhibno vključijo v vsakodnevne sodelovalne dejavnosti med človekom in strojem. Tukaj opisujemo naše stalno delo na (splošnem) dialognem sistemu, opremljenem s prostorskim specialistom z pojasnjevalnimi zmožnostmi. Ta sistem smo uporabili za določeno nalogo označevanja prostorskih konfiguracij blokov v preprosti fizični domeni blokov sveta (BW) z uporabo naravnih lokacijskih izrazov ter ustvarjanja utemeljitev predlaganih prostorskih opisov z navedbo dejavnikov, s katerimi je sistem prišel do določenega sklepa.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>ככל שאי.איי. מגיעה לאימוץ רחב יותר, מעצב מערכות שיכולות להסביר ולהפרש הופך לצורך קריטי. במיוחד, כשמדובר במערכות דיאלוג, ההיגיון שלהם חייב להיות שקט ויצטרך להתאים לאינטואיציות אנושיות כדי שהם יוכלו להיות מושלמים באופן בלתי מתאים לפעילות משותפת יומית של מכונות אנושיות. כאן, אנו מתארים את העבודה הממשיכת שלנו על מערכת דיאלוג (מטרה כללית) מוכשרת במומחה חללית עם יכולות הסבירות. שימשנו את המערכת הזאת למשימה מסויימת של תיאור התסדרות חלליות של בלוקים בתחום פיזי בלוקים עולם פשוט (BW) בשימוש ביטויים מקומיים טבעיים, כמו גם לייצר תיאורים לתיאורים חלליים המוצעים על ידי המצב של הגורמים שהמערכת השתמשה כדי להגיע למסקנה מסויימת.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>AI་གིས་ཞུགས་པ་ཆེ་རུ་གཏོང་བྱེད་རྒྱུ་དང་། སྔོན་དུ་གསལ་བཤད་ནུས་དང་འགྲེལ་བཤད་ནུས་ཡོད་པའི་ལག་ལེན་གྱི་ཆེད ཁྱད་པར་ན། ཌའི་ལོ་རིམ་དང་འཆར་གཞུང་ལ་བྱུང་བའི་སྐབས་ཁོང་ཚོའི་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་ནི་ཡིན་པ་ལས་འཕགས་པ་ཞིག་ཡིན་པའི་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་འདུག འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་དུས་ཡོད་པའི་ལཱ་གཡོག་འགོད་པའི་གླེང་སྒྲོམ་གྱི་མ་ལག་གི་ཐོག ང་ཚོས་མ་ལག་འདི་ལྟར་འཆར་བཀོད་སྟངས་དམིགས་ཀྱི་ལས་འགུལ་གསལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་གྲོང་གླིང་འཛམ་གླིང་ནང་ལས།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Why Should I Turn Left? Towards Active Explainability for Spoken Dialogue Systems.<fixed-case>I</fixed-case> Turn Left? Towards Active Explainability for Spoken Dialogue Systems.</title>
      <author><first>Vladislav</first><last>Maraev</last></author>
      <author><first>Ellen</first><last>Breitholtz</last></author>
      <author><first>Christine</first><last>Howes</last></author>
      <author><first>Jean-Philippe</first><last>Bernardy</last></author>
      <pages>58–64</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we argue that to make dialogue systems able to actively explain their decisions they can make use of enthymematic reasoning. We motivate why this is an appropriate strategy and integrate it within our own proof-theoretic dialogue manager framework based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_logic">linear logic</a>. In particular, this enables a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue_system">dialogue system</a> to provide reasonable answers to why-questions that query information previously given by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="de99a229">2021.reinact-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>maraev-2021-turn</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>