<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.dravidianlangtech">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-04-19">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Speech and Language Technologies for Dravidian Languages</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ruba</first><last>Priyadharshini</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anand</first><last>Kumar M</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Parameswari</first><last>Krishnamurthy</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Sherly</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Kyiv</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="b92e3684">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>dravidianlangtech-2021-speech</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Towards Offensive Language Identification for Dravidian Languages<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian Languages</title>
      <author><first>Siva</first><last>Sai</last></author>
      <author><first>Yashvardhan</first><last>Sharma</last></author>
      <pages>18–27</pages>
      <abstract>Offensive speech identification in countries like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/India">India</a> poses several challenges due to the usage of code-mixed and romanized variants of multiple languages by the users in their posts on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. The challenge of offensive language identification on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian languages</a> is harder, considering the low resources available for the same. In this paper, we explored the zero-shot learning and few-shot learning paradigms based on multilingual language models for offensive speech detection in code-mixed and romanized variants of three Dravidian languages-Malayalam, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a>. We propose a novel and flexible approach of selective translation and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transliteration">transliteration</a> to reap better results from fine-tuning and ensembling multilingual transformer networks like XLMRoBERTa and mBERT. We implemented pretrained, fine-tuned, and ensembled versions of XLM-RoBERTa for offensive speech classification. Further, we experimented with interlanguage, inter-task, and multi-task transfer learning techniques to leverage the rich resources available for offensive speech identification in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English language</a> and to enrich the models with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_transfer">knowledge transfer</a> from related tasks. The proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> yielded good results and are promising for effective offensive speech identification in low resource settings.</abstract>
      <url hash="3f6afca2">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.3</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="08081334">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.3.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>sai-sharma-2021-towards</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/sivaandme/tolidl_dravidianlangtech_eacl_2021" additional="false">sivaandme/tolidl_dravidianlangtech_eacl_2021</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Sentiment Classification of Code-Mixed Tweets using Bi-Directional RNN and Language Tags<fixed-case>RNN</fixed-case> and Language Tags</title>
      <author><first>Sainik</first><last>Mahata</last></author>
      <author><first>Dipankar</first><last>Das</last></author>
      <author><first>Sivaji</first><last>Bandyopadhyay</last></author>
      <pages>28–35</pages>
      <abstract>Sentiment analysis tools and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> have been developed extensively throughout the years, for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_Europe">European languages</a>. In contrast, similar <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tool">tools</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_India">Indian Languages</a> are scarce. This is because, state-of-the-art pre-processing tools like POS tagger, shallow parsers, etc., are not readily available for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_India">Indian languages</a>. Although, such working tools for Indian languages, like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bengali_language">Bengali</a>, that are spoken by the majority of the population, are available, finding the same for less spoken languages like, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, is difficult. Moreover, due to the advent of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>, the multi-lingual population of India, who are comfortable with both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> ad their regional language, prefer to communicate by mixing both languages. This gives rise to massive code-mixed content and automatically annotating them with their respective sentiment labels becomes a challenging task. In this work, we take up a similar challenge of developing a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis model</a> that can work with English-Tamil code-mixed data. The proposed work tries to solve this by using bi-directional LSTMs along with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tag_(metadata)">language tagging</a>. Other traditional methods, based on classical machine learning algorithms have also been discussed in the literature, and they also act as the baseline systems to which we will compare our Neural Network based model. The performance of the developed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a>, based on Neural Network architecture, garnered <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">precision</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a>, and F1 scores of 0.59, 0.66, and 0.58 respectively.</abstract>
      <url hash="c9f9f121">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.4</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="f31cfd86">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.4.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>mahata-etal-2021-sentiment</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Task-Oriented Dialog Systems for Dravidian Languages<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian Languages</title>
      <author><first>Tushar</first><last>Kanakagiri</last></author>
      <author><first>Karthik</first><last>Radhakrishnan</last></author>
      <pages>85–93</pages>
      <abstract>Task-oriented dialog systems help a user achieve a particular goal by parsing user requests to execute a particular action. These systems typically require copious amounts of training data to effectively understand the user intent and its corresponding slots. Acquiring large training corpora requires significant manual effort in annotation, rendering its construction infeasible for low-resource languages. In this paper, we present a two-step approach for automatically constructing task-oriented dialogue data in such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Programming_language">languages</a> by making use of annotated data from high resource languages. First, we use a machine translation (MT) system to translate the utterance and slot information to the target language. Second, we use token prefix matching and mBERT based semantic matching to align the slot tokens to the corresponding tokens in the utterance. We hand-curate a new test dataset in two low-resource Dravidian languages and show the significance and impact of our training dataset construction using a state-of-the-art mBERT model-achieving a Slot F1 of 81.51 (Kannada) and 78.82 (Tamil) on our test sets.</abstract>
      <url hash="9a041745">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.11</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="4029e3a8">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.11.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>kanakagiri-radhakrishnan-2021-task</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>A Survey on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paralinguistics">Paralinguistics</a> in Tamil Speech Processing<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>amil Speech Processing</title>
      <author><first>Anosha</first><last>Ignatius</last></author>
      <author><first>Uthayasanker</first><last>Thayasivam</last></author>
      <pages>94–99</pages>
      <abstract>Speech carries not only the semantic content but also the paralinguistic information which captures the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Style_(sociolinguistics)">speaking style</a>. Speaker traits and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotional states</a> affect how words are being spoken. The research on paralinguistic information is an emerging field in speech and language processing and it has many potential applications including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">speech recognition</a>, speaker identification and verification, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_recognition">emotion recognition</a> and accent recognition. Among them, there is a significant interest in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_recognition">emotion recognition</a> from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech">speech</a>. A detailed study of paralinguistic information present in speech signal and an overview of research work related to speech emotion for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil Language</a> is presented in this paper.</abstract>
      <url hash="783d58b8">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>ignatius-thayasivam-2021-survey</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Is this Enough?-Evaluation of Malayalam Wordnet<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>alayalam <fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ordnet</title>
      <author><first>Nandu</first><last>Chandran Nair</last></author>
      <author><first>Maria-chiara</first><last>Giangregorio</last></author>
      <author><first>Fausto</first><last>Giunchiglia</last></author>
      <pages>100–108</pages>
      <abstract>Quality of a product is the degree to which a product meets the customer’s expectation, which must also be valid for the case of lexical semantic resources. Conducting a periodic evaluation of resources is essential to ensure if the resources meet a native speaker’s expectations and free from errors. This paper defines the possible mistakes in a lexical semantic resource and explains the steps applied to quantify Malayalam wordnet quality. Malayalam is one of the classical languages of India. We hope to subset the less quality part of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wordnet">wordnet</a> and perform <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crowdsourcing">crowdsourcing</a> to make it better.</abstract>
      <url hash="c0828890">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.13</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="ce1a16a2">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.13.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>chandran-nair-etal-2021-enough</bibkey>
    <title_ar>هل هذا يكفي؟ - تقييم المالايالامية Wordnet</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Isso é suficiente?-Avaliação de Malayalam Wordnet</title_pt>
      <title_es>¿Es esto suficiente? -Evaluación de Wordnet en malayalam</title_es>
      <title_ja>これで十分ですか？-マラヤーラム語ワードネットの評価</title_ja>
      <title_zh>足乎?-马拉雅拉姆语Wordnet之评也</title_zh>
      <title_hi>क्या यह पर्याप्त है?</title_hi>
      <title_ga>An leor é seo? -Meastóireacht ar Wordnet Mailéalaimis</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ეჲჟრარყფნჲ ლთ ვ? Malayalam WordnetName</title_ka>
      <title_el>Φτάνει αυτό; Αξιολόγηση του Malayalam Wordnet</title_el>
      <title_hu>Ez elég? A Malayalam Wordnet értékelése</title_hu>
      <title_it>È abbastanza?- Valutazione di Malayalam Wordnet</title_it>
      <title_lt>Ar tai pakanka? Malayalam Wordnet vertinimas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Доста ли е ова? Оценка на Malayalam Wordnet</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Is this Enough?- Penghargaan Malayalam Wordnet</title_ms>
      <title_kk>Бұл жеткілікті пе? Malayalam Wordnet оқу</title_kk>
      <title_ml>ഇത് മതി? മാലായലാം വാര്‍ഡ്നെറ്റിന്റെ പ്രക്രിയയം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Dan huwa biżżejjed?- Evalwazzjoni tal-Malayalam Wordnet</title_mt>
      <title_no>Er dette nok? Evaluering av Malayalam Wordnet</title_no>
      <title_pl>Czy to wystarczy? Ocena Malayalam Wordnet</title_pl>
      <title_mn>Энэ хангалттай уу? Malayalam Wordnet-ын үнэлгээ</title_mn>
      <title_ro>E de ajuns? Evaluarea Malayalam Wordnet</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Je li ovo dovoljno? Evaluacija Malayalama Wordneta</title_sr>
      <title_si>මේක ඇති? Name</title_si>
      <title_so>Tani ma kugu filan?- Qiimeynta hadalka Malayalam</title_so>
      <title_sv>Är det här tillräckligt? Utvärdering av Malayalam Wordnet</title_sv>
      <title_ta>இது போதுமா? Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>یہ کافی ہے؟ Malayalam Wordnet کی ارزش</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Bu yetarli emas?- Malayalam soʻzni tasdiqlash</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Có đủ không? Đánh giá Malayaủng Wordet</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Is dit genoeg? Evaluatie van Malayalam Wordnet</title_nl>
      <title_da>Er det nok? Evaluering af Malayalam Wordnet</title_da>
      <title_de>Ist das genug?- Bewertung von Malayalam Wordnet</title_de>
      <title_hr>Je li ovo dovoljno? Evaluacija Malayalama Wordneta</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Достатъчно ли е? Оценка на Малаялам Wordnet</title_bg>
      <title_ko>이 정도면 됐어-Malayalam Wordnet 평가</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Hii inatosha?- Uthibitisho wa neno la Malayalam</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Bu ýetermi? Malayalam Wordnet ýagdaýyny çykmak</title_tr>
      <title_id>Apakah ini Cukup? Evaluasi Malayalam Wordnet</title_id>
      <title_fa>اين کافيه؟ ارزیابی Malayalam Wordnet</title_fa>
      <title_sq>A mjafton kjo? Vlerësimi i Malayalam Wordnet</title_sq>
      <title_am>ይበቃልን? ማላይላም ቃላት</title_am>
      <title_hy>Արդյո՞ք դա բավարար է: Մալայալամ Wordnet-ի գնահատումը</title_hy>
      <title_bs>Je li ovo dovoljno? Evaluacija Malayalama Wordneta</title_bs>
      <title_az>Bu yet톛r mi? Malayalam Wordnet qiym톛ti</title_az>
      <title_bn>এটা কি যথেষ্ট? মালায়ালাম ওয়ার্ডনেটের মূল্যায়ন</title_bn>
      <title_af>Is dit genoeg? Evalueer van Malayalam Wordnet</title_af>
      <title_et>Kas sellest piisab?- Malajalami Wordneti hindamine</title_et>
      <title_cs>Je to dost? Hodnocení Malayalamu Wordnet</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Onko tämä tarpeeksi? - Malayalam Wordnetin arviointi</title_fi>
      <title_ca>És prou? Evaluació de Malayalam Wordnet</title_ca>
      <title_jv>Kuwi ngene ? Language</title_jv>
      <title_ha>Ashe, kuma yã isa? Evaluation of Malayalam Wordnet</title_ha>
      <title_bo>འདི་ལྷག་པ་ཡིན་ནམ། Malayalam Wordnet ཡི་ཚད་ལྡན་གྲངས</title_bo>
      <title_sk>Je to dovolj? - Ocena malajalamskega Wordneta</title_sk>
      <title_he>זה מספיק? הערכה של Malayalam Wordnet</title_he>
      <abstract_pt>Qualidade de um produto é o grau em que um produto atende a expectativa do cliente, o que também deve ser válido para o caso de recursos semânticos lexicais. A realização de uma avaliação periódica dos recursos é essencial para garantir que os recursos atendam às expectativas de um falante nativo e estejam livres de erros. Este artigo define os possíveis erros em um recurso semântico lexical e explica as etapas aplicadas para quantificar a qualidade da rede de palavras Malayalam. Malayalam é uma das línguas clássicas da Índia. Esperamos dividir a parte de menor qualidade do wordnet e realizar o crowdsourcing para torná-lo melhor.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>جودة المنتج هي الدرجة التي يلبي بها المنتج توقعات العميل ، والتي يجب أن تكون صالحة أيضًا في حالة الموارد الدلالية المعجمية. يعد إجراء تقييم دوري للموارد أمرًا ضروريًا للتأكد من أن الموارد تلبي توقعات المتحدث الأصلي وخالية من الأخطاء. تحدد هذه الورقة الأخطاء المحتملة في المورد الدلالي المعجمي وتشرح الخطوات المطبقة لتحديد جودة الكلمات المالايالامية. المالايالامية هي إحدى اللغات الكلاسيكية في الهند. نأمل أن نضع الجزء الأقل جودة من wordnet وأداء التعهيد الجماعي لجعله أفضل.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>La calidad de un producto es el grado en que un producto cumple con las expectativas del cliente, lo que también debe ser válido para el caso de los recursos semánticos léxicos. Llevar a cabo una evaluación periódica de los recursos es esencial para garantizar que los recursos cumplan con las expectativas de un hablante nativo y estén libres de errores. Este artículo define los posibles errores en un recurso semántico léxico y explica los pasos aplicados para cuantificar la calidad de wordnet en malayalam. El malayalam es uno de los idiomas clásicos de la India. Esperamos crear subconjuntos de la parte de menor calidad de la wordnet y realizar crowdsourcing para mejorarla.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>製品の品質とは、製品が顧客の期待を満たす度合いです。これは、語彙的意味リソースの場合にも有効でなければなりません。リソースを定期的に評価することは、リソースがネイティブスピーカーの期待を満たし、エラーがないことを保証するために不可欠です。この論文では、語彙的意味論的リソースにおける可能性のある間違いを定義し、マラヤーラム語のワードネット品質を定量化するために適用されるステップを説明した。マラヤーラム語（マラヤーラムご）は、インドの古典語のひとつ。私たちは、ワードネットの品質の低い部分をサブセットし、それを改善するためにクラウドソーシングを実行することを望んでいます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>产品之质,客户所望,词汇语义资必效。 定期质于保母语人士之期无过。 本文定义词汇语义资源之误,并解量化马拉雅拉姆语词网之步骤。 马拉雅拉姆语者,印度古典语之一也。 愿子集wordnet中,行众包以益之。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>एक उत्पाद की गुणवत्ता वह डिग्री है जिस पर एक उत्पाद ग्राहक की अपेक्षा को पूरा करता है, जो लेक्सिकल शब्दार्थ संसाधनों के मामले के लिए भी मान्य होना चाहिए। संसाधनों का आवधिक मूल्यांकन करना यह सुनिश्चित करने के लिए आवश्यक है कि संसाधन एक देशी वक्ता की अपेक्षाओं को पूरा करते हैं और त्रुटियों से मुक्त होते हैं या नहीं। यह पेपर एक लेक्सिकल शब्दार्थ संसाधन में संभावित गलतियों को परिभाषित करता है और मलयालम वर्डनेट गुणवत्ता को मापने के लिए लागू चरणों की व्याख्या करता है। मलयालम भारत की शास्त्रीय भाषाओं में से एक है। हम वर्डनेट के कम गुणवत्ता वाले हिस्से को सबसेट करने और इसे बेहतर बनाने के लिए क्राउडसोर्सिंग करने की उम्मीद करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Is éard atá i gcáilíocht táirge ná an méid a chomhlíonann táirge ionchas an chustaiméara, a chaithfidh a bheith bailí freisin i gcás acmhainní shéimeantacha léacsúla. Tá sé ríthábhachtach meastóireacht thréimhsiúil a dhéanamh ar acmhainní lena chinntiú an gcomhlíonann na hacmhainní ionchais an chainteora dúchais agus saor ó earráidí. Sainmhíníonn an páipéar seo na botúin a d’fhéadfadh a bheith in acmhainn shéimeantach léacsach agus mínítear na céimeanna a cuireadh i bhfeidhm chun cáilíocht wordnet Mailéalaimis a chainníochtú. Tá Mailéalaimis ar cheann de theangacha clasaiceacha na hIndia. Tá súil againn an chuid den wordnet nach bhfuil chomh mór sin a fho-chur agus sluafhoinsiú a dhéanamh chun é a fheabhsú.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>A termék minősége az a mérték, hogy a termék megfelel a vevő elvárásainak, amelynek a lexikai szemantikai erőforrások esetében is érvényesnek kell lennie. Az erőforrások rendszeres értékelése elengedhetetlen annak biztosításához, hogy az erőforrások megfelelnek-e az anyanyelvű elvárásoknak és hibáktól mentesek-e. Ez a tanulmány meghatározza a lexikai szemantikai erőforrások esetleges hibáit, és elmagyarázza, hogy milyen lépéseket alkalmaznak a malayalam szóhálózat minőségének számszerűsítésére. A Malayalam India egyik klasszikus nyelve. Reméljük, hogy a wordnet kevésbé minőségi részét alá tudjuk állítani és közösségi forrásokat végezni, hogy jobb legyen.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Η ποιότητα ενός προϊόντος είναι ο βαθμός στον οποίο ένα προϊόν ανταποκρίνεται στις προσδοκίες του πελάτη, ο οποίος πρέπει επίσης να ισχύει στην περίπτωση των λεξικών σημασιολογικών πόρων. Η διεξαγωγή περιοδικής αξιολόγησης των πόρων είναι απαραίτητη για να διασφαλιστεί αν οι πόροι ανταποκρίνονται στις προσδοκίες ενός φυσικού ομιλητή και δεν περιέχουν λάθη. Η παρούσα εργασία καθορίζει τα πιθανά λάθη σε έναν λεξικό σημασιολογικό πόρο και εξηγεί τα βήματα που εφαρμόζονται για τον ποσοτικό προσδιορισμό της ποιότητας του λεξικού. Τα Μαλαγιάλαμ είναι μια από τις κλασικές γλώσσες της Ινδίας. Ελπίζουμε να υποσύνουμε το λιγότερο ποιοτικό μέρος του κειμένου και να εκτελέσουμε για να το κάνουμε καλύτερο.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>პროდისტის კოლექტური კოლექტური კოლექტური კოლექტურის განსაზღვრება, რომელიც უნდა იყოს სწორედ ლექსიკალური სმენტიკური რესურსის შესახებ. რესურსის პერიოდიკური განსაზღვრება მნიშვნელოვანია, რომ დარწმუნოთ, თუ რესურსები შეუძლებელია მართალის განსაზღვრება და შეცდომიდან თავისუფალი. ამ დოკუნტის შესაძლებელი შეცდომები ლექსიკალური სიმენტიკური რესურსში განსაზღვრებს და განახსენებს მალაიალური სიმბოლოების კვანტიფიკაციაში გამოყენებული ნაწი მალაიალამ იყო ინდოეთის კლასიკური ენების ერთი. ნაეწგამვ ჟვ, ფვ ღვ ოჲეკლძფთმ ოჲ-მალკჲ კალთრვლნჲრჲ ფაჟრჲ ნა ჟლსფაინჲრჲ მწჟრჲ თ ღვ ოპაგთმ ოსბლსკსპჟთპანვ, ჱა ეა დჲ ნაოპაგთ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Qualità di un prodotto è il grado in cui un prodotto soddisfa le aspettative del cliente, che deve essere valido anche nel caso delle risorse semantiche lessicali. Effettuare una valutazione periodica delle risorse è essenziale per garantire che le risorse soddisfino le aspettative di un madrelingua e siano esenti da errori. Questo articolo definisce i possibili errori in una risorsa semantica lessicale e spiega i passaggi applicati per quantificare la qualità del wordnet Malayalam. Malayalam è una delle lingue classiche dell'India. Speriamo di sottomettere la parte meno qualità del wordnet ed eseguire crowdsourcing per renderlo migliore.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Квалитетот на производот е степенот во кој производот ги исполнува очекувањата на клиентот, што мора да биде валидно и за случајот на лексичките семантични ресурси. Conducting a periodic evaluation of resources is essential to ensure if the resources meet a native speaker's expectations and free from errors.  Оваа хартија ги дефинира можните грешки во лексичкиот семантичен ресурс и ги објаснува чекорите што се применуваат за квантификување на квалитетот на малјајајанскиот збор. Малајалам е еден од класичните јазици на Индија. Се надеваме дека ќе го потсетиме помалку квалитетниот дел од зборот и ќе извршиме пулсорсирање за да го подобриме тоа.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Quality of a product is the degree to which a product meets the customer's expectation, which must also be valid for the case of lexical semantic resources.  Siekiant užtikrinti, kad ištekliai atitiktų vietinio kalbėtojo lūkesčius ir nebūtų klaidų, būtina periodiškai įvertinti išteklius. Šiame dokumente apibrėžiamos galimos klaidos, susijusios su leksiniu semantiniu ištekliu, ir paaiškinami veiksmai, taikomi siekiant kiekybiškai įvertinti Malaijos žodžių kokybę. Malailamas yra viena iš klasikinių Indijos kalbų. Tikimės sutelkti mažiau kokybišką žodžio dalį ir vykdyti visuomenės išteklius, kad ji būtų geresnė.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Kualiti produk adalah darjah yang mana produk memenuhi harapan pelanggan, yang juga mesti sah untuk kes sumber semantik leksikal. Melakukan penilaian periodik sumber adalah penting untuk memastikan jika sumber memenuhi harapan pembicara asli dan bebas dari ralat. This paper defines the possible mistakes in a lexical semantic resource and explains the steps applied to quantify Malayalam wordnet quality.  Malayalam adalah salah satu bahasa klasik India. Kami berharap untuk menentukan bahagian yang kurang kualiti dari kata-kata dan melakukan crowdsourcing untuk membuatnya lebih baik.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഒരു ഉല്‍പാദ്യത്തിന്റെ ഗുണവും കസ്റ്ററുടെ പ്രതീക്ഷ കാണുന്ന ഒരു ക്രീഡിയാണ്. അതും ലെക്സിക്സിക്കല്‍ സെമാന്റിക് വിഭവങ്ങളുടെ കേ വിഭവങ്ങളുടെ പ്രതീക്ഷയും പിശകുകളില്‍ നിന്നും സ്വതന്ത്ര്യങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടെത്തുകയും ചെയ്യുന്നുവോ എന്ന് ഉറപ്പ് വരുത്തുന്നതിന് വി This paper defines the possible mistakes in a lexical semantic resource and explains the steps applied to quantify Malayalam wordnet quality.  മലക്കാലം ഇന്ത്യയുടെ ക്ലാസിക്കല്‍ ഭാഷകളില്‍ ഒരാളാണ്. ഈ വാര്‍ഡെറ്റിന്റെ കുറച്ച് കുറച്ച് ഗുണവും കീഴ്പ്പെടുത്തുമെന്ന് നമുക്ക് പ്രതീക്ഷിക്കുന്നു. അത്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-kwalità ta’ prodott hija l-grad s a fejn prodott jissodisfa l-aspettattiva tal-klijent, li għandu jkun validu wkoll għall-każ ta’ riżorsi semantiċi lexiċi. It-twettiq ta’ evalwazzjoni perjodika tar-riżorsi huwa essenzjali biex jiġi żgurat jekk ir-riżorsi jissodisfawx l-aspettattivi ta’ kelliem nattiv u ħielsa minn żbalji. Dan id-dokument jiddefinixxi l-iżbalji possibbli f’riżorsa semantika lexika u jispjega l-passi applikati għall-kwantifikazzjoni tal-kwalità tal-kliem tal-Malasja. Malayalam is one of the classical languages of India.  Nittamaw li jissottomettu l-parti inqas ta' kwalità tal-kliem u nagħmlu crowdsourcing biex jagħmluha aħjar.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Jakość produktu to stopień, w jakim produkt spełnia oczekiwania klienta, co musi być również ważne w przypadku leksykalnych zasobów semantycznych. Przeprowadzanie okresowej oceny zasobów jest niezbędne, aby upewnić się, że zasoby spełniają oczekiwania native speakera i wolne od błędów. Niniejszy artykuł określa możliwe błędy w leksykalnym zasobie semantycznym i wyjaśnia kroki stosowane do ilościowego określenia jakości słowa Malayalam. Malajalam jest jednym z klasycznych języków Indii. Mamy nadzieję, że podzestawimy mniej jakościową część Wordnetu i wykonamy crowdsourcing, aby uczynić ją lepszą.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_kk>Продуктың сапасы - продукттың клиентінің күту күтуінің деңгейіне сәйкес келетін градусы. Бұл лексикалық семантикалық ресурстар үшін де дұрыс болу керек. Ресурстардың күтпеген және қателерден бос болуын тексеру үшін кейбірдегі ресурстарды бағалау керек. Бұл қағаз лексикалық семантикалық ресурстағы мүмкін қателерді анықтайды және Малайям сөз сапасының көптеген қадамдарын түсіндіреді. Малайям - Индияның классикалық тілдерінің бірі. Біз сөздердің сапаттық бөлігін төмендету үшін көпшілігін жақсарту үшін көпшілік көпшілігін жасауға болады деп үміттенеміз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_sr>Kvaliteta proizvoda je stepen na koji proizvod ispunjava očekivanje klijenta, koji takođe mora biti validan za slučaj leksičkih semantičkih resursa. Povedenje periodične procjene resursa je važno da se osigura da li resursi ispunjavaju očekivanja prirodnog govornika i besplatne od grešaka. Ovaj papir definiše moguće greške u leksičkom semantičkom resursu i objašnjava korake primjenjene za kvantifikaciju kvalitete vrijednosti Malajalama. Malajalam je jedan od klasičnih jezika Indije. Nadamo se da ćemo podnijeti manje kvalitetni deo rečenog i izvršiti većinu društva kako bi ga poboljšali.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_no>Kvaliteten på eit produkt er graden til at eit produkt møter forventinga på klienten, som også må vera gyldig for tilfellet på leksiske semantiske ressursar. Å gjera ein periodisk evaluering av ressursar er nødvendig for å sikre at ressursane møtar forventingar til ein native taler og ledig frå feil. Denne papiret definerer dei moglege feilene i eit leksisk semantisk ressurs og forklarer kor steg som vert brukt til kvantifikasjon av Malayalam- ordkvalitet. Malayalam er ein av dei klassiske språka i India. Vi håper å undersøke den mindre kvalitetdelen av ordlista og utføre crowdsourcing for å gjera det bedre.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Calitatea unui produs este gradul în care un produs îndeplinește așteptările clientului, care trebuie să fie valabil și în cazul resurselor semantice lexicale. Efectuarea unei evaluări periodice a resurselor este esențială pentru a se asigura că resursele corespund așteptărilor unui vorbitor nativ și nu conțin erori. Această lucrare definește posibilele greșeli într-o resursă semantică lexicală și explică pașii aplicați pentru cuantificarea calității cuvintelor malayalam. Malayalam este una dintre limbile clasice din India. Sperăm să subestimăm partea mai puțin calitate a wordnet-ului și să efectuăm crowdsourcing pentru a o face mai bună.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mn>Бүтээгдэхүүний сайн чанар нь хэрэглэгчдийн хүлээн зөвшөөрөх хэмжээтэй тэнцүү хэмжээг юм. Энэ нь лексикийн semantic нөөц боломжтой байх ёстой. Магадгүй баялаг баялаг үнэлэх нь эх орнуудын илтгэгчийн хүлээн зөвшөөрөх болон алдаасаа чөлөөлөх боломжтой байх нь чухал. Энэ цаас лексикийн хэмжээний баялаг дээр боломжтой алдаа тодорхойлж, Малайамын хэмжээний үнэ цэнэтэй хэмжээнд хэрэглэгдсэн алдаа тайлбарладаг. Малайям бол Энэтхэгийн классик хэл. Бид илүү сайжруулахын тулд үнэтэй хэсгийг багасгаж, олон нийтийн асуудал хийх гэж найдаж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_si>ප්‍රතිපත්තියේ ප්‍රතිපත්තිය තමයි ප්‍රතිපත්තියක් ග්‍රාහකයාගේ බලාපොරොත්තුව සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න ප්‍රතිපත්තිය, ඒක තම මුළුවන්ගේ අවශ්‍ය විශ්ලේෂණයක් නිර්මාණය කරන්න අවශ්‍ය විශ්ලේෂණයක් නිර්මාණය කරනවා මුළුවන්ගේ ප්‍රශ් මේ පැත්තේ ලෙක්සිකාලික සාමාන්තික ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්න පුළුවන් වැරැද්දක් විශ්වාස කරනවා සහ මලායාලාම් වච මලයාලාම් තමයි ඉන්දියාවේ සාමාන්‍ය භාෂාවල් එකක්. අපි බලාපොරොත්තු කරනවා වර්ඩ්නේට් වලින් වලින් ප්‍රශ්ණතාවක් අඩු කොටස් සම්බන්ධ කරනවා ඒක හොඳට කරග</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Kvalitet på en produkt är den grad i vilken en produkt uppfyller kundens förväntningar, vilket också måste gälla för lexikala semantiska resurser. Att genomföra en periodisk utvärdering av resurser är viktigt för att säkerställa att resurserna uppfyller en infödd talares förväntningar och är fria från fel. Denna uppsats definierar möjliga misstag i en lexikal semantisk resurs och förklarar de steg som tillämpas för att kvantifiera Malayalam wordnet kvalitet. Malayalam är ett av de klassiska språken i Indien. Vi hoppas kunna undersätta den mindre kvalitetsdelen av wordnet och utföra crowdsourcing för att göra det bättre.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Takhasuska alaabadu waa shahaadada ay dhakhtarku ka hor timaado rajada macaamiisha, taas oo ay sidoo kale shaqeyn tahay, haddii ay tahay macluumaadka qaybiga ah. Ka baaritaanta qiimeynta nololeedka ee waqtiga joogtada ah waa muhiim in aad hubsato in resources ay ka buuxdaan rajada hadalka hooyo iyo in aan khalad la’aan ahayn. Kanu wuxuu qoraa khaladaha suurtagalka ah oo ku qoran resource leksikal ah, wuxuuna caddeeyaa tallaabooyin lagu soo bandhigay si ay u qiyaasaan qiimaha hadalka Malayalam. Malayalam waa mid ka mid ah luqadaha fasaxyada ee India. Waxaan rajaynaynaa inaannu hoosaysiinno qiimo yar oo ka mid ah hadalka, waxaana sameynaynaa koosaarka dadweynaha si aan u hagaajinno.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>ஒரு பொருளின் தரம் ஒரு பொருள் கஸ்டமரின் எதிர்பார்ப்பை சந்திக்கும் degree ஆகும், அது லெக்சிக்சியல் பாதிப்பு வளங்கள் செல்லுபடியாக இர ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட மூலங்களை பரிசோதிக்க முக்கியமானது ஒரு பேச்சாளரின் எதிர்பார்ப்பு மற்றும் பிழைகளிலிருந்து இலவசமாக இரு இந்த காகிதத்தின் முடியும் தவறுகளை லெக்சிக்சியல் பெம்மான்டிக் மூலத்தில் வரையறுக்கிறது மற்றும் மாலாய்லாம் சொல்லப்பட் மலாய்லாம் இந்தியாவின் வகுப்பு மொழிகளில் ஒன்று. நாம் வார்த்தையின் குறைந்த தரம் பகுதியை கழிக்க நம்புகிறோம் மற்றும் அதை நன்றாக செய்ய மக்கள் மூலம் செயல்பட</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ایک محصولات کی کیفیت ہے جسے ایک محصولات مشترک کی انتظار سے ملتی ہے، اور یہ بھی لکسیکل سیمانٹی منٹی منٹیوں کے مطابق مطابق ہے. مسئولوں کا مقررہ ارزیابی کرنا ضروری ہے تاکہ مطمئن ہو جائے کہ مسئولوں کی امید اور غلطی سے آزاد ہوتی ہیں. This paper defines the possible mistakes in a lexical semantic resource and explains the steps applied to quantify Malayalam worded quality. مالایالام هند کی کلاسیک زبانوں میں سے ایک ہے۔ ہم امید رکھتے ہیں کہ اس کی کم کیفیت کا حصہ مقرر کریں اور اسے اچھا کر دیں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Chất lượng của một s ản phẩm là mức độ đáp ứng được mong đợi của khách hàng, cũng phải hợp lệ với các nguồn văn hóa đơn. Việc kiểm tra thường xuyên các nguồn tài nguyên là điều cần thiết để đảm bảo nếu nguồn tài nguyên đáp ứng được nhu cầu của người phát ngôn và không bị lỗi. Tờ giấy này xác định những sai lầm có thể xảy ra trong một nguồn ngữ pháp văn học và giải thích những bước được áp dụng để định lượng chất lượng từ Malayaham. Malayala là một trong những ngôn ngữ cổ điển của Ấn Độ. Chúng tôi hy vọng sẽ lệ thuộc phần dưới chất lượng của Từ và thực hiện crodsouring để nó tốt hơn.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Quality of a product is the degree to which a product meets the customer's expectation, which must also be valid for the case of lexical semantic resources.  Mavzularni davomida qiymatlash, murasalar natijadagi gapiruvchi kutilgan va xatolar bilan boshqarishga muhim. Bu qogʻoz leksikal semantik Resource ichidagi muvaffaqiyatlarni aniqlaydi va Malayalamning soʻzni sifatini aniqlash uchun qoʻllanmalarni aniqlaydi. Malayalam Hindistonning klassik tillaridan biri. Biz so'zning dunyoning qiymatini kamaytirish va buni yaxshiroq qilish uchun jamiyatlarni bajaramiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_da>Kvaliteten af et produkt er, i hvilket omfang et produkt opfylder kundens forventninger, hvilket også skal gælde for leksikske semantiske ressourcer. En periodisk evaluering af ressourcerne er afgørende for at sikre, om ressourcerne opfylder en indfødt talers forventninger og er fri for fejl. Denne artikel definerer de mulige fejl i en leksikisk semantisk ressource og forklarer de trin, der anvendes til at kvantificere Malayalam wordnet kvalitet. Malayalam er et af de klassiske sprog i Indien. Vi håber at undersætte den mindre kvalitet del af wordnet og udføre crowdsourcing for at gøre det bedre.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Kvaliteta proizvoda je stupanj na koji proizvod ispunjava očekivanje klijenta, koji također mora biti vrijedan za slučaj leksičkih semantičkih resursa. Povedenje periodične procjene resursa je ključno za osiguranje da li resursi ispunjavaju očekivanja domaćeg govornika i besplatne od grešaka. Ovaj papir definira moguće greške u leksičkom semantičkom resursu i objašnjava korake primjenjene za kvantifikaciju kvalitete vrijednosti Malayalam a. Malayalam je jedan od klasičnih jezika Indije. Nadamo se da ćemo podnijeti manje kvalitetni dio riječi i izvršiti crowdsourcing kako bi ga poboljšali.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Качеството на даден продукт е степента, до която даден продукт отговаря на очакванията на клиента, което трябва да бъде валидно и за случая на лексикални семантични ресурси. Провеждането на периодична оценка на ресурсите е от съществено значение, за да се гарантира, че ресурсите отговарят на очакванията на родния език и без грешки. Настоящата статия определя възможните грешки в лексикалния семантичен ресурс и обяснява стъпките, приложени за количествено определяне на качеството на малаяламската дума. Малаялам е един от класическите езици на Индия. Надяваме се да подредим по-малко качествената част на думата и да извършим краудсорсинг, за да я направим по-добра.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Kwaliteit van een product is de mate waarin een product voldoet aan de verwachtingen van de klant, wat ook geldt voor lexicale semantische bronnen. Het uitvoeren van een periodieke evaluatie van resources is essentieel om ervoor te zorgen dat de resources voldoen aan de verwachtingen van een moedertaalspreker en vrij van fouten. Dit document definieert de mogelijke fouten in een lexicale semantische bron en legt de stappen uit die worden toegepast om Malayalam wordnet kwaliteit te kwantificeren. Malayalam is een van de klassieke talen van India. We hopen het minder kwalitatieve deel van het woordnet te subset en crowdsourcing uit te voeren om het beter te maken.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Qualität eines Produkts ist der Grad, in dem ein Produkt den Erwartungen des Kunden entspricht, was auch für lexikalische semantische Ressourcen gelten muss. Eine regelmäßige Bewertung der Ressourcen ist unerlässlich, um sicherzustellen, dass die Ressourcen den Erwartungen eines Muttersprachlers entsprechen und fehlerfrei sind. Diese Arbeit definiert die möglichen Fehler in einer lexikalischen semantischen Ressource und erläutert die Schritte, die zur Quantifizierung der Malayalam-Wordnet-Qualität angewendet werden. Malayalam ist eine der klassischen Sprachen Indiens. Wir hoffen, den weniger hochwertigen Teil des Wordnets zu untergliedern und Crowdsourcing durchzuführen, um es besser zu machen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kualitas produk adalah tingkat sehingga produk memenuhi harapan pelanggan, yang juga harus valid untuk kasus sumber semantis leksik. Menjalankan evaluasi periodik sumber daya penting untuk memastikan apakah sumber daya memenuhi harapan pembicara asli dan bebas dari kesalahan. Kertas ini mendefinisikan kesalahan yang mungkin dalam sumber daya semantis lexik dan menjelaskan langkah yang diterapkan untuk mengurangi kualitas kata Malayalam. Malayalam is one of the classical languages of India.  Kami berharap untuk menentukan bagian yang kurang kualitas dari kata-kata dan melakukan crowdsourcing untuk membuatnya lebih baik.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>کیفیت یک محصول درجه‌ای است که یک محصول به انتظار مشتری پیدا می‌کند، که باید برای موضوع منابع semantic زبان‌شناسی هم قابل باشد. ارزیابی یک ارزیابی عمومی از منابع برای مطمئن کردن اینکه منابع انتظار یک صحبت کننده و آزاد از اشتباهی است. این کاغذ اشتباهی ممکن را در یک منبع طبیعی زبان‌شناسی تعریف می‌کند و قدم‌هایی را برای تعریف کیفیت زبان‌شناسی مالایالم توضیح می‌دهد. مالایالام یکی از زبانهای کلاسیک هند است. امیدواریم بخشی کیفیت کمتری از کلمه‌های ارزش را تحویل بدیم و اجرا کنیم که آن را بهتر کنیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Uwango wa bidhaa ni kiwango ambacho bidhaa inakutana na matumaini ya wateja, ambacho lazima iwe sahihi kwa kesi ya vyanzo vya seksua vya lexico. Kufanya uchunguzi wa rasilimali kwa mara ni muhimu kuhakikisha kama rasilimali zinakutana na matarajio ya mzungumzaji wa asili na kutokana na makosa. Gazeti hili linaelezea makosa yanayoweza katika rasilimali ya sekondari ya lexico na inaelezea hatua zinazotumiwa ili kuthibitisha kiwango kinachoitwa Malayalam. Malayalam ni moja ya lugha za kiganjani za India. Tunatumaini kupunguza kiwango kidogo cha utamaduni na kutekeleza vyanzo vya umma ili kuifanya vizuri zaidi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Çaplanjaň kaliwaty müşterileriň garaşylygynyň bardygyna görýän derejedir. Bu senediň esasy semantik çeşmeleri üçin hem gowy bolmaly. Ressuratlaryň periyodik çykyşyny edip bilmek üçin gadyry çykyşyň jaýynyň umytlarynyň we ýalňyşlaryň boş bolmagyny garaşdyrmak üçin gerekli. Bu kagyz bir tekiz semantik çeşmede mümkin ýalňyşlyklary takyklaýar we Malayalamyň seçeneklerini golaýlaýar Malayalam Hindistanyň klasik dillerinden biri. Biz kelläniň azajyk hasaplanyň bir bölegini üýtgetmegimizi umyt edýäris we köpüşimizi gowurak etmek üçin köpüşimizi üýtgetmegimizi umyt edýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Kwaliteti i një produkti është grada në të cilën një produkt përmbush shpresat e klientit, e cila duhet të jetë gjithashtu e vlefshme për rastin e burimeve lexike semantike. Ekzekutimi i një vlerësimi periodik të burimeve është thelbësor për të siguruar nëse burimet përmbushin shpresat e një folësi vendas dhe pa gabime. Kjo letër përcakton gabimet e mundshme në një burim lexik semantik dhe shpjegon hapat e aplikuar për kuantifikimin e cilësisë së fjalëkalimit Malayalam. Malayalami është një nga gjuhët klasike të Indisë. Ne shpresojmë të nënvendosim pjesën më të paktë cilësie të fjalëkalimit dhe të kryejmë crowdsourcing për ta bërë atë më të mirë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Պարտադրի որակը այն է, թե ինչքանով է ապրանքը համապատասխանում հաճախորդի սպասելիքներին, ինչը պետք է համապատասխանի նաև լեքսիկական սեմանտիկ ռեսուրսների դեպքում: Ռեսուրսների պարբերական գնահատման իրականացումը կարևոր է, որպեսզի համոզվի, թե արդյոք ռեսուրսները համապատասխանում են բնիկ խոսնականի սխալներին և ազատ են սխալներից: Այս աշխատանքը սահմանում է լեքսիկական սեմանտիկ ռեսուրսների հնարավոր սխալները և բացատրում է այն քայլերը, որոնք կիրառվում են մալայալական բառերի որակի չափման համար: Մալայալամը Հնդկաստանի դասական լեզուներից մեկն է: Մենք հույս ունենք կազմել բառի ավելի քիչ որակային մասը և կատարել ժողովրդավար ռեսուրսներ, որպեսզի այն ավելի լավ դարձնի:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ko>제품 품질이란 제품이 고객의 기대를 충족시키는 정도를 가리키며 어휘와 의미 자원에 있어 품질도 반드시 효과적이어야 한다.자원에 대한 정기적인 평가는 자원이 모국어인들의 기대를 충족시키고 오류가 없는지 확인하는 데 매우 중요하다.본고는 어휘 의미 자원에서 발생할 수 있는 오류를 정의하고 Malayalam wordnet의 품질을 계량화하는 절차를 설명한다.말레이시아어는 인도의 고전어 중의 하나다.우리는wordnet에서 품질이 비교적 나쁜 부분에 대해 서브집합을 구분하고, 이를 더욱 좋게 하기 위해 크라우드소싱을 진행하기를 희망한다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_bn>একটি পণ্যের মান হচ্ছে যেখানে একটি পণ্য ক্যাটমারের প্রত্যাশার সাথে মিলিত হয়, যা লেক্সিক্সিক্যাল সেম্যান্টিক সম্পদের ক্ষেত্ সম্পদের নিয়মিত মূল্য নিশ্চিত করা গুরুত্বপূর্ণ যে সম্পদ স্থানীয় ভাষাকে আশা ও ভুল থেকে মুক্তি পাওয়া যায় কিনা। এই পত্রিকাটি লেক্সিকাল সেমেন্টিক সম্পদের মধ্যে সম্ভাব্য ভুল ব্যাখ্যা করে এবং মালায়ালামের শব্দের মান পরিমাণের জন্য প্রয়ো মালায়ালাম ভারতের ক্লাসিক ভাষার অন্যতম। আমরা আশা করি ওয়ার্ডনেটের কম মানের অংশ এবং জনসোর্সিং এর কাজ করতে পারি।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_af>Kwaliteit van 'n produkt is die grad waarop 'n produkt met die kliënt se verwagting ooreenstem, wat moet ook geldig wees vir die geval van leksiese semantiese hulpbronne. Die uitvoering van 'n periodieke evaluering van hulpbronne is nuutsaaklik om te verseker of die hulpbronne die verwagtings van 'n nasionale spreker en vry van foute ontmoet. Hierdie papier definieer die moontlike foute in 'n leksiese semantiese hulpbron en verduidelik die stappe wat gebruik word na kvantifikasie van Malayalam wordnet kwaliteit. Malayalam is een van die klassieke tale van Indië. Ons hoop om die minder kwaliteit deel van die woorde te onderstel en om dit beter te maak.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_bs>Kvaliteta proizvoda je stepena na koju proizvod ispunjava očekivanje klijenta, koja također mora biti vrijedna za slučaj leksičkih semantičkih resursa. Povedenje periodične procjene resursa je ključno da se osigura da li resursi ispunjavaju očekivanja domaćeg govornika i besplatne od grešaka. Ovaj papir definira moguće greške u leksičkom semantičkom resursu i objašnjava korake primjenjene za kvantifikaciju kvalitete vrijednosti Malayalam a. Malayalam je jedan od klasičnih jezika Indije. Nadamo se da ćemo podijeliti manje kvalitetni dio riječi i izvršiti crowdsourcing kako bi ga poboljšali.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_am>የሀብት ብልሃት የአጋራጆችን ተስፋ የሚያገኘው ግንኙነት ነው፤ ለሌክሲካዊ የsemantic ሀብት ጉዳይ ጥሩ ነው፡፡ የሀብትን ግንኙነት በመቀበል የግዛት ንግግር ተስፋ እና ከስህተት ነፃ እንዲያገኙ ማረጋገጥ ግድ ነው፡፡ This paper defines the possible mistakes in a lexical semantic resource and explains the steps applied to quantify Malayalam wordnet quality.  ማላይላም የህንድ ቋንቋዎች አንዱ ነው፡፡ አነስተኛውን ትክክል እናሳድገው ዘንድ እናስፈራራለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_ca>La qualitat d'un producte és el grau en què un producte satisfet les expectatives del client, que també ha de ser válida en el cas dels recursos semàntics lèxics. Realitzar una evaluació periódica dels recursos és essencial per assegurar si els recursos satisfen les expectatives d'un orador natiu i sense errors. Aquest paper defineix els possibles errors d'un recurso semàntic lèxic i explica les etapes aplicades per quantificar la qualitat de les paraules malayalanes. El malàyalam és una de les llengües clàssiques de l'Índia. Esperem subconfigurar la part de la paraula de menys qualitat i fer crowdsourcing per millorar-la.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Toote kvaliteet on määr, mil määral toode vastab kliendi ootustele, mis peab kehtima ka leksikaalsete semantiliste ressursside puhul. Ressursside perioodiline hindamine on oluline, et tagada, kas ressursid vastavad emakeelena kõneleja ootustele ja ei esine vigu. Käesolevas artiklis määratletakse võimalikud vead leksikaalses semantilises ressursis ja selgitatakse samme, mida rakendatakse Malayalami wordnet kvantifitseerimiseks. Malajalam on üks India klassikalisi keeli. Loodame, et teeme vähem kvaliteetse osa sõnastikust ja teostame ühishankimist, et muuta see paremaks.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_cs>Kvalita produktu je stupeň, do jaké produkt splňuje očekávání zákazníka, což musí platit i pro případ lexikálních sémantických zdrojů. Provádění pravidelného vyhodnocování zdrojů je nezbytné pro zajištění, zda zdroje splňují očekávání rodilého mluvčího a neobsahují chyby. Tento příspěvek definuje možné chyby v lexikálním sémantickém zdroji a vysvětluje kroky aplikované pro kvantifikaci kvality malajálamského slovního sítě. Malajálám je jedním z klasických jazyků Indie. Doufáme, že podsestavíme méně kvalitní část Wordnetu a provedeme crowdsourcing, aby byla lepší.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_az>Produktın qiyməti müşterilərin gözlədiyi dərəcədir. Bu da leksik semantik kaynaqların vasitəsi üçün dəyərlidir. Məlumatların periyodik değerlendirməsi yerli s öhbətçinin gözləmələri və hatalardan uzaq olmasını əmin etmək üçün vacibdir. Bu kağıt leksik semantik çoxluğunda mümkün xətaları təsdiqləyir və Malayalam qiyməti qiymətlərinə uyğun adımları təsdiqləyir. Malayalam Hindistanın klasik dillərindəndir. Biz istəyirik ki, sözünün daha az kaliteli bir parçasını yerləşdirmək və onu daha yaxşılaşdırmaq üçün qövmünün istifadəsini yerinə yetirmək üçün.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_fi>Tuotteen laatu on se, missä määrin tuote vastaa asiakkaan odotuksia, minkä on oltava pätevä myös sanastollisten semanttisten resurssien tapauksessa. Resurssien säännöllinen arviointi on välttämätöntä sen varmistamiseksi, että resurssit täyttävät äidinkielenään puhuvan odotukset ja eivät sisällä virheitä. Tässä artikkelissa määritellään mahdolliset virheet sanastossa semanttisessa resurssissa ja selitetään vaiheet, joita sovelletaan malayalam wordnetin laadun kvantifiointiin. Malayalam on yksi Intian klassisista kielistä. Toivomme, että voimme jakaa vähemmän laadukkaita osia sanakirjasta ja suorittaa joukkoistamista tehdäksemme siitä paremman.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>Kakovost izdelka je stopnja, do katere izdelek ustreza pričakovanjem kupca, kar mora veljati tudi za primer leksikalnih semantičnih virov. Izvajanje rednega ocenjevanja virov je bistvenega pomena za zagotovitev, ali viri ustrezajo pričakovanjem maternega govorca in brez napak. V prispevku so opredeljene možne napake v leksikalnem semantičnem viru in pojasnjene korake za kvantifikacijo kakovosti malayalamske besedne mreže. Malajalam je eden od klasičnih jezikov Indije. Upamo, da bomo podsestavili manj kakovosten del besednega omrežja in izvedli množično sourcing, da bi ga izboljšali.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Tsarin alama yana da daraja wanda da manunukan ta haɗa na matumain mai amfani da shi, da haka, sai ya kamata zama mai inganci ga masu kashewa na fassarar mutane. Ana muhimu a ƙididdige abincin a lokacin da ake so dõmin ka hakaƙa idan ma'auni za'a haɗu da tsammãni ga mai sauri na mataifa da kuma ba da ɓata ba. This paper defines the possible mistakes in a lexical semantic resource and explains the steps applied to quantify Malayalam wordnet quality.  Malayalam yana daga harshen na'ura na India. Munã kwaɗayin mu sami rabin abu kaɗan daga maganar nan kuma mu yi aiki na samun mutane dõmin ya kyautata shi.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>kalite ning alat sing digari, digari sing nêmên bakal kelompok nggawe winih kanggo awak dhéwé, kudu kene winih kanggo kelompok sematik dhéwé. Where's the reference Perintah iki dipun nggawe eror sing dipunangé ning semancis seneng lejih dan wong-wong kuwi nggawe gerakan kanggo kuwi nggawe kalaman sing apik dadi kalaman apik. malajalm kuwi sing mungkin karo alèh basa ning barang endi. Awak dhéwé nglanggar aturan macem kuwi nggawe luwih apik lan ijol-ijolan winih lan ijol-ijolan winih kanggo awak dhéwé luwih apik.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>དངོས་ཐོག་ཆའི་རྒྱུ་དངོས་ཡོད་ཚད་ནི་ཐོག་ཆའི་རྒྱུ་དངོས་ཐོག་འཕྲད་ཡོད་པ་དེ་རྩ་ལག་པོ་ཞིག་གི་རེ་འདྲ་བ་དང་མཐུན་སྒྲིག་ཡོད། རྒྱུ་དངོས་ཐོག་ཆས་ཀྱི་ཆེད་དུས་མཚམས་ལྟ་ཞིབ་བྱེད་ནི་རྒྱུ་དངོས་ཐོག ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་སྐད་ཡིག་གཟུགས་རིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་བྱུང་བའི་ནོར་འཁྲུལ་བ་དག་ལ་ངོས་འཛིན་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། རྒྱ་གར་གྱི་སྲོལ་རྒྱུན་གྱི་སྐད་ཆ་གཅིག་རེད། ང་ཚོས་ཚིག་གྲངས་ཀྱི་ཚིག</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>איכות המוצר היא המידה שבה מוצר מתאים לצפייה של הלקוח, אשר גם חייב להיות תקין למקרה של משאבים סמנטיים לקסיים. לבצע עריכה פרופודית של משאבים חיונית כדי להבטיח אם המשאבים מתאימים לצפיות של רמקול מקומי וחוץ לטעויות. הנייר הזה מגדיר את הטעויות האפשריות במשאב סמנטי לקסיקלי ומסביר את השלבים שמשתמשים כדי לקוונטיב איכות מילים מליאלאם. Malayalam is one of the classical languages of India.  אנו מקווים להחליף את החלק הכי פחות איכותי של המילה ולביצע מערכות קהל כדי לשפר את זה.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>LA-SACo : A Study of Learning Approaches for Sentiments Analysis inCode-Mixing Texts<fixed-case>LA</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>SAC</fixed-case>o: A Study of Learning Approaches for Sentiments Analysis in<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ode-Mixing Texts</title>
      <author><first>Fazlourrahman</first><last>Balouchzahi</last></author>
      <author><first>H L</first><last>Shashirekha</last></author>
      <pages>109–118</pages>
      <abstract>Substantial amount of text data which is increasingly being generated and shared on the internet and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> every second affect the society positively or negatively almost in any aspect of online world and also business and industries. Sentiments / opinions / reviews’ of users posted on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> are the valuable information that have motivated researchers to analyze them to get better insight and feedbacks about any product such as a video in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Instagram">Instagram</a>, a movie in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netflix">Netflix</a>, or even new brand car introduced by BMW. Sentiments are usually written using a combination of languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> which is resource rich and regional languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, etc. which are resource poor. However, due to technical constraints, many users prefer to pen their opinions in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_script">Roman script</a>. These kinds of texts written in two or more languages using a common language script or different language scripts are called code-mixing texts. Code-mixed texts are increasing day-by-day with the increase in the number of users depending on various online platforms. Analyzing such texts pose a real challenge for the researchers. In view of the challenges posed by the code-mixed texts, this paper describes three proposed models namely, SACo-Ensemble, SACo-Keras, and SACo-ULMFiT using Machine Learning (ML), Deep Learning (DL), and Transfer Learning (TL) approaches respectively for the task of Sentiments Analysis in Tamil-English and Malayalam-English code-mixed texts.</abstract>
      <url hash="74b7ee63">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.14</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="64818c3e">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.14.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>balouchzahi-shashirekha-2021-la</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/dakshina">Dakshina</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Findings of the Shared Task on Troll Meme Classification in Tamil<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>amil</title>
      <author><first>Shardul</first><last>Suryawanshi</last></author>
      <author><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></author>
      <pages>126–132</pages>
      <abstract>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet">internet</a> has facilitated its user-base with a platform to communicate and express their views without any censorship. On the other hand, this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_speech">freedom of expression</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_speech">free speech</a> can be abused by its user or a troll to demean an individual or a group. Demeaning people based on their gender, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexual_orientation">sexual orientation</a>, religious believes or any other characteristics trolling could cause great distress in the online community. Hence, the content posted by a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_troll">troll</a> needs to be identified and dealt with before causing any more damage. Amongst all the forms of troll content, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meme">memes</a> are most prevalent due to their popularity and ability to propagate across cultures. A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_troll">troll</a> uses a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_meme">meme</a> to demean, attack or offend its targetted audience. In this shared task, we provide a resource (TamilMemes) that could be used to train a system capable of identifying a troll meme in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil language</a>. In our TamilMemes dataset, each meme has been categorized into either a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_troll">troll</a> or a not_troll class. Along with the meme images, we also provided the Latin transcripted text from memes. We received 10 system submissions from the participants which were evaluated using the weighted average F1-score. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> with the weighted average F1-score of 0.55 secured the first rank.</abstract>
      <url hash="add32867">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>suryawanshi-chakravarthi-2021-findings</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Findings of the Shared Task on Offensive Language Identification in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a><fixed-case>T</fixed-case>amil, <fixed-case>M</fixed-case>alayalam, and <fixed-case>K</fixed-case>annada</title>
      <author><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></author>
      <author><first>Ruba</first><last>Priyadharshini</last></author>
      <author><first>Navya</first><last>Jose</last></author>
      <author><first>Anand</first><last>Kumar M</last></author>
      <author><first>Thomas</first><last>Mandl</last></author>
      <author><first>Prasanna Kumar</first><last>Kumaresan</last></author>
      <author><first>Rahul</first><last>Ponnusamy</last></author>
      <author><first>Hariharan</first><last>R L</last></author>
      <author><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <author><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Sherly</last></author>
      <pages>133–145</pages>
      <abstract>Detecting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Profanity">offensive language</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_localisation">local languages</a> is critical for moderating user-generated content. Thus, the field of offensive language identification in under-resourced Tamil, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada languages</a> are essential. As the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User-generated_content">user-generated content</a> is more code-mixed and not well studied for under-resourced languages, it is imperative to create resources and conduct benchmarking studies to encourage research in under-resourced Dravidian languages. We created a shared task on offensive language detection in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian languages</a>. We summarize here the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> for this challenge which are openly available at https://competitions.codalab.org/competitions/27654, and present an overview of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Method_(computer_programming)">methods</a> and the results of the competing systems.</abstract>
      <url hash="f1a38b6e">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>chakravarthi-etal-2021-findings-shared</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>GX@DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : Multilingual Neural Machine Translation and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Back-translation">Back-translation</a><fixed-case>GX</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Multilingual Neural Machine Translation and Back-translation</title>
      <author><first>Wanying</first><last>Xie</last></author>
      <pages>146–153</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we describe the GX system in the EACL2021 shared task on machine translation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian languages</a>. Given the low amount of parallel training data, We adopt two methods to improve the overall performance : (1) multilingual translation, we use a shared encoder-decoder multilingual translation model handling multiple languages simultaneously to facilitate the translation performance of these languages ; (2) back-translation, we collected other open-source parallel and monolingual data and apply back-translation to benefit from the monolingual data. The experimental results show that we can achieve satisfactory <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation">translation</a> results in these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian languages</a> and rank first in English-Telugu and Tamil-Telugu translation.</abstract>
      <url hash="0f7d597e">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.18</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="c00cd1d1">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.18.Software.zip</attachment>
      <attachment type="Dataset" hash="3df2f2ff">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.18.Dataset.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>xie-2021-gx</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Simon @ DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : Detecting Offensive Content in Kannada Language<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Detecting Offensive Content in <fixed-case>K</fixed-case>annada Language</title>
      <author><first>Qinyu</first><last>Que</last></author>
      <pages>160–163</pages>
      <abstract>This article introduces the system for the shared task of Offensive Language Identification in Dravidian Languages-EACL 2021. The world’s information technology develops at a high speed. People are used to expressing their views and opinions on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. This leads to a lot of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Profanity">offensive language</a> on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. As people become more dependent on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>, the detection of offensive language becomes more and more necessary. This shared task is in three languages : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a>. Our team takes part in the Kannada language task. To accomplish the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a>, we use the XLM-Roberta model for pre-training. But the capabilities of the XLM-Roberta model do not satisfy us in terms of statement information collection. So we made some tweaks to the output of this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a>. In this paper, we describe the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> and experiments for accomplishing the task of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada language</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="949b9d6b">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.20</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="cacbc4a0">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.20.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>que-2021-simon</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>Hypers@DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : Offensive language identification in Dravidian code-mixed YouTube Comments and Posts<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Offensive language identification in <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian code-mixed <fixed-case>Y</fixed-case>ou<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ube Comments and Posts</title>
      <author><first>Charangan</first><last>Vasantharajan</last></author>
      <author><first>Uthayasanker</first><last>Thayasivam</last></author>
      <pages>195–202</pages>
      <abstract>Code-Mixed Offensive contents are used pervasively in social media posts in the last few years. Consequently, gained the significant attraction of the research community for identifying the different forms of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_(media)">content</a> (e.g., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hate_speech">hate speech</a>, and sentiments) and contributed to the creation of datasets. Most of the recent studies deal with high-resource languages (e.g., English) due to many publicly available datasets, and by the lack of dataset in low-resource anguages, those studies are slightly involved in these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">languages</a>. Therefore, this study has the focus on offensive language identification on code-mixed low-resourced Dravidian languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a> using the bidirectional approach and fine-tuning strategies. According to the leaderboard, the proposed model got a 0.96 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FIVB_World_Rankings">F1-score</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, 0.73 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FIVB_World_Rankings">F1-score</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, and 0.70 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FIVB_World_Rankings">F1-score</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a> in the bench-mark. Moreover, in the view of multilingual models, this modal ranked 3rd and achieved favorable results and confirmed the model as the best among all systems submitted to these shared tasks in these three languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="0b747938">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.26</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="3abd65e7">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.26.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>vasantharajan-thayasivam-2021-hypers</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="29">
      <title>ZYJ123@DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : Offensive Language Identification based on XLM-RoBERTa with DPCNN<fixed-case>ZYJ</fixed-case>123@<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Offensive Language Identification based on <fixed-case>XLM</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>a with <fixed-case>DPCNN</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Yingjia</first><last>Zhao</last></author>
      <author><first>Xin</first><last>Tao</last></author>
      <pages>216–221</pages>
      <abstract>The development of online media platforms has given users more opportunities to post and comment freely, but the negative impact of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Profanity">offensive language</a> has become increasingly apparent. It is very necessary for the automatic identification system of offensive language. This paper describes our work on the task of Offensive Language Identification in Dravidian language-EACL 2021. To complete this task, we propose a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> based on the multilingual model XLM-Roberta and DPCNN. The test results on the official test data set confirm the effectiveness of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weighted_arithmetic_mean">weighted average F1-score</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tami_language">Tami language</a> are 0.69, 0.92, and 0.76 respectively, ranked 6th, 6th, and 3rd</abstract>
      <url hash="155ffbbb">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.29</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="adbbfa1f">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.29.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>zhao-tao-2021-zyj123</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="32">
      <title>CUSATNLP@DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : Language Agnostic Classification of Offensive Content in Tweets<fixed-case>CUSATNLP</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021:Language Agnostic Classification of Offensive Content in Tweets</title>
      <author><first>Sara</first><last>Renjit</last></author>
      <author><first>Sumam Mary</first><last>Idicula</last></author>
      <pages>236–242</pages>
      <abstract>Identifying offensive information from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">tweets</a> is a vital <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_processing_in_the_brain">language processing task</a>. This task concentrated more on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and other foreign languages these days. In this shared task on Offensive Language Identification in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian Languages</a>, in the First Workshop of Speech and Language Technologies for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian Languages</a> in EACL 2021, the aim is to identify offensive content from code mixed Dravidian Languages Kannada, Malayalam, and Tamil. Our team used language agnostic BERT (Bidirectional Encoder Representation from Transformers) for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_embedding">sentence embedding</a> and a Softmax classifier. The language-agnostic representation based classification helped obtain good performance for all the three languages, out of which results for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam language</a> are good enough to obtain a third position among the participating teams.</abstract>
      <url hash="a51816d3">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.32</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="b1886780">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.32.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>renjit-idicula-2021-cusatnlp</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/olid">OLID</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="40">
      <title>Maoqin @ DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : The Application of Transformer-Based Model<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: The Application of Transformer-Based Model</title>
      <author><first>Maoqin</first><last>Yang</last></author>
      <pages>281–286</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the result of team-Maoqin at DravidianLangTech-EACL2021. The provided task consists of three languages(Tamil, Malayalam, and Kannada), I only participate in one of the language task-Malayalam. The goal of this task is to identify offensive language content of the code-mixed dataset of comments / posts in Dravidian Languages (Tamil-English, Malayalam-English, and Kannada-English) collected from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. This is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_and_contrast_of_classification_schemes_in_linguistics_and_metadata">classification task</a> at the comment / post level. Given a Youtube comment, systems have to classify it into Not-offensive, Offensive-untargeted, Offensive-targeted-individual, Offensive-targeted-group, Offensive-targeted-other, or Not-in-indented-language. I use the transformer-based language model with BiGRU-Attention to complete this task. To prove the validity of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a>, I also use some other neural network models for comparison. And finally, the team ranks 5th in this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> with a weighted average F1 score of 0.93 on the private leader board.</abstract>
      <url hash="82c26192">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.40</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="13ddadaf">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.40.Software.zip</attachment>
      <attachment type="Dataset" hash="6a0cfa42">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.40.Dataset.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>yang-2021-maoqin</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="41">
      <title>Simon @ DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : Meme Classification for Tamil with BERT<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Meme Classification for <fixed-case>T</fixed-case>amil with <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Qinyu</first><last>Que</last></author>
      <pages>287–290</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we introduce the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> for the task of meme classification for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, submitted by our team. In today’s society, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> has become an important platform for people to communicate. We use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> to share information about ourselves and express our views on things. It has gradually developed a unique form of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotional_expression">emotional expression</a> on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_meme">social media   meme</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meme">meme</a> is an expression that is often ironic. This also gives the meme a unique sense of humor. But it’s not just positive content on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. There’s also a lot of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Profanity">offensive content</a>. Meme’s unique expression makes <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_technology">it</a> often used by some users to post offensive content. Therefore, it is very urgent to detect the offensive content of the meme. Our team uses the natural language processing method to classify the offensive content of the meme. Our team combines the BERT model with the CNN to improve the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a>’s ability to collect statement information. Finally, the F1-score of our team in the official test set is 0.49, and our method ranks 5th.</abstract>
      <url hash="49218d9c">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.41</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="b1295902">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.41.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>que-2021-simon-dravidianlangtech</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="45">
      <title>SSNCSE_NLP@DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : Offensive Language Identification on Multilingual Code Mixing Text<fixed-case>SSNCSE</fixed-case>_<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021: Offensive Language Identification on Multilingual Code Mixing Text</title>
      <author><first>Bharathi</first><last>B</last></author>
      <author><first>Agnusimmaculate Silvia</first><last>A</last></author>
      <pages>313–318</pages>
      <abstract>Social networks made a huge impact in almost all fields in recent years. Text messaging through the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet">Internet</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_phone">cellular phones</a> has become a major medium of personal and commercial communication. Everyday we have to deal with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_messaging">texts</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Email">emails</a> or different types of messages in which there are a variety of attacks and abusive phrases. It is the moderator’s decision which comments to remove from the platform because of violations and which ones to keep but an automatic software for detecting abusive languages would be useful in recent days. In this paper we describe an automatic offensive language identification from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian languages</a> with various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning algorithms</a>. This is work is shared task in DravidanLangTech-EACL2021. The goal of this task is to identify offensive language content of the code-mixed dataset of comments / posts in Dravidian Languages ((Tamil-English, Malayalam-English, and Kannada-English)) collected from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. This work explains the submissions made by SSNCSE_NLP in DravidanLangTech-EACL2021 Code-mix tasks for Offensive language detection. We achieve F1 scores of 0.95 for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam</a>, 0.7 for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannada">Kannada</a> and 0.73 for task2-Tamil on the test-set.</abstract>
      <url hash="9c046cd9">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.45</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="1a71520a">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.45.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>b-a-2021-ssncse</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="47">
      <title>MUCS@DravidianLangTech-EACL2021 : COOLI-Code-Mixing Offensive Language Identification<fixed-case>MUCS</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidian<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EACL</fixed-case>2021:<fixed-case>COOLI</fixed-case>-Code-Mixing Offensive Language Identification</title>
      <author><first>Fazlourrahman</first><last>Balouchzahi</last></author>
      <author><first>Aparna</first><last>B K</last></author>
      <author><first>H L</first><last>Shashirekha</last></author>
      <pages>323–329</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the models submitted by the team MUCS for Offensive Language Identification in Dravidian Languages-EACL 2021 shared task that aims at identifying and classifying code-mixed texts of three language pairs namely, Kannada-English (Kn-En), Malayalam-English (Ma-En), and Tamil-English (Ta-En) into six predefined categories (5 categories in Ma-En language pair). Two models, namely, COOLI-Ensemble and COOLI-Keras are trained with the char sequences extracted from the sentences combined with words as features. Out of the two proposed models, COOLI-Ensemble model (best among our models) obtained first rank for Ma-En language pair with 0.97 weighted F1-score and fourth and sixth ranks with 0.75 and 0.69 weighted F1-score for Ta-En and Kn-En language pairs respectively.</abstract>
      <url hash="e3ceb3f5">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.47</url>
      <attachment type="Software" hash="fcfa40d4">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.47.Software.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>balouchzahi-etal-2021-mucs</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="51">
      <title>OffTamil@DravideanLangTech-EASL2021 : Offensive Language Identification in Tamil Text<fixed-case>O</fixed-case>ff<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>amil@<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ravidean<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ang<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ech-<fixed-case>EASL</fixed-case>2021: Offensive Language Identification in <fixed-case>T</fixed-case>amil Text</title>
      <author><first>Disne</first><last>Sivalingam</last></author>
      <author><first>Sajeetha</first><last>Thavareesan</last></author>
      <pages>346–351</pages>
      <abstract>In the last few decades, Code-Mixed Offensive texts are used penetratingly in social media posts. Social media platforms and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_community">online communities</a> showed much interest on offensive text identification in recent years. Consequently, research community is also interested in identifying such content and also contributed to the development of corpora. Many publicly available corpora are there for research on identifying offensive text written in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English language</a> but rare for low resourced languages like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>. The first code-mixed offensive text for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dravidian_languages">Dravidian languages</a> are developed by shared task organizers which is used for this study. This study focused on offensive language identification on code-mixed low-resourced Dravidian language Tamil using four classifiers (Support Vector Machine, random forest, k- Nearest Neighbour and Naive Bayes) using chi2 feature selection technique along with BoW and TF-IDF feature representation techniques using different combinations of n-grams. This proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> achieved an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of 76.96 % while using linear SVM with TF-IDF feature representation technique.</abstract>
      <url hash="6d5562be">2021.dravidianlangtech-1.51</url>
      <bibkey>sivalingam-thavareesan-2021-offtamil</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>