<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.nlp4convai">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-10-28">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Conversational AI</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Alexandros</first><last>Papangelis</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Paweł</first><last>Budzianowski</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Bing</first><last>Liu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elnaz</first><last>Nouri</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Abhinav</first><last>Rastogi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yun-Nung</first><last>Chen</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="e583b414">2021.nlp4convai-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp4convai-2021-natural</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Not So Fast, Classifier   Accuracy and Entropy Reduction in Incremental Intent Classification</title>
      <author><first>Lianna</first><last>Hrycyk</last></author>
      <author><first>Alessandra</first><last>Zarcone</last></author>
      <author><first>Luzian</first><last>Hahn</last></author>
      <pages>52–67</pages>
      <abstract>Incremental intent classification requires the assignment of intent labels to partial utterances. However, partial utterances do not necessarily contain enough information to be mapped to the intent class of their complete utterance (correctly and with a certain degree of confidence). Using the final interpretation as the ground truth to measure a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier’s accuracy</a> during intent classification of partial utterances is thus problematic. We release inCLINC, a dataset of partial and full utterances with human annotations of plausible intent labels for different portions of each utterance, as an upper (human) baseline for incremental intent classification. We analyse the incremental annotations and propose entropy reduction as a measure of human annotators’ convergence on an interpretation (i.e. intent label). We argue that, when the annotators do not converge to one or a few possible interpretations and yet the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> already identifies the final intent class early on, it is a sign of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overfitting">overfitting</a> that can be ascribed to artefacts in the dataset.</abstract>
      <url hash="f0275347">2021.nlp4convai-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>hrycyk-etal-2021-fast</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.6</doi>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/clinc150">CLINC150</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Amendable Generation for Dialogue State Tracking</title>
      <author><first>Xin</first><last>Tian</last></author>
      <author><first>Liankai</first><last>Huang</last></author>
      <author><first>Yingzhan</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Siqi</first><last>Bao</last></author>
      <author><first>Huang</first><last>He</last></author>
      <author><first>Yunyi</first><last>Yang</last></author>
      <author><first>Hua</first><last>Wu</last></author>
      <author><first>Fan</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Shuqi</first><last>Sun</last></author>
      <pages>80–92</pages>
      <abstract>In task-oriented dialogue systems, recent dialogue state tracking methods tend to perform one-pass generation of the dialogue state based on the previous dialogue state. The mistakes of these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> made at the current turn are prone to be carried over to the next turn, causing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Error_propagation">error propagation</a>. In this paper, we propose a novel Amendable Generation for Dialogue State Tracking (AG-DST), which contains a two-pass generation process : (1) generating a primitive dialogue state based on the dialogue of the current turn and the previous dialogue state, and (2) amending the primitive dialogue state from the first pass. With the additional amending generation pass, our model is tasked to learn more robust dialogue state tracking by amending the errors that still exist in the primitive dialogue state, which plays the role of reviser in the double-checking process and alleviates unnecessary error propagation. Experimental results show that AG-DST significantly outperforms previous works in two active DST datasets (MultiWOZ 2.2 and WOZ 2.0), achieving new state-of-the-art performances.</abstract>
      <url hash="37682d1b">2021.nlp4convai-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>tian-etal-2021-amendable</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.8</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/PaddlePaddle/Knover/tree/develop/projects/AG-DST" additional="false">PaddlePaddle/Knover</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/multiwoz">MultiWOZ</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wizard-of-oz">Wizard-of-Oz</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>What Went Wrong? Explaining Overall Dialogue Quality through Utterance-Level Impacts</title>
      <author><first>James D.</first><last>Finch</last></author>
      <author><first>Sarah E.</first><last>Finch</last></author>
      <author><first>Jinho D.</first><last>Choi</last></author>
      <pages>93–101</pages>
      <abstract>Improving user experience of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue_system">dialogue system</a> often requires intensive developer effort to read conversation logs, run statistical analyses, and intuit the relative importance of system shortcomings. This paper presents a novel approach to automated analysis of conversation logs that learns the relationship between user-system interactions and overall dialogue quality. Unlike prior work on utterance-level quality prediction, our approach learns the impact of each interaction from the overall user rating without utterance-level annotation, allowing resultant model conclusions to be derived on the basis of empirical evidence and at low cost. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> identifies <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interaction">interactions</a> that have a strong correlation with the overall dialogue quality in a chatbot setting. Experiments show that the automated analysis from our model agrees with expert judgments, making this work the first to show that such weakly-supervised learning of utterance-level quality prediction is highly achievable.</abstract>
      <url hash="e6426f79">2021.nlp4convai-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>finch-etal-2021-went</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.9</doi>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/topical-chat">Topical-Chat</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Semi-supervised Intent Discovery with Contrastive Learning</title>
      <author><first>Xiang</first><last>Shen</last></author>
      <author><first>Yinge</first><last>Sun</last></author>
      <author><first>Yao</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Mani</first><last>Najmabadi</last></author>
      <pages>120–129</pages>
      <abstract>User intent discovery is a key step in developing a Natural Language Understanding (NLU) module at the core of any modern Conversational AI system. Typically, human experts review a representative sample of user input data to discover new intents, which is subjective, costly, and error-prone. In this work, we aim to assist the NLU developers by presenting a novel method for discovering new intents at scale given a corpus of utterances. Our method utilizes supervised contrastive learning to leverage information from a domain-relevant, already labeled dataset and identifies new intents in the corpus at hand using unsupervised K-means clustering. Our method outperforms the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_of_the_art">state-of-the-art</a> by a large margin up to 2 % and 13 % on two benchmark datasets, measured by clustering accuracy. Furthermore, we apply our method on a large dataset from the travel domain to demonstrate its effectiveness on a real-world use case.</abstract>
      <url hash="8cbac7a3">2021.nlp4convai-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>shen-etal-2021-semi</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.12</doi>
    <title_ar>اكتشاف النوايا شبه الخاضع للإشراف مع التعلم التقابلي</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Descoberta de intenção semi-supervisionada com aprendizagem contrastiva</title_pt>
      <title_es>Descubrimiento de intenciones semisupervisado con aprendizaje contrastivo</title_es>
      <title_ja>対照的な学習による半監督的な意図の発見</title_ja>
      <title_zh>有半监于学者</title_zh>
      <title_hi>Contrastive Learning के साथ अर्ध-पर्यवेक्षित इरादा डिस्कवरी</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Fionnachtain Rúin leathmhaoirsithe le Foghlaim Chodarsnachta</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ნახევარჯერი ინტერნტი განახლება კონტრესტიგური სწავლების შესახებ</title_ka>
      <title_el>Ημι-εποπτευόμενη ανακάλυψη προθέσεων με Αντιστατική Μάθηση</title_el>
      <title_hu>Félig felügyelt Intent Discovery kontrasztív tanulással</title_hu>
      <title_it>Scoperta di Intent Semisupervisionata con Apprendimento Contrastivo</title_it>
      <title_lt>Puskontroliuojamas ketinimas atskleisti kontrastinį mokymąsi</title_lt>
      <title_kk>Контрастырлық оқу арқылы жарты бақылау үшін</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Penemuan Intent Semi-mengawasi dengan Belajar Kontrastif</title_ms>
      <title_ml>കോണ്‍ട്രാസ്റ്ററിവ് പഠിക്കുന്നതിനൊപ്പം സെമി- നിരീക്ഷിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഉള്ള ഡിസ്ക്വറി</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Sejbien Intent Semi-Sorveljat b’Tagħlim Kontrastiv</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Хагасалтай суралцах талаар удирдлагатай ухаан олох</title_mn>
      <title_no>Halvoversikt intentoppdaging med kontrastiv læring</title_no>
      <title_pl>Pół-nadzorowane odkrycie intencji z kontrastywnym uczeniem się</title_pl>
      <title_mk>Половина надгледувано откривање на намерата со контрастивно учење</title_mk>
      <title_ro>Descoperirea intenției semi-supravegheată cu învățare contrastivă</title_ro>
      <title_si>සම්බන්ධ විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට පරීක්ෂණය කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Ku baaraandegista waxbarashada xiriirka</title_so>
      <title_sv>Halvövervakad Intent Discovery med kontrastivt lärande</title_sv>
      <title_ta>பாதி கண்காணிக்கப்பட்ட உள்ளடக்க கண்டுபிடிப்பு</title_ta>
      <title_ur>کنٹرسٹیو سیکھنے کے ساتھ نصف نظارت والی مضبوط دیسکوری</title_ur>
      <title_sr>Polovično nadgledano intenzivno otkriće sa kontrastivnim učenjem</title_sr>
      <title_uz>@ info: whatsthis</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Nửa giám sát tỉ lệ thu nhập với Tương phản học</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Semi-supervised Intent Discovery met Contrastive Learning</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Полунадзорно откриване на намерения с контрастивно обучение</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Polovično nadzirano intenzivno otkriće s kontrastivnim učenjem</title_hr>
      <title_da>Semi-supervised Intent Discovery med kontrastiv læring</title_da>
      <title_de>Halbüberwachte Intent Discovery mit kontrastivem Lernen</title_de>
      <title_id>Penemuan Intent Semi-supervised dengan Belajar Kontrastif</title_id>
      <title_ko>비교 학습에 기초한 반감독 의도 발견</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Ugunduzi wa Intaneti na Ufundishaji Mkuu</title_sw>
      <title_fa>پایین مراقبت مشهور با یادگیری متفاوت</title_fa>
      <title_af>Half- superviseer Intent Discovery met kontrastiewe leer</title_af>
      <title_tr>Kontrol öğrenmek ile kalan Kontrol Kontrol Kalamy</title_tr>
      <title_am>CategoryName</title_am>
      <title_sq>Semi-supervised Intent Discovery with Contrastive Learning</title_sq>
      <title_bn>পরিচিতি শিক্ষা দ্বারা সামিন-পর্যবেক্ষণ করা ইন্টারনেট ডিস্কোরি</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Կամի-վերահսկված մտադրական բացահայտությունը հակադրական ուսումնասիրությամբ</title_hy>
      <title_bs>Pola nadzornog Intenzivnog otkrića s kontrastivnim učenjem</title_bs>
      <title_az>Kontrast 칬yr톛nm톛si il톛 yar캼-g칬zl톛yirl톛n 칐yr톛nm톛</title_az>
      <title_ca>Descubrir intencions semisupervisades amb aprenentatge contrastiu</title_ca>
      <title_et>Pooljuhendatud kavatsuste avastamine koos kontrastiivse õppega</title_et>
      <title_cs>Objevování záměru s polovičním dohledem s kontrastním učením</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Semi-ohjattu Intent Discovery with Contrastive Learning</title_fi>
      <title_sk>Polnadzorovano odkrivanje namenov s kontrastnim učenjem</title_sk>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_jv>Learn Mode</title_jv>
      <title_he>Semi-supervised Intent Discovery with Contrastive Learning</title_he>
      <title_bo>རྒྱ་སྐྱེན་ཚད་ལྷན་རྒྱས་ལྗོངས་ཀྱི་སྣ་ཚོགས་སྟོན་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>يعد اكتشاف نية المستخدم خطوة أساسية في تطوير وحدة فهم اللغة الطبيعية (NLU) في صميم أي نظام حديث للذكاء الاصطناعي للمحادثة. عادة ، يقوم الخبراء البشريون بمراجعة عينة تمثيلية من بيانات إدخال المستخدم لاكتشاف نوايا جديدة ، وهي ذاتية ومكلفة وعرضة للخطأ. في هذا العمل ، نهدف إلى مساعدة مطوري NLU من خلال تقديم طريقة جديدة لاكتشاف نوايا جديدة على نطاق واسع في ضوء مجموعة من الأقوال. تستخدم طريقتنا التعلم التباين الخاضع للإشراف للاستفادة من المعلومات من مجموعة بيانات ذات صلة بالمجال ومُصنفة بالفعل وتحدد النوايا الجديدة في المجموعة الموجودة باستخدام مجموعات K غير الخاضعة للإشراف. تتفوق طريقتنا في الأداء على أحدث التقنيات بهامش كبير يصل إلى 2٪ و 13٪ على مجموعتي بيانات معياريتين ، تقاس بدقة التجميع. علاوة على ذلك ، نطبق طريقتنا على مجموعة بيانات كبيرة من مجال السفر لإثبات فعاليتها في حالة استخدام في العالم الحقيقي.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>A descoberta de intenção do usuário é uma etapa fundamental no desenvolvimento de um módulo de compreensão de linguagem natural (NLU) no centro de qualquer sistema de IA conversacional moderno. Normalmente, especialistas humanos analisam uma amostra representativa de dados de entrada do usuário para descobrir novas intenções, que são subjetivas, caras e propensas a erros. Neste trabalho, pretendemos ajudar os desenvolvedores de NLUs apresentando um novo método para descobrir novas intenções em escala dado um corpus de enunciados. Nosso método utiliza aprendizado contrastivo supervisionado para alavancar informações de um conjunto de dados já rotulado e relevante para o domínio e identifica novas intenções no corpus em questão usando clustering K-means não supervisionado. Nosso método supera o estado da arte por uma grande margem de até 2% e 13% em dois conjuntos de dados de referência, medidos pela precisão do agrupamento. Além disso, aplicamos nosso método em um grande conjunto de dados do domínio de viagens para demonstrar sua eficácia em um caso de uso do mundo real.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>El descubrimiento de la intención del usuario es un paso clave en el desarrollo de un módulo de comprensión del lenguaje natural (NLU) que sea el núcleo de cualquier sistema de IA conversacional moderno. Por lo general, los expertos humanos revisan una muestra representativa de los datos de entrada de los usuarios para descubrir nuevas intenciones, que son subjetivas, costosas y propensas a errores. En este trabajo, nuestro objetivo es ayudar a los desarrolladores de NLU presentando un método novedoso para descubrir nuevas intenciones a escala dado un conjunto de enunciados. Nuestro método utiliza el aprendizaje contrastivo supervisado para aprovechar la información de un conjunto de datos relevante para el dominio, ya etiquetado, e identifica nuevas intenciones en el corpus en cuestión mediante la agrupación de K-means no supervisada. Nuestro método supera al estado de la técnica por un amplio margen de hasta un 2% y un 13% en dos conjuntos de datos de referencia, medidos por la precisión de los clústeres. Además, aplicamos nuestro método en un gran conjunto de datos del dominio de viajes para demostrar su eficacia en un caso de uso del mundo real.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>ユーザーインテント発見は、現代の会話型AIシステムの中核である自然言語理解（ NLU ）モジュールを開発するための重要なステップです。通常、人間の専門家は、代表的なユーザー入力データのサンプルをレビューして、主観的でコストが高く、エラーが発生しやすい新しいインテントを発見します。この研究では、発話の主体として与えられた規模で新しいインテントを発見するための斬新な方法を提示することで、NLU開発者を支援することを目指しています。私たちの方法は、監視下の対照的な学習を利用して、ドメインに関連する、すでにラベル付けされたデータセットからの情報を活用し、監視下のK平均クラスタリングを使用して、手元のコーパス内の新しいインテントを識別します。当社の方法は、クラスタリングの精度によって測定される2つのベンチマークデータセットで、最先端のものを最大2%と13%の大幅なマージンで上回っています。さらに、旅行ドメインの大きなデータセットにメソッドを適用して、実際のユースケースでの有効性を実証します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>用户意发自然语言解(NLU)模块之关键步骤,自然语言解(NLU)模块今世会话AI统之心也。 凡人伦专家审有代表性者用户输数样本,以见新意,此主观也,贵而易失也。 于此之事,所以助NLU开发人员新,大见新意于给定语料库也。 吾法以监督比学以自关、已标之数,而用无监之K均值聚类以识手头语料库中新意。 吾法于两准集上以达2%13%之巨胜优于先进,以聚类准确性量之。 宜用于旅行域之大集,以验用例之有效性。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>उपयोगकर्ता इरादे की खोज किसी भी आधुनिक संवादात्मक एआई सिस्टम के मूल में एक प्राकृतिक भाषा समझ (एनएलयू) मॉड्यूल विकसित करने में एक महत्वपूर्ण कदम है। आमतौर पर, मानव विशेषज्ञ नए इरादों की खोज करने के लिए उपयोगकर्ता इनपुट डेटा के एक प्रतिनिधि नमूने की समीक्षा करते हैं, जो व्यक्तिपरक, महंगा और त्रुटि-प्रवण है। इस काम में, हम कथनों के एक कॉर्पस को दिए गए पैमाने पर नए इरादों की खोज के लिए एक उपन्यास विधि प्रस्तुत करके एनएलयू डेवलपर्स की सहायता करने का लक्ष्य रखते हैं। हमारी विधि एक डोमेन-प्रासंगिक, पहले से ही लेबल किए गए डेटासेट से जानकारी का लाभ उठाने के लिए पर्यवेक्षित कंट्रास्टिव लर्निंग का उपयोग करती है और असुरक्षित के-मतलब क्लस्टरिंग का उपयोग करके हाथ में कॉर्पस में नए इरादों की पहचान करती है। हमारी विधि दो बेंचमार्क डेटासेट पर 2% और 13% तक के बड़े मार्जिन से अत्याधुनिक को मात देती है, जिसे क्लस्टरिंग सटीकता द्वारा मापा जाता है। इसके अलावा, हम वास्तविक दुनिया के उपयोग के मामले पर अपनी प्रभावशीलता प्रदर्शित करने के लिए यात्रा डोमेन से एक बड़े डेटासेट पर हमारी विधि लागू करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Is céim ríthábhachtach é fionnachtain rún an úsáideora chun modúl Tuiscint Teanga Nádúrtha (NLU) a fhorbairt i gcroílár aon chórais nua-aimseartha AI Conversational. De ghnáth, déanann saineolaithe daonna athbhreithniú ar shampla ionadaíoch de shonraí ionchuir úsáideoirí chun rúin nua a fháil amach, atá suibiachtúil, costasach agus seans maith go bhfuil earráidí ann. San obair seo, tá sé mar aidhm againn cabhrú le forbróirí an NLU trí mhodh úrnua a chur i láthair le hintinn nua a aimsiú ar scála i bhfianaise corpas cainte. Úsáideann ár modh foghlaim chodarsnachta maoirsithe chun faisnéis a ghiaráil ó thacar sonraí a bhaineann leis an bhfearann, atá lipéadaithe cheana féin agus sainaithnítear cuspóirí nua sa chorpas atá idir lámha ag baint úsáide as cnuasach K-modhanna gan mhaoirseacht. Feidhmíonn ár modh níos fearr ná an úrscothacht le corrlach mór suas le 2% agus 13% ar dhá thacar sonraí tagarmhairc, arna dtomhas ag cruinneas cnuasaithe. Ina theannta sin, cuirimid ár modh i bhfeidhm ar thacar sonraí mór ón bhfearann taistil chun a éifeachtúlacht a léiriú ar chás úsáide sa saol fíor.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>A felhasználói szándék felfedezése kulcsfontosságú lépés egy természetes nyelvi megértés (NLU) modul kifejlesztésében, amely minden modern beszélgetési AI rendszer középpontjában áll. Általában az emberi szakértők áttekintik a felhasználói beviteli adatok reprezentatív mintáját, hogy új szándékokat fedezzenek fel, amelyek szubjektív, költséges és hibákra hajlamosak. Ebben a munkában az NLU fejlesztőinek segítséget kívánunk nyújtani egy új módszer bemutatásával, amelynek segítségével új szándékokat fedezhetünk fel nagyságrendű kifejezésekkel. Módszerünk felügyelt kontrasztív tanulást használ arra, hogy felhasználjuk a domain-releváns, már megjelölt adatkészletből származó információkat, és felügyelet nélküli K-means klaszterezéssel azonosítsuk az aktuális korpuszban található új szándékokat. Módszerünk nagy mértékben, akár 2%-kal, akár 13%-kal felülmúlja a korszerű adatokat a klaszterezési pontossággal mérve. Ezenkívül a módszerünket az utazási domain nagy adathalmazára alkalmazzuk, hogy igazoljuk hatékonyságát egy valós felhasználási esetben.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Η ανακάλυψη προθέσεων χρήστη είναι ένα βασικό βήμα για την ανάπτυξη μιας ενότητας κατανόησης φυσικής γλώσσας στον πυρήνα οποιουδήποτε σύγχρονου συστήματος τεχνητής νοημοσύνης συνομιλίας. Συνήθως, οι ανθρώπινοι εμπειρογνώμονες εξετάζουν ένα αντιπροσωπευτικό δείγμα δεδομένων εισόδου χρηστών για να ανακαλύψουν νέες προθέσεις, οι οποίες είναι υποκειμενικές, δαπανηρές και επιρρεπείς σε σφάλματα. Σε αυτή την εργασία, στοχεύουμε να βοηθήσουμε τους προγραμματιστές παρουσιάζοντας μια νέα μέθοδο για την ανακάλυψη νέων προθέσεων σε κλίμακα με βάση ένα σωρό εκφράσεων. Η μέθοδος μας χρησιμοποιεί εποπτευμένη αντίθετη μάθηση για να αξιοποιήσει πληροφορίες από ένα σχετικό, ήδη επισημασμένο σύνολο δεδομένων και να εντοπίσει νέες προθέσεις στο εν λόγω σώμα χρησιμοποιώντας μη επιτηρημένη συσσώρευση Κ-μέσων. Η μέθοδος μας ξεπερνά τη σύγχρονη τεχνολογία κατά μεγάλο περιθώριο έως 2% και 13% σε δύο σύνολα δεδομένων αναφοράς, που μετρώνται με ακρίβεια ομαδοποίησης. Επιπλέον, εφαρμόζουμε τη μέθοδο μας σε ένα μεγάλο σύνολο δεδομένων από τον τομέα των ταξιδιών για να αποδείξουμε την αποτελεσματικότητά της σε μια πραγματική περίπτωση χρήσης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>მომხმარებლის მისამართვის აღმოჩენა - საკუთარი კონფიგურაციო სისტემის კონფიგურაციის მოდულის განვითარებაში. ადამიანის ექსპერტები გამოსახულებელი მონაცემების გამოსახულებელი გამოსახულებელი მონაცემების გამოსახულება, რომელიც განსახულებელია ახალი მისახულებები, რომელიც სუბე ამ სამუშაოში ჩვენ მინდა დახმარება NLU განვითარებისთვის პრომენტის მეთოდის გაჩვენება ახალი საზოგადოებების მაგალითვის, როგორც კოპუსის გამოყენება. ჩვენი მეთოდი გამოყენებს მონაცემებული კონტროსტიური სწავლება, რომელიც დიომინის შესახებ შესახებ ინფორმაციის შესახებ, უკვე მონიშნული მონაცემების სეტატიდან და განსახულებს ახალი საზო ჩვენი პროცემი გავაკეთება კლასტერისტის მარტივის შესაძლებლობით 2% და 13% უფრო მეტი. დამატებით, ჩვენ გავაკეთებთ ჩვენი მეთოდი მონაცემების დიდი მონაცემების კონფიგურაციის დემონიდან, რომ გამოყენებთ მისი ეფექტიურობა რეალური მსოფლიო</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>La scoperta delle intenzioni degli utenti è un passo chiave nello sviluppo di un modulo di comprensione del linguaggio naturale (NLU) al centro di qualsiasi moderno sistema di intelligenza artificiale conversazionale. In genere, gli esperti umani esaminano un campione rappresentativo di dati inseriti dagli utenti per scoprire nuovi intenti, che sono soggettivi, costosi e soggetti a errori. In questo lavoro, miriamo ad assistere gli sviluppatori di NLU presentando un nuovo metodo per scoprire nuovi intenti su larga scala dato un corpus di dichiarazioni. Il nostro metodo utilizza l'apprendimento contrastante supervisionato per sfruttare le informazioni provenienti da un set di dati già etichettato rilevante per il dominio e identifica nuovi intenti nel corpus in questione utilizzando clustering non supervisionato di K-means. Il nostro metodo supera lo stato dell'arte di un ampio margine fino al 2% e al 13% su due set di dati benchmark, misurati con precisione di clustering. Inoltre, applichiamo il nostro metodo su un ampio set di dati del dominio viaggi per dimostrare la sua efficacia su un caso d'uso reale.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Naudotojo ketinimų atradimas yra pagrindinis žingsnis kuriant modulį „Natural Language Understanding“ (NLU), kuris yra bet kurios modernios konversacinės AI sistemos pagrindas. Paprastai žmogaus ekspertai peržiūri reprezentatyvų naudotojų duomenų rinkinį, kad galėtų nustatyti naujus tikslus, kurie yra subjektyvūs, brangūs ir linkę klaidų. In this work, we aim to assist the NLU developers by presenting a novel method for discovering new intents at scale given a corpus of utterances.  Mūsų metodas naudoja kontroliuojamą kontrastinį mokymąsi, kad sutelktume informaciją iš dominijai svarbių, jau pažymėtų duomenų rinkinio ir nustato naujus ketinimus aptariamame korpuse naudojant nepastebimą K priemonių klasifikavimą. Mūsų metodas dviejuose lyginamuosiuose duomenų rinkiniuose, išmatuotuose klasifikuojant tikslumą, viršija pažangiausią lygį iki 2 % ir 13 %. Be to, mes taikome savo metodą dideliam kelionių srities duomenų rinkiniui, kad įrodytume jo veiksmingumą realaus pasaulio naudojimo atveju.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>User intent discovery is a key step in developing a Natural Language Understanding (NLU) module at the core of any modern Conversational AI system.  Типично, човечките експерти прегледуваат претставен примерок на кориснички внесени податоци за откривање на нови намери, кои се субјективни, скапи и спротивни на грешки. Во оваа работа, ние имаме за цел да им помогнеме на развивачите на НЛУ со претставување на нов метод за откривање на нови намери на скала со оглед на корпус на изрази. Нашиот метод го користи надгледуваното контрастивно учење за да се искористи информациите од домен релевантни, веќе означени податоци и идентификува нови намери во корпусот во рацете користејќи ненадгледувано кластерирање на K-средства. Нашиот метод ја надминува најдобрата технологија со голема маргина до 2 и 13 отсто на двата бази на податоци, мерени со групирање на точноста. Покрај тоа, го применуваме нашиот метод на голем компјутер податоци од доменот за патување за да ја демонстрираме нејзината ефикасност во случајот на искористување во реалниот свет.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Penemuan niat pengguna adalah langkah kunci dalam mengembangkan modul Pemahaman Bahasa Biasa (NLU) di inti mana-mana sistem AI Perbualan Modern. Secara biasa, ahli manusia meninjau sampel mewakili data input pengguna untuk menemukan niat baru, yang subjektif, mahal, dan cenderung-ralat. Dalam kerja ini, kami bertujuan untuk membantu pembangun NLU dengan memperkenalkan kaedah baru untuk menemukan niat baru pada skala diberikan satu korpus ucapan. Our method utilizes supervised contrastive learning to leverage information from a domain-relevant, already labeled dataset and identifies new intents in the corpus at hand using unsupervised K-means clustering.  Kaedah kami melampaui keadaan-state-of-the-art dengan margin besar sehingga 2% dan 13% pada dua set data benchmark, diukur dengan ketepatan clustering. Selain itu, kami menggunakan kaedah kami pada set data besar dari domain perjalanan untuk menunjukkan keefektivitasnya pada kes penggunaan dunia nyata.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഉപയോക്താവിന്റെ ലക്ഷ്യം കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നത് സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷയുടെ (NLU) ഗ്രഹിക്കുന്നതില്‍ നിന്നും ആധുനിക സംസാരിക്കുന്ന ഏതെങ സാധാരണ മനുഷ്യരുടെ വിശേഷിപ്പുകാര്‍ ഉപയോക്താവിന്റെ ഇന്‍പുട്ട് വിവരങ്ങളുടെ പ്രതിനിധിയുടെ ഉദാഹരണമായി പരിശോധിക്കുന്നു. അത്  ഈ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനത്തില്‍, നമ്മള്‍ NLU വികസിപ്പിക്കുന്നവരെ സഹായിക്കാന്‍ ഉദ്ദേശിക്കുന്നു. വാക്കുകളുടെ കോര്‍പ്പുസ് കൊണ്ട് പുതിയ ഉദ്ദ നമ്മുടെ രീതിയില്‍ നിരീക്ഷിക്കപ്പെട്ട വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത് ഒരു ഡൊമെയിന്‍ ബന്ധപ്പെട്ട വിവരങ്ങളില്‍ നിന്നും നിരീക്ഷിക്കപ്പെട്ട വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഉപ നമ്മുടെ രീതിയില്‍ രണ്ട് ശതമാനത്തേക്കുള്ള ഒരു വലിയ മാര്‍ഗിനിലൂടെയും 13% പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. രണ്ട് ബെന്‍ച്മാര്‍ക്ക് ഡേറ്റ അതിനുശേഷം, ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഞങ്ങളുടെ രീതിയില്‍ യാത്ര ഡോമെയില്‍ നിന്നും വലിയ ഡാറ്റാസെറ്റില്‍ പ്രയോഗിക്കുന്നു. അതിന്റെ പ്രഭാവ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Хэрэглэгчийн зорилго олж мэдэх нь байгалийн хэл ойлголтын (NLU) модулийг орчин үеийн ярилцлагын AI системийн төвшинд хөгжүүлэх чухал алхам юм. Хүмүүсийн мэргэжилтнүүд хэрэглэгчийн өгөгдлийн загварын жишээ нь шинэ зорилго олж мэдэхэд хэрэглэгчийн өгөгдлийн загварыг шалгаж үздэг. Энэ ажлын тулд бид НЛУ хөгжүүлэгчдэд шинэ зорилго олж мэдэхийн тулд шинэ арга замыг нээхэд тусалдаг. Бидний арга нь холбоотой мэдээллийг хэрэгжүүлэхэд, аль хэдийн нэрлэгдсэн өгөгдлийн сангуудыг удирдах эсрэг суралцах суралцаг ашигладаг. Мөн холбоотгүй K-means кластеринг ашиглаж байгаа корпус-ын шинэ зорилго тодорхой Бидний арга нь урлагийн хувьд 2% болон 13% хүртэл хоёр давхар өгөгдлийн сангийн хувьд хэмжээтэй байдаг. Мөн бид аялал холбоотой том өгөгдлийн санг бодит ертөнцийн хэрэглээний тухай үр дүнтэй байдлыг харуулахын тулд өөрсдийн арга замыг ашигладаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Brukarhending er ein nøkkelsteg i å utvikla ein naturleg språk-forståking (NLU) modul på kjernen av alle moderne samtalesystemet. Vanlegvis er menneskelige ekspertar gjennomsikt eit reprezentativt prøve av brukaradata for å oppdaga nye forstånadar, som er subjektiv, kostnad og feilprone. I denne arbeiden må vi hjelpa NLU-utviklarane ved å oppdaga ein novel metode for å oppdaga nye innstillingar på skala gjeve eit korpus av uttaler. Metoden vårt bruker kontrollerte kontrastlæring for å levera informasjon frå ein domenerelevant, allereie merket datasett og identifiserer nye innstillingar i korpusen ved hånd ved hjelp av ikkje oppretta K- betyr klassering. Metoden vårt utfører kunsttilstanden med ein stor margin opp til 2 % og 13 % på to benchmarkdatasett, målt ved klassering av nøyaktighet. I tillegg kan vi bruke metoden vårt på ein stor dataset frå reisområdet for å demonstrere effektiviteten på ein verkeleg bruk tilfelle.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_mt>L-iskoperta tal-intenzjoni tal-utent hija pass ewlieni fl-iżvilupp ta’ modulu ta’ Ftehim tal-Lingwa Naturali (NLU) fil-qalba ta’ kwalunkwe sistema modern a tal-AI Konversazzjonali. Tipikament, l-esperti umani jirrevedu kampjun rappreżentattiv tad-dejta tal-input tal-utent biex jiskopru intenzjonijiet ġodda, li huma soġġettivi, għaljin u suxxettibbli għall-iżbalji. In this work, we aim to assist the NLU developers by presenting a novel method for discovering new intents at scale given a corpus of utterances.  Il-metodu tagħna juża t-tagħlim kontrastiv sorveljat biex iħeġġeġ l-informazzjoni minn sett ta’ dejta rilevanti għad-dominju, diġà ttikkettat u jidentifika intenzjonijiet ġodda fil-korpus inkwistjoni bl-użu ta’ raggruppament mhux sorveljat tal-mezzi K. Il-metodu tagħna huwa aktar avvanzat minn marġini kbir sa 2% u 13% fuq żewġ settijiet ta’ dejta ta’ referenza, imkejla permezz ta’ raggruppament ta’ preċiżjoni. Barra minn hekk, a ħna napplikaw il-metodu tagħna fuq sett kbir ta’ dejta mid-dominju tal-ivvjaġġar biex nippruvaw l-effettività tiegħu fuq każ ta’ użu fid-dinja reali.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Odkrywanie intencji użytkownika jest kluczowym krokiem w opracowywaniu modułu zrozumienia języka naturalnego (NLU) w rdzeniu każdego nowoczesnego systemu sztucznej inteligencji konwersacyjnej. Zazwyczaj eksperci ludzie przeglądają reprezentatywną próbkę danych wejściowych użytkowników, aby odkryć nowe intencje, które są subiektywne, kosztowne i podatne na błędy. W niniejszej pracy chcemy pomóc deweloperom NLU przedstawiając nowatorską metodę odkrywania nowych intencji na skalę biorąc pod uwagę korpus wypowiedzi. Nasza metoda wykorzystuje nadzorowane uczenie się kontrastywne, aby wykorzystać informacje z istotnego dla domeny, już oznaczonego zbioru danych i identyfikować nowe intencje w danym korpusie za pomocą nienadzorowanego klastrowania K-środków. Nasza metoda przewyższa state-of-the-art o duży margines do 2% i 13% na dwóch zbiorach danych referencyjnych mierzonych dokładnością klastrowania. Ponadto stosujemy naszą metodę na dużym zbiorze danych z domeny podróży, aby zademonstrować jej skuteczność w realnym przypadku użycia.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>Otkrivanje korisnika namjere je ključni korak u razvoju modula prirodnog razumevanja jezika (NLU) u jezeru svakog modernog razgovornog AI sistema. Obično, ljudski stručnjaci pregledaju reprezentativan uzorak podataka za ulazak korisnika kako bi otkrili nove namjere, koje su subjektivne, skupe i pogrešne. U ovom poslu, mi ciljamo da pomognemo razvojnicima NLU predstavljajući novu metodu za otkrivanje novih namera na skali s obzirom na korpus govora. Naša metoda koristi nadzorno kontrastivno učenje da utiče na informacije iz domena relevantne, već označene podatke i identifikuje nove namjere u korpusu na ruku koristeći nepotrebne skupljanje K-znakova. Naša metoda iznosi stanje umjetnosti sa velikom marginom do 2% i 13% na dva seta podataka o kriteriji, mjerena po skupljanju tačnosti. Osim toga, mi primjenjujemo našu metodu na veliku kompletu podataka iz domena putovanja da pokažemo svoju efikasnost na slučaju korištenja stvarnog svijeta.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_kk>Пайдаланушының мақсаты табу - табиғи тілді түсініктіру (NLU) модулін кез келген қазіргі қатынастық AI жүйесінің негізінде жасау үшін кілт қадам. Әдетте, адамдар эксперттері жаңа мақсаттарды табу үшін пайдаланушылардың келтірілген деректерінің үлгісін тексеру үшін, бұл мақсатты, бағатты және қатені түсіндіру үшін. Бұл жұмыс ішінде НЛУ жасаушыларына көмектесу мақсатымыз, сөздердің корпусы келтірілген жаңа мақсаттарын табу үшін романдық әдісін көрсету арқылы. Біздің әдіміміз доменге қатынасыз етілген деректер жинағынан мәліметті өзгерту үшін бақылайтын контрастырлық оқытуды қолданады және қолданыстағы корпустың жаңа мақсаттарын K- means кластерін қолдану ү Біздің әдіміміз 2% және 13% деңгейіндегі құрылғының күйіне шектеу үлкен шектері, кластерлік дұрыстығымен өлшемін. Қосымша, біз әдімімізді саяқтау доменінің үлкен деректер жиынына қолдану үшін әлемдік пайдалану үшін оның ең әсер етілігін көрсету үшін қолданамыз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ro>Descoperirea intenției utilizatorului este un pas cheie în dezvoltarea unui modul Natural Language Understanding (NLU) în centrul oricărui sistem modern conversațional AI. De obicei, experții umani revizuiesc un eșantion reprezentativ de date introduse de utilizatori pentru a descoperi noi intenții, care sunt subiective, costisitoare și predispuse la erori. În această lucrare, ne propunem să ajutăm dezvoltatorii NLU prin prezentarea unei metode noi de descoperire a intențiilor noi la scară, dată fiind un corpus de pronunțări. Metoda noastră utilizează învățarea contrastivă supravegheată pentru a valorifica informațiile dintr-un set de date relevant pentru domeniu, deja etichetat și identifică noi intenții în corpul respectiv folosind clustering nesupravegheat K-means. Metoda noastră depășește cele mai moderne standarde cu o marjă mare de până la 2% și 13% pe două seturi de date de referință, măsurate prin acuratețea clusterizării. Mai mult decât atât, aplicăm metoda noastră pe un set mare de date din domeniul turismului pentru a demonstra eficacitatea acestuia într-un caz de utilizare din lumea reală.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>පාවිච්චි අදහසක් හොයාගන්නේ ස්වභාවික භාෂාව තේරුම්ගන්න (NLU) මොඩ්යුල් එකක් හොයාගන්න පුළුවන් පැත්ත සාමාන්‍යයෙන්, මිනිස්සු විශ්වාසිකයෝ ප්‍රභාවිතයේ ඇතුළු තොරතුරු නිර්මාණයක් පරීක්ෂණය කරන්න, අළුත් අරමුණ මේ වැඩේ අපි අදහස් කරනවා NLU විකාශකයන්ට උදව් කරන්න, අලුත් අදහස් හොයාගන්න අළුත් අදහස් ප්‍රවේශයක් තියෙන්නේ කොර්පුස් ව අපේ විධානය පාලනය කරනවා පරීක්ෂා වෙන්න ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක ඉගෙනීම සඳහා ඩොමේන් එක්ක සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න තොරතුරු ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක වි අපේ විධානය තත්වය 2% සහ 13% විශාල දත්ත සේට් දෙකට වැඩියි, ස්ථානයක් සිද්ධ විශාල කරන්නේ. තවත්, අපි අපේ විදියට ප්‍රයෝජනයක් ඇත්ත ලෝකයේ ප්‍රයෝජනයක් විදියට ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න ලොකු දත්ත සෙට් එක්ක ප්‍ර</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Isticmaaluhu waxyaabaha ku saabsan in uu horumariyo qalabka waxgarashada afka asalka ah (NLU) oo ku qoran kooxa nidaamka caalamiga ah ee la hadlo oo dhan. Sida caadiga ah khabiiriyiinta dadku waxay ka fiiriyaan tusaale ahaan macluumaadka internetka si ay u ogaadaan waxyaabaha cusub, kaas oo ah mid la dhiganayo, kharash iyo kharash. Markaas waxan, waxaynu ku talo galaynaa in aan u caawinno horumarinta NLU-ka soo hormariyo qaab saxda ah oo lagu soo ogaado qasabka cusub ee lagu soo qoray hadal. Our method utilizes supervised contrastive learning to leverage information from a domain-relevant, already labeled dataset and identifies new intents in the corpus at hand using unsupervised K-means clustering.  Midabkayagu wuxuu ku soo bandhigaa xaaladda farshaxanta oo aad u weyn ilaa 2% iyo 13% oo ku qoran labada sawirada ee benchmark, oo lagu qiyaasay saxda. Intaas waxaa dheer, qaabkeenna waxaynu ku isticmaalnaa macluumaad badan oo ka yimid gudaha safarka si aan u muujinno faa'iidadeeda xaalada isticmaalka ee caalamka ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>@ info புதிய உள்ளீட்டு தரவை கண்டுபிடிக்க மனித சிறப்பாளர்கள் ஒரு பிரதிநிதிய மாதிரியை பார்க்கவும், புதிய செயல்பாடு இந்த வேலையில், நாம் NLU உருவாக்குபவர்களுக்கு உதவ வேண்டும் புதிய வார்த்தைகள் கொடுக்கப்பட்ட பேச்சுகளின் குறுக்குறிப்பை கண்டு எங்கள் முறைமையை பயன்படுத்துகிறது ஒரு களம் தொடர்புடையது, ஏற்கனவே குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட தகவல் அமைப்பிலிருந்து தேவைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, மற்றும் குறிப்புகளில எங்கள் முறை 2% மற்றும் 13% க்கு மேல் இரு பெங்க்மார்க் தரவுத்தளங்களில் இருந்து முறையில் செயல்படுத்துகிறது, தெளிவாக்கும் சரிய அதற்கும், நாம் பயணம் களத்திலிருந்து பெரிய தகவல் அமைப்பில் எங்கள் முறையை பயன்படுத்துகிறோம் ஒரு உண்மையான உலக பயன்பாடு விஷயத்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_sv>Upptäckt av användaravsikter är ett viktigt steg i utvecklingen av en Natural Language Understanding (NLU) modul som är kärnan i alla moderna konversations AI-system. Vanligtvis granskar mänskliga experter ett representativt urval av användarindata för att upptäcka nya intentioner, som är subjektiva, kostsamma och felbenägna. I detta arbete syftar vi till att hjälpa NLU-utvecklarna genom att presentera en ny metod för att upptäcka nya intentioner i skala givet en korpus av yttranden. Vår metod använder övervakad kontrastiv inlärning för att utnyttja information från en domänrelevant, redan märkt datauppsättning och identifierar nya intentioner i den aktuella korpusen med hjälp av oövervakad K-means klustring. Vår metod överträffar toppmodern med en stor marginal på upp till 2% och 13% på två referensdatauppsättningar, mätt med klustringsnoggrannhet. Dessutom använder vi vår metod på en stor datamängd från resedomänen för att visa dess effektivitet på ett verkligt användningsfall.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>یوسٹر کا مطلب اچانک ایک کلی سٹم ہے جسے ہر مدرنی مکالمانی AI سیسٹم کے مرکز میں ایک طبیعی زبان سمجھنے کے (NLU) موڈل کو توسعہ دینے میں۔ عام طور پر، انسان کے متخصص ایک نمونہ کے مطابق کارساز اینپیٹ ڈیٹے کی روشن کریں تاکہ نئی مطابق پیدا کریں، جو سرپرست، قیمت اور غلطی کے مطابق ہے. اس کام میں ہم نے NLU ڈلوگروں کی مدد کرنا چاہا ہے کہ ایک نو طریقہ پیش کریں کہ ایک کلمات کی کورپوس کے ذریعے نئی قصد کو اچھی تلاش کریں۔ ہمارا طریقہ ایک ڈومین کے معاملہ سے اطلاعات لازم کرنے کے لئے نظارت کی مخالفت کی تعلیم کے مطابق استعمال کرتا ہے، پہلے سے لکھی ہوئی ڈاٹ سٹ اور حاضر کورپوس میں نئی مطابق پہچان دیتا ہے جو غیر قائم کی مطابق کلاستر کے مطا ہمارا طریقہ آرتی کی حالت کو 2% تک اور 13% تک ایک بڑی مارجینٹ سے نکلتا ہے، دو بنچم مارک ڈیٹ سٹ پر، کلسٹر کی دقیق سے اندازہ کیا گیا ہے۔ اور ہم نے اپنے طریقے کو سفر ڈومین سے ایک بڑے ڈاٹ سٹ پر لازم کیا ہے کہ ایک حقیقی دنیا کے استعمال کیس پر اس کا اثرات دکھائے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Odatda, oddiy oddiy ekspertlar foydalanuvchi input maʼlumotini aniqlash uchun yangi qanday qanday bogʻ'liq, qiymati va xato roʻy beradi. In this work, we aim to assist the NLU developers by presenting a novel method for discovering new intents at scale given a corpus of utterances.  Bizning usuli domen muhim maʼlumotni koʻpaytirish uchun boshqaruvchi o'rganishdan foydalanadi. Maʼlumotlar tarkibini tayyorlash va qoʻllanmagan K- ma'noda qo'llanmagan yangi qatlamni aniqlaydi. Bizning usuli sanarning holatini 2% va 13% dan ikkita benchmark maʼlumotlar tarkibida bajaradi. Bu tashkilotni tayyorlash mumkin. Ko'pchilik, biz safar domenadan katta maʼlumotlar tarkibini qo'llayapmiz, bu muallif dunyodagi foydalanish davomida ishlatishni ko'rsatish uchun.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Phát hiện mục đích người dùng là một bước quan trọng trong việc phát triển mô- đun ngôn ngữ tự nhiên (Ntrường) ở trung tâm của hệ thống AI đối thoại hiện đại. Thường thì, chuyên gia nhân loại xem xét một mẫu dữ liệu nhập người dùng đại diện để khám phá ý định mới, mà là chủ quan, tốn kém và dễ bị lỗi. Trong công việc này, chúng tôi dự định giúp đỡ những người phát triển Ntrường hợp này bằng cách đưa ra một phương pháp mới để khám phá những ý định mới trên quy mô dựa vào tập hợp những lời nói. Phương pháp của chúng tôi dùng khả năng học tương đối giám sát để thu thập thông tin từ một tập hợp dữ liệu tương ứng miền, đã được đánh dấu và xác định các mục đích mới trong tập hợp này. Cách của chúng tôi vượt trội khả năng đạt được trạng thái nghệ thuật, với một khoảng cách lớn đến 2+ và 13=. trên hai tập tin tiêu chuẩn, đo được bằng độ chính xác lập. Chúng tôi dùng phương pháp của chúng tôi trên một tập tin lớn từ miền du lịch để chứng minh hiệu quả của nó trong một trường hợp sử dụng thực tế.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Откриването на намеренията на потребителя е ключова стъпка в разработването на модул за разбиране на естествения език (НЛУ) в основата на всяка модерна система за разговор с изкуствен интелект. Обикновено човешките експерти преглеждат представителна извадка от потребителски входни данни, за да открият нови намерения, които са субективни, скъпи и склонни към грешки. В тази работа ние се стремим да подпомогнем разработчиците на НЛУ чрез представяне на нов метод за откриване на нови намерения в мащаб, даден корпус от изказвания. Нашият метод използва контролирано контрастивно обучение, за да използва информация от съответния домейн, вече обозначен набор от данни и идентифицира нови намерения в настоящия корпус, като използва ненадзорни клъстери. Нашият метод превъзхожда най-съвременните с голям марж до 2% и 13% при два сравнителни набора данни, измерени чрез точност на клъстерите. Освен това прилагаме метода си върху голям набор от данни от областта на пътуването, за да демонстрираме ефективността му при реални случаи на употреба.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>User Intent Discovery is een belangrijke stap in het ontwikkelen van een Natural Language Understanding (NLU)-module die de kern vormt van elk modern Conversational AI-systeem. Meestal beoordelen menselijke experts een representatieve steekproef van gebruikersinvoergegevens om nieuwe intenties te ontdekken, die subjectief, duur en foutgevoelig zijn. In dit werk willen we de NLU ontwikkelaars helpen door een nieuwe methode voor het ontdekken van nieuwe intenties op schaal te presenteren met behulp van een corpus van uitingen. Onze methode maakt gebruik van supervised contrastive learning om informatie uit een domein-relevante, reeds gelabelde dataset te benutten en nieuwe intenties in het betreffende corpus te identificeren met behulp van onbeheerde K-means clustering. Onze methode overtreft de state-of-the-art met een grote marge tot 2% en 13% op twee benchmark datasets, gemeten door clustering nauwkeurigheid. Daarnaast passen we onze methode toe op een grote dataset uit het travel domein om de effectiviteit ervan aan te tonen op een real-world use case.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Otkrivanje korisnika namjere je ključni korak u razvoju modula prirodnog razumijevanja jezika (NLU) u srži svakog modernog razgovornog sustava AI-a. Obično, ljudski stručnjaci pregledaju reprezentativan uzorak podataka za ulazak korisnika kako bi otkrili nove namjere, koje su subjektivne, skupe i pogrešne. U ovom poslu ciljamo pomoći razvojnicima NLU-a predstavljajući novu metodu za otkrivanje novih namjera na skali s obzirom na korpus govora. Naša metoda koristi nadzorno kontrastivno učenje kako bi iskoristili informacije iz domena relevantne, već označene podatke i identificirali nove namjere u korpusu na ruku koristeći nepotrebne skupljanje K-means. Naša metoda iznosi stanje umjetnosti velikom marginom do 2% i 13% na dvije baze podataka o referenciji, mjerene po skupljanju to čnosti. Osim toga, mi primjenjujemo našu metodu na veliku kompletu podataka iz domena putovanja kako bi pokazali svoju učinkovitost na slučaju korištenja stvarnog svijeta.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Opdagelse af brugerhensigter er et vigtigt skridt i udviklingen af et NLU-modul (Natural Language Understanding), som er kernen i ethvert moderne Conversational AI-system. Typisk gennemgår menneskelige eksperter et repræsentativt udsnit af brugerinput data for at opdage nye hensigter, som er subjektive, dyre og fejltilbøjelige. I dette arbejde har vi til formål at hjælpe NLU-udviklerne ved at præsentere en ny metode til at opdage nye intentioner i skala givet et korpus af udtalelser. Vores metode bruger overvåget kontrastiv læring til at udnytte oplysninger fra et domænerelateret, allerede mærket datasæt og identificerer nye hensigter i det aktuelle korpus ved hjælp af ukontrolleret K-means clustering. Vores metode overgår den nyeste teknologi med en stor margin på op til 2% og 13% på to benchmark datasæt målt ved klyngernes nøjagtighed. Desuden anvender vi vores metode på et stort datasæt fra rejsedomænet for at demonstrere dens effektivitet på en virkelig brugssag.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_ko>사용자의 의도 발견은 자연언어 이해(NLU) 모듈을 개발하는 관건적인 절차이고 자연언어 이해 모듈은 어떠한 현대 대화 인공지능 시스템의 핵심이다.통상적으로 인류 전문가들은 사용자가 입력한 데이터의 대표적인 견본을 살펴보고 새로운 의도를 발견하는데 이것은 주관적이고 대가가 높으며 잘못되기 쉽다.이 작업에서 우리의 목표는 NLU 개발자가 주어진 언어 자료 라이브러리에서 대규모의 새로운 의도를 발견하도록 돕는 새로운 방법을 제시하는 것이다.우리의 방법은 감독이 있는 대비 학습을 이용하여 분야와 관련된 이미 표시된 데이터 집합의 정보를 활용하고 감독이 없는 K-균일치 집합을 이용하여 수중 어료 라이브러리의 새로운 의도를 식별한다.집계 정확도 측정을 통해 우리의 방법은 두 기준 데이터 집합에서 최신 기술보다 훨씬 우수한데 각각 2%와 13퍼센트에 달한다.그 밖에 우리는 우리의 방법을 관광 분야의 대형 데이터 집합에 응용하여 현실 세계의 용례에서 그 유효성을 증명할 것이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>User Intent Discovery ist ein wichtiger Schritt bei der Entwicklung eines Natural Language Understanding (NLU)-Moduls im Kern eines modernen Conversational AI-Systems. Normalerweise überprüfen menschliche Experten eine repräsentative Stichprobe von Benutzereingabedaten, um neue Absichten zu entdecken, die subjektiv, kostspielig und fehleranfällig sind. In dieser Arbeit wollen wir die NLU-Entwickler unterstützen, indem wir eine neuartige Methode vorstellen, um neue Intentionen im Maßstab anhand eines Korpus von Äußerungen zu entdecken. Unsere Methode nutzt überwachtes kontrastives Lernen, um Informationen aus einem domänenrelevanten, bereits markierten Datensatz zu nutzen und neue Intentionen im vorliegenden Korpus mittels unbeaufsichtigtem K-Means Clustering zu identifizieren. Unsere Methode übertrifft den Stand der Technik um eine große Marge bis zu 2% und 13% auf zwei Benchmark-Datensätzen, gemessen durch Clustering-Genauigkeit. Darüber hinaus wenden wir unsere Methode auf einem großen Datensatz aus der Travel Domain an, um deren Wirksamkeit auf einem realen Anwendungsfall zu demonstrieren.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Penemuan niat pengguna adalah langkah kunci dalam mengembangkan modul Pemahaman Bahasa Alami (NLU) di inti setiap sistem AI konversasi modern. Secara biasa, ahli manusia meninjau sampel reprezentatif dari data input pengguna untuk menemukan tujuan baru, yang subjektif, mahal, dan cenderung kesalahan. In this work, we aim to assist the NLU developers by presenting a novel method for discovering new intents at scale given a corpus of utterances.  Metode kami menggunakan pembelajaran kontras yang diawasi untuk menggunakan informasi dari set data yang relevan domain, yang sudah ditabel dan mengidentifikasi niat baru dalam tubuh di tangan menggunakan clustering K-means yang tidak diawasi. Metode kita melebihi state-of-the-art dengan margin besar hingga 2% dan 13% pada dua set data benchmark, diukur dengan akurasi clustering. Furthermore, we apply our method on a large dataset from the travel domain to demonstrate its effectiveness on a real-world use case.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>کشف هدف کاربر یک قدم کلید در توسعه یک مدول درک زبان طبیعی (NLU) در مرکز هر سیستم مکالمه‌ی AI مدرن است. معمولاً متخصص‌کننده‌های انسان یک نمونه نمونه‌ای از داده‌های ورودی کاربر را برای کشف هدف‌های جدید تحقیق می‌کنند، که موجود، ارزشمند و خطایی است. در این کار، ما هدف داریم به توسعه‌کنندگان NLU کمک کنیم با پیشنهاد روش نویسی برای کشف هدف‌های جدید در مقیاس با یک جسد سخنرانی داده شود. روش ما از یادگیری متفاوتی که از یک دامنه مربوط به اطلاعات تحت نظر قرار گرفته است استفاده می‌کند و از طریق کلاسترینگ K-یعنی غیرقابل تحت نظر قرار گرفته است هدف‌های جدید در کورپوس مشخص می‌کند. روش ما با یک مرز بزرگ تا ۲ درصد و ۱۳ درصد در دو مجموعه اطلاعات صندوق، به اندازه‌گیری با دقیق تنظیم می‌شود. علاوه بر این، ما روش خود را روی یک مجموعه داده بزرگ از دامنه سفر برای نشان دادن موثرتش در مورد پرونده استفاده از دنیای واقعی استفاده کنیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Lengo la mtumiaji kutambua ni hatua muhimu katika kuandaa kituo cha kuelewa lugha ya asili (NLU) katika mfumo wa UKI wa kisasa. Kwa kawaida, wataalam wa binadamu wanapitia mfano wa mwakilishi wa taarifa za watumiaji ili kutambua malengo mapya, ambayo ni muhimu, gharama na yenye makosa. Katika kazi hii, tunalenga kusaidia waendelezaji wa NLU kwa kutoa mbinu ya riwaya ya kutambua nia mpya kwa kiwango kinachotolewa na makampuni ya hotuba. Utawala wetu unatumia utaratibu wa kujifunza tofauti za kutoa taarifa kutoka kwenye seti ya taarifa zinazohusiana na ndani, tayari zinaonyesha nia mpya katika makampuni hayo kwa kutumia viungo vya K-maana yasiyoeleweka. Utawala wetu unaonyesha hali ya sanaa kwa kiwango kikubwa cha kufikia asilimia 2 na asilimia 13 kwenye seti mbili za bendera, zilizopima kwa usahihi. Zaidi ya hayo, tunatumia njia yetu kwenye seti kubwa ya taarifa kutoka kwenye eneo la safari ili kuonyesha ufanisi wake kwenye kesi ya matumizi ya dunia halisi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Ullan챌y maksady ke힊fedilmek, Tebi첵al Dili d체힊체nmek (NLU) modulyny her modern Conversational AI sistemini흫 esbapynda 첵eti힊dirmek 체챌in wajyp ad캇md캇r. Adamlar uzmanlary t채ze ni첵etleri tapmak 체챌in ullan챌ylary흫 girdi maglumatyny흫 t채ze ni첵etlerini tapmak 체챌in bir nusgasyny barla첵arlar. Bu i힊de NLU 철wrenmelerine k철mek etmek ama챌ladyk. T채ze ni첵etleri bir k철p체s beril첵채n 챌yky힊lary a 챌mak 체챌in t채ze maksady a챌mak 체챌in bir t채ze y철ntem g철rkezmek 체챌in. Bizi흫 y철ntemimiz, 체st체nde g철zlenen kontrast 철wrenmegi domeny흫 m철h체m bolan, e첵첵채m etilen veri setirmelerinden ge챌irmek 체챌in g철zlenen kontrast 철wrenmegi ullan첵ar we 철nde kod첵usda t채ze maksadlary tany첵ar. Bizi흫 첵agda첵ymyz 2% we 13% b체y체k gabdaly iki benchmark veri setirlerinde 철l챌체p 첵철re첵채r. Daha da, biz yolculuklardan b체y체k bir dataset 체zerinde y철n체mizi ger챌ek d체n첵채 i힊le첵채n durumda etkinli휓ini kan캇tlamak 체챌in uyguladyk.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Gebruiker doel ontdekking is 'n sleutel stap in die ontwikkeling van 'n Natuurlike Taal Verstaan (NLU) module by die kern van enige moderne Gespraakte AI stelsel. Tipe, menslike eksperte hersien 'n voorskynlike voorbeeld van gebruiker invoer data om nuwe doels te ontdek, wat is subjektief, koste en fout- prone. In hierdie werk is ons doel om die NLU ontwikkelaars te help deur 'n nuwe metode te voorsien om nuwe doels op skaal te ontdek wat 'n korpus van uitspraak gegee het. Ons metode gebruik die ondersoekte kontrastiewe leer om inligting van 'n domein- relevante, reeds etiketeerde datastel te verwys en identifiseer nuwe doels in die korpus by die hand te gebruik met onondersoekte K- betekens clustering. Ons metode uitvoer die state-of-the-art deur 'n groot marjin tot 2% en 13% op twee benchmarkdatastelle, gemeet deur klastering presies. Ons het ook ons metode aanwend op 'n groot datastel van die reis domein om sy effektiviteit te wys op 'n reël wêreld gebruik geval.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Zbulimi i qëllimeve të përdoruesit është një hap kyç në zhvillimin e një moduli të kuptimit të gjuhës natyrore (NLU) në qendër të çdo sistemi modern AI konversational. Zakonisht, ekspertët njerëzorë shqyrtojnë një shembull përfaqësues të të dhënave të hyrjes së përdoruesve për të zbuluar qëllime të reja, që janë subjektive, të shtrenjta dhe të rrezikshme për gabime. Në këtë punë, ne synojmë të ndihmojmë zhvilluesit e NLU duke paraqitur një metodë të re për zbulimin e qëllimeve të reja në shkallë të dhënë një korpus shprehjesh. Metoda jonë përdorë mësimin kontrastiv të mbikqyrur për të përdorur informacionin nga një grup i të dhënave të rëndësishme për domenin, të etiketuar tashmë dhe identifikon qëllime të reja në korpus në dorë duke përdorur grupimin e K-means të pa mbikqyrur. Metoda jonë e tejkalon gjendjen më të avancuar me një marxh të madh deri në 2% dhe 13% në dy grupe të dhënash referenciale, të matura nga grupimi i saktësisë. Përveç kësaj, ne aplikojmë metodën tonë në një set të madh të dhënash nga domenia e udhëtimit për të demonstruar efektshmërinë e saj në një rast përdorimi në botën reale.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>User intent discovery is a key step in developing a Natural Language Understanding (NLU) module at the core of any modern Conversational AI system.  በተለመደው፣ የሰው ባለምህርት አዋቂዎች አዲስ ዓይነት፣ ዋጋው እና የስህተት ስህተት የሚያስፈልገውን አዲስ ዓይነት ለማግኘት የጥያቄ የድምፅ ምሳሌ ይመልሳሉ፡፡ በዚህ ሥራ የNLU አካባቢዎች የንግግር አካባቢ የተሰጠውን አዲስ አሳብ ለማግኘት አዲስ ልማድ እናስረዳለን፡፡ የድምፅ አካባቢ መረጃዎችን ከዶሜን-አካባቢ እና አዲስ ጉዳይ በኮንፓስ ውስጥ በተጠበቀው የK-ማዕከል ጉዳይ በመጠቀም አዲስ ጉዳይ ይታያል፡፡ የ-የ-የ-ዐርድ ግንኙነታችን 2 በመቶ እና 13 በመቶ በሁለት የbenchmark ዳርቻዎች ላይ ያሳርፋል፡፡ በተጨማሪም፣ መንገዳችንን በመንገድ ዳታዎች ላይ እናስጠጋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Օգտագործողի մտադրության հայտնաբերումը գլխավոր քայլ է բնական լեզվի հասկանալու (ՆԼU) մոդուլների զարգացման մեջ ցանկացած ժամանակակից հաղորդակցման ԱԲ համակարգի հիմքում: Սովորաբար մարդու մասնագետները վերլուծում են օգտագործողի մուտքագրման տվյալների ներկայացուցիչ նմուշը նոր նպատակներ հայտնաբերելու համար, որոնք սուբյեկտիվ են, թանկ և սխալների հակված են: Այս աշխատանքի ընթացքում մենք նպատակում ենք օգնել ՆԼԵՄ-ի զարգացողներին ներկայացնելով նոր մեթոդ նոր նպատակների հայտնաբերելու համար աստիճաններով: Մեր մեթոդը օգտագործում է վերահսկված հակադրական ուսումնասիրությունը, որպեսզի օգտագործենք տեղեկատվությունը, որը արդեն նշանակում է բնագավառի, արդեն պիտակուցված տվյալների համակարգում, և հայտնաբերում է նոր նպատակներ ձեռքի մարմնում, օգտագործելով անվերահսկ Մեր մեթոդը գերազանցում է ամենակարևորը մինչև 2 և 13 տոկոսով երկու համեմատական տվյալների համակարգերի վրա, չափված ճշգրտության խմբագրման միջոցով: Furthermore, we apply our method on a large dataset from the travel domain to demonstrate its effectiveness on a real-world use case.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>User intent discovery is a key step in developing a Natural Language Understanding (NLU) module at the core of any modern Conversational AI system.  সাধারণত মানুষ বিশেষজ্ঞরা নতুন উদ্দেশ্য আবিষ্কারের জন্য ব্যবহারকারীর ইনপুট তথ্যের প্রতিনিধির নমুনা পর্যবেক্ষণ করেছেন, যা  এই কাজে আমরা এনএলইউ ডেভেলপারদের সাহায্য করার উদ্দেশ্য হচ্ছি ভাষণের কোর্পাসের কারণে নতুন উদ্দেশ্য আবিষ্কারের মাধ্যমে একটি নবনের মাধ্ আমাদের পদ্ধতি একটি ডোমেইন-সম্পর্কিত তথ্য প্রদান করার জন্য বিরোধীতা শিক্ষা ব্যবহার করে, ইতোমধ্যে লেবেল করা হয়েছে ডাটাসেট এবং কোর্পাসে নতুন উদ্দেশ্য চিহ্নি আমাদের পদ্ধতি দুই বেনম্যার্ক ডাটাসেটের মাধ্যমে বিশাল মার্জিনের দ্বারা দুই শতাংশ এবং ১৩% বেঞ্চার্ক ডাটাসেটের মাধ্যমে প এছাড়াও, আমরা ভ্রমণের ডোমেইন থেকে বিশাল ডাটাসেটের মাধ্যমে আমাদের পদ্ধতি প্রয়োগ করি একটি বাস্তব ব্যবহারের কেসের উপর তার কার</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>El descobriment de l'intenció de l'usuari és un pas clau en el desenvolupament d'un módul d'Entensió de Llingua Natural (NLU) al nucli de qualsevol sistema d'AI conversacional modern. Normalment, els experts humans revisen una mostra representativa de dades d'entrada d'usuaris per descobrir noves intencions, subjectives, costoses i propensos a errors. En aquest treball, busquem ajudar els desenvolupadors de la NLU presentant un mètode nou per descobrir noves intencions a escala dada un corpus d'expressions. El nostre mètode utilitza l'aprenentatge contrastiu supervisat per aprofitar la informació d'un conjunt de dades relevants per domini, ja etiquetat, i identifica noves intencions al cos a mà fent servir una agrupació de mitjans K sense supervisió. El nostre mètode supera l'actualitat d'un gran marge fins al 2% i al 13% en dos conjunts de dades de referència, mesurats agrupant la precisió. A més, aplicam el nostre mètode en un gran conjunt de dades del domini de viatge per demostrar la seva eficacia en un cas d'ús del món real.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>Otkrivanje korisnika namjere je ključni korak u razvoju modula prirodnog razumijevanja jezika (NLU) u jezeru svakog modernog razgovornog AI sistema. Obično, ljudski stručnjaci pregledaju reprezentantni uzorak podataka za ulazak korisnika kako bi otkrili nove namjere, koje su subjektivne, skupe i pogrešne. U ovom poslu, mi ciljamo da pomognemo razvojnicima NLU-a predstavljajući novu metodu za otkrivanje novih namjera na skali s obzirom na korpus govora. Naša metoda koristi nadzorno kontrastivno učenje kako bi iskoristili informacije iz domena relevantne, već označene podatke i identificirali nove namjere u korpusu na ruku koristeći nepotrebne skupljanje K-medija. Naša metoda iznosi stanje umjetnosti velikom marginom do 2% i 13% na dvije baze podataka o referenciji, mjerene po skupljanju tačnosti. Osim toga, mi primjenjujemo našu metodu na veliku kompletu podataka iz domena putovanja kako bi pokazali svoju učinkovitost na slučaju korištenja stvarnog svijeta.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Zjištění záměru uživatele je klíčovým krokem při vývoji modulu porozumění přirozenému jazyku (NLU) v jádru každého moderního konverzačního AI systému. Lidští odborníci obvykle zkontrolují reprezentativní vzorek vstupních dat uživatelů, aby objevili nové záměry, které jsou subjektivní, nákladné a náchylné k chybám. Cílem této práce je pomoci vývojářům NLU představením nové metody pro objevování nových záměrů v měřítku vzhledem k korpusu projevů. Naše metoda využívá kontrastní učení, které využívá k využití informací z doménově relevantní, již označené datové sady a identifikuje nové záměry v daném korpusu pomocí bez dozoru K-means clustering. Naše metoda výrazně překonává nejmodernější stav techniky až do 2% a 13% na dvou referenčních datových sadách měřených přesností clusteru. Dále aplikujeme naši metodu na velký datový soubor z cestovní domény, abychom demonstrovali její efektivitu na reálném případě použití.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_az>İstifadəçi niyyəti keşif hər modern Konuşatlı AI sisteminin dibində təbiətli dil anlama modulu təşkil etmək üçün anahtar adımdır. İnsan ekspertləri yeni niyyətləri keşf etmək üçün istifadəçilərin giriş verilənlərin nümunəsini təhsil edirlər, bu da subjektiv, mal və xəta-prone idir. Bu işdə NLU mükəmməçilərinə kömək etmək istəyirik, sözlərin korpusu ilə yeni niyyətləri keşfetmək üçün yeni bir metod göstərmək üçün. Bizim metodumuz domenalı məlumatlardan məlumatları istifadə etmək üçün gözləyirli müxtəlif öyrənmək üçün istifadə edir, əvvəlcə etiket edilmiş veri qutusu və əlində olan korpusda yeni niyyətləri tanıyır ki-məlumatların klasterindən istifadə edilməz. Bizim metodumuz 2%-ə və 13%-ə qədər böyük bir margin ilə, iki benchmark veri qutusu ilə ölçülür. Daha sonra, biz yolculuğumuzu gerçek dünyanın istifadə etmə məsələsində çox böyük bir veri qutusuna istifadə edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_fi>Käyttäjän aikomusten löytäminen on keskeinen askel kehitettäessä Natural Language Understanding (NLU) -moduulia jokaisen nykyaikaisen Conversational AI -järjestelmän ytimessä. Tyypillisesti ihmisasiantuntijat tarkistavat edustavan otoksen käyttäjän syöttötiedoista löytääkseen uusia tarkoituksia, jotka ovat subjektiivisia, kalliita ja virhealttiita. Tässä työssä pyrimme auttamaan NLU:n kehittäjiä esittelemällä uudenlaisen menetelmän uusien aikomusten löytämiseen mittakaavassa lausekorpusen avulla. Menetelmämme hyödyntää valvottua kontrastioppimista hyödyntäen tietoa toimialueen relevantista, jo merkitystä aineistosta ja tunnistaa uusia tarkoituksia käsillä olevassa korpusessa valvomattomalla K-means-klusteroinnilla. Menetelmämme suoriutuu viimeisintä tekniikkaa suuremmalla marginaalilla, jopa 2% ja 13% kahdella vertailuaineistolla klusteroinnin tarkkuudella mitattuna. Lisäksi käytämme menetelmäämme suuressa matkustusalueen aineistossa osoittaaksemme sen tehokkuuden todellisessa käyttötapauksessa.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Kasutaja kavatsuste avastamine on oluline samm loodusliku keele mõistmise mooduli väljatöötamisel, mis on mis tahes kaasaegse vestlusliku AI süsteemi keskmes. Tavaliselt vaatavad inimeksperdid läbi kasutaja sisendandmete representatiivse valimi, et avastada uusi kavatsusi, mis on subjektiivsed, kulukad ja veakalduvad. Käesolevas töös on meie eesmärk aidata NLU arendajaid, esitades uudse meetodi uute kavatsuste avastamiseks mastaabis väljenduskorpuse alusel. Meie meetod kasutab juhendatud kontrastiivset õpet, et kasutada teavet domeeni asjakohasest, juba märgistatud andmekogumist ning tuvastada käesolevas korpuses uued kavatsused, kasutades järelevalveta K-means klastrit. Meie meetod ületab tehnika taseme suure marginaaliga kuni 2% ja 13% kahe võrdlusandmekogumi puhul, mida mõõdetakse klastrite täpsusega. Lisaks rakendame oma meetodit reisi domeeni suurtele andmekogumitele, et demonstreerida selle efektiivsust reaalses maailmas kasutusjuhtumis.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_sk>Odkrivanje namena uporabnikov je ključni korak pri razvoju modula za razumevanje naravnega jezika (NLU) v jedru katerega koli sodobnega sistema pogovorne umetne inteligence. Običajno človeški strokovnjaki pregledajo reprezentativni vzorec vnosnih podatkov uporabnikov, da odkrijejo nove namene, ki so subjektivni, dragi in nagnjeni k napakam. V tem delu želimo pomagati razvijalcem NLU s predstavitvijo nove metode odkrivanja novih namenov v obsegu glede na korpus izgovorov. Naša metoda uporablja nadzorovano kontrastno učenje za izkoriščanje informacij iz domensko pomembnega, že označenega nabora podatkov in identificira nove namene v obravnavanem korpusu z uporabo nenadzorovanega grozdja K-means. Naša metoda presega najsodobnejše rezultate z veliko maržo do 2% in 13% na dveh referenčnih naborih podatkov, merjenih z natančnostjo grozdov. Poleg tega našo metodo uporabljamo na velikem naboru podatkov iz potovalne domene, da dokažemo njeno učinkovitost v realnem primeru uporabe.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Aiki na amfani da mai amfani da shi yana da wata matsayi cikin buɗe wani module na Fasahan Lugha na Natural (NLU) a ƙarƙashin wani na'ura na masu haɗi da AI na yanzu. A bayani, masu sani na mutum suna rubutu wani misali na misali da mazaɓa na amfani da cikin shirin ayuka dõmin ya gane na zane-zane, wanda yana da ƙanƙantar da, masu kyauta, da kuma don ya sami ɓata. Daga wannan aikin, Munã nufin mu taimake NLU masu developer da su gaura wata hanyoyi na yanzu dõmin ka gane wata kashfa na yanzu a tsakanin da aka ba da wata kalma na magana. MethoyinMu na amfani da tsarin da aka tsare mutane da ake amfani da shi zuwa tsarin bayani da aka samu da shi, wanda aka yi amfani da shi na tsarin danahan da aka yi amfani da shi, kuma yana gane na yanzu cikin makampyutan da aka tsare shi, kuma don ka yi amfani da clundin na K-ma'anar da ba'a tsare shi ba. Tayiyinmu na samar da halin-art mai girma zuwa 2% da 13% a kan data-bankers biyu, aka ƙaddara shi da ya ƙari tsari. Furan haka, za mu yi amfani da hanyoyinmu kan tsarin bayani masu girma daga gudan safari dõmin mu nuna masu amfani da halinsa a cikin duniya.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>גילוי הכוונה של המשתמש הוא צעד מפתח בפיתוח מודול להבין שפת טבעית (NLU) בלב כל מערכת AI משוחרת מודרנית. בדרך כלל, מומחים אנושיים מבקרים דגימה מייצגית של נתוני הכניסה של משתמשים כדי לגלות כוונות חדשות, שהיא סוביקטיבית, יקרה, ונוטלת לשגיאות. בעבודה הזו, אנחנו מתכוונים לסייע לפיתוחים של NLU על ידי הצגת שיטה חדשה לגלות כוונות חדשות בקנה מידה השיטה שלנו משתמשת ללמוד נוגד מבוקש כדי להשיג מידע ממערכת נתונים רלוונטית לתחום, שכבר מסומנת ומזוהה כוונות חדשות בקורפוס בידיים באמצעות קבוצת K-means לא מבוקשת. השיטה שלנו מעליפה את המצב המיוחד על ידי שווה גדולה עד 2% ו-13% על שני קבוצות נתונים של רמז, המדודה על ידי מדויקת קבוצה. חוץ מזה, אנחנו משתמשים בשיטה שלנו על קבוצת נתונים גדולה מתחום הנסיעה כדי להוכיח את היעילות שלה על מקרה שימוש בעולם אמיתי.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Ngawe Perintah Panjenengan pengguna nggawe barang kelas kuwi nggawe modul Terasar Ingkang Sampeyan (NLU) nang sampek sistem AI sing nambah. Tipik, Human Skill Nang lan iki, awak dhéwé iso nglanggar bantuan NLU pengguna-pengguna neng gewis ngulinakake tarjamahan kanggo kebebasan bingi kebutaan kanggo nguasakno perusahaan anyar. We method used super Vised contrastative Learning to raise information from a domain-responsible, before label dataset and detects new ntents in the corus at hand use unupperused K-means clustering. method We use this method on a big dataset from the time domain to show the effect on a true-world use Case.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་དམིགས་ཡུལ་དེ་རྙོགས་ཚུལ་ནི་རང་བཞིན་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་རྟོགས་ཀྱི་རྩིས་མཐུན་ཤིག་ཅིག་རེད། སྤྱིར་བཏང་བ། མི་ནོར་ཆེན་གྱིས་ལག་ལེན་པའི་ནང་འཇུག་བྱས་ཆ་གསརཔ་ཞིག་ལ་བལྟ་བུ་འཇུག་བྱེད་པའི་དཔེ་བརྗོད་རྐྱེན་བྱས་ཆོས། འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་རྩོམ་པ་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་NLU་དར་སྤེལ་པོ་ཚོར་བརྗོད་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་གསར་བ་ཞིག་སྟོན་རྒྱུ་དང་། Our method utilizes supervised contrastive learning to leverage information from a domain-relevant, already labeled dataset and identifies new intents in the corpus at hand using unsupervised K-means clustering. ང་ཚོའི་ལམ་ལུགས་འདིས་གནས་སྟངས་གཟུགས་རིས་ཀྱི་གནས་སྟངས་འདི་ཚད་གཞིར་གྱི་ཚད་གཞིར་སྟངས་གཉིས་ལས་བརྩམས་གཏོང་ཚད་གཞིར་བཟོ་བ་ཡིན། ད་དུང་། ང་ཚོས་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ཞིག་གཡིས་ཆེན་པོ་ཞིག་གིས་འགྲུལ་སྐྱོང་ཆེན་གྱིས་དོན་འཛམ་གླིང་གི་ལག་ལེན་བྱེད་</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>CS-BERT : a pretrained model for customer service dialogues<fixed-case>CS</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>: a pretrained model for customer service dialogues</title>
      <author><first>Peiyao</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Joyce</first><last>Fang</last></author>
      <author><first>Julia</first><last>Reinspach</last></author>
      <pages>130–142</pages>
      <abstract>Large-scale pretrained transformer models have demonstrated state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance in a variety of NLP tasks. Nowadays, numerous pretrained models are available in different model flavors and different languages, and can be easily adapted to one’s downstream task. However, only a limited number of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> are available for dialogue tasks, and in particular, goal-oriented dialogue tasks. In addition, the available pretrained models are trained on general domain language, creating a mismatch between the pretraining language and the downstream domain launguage. In this contribution, we present CS-BERT, a BERT model pretrained on millions of dialogues in the customer service domain. We evaluate CS-BERT on several downstream customer service dialogue tasks, and demonstrate that our in-domain pretraining is advantageous compared to other pretrained models in both zero-shot experiments as well as in finetuning experiments, especially in a low-resource data setting.</abstract>
      <url hash="b4a6387c">2021.nlp4convai-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>wang-etal-2021-cs</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.13</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>PLATO-KAG : Unsupervised Knowledge-Grounded Conversation via Joint Modeling<fixed-case>PLATO</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>KAG</fixed-case>: Unsupervised Knowledge-Grounded Conversation via Joint Modeling</title>
      <author><first>Xinxian</first><last>Huang</last></author>
      <author><first>Huang</first><last>He</last></author>
      <author><first>Siqi</first><last>Bao</last></author>
      <author><first>Fan</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Hua</first><last>Wu</last></author>
      <author><first>Haifeng</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <pages>143–154</pages>
      <abstract>Large-scale conversation models are turning to leveraging <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge">external knowledge</a> to improve the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">factual accuracy</a> in response generation. Considering the infeasibility to annotate the external knowledge for large-scale dialogue corpora, it is desirable to learn the knowledge selection and response generation in an unsupervised manner. In this paper, we propose PLATO-KAG (Knowledge-Augmented Generation), an unsupervised learning approach for end-to-end knowledge-grounded conversation modeling. For each dialogue context, the top-k relevant knowledge elements are selected and then employed in knowledge-grounded response generation. The two components of knowledge selection and response generation are optimized jointly and effectively under a balanced objective. Experimental results on two publicly available datasets validate the superiority of PLATO-KAG.</abstract>
      <url hash="8ce43e25">2021.nlp4convai-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>huang-etal-2021-plato</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.14</doi>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/holl-e">Holl-E</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wizard-of-wikipedia">Wizard of Wikipedia</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Personalized Search-based Query Rewrite System for Conversational AI<fixed-case>AI</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Eunah</first><last>Cho</last></author>
      <author><first>Ziyan</first><last>Jiang</last></author>
      <author><first>Jie</first><last>Hao</last></author>
      <author><first>Zheng</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <author><first>Saurabh</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Xing</first><last>Fan</last></author>
      <author><first>Chenlei</first><last>Guo</last></author>
      <pages>179–188</pages>
      <abstract>Query rewrite (QR) is an emerging component in conversational AI systems, reducing user defect. User defect is caused by various reasons, such as errors in the spoken dialogue system, users’ slips of the tongue or their abridged language. Many of the user defects stem from personalized factors, such as user’s speech pattern, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialect">dialect</a>, or preferences. In this work, we propose a personalized search-based QR framework, which focuses on automatic reduction of user defect. We build a personalized index for each user, which encompasses diverse affinity layers to reflect personal preferences for each user in the conversational AI. Our personalized QR system contains retrieval and ranking layers. Supported by user feedback based learning, training our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> does not require hand-annotated data. Experiments on personalized test set showed that our personalized QR system is able to correct systematic and user errors by utilizing phonetic and semantic inputs.</abstract>
      <url hash="8a3b1465">2021.nlp4convai-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>cho-etal-2021-personalized</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.17</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>AuGPT : Auxiliary Tasks and Data Augmentation for End-To-End Dialogue with Pre-Trained Language Models<fixed-case>AuGPT</fixed-case>: Auxiliary Tasks and Data Augmentation for End-To-End Dialogue with Pre-Trained Language Models</title>
      <author><first>Jonáš</first><last>Kulhánek</last></author>
      <author><first>Vojtěch</first><last>Hudeček</last></author>
      <author><first>Tomáš</first><last>Nekvinda</last></author>
      <author><first>Ondřej</first><last>Dušek</last></author>
      <pages>198–210</pages>
      <abstract>Attention-based pre-trained language models such as GPT-2 brought considerable progress to end-to-end dialogue modelling. However, they also present considerable risks for task-oriented dialogue, such as lack of knowledge grounding or diversity. To address these issues, we introduce modified training objectives for language model finetuning, and we employ massive data augmentation via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Back-translation">back-translation</a> to increase the diversity of the training data. We further examine the possibilities of combining data from multiples sources to improve performance on the target <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>. We carefully evaluate our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_complexity_theory">contributions</a> with both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_complexity_theory">human and automatic methods</a>. Our model substantially outperforms the baseline on the MultiWOZ data and shows competitive performance with state of the art in both automatic and human evaluation.</abstract>
      <url hash="5050e18c">2021.nlp4convai-1.19</url>
      <bibkey>kulhanek-etal-2021-augpt</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.19</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ufal/augpt" additional="false">ufal/augpt</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/multiwoz">MultiWOZ</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/taskmaster-1">Taskmaster-1</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Using Pause Information for More Accurate Entity Recognition</title>
      <author><first>Sahas</first><last>Dendukuri</last></author>
      <author><first>Pooja</first><last>Chitkara</last></author>
      <author><first>Joel Ruben Antony</first><last>Moniz</last></author>
      <author><first>Xiao</first><last>Yang</last></author>
      <author><first>Manos</first><last>Tsagkias</last></author>
      <author><first>Stephen</first><last>Pulman</last></author>
      <pages>243–250</pages>
      <abstract>Entity tags in human-machine dialog are integral to natural language understanding (NLU) tasks in conversational assistants. However, current systems struggle to accurately parse spoken queries with the typical use of text input alone, and often fail to understand the user intent. Previous work in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistics">linguistics</a> has identified a cross-language tendency for longer speech pauses surrounding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noun">nouns</a> as compared to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verb">verbs</a>. We demonstrate that the linguistic observation on pauses can be used to improve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> in machine-learnt language understanding tasks. Analysis of pauses in French and English utterances from a commercial voice assistant shows the statistically significant difference in pause duration around multi-token entity span boundaries compared to within entity spans. Additionally, in contrast to text-based NLU, we apply pause duration to enrich contextual embeddings to improve shallow parsing of entities. Results show that our proposed novel embeddings improve the relative error rate by up to 8 % consistently across three domains for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>, without any added annotation or alignment costs to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="df826e0f">2021.nlp4convai-1.22</url>
      <bibkey>dendukuri-etal-2021-using</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.22</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Teach Me What to Say and I Will Learn What to Pick : Unsupervised Knowledge Selection Through Response Generation with Pretrained Generative Models<fixed-case>I</fixed-case> Will Learn What to Pick: Unsupervised Knowledge Selection Through Response Generation with Pretrained Generative Models</title>
      <author><first>Ehsan</first><last>Lotfi</last></author>
      <author><first>Maxime</first><last>De Bruyn</last></author>
      <author><first>Jeska</first><last>Buhmann</last></author>
      <author><first>Walter</first><last>Daelemans</last></author>
      <pages>254–262</pages>
      <abstract>Knowledge Grounded Conversation Models are usually based on a selection / retrieval module and a generation module, trained separately or simultaneously, with or without having access to a ‘gold’ knowledge option. With the introduction of large pre-trained generative models, the selection and generation part have become more and more entangled, shifting the focus towards enhancing knowledge incorporation (from multiple sources) instead of trying to pick the best knowledge option. These approaches however depend on knowledge labels and/or a separate dense retriever for their best performance. In this work we study the unsupervised selection abilities of pre-trained generative models (e.g. BART) and show that by adding a score-and-aggregate module between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Encoder">encoder</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Codec">decoder</a>, they are capable of learning to pick the proper knowledge through minimising the language modelling loss (i.e. without having access to knowledge labels). Trained as such, our model-K-Mine-shows competitive selection and generation performance against models that benefit from knowledge labels and/or separate dense retriever.</abstract>
      <url hash="6fbace53">2021.nlp4convai-1.24</url>
      <bibkey>lotfi-etal-2021-teach</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.24</doi>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/holl-e">Holl-E</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wizard-of-wikipedia">Wizard of Wikipedia</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="25">
      <title>Influence of user personality on dialogue task performance : A case study using a rule-based dialogue system</title>
      <author><first>Ao</first><last>Guo</last></author>
      <author><first>Atsumoto</first><last>Ohashi</last></author>
      <author><first>Ryu</first><last>Hirai</last></author>
      <author><first>Yuya</first><last>Chiba</last></author>
      <author><first>Yuiko</first><last>Tsunomori</last></author>
      <author><first>Ryuichiro</first><last>Higashinaka</last></author>
      <pages>263–270</pages>
      <abstract>Endowing a task-oriented dialogue system with adaptiveness to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_(computing)">user personality</a> can greatly help improve the performance of a dialogue task. However, such a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue_system">dialogue system</a> can be practically challenging to implement, because it is unclear how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_(computing)">user personality</a> influences dialogue task performance. To explore the relationship between user personality and dialogue task performance, we enrolled participants via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crowdsourcing">crowdsourcing</a> to first answer specified personality questionnaires and then chat with a dialogue system to accomplish assigned tasks. A rule-based dialogue system on the prevalent Multi-Domain Wizard-of-Oz (MultiWOZ) task was used. A total of 211 participants’ personalities and their 633 dialogues were collected and analyzed. The results revealed that sociable and extroverted people tended to fail the task, whereas neurotic people were more likely to succeed. We extracted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_feature">features</a> related to user dialogue behaviors and performed further analysis to determine which kind of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior">behavior</a> influences task performance. As a result, we identified that average utterance length and slots per utterance are the key features of dialogue behavior that are highly correlated with both task performance and user personality.</abstract>
      <url hash="8a9c940d">2021.nlp4convai-1.25</url>
      <bibkey>guo-etal-2021-influence</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.25</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Towards Zero and Few-shot Knowledge-seeking Turn Detection in Task-orientated Dialogue Systems</title>
      <author><first>Di</first><last>Jin</last></author>
      <author><first>Shuyang</first><last>Gao</last></author>
      <author><first>Seokhwan</first><last>Kim</last></author>
      <author id="yang-liu-icsi"><first>Yang</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Dilek</first><last>Hakkani-Tur</last></author>
      <pages>281–288</pages>
      <abstract>Most prior work on task-oriented dialogue systems is restricted to supporting domain APIs. However, users may have requests that are out of the scope of these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_programming_interface">APIs</a>. This work focuses on identifying such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_(computing)">user requests</a>. Existing methods for this task mainly rely on fine-tuning pre-trained models on large annotated data. We propose a novel method, REDE, based on adaptive representation learning and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Density_estimation">density estimation</a>. REDE can be applied to zero-shot cases, and quickly learns a high-performing detector with only a few shots by updating less than 3 K parameters. We demonstrate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rede">REDE</a>’s competitive performance on DSTC9 data and our newly collected test set.</abstract>
      <url hash="bc4804fa">2021.nlp4convai-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>jin-etal-2021-towards</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4convai-1.27</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/jind11/rede" additional="false">jind11/rede</pwccode>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>