<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.mmtlrl">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-11-09">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Multimodal Machine Translation for Low Resource Languages (MMTLRL 2021)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Thoudam</first><last>Doren Singh</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Cristina</first><last>España i Bonet</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sivaji</first><last>Bandyopadhyay</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Josef</first><last>van Genabith</last></editor>
      <publisher>INCOMA Ltd.</publisher>
      <address>Online (Virtual Mode)</address>
      <month>September</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="cd3e0b50">2021.mmtlrl-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>mmtlrl-2021-multimodal</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Models and Tasks for Human-Centered Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Marine</first><last>Carpuat</last></author>
      <pages>1</pages>
      <abstract>In this talk, I will describe current research directions in my group that aim to make machine translation (MT) more human-centered. Instead of viewing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_to_machine">MT</a> solely as a task that aims to transduce a source sentence into a well-formed target language equivalent, we revisit all steps of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_to_machine">MT research and development lifecycle</a> with the goal of designing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_to_machine">MT systems</a> that are able to help people communicate across language barriers. I will present methods to better characterize the parallel training data that powers MT systems, and how the degree of equivalence impacts translation quality. I will introduce models that enable flexible conditional language generation, and will discuss recent work on framing machine translation tasks and evaluation to center human factors.</abstract>
      <url hash="1210d2dd">2021.mmtlrl-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>carpuat-2021-models</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Multimodal Simultaneous Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Lucia</first><last>Specia</last></author>
      <pages>30</pages>
      <abstract>Simultaneous machine translation (SiMT) aims to translate a continuous input text stream into another language with the lowest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latency_(engineering)">latency</a> and highest quality possible. Therefore, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation">translation</a> has to start with an incomplete source text, which is read progressively, creating the need for anticipation. In this talk I will present work where we seek to understand whether the addition of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_system">visual information</a> can compensate for the missing source context. We analyse the impact of different multimodal approaches and visual features on state-of-the-art SiMT frameworks, including fixed and dynamic policy approaches using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">reinforcement learning</a>. Our results show that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context_(language_use)">visual context</a> is helpful and that visually-grounded models based on explicit object region information perform the best. Our qualitative analysis illustrates cases where only the multimodal systems are able to translate correctly from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> into gender-marked languages, as well as deal with differences in word order, such as adjective-noun placement between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="9eebbc4e">2021.mmtlrl-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>specia-2021-multimodal</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Multimodal Neural Machine Translation System for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> to Bengali<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish to <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>engali</title>
      <author><first>Shantipriya</first><last>Parida</last></author>
      <author><first>Subhadarshi</first><last>Panda</last></author>
      <author><first>Satya Prakash</first><last>Biswal</last></author>
      <author><first>Ketan</first><last>Kotwal</last></author>
      <author><first>Arghyadeep</first><last>Sen</last></author>
      <author><first>Satya Ranjan</first><last>Dash</last></author>
      <author><first>Petr</first><last>Motlicek</last></author>
      <pages>31–39</pages>
      <abstract>Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) systems utilize additional information from other modalities beyond text to improve the quality of machine translation (MT). The additional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modality_(semiotics)">modality</a> is typically in the form of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_image">images</a>. Despite proven advantages, it is indeed difficult to develop an MMT system for various languages primarily due to the lack of a suitable multimodal dataset. In this work, we develop an MMT for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bengali_language">English- Bengali</a> using a recently published Bengali Visual Genome (BVG) dataset that contains images with associated bilingual textual descriptions. Through a comparative study of the developed MMT system vis-a-vis a Text-to-text translation, we demonstrate that the use of multimodal data not only improves the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation">translation</a> performance improvement in BLEU score of +1.3 on the development set, +3.9 on the evaluation test, and +0.9 on the challenge test set but also helps to resolve ambiguities in the pure text description. As per best of our knowledge, our English-Bengali MMT system is the first attempt in this direction, and thus, can act as a baseline for the subsequent research in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multilingualism">MMT</a> for low resource languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="bdc63cae">2021.mmtlrl-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>parida-etal-2021-multimodal</bibkey>
    <title_ar>نظام ترجمة الآلة العصبية متعدد الوسائط من الإنجليزية إلى البنغالية</title_ar>
      <title_fr>Système de traduction automatique neuronale multimodale pour l'anglais vers le bengali</title_fr>
      <title_es>Sistema de traducción automática neuronal multimodal para inglés a bengalí</title_es>
      <title_ja>英語からベンガル語へのマルチモーダルニューラルマシン翻訳システム</title_ja>
      <title_zh>英语至孟加拉语者多模态神经机器翻译统</title_zh>
      <title_pt>Sistema de tradução automática neural multimodal para inglês para bengali</title_pt>
      <title_hi>मल्टीमॉडल न्यूरल मशीन अनुवाद प्रणाली के लिए अंग्रेजी के लिए बंगाली</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Multimodal Neural Machine Translation System for English to Bengali (Система мультимодального нейронного машинного перевода с английского на бенгальский)</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Córas Ilmhódúil Néar-Aistrithe Meaisín don Bhéarla go Beangáilis</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Πολυmodal Νευρικό Μηχανολογικό Μεταφραστικό Σύστημα για Αγγλικά στα Βεγγαλικά</title_el>
      <title_hu>Multimodális neurális gépi fordító rendszer angol-bengáli nyelvre</title_hu>
      <title_it>Sistema di traduzione automatica neurale multimodale per inglese a bengalese</title_it>
      <title_kk>Ағылшын тілінде бенгалшаға көптеген нейралық машинаны аудару жүйесі</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Daugiarūšių neurologinių mašinų vertimo anglų kalba į bengalį sistema</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Мултимодилен систем за преведување на неврални машини за англиски на бенгалиName</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Sistem Terjemahan Mesin Neural Multimodal untuk Bahasa Inggeris ke Bengali</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ഇംഗ്ലീഷിലേക്കു് ഇംഗ്ലീഷിലേക്കു് ബാങ്കാലിലേക്കു് മള്‍മൊഡോള്‍ നെയുറല്‍ മെഷീന്‍ പരി</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Sistema ta’ Traduzzjoni Multimodali ta’ Magni Newrali għall-Ingliż għall-Bengali</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Англи хэлний болон Бенгалид олон моделийн мэдрэлийн машин хөгжүүлэх систем</title_mn>
      <title_no>Name</title_no>
      <title_pl>Multimodalny neuronowy system maszynowego tłumaczenia dla angielskiego na bengalski</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Multimodalni Neuralni sistem prevoda mašine za engleski na Bengali</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Sistem de traducere mașină neurală multimodală pentru engleză în bengală</title_ro>
      <title_si>බෙන්ගාලියට ඉංග්‍රීසිය සඳහා ගොඩක් මාධ්‍යමාන්‍ය පද්ධතිName</title_si>
      <title_so>Isticmaalka tarjumaadda ee afka Ingiriis ee Bengali</title_so>
      <title_ta>ஆங்கிலத்துக்கான மொழிபெயர்ப்பு மொழிபெயர்ப்பு அமைப்பு</title_ta>
      <title_sv>Multimodalt neural maskinĂ¶versĂ¤ttningssystem fĂ¶r engelska till bengali</title_sv>
      <title_ur>انگلیسی کے لئے بہت سی موڈال نیورال ماشین ترجمہ سیسٹم بنگالی سے</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Inglizcha tilidan Bengalchaga muloqat tarjima tizimi</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Hệ thống dịch máy thần kinh đa phương cho người Anh sang Bengal</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Мултимодална неврална машинен превод система за английски на бенгалски</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Multimodaal Neural Machine Translation Systeem voor Engels naar Bengaals</title_nl>
      <title_da>Multimodal Neural Machine Oversættelse System til engelsk til bengali</title_da>
      <title_hr>Multimodalni Neuralni sustav prevoda stroja za engleski na Bengali</title_hr>
      <title_ko>영어부터 방글라데시어까지의 다중모드 신경기계 번역 시스템</title_ko>
      <title_de>Multimodales neuronales maschinelles Übersetzungssystem für Englisch nach Bengali</title_de>
      <title_id>Sistem Translation Mesin Neural Multimodal untuk Bahasa Inggris ke Bengali</title_id>
      <title_sw>Multimodal Neural Machine Translation System for English to Bengali</title_sw>
      <title_fa>سیستم ترجمه ماشین عصبی برای انگلیسی به بنگالیName</title_fa>
      <title_af>Multimodaal Neurale Masjien Vertaling Stelsel vir Engels na BengaliName</title_af>
      <title_tr>캅ngiliz챌e we Bengali 챌e 체챌in 철r채n modal n채raly enjamlar terjime sistemi</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Sistemi Multimodal i Translation Neural Machine për Anglishtin në Bengali</title_sq>
      <title_am>Multimodal Neural Machine Translation System for English to Bengali</title_am>
      <title_hy>Multimodal Neural Machine Translation System for English to Bengali</title_hy>
      <title_bn>ইংরেজি থেকে বাংলায় অনুবাদ সিস্টেম</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Multimodalni Neuralni sistem prevoda mašine za engleski na Bengali</title_bs>
      <title_az>İngilizce üçün çoxlu modal Nöral Makina Çeviri Sistemi Bengalidir</title_az>
      <title_et>Multimodaalne neuroalne masintõlke süsteem inglise keelest bengali keelde</title_et>
      <title_cs>Multimodální neuronový strojový překlad systém pro angličtinu do bengálštiny</title_cs>
      <title_ca>Multimodal Machine Translation System for English to Bengali</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Multimodal Neural Machine Translation System for English to Bengali</title_fi>
      <title_sk>Multimodalni nevralni strojni prevajalski sistem za angleščino v bengali</title_sk>
      <title_ha>@ item Spelling dictionary</title_ha>
      <title_he>Multimodal Neural Machine Translation System for English to Bengali</title_he>
      <title_bo>English to Bengali</title_bo>
      <title_jv>System kanggo Inggris kanggo Bengal</title_jv>
      <abstract_pt>Os sistemas de tradução automática multimodal (MMT) utilizam informações adicionais de outras modalidades além do texto para melhorar a qualidade da tradução automática (MT). A modalidade adicional é tipicamente na forma de imagens. Apesar das vantagens comprovadas, é realmente difícil desenvolver um sistema MMT para várias linguagens principalmente devido à falta de um conjunto de dados multimodal adequado. Neste trabalho, desenvolvemos um MMT para inglês-bengali usando um conjunto de dados Bengali Visual Genome (BVG) publicado recentemente que contém imagens com descrições textuais bilíngues associadas. Através de um estudo comparativo do sistema MMT desenvolvido vis-a-vis uma tradução de texto para texto, demonstramos que o uso de dados multimodais não só melhora a melhoria do desempenho de tradução na pontuação BLEU de +1,3 no conjunto de desenvolvimento, +3,9 no teste de avaliação e +0,9 no conjunto de teste de desafio, mas também ajuda a resolver ambiguidades na descrição do texto puro. De acordo com nosso conhecimento, nosso sistema MMT inglês-bengali é a primeira tentativa nessa direção e, portanto, pode atuar como uma linha de base para a pesquisa subsequente em MMT para idiomas de baixo recurso.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Les systèmes de traduction automatique multimodale (MMT) utilisent des informations supplémentaires provenant d'autres modalités que le texte pour améliorer la qualité de la traduction automatique (MT). La modalité supplémentaire se présente généralement sous la forme d'images. Malgré des avantages avérés, il est en effet difficile de développer un système MMT pour différentes langues, principalement en raison de l'absence d'un ensemble de données multimodal approprié. Dans ce travail, nous développons un MMT pour l'anglais-bengali à l'aide d'un ensemble de données Bengali Visual Genome (BVG) récemment publié qui contient des images avec des descriptions textuelles bilingues associées. Grâce à une étude comparative du système MMT développé par rapport à une traduction de texte à texte, nous démontrons que l'utilisation de données multimodales améliore non seulement l'amélioration des performances de traduction du score BLEU de +1,3 sur l'ensemble de développement, +3,9 sur le test d'évaluation et +0,9 sur l'ensemble de test de défi, mais aide également à résoudre les ambiguïtés dans la description purement textuelle. Au mieux de nos connaissances, notre système MMT anglais-bengali est la première tentative dans cette direction et peut donc servir de base pour les recherches ultérieures sur le MMT pour les langues à faible ressource.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_es>Los sistemas de traducción automática multimodal (MMT) utilizan información adicional de otras modalidades más allá del texto para mejorar la calidad de la traducción automática (MT). La modalidad adicional suele ser en forma de imágenes. A pesar de las ventajas comprobadas, es difícil desarrollar un sistema de MMT para varios idiomas, principalmente debido a la falta de un conjunto de datos multimodal adecuado. En este trabajo, desarrollamos un MMT para inglés-bengalí utilizando un conjunto de datos del Genoma Visual Bengalí (BVG) recientemente publicado que contiene imágenes con descripciones textuales bilingües asociadas. A través de un estudio comparativo del sistema MMT desarrollado frente a una traducción de texto a texto, demostramos que el uso de datos multimodales no solo mejora la mejora del rendimiento de la traducción en la puntuación BLEU de +1.3 en el conjunto de desarrollo, +3.9 en la prueba de evaluación y +0.9 en el conjunto de pruebas de desafío, sino que también ayuda a resolver ambigüedades en la descripción de texto puro. Según nuestro leal saber y entender, nuestro sistema MMT inglés-bengalí es el primer intento en esta dirección y, por lo tanto, puede actuar como base para la investigación posterior en MMT para idiomas de bajos recursos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ar>تستخدم أنظمة الترجمة الآلية متعددة الوسائط (MMT) معلومات إضافية من طرائق أخرى بخلاف النص لتحسين جودة الترجمة الآلية (MT). الطريقة الإضافية عادة ما تكون في شكل صور. على الرغم من المزايا المثبتة ، من الصعب بالفعل تطوير نظام MMT للغات مختلفة بسبب عدم وجود مجموعة بيانات مناسبة متعددة الوسائط. في هذا العمل ، قمنا بتطوير MMT للغة الإنجليزية-البنغالية باستخدام مجموعة بيانات الجينوم المرئي البنغالي (BVG) التي تم نشرها مؤخرًا والتي تحتوي على صور ذات أوصاف نصية ثنائية اللغة مرتبطة بها. من خلال دراسة مقارنة لنظام MMT المطور مقابل ترجمة نص إلى نص ، نوضح أن استخدام البيانات متعددة الوسائط لا يؤدي فقط إلى تحسين أداء الترجمة في درجة BLEU البالغة +1.3 في مجموعة التطوير ، +3.9 في اختبار التقييم ، و +0.9 في مجموعة اختبار التحدي ولكنها تساعد أيضًا في حل الغموض في وصف النص الخالص. وفقًا لأفضل ما لدينا من معلومات ، فإن نظام MMT الإنجليزي-البنغالي الخاص بنا هو المحاولة الأولى في هذا الاتجاه ، وبالتالي ، يمكن أن يكون بمثابة الأساس للبحث اللاحق في العلاج المداوم بالميثادون للغات منخفضة الموارد.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_ru>Мультимодальные системы машинного перевода (MMT) используют дополнительную информацию из других способов, помимо текста, для улучшения качества машинного перевода (MT). Дополнительная модальность, как правило, представлена в виде изображений. Несмотря на доказанные преимущества, действительно трудно разработать систему ММТ для различных языков, в первую очередь из-за отсутствия подходящего мультимодального набора данных. В этой работе мы разрабатываем MMT для англо-бенгальского языка с использованием недавно опубликованного набора данных Бенгальского визуального генома (BVG), который содержит изображения с соответствующими двуязычными текстовыми описаниями. Сравнительное исследование разработанной системы MMT в сравнении с переводом от текста к тексту демонстрирует, что использование мультимодальных данных не только улучшает улучшение производительности перевода в баллах BLEU +1,3 на наборе разработок, +3,9 на оценочном тесте и +0,9 на наборе контрольных тестов, но и помогает устранить двусмысленности в чисто текстовом описании. Насколько нам известно, наша англо-бенгальская система MMT является первой попыткой в этом направлении, и, таким образом, может выступать в качестве основы для последующих исследований в MMT для языков с низким уровнем ресурсов.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_zh>多模式机器翻译 (MMT) 系统因文本之外附加信息以重机器翻译 (MT) 质。 附加模式常以图像见。 虽有验势,乏其多模态数据集,诚难为诸言MMT统。 于此之事,用近孟加拉语视基因组(BVG)数集发英语孟加拉语之MMT,该数集包有相关双语文本述之象。 凡开 MMT 系统与文本至文本译者较之,余证之,多模式数不惟可以重译性,BLEU开集者得分为 +1.3,评估测试为 +3.9,挑战试集为 +0.9,又有助于纯文本述中之歧义。 以吾所知,吾英语 - 孟加拉语MMT系统乃朝此一向之一试,故可以为后于卑资言语之MMT究其基线。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>मल्टीमॉडल मशीन ट्रांसलेशन (एमएमटी) सिस्टम मशीन अनुवाद (एमटी) की गुणवत्ता में सुधार करने के लिए पाठ से परे अन्य तौर-तरीकों से अतिरिक्त जानकारी का उपयोग करते हैं। अतिरिक्त रूपरेखा आमतौर पर छवियों के रूप में होती है। सिद्ध लाभों के बावजूद, मुख्य रूप से एक उपयुक्त मल्टीमॉडल डेटासेट की कमी के कारण विभिन्न भाषाओं के लिए एक एमएमटी प्रणाली विकसित करना वास्तव में मुश्किल है। इस काम में, हम हाल ही में प्रकाशित बंगाली विजुअल जीनोम (बीवीजी) डेटासेट का उपयोग करके अंग्रेजी-बंगाली के लिए एक एमएमटी विकसित करते हैं जिसमें संबंधित द्विभाषी पाठ्य विवरण के साथ छवियां होती हैं। विकसित एमएमटी प्रणाली के तुलनात्मक अध्ययन के माध्यम से एक पाठ-से-पाठ अनुवाद की तुलना में, हम प्रदर्शित करते हैं कि मल्टीमॉडल डेटा का उपयोग न केवल विकास सेट पर +1.3 के BLEU स्कोर में अनुवाद प्रदर्शन में सुधार में सुधार करता है, मूल्यांकन परीक्षण पर +3.9, और चुनौती परीक्षण सेट पर +0.9, लेकिन शुद्ध पाठ विवरण में अस्पष्टताओं को हल करने में भी मदद करता है। हमारे सर्वोत्तम ज्ञान के अनुसार, हमारी अंग्रेजी-बंगाली एमएमटी प्रणाली इस दिशा में पहला प्रयास है, और इस प्रकार, कम संसाधन भाषाओं के लिए एमएमटी में बाद के शोध के लिए एक आधार रेखा के रूप में कार्य कर सकती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ja>マルチモーダル機械翻訳（ MMT ）システムは、機械翻訳（ MT ）の品質を向上させるために、テキスト以外の他のモダリティからの追加情報を利用します。 追加のモダリティは、典型的には、画像の形態である。 実証された利点にもかかわらず、様々な言語のためのMMTシステムを開発することは、主に適切なマルチモーダルデータセットの欠如のために、実際には困難である。 この研究では、最近発表されたベンガル視覚ゲノム（ BVG ）データセットを使用して、英語とベンガル語のためのMMTを開発しています。このデータセットには、バイリンガルテキスト記述に関連する画像が含まれています。 テキスト間翻訳に対する開発されたMMTシステムの比較研究を通じて、マルチモーダルデータの使用は、開発セットのBLEUスコア+1.3、評価テストの+3.9、およびチャレンジテストセットの+0.9の翻訳パフォーマンス向上を改善するだけでなく、純粋なテキスト記述の曖昧さを解決するのに役立つことを実証します。 私たちの知る限りでは、私たちの英語-ベンガル語MMTシステムはこの方向の最初の試みであり、したがって、低資源言語のMMTにおけるその後の研究のベースラインとして機能することができます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ga>Úsáideann córais Ilmhódúla Aistriúcháin Mheacainéil (MMT) faisnéis bhreise ó mhodhanna eile seachas téacs chun cáilíocht an aistriúcháin mheaisín (MT) a fheabhsú. Is gnách go mbíonn an mhodhúlacht bhreise i bhfoirm íomhánna. In ainneoin buntáistí cruthaithe, tá sé deacair go deimhin córas MMT a fhorbairt do theangacha éagsúla go príomha mar gheall ar easpa tacar sonraí ilmhódúil oiriúnach. Sa obair seo, forbraimid MMT don Bhéarla-Beangáilis ag baint úsáide as tacar sonraí Gánóim Amhairc Bheangáilis (BVG) a foilsíodh le déanaí ina bhfuil íomhánna le cur síos téacs dátheangach bainteach. Trí staidéar comparáideach a dhéanamh ar an gcóras MMT forbartha vis-a-vis aistriúchán Téacs-go-téacs, léirímid go gcuireann úsáid sonraí ilmhódacha ní hamháin feabhas ar fheabhsú feidhmíochta aistriúcháin ar scór BLEU de +1.3 ar an tacar forbartha, +3.9 ar an tástáil mheastóireachta, agus +0.9 ar an tacar tástála dúshláin ach cuidíonn sé freisin le débhríochtaí a réiteach sa chur síos téacs íon. De réir mar is fearr is eol dúinn, is é ár gcóras MMT Béarla-Beangáilis an chéad iarracht sa treo seo, agus mar sin is féidir leis feidhmiú mar bhonnlíne don taighde ina dhiaidh sin i MMT do theangacha íseal-acmhainne.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Τα πολυμodale συστήματα μηχανικής μετάφρασης (ΜΤ) χρησιμοποιούν πρόσθετες πληροφορίες από άλλες μεθόδους πέρα από το κείμενο για να βελτιώσουν την ποιότητα της μηχανικής μετάφρασης (ΜΤ). Η πρόσθετη μέθοδος είναι συνήθως με τη μορφή εικόνων. Παρά τα αποδεδειγμένα πλεονεκτήματα, είναι πράγματι δύσκολο να αναπτυχθεί ένα σύστημα MMT για διάφορες γλώσσες κυρίως λόγω της έλλειψης κατάλληλου πολυμορφικού συνόλου δεδομένων. Σε αυτή την εργασία, αναπτύσσουμε ένα σύνολο δεδομένων για Αγγλικά-Βεγγαλικά χρησιμοποιώντας ένα πρόσφατα δημοσιευμένο σύνολο δεδομένων που περιέχει εικόνες με σχετικές δίγλωσσες περιγραφές κειμένου. Μέσα από μια συγκριτική μελέτη του αναπτυγμένου συστήματος σε σχέση με μια μετάφραση κειμένου σε κείμενο, καταδεικνύουμε ότι η χρήση πολυμορφικών δεδομένων όχι μόνο βελτιώνει τη βελτίωση της απόδοσης μετάφρασης στο σκορ ΒΛΕΕ +1.3 στο σύνολο ανάπτυξης, +3.9 στο τεστ αξιολόγησης και +0.9 στο σετ δοκιμών πρόκλησης, αλλά επίσης βοηθά στην επίλυση ασάφειας στην περιγραφή καθαρού κειμένου. Σύμφωνα με τις καλύτερες γνώσεις μας, το αγγλο-βενγκαλικό σύστημα είναι η πρώτη προσπάθεια προς αυτή την κατεύθυνση, και έτσι, μπορεί να λειτουργήσει ως βάση για την μετέπειτα έρευνα στο ΜΜΤ για γλώσσες χαμηλού πόρου.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) სისტემები დამატებული ინფორმაცია ტექსტის გარეშე სხვა მოდიალებიდან გამოიყენება მაქსინის გარეშე (MT) კაalitეტის გარეშე. დამატებული მოდიალობა ტიპულად გამოსახულების ფორმაში. თუმცა დაკავშირებული მოსახლეობები, მართლაც ძალიან რთულია MMT სისტემის განვითარება განსხვავება განსხვავებული ენებისთვის, რომლებიც პირველი იყო საჭირო მლიტმოდიალური მო ამ სამუშაოში, ჩვენ ინგლისური- ბენდალისთვის MMT-ს განვითარებთ გამოყენებული ბენდალისური ვიზუალური გენომის (BVG) მონაცემების კონფიგურაციაში, რომელიც შევყენებული ორიენგურ განვითარებული MMT სისტემის შესახებ ტექსტის ტექსტის შესახებ, ჩვენ გამოჩვენებთ, რომ მრავალმოდიალური მონაცემების გამოყენება არა მხოლოდ მუშაობის შესახებ განვითარებაში +1.3 წერტილის შესახებ განვითარებაში, +3.9 წერტილის ტესტის შესახებ და +0.9 წერტილის შესახებ, მაგრამ როგორც ჩვენი უკეთესი მეცნიერებაში, ჩვენი ინგლისური-ბენდალიური MMT სისტემა არის პირველი მოცდილობა ამ მხარეს, და ამიტომ შეიძლება იქნება, როგორც მხარეს მხარეს რესურსის ენათებისთვის</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>I sistemi di traduzione automatica multimodale (MMT) utilizzano informazioni aggiuntive provenienti da altre modalità oltre al testo per migliorare la qualità della traduzione automatica (MT). La modalità aggiuntiva è tipicamente sotto forma di immagini. Nonostante i vantaggi comprovati, è infatti difficile sviluppare un sistema MMT per varie lingue principalmente a causa della mancanza di un set di dati multimodali adeguato. In questo lavoro, sviluppiamo un MMT per inglese-bengalese utilizzando un set di dati Bengali Visual Genome (BVG) recentemente pubblicato che contiene immagini con descrizioni testuali bilingue associate. Attraverso uno studio comparativo del sistema MMT sviluppato rispetto a una traduzione testo-testo, dimostriamo che l'utilizzo di dati multimodali non solo migliora il miglioramento delle prestazioni di traduzione nel punteggio BLEU di +1,3 sul set di sviluppo, +3,9 sul test di valutazione e +0,9 sul set di test sfida, ma aiuta anche a risolvere ambiguità nella descrizione del testo puro. Come da meglio delle nostre conoscenze, il nostro sistema MMT inglese-bengalese è il primo tentativo in questa direzione, e quindi, può fungere da base per la successiva ricerca in MMT per le lingue a basso contenuto di risorse.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Daugiatransporto mašinų vertimo (MMT) sistemos naudoja papildomą informaciją, gautą taikant kitas nei teksto formas, kad pagerintų mašinų vertimo (MT) kokybę. Papildomas režimas paprastai yra vaizdų pavidalo. Nepaisant įrodytų pranašumų, iš tiesų sunku sukurti MMT sistemą įvairioms kalboms, visų pirma dėl tinkamo daugiarūšio duomenų rinkinio trūkumo. Šiame darbe parengiame MMT anglų-bengalų kalbai naudojant neseniai paskelbtą Bengalų vizualinės genomos (BVG) duomenų rinkinį, kuriame yra vaizdų su susijusiais dvikalbiais tekstiniais aprašymais. Atliekant lyginamąjį tyrimą dėl sukurtos MMT sistemos teksto vertimo į tekstą, mes įrodome, kad daugiarūšio duomenų naudojimas ne tik pagerina vertimo rezultatų pagerėjimą BLEU taške +1,3 vystymosi rinkinio, +3,9 vertinimo bandymo ir +0,9 iššūkio bandymo rinkinio, bet ir padeda išspręsti dviprasmiškumą vien teksto aprašyme. Kaip geriausiai žinome, mūsų anglų ir bengalų MMT sistema yra pirmasis bandymas šia kryptimi ir todėl gali būti tolesnių MMT mokslinių tyrimų, skirtų mažai išteklių turinčioms kalboms, pagrindu.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Мәліметтік машинаны аудару (MMT) жүйелері машинаны аудару (MT) сапасын жақсарту үшін мәтіннен артық басқа әдістерден қосымша мәліметті қолданып қолданылады. Қосымша модельдік кәдімгі кескіндер түрінде. Қолданатын мүмкіндіктерге қарамастан, бірнеше тілдер үшін MMT жүйесін жасау қиын, негізінде бірнеше көптеген көптеген деректер жинағы жоқ болғанда. Бұл жұмыс ішінде, біз ағылшын- бенгали үшін MMT жаңа жарияланған бенгали визуалдық GNOME (BVG) деректер жиынын қолдануға арналған екі тілді мәтіндік сипаттамасы бар кескіндерді жасап жатырмыз Мәтін- мен мәтін аудармасына қарсы жұмыс істеген MMT жүйесінің салыстырмалы зерттеулері арқылы, біз мәтін- мен мәтін аудармасының қолдануын тек бірнеше модалдық деректерді қолдануға қажет болмайды, жұмыс бағдарламасында +1, 3, 9 және +0, 9 және мәтін сипаттамасының ақпараттығын шешуге Біздің біліміміздің ең жақсы түрінде, ағылшын-Бенгали MMT жүйесіміз осы бағыттағы алғашқы әрекетті болып, сондықтан MMT тілдерінің келесі зерттеулерінің негізгі жолы болып тұрады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Sistem Terjemahan Mesin Multimodal (MMT) menggunakan maklumat tambahan dari modaliti lain diluar teks untuk meningkatkan kualiti terjemahan mesin (MT). Modaliti tambahan biasanya dalam bentuk imej. Walaupun keuntungan terbukti, ia benar-benar sukar untuk mengembangkan sistem MMT untuk berbagai bahasa terutama kerana kekurangan set data multimodal yang sesuai. Dalam kerja ini, kami mengembangkan MMT untuk Bahasa Inggeris-Bengali menggunakan set data Genom Visual Bengali (BVG) yang baru-baru ini diterbitkan yang mengandungi imej dengan deskripsi teks dua bahasa yang berkaitan. Melalui kajian perbandingan sistem MMT dikembangkan terhadap terjemahan Teks-ke-Teks, kami menunjukkan bahawa penggunaan data multimodal tidak hanya meningkatkan peningkatan prestasi terjemahan pada skor BLEU +1.3 pada set pengembangan, +3.9 pada ujian penilaian, dan +0.9 pada set ujian cabaran tetapi juga membantu untuk menyelesaikan ambiguiti dalam keterangan teks yang murni. As per best of our knowledge, our English-Bengali MMT system is the first attempt in this direction, and thus, can act as a baseline for the subsequent research in MMT for low resource languages.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Системите за мултимодилни машински преводи (ММТ) користат дополнителни информации од други модели надвор од текстот за подобрување на квалитетот на машински превод (МТ). Дополнителниот модел е обично во форма на слики. И покрај докажаните предности, навистина е тешко да се развие ММТ систем за различни јазици, главно поради недостатокот на соодветен мултимодилен податок. Во оваа работа, развиваме ММТ за англиско-бенгали користејќи неодамна објавен бенгалиски видовен геном (БВГ) податок кој содржи слики со поврзани двојјазични текстуални описи. Со споредлива студија на развиениот ММТ систем во однос на превод од текст до текст, ние покажуваме дека употребата на мултимодилни податоци не само што го подобрува подобрувањето на резултатот на преводот во БЛЕУ од +1,3 на составот на развој, +3,9 на тестот на евалуација, и +0,9 на составот на тестот на предизвик, туку и помага во решавањето на двоумисностите во Според нашето најдобро знаење, нашиот англиско-бенгалиски систем ММТ е првиот обид во оваа насока, и така може да дејствува како основа за следното истражување на ММТ за јазици со ниски ресурси.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_hu>A multimodális gépi fordító (MMT) rendszerek a szövegen kívül más módszerekből származó további információkat használnak fel a gépi fordítás minőségének javítása érdekében. A kiegészítő mód jellemzően képek formájában történik. A bizonyított előnyök ellenére valóban nehéz egy MMT rendszer kifejlesztése különböző nyelvekre, elsősorban a megfelelő multimodális adatkészlet hiánya miatt. Ebben a munkában egy angol-bengáli MMT-t dolgozunk ki egy nemrégiben megjelent Bengáli Visual Genome (BVG) adatkészlettel, amely kétnyelvű szöveges leírásokkal ellátott képeket tartalmaz. A fejlesztett MMT rendszer összehasonlító tanulmányozásával egy szöveg-szöveg fordítással összehasonlítottuk, hogy a multimodális adatok felhasználása nemcsak a fejlesztési készleten +1,3, az értékelési teszten +3,9 és a kihívási teszten +0,9, hanem segít a tiszta szövegleírás kétértelműségének megoldásában is. A legjobb tudásunk szerint az angol-bengáli MMT rendszerünk az első kísérlet ebben az irányban, és így alapként szolgálhat a következő MMT kutatáshoz alacsony erőforrású nyelveken.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_mt>Is-sistemi tat-Traduzzjoni Multimodali tal-Makkinarju (MMT) jużaw informazzjoni addizzjonali minn modalitajiet oħra lil hinn mit-test biex itejbu l-kwalità tat-traduzzjoni tal-makkinarju (MT). Il-modalità addizzjonali hija tipikament fil-forma ta’ immaġni. Minkejja l-vantaġġi ppruvati, huwa tabilħaqq diffiċli li tiġi żviluppata sistema MMT għal diversi lingwi primarjament minħabba n-nuqqas ta’ sett ta’ dejta multimodali adattat. F’dan ix-xogħol, qed niżviluppaw MMT għall-Ingliż-Bengali bl-użu ta’ sett ta’ dejta ppubblikat reċentement dwar il-Ġenom Viswali Bengali (BVG) li fih immaġni b’deskrizzjonijiet testwali billingwi assoċjati. Permezz ta’ studju komparattiv tas-sistema MMT żviluppata fil-konfront ta’ traduzzjoni minn test għal test, nagħmlu xhieda li l-użu ta’ dejta multimodali mhux biss itejjeb it-titjib fil-prestazzjoni tat-traduzzjoni fil-punteġġ BLEU ta’ +1.3 fuq is-sett tal-iżvilupp, +3.9 fuq it-test ta’ evalwazzjoni, u +0.9 fuq is-sett tat-test ta’ sfida iżda jgħin ukoll biex jiġu solvuti l-ambigwitajiet fid-deskrizzjoni pura tat-test. Skont l-a ħjar tagħrif tagħna, is-sistema tagħna ta’ MMT Ingliż-Bengali hija l-ewwel tentattiv f’din id-direzzjoni, u għalhekk, tista’ taġixxi bħala linja bażi għar-riċerka sussegwenti f’MMT għal lingwi b’riżorsi baxxi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>മള്‍മോഡല്‍ മെഷീന്‍ പരിഭാഷ (MMT) സിസ്റ്റത്തില്‍ നിന്നും പദാവലിയില്‍ നിന്നും കൂടുതല്‍ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു. മെഷീന്‍ പരിഭാഷ The additional modality is typically in the form of images.  വ്യത്യഭാഷകള്‍ക്ക് വേണ്ടി MMT സിസ്റ്റം ഉണ്ടാക്കുവാന്‍ വളരെ ബുദ്ധിമുട്ടുണ്ടെന്ന് തെളിയിച്ചിട്ടുണ്ടെങ്കിലും പ്രധാന ഈ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനത്തില്‍, നമ്മള്‍ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ്- ബെങ്കാലിക്ക് ഒരു എംഎംഎംടി നിര്‍മ്മിക്കുന്നു. അടുത്തുതന്നെ പ്രസിദ്ധീകരിച്ച ബംഗാലി വിസ്വ മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്തിയ MMT സിസ്റ്റം വിസ്- വിസ്- വിസ്- വിസ്സ്- ടെക്സ്റ്റ്- ടെക്സ്റ്റ്- ടെക്സ്റ്റ്- ടെക്സ്റ്റ് പരിഭാഷപ്പെടുത്തിയ ഒരു പദാവലിയുടെ ഉപയോഗം വെളുപ്പെടുത്തിയിരിക്കുന്നു, +1. 3. 9 വികസ നമ്മുടെ അറിവിന്റെ ഏറ്റവും മികച്ചപ്പോള്‍, ഞങ്ങളുടെ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ്-ബാങ്കാലി എംഎംഎംടി സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ ആദ്യത്തെ ശ്രമിക്കുന്നതാണ്, അതുകൊണ്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Мэдээллийн машины хөгжүүлэлт (MMT) системүүд машины хөгжүүлэлтийн (MT) качестыг сайжруулахын тулд мөн өөр хэлбэрээс нэмэлт мэдээллийг ашигладаг. Хамгийн нэмэлт загвар нь зурагтай хэлбэртэй. Гэхдээ олон төрлийн өгөгдлийн сангийн алдаггүй байдалд MMT системийг олон хэл дээр хөгжүүлэх нь хэцүү. Энэ ажлын тулд бид англи-бенгалийн MMT-г саяхан хэлний бичлэгийн дүрслэлтэй зураг дүрслэж байгаа Бенгалийн Визуал Геном (BVG) өгөгдлийн санг ашиглан хөгжүүлж байна. Хөгжигдсэн MMT системийн харьцуулалтын тухай харьцуулсан судалгаагаар бид олон модуль өгөгдлийн хэрэглээ зөвхөн хөгжлийн тоо дээр +1.3 болон +3.9 болон +0.9 болон шийдвэрлэлийн туршилтын тухай олон модуль өгөгдлийн хэрэглээ зөвхөн цэвэр текст тодорхойлолтын хэмжээсүүдийг шийдвэрлэхэд тусалдаг. Бидний мэдлэгийн хамгийн сайн хувьд Англи-Бенгали МТ систем бол энэ чиглэлд хамгийн эхний хичээл юм. Иймээс MMT-ийн дараагийн судалгааны үндсэн шугам болж болох юм.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Multimodalne systemy tłumaczenia maszynowego (MMT) wykorzystują dodatkowe informacje z innych sposobów poza tekstem, aby poprawić jakość tłumaczenia maszynowego (MT). Dodatkowa modalność jest zazwyczaj w postaci obrazów. Pomimo udowodnionych zalet opracowanie systemu MMT dla różnych języków jest rzeczywiście trudne, przede wszystkim ze względu na brak odpowiedniego multimodalnego zbioru danych. W niniejszej pracy opracowujemy MMT dla angielsko-bengalskiego z wykorzystaniem niedawno opublikowanego zestawu danych Bengali Visual Genome (BVG), który zawiera obrazy z powiązanymi dwujęzycznymi opisami tekstowymi. Poprzez analizę porównawczą opracowanego systemu MMT w stosunku do tłumaczenia Text-to-Text, wykazujemy, że wykorzystanie danych multimodalnych nie tylko poprawia wydajność tłumaczenia w wyniku BLEU +1,3 na zestawie deweloperskim, +3.9 na testie ewaluacyjnym oraz +0,9 na zestawie testów wyzwań, ale także pomaga rozwiązać niejasności w czystym opisie tekstu. Zgodnie z naszą najlepszą wiedzą, nasz angielsko-bengalski system MMT jest pierwszą próbą w tym kierunku, a tym samym może stanowić bazę podstawową dla późniejszych badań MMT dla języków niskich zasobów.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Multimodal maskinsomsetjingssystemer (MMT) brukar ekstra informasjon frå andre modusar over tekst for å forbetra kvaliteten på maskinsomsetjing (MT). Det fleire modulen er vanlegvis i form av bilete. Til tross beviserte fordeler, er det truleg vanskeleg å utvikla eit MMT- systemet for ulike språk først på grunn av mangling av eit passande multimodal datasett. I denne arbeida utviklar vi ein MMT for engelsk- Bengali med ein nyleg utgjeven dataset for Bengalisk visuell genom (BVG), som inneheld bilete med tilknytte bilingstekstskildringar. Gjennom eit sammenlignbare studie av den utviklingssystemet for MMT-omsetjinga mot tekst-til-tekst, viser vi at bruken av multimodal data ikkje berre forbetrar utviklingssystemet i BLEU-scoren +1,3 på utviklingssystemet, +3,9 på evalueringstest, og +0,9 på utfordringstest-settet, men også hjelper å løyse utviklingssystemet i den reine tekstskildringa. Som beste av vårt kunnskap, er det første forsøket i denne retninga i engelsk-bengalisk MMT-systemet vårt, og derfor kan handsama som grunnlinje for det følgjande forskningen i MMT for låg ressursspråk.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Sistemele de traducere automată multimodală (MMT) utilizează informații suplimentare din alte modalități dincolo de text pentru a îmbunătăți calitatea traducerii automate (MT). Modalitatea suplimentară este de obicei sub formă de imagini. În ciuda avantajelor dovedite, este într-adevăr dificil să se dezvolte un sistem MMT pentru diferite limbi, în principal din cauza lipsei unui set de date multimodal adecvat. În această lucrare, dezvoltăm un MMT pentru limba engleză-bengală folosind un set de date Bengali Visual Genom (BVG) recent publicat care conține imagini cu descrieri textuale bilingve asociate. Prin intermediul unui studiu comparativ al sistemului MMT dezvoltat în raport cu o traducere text-text, demonstrăm că utilizarea datelor multimodale nu numai că îmbunătățește performanța traducerii în scorul BLEU de +1,3 pe setul de dezvoltare, +3,9 pe testul de evaluare și +0,9 pe setul de teste provocări, dar ajută și la rezolvarea ambiguităților în descrierea textului pur. Conform celor mai bune cunoștințe ale noastre, sistemul nostru MMT engleză-bengalez este prima încercare în această direcție și, prin urmare, poate acționa ca o bază pentru cercetarea ulterioară în MMT pentru limbi cu resurse reduse.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Multimodalni sistemi prevoda mašina (MMT) koriste dodatne informacije iz drugih načina izvan teksta kako bi poboljšali kvalitet prevoda mašine (MT). Dodatna modalitet je obično u obliku slika. Uprkos dokazanim prednostima, zaista je teško razviti sistem MMT za različite jezike glavno zbog nedostatka odgovarajućeg multimodalnog seta podataka. U ovom poslu razvijemo MMT za engleski-bengali koristeći nedavno objavljenu grupu podataka Bengalijskog vizualnog genoma (BVG), koja sadrži slike sa povezanim dvojezičkim tekstualnim opisom. Kroz usporedno ispitivanje razvijenog MMT sistema u odnosu na prevod teksta do teksta, pokazujemo da upotreba multimodalnih podataka ne samo poboljšava poboljšanje učinkovitosti prevoda u BLEU rezultatu +1,3 na setu razvoja, +3,9 na testu za procjenu, i +0,9 na setu test a izazova, nego takođe pomaže da reši ambiguitet u čistom tekstu opisu. Kao najbolje od našeg znanja, naš engleski-bengalski MMT sistem je prvi pokušaj u ovom smjeru, i tako se može ponašati kao osnovna linija za sljedeće istraživanje u MMT-u za niske jezike resursa.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) system använder ytterligare information från andra metoder utöver text för att förbättra kvaliteten på maskinöversättning (MT). Den extra modaliteten är vanligtvis i form av bilder. Trots bevisade fördelar är det verkligen svårt att utveckla ett MMT-system för olika språk främst på grund av bristen på lämpliga multimodala datamängder. I detta arbete utvecklar vi ett MMT för engelsk-bengaliska med hjälp av en nyligen publicerad Bengali Visual Genome (BVG) dataset som innehåller bilder med tillhörande tvåspråkiga textbeskrivningar. Genom en jämförande studie av det utvecklade MMT-systemet gentemot en text-till-text-översättning visar vi att användningen av multimodala data inte bara förbättrar översättningsresultatens förbättring i BLEU-poäng på +1,3 på utvecklingsuppsättningen, +3,9 på utvärderingstestet och +0,9 på utmaningstestet utan också bidrar till att lösa tvetydigheter i den rena textbeskrivningen. Enligt bästa av vår kunskap är vårt engelsk-bengaliska MMT-system det första försöket i denna riktning, och kan därmed fungera som utgångspunkt för den efterföljande forskningen inom MMT för lågresursspråk.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>பல மாற்று இயந்திரம் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு (MMT) அமைப்புகள் உரைக்கும் மேலான மொழிமாற்றியின் தரம் மேம்படுத்த இயந்திரத்தை மாற்றுவதற் கூடுதல் முறைமை பிம்பங்களின் வடிவத்தில் வழக்கமாக உள்ளது. முதலில் பொருத்தமான பல தரவுத்தளத்தின் காரணத்தால் MMT முறைமையை உருவாக்க முடியும். இந்த வேலையில், நாம் ஒரு MMT ஆங்கிலம்- பெங்காலி சமீபத்தில் வெளிப்படையிடப்பட்ட பெங்காலி பார்வையுள்ள தகவல் அமைப்பை பயன்படுத்துகிறோம். இது இரு  மேம்படுத்தப்பட்ட MMT முறைமையின் ஒப்பிடுபடுத்தல் வழியாக, உரையில் இருந்து உரை மொழிபெயர்ப்பில் பயன்படுத்தல் பல முறைமையான தகவல்கள் பயன்படுத்தல் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு செயல்பாடு மேம்படுத்தலை மட்டும் மாற்றியமைக்கவில்லை முன்ன எங்கள் அறிவின் சிறந்த போது, எங்கள் ஆங்கிலத்தில்- பெங்காலி MMT அமைப்பு இந்த திசையில் முதல் முயற்சி ஆகும், அதனால், குறைந்த மூலத்திற்கு பின்வரும்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_si>Multi-mode machine translation (MMT) පද්ධතිය පද්ධතිය පද්ධතිය පරීක්ෂණය විශේෂයේ පද්ධතිය (MT) ගැන වාර්තාවක් විසින් අනිත් ප්‍රවේ පින්තූර වර්ගයක් සාමාන්‍ය වර්ගයෙන් විතරයි. ප්‍රයෝජනයක් පුළුවන් වුනා නමුත්, විවිධ භාෂාවට MMT පද්ධතියක් නිර්මාණය කරන්න ඇත්තටම අමාරුයි, මුලින්ම විවිධ මේ වැඩේ අපි ඉංග්‍රීසිය- බෙන්ගාලී වෙනුවෙන් MMT විස්තර කරනවා අවස්ථානයෙන් බෙන්ගාලි විස්තර ජීනෝම (BVG) දත්ත සෙට් එක්ක Through a comparive study of the elaborated MMT system versus a-vs a-as a Text-to-text translation, we show that the use of Multimode data not just impropers the translation Perfection in BLUE score of +1.3 on the progress set, +3.9 on the evalution testing, and +0.9 on the challenge testing set but as well as help to resolution the Ambguities in the clear text Description. අපේ දැනගන්න හොඳම දේවල් වලින්, අපේ ඉංග්‍රීසි-බෙන්ගාලි MMT පද්ධතිය තමයි මේ පැත්තේ පළමු උත්සහ කරනවා, ඒ වගේම, MMT වල පස්සේ පරීක්</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Isticmaalka turjumista machine badan (MMT) waxay isticmaalaan macluumaad dheeraad ah oo ka soo baxa qaababka kale oo aan qoraalka ka baxsan si uu u hagaajiyo quality of translation machine (MT). Noocyada dheeraadka ah waa sida caadiga ah sawirada. Inta kastoo lagu xaqiijiyey faa'iido, waa adag tahay in aad horumarinto nidaam MMT oo luqado kala duduwan ugu baahan, sababtoo ah baahida kooxaha macluumaadka kala duduwan. Markaas waxan, waxaynu horumarinnaa MMT ee ingiriisiga- Bengali isticmaalaya taariikhda la soo daabacay ee la soo daabacay ee Bengali Visual Genome (BVG) oo ku jira sawirro la xiriira qoraalka labada luuqadood. During a comparative study of the developed MMT system vis-a-vis a-vis a text-to-text translation, we demonstrate that isticmaalka data multiodal oo aan only improve beddelka performance in the BLEU score +1.3 on the development set, +3.9 on imtixaanka qiimeynta, and +0.9 on the challenge set, but also helps to resolve ambiguities in ay ku qoran sawirka daahirka ah. Sida ugu fiican aqoonteenna, nidaamka Ingiriiska-Bengali MMT waa isku dayada ugu horreeya ee halkan, sidaa darteed waxay u shaqeyn karaan sida hoose baaritaanka ugu dambeeya ee MMT luqadaha gaaban.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ur>Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) systems use additional information from other modalities beyond text to improve the quality of machine translation (MT). اضافہ موڈلیٹ معمولاً تصاویروں کی شکل میں ہے۔ اگرچہ فائدہ اثبات کی وجہ سے، بہت سی زبانوں کے لئے MMT سیستم کی تخلیق کرنا بہت مشکل ہے، سب سے پہلے ایک مناسب multimodal dataset کے ناکام ہونے کے باعث۔ اس کام میں ہم نے انگلیسی- بنگالی کے لئے ایک MMT ایجاد کیا ہے جو اچھی طرح بنگالی ویسئل جینوم (BVG) ڈاٹ سٹ کے استعمال کرتا ہے جو دو زبان کی متن کی توصیف کے ساتھ تصاویر لگاتے ہیں. ایک مقایسہ تحقیقات کے ذریعہ ایک ٹیکسٹ پر متن کی ترجمہ کے مطابق مطابق MMT سیسٹم کے مطابق، ہم دکھاتے ہیں کہ ملتی موڈال ڈیٹے کا استعمال صرف تقویم کے سٹے پر +1.3 کی ترجمہ کے فعالیت کا improving نہیں کرتا +3.9 اور +0.9 کی تحقیقات کے مطابق تست کے مطابق مطابق ہے بلکہ پاک ٹیکسٹ کی توصیف کے مطابق غیر ہمارے علم میں سے بہترین طور پر، ہماری انگلیسی-بنگالی MMT سیسٹم اس کی طرف سے پہلی کوشش ہے، اور اسی طرح، MMT میں کم سرمایہ زبانوں کے لئے اس کے بعد کی تحقیق کے لئے بنیادی لین بنا سکتا ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Qoʻshimcha usuli rasmlar shaklida. @ info Bu ishda biz yaqinda ochilgan Bengalcha Visual Genome (BVG) haqida rasmlar bilan bogʻliq tillar tarkibi bilan bogʻliq boʻlgan, ingliz- Bengalcha uchun MMT dasturini yaratishmiz. @ info: whatsthis Bizning eng yaxshi o'rganimiz haqida, bizning ingliz-Bengali MMT tizimimizning birinchi tizimi bu tizimning birinchi jarayonini ko'rsatishimiz mumkin, shunday qilib, keyingi ma'lum tillari uchun MMT ta'qidirish asosiy bazasi bo'lishi mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Hệ thống dịch cỗ máy đa chiều (MMT) sử dụng thông tin thêm từ các phương thức khác ngoài văn bản để cải thiện chất lượng dịch cỗ máy (MTV). Tính cách bổ sung thường nằm dưới hình ảnh. Mặc dù có nhiều ưu điểm, nhưng rất khó để phát triển một hệ thống MMT cho nhiều ngôn ngữ khác nhau, chủ yếu vì thiếu một bộ dữ liệu đa phương thích hợp. Trong tác phẩm này, chúng tôi phát triển một tập tin MMT cho người Anh- Bengali, nhờ một tập tin gen ảo Bengal (BKG) mới công bố, chứa ảnh với mô tả hai thứ có liên quan. Bằng một nghiên cứu tương ứng của hệ thống MMT với một bản dịch văn bản với một bản dịch, chúng tôi chứng minh rằng sử dụng các dữ liệu đa phương không chỉ cải thiện khả năng dịch của dịch trong số lệch lạc của +1.3 trong bộ phát triển, +3.9 trong thử đánh giá, và +0.9 trong tập thử thách thách được đặt, nhưng cũng giúp giải quyết các mâu thuẫn trong mô tả văn bản nguyên chất. Theo như chúng tôi biết, hệ thống MMT Anh-Bengal của chúng tôi là thử nghiệm đầu tiên ở hướng này, và có thể đóng vai một cơ sở để nghiên cứu tiếp theo ở MMT về các ngôn ngữ có ít tài nguyên.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Мултимодалните системи за машинен превод (ММТ) използват допълнителна информация от други модификации освен текста, за да подобрят качеството на машинния превод (МТ). Допълнителният модал обикновено е под формата на изображения. Въпреки доказаните предимства, наистина е трудно да се разработи ММТ система за различни езици главно поради липсата на подходящ мултимодален набор от данни. В тази работа разработихме ММТ за английско-бенгалски език, използвайки наскоро публикуван бенгалски визуален геном (БВГ), който съдържа изображения със свързани двуезични текстови описания. Чрез сравнително проучване на разработената ММТ система спрямо превод от текст към текст демонстрираме, че използването на мултимодални данни не само подобрява ефективността на превода в резултат от +1.3 на комплекта разработки, +3.9 на теста за оценка и +0.9 на комплекта изпитания, но и помага за разрешаване на двусмислици в описанието на чистия текст. Доколкото знаем, нашата английско-бенгалска ММТ система е първият опит в тази посока и по този начин може да действа като основа за последващите изследвания в ММТ за езици с нисък ресурс.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Multimodalni sustavi prevoda strojeva (MMT) koriste dodatne informacije iz drugih načina izvan teksta kako bi se poboljšala kvalitet prevoda strojeva (MT). Dodatna modalitet je obično u obliku slika. Uprkos dokazanim prednostima, zaista je teško razviti MMT sustav za različite jezike primarno zbog nedostatka odgovarajućeg multimodalnog seta podataka. U ovom poslu razvijemo MMT za engleski-bengali koristeći nedavno objavljenu skupu podataka Bengalskog vizualnog genoma (BVG), koja sadrži slike s povezanim dvojezičkim tekstualnim opisima. Prema usporedbenom ispitivanju razvijenog MMT sustava u odnosu na prevod teksta do teksta, pokazujemo da uporaba multimodalnih podataka ne samo poboljšava poboljšanje učinkovitosti prevoda u BLEU rezultatu +1,3 na određenom razvoju, +3,9 na testu za procjenu i +0,9 na određenom testu izazova, nego također pomaže rješavanju nesposobnosti u čistom opisu teksta. Kao najbolje od našeg znanja, naš engleski-bengalski MMT sustav je prvi pokušaj u ovom smjeru, i tako se može ponašati kao početak za sljedeće istraživanje u MMT-u za niske jezike resursa.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Multimodale Machine Translation (MMT)-systemen gebruiken aanvullende informatie uit andere modaliteiten dan tekst om de kwaliteit van machinevertaling (MT) te verbeteren. De extra modaliteit is meestal in de vorm van beelden. Ondanks bewezen voordelen is het inderdaad moeilijk om een MMT-systeem voor verschillende talen te ontwikkelen, vooral vanwege het ontbreken van een geschikte multimodale dataset. In dit werk ontwikkelen we een MMT voor Engels-Bengaals met behulp van een recent gepubliceerde Bengaals Visual Genome (BVG) dataset die afbeeldingen bevat met bijbehorende tweetalige tekstbeschrijvingen. Door een vergelijkende studie van het ontwikkelde MMT-systeem ten opzichte van een tekst-naar-tekst vertaling, tonen we aan dat het gebruik van multimodale data niet alleen de verbetering van de vertaalprestaties in BLEU score van +1.3 op de ontwikkelset, +3.9 op de evaluatietest en +0.9 op de challenge test set verbetert, maar ook helpt om dubbelzinnigheden in de zuivere tekstbeschrijving op te lossen. Volgens onze beste kennis is ons Engels-Bengaals MMT-systeem de eerste poging in deze richting, en dus kan fungeren als basis voor het daaropvolgende onderzoek in MMT voor low resource talen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Multimodale maskinoversættelsessystemer (MMT) bruger yderligere oplysninger fra andre metoder end tekst til at forbedre kvaliteten af maskinoversættelse (MT). Den ekstra modalitet er typisk i form af billeder. Trods dokumenterede fordele er det faktisk vanskeligt at udvikle et MMT-system til forskellige sprog primært på grund af manglen på et passende multimodalt datasæt. I dette arbejde udvikler vi et MMT til engelsk-bengalisk ved hjælp af et nyligt offentliggjort Bengali Visual Genome (BVG) datasæt, der indeholder billeder med tilhørende tosprogede tekstbeskrivelser. Gennem en sammenlignende undersøgelse af det udviklede MMT-system i forhold til en tekst-til-tekst-oversættelse viser vi, at brugen af multimodale data ikke blot forbedrer oversættelsespræstationsforbedringen i BLEU score på +1,3 på udviklingssættet, +3,9 på evalueringstesten og +0,9 på udfordringstestsættet, men også bidrager til at løse tvetydigheder i den rene tekstbeskrivelse. Vores engelsk-bengaliske MMT system er det første forsøg i denne retning, og kan således fungere som baseline for den efterfølgende forskning i MMT for lav ressource sprog.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Multimodale Machine Translation (MMT) Systeme nutzen zusätzliche Informationen aus anderen Modalitäten jenseits von Text, um die Qualität der maschinellen Übersetzung (MT) zu verbessern. Die zusätzliche Modalität ist typischerweise in Form von Bildern. Trotz nachgewiesener Vorteile ist es in der Tat schwierig, ein MMT-System für verschiedene Sprachen zu entwickeln, vor allem aufgrund des Fehlens eines geeigneten multimodalen Datensatzes. In dieser Arbeit entwickeln wir ein MMT für Englisch-Bengali unter Verwendung eines kürzlich veröffentlichten Bengali Visual Genome (BVG)-Datensatzes, der Bilder mit zugehörigen zweisprachigen Textbeschreibungen enthält. Durch eine vergleichende Studie des entwickelten MMT-Systems gegenüber einer Text-zu-Text-Übersetzung zeigen wir, dass die Verwendung multimodaler Daten nicht nur die Verbesserung der Übersetzungsleistung im BLEU-Score von +1.3 auf dem Entwicklungssatz, +3.9 auf dem Evaluationstest und +0.9 auf dem Challenge-Test verbessert, sondern auch hilft, Mehrdeutigkeiten in der reinen Textbeschreibung zu lösen. Nach bestem Wissen ist unser englisch-bengalisches MMT-System der erste Versuch in diese Richtung und kann somit als Grundlage für die anschließende Forschung in MMT für ressourcenarme Sprachen dienen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Sistem Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) menggunakan informasi tambahan dari modalitas lain diluar teks untuk meningkatkan kualitas terjemahan mesin (MT). Modalitas tambahan biasanya dalam bentuk gambar. Despite proven advantages, it is indeed difficult to develop an MMT system for various languages primarily due to the lack of a suitable multimodal dataset.  Dalam pekerjaan ini, kami mengembangkan MMT untuk bahasa Inggris-Bengali menggunakan dataset Genome Visual Bengali (BVG) yang baru-baru ini diterbitkan yang mengandung gambar dengan deskripsi tekstual bilingual yang terkait. Through a comparative study of the developed MMT system vis-a-vis a Text-to-text translation, we demonstrate that the use of multimodal data not only improves the translation performance improvement in BLEU score of +1.3 on the development set, +3.9 on the evaluation test, and +0.9 on the challenge test set but also helps to resolve ambiguities in the pure text description.  Seperti yang terbaik dari pengetahuan kita, sistem MMT Inggris-Bengali kita adalah percobaan pertama dalam arah ini, dan oleh itu, dapat bertindak sebagai dasar untuk penelitian berikutnya dalam MMT untuk bahasa sumber daya rendah.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>다중모드기계번역(MMT) 시스템은 텍스트 이외의 다른 모드의 추가 정보를 이용하여 기계번역(MT)의 질을 향상시킨다.추가 모드는 일반적으로 이미지 형식으로 존재합니다.장점이 입증됐지만, 적절한 다중모드 데이터 세트가 부족해 다양한 언어를 위한 MMT 시스템 개발이 어려운 것은 사실이다.이 작업에서 우리는 최근 발표된 방글라데시어 시각유전자조(BVG) 데이터 집합을 이용하여 영어-방글라데시어의 MMT를 개발했는데 이 데이터 집합에는 이중 언어 텍스트에 대한 설명이 담긴 이미지가 포함되어 있다.개발된 MMT 시스템과 텍스트에서 텍스트로 번역하는 것에 대한 비교 연구를 통해 우리는 다중모드 데이터를 사용하면 개발집 BLEU의 점수가 +1.3이고 평가 테스트가 +3.9이며 도전 테스트집이 +0.9인 번역 성능을 향상시킬 수 있을 뿐만 아니라 순수한 텍스트 묘사에서 잘못된 뜻을 해결하는 데도 도움이 된다는 것을 증명했다.우리의 영어-방글라데시어 MMT 시스템은 이 분야의 첫 시도인 것으로 알려져 후속 저자원 언어 MMT 연구의 기선이 될 수 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) systems utilize additional information from other modalities beyond text to improve the quality of machine translation (MT).  Utawala wa ziada ni kawaida katika picha. Pamoja na faida zilizothibitiwa, ni vigumu kuendeleza mfumo wa MMT kwa lugha mbalimbali hasa kwa sababu ya ukosefu wa taarifa zinazofaa zaidi. Katika kazi hii, tunatengeneza MMT kwa ajili ya Kiingereza- Bengali kwa kutumia taarifa za hivi karibuni zilizochapishwa na Visual Genome (BVG) ya Bengali ambayo ina picha zinazohusiana na maelezo yanayohusiana na lugha mbili. Kupitia utafiti uliobanisha mfumo wa MMT ulioanzishwa kwa namna-vis-a-tafsiri ya maandishi ya simu za mkononi, tunaonyesha kwamba matumizi ya takwimu mbalimbali sio tu kuboresha uboreshaji wa ufanisi wa tafsiri katika vipindi vya BLEU +1.3 kwenye seti ya maendeleo, +3.9 juu ya jaribio la uchunguzi, na +0.9 juu ya mtihani wa changamoto uliotengenezwa lakini pia inasaidia kutatua miongozo katika maelezo safi ya maandishi. Kama ilivyo kwa ufahamu wetu, mfumo wetu wa MMT wa Kiingereza na Bengali ni jaribio la kwanza katika mwelekeo huu, na kwa hiyo, inaweza kufanya kazi kama msingi wa utafiti wa baadaye katika lugha ndogo ya rasilimali.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>سیستم‌های ترجمه ماشین‌های چندmodal (MMT) اطلاعات اضافه از روش‌های دیگر فراتر از متن استفاده می‌کنند تا کیفیت ترجمه ماشین (MT) را بهتر کند. مدل اضافه معمولاً در شکل تصاویر است. با وجود مزاحمت ثابت شده، در واقع سیستم MMT برای زبانهای مختلف در اصل به دلیل ناتوانی یک مجموعه داده های متوسطی مناسب توسعه کردن سخت است. در این کار، ما یک MMT برای انگلیسی- بنگالی را با استفاده از یک مجموعه داده‌های بینایی بنگالی (BVG) منتشر می‌کنیم که با توصیف‌های متن‌های دو زبان ارتباط دارد. از طریق یک مطالعه مقایسه‌ای از سیستم MMT توسعه‌شده در مقابل ترجمه‌ی متن به متن، نشان می‌دهیم که استفاده از داده‌های چندین مدال تنها بهترین ترجمه‌های عملکرد ترجمه‌ای در امتحان توسعه +1.3 در مقابل توسعه +3.9 در امتحان ارزیابی و +0.9 در مجموعه‌ی امتحان چالش را بهتر می‌کند، بلکه همچنین کمک می‌کند تا به عنوان بهترین دانش ما، سیستم انگلیسی-بنگالی MMT ما اولین تلاش در این جهت است، و بنابراین، می تواند به عنوان خط بنیادی برای تحقیقات بعدی در MMT برای زبانهای منابع کم عمل کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sq>Sistemet Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) përdorin informacion shtesë nga modalitetet e tjera përtej tekstit për të përmirësuar cilësinë e përkthimit të makinave (MT). The additional modality is typically in the form of images.  Megjithë avantazhet e vërtetuara, është me të vërtetë e vështirë të zhvillohet një sistem MMT për gjuhë të ndryshme kryesisht për shkak të mungesës së një sëre të dhënash multimodale të përshtatshme. Në këtë punë, ne zhvillojmë një MMT për anglisht-bengalët duke përdorur një set të dhënash të botuar kohët e fundit për gjenom vizual bengalë (BVG) që përmban imazhe me përshkrime tekstuale të lidhura me dy gjuhë. Nëpërmjet një studimi krahasues të sistemit të zhvilluar MMT në lidhje me një përkthim teksti-në-tekst, ne demonstrojmë se përdorimi i të dhënave multimodale jo vetëm përmirëson përmirësimin e performancës së përkthimit në rezultatin BLEU të +1.3 në sistemin e zhvillimit, +3.9 në test in e vlerësimit dhe +0.9 në grupin e testit të sfidave por ndihmon gjithashtu për të zgjidhur pasiguritë në përshkrimin e thjeshtë të tekstit. Sipas njohurive tona më të mira, sistemi ynë anglo-bengali MMT është përpjekja e parë në këtë drejtim dhe kështu, mund të veprojë si bazë për kërkimin e ardhshëm në MMT për gjuhët e ulëta të burimeve.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>Multimodal machine translation (MMT) systems use additional information from other modalities beyond text to improve the quality of machine translation (MT). ጨዋታው ዓይነት በተጨማሪው መልክ በመስመር ላይ ነው፡፡ ምንም እንኳን ጥቅም ቢፈጸመ፣ በመጀመሪያ በመጠቀም ብልሃት የዳታተር ዕቅድን በመግኘት የMMT ስርዓት ለማድረግ በጣም አስቸጋሪ ነው፡፡ በዚህ ሥራ፣ በቅርብ ዘመን በተለየ የባንጋሊ Visual Genome (BVG) ዳታ-ሰርሰት የኢንጂልኛ-በንጋልኛ-ቢንጋሊ የሚታየው ምስሎችን የሚታያዩ ሁለት ቋንቋዎች የጽሑፍ ጽሑፍ ጽሑፎችን የሚያስቀምጥ ምስሎችን እናሳድጋለን፡፡ Through a comparative study of the developed MMT system vis-a-vis a Text-to-text translation, we demonstrate that the use of multimodal data not only improves the translation performance improvement in BLEU score of +1.3 on the development set, +3.9 on the evaluation test, and +0.9 on the challenge test set but also helps to resolve ambiguities in the pure text description.  በአውቀታችን የተሻለ እንደሆነ እንግሊዘኛ-በንጋሊ MMT-ስርዓታችን የዚህ መንገድ የመጀመሪያ ፈቃድ ነው፣ እንደዚሁም፣ በሚከተለው የዋናው የክፍለ ዕቃ ቋንቋዎች የMMT ጥናት መሠረት መጀመሪያ ይችላል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_tr>Çoklumodal Ullançy Terjime (MMT) sistemleri makine terjime etmeginiň (MT) kalitesini öňlemek üçin başga modlerden gowy maglumaty ullanýarlar. Edil modalitet adatça suratlar şeklinde. Birnäçe diller üçin MMT sistemini bejermek kyn. Öňünden näçe möhüm multimodal veri setiriniň ýok bolmasyna sebäbi. Bu işde, biz iňlisçe-Bengali ýa üçin iňlisçe görkezilýän bir Bengaliýa Görsel GNOME (BVG) maglumat setirini ullanýarys. MMT sisteminiň gelişmegi bilen metin terjime edilmesine görä karşılaşyklaşyklaşyk barlag bilen, multimodal maglumatyň ullanmasynyň diňe BLEU terjime etmek üçin +1.3 düzümlenmegiň düzümlenmesinde +3.9 we çözümleme testinde +0.9 netijesini çözmekde kömekleyär. Bilgimiziň iň gowy görä, iňlisçe-Bengali ýa MMT sistemimiz bu ýolyň ilkinji synanyşdyr. Şol sebäbi, MMT-iň az resurslar dilleri üçin yzyna gelen araştyrymyz üçin baseli bolup biler.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Multimodale Masjien Vertaling (MMT) stelsels gebruik addisionele inligting van ander modaliteite buite teks om die kwaliteit van masjien vertaling (MT) te verbeter. Die addisionele modaliteit is tipies in die vorm van beelde. Onthou bevestige voordeel is dit sekerlik moeilik om 'n MMT stelsel vir verskeie tale te ontwikkel vanweë die ontbreek van 'n geskikte multimodale datastel. In hierdie werk ontwikkel ons 'n MMT vir Engels- Bengali met 'n onlangs gepubliseerde Bengali Visuele genoem (BVG) datastel wat beelde bevat met geassosieerde bilinguele teksverskrifte. Deur 'n vergelykbare studie van die ontwikkelde MMT stelsel teenoor 'n Teks-na-teks vertaling, wys ons dat die gebruik van multimodale data nie slegs die vertaling-prestasie verbetering in BLES aantal van +1.3 op die ontwikkelingsstel, +3.9 op die evaluering toets, en +0.9 op die uitdagingstoets stel maar ook hulp om onbedryfde in die suiwer teks beskrywing te los. As per die beste van ons kennis, is ons Engels-Bengali MMT stelsel die eerste probeer in hierdie rigting, en daarom kan werk as 'n basilyn vir die volgende ondersoek in MMT vir lae hulpbron tale.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Մոլորմոդալ մեքենայի թարգմանման (ՄՄԹ) համակարգերը օգտագործում են ավելացյալ տեղեկատվություն տեքստից դուրս գալիս այլ մեթոդներից, որպեսզի բարելավեն մեքենայի թարգմանման (ՄԹ) որակը: Ավելի մեթոդը սովորաբար պատկերների տեսքով է: Չնայած ապացուցված առավելություններին, իսկապես դժվար է զարգացնել ՄՄԹ համակարգ տարբեր լեզուների համար, հիմնականում համապատասխանատու բազմամոդալ տվյալների բացակայության պատճառով: In this work, we develop an MMT for English- Bengali using a recently published Bengali Visual Genome (BVG) dataset that contains images with associated bilingual textual descriptions.  Համեմատական ուսումնասիրության միջոցով զարգացած ՄՄԹ համակարգի վերաբերյալ տեքստի-տեքստի թարգմանման, մենք ցույց ենք տալիս, որ բազմամոդալ տվյալների օգտագործումը ոչ միայն բարելավում է զարգացման համակարգի +1.3 գնահատականի թարգմանման արդյունքի բարելավումը, +3.9 գնահատականի թեստի և +0.9 մարտահրավերի թեստի համակարգի միջոցով Ինչպես լավագույն է մեր գիտելիքներից, մեր անգլերեն-բենգալացի ՄՄԹ համակարգը առաջին փորձն է այս ուղղությամբ, և այսպես կարող է գործել որպես հիմք ՀՄԹ-ի հետագա հետազոտությունների համար ցածր ռեսուրսների լեզուների համար:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Multimodal Makin Çeviri (MMT) sistemləri mətndən ötrü başqa modlərdən artıq məlumatları istifadə edir maşın çevirisinin keyfiyyətini artırmaq üçün (MT). Əlavə modaliyyəti genellikle şəkillərin şəkillərinin şəkilindədir. Həqiqətən, müxtəlif dillər üçün MMT sistemini təhsil etmək çox çətin bir multimodal veri seti yoxdur. Bu işdə, biz İngilizce-Bengali üçün MMT təhsil edirik ki, son zamanlarda Bengali Visual GNOME (BVG) verilən verilən verilən rəsmi ilə əlaqə edilən iki dil tekst təfsilələri ilə istifadə edir. Yaxınlaşdırılmış MMT sisteminin mətnə-mətnə çevirilməsi ilə, çoxlu modal məlumatların istifadəsi yalnızca BLEU qiymətində +1.3 qiymətlərinin düzəltməsini daha yaxşılaşdırmağını göstərdik, tədbir sınamasında +3.9 və çətin sınamasında +0.9 qiymətlərinin çətinliklərini çəkməyə kömək edir. Bizim elmimizin ən yaxşısı kimi, İngiliz-Bengali MMT sistemimiz bu tərəfdə ilk çabalayır. Beləliklə, MMT'nin sonrakı araştırmaların düşük ressurs dillərini üçün ilk dəfə olar.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Multimodalni sistemi prevoda mašina (MMT) koriste dodatne informacije iz drugih načina izvan teksta kako bi poboljšala kvalitet prevoda mašine (MT). Dodatna modalitet je obično u obliku slika. Uprkos dokazanim prednostima, zaista je teško razviti MMT sistem za različite jezike glavno zbog nedostatka odgovarajućeg multimodalnog seta podataka. U ovom poslu razvijemo MMT za engleski-bengali koristeći nedavno objavljenu grupu podataka Bengalijskog vizualnog genoma (BVG), koja sadrži slike sa povezanim dvojezičkim tekstualnim opisom. Prema usporedbenom ispitivanju razvijenog MMT sistema u odnosu na prevod teksta do teksta, pokazujemo da korištenje multimodalnih podataka ne samo poboljšava poboljšanje učinkovitosti prevoda u BLEU rezultatu +1,3 na setu razvoja, +3,9 na testu za procjenu, i +0,9 na setu izazovnih test a, već i pomaže da rješavaju nesposobnosti u čistom opisu teksta. Kao najbolje od našeg znanja, naš engleski-bengalski MMT sistem je prvi pokušaj u ovom smjeru, i tako se može ponašati kao osnovna linija za sljedeće istraživanje u MMT-u za niske jezike resursa.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_bn>মাল্টিমোডাল মেশিন অনুবাদ (MMT) সিস্টেম ব্যবহার করে মেশিন অনুবাদের মান উন্নত করার জন্য টেক্সটের বাইরে অন্যান্য মোডেল থেকে আরো  অতিরিক্ত মোডিয়াটি সাধারণত ছবির রূপে প্রদর্শন করা হয়। প্রমাণিত সুবিধা সত্ত্বেও, বিভিন্ন ভাষার জন্য এমএমটি সিস্টেম উন্নয়নের কঠিন, প্রধান মাল্টিমোডাল ডাটাসেটের অভাবের কারণে। এই কাজে আমরা ইংরেজী বাংলাদেশের জন্য এক এমএমটি তৈরি করি সম্প্রতি প্রকাশিত বাংলা ভিসুয়েল জেনোম (বিভিজি) ডাটাসেট ব্যবহার করে যা দুই ভাষায় যুক্ত ট উন্নয়নশীল এমএমটি সিস্টেম ভিস-এ-ভিসের একটি টেক্সট-থেকে টেক্সট অনুবাদের মাধ্যমে আমরা প্রমাণ করি যে বিলিউ স্কোরের ব্যবহার শুধুমাত্র অনুবাদের উন্নয়নের পরীক্ষার ব্যাপারে + ১. ৩. আমাদের জ্ঞানের সবচেয়ে ভালোভাবে আমাদের ইংরেজী বাংলা এমএমটি সিস্টেম এই দিকে প্রথম প্রচেষ্টা হচ্ছে, আর তাই এমএমটির পরবর্তী সম্পদের গবেষণার জন্য কম</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>Els sistemes multimodals de traducció de màquines (MMT) utilitzen informació adicional d'altres modalitats més enllà del text per millorar la qualitat de traducció de màquines (MT). La modalitat adicional està típicament en forma d'imatges. Malgrat les proves d'avantatges, és realment difícil desenvolupar un sistema MMT per diverses llengües, principalment a causa de la falta d'un conjunt de dades multimodals adequat. En aquesta obra, desenvolupem un MMT per anglès-bengalès utilitzant un conjunt de dades del genoma visual bengalès (BVG) publicat recentment que conté imatges amb descripcions textuals bilingues associades. Through a comparative study of the developed MMT system vis-a-vis a Text-to-text translation, we demonstrate that the use of multimodal data not only improves the translation performance improvement in BLEU score of +1.3 on the development set, +3.9 on the evaluation test, and +0.9 on the challenge test set but also helps to resolve ambiguities in the pure text description.  Segons el nostre coneixement, el nostre sistema MMT anglo-bengalí és el primer intent en aquesta direcció, i per tant, pot actuar com a base per a la recerca posterior en MMT per llengües de baix recursos.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Multimodální strojový překlad (MMT) systémy využívají další informace z jiných modalit mimo text, aby zlepšily kvalitu strojového překladu (MT). Další modalita je typicky ve formě obrazů. Navzdory prokázaným výhodám je skutečně obtížné vyvinout MMT systém pro různé jazyky především kvůli nedostatku vhodného multimodálního datového souboru. V této práci vyvíjíme MMT pro angličtinu-bengálštinu s využitím nedávno publikovaného Bengálského Visual Genome (BVG) datového souboru obsahujícího obrázky s přidruženými dvojjazyčnými textovými popisy. Prostřednictvím srovnávací studie vyvinutého MMT systému vůči textovému překladu ukazujeme, že použití multimodálních dat nejen zlepšuje zlepšení výkonnosti překladu v BLEU skóre +1,3 na vývojové sadě, +3.9 na hodnotícím testu a +0,9 na testové sadě výzvy, ale také pomáhá řešit nejasnosti v čistém textovém popisu. Podle našich nejlepších znalostí je náš anglicko-bengálský MMT systém prvním pokusem v tomto směru, a proto může sloužit jako základ pro následný výzkum MMT pro jazyky s nízkými zdroji.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Multimodaalisten konek채채nn철sj채rjestelmien (MMT) avulla voidaan parantaa konek채채nn철ksen laatua my철s muilla tavoin kuin tekstill채. Lis채muoto on tyypillisesti kuvien muodossa. Todistetuista eduista huolimatta MMT-j채rjestelm채n kehitt채minen eri kielille on todella vaikeaa p채채asiassa sopivan multimodaalisen aineiston puuttumisen vuoksi. T채ss채 ty철ss채 kehit채mme englannin ja bengalin MMT:n k채ytt채en 채skett채in julkaistua bengalin visuaalista genomia (BVG) sis채lt채v채채 aineistoa, joka sis채lt채채 kuvia ja niihin liittyvi채 kaksikielisi채 tekstuaalisia kuvauksia. Kehitetyn MMT-j채rjestelm채n vertailevan tutkimuksen avulla voidaan osoittaa, ett채 multimodaalisen datan k채ytt철 ei ainoastaan paranna k채채nn철ksen suorituskyky채 BLEU-pisteell채 +1,3 kehityssarjassa, +3,9 arviointitestiss채 ja +0,9 haastetestiss채, vaan auttaa my철s ratkaisemaan ep채selvyyksi채 puhtaan tekstin kuvauksessa. Tietojemme mukaan englanti-bengali MMT-j채rjestelm채 on ensimm채inen yritys t채h채n suuntaan, ja n채in ollen se voi toimia perustana my철hemmille MMT-tutkimuksille v채h채varaisille kielille.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Mitmeliigilised masintõlke süsteemid kasutavad masintõlke kvaliteedi parandamiseks lisateavet muudest viisidest peale teksti. Lisavõimalus on tavaliselt kujutiste kujul. Hoolimata tõestatud eelistest on MMT-süsteemi väljatöötamine erinevate keelte jaoks tõepoolest raske peamiselt sobiva mitmeliigilise andmekogumi puudumise tõttu. Selles töös töötame välja MMT inglise- bengali keele jaoks, kasutades hiljuti avaldatud Bengali visuaalse genoomi (BVG) andmekogumit, mis sisaldab pilte, millel on seotud kakskeelsed tekstikirjeldused. Arendatud MMT süsteemi võrdleva uuringu kaudu tekstist tekstisse tõlkimisega näitame, et mitmeliigiliste andmete kasutamine mitte ainult ei paranda tõlketõhususe paranemist BLEU skoori +1,3 arenduskomplektis, +3,9 hindamistestis ja +0,9 väljakutsetestis, vaid aitab ka lahendada mitmetähendusi puhta teksti kirjelduses. Meie parimate teadmiste kohaselt on meie inglise-bengali MMT süsteem esimene katse selles suunas ja seega võib see toimida lähtekohana hilisematele MMT-uuringutele vähese ressursiga keeltele.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_he>Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) systems utilize additional information from other modalities beyond text to improve the quality of machine translation (MT).  המודיאליות הנוספת היא בדרך כלל בצורה של תמונות. למרות יתרונות מווכחות, באמת קשה לפתח מערכת MMT לשפות שונות בעיקר בגלל חוסר קבוצת מידע מולטומודאלית מתאימה. בעבודה הזאת, אנחנו מפתחים MMT לאנגלית-בנגאלית בשימוש בסט נתונים של גנום חזותי בנגאלי (BVG) שהופרסם לאחרונה באמצעות מחקר שיוותי של מערכת MMT מפותחת בנוגע לתרגום טקסט-לטקסט, אנו מראים שהשימוש במידע רב-מודלי לא רק משפר את שיפור ביצועי התרגום בתוצאה BLEU של +1.3 על קבוצת הפיתוח, +3.9 על מבחן הערכה, ו +0.9 על קבוצת מבחן האתגר, אלא גם עוזר לפתור את השפעות בתיאור הטקסט הטהור. לפי הידע הטוב ביותר שלנו, מערכת MMT אנגלית-בנגלית שלנו היא הניסיון הראשון בכיוון הזה, וכך, יכול לפעול כבסיס למחקר אחר כך ב MMT לשפות משאבים נמוכות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>@ info: whatsthis Tsarin da aka ƙara yana cikin tsarin zane. Inã da ingawa da aka jarraba amfani, sai ya yi nau'i a buɗa'in ka buɗa wata na MMT na cikin harshen dabam-daban, maimainlin da ba'a zartar da wani tsari mai daidai na mutumodal. Daga wannan aikin, munã buɗe wata MMT wa Ingiriya- Bangali da aka yi amfani da wani danne na fassarar da aka yanzu ta bangali Fassarar (BV G) wanda ke ƙunsa da zane da fassaran rubutun biyu na'ura. Daga wani littãfi na daidai da aka buɗe na MMT-na-tusa a-fassarar-matsayin-zuwa-text, za mu nuna cẽwa istinin multiodal data bã zai ƙara wa tsarin ajin fassarar gabanin na BLEU na nau'in na+1.3 na daidaita, +3.9 a kan jarrabar evaluation, da kuma+0.9 kan jarrabar muhalli, amma yana taimako ya bayyana ambigui cikin description mai tsari na rubutu. Kama kyakkyawan ilimu, na'urarmu na Ingiriya-Bangali MMT ne na farkon jarraba cikin wannan hanyar, kuma kamar haka, yana iya iya aikin kama bango ga research na daban cikin MMT wa lugha masu ƙaranci.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Multimodalni sistemi strojnega prevajanja (MMT) uporabljajo dodatne informacije iz drugih načinov razen besedila za izboljšanje kakovosti strojnega prevajanja (MT). Dodatna modalnost je običajno v obliki slik. Kljub dokazanim prednostim je sistem MMT za različne jezike resnično težko razviti predvsem zaradi pomanjkanja ustreznega multimodalnega nabora podatkov. V tem delu smo razvili MMT za angleško-bengalščino z uporabo nedavno objavljenega bengalskega vizualnega genoma (BVG), ki vsebuje slike s povezanimi dvojezičnimi besedilnimi opisi. S primerjalno študijo razvitega MMT sistema v primerjavi s prevodom besedila v besedilo dokazujemo, da uporaba multimodalnih podatkov ne le izboljšuje izboljšanje prevajalske uspešnosti pri rezultatih BLEU za +1,3 na razvojnem nizu, +3,9 na evalvacijskem testu in +0,9 na izzivnem testu, temveč tudi pomaga odpraviti dvoumnosti pri opisu čistega besedila. Po našem najboljšem znanju je naš angleško-bengalski MMT sistem prvi poskus v to smer in tako lahko deluje kot osnova za nadaljnje raziskave MMT za jezike z nizkimi viri.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>Multimodal Machine Translation (MMT) systems use additional information from other modalities beyond text to improve the quality of machine translation (MT). སྣང་ཚུལ་ཁྱད་པར་ནི་བརྙན་རིས་ཀྱི་དབྱིབས་ཡོད་པ་རེད། སྐྱོན་རྐྱེན་ཚད་ལྟ་བུ་ཞིག་ཡིན་ནའང་མ་ཟད། རིགས་སྔར་ཐབས་ལམ་འདྲ་བའི་སྐད་རིགས་ཤིག་ཆགས་ཐབས་མེད། ལས་ཀ་འདི་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོས་ཉེ་ཆར་དཔར་བསྐྲུན་ཡོད་པའི་བེན་སྤྱོད་པའི་ཨིན་ཇིའི་ལྟ་བུའི་ཇི་ནོམ། Through a comparative study of the developed MMT system vis-a-vis a Text-to-text translation, we demonstrate that the use of multimodal data not only improves the translation performance improvement in BLEU score of +1.3 on the development set, +3.9 on the evaluation test, and +0.9 on the challenge test set but also helps to resolve ambiguities in the pure text description. ང་ཚོའི་ཤེས་ཡོད་ཚད་ལྷན་ཤེས་ཚད་ལྡན་པའི་དབྱིན་ཡིག་གཟུགས་བ་ཅིག་ཡིན།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_jv>Multimodal Mas Terjamahan (mm T) sistem kang gambar informasi tambahan nang modalitat sing wis ambang teks kanggo nggawe kalitas karo terjamahan (MT). modalité tambah dipun wae dadi neng sampeyan gambar. Ingat kabèh bener, kuwi susahe kanggo nggawe sistem LTT kanggo langgar sampeyan uga wigatining dadi multimodal. Nan barêng-barêng iki, kita sampeyan SMT kanggo ngilanggar-Bengal kuwi ngulinakake dipuluhayé BenGali Visual GNOME (BVG) dadi sing sampeyan gambar barang kelangan textual sing sampeyan gambar. Ato sampeyan karo sistem nggunakaké sistem LTT sing nggawe tarjamahan karo teks-karo teks nggambar, kéné sumulakno ngono nggawe data multimodal kuwi jenis nglanggar tarjamahan kanggo nyenggap tarjamahan karo suku + 1.3 kanggo nggawe geranggap tarjamahan kanggo nyenggap tarjamahan liyane + 3.9 kanggo nyenggap ujaran tentang, lan + 0.9 kanggo nyenggap ujaran oleh nuné beraksi sing berarti ujar Awak dhéwé luwih apik dhéwé, sistem ingkang Bengal-Bengal kuwi sistem sing sampeyan anyar iki ning diralah iki, lan ngono, iso diangubah sing beraksi kanggo ngerasakno sing sumulai tarjamahan kanggo ngilanggar nggambar uwis kuwi nggo langkung banjuré.</abstract_jv>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>