<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.smm4h">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Sixth Social Media Mining for Health (#SMM4H) Workshop and Shared Task</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Arjun</first><last>Magge</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ari</first><last>Klein</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Antonio</first><last>Miranda-Escalada</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mohammed Ali</first><last>Al-garadi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ilseyar</first><last>Alimova</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Zulfat</first><last>Miftahutdinov</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Eulalia</first><last>Farre-Maduell</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Salvador Lima</first><last>Lopez</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ivan</first><last>Flores</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Karen</first><last>O'Connor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Davy</first><last>Weissenbacher</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elena</first><last>Tutubalina</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Abeed</first><last>Sarker</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Juan M</first><last>Banda</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Martin</first><last>Krallinger</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Graciela</first><last>Gonzalez-Hernandez</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Mexico City, Mexico</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="85c83d62">2021.smm4h-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="dd6d7630">2021.smm4h-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>smm4h-2021-social</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>View Distillation with Unlabeled Data for Extracting Adverse Drug Effects from User-Generated Data</title>
      <author><first>Payam</first><last>Karisani</last></author>
      <author><first>Jinho D.</first><last>Choi</last></author>
      <author><first>Li</first><last>Xiong</last></author>
      <pages>7–12</pages>
      <abstract>We present an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a> based on multi-layer transformers for identifying Adverse Drug Reactions (ADR) in social media data. Our model relies on the properties of the problem and the characteristics of contextual word embeddings to extract two views from documents. Then a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> is trained on each view to label a set of unlabeled documents to be used as an initializer for a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> in the other view. Finally, the initialized classifier in each view is further trained using the initial training examples. We evaluated our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> in the largest publicly available ADR dataset. The experiments testify that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> significantly outperforms the transformer-based models pretrained on domain-specific data.</abstract>
      <url hash="dca91337">2021.smm4h-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>karisani-etal-2021-view</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>The ProfNER shared task on automatic recognition of occupation mentions in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> : systems, evaluation, guidelines, embeddings and corpora<fixed-case>P</fixed-case>rof<fixed-case>NER</fixed-case> shared task on automatic recognition of occupation mentions in social media: systems, evaluation, guidelines, embeddings and corpora</title>
      <author><first>Antonio</first><last>Miranda-Escalada</last></author>
      <author><first>Eulàlia</first><last>Farré-Maduell</last></author>
      <author><first>Salvador</first><last>Lima-López</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis</first><last>Gascó</last></author>
      <author><first>Vicent</first><last>Briva-Iglesias</last></author>
      <author><first>Marvin</first><last>Agüero-Torales</last></author>
      <author><first>Martin</first><last>Krallinger</last></author>
      <pages>13–20</pages>
      <abstract>Detection of occupations in texts is relevant for a range of important application scenarios, like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Competitive_intelligence">competitive intelligence</a>, sociodemographic analysis, legal NLP or health-related occupational data mining. Despite the importance and heterogeneous data types that mention <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Job">occupations</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_mining">text mining</a> efforts to recognize them have been limited. This is due to the lack of clear annotation guidelines and high-quality Gold Standard corpora. Social media data can be regarded as a relevant source of information for real-time monitoring of at-risk occupational groups in the context of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandemic">pandemics</a> like the COVID-19 one, facilitating intervention strategies for occupations in direct contact with infectious agents or affected by mental health issues. To evaluate current NLP methods and to generate resources, we have organized the ProfNER track at SMM4H 2021, providing ProfNER participants with a Gold Standard corpus of manually annotated tweets (human IAA of 0.919) following annotation guidelines available in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_language">Spanish</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, an occupation gazetteer, a machine-translated version of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">tweets</a>, and FastText embeddings. Out of 35 registered teams, 11 submitted a total of 27 runs. Best-performing participants built <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> based on recent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP technologies</a> (e.g. transformers) and achieved 0.93 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-score">F-score</a> in Text Classification and 0.839 in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named-entity_recognition">Named Entity Recognition</a>. Corpus : https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4309356</abstract>
      <url hash="e48e2e6a">2021.smm4h-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>miranda-escalada-etal-2021-profner</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Transformer-based Multi-Task Learning for Adverse Effect Mention Analysis in Tweets</title>
      <author><first>George-Andrei</first><last>Dima</last></author>
      <author><first>Dumitru-Clementin</first><last>Cercel</last></author>
      <author><first>Mihai</first><last>Dascalu</last></author>
      <pages>44–51</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents our contribution to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media_mining">Social Media Mining</a> for Health Applications Shared Task 2021. We addressed all the three subtasks of Task 1 : Subtask A (classification of tweets containing adverse effects), Subtask B (extraction of text spans containing adverse effects) and Subtask C (adverse effects resolution). We explored various pre-trained transformer-based language models and we focused on a multi-task training architecture. For the first subtask, we also applied adversarial augmentation techniques and we formed model ensembles in order to improve the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robustness_(computer_science)">robustness</a> of the prediction. Our system ranked first at Subtask B with 0.51 F1 score, 0.514 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">precision</a> and 0.514 recall. For Subtask A we obtained 0.44 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">F1 score</a>, 0.49 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">precision</a> and 0.39 recall and for Subtask C we obtained 0.16 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">F1 score</a> with 0.16 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">precision</a> and 0.17 recall.</abstract>
      <url hash="a7a8d292">2021.smm4h-1.7</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.7</doi>
      <bibkey>dima-etal-2021-transformer</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/smm4h">SMM4H</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>UACH-INAOE at SMM4H : a BERT based approach for classification of COVID-19 Twitter posts<fixed-case>UACH</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>INAOE</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>SMM</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>: a <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> based approach for classification of <fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 <fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter posts</title>
      <author><first>Alberto</first><last>Valdes</last></author>
      <author><first>Jesus</first><last>Lopez</last></author>
      <author><first>Manuel</first><last>Montes</last></author>
      <pages>65–68</pages>
      <abstract>This work describes the participation of the Universidad Autnoma de Chihuahua-Instituto Nacional de Astrofsica, ptica y Electrnica team at the Social Media Mining for Health Applications (SMM4H) 2021 shared task. Our team participated in task 5 and 6, both focused on the automatic classification of Twitter posts related to COVID-19. Task 5 was oriented on solving a binary classification problem, trying to identify self-reporting tweets of potential cases of COVID-19. Task 6 objective was to classify tweets containing COVID-19 symptoms. For both tasks we used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> based on bidirectional encoder representations from transformers (BERT). Our objective was to determine if a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> pretrained on a corpus in the domain of interest can outperform one trained on a much larger general domain corpus. Our F1 results were encouraging, 0.77 and 0.95 for task 5 and 6 respectively, having achieved the highest score among all the participants in the latter.</abstract>
      <url hash="2893b80e">2021.smm4h-1.10</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.10</doi>
      <bibkey>valdes-etal-2021-uach</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Word Embeddings, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosine_similarity">Cosine Similarity</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">Deep Learning</a> for Identification of Professions &amp; Occupations in Health-related Social Media</title>
      <author><first>Sergio</first><last>Santamaría Carrasco</last></author>
      <author><first>Roberto</first><last>Cuervo Rosillo</last></author>
      <pages>74–76</pages>
      <abstract>ProfNER-ST focuses on the recognition of professions and occupations from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a> using Spanish data. Our participation is based on a combination of word-level embeddings, including pre-trained Spanish BERT, as well as cosine similarity computed over a subset of entities that serve as input for an encoder-decoder architecture with attention mechanism. Finally, our best score achieved an F1-measure of 0.823 in the official test set.</abstract>
      <url hash="569439cf">2021.smm4h-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.12</doi>
      <bibkey>santamaria-carrasco-cuervo-rosillo-2021-word</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>A Joint Training Approach to Tweet Classification and Adverse Effect Extraction and Normalization for SMM4H 2021<fixed-case>SMM</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>H</fixed-case> 2021</title>
      <author><first>Mohab</first><last>Elkaref</last></author>
      <author><first>Lamiece</first><last>Hassan</last></author>
      <pages>91–94</pages>
      <abstract>In this work we describe our submissions to the Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. We investigated the effectiveness of a joint training approach to Task 1, specifically classification, extraction and normalization of Adverse Drug Effect (ADE) mentions in English tweets. Our approach performed well on the normalization task, achieving an above average f1 score of 24 %, but less so on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a> and extraction, with f1 scores of 22 % and 37 % respectively. Our experiments also showed that a larger dataset with more negative results led to stronger results than a smaller more balanced dataset, even when both datasets have the same positive examples. Finally we also submitted a tuned BERT model for Task 6 : Classification of Covid-19 tweets containing symptoms, which achieved an above average f1 score of 96 %.</abstract>
      <url hash="afac2480">2021.smm4h-1.16</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.16</doi>
      <bibkey>elkaref-hassan-2021-joint</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Uma abordagem de treinamento conjunto para classificação de tweets e extração e normalização de efeitos adversos para SMM4H 2021</title_pt>
      <title_zh>SMM4H 2021之推文类不良反应取与归一化合训练方法</title_zh>
      <title_ar>نهج تدريبي مشترك لتصنيف التغريدات واستخراج التأثير الضار والتطبيع لـ SMM4H 2021</title_ar>
      <title_es>Un enfoque de entrenamiento conjunto para la clasificación de tuits y la extracción y normalización de efectos adversos para SMM4H 2021</title_es>
      <title_ja>SMM 4 H 2021のためのツイート分類と有害作用抽出と正規化のための共同トレーニングアプローチ</title_ja>
      <title_hi>SMM4H 2021 के लिए वर्गीकरण और प्रतिकूल प्रभाव निष्कर्षण और सामान्यीकरण ट्वीट करने के लिए एक संयुक्त प्रशिक्षण दृष्टिकोण</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Cur Chuige Comhpháirteach Oiliúna maidir le hAicmiú Tweet agus Eastóscadh agus Normalú Tionchair Dhíobhálacha do SMM4H 2021</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Μια κοινή εκπαιδευτική προσέγγιση για την ταξινόμηση και την εξαγωγή δυσμενών επιπτώσεων και την ομαλοποίηση για το SMM4H 2021</title_el>
      <title_hu>Közös képzési megközelítés a Tweet osztályozására és a negatív hatások kivonására és normalizálására az SMM4H 2021-ben</title_hu>
      <title_kk>SMM4H 2021 бағдарламасының жалпы оқыту жағдайы Tweet классификациясы және қарсы эффекттерді тарқату және нормализациясы</title_kk>
      <title_lt>A Joint Training Approach to Tweet Classification and Adverse Effect Extraction and Normalization for SMM4H 2021</title_lt>
      <title_it>Un approccio formativo congiunto per la classificazione dei Tweet e l'estrazione e la normalizzazione degli effetti avversi per SMM4H 2021</title_it>
      <title_mk>Заеднички пристап на обука за класификација на Твит и екстракција и нормализација на негативни ефекти за SMM4H 2021</title_mk>
      <title_mt>Approċċ Konġunt tat-Taħriġ għall-Klassifikazzjoni tat-Tweet u l-Estrazzjoni u n-Normalizzazzjoni tal-Effetti Avversi għall-SMM4H 2021</title_mt>
      <title_ms>A Joint Training Approach to Tweet Classification and Adverse Effect Extraction and Normalization for SMM4H 2021</title_ms>
      <title_no>Name</title_no>
      <title_ml>SM4H 2021-ന് വേണ്ടി ടൂട്ടിക്ലാസിക്ഷനും പ്രഭാവം പുറത്തെടുക്കുന്നതിനും നോര്‍മാലിഷഷനിലേക്കും ഒരു യൂണ്ട് പരിശീലിയുട</title_ml>
      <title_mn>SMM4H 2021 оны тусламжтайгаар хуваалцах, эсрэг нөлөө гаргах, нормализацийн тусламжтайгаар</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Wspólne podejście szkoleniowe do klasyfikacji Tweet oraz ekstrakcji i normalizacji skutków niepożądanych dla SMM4H 2021</title_pl>
      <title_ro>O abordare comună de formare pentru clasificarea Tweet și extragerea și normalizarea efectelor adverse pentru SMM4H 2021</title_ro>
      <title_so>A Joint Training Approach to Tweet Classification and Adverse Effect Extraction and Normalization for SMM4H 2021</title_so>
      <title_sr>Joint Training Approach to Tweet Classification and Adverse Effects Extraction and Normalization for SMM4H 2021</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_sv>En gemensam utbildningsmetod för tweetklassificering och extraktion av negativa effekter och normalisering för SMM4H 2021</title_sv>
      <title_ur>Name</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>A Liên kết huấn luyện tiếp cận chắp vá và hiệu ứng xấu cho khí cao su</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Съвместен обучителен подход за класификация и извличане и нормализиране на неблагоприятни ефекти за СММ4Х 2021</title_bg>
      <title_da>En fælles uddannelsesmetode til tweetklassificering og ekstraktion og normalisering af negative virkninger for SMM4H 2021</title_da>
      <title_nl>Een gezamenlijke trainingsaanpak voor tweetclassificatie en extractie en normalisatie van nadelige effecten voor SMM4H 2021</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Zajednički pristup obuke klasifikaciji i izvlačenju nuspojava i normalizaciji SMM4H 2021</title_hr>
      <title_id>A Joint Training Approach to Tweet Classification and Adverse Effect Extraction and Normalization for SMM4H 2021</title_id>
      <title_sw>Mafunzo ya pamoja ya Kupata Makosoleo ya Twita na Kutokana na Utoa na Uhalifu kwa SMM4H 2021</title_sw>
      <title_fa>Name</title_fa>
      <title_de>Ein gemeinsamer Trainingsansatz zur Tweet Klassifizierung und Extraktion und Normalisierung von unerwünschten Wirkungen für SMM4H 2021</title_de>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_tr>SMM4H 2021</title_tr>
      <title_ko>SMM4H 2021 트위터 분류, 악영향 추출 및 표준화된 합동훈련 방법</title_ko>
      <title_sq>Një metodë e përbashkët stërvitjeje për klasifikimin e Tweet-it dhe nxjerrjen dhe normalizimin e efekteve të dëmshme për SMM4H 2021</title_sq>
      <title_hy>SMM4H 2021</title_hy>
      <title_am>A Joint Training Approach to Twitter Classification and Adverse Effect Extraction and Normalization for SMM4H 2021</title_am>
      <title_az>SMM4H 2021 üçün Tövyt Klasifikasyonu və Tövrat Etkinlik Extraction və Normalizasyonu</title_az>
      <title_bs>Zajednički pristup treninga za klasifikaciju i izvlačenje nuspojava i normalizaciju SMM4H 2021</title_bs>
      <title_bn>এসএমএম৪হ ২০২১ এর জন্য টুইট ক্লাসিকেশন এবং প্রভাব বহিস্কার এবং স্বাভাবিক প্রশিক্ষণের একটি যুক্ত প্রশিক্ষণ</title_bn>
      <title_cs>Společný tréninkový přístup k klasifikaci tweetů a extrakci a normalizaci nežádoucích účinků pro SMM4H 2021</title_cs>
      <title_et>SMM4H 2021 ühine koolitusmeetod Tweet klassifitseerimiseks ja kahjuliku mõju ekstraheerimiseks ja normaliseerimiseks</title_et>
      <title_ca>Un enfocament conjunt de formació a la classificació de Tweet i extracció i normalització d'efectes adversos per SMM4H 2021</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Yhteinen koulutusmenetelmä twiittien luokitteluun ja haitallisten vaikutusten poistoon ja normalisointiin SMM4H 2021</title_fi>
      <title_ha>A Join Training Approach to Twitter Classification and Adverse Effect Extration and Namalization for SMM4H 2021</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Skupni pristop usposabljanja za klasifikacijo Tweet ter ekstrakcijo in normalizacijo škodljivih učinkov za SMM4H 2021</title_sk>
      <title_bo>A Joint Training Approach to Tweet Classification and Adverse Effect Extraction and Normalization for SMM4H 2021</title_bo>
      <title_jv>Name</title_jv>
      <title_he>גישה משותפת לאימונים לציוד טוויט והוציאה והנורמליזציה של SMM4H 2021</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>في هذا العمل ، نصف تقديماتنا إلى المهمة المشتركة للتعدين على وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي من أجل الصحة (SMM4H) 2021. لقد حققنا في فعالية نهج التدريب المشترك للمهمة 1 ، وتحديداً تصنيف واستخراج وتطبيع تأثيرات الأدوية الضارة (ADE) المذكورة في التغريدات الإنجليزية. كان أداء مقاربتنا جيدًا في مهمة التطبيع ، حيث حققت درجة F1 أعلى من المتوسط بنسبة 24 ٪ ، ولكن أقل من ذلك في التصنيف والاستخراج ، مع درجات f1 بنسبة 22 ٪ و 37 ٪ على التوالي. أظهرت تجاربنا أيضًا أن مجموعة بيانات أكبر ذات نتائج سلبية أكثر أدت إلى نتائج أقوى من مجموعة بيانات أصغر وأكثر توازناً ، حتى عندما تحتوي كلتا مجموعتي البيانات على نفس الأمثلة الإيجابية. أخيرًا ، قدمنا أيضًا نموذج BERT مضبوطًا للمهمة 6: تصنيف تغريدات Covid-19 التي تحتوي على أعراض ، والتي حققت درجة أعلى من المتوسط بنسبة 96 ٪.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Neste trabalho descrevemos nossas submissões para a Tarefa Compartilhada Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021. Investigamos a eficácia de uma abordagem de treinamento conjunto para a Tarefa 1, especificamente classificação, extração e normalização de menções de Efeitos Adversos de Drogas (ADE) em tweets em inglês. Nossa abordagem teve um bom desempenho na tarefa de normalização, alcançando uma pontuação f1 acima da média de 24%, mas menos na classificação e extração, com pontuações f1 de 22% e 37%, respectivamente. Nossos experimentos também mostraram que um conjunto de dados maior com mais resultados negativos levou a resultados mais fortes do que um conjunto de dados menor e mais balanceado, mesmo quando ambos os conjuntos de dados têm os mesmos exemplos positivos. Por fim, também enviamos um modelo BERT ajustado para a Tarefa 6: Classificação de tweets Covid-19 contendo sintomas, que alcançou uma pontuação f1 acima da média de 96%.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>En este trabajo describimos nuestras presentaciones a la Tarea Compartida Minería de Redes Sociales para la Salud (SMM4H) 2021. Investigamos la eficacia de un enfoque de entrenamiento conjunto para la Tarea 1, específicamente la clasificación, extracción y normalización de las menciones de los efectos adversos de los medicamentos (ADE) en los tuits en inglés. Nuestro enfoque tuvo un buen desempeño en la tarea de normalización, logrando una puntuación f1 superior a la media del 24%, pero menos en clasificación y extracción, con puntuaciones f1 del 22% y 37% respectivamente. Nuestros experimentos también mostraron que un conjunto de datos más grande con resultados más negativos condujo a resultados más sólidos que un conjunto de datos más pequeño y equilibrado, incluso cuando ambos conjuntos de datos tienen los mismos ejemplos positivos. Finalmente, también presentamos un modelo BERT ajustado para la Tarea 6: Clasificación de los tuits de Covid-19 que contienen síntomas, que logró una puntuación f1 superior a la media del 96%.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>この作業では、ソーシャルメディア・マイニング・フォー・ヘルス（ SMM 4 H ） 2021シェアードタスクへの提出物について説明します。私たちは、タスク1への共同トレーニングアプローチ、特に英語のツイートでの有害薬物効果（ ADE ）の分類、抽出、および正規化の有効性を調査しました。私たちのアプローチは正規化タスクでうまく機能し、平均以上のf 1スコア24 ％を達成しましたが、分類と抽出ではそれほど高くなく、f 1スコアはそれぞれ22 ％と37 ％でした。私たちの実験では、ネガティブな結果が多い大きなデータセットは、両方のデータセットが同じポジティブな例を持っている場合でも、より小さくバランスの取れたデータセットよりも強力な結果をもたらすことも示されました。最後に、私たちはまた、タスク6 ：症状を含むCovid -19ツイートの分類のための調整されたBERTモデルを提出しました。これは、平均f 1スコア96 ％を上回る成績を達成しました。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>于兹之事,述我于社交媒体(SMM4H)2021共其材。 按1合训练方法之有效性,特英语推文中药物不良反应(ADE)之类,提取标准化。 吾道见善于归一化,f1得分高于平均水平24%,而取类则下,f1得分为22%37%。 吾实验犹明,多负面之数集比小而衡,虽两数同正示例亦如之。 为任6取一BERT:含其Covid-19推文,其f1得分高于平均水平96%。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>इस काम में हम स्वास्थ्य के लिए सोशल मीडिया माइनिंग (SMM4H) 2021 साझा कार्य के लिए हमारी प्रस्तुतियों का वर्णन करते हैं। हमने कार्य 1 के लिए एक संयुक्त प्रशिक्षण दृष्टिकोण की प्रभावशीलता की जांच की, विशेष रूप से वर्गीकरण, निष्कर्षण और प्रतिकूल दवा प्रभाव (एडीई) के सामान्यीकरण का उल्लेख अंग्रेजी ट्वीट्स में किया गया है। हमारे दृष्टिकोण ने सामान्यीकरण कार्य पर अच्छा प्रदर्शन किया, 24% के ऊपर के औसत f1 स्कोर को प्राप्त किया, लेकिन वर्गीकरण और निष्कर्षण पर कम, क्रमशः 22% और 37% के f1 स्कोर के साथ। हमारे प्रयोगों से यह भी पता चला है कि अधिक नकारात्मक परिणामों के साथ एक बड़े डेटासेट ने एक छोटे से अधिक संतुलित डेटासेट की तुलना में मजबूत परिणाम दिए, भले ही दोनों डेटासेट में समान सकारात्मक उदाहरण हों। अंत में हमने टास्क 6 के लिए एक ट्यून किए गए BERT मॉडल को भी प्रस्तुत किया: लक्षणों वाले कोविद -19 ट्वीट्स का वर्गीकरण, जिसने 96% के औसत से ऊपर का औसत f1 स्कोर हासिल किया।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>San obair seo déanaimid cur síos ar ár n-aighneachtaí don Tasc Comhroinnte um Mhianadóireacht ar na Meáin Shóisialta le haghaidh Sláinte (SMM4H) 2021. Rinneamar imscrúdú ar éifeachtúlacht cur chuige comhoiliúna i leith Tasc 1, go sonrach aicmiú, asbhaint agus normalú tagairtí i dtvuíteanna Béarla a bhaineann le Éifeacht Dhíobhálach Drugaí (ADE). D’fheidhmigh ár gcur chuige go maith ar an tasc normalaithe, ag baint amach scór f1 os cionn an mheáin de 24%, ach ní ba lú ná sin maidir le haicmiú agus asbhaint, le scóir f1 de 22% agus 37% faoi seach. Léirigh ár dturgnaimh freisin gur tháinig torthaí níos láidre as tacar sonraí níos mó le torthaí níos diúltaí ná tacar sonraí níos lú níos cothroime, fiú nuair a bhíonn na samplaí dearfacha céanna ag an dá thacar sonraí. Mar fhocal scoir chuireamar isteach freisin múnla tiúnta BERT le haghaidh Tasc 6: Aicmiú tvuíteanna Covid-19 ina bhfuil airíonna, a bhain amach scór f1 os cionn an mheáin de 96%.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ამ სამუშაოში ჩვენ 2021 წლის სოციალური მედიაში საზოგადოება (SMM4H) სხვა სამუშაო სამუშაო სამუშაო დავალებათ. ჩვენ განსხვავით ერთადერთი განსწავლების პროგრამის ეფექტიკურობას, განსაკუთრებით კლასიფიკაცია, ექსტრექცია და ნორმალიზაცია ინგლისური tweets-ში. ჩვენი პროგორმაცია ნორმალიზაციის რაოდენობაში კარგი გავაკეთებულია, რომელიც უფრო მეორე f1 წოდენობა 24%-ის, მაგრამ უფრო მეორე კლასიფიკაცია და ექსტრაქცია, რომელიც f1 წოდენობა 22 ჩვენი ექსპერიმენტები ასევე გამოჩვენეთ, რომ უფრო დიდი მონაცემების კონფიგურაცია, რომელიც უფრო მინდა უფრო დიდი მონაცემების კონფიგურაცია, უფრო მცირე ბა საბოლოოდ ჩვენ ასევე გადავიტანეთ განსხვავებული BERT მოდელი 6-ის დავალებისთვის: Covid-19 tweets-ის კლასიფიკაცია, რომლებიც სიმპტომები აქვს, რომელიც საშუალოდ მეტი f1 მოდელი 96%.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Ebben a munkában bemutatjuk a Közösségi Média Bányászat az Egészségért (SMM4H) 2021 Megosztott Feladatához való beadványainkat. Megvizsgáltuk az 1. feladat közös képzési megközelítésének hatékonyságát, különösen a mellékhatás (ADE) besorolását, extrakcióját és normalizálását angol tweetekben. Megközelítésünk jól teljesített a normalizációs feladatban, 24%-os átlag feletti f1 pontszámot ért el, de kevésbé osztályozást és extrakciót, 22%-os, illetve 37%-os f1 pontszámot. Kísérleteink azt is mutatták, hogy egy nagyobb, negatív eredményekkel rendelkező adatkészlet erősebb eredményeket eredményezett, mint egy kisebb, kiegyensúlyozottabb adatkészlet, még akkor is, ha mindkét adatkészlet ugyanazon pozitív példával rendelkezik. Végezetül benyújtottunk egy hangolt BERT modellt a 6. feladathoz: A tüneteket tartalmazó Covid-19 tweetek osztályozása, amely az átlag feletti f1 pontszámot érte el 96%.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Σε αυτή την εργασία περιγράφουμε τις υποβολές μας στην Κοινή Εργασία Κοινωνικών Μέσων Εξόρυξης για την Υγεία (Κοινή Εργασία). Ερευνήσαμε την αποτελεσματικότητα μιας κοινής εκπαιδευτικής προσέγγισης στην εργασία 1, συγκεκριμένα την ταξινόμηση, εξαγωγή και ομαλοποίηση των αναφορών ανεπιθύμητων φαρμάκων (ADE) στα αγγλικά tweets. Η προσέγγισή μας πέτυχε καλά στο έργο ομαλοποίησης, επιτυγχάνοντας μια ανώτερη βαθμολογία f1 24%, αλλά λιγότερο στην ταξινόμηση και εξαγωγή, με βαθμολογίες f1 22% και 37% αντίστοιχα. Τα πειράματά μας έδειξαν επίσης ότι ένα μεγαλύτερο σύνολο δεδομένων με περισσότερα αρνητικά αποτελέσματα οδήγησε σε ισχυρότερα αποτελέσματα από ένα μικρότερο πιο ισορροπημένο σύνολο δεδομένων, ακόμα και όταν και τα δύο σύνολα δεδομένων έχουν τα ίδια θετικά παραδείγματα. Τέλος, υποβάλαμε επίσης ένα συντονισμένο μοντέλο για την εργασία 6: Ταξινόμηση tweets που περιέχουν συμπτώματα, το οποίο πέτυχε μια ανώτερη από τον μέσο όρο βαθμολογία των 96%.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл жұмыста 2021 жылы Ортақ тапсырманың социалдық медиа балауына (SMM4H) жіберімізді таңдаймыз. Біз 1- тапсырма үшін біріктірілген оқыту тәсілдігін зерттедік, осындай-ағылшын tweets тізімінде айтылатын қарсы наркотикалық эффекттерді (ADE) тарқату және нормализациялау. Біздің қасиетіміз нормализациялау тапсырмасында жақсы орындалды, орташа f1 нүктесі 24% деп жеткізді, бірақ қасиетті және тарқатуға арналған, f1 нүктесі 22% мен 37% деп жеткізді. Біздің тәжірибеміз сондай-ақ кейбір негативті нәтижелерден үлкен деректер жинағы бірнеше нәтижелерді балансирован деректер жинағынан күш нәтижелерді көрсетуге болады. Екі дер Соңында біз сондай-ақ 6- тапсырма үшін BERT үлгісін жібердік: Covid-19 tweets классификациясы бар симптомдар бар, ол орташа f1 деңгейіндегі 96% деңгейінде жеткізді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_it>In questo lavoro descriviamo i nostri contributi al Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Abbiamo esaminato l'efficacia di un approccio formativo congiunto al Task 1, in particolare classificazione, estrazione e normalizzazione delle menzioni di effetti avversi della droga (ADE) nei tweet inglesi. Il nostro approccio ha funzionato bene nel compito di normalizzazione, raggiungendo un punteggio f1 superiore alla media del 24%, ma meno sulla classificazione e l'estrazione, con punteggi f1 rispettivamente del 22% e del 37%. I nostri esperimenti hanno anche dimostrato che un set di dati più ampio con risultati più negativi ha portato a risultati più forti di un set di dati più piccolo e bilanciato, anche quando entrambi i set di dati hanno gli stessi esempi positivi. Infine abbiamo presentato anche un modello BERT sintonizzato per Task 6: Classificazione dei tweet Covid-19 contenenti sintomi, che ha raggiunto un punteggio superiore alla media di f1 del 96%.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame darbe apibūdiname savo pareiškimus Socialinės žiniasklaidos kasybos sveikatos srityje (SMM4H) 2021 m. bendrai užduočiai. We investigated the effectiveness of a joint training approach to Task 1, specifically classification, extraction and normalization of Adverse Drug Effect (ADE) mentions in English tweets.  Mūsų metodas gerai atliko normalizacijos užduotį, pasiekti didesnį nei vidutinis f1 balas 24 %, bet mažiau klasifikacijos ir ekstrakcijos atveju, o f1 balai atitinkamai 22 % ir 37 %. Mūsų eksperimentai taip pat parodė, kad didesnis duomenų rinkinys su labiau neigiamais rezultatais sukėlė didesnius rezultatus nei mažesnis labiau subalansuotas duomenų rinkinys, net jei abu duomenų rinkiniai turi tokių pačių teigiamų pavyzdžių. Galiausiai taip pat pateikėme pritaikytą BERT model į 6 uždaviniui: Covid-19 tweetų klasifikavimas su simptomais, kurie pasiekė didesnį nei vidutinis f1 balas 96 %.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ ജോലിയില്‍ നമ്മുടെ സോഷ്യല്‍ മീഡിയ മിനിങ്ങിന്‍റെ കീഴടങ്ങള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ വിവരിച്ചുകൊടുക്കുന്നു. ആശ്വാസത്തിന്‍റെ മിനിങ് ടാസ്ക് 1-ലേക്കുള്ള യൂട്ട് ട്രെയിനിലേക്കുള്ള പരിശീലനത്തിന്റെ പ്രവർത്തികമാണ് ഞങ്ങള്‍ അന്വേഷിച്ചു. പ്രത്യേകിച്ച് വിശേഷം വിവരങ് നമ്മുടെ സമ്പാദ്യം സാധാരണ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിക്കുന്നതില്‍ നന്നായി പ്രവര്‍ത്തിച്ചു. ശരാരം എഫ്‌1 സ്കോര്‍ 24 ശതമാനത്തിന് മീതെ എത്തുന്നതാണ്, പക്ഷെ ക്ലാസ്ഫി നമ്മുടെ പരീക്ഷണങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചു കൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നത് കൂടുതല്‍ നെഗേറ്റീവ് ഫലങ്ങളുള്ള വലിയ ഡാറ്റാസറ്റുകള്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ ശക്തമായ ഫലങ്ങള്‍ കാ Finally we also submitted a tuned BERT model for Task 6: Classification of Covid-19 tweets containing symptoms, which achieved an above average f1 score of 96%.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_ms>Dalam kerja ini kami menggambarkan penghantaran kami kepada Media Sosial Menyembah Kesehatan (SMM4H) 2021 Tugas Berkongsi. Kami menyelidiki kegunaan pendekatan latihan bersama untuk Tugas 1, secara khusus klasifikasi, ekstraksi dan normalisasi kesan dadah (ADE) disebut dalam tweet Inggeris. Pendekatan kami berjalan dengan baik pada tugas normalisasi, mencapai skor f1 di atas rata-rata 24%, tetapi kurang pada klasifikasi dan ekstraksi, dengan skor f1 22% dan 37% respectively. Our experiments also showed that a larger dataset with more negative results led to stronger results than a smaller more balanced dataset, even when both datasets have the same positive examples.  Akhirnya, kami juga menghantar model BERT yang sesuai untuk Tugas 6: Pengklasifikasi tweet Covid-19 yang mengandungi gejala, yang mencapai skor f1 di atas rata-rata 96%.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ ажлын хувьд бид 2021 оны нийгмийн мэдээллийн салбарын багасгал хөрөнгө оруулалтыг тайлбарлаж байна. Бид 1-р ажил дээр хамтдаа сургалтын үр дүнг судалж, ялангуяа англи хэлний tweets дээр хэлж байгаа эсрэг наркотийн эффект (ADE) нэмэгдүүлэх, хадгалах болон нормализацийг судалсан. Бидний арга хэмжээний ажил дээр сайн ажиллаж байлаа. Дунд дундаж f1 хувь нь 24%-той хүртэл, гэхдээ хэмжээний хувьд, хадгалах нь бага байлаа. f1 хувьд 22%-37%-той бага байлаа. Бидний туршилтууд мөн илүү сөрөг үр дүнтэй том өгөгдлийн санг баланслагдсан өгөгдлийн санаас илүү хүчтэй үр дүнг үзүүлсэн. Хоёр өгөгдлийн санг ижил эерэг жишээлүүд байсан ч гэсэн. Эцэст нь бид мөн ажил 6-ын BERT загварыг дамжуулсан: Covid-19 tweets-ийн классификацийн шинж тэмдэгтийг агуулсан бөгөөд энэ нь дундаж f1 оноо 96% гарсан.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mk>Во оваа работа ги опишуваме нашите поднесувања на Социјалните медиуми за здравство (SMM4H) 2021 заедничка задача. Ја истражувавме ефикасноста на заедничкиот пристап на обука кон задачата 1, специфично класификација, екстракција и нормализација на спомените на Негативниот ефект на дрогата (АДЕ) на англиски твитови. Our approach performed well on the normalization task, achieving an above average f1 score of 24%, but less so on classification and extraction, with f1 scores of 22% and 37% respectively.  Нашите експерименти, исто така, покажаа дека поголем компјутер податоци со поголеми негативни резултати доведоа до посилни резултати отколку помал побалансиран компјутер податоци, дури и кога двата компјутери податоци имаат исти позит Конечно, исто така, поднесовме приспособен модел БЕРТ за задачата 6: Класификација на твитовите Covid-19 кои содржат симптоми, кој постигна над просечната оценка f1 од 96 отсто.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ro>În această lucrare descriem depunerile noastre la Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Am investigat eficacitatea unei abordări comune de instruire a sarcinii 1, în special clasificarea, extragerea și normalizarea mențiunilor de efect advers al medicamentului (ADE) în tweeturile în limba engleză. Abordarea noastră s-a descurcat bine în sarcina de normalizare, obținând un scor f1 peste medie de 24%, dar mai puțin în clasificare și extracție, cu scoruri f1 de 22% și respectiv 37%. Experimentele noastre au arătat, de asemenea, că un set de date mai mare cu rezultate mai negative a dus la rezultate mai puternice decât un set de date mai mic, mai echilibrat, chiar și atunci când ambele seturi de date au aceleași exemple pozitive. În cele din urmă, am prezentat, de asemenea, un model BERT reglat pentru Sarcina 6: Clasificarea tweeturilor Covid-19 conținând simptome, care a obținut un scor f1 peste medie de 96%.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>W niniejszej pracy opisujemy nasze zgłoszenia do Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Badaliśmy skuteczność wspólnego podejścia szkoleniowego do zadania 1, w szczególności klasyfikacji, ekstrakcji i normalizacji wzmianek o niepożądanym efekcie leku (ADE) w angielskich tweetach. Nasze podejście sprawdziło się dobrze w zadaniu normalizacyjnym, osiągając ponadśredni wynik f1 24%, ale mniej w klasyfikacji i ekstrakcji, z wynikami f1 odpowiednio 22% i 37% . Nasze eksperymenty wykazały również, że większy zbiór danych z większymi negatywnymi wynikami prowadził do silniejszych wyników niż mniejszy bardziej zrównoważony zbiór danych, nawet jeśli oba zbiory danych mają te same pozytywne przykłady. Na koniec przedstawiliśmy również dostrojony model BERT dla zadania 6: Klasyfikacja tweetów Covid-19 zawierających objawy, który osiągnął ponadśredni wynik f1 96%.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>I denne arbeiden beskriver vi våre søknader til den sosiale mediamining for helse (SMM4H) 2021 delte oppgåva. Vi undersøkte effektiviteten av ein samanlig treningstilnærming til oppgåve 1, spesifikke klassifisering, ekstrahering og normalisering av Adverse Drug Effect (ADE) som er avgjeven i engelsk tweets. Nærminga vårt utførte godt på normaliseringsdata, og når det gjennomsnittlig f1- poeng på 24%, men mindre så på klassifikasjon og utpakking, med f1- poeng på 22% og 37%. Eksperimentane våre viste også at ein større dataset med meir negativ resultat førte til sterke resultat enn ein mindre meir balansert dataset, sjølv når begge dataset har samme positiv eksemplar. I slutt har vi også sendt ein tunert BERT-modell for oppgåve 6: Classification of Covid-19 tweets containing symptoms, which achieved an above average f1 score of 96%.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_mt>F’din il-ħidma niddeskrivu s-sottomissjonijiet tagħna lill-Minjieri tal-Midja Soċjali għas-Saħħa (SMM4H) 2021 Kompitu Konġunt. Investigajna l-effikaċja ta’ approċċ konġunt ta’ taħriġ għall-Kompitu 1, speċifikament klassifikazzjoni, estrazzjoni u normalizzazzjoni ta’ msemmija fl-Effett Avversi tal-Mediċin a (ADE) fit-tweets bl-Ingliż. L-approċċ tagħna wettaq tajjeb fuq il-kompitu ta’ normalizzazzjoni, u kiseb punteġġ f1 ogħla mill-medja ta’ 24%, iżda inqas hekk fuq il-klassifikazzjoni u l-estrazzjoni, b’punteġġi f1 ta’ 22% u 37% rispettivament. L-esperimenti tagħna wrew ukoll li sett ta’ dejta akbar b’riżultati aktar negattivi wassal għal riżultati aktar b’saħħithom minn sett ta’ dejta iżgħar aktar ibbilanċjat, anki meta ż-żewġ settijiet ta’ dejta jkollhom l-istess eżempji pożittivi. Finally we also submitted a tuned BERT model for Task 6: Classification of Covid-19 tweets containing symptoms, which achieved an above average f1 score of 96%.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_sr>U ovom poslu opisujemo svoje podatke za rudarstvo socijalnih medija za zdravlje (SMM4H) 2021. zajedničkom zadatku. Istražili smo učinkovitost zajedničkog pristupa obuke zadatku 1, posebno klasifikaciji, ekstrahaciji i normalizaciji nuspojava na engleskim tweetima. Naš pristup je dobro obavljen na normalizacijskom zadatku, ostvario iznad prosječnog f1 rezultata od 24%, ali manje na klasifikaciji i izvlačenju, sa f1 rezultatima od 22% i 37%. Naši eksperimenti su takođe pokazali da je veća kompleta podataka sa više negativnih rezultata dovela do jača rezultata od manje balanciranije kompleta podataka, čak i kada oba kompleta podataka imaju isti pozitivni primer. Na kraju smo takođe predali i napravljeni model BERT za zadatak 6: klasifikacija Covid-19 tweets koji sadrže simptome, koji je postigao iznad prosječnog f1 rezultata od 96%.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ වැඩේ අපි 2021 සාමාජික මිඩියාව ස්වාස්ථ්‍ය විධානය (SMM4H) වෙනුවෙන් අපේ පිළිබඳින් විස්තර කරනවා. අපි පරීක්ෂණය කළා සාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රශ්නයක් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශේෂයෙන්, ප්‍රශ්නයක් සහ සාමාන්‍ය ව්‍යාප්‍ති අපේ ප්‍රමාණය සාමාන්‍ය වැඩේ හොඳයි, සාමාන්‍ය වැඩි වැඩිය f1 ප්‍රමාණයක් 24%, නමුත් වැඩිය සහ ප්‍රමාණය සඳහා ප්‍රමාණය සඳහා ප්‍රමාණය සඳහා f1 අපේ පරීක්ෂණය පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන් විශාල දත්ත සෙට් එක්ක වඩා විශාල ප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රති අන්තිමේදී අපි අන්තිමේදී වැඩ 6 වෙනුවෙන් සම්පූර්ණ BERT මොඩේලයක් පිළිගත්තා: කෝවිඩ්-19 ට්විට් වලට සංකේතයක් තියෙන්න</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>I det här arbetet beskriver vi våra bidrag till Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Vi undersökte effektiviteten av en gemensam utbildningsmetod för uppgift 1, specifikt klassificering, extraktion och normalisering av Adverse Drug Effect (ADE) omnämningar i engelska tweets. Vårt tillvägagångssätt presterade bra på normaliseringsuppgiften och uppnådde en f1-poäng över genomsnittet på 24%, men mindre på klassificering och extraktion, med f1-poäng på 22% respektive 37%. Våra experiment visade också att en större datamängd med mer negativa resultat ledde till starkare resultat än en mindre mer balanserad datamängd, även när båda datauppsättningarna har samma positiva exempel. Slutligen lämnade vi också in en justerad BERT-modell för Uppgift 6: Klassificering av Covid-19 tweets innehållande symtom, som uppnådde en poäng över genomsnittet f1 på 96%.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Shaqadan ayaannu ku qoraynaa hoosaysiintayada daryeelka caafimaadka bulshada (SMM4H) 2021 Shaqada la sharciyey. Waxaannu baaraynay waxyaabaha ay u leedahay qaabka iskuulka waxbarashada wadajirka ah ee shaqada 1, si gaar ah u kala soocaynta, soo bixinta iyo caadooyinka arimaha dawooyinka ee afka Ingiriiska. Dhaqdhaheenna waxay si wanaagsan u sameeyeen shaqada caadiga ah, waxayna gaadheen qiimaha ugu badnaan iskuulka f1 oo ah 24%, laakiin wax ka yar fasaxa iyo ka bixinta, iskuulka f1 ee ugu dhexeeya 22% iyo 37 boqolkiiba. Imtixaankayada ayaa sidoo kale muujiyey in kooban macluumaad ka weyn oo ay ku jiraan matooyin wax ka badan, waxay sababtay resulto ka sii xoogaysan in ka sii yar sameynta macluumaadka, xataa marka labada database ay haystaan tusaalooyin isku mid ah. Ugu dambaysta waxaan sidoo kale u soo dhiibnay Tusaale BERT oo loo qoray shaqo 6: Kalajarida qoraalka Covid-19 oo ku jira calaamado, taasoo gaadhay iskuul ka badan f1 boqolkiiba 96 boqolkiiba.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ur>اس کام میں ہم نے 2021 شریک ٹاکس کے لئے سوسیل میڈیا مینینگ (SMM4H) کے ذریعے اپنے مسائل کو توصیح دیتے ہیں. ہم نے تاسک ۱ کے ساتھ ایک جوڑ ترینسی طریقے کے مطابق تحقیق کی، مخصوصاً کلاسیفوں، اخراج اور عاملی انگلیسی ٹویٹوں میں ذکر کی۔ ہمارا طریقہ عامل کرنے کے کام پر بہت اچھا کام کیا گیا تھا، ایک متوسط f1 اسکو 24% کی پہنچ رہا تھا، لیکن بہت کم طریقہ اور اخراج کے ذریعہ، اور f1 اسکو 22% اور 37% کے ذریعہ. ہماری آزمائش نے بھی دکھائی کہ بہت بڑے ڈاٹ سٹ کے ساتھ بہت منفی نتیجے کے ساتھ ایک چھوٹے برالیس ڈاٹ سٹ سے زیادہ قوی نتیجے پہنچائے، اگرچہ دونوں ڈاٹ سٹ ایک مثبت مثال ملے آخر میں ہم نے ٹاکس 6 کے لئے ایک تنظیم BERT موڈل بھیجا تھا: Covid-19 ٹویٹ کے کلاسیفٹ کے ذریعہ نشانیاں حامل ہوئے ہیں، جو ایک متوسط f1 اسکور 96 درصد تک پہنچ گئے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த வேலையில் நாம் எங்கள் சமூக ஊடகத்திற்கு ஒப்புக்கொள்ள விவரிக்கிறோம் சோதனைக்கு (SMM4H) 2021 பகிர்ந்த பணியை கூட்ட நாங்கள் செயல் 1 க்கு ஒரு இணைய பயிற்சி செயல்பாட்டின் விளைவுகளை ஆய்வு செய்தோம், குறிப்பாக வகுப்பு, பிரித்தல் மற்றும் இயல்பான விளைவு நம்முடைய செயல்பாடு வழக்கமான செயல்பாட்டில் நன்றாக செய்தது, சராசரியான F1 புள்ளிகள் 24% மேல் அடைந்தது, ஆனால் வகுப்பில் மற்றும் பிரிப்பு பெறுவதி மேலும் எதிர்மறை முடிவுகளுடன் பெரிய தரவுத்தளத்தை காண்பித்துள்ளோம். இரு தரவுத் தளங்களும் அதே நேர்ம உதாரணங்கள் இருக்கும் போதும்  இறுதியில் நாம் செயல் 6 க்கு ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட BERT மாதிரியை கூட்டினோம்: குவிட்-19 குறியீடுகள் உள்ள வகைப்படுத்தல், அது சராசரி f1 புள்ளி</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Bu vazifanda, 2021 yordamida qo'shilgan vazifa haqida jamiyat media ta'minlovchimizni anglatamiz. Biz Vazifani 1'ga birlashtirish usulining effektini o'rganib ko'rib chiqardik, boshqa narsalar Effektlarini ajratish va oddiylikni ingliz Twitter tilida tahrirlash imkoniyatini o'rganamiz. Bizning fikrimiz oddiylik vazifasini bajaradi, o'rtacha soni 24%'dan ortiq f1 scorini topish, lekin darajalashtirish va chiqarish bilan bir xil f1 scorida 22% va 37% darajaga ega bo'lgan. Bizning tajribalarimiz esa ko'proq negativ natijalar bilan katta maʼlumotlar tarkibini ko'rsatadi va ikkita maʼlumotlar sonlarida bir yaxshi misol bor. Oxirgi biz Vazifani 6 uchun bir bir bir bir bir BERT modelini qoʻllab berdik: Koid-19 xabarlarni taqlash imkoniyatlari bilan imkoniyatlash va u 96 foizdan ortiq f1 foiz topdi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Trong công việc này, chúng tôi mô tả những kiến nghị của chúng tôi cho công việc chia sẻ cán bộ truyền thông xã hội (SMM44H) 2021. Chúng tôi đã điều tra tính hiệu quả của một phương pháp huấn luyện chung cho Nhiệm vụ 1, đặc biệt phân loại, chiết xuất và tổng hợp các hiệu ứng thuốc trái phép (ADE) được nhắc đến trên Twitter của người Anh. Cách tiếp cận của chúng tôi thực hiện rất tốt trong nhiệm vụ bình thường, đạt được một điểm trên trung bình f1 của 24=, nhưng ít hơn là về phân loại và trích xuất, với điểm f1 trên 2297=. và 37=. Các thí nghiệm của chúng tôi cũng cho thấy rằng một tập tin lớn với kết quả tiêu cực nhiều hơn đã có kết quả mạnh hơn một bộ dữ liệu nhỏ hơn so với một tập tin nhỏ hơn, ngay cả khi cả hai bộ dữ liệu đều có cùng một ví dụ tích cực. Cuối cùng chúng tôi cũng đưa ra một mô hình thực phẩm thiếu sót cho Task 6: Classification of Covid-19 đã cho thấy triệu chứng cao hơn so với trung bình Điểm F1 của 96=.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>In dit werk beschrijven we onze inzendingen aan de Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. We onderzochten de effectiviteit van een gezamenlijke trainingsaanpak voor Task 1, met name classificatie, extractie en normalisatie van ADE vermeldingen in Engelse tweets. Onze aanpak presteerde goed bij de normalisatietaak, waarbij we een bovengemiddelde f1 score van 24%, bereikten, maar minder op classificatie en extractie, met f1 scores van respectievelijk 22% en 37% . Onze experimenten toonden ook aan dat een grotere dataset met meer negatieve resultaten resulteerde in sterkere resultaten dan een kleinere meer gebalanceerde dataset, zelfs als beide datasets dezelfde positieve voorbeelden hebben. Tot slot hebben we ook een getuned BERT model ingediend voor Task 6: Classificatie van Covid-19 tweets met symptomen, die een bovengemiddelde f1 score van 96%.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>U ovom poslu opisujemo svoje podatke za rudarstvo socijalnih medija za zdravlje (SMM4H) 2021. zajedničkom zadatku. Istražili smo učinkovitost zajedničkog pristupa obuke zadatku 1, posebno klasifikaciji, ekstrakciji i normalizaciji nuspojavnih učinka droge (ADE) spomenuti na engleskim tweetima. Naš pristup je dobro obavljen na normalizacijskom zadatku, ostvario iznad prosječnog f1 rezultata od 24%, ali manje na klasifikaciji i izvlačenju, s f1 rezultatima od 22% i 37%. Naši eksperimenti su također pokazali da je veća kompleta podataka s negativnijim rezultatima dovela do jača rezultata nego manja kompleta balanciranih podataka, čak i kada oba kompleta podataka imaju isti pozitivni primjer. Konačno smo također predali i napravljeni model BERT za zadatak 6: klasifikacija Covid-19 tweets sadržajućih simptoma, koji je postigao iznad prosječnog f1 rezultata od 96%.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_id>Dalam pekerjaan ini kami menggambarkan pengiriman kami ke Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Kami menyelidiki efektivitas pendekatan pelatihan bersama untuk Tugas 1, khususnya klasifikasi, ekstraksi dan normalisasi efek obat (ADE) disebutkan dalam tweet Inggris. Pendekatan kami berhasil dalam tugas normalisasi, mencapai skor f1 di atas rata-rata 24%, tetapi kurang begitu pada klasifikasi dan ekstraksi, dengan skor f1 22% dan 37% respectively. Eksperimen kami juga menunjukkan bahwa set data yang lebih besar dengan hasil yang lebih negatif menyebabkan hasil yang lebih kuat daripada set data yang lebih seimbang, bahkan ketika kedua set data memiliki contoh positif yang sama. Akhirnya kami juga mengirim model BERT tuned untuk Task 6: Klasifikasi tweet Covid-19 yang mengandung gejala, yang mencapai nilai F1 di atas rata-rata 96%.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>이 작업에서 우리는 소셜미디어 건강발굴(SMM4H) 2021 공유 임무에 대한 제출을 묘사했다.우리는 임무 1에 대한 공동 교육 방법의 유효성, 특히 영어 트윗에서 언급한 약물불량반응(ADE)의 분류, 추출과 표준화에 대해 조사했다.우리의 방법은 표준화 임무에서 양호했다. f1의 득점은 평균 수준인 24%보다 높았지만 분류와 추출에 있어서 비교적 좋지 않았다. f1의 득점은 각각 22%와 37%였다.우리의 실험은 두 데이터 집합이 모두 같은 긍정적인 예를 가지고 있어도 더 큰 데이터 집합은 더 많은 부정적인 결과를 낳고 더 작고 균형 잡힌 데이터 집합보다 더 강한 결과를 낳는다는 것을 보여 주었다.마지막으로 우리는 임무 6에 최적화된 버트 모델을 제출했다. 증상을 포함하는 코로나 트윗을 분류한 결과 f1의 점수가 평균 96% 보다 높았다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>In dieser Arbeit beschreiben wir unsere Beiträge zum Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Wir untersuchten die Effektivität eines gemeinsamen Trainingsansatzes für Task 1, insbesondere Klassifizierung, Extraktion und Normalisierung von unerwünschten Medikamenteneffekten (ADE) Erwähnungen in englischen Tweets. Unser Ansatz hat sich bei der Normalisierungsaufgabe gut bewährt und einen überdurchschnittlichen f1-Score von 24%, aber weniger bei Klassifizierung und Extraktion erzielt, wobei f1-Score von 22% bzw. 37% beträgt. Unsere Experimente zeigten auch, dass ein größerer Datensatz mit mehr negativen Ergebnissen zu stärkeren Ergebnissen führte als ein kleinerer, ausgewogenerer Datensatz, selbst wenn beide Datensätze die gleichen positiven Beispiele haben. Schließlich haben wir auch ein abgestimmtes BERT-Modell für Task 6: Klassifizierung von Covid-19-Tweets mit Symptomen eingereicht, das einen überdurchschnittlichen f1-Score von 96%.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_sw>Katika kazi hii tunaelezea ujumbe wetu wa Vyombo vya Habari vya Kijamii wa Kumbukumbu kwa Afya (SMM4H) 2021. Tulichunguza ufanisi wa mbinu za mafunzo ya pamoja kwa Task 1, hususani usambazaji, utekelezaji na utaratibu wa Tamko za Utawala (ADE) katika twiti za Kiingereza. Hatua yetu ilifanya vizuri katika kazi ya kawaida, kutekeleza kiwango cha wastani wa f1 cha asilimia 24, lakini kidogo sana kwa usambazaji na utekelezaji, na vipande vya f1 kwa asilimia 22 na 37. Majaribio yetu pia yalionyesha kuwa taarifa kubwa zaidi yenye matokeo hasi yalisababisha matokeo yenye nguvu zaidi ya seti ndogo ya data yenye usawa, hata pale taarifa zote hizo zina mifano nzuri. Mwisho pia tuliwasilisha mfano wa BERT kwa ajili ya kazi 6: Kutangaza ujumbe wa twiti za Covid-19 zilizo na dalili, ambazo zilipata kiwango cha wastani f1 cha asilimia 96.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>در این کار ما تحویل‌های خود را به وزارت رسانه‌های اجتماعی برای سلامت (SMM4H) 2021 مشخص می‌کنیم. ما تحقیق کرده‌ایم فعالیت یک روش آموزش مشترک برای تابع ۱، مخصوصاً کلی‌سازی، استخراج و عامل‌سازی اثر مواد مخالف مواد مخالف (ADE) را در تویت‌های انگلیسی بیان می‌کند. دسترسی ما در کار عادی انجام داده بود، تا یک امتیاز f1 متوسط بالاتر از ۲۴ درصد رسید، اما کمتر از آن در دسترسی و استخراج، با امتیاز f1 از ۲۲ درصد و ۳۳ درصد. آزمایشات ما هم نشان دادند که یک مجموعه داده بزرگ با نتایج منفی بیشتری به نتایج قوی تر از یک مجموعه داده های متناسب تر، حتی وقتی هر دو مجموعه داده ها مثل مثال مثبت دارند. بالاخره ما همچنین یک مدل BERT تنظیم برای Task 6 را فرستادیم: کلاسیف توئیت Covid-19 که شامل علائم است، که در میانگین نمونه f1 از 96 درصد بالا رسید.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Bu işde 2021-nji Beýik Taýramyzy Sosyal Medýdanlaryň Haýgylygyny Taýýarlamak üçin (SMM4H) sahypalarymyzy tassyklaýarys. Biz 1-nji Görev 1-nji ýarym taýramçylygynyň etkinliýetini bardyk. Özellikle döwlet sanlarynda "Adverse Drug Effect (ADE)" diýip ýazylýar. Bizim yaklaşımız normalizasyon görevinde, ortalama f1 noktası 24% üstünde ulaştı, fakat bu şekilde klasifikasyon ve çıkarma üzerinde f1 noktası 22 ve 37% olmuştu. Biziň deneylerimiz hem köp daty setirini negatif netijeleri bilen kiçi baýlanan daty setirinden has güýçli netijelere getirdi. Hem iki daty setirini hem bir positif mysal bolsa hem. Sonunda da görev 6 için ayarlanmış BERT modeli gönderdik:</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Në këtë punë ne përshkruajmë paraqitjet tona në Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Task Shared. Ne hetuam efektshmërinë e një qasje të përbashkët trainimi për detyrën 1, veçanërisht klasifikimin, nxjerrjen dhe normalizimin e përmendimeve të efektit të dëmshëm të drogës (ADE) në tweetet angleze. Përqasja jonë kryei mirë në detyrën e normalizimit, duke arritur një rezultat mbi mesataren e f1-së prej 24%, por më pak në klasifikimin dhe nxjerrjen, me rezultatet e f1-së prej 22% dhe 37% respektivisht. Eksperimentet tona treguan gjithashtu se një grup më i madh i të dhënave me rezultate më negative çoi në rezultate më të forta sesa një grup më i vogël i të dhënave më të balancuara, edhe kur të dy grupet e të dhënave kanë të njëjtat shembuj pozitiv. Më në fund ne dërguam gjithashtu një model të përshtatur BERT për detyrën 6: Klasifikimi i tweeteve Covid-19 që përmbajnë simptomë, që arritën një rezultat mbi mesataren e f1 prej 96%.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_af>In hierdie werk beskrywe ons onderskrifte aan die sosiale media-mining vir gesondheid (SMM4H) 2021 Gedeelde taak. Ons het die effektiviteit van 'n joint oefening toegang tot taak 1, spesifieke klasifikasie, uitpakking en normalisering van Adverse Drug Effekte (ADE) in Engelske tweets bepaal. Ons toegang het goed uitgevoer op die normalisering taak, tot 'n bo gemiddelde f1 telling van 24%, maar minder so op klasifikasie en uittrekking, met f1 telling van 22% en 37% respectively. Ons eksperimente het ook wys dat 'n groter datastel met meer negatiewe resultate gelei het na sterker resultate as 'n kleiner meer balanse datastel, selfs wanneer beide datastel dieselfde positiewe voorbeelde het. Eindelik het ons ook 'n aangestuurde BERT model vir Taak 6 aangestuur: Klassifikasie van Covid-19 tweets wat simptome bevat het, wat 'n boonste gemiddelde f1 punt van 96%.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Այս աշխատանքում մենք նկարագրում ենք մեր ներկայացումները 2021 թվականի Սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցների առողջապահության (SMM4H) հանքահանգում: Մենք ուսումնասիրեցինք 1-րդ խնդրի ընդհանուր ուսումնասիրության արդյունավետությունը, հատկապես անգլերենի թվիթերում հայտարարված անգամ թմրանյութերի թերաֆեկտի դասակարգումը, վերացումը և նորմալիզացիան: Մեր մոտեցումը լավ կատարեց նորմալիզացիայի խնդիրը, հասնելով 24 տոկոսի բարձր միջին f1 գնահատականը, սակայն ավելի քիչ՝ դասակարգման և դուրս բերման համար, f1 գնահատականը 22 տոկոսի և 37 տոկոսի: Մեր փորձարկումները նաև ցույց տվեցին, որ ավելի մեծ տվյալների համակարգը, որն ավելի բացասական արդյունքներ ուներ, հանգեցրեց ավելի ուժեղ արդյունքների, քան ավելի փոքր հավասարակշռություն ունեցող տվյալների համակարգը, նույնիսկ երբ երկու տվ Վերջապես մենք նաև ներկայացրեցինք BER-ի համակարգված մոդել 6-ի համար. Covit-19 թվիթերի դասակարգման, որոնք պարունակում էին ախտանիշներ, որոնք հասան 96 տոկոսի բարձր միջին f1 գնահատականի:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>በዚህ ሥራ 2021 የተሰራጨውን ስራ ለማኅበራዊ ሚዲያ የጤና አሳብ አሳብ (SMM4H) እናሳውቃለን፡፡ በንግግሊዝኛ ትዊተሮች ላይ የተለየ የበይነመረ የሕንጻ አካሄድ (ADE) ማስታወቂያውን፣ ለመለየት እና የመጠቀምን የግል ትምህርት ማቀናቀፍ እና ትምህርት ማድረጊያውን መረመርን፡፡ የተለመደው ሥርዓታችን በተለየ ጠቅላላ F1 score 24 በመቶ ላይ እንዲደርስ ነው፤ ነገር ግን በትክክል እና ለመውጣት በጣም ጥቂት ነው፡፡ ፈተናዎቻችን ደግሞ፣ የዳታ መስመር አንድ መልካም ምሳሌ ባለበት ጊዜ ከታናሹ የዳታ ክፍሎች የበለጠ ትልቁ ፍሬዎችን እንዲያበረታባቸው ነው፡፡ በመጨረሻም ለስራ 6 የBERT ሞዴል አቀረብነው፡፡ ምልክቶች የሚኖሩበት ቁጥር-19 ትዊተሮችን መግለጫ፣ የ96 በመቶ የበለጠ የF1 score አግኝቷል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Bu iŇüd…ô 2021-ci il…ô paylaŇüńĪlmńĪŇü iŇü Sosyal Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) m…ôlumatńĪmńĪzńĪ t…ôsdiql…ôyirik. Biz 1. Task √ľ√ß√ľn birlikd…ô t…ôhsil edil…ôn t…ôhsil t…ôhsil t…ôhsil edilm…ôsini araŇüdńĪrdńĪq. √Ėzellikle ńįngilizci tweetl…ôrd…ô "Adverse Drug Effect (ADE)" s√∂yl…ôdikl…ôri, se√ßm…ôk v…ô normalizasyon. Bizim yaxńĪnlńĪńüńĪmńĪz normalizasyon iŇüind…ô yaxŇüńĪ iŇül…ôdi, ortalama f1 d…ôr…ôc…ôsini 24%-d…ôn artńĪrdńĪ, lakin bu d…ôr…ôc…ônin klasifikasyonu v…ô √ßńĪxartmasńĪ √ľ√ß√ľn f1 d…ôr…ôc…ôsini 22%-d…ôn v…ô 37%-d…ôn az etdi. Bizim eksperimentl…ôrimiz d…ô bel…ô g√∂st…ôrdi ki, daha negatif sonu√ßlarńĪ il…ô daha b√∂y√ľk veril…ôn veril…ôn qurńüular daha ki√ßik balanslńĪ veril…ôn qurńüulardan daha q√ľvv…ôtli sonu√ßlar olardńĪ, h…ôtta h…ôr iki veril…ôn qurńüularńĪ eyni pozitif n√ľmun…ôl…ôr olsa Sonunda biz d…ô 6. Task √ľ√ß√ľn m√ľ…ôyy…ôn bir BERT modeli t…ôblińü etdik: Covid-19 tweets klasifikasyonu simptomlar i√ß…ôrik, bu da ortalama f1 d…ôr…ôc…ôsi 96%-d…ôn √ľst√ľn oldu.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>এই কাজে আমরা সামাজিক মিডিয়ার স্বাস্থ্যের জন্য মিনিং (এসএমএফ৪হ) ২০১১ শেয়ার করা কাজের কাজে আমাদের প্রতিপাদক বর্ণনা কর আমরা টাস্ক ১-এ যৌথ প্রশিক্ষণের কার্যক্রম তদন্ত করেছি, বিশেষ করে ইংরেজী টুইটে বিভিন্ন ভাষায় অ্যাডভার্স মাদক প্রভাবের (এডি) উল্লেখ করা যা আমাদের পদক্ষেপ স্বাভাবিক কাজের উপর ভালো করেছে, গড়ে ২৪% ফি১ স্কোর পাওয়া যাচ্ছে, কিন্তু শ্রেণীবিভক্ত এবং বের করে নেওয়ার ব্যাপারে কম, যার ফলে  আমাদের পরীক্ষাও দেখা যাচ্ছে যে আরো নেতিবাচক ফলাফলের একটি বড় ডাটাসেটের ফলাফল বেশী শক্তিশালী হয়েছে, এমনকি যদি দুটো ডাটাসেটও একই পজিটিভ উদ Finally we also submitted a tuned BERT model for Task 6: Classification of Covid-19 tweets containing symptoms, which achieved an above average f1 score of 96%.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>U ovom poslu opisujemo svoje podatke na ministarstvo socijalnih medija za zdravlje (SMM4H) 2021. zajednički zadatak. Istražili smo učinkovitost zajedničkog pristupa obuke zadatku 1, posebno klasifikaciji, ekstrakciji i normalizaciji nuspojava na engleskim tweetima. Naš pristup je dobro obavljen na normalizacijskom zadatku, ostvario iznad prosječnog f1 rezultata od 24%, ali manje na klasifikaciji i izvlačenju, sa f1 rezultatima od 22% i 37%. Naši eksperimenti su također pokazali da je veća kompleta podataka sa više negativnih rezultata dovela do jača rezultata od manje balanciranije kompleta podataka, čak i kada oba kompleta podataka imaju isti pozitivni primjer. Konačno smo također predali i napravljeni model BERT za zadatak 6: klasifikacija Covid-19 tweets koji sadrže simptome, koji je postigao iznad prosječnog f1 rezultata od 96%.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>En aquesta feina descrivim les nostres presentacions a la Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Vam investigar l'eficacia d'un enfocament de formació conjunta a la tasca 1, específicament la classificació, l'extracció i la normalització de les mencions d'efecte advers de medicaments (ADE) en tweets anglès. El nostre enfocament va funcionar bé en la tasca de normalització, aconseguint una puntuació f1 superior a la mitjana del 24%, però menys en la classificació i l'extracció, amb puntuacions f1 del 22% i 37%, respectivament. Els nostres experiments també van demostrar que un conjunt de dades més gran amb resultats més negatius va portar a resultats més forts que un conjunt de dades més petit equilibrat, fins i tot quan ambdós conjunts de dades tenen els mateixos exemples positius. Finalment també vam presentar un model de BERT ajustad per a la tasca 6: Classificació de tweets Covid-19 contenent símptomes, que van aconseguir una puntuació f1 superior a la mitjana del 96%.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>V této práci popisujeme naše příspěvky na Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Zkoumali jsme účinnost společného tréninkového přístupu k úkolu 1, konkrétně klasifikace, extrakce a normalizace zmínek o nežádoucím léčivém efektu (ADE) v anglických tweetech. Náš přístup se v normalizačním úkolu vedl dobře, dosáhl nadprůměrného f1 skóre 24%, ale méně v klasifikaci a extrakci, s f1 skóre 22% a 37% respektive. Naše experimenty také ukázaly, že větší datová sada s více negativními výsledky vede k silnějším výsledkům než menší vyváženější datová sada, i když obě datové sady mají stejné pozitivní příklady. Nakonec jsme také předložili vyladěný BERT model pro Úkol 6: Klasifikace Covid-19 tweetů obsahujících symptomy, který dosáhl nadprůměrného f1 skóre 96%.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Selles töös kirjeldame oma esitusi sotsiaalmeedia kaevandamiseks tervisele (SMM4H) 2021. aasta jagatud ülesandele. Uurisime ühise koolituse meetodi efektiivsust ülesandele 1, täpsemalt inglise keeles kõrvaltoimete klassifitseerimist, ekstraheerimist ja normaliseerimist. Meie lähenemisviis sai normaliseerimise ülesandes hästi hakkama, saavutades keskmisest suurema f1 skoori 24%, kuid vähem klassifitseerimisel ja ekstraheerimisel, f1 skooriga vastavalt 22% ja 37%. Meie eksperimendid näitasid ka, et suurem negatiivsete tulemustega andmekogum viis suuremate tulemusteni kui väiksem tasakaalustatud andmekogum, isegi kui mõlemal andmekogumil on samad positiivsed näited. Lõpuks esitasime ka häälestatud BERT mudeli ülesandele 6: Covid-19 sümptomeid sisaldavate säutsude klassifitseerimine, mis saavutas keskmisest kõrgema f1 skoori 96%.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä työssä kuvailemme ehdotuksia Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task -ohjelmaan. Tutkimme yhteisen koulutusmenetelmän tehokkuutta tehtävään 1, erityisesti englanninkielisten twiittien haittavaikutusten luokittelua, ekstraktiota ja normalisointia. Lähestymistapamme suoriutui hyvin normalisointitehtävässä saavuttaen keskimääräistä suuremman f1-pisteen 24%, mutta vähemmän luokittelussa ja ekstraktiossa, f1-pisteet 22% ja 37%. Kokeet osoittivat myös, että suurempi negatiivisempi aineisto johti vahvempiin tuloksiin kuin pienempi tasapainoisempi aineisto, vaikka molemmissa aineistoissa olisi samat positiiviset esimerkit. Lopuksi toimitimme myös viritetyn BERT-mallin tehtävään 6: oireita sisältävien Covid-19-twiittien luokitus, joka saavutti keskimääräisen f1-pisteen 96%.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bg>В тази работа описваме нашите предложения към Споделена задача за Социалните медии Минно дело за здраве (СММ4Х) 2021. Изследвахме ефективността на съвместния тренировъчен подход към задача 1, по-специално класификация, екстракция и нормализиране на споменаваните в английски туитове нежелани лекарствени ефекти (АДД). Подходът ни се представи добре при задачата за нормализиране, като постигна над средния резултат от 24%, но по-малко при класификацията и екстракцията, със съответно 22% и 37%. Нашите експерименти също показаха, че по-голям набор от данни с повече отрицателни резултати води до по-силни резултати от по-малък, по-балансиран набор от данни, дори когато и двата набора от данни имат едни и същи положителни примери. Накрая представихме и настроен модел за задача 6: Класификация на туитове съдържащи симптоми, които постигнаха над средния резултат от 96%.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>I dette arbejde beskriver vi vores indlæg til Social Media Mining for Health (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Task. Vi undersøgte effektiviteten af en fælles træning tilgang til opgave 1, specielt klassificering, ekstraktion og normalisering af Adverse Drug Effect (ADE) omtaler i engelske tweets. Vores tilgang klarede sig godt på normaliseringsopgaven og opnåede en f1 score over gennemsnittet på 24%, men mindre på klassificering og ekstraktion, med f1 score på henholdsvis 22% og 37%. Vores eksperimenter viste også, at et større datasæt med mere negative resultater førte til stærkere resultater end et mindre mere afbalanceret datasæt, selv når begge datasæt har de samme positive eksempler. Endelig indsendte vi også en tunet BERT model til opgave 6: Klassificering af Covid-19 tweets indeholdende symptomer, som opnåede en f1 score over gennemsnittet på 96%.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_sk>V tem delu opisujemo naše prispevke k skupni nalogi za rudarjenje v socialnih medijih za zdravje (SMM4H) 2021. Raziskovali smo učinkovitost skupnega pristopa usposabljanja k nalogi 1, zlasti klasifikacija, ekstrakcija in normalizacija omenjenih neželenih učinkov zdravil (ADE) v angleških tweetih. Naš pristop se je dobro izkazal pri nalogi normalizacije, saj je dosegel nadpovprečno oceno f1 24%, manj pa pri klasifikaciji in ekstrakciji, z oceno f1 22% oziroma 37%. Naši poskusi so pokazali tudi, da je večji nabor podatkov z večjimi negativnimi rezultati vodil do močnejših rezultatov kot manjši bolj uravnoteženi nabor podatkov, tudi če imata obe nabori enake pozitivne primere. Na koncu smo predložili tudi prilagojen BERT model za nalogo 6: Klasifikacija tvitov Covid-19, ki vsebujejo simptome, ki je dosegel nadpovprečno oceno f1 96%.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>A cikin wannan aikin da Muke describe musuluntu zuwa the Socic Media Mining for Heatherhood (SMM4H) 2021 Shared Takar. Haƙĩƙa, Mun ƙidãya mafiya aikin haɗiya zuwa Tafiyar 1, hasa'a, classified, fitarwa da kuma normal wa sunayen Effekt na Narci (ADU) cikin Ingiriya. Our approach performed well on the normalization task, achieving an above average f1 score of 24%, but less so on classification and extraction, with f1 scores of 22% and 37% respectively.  Kayan jarrabayenmu suka nuna cewa, samun danne mafi girma da matsalan negative sun ƙara matsala mafi ƙaranci daga samun da aka daidaita, kuma kõ dã sami biyu na danganta sun sami misãlai masu daidai. Ga ƙarshen, mun sami wani misali na BERT wa aikin 6: Tsariya na Kwamf1-19 mai ƙunsa da ayukan ayukan, wanda ya sami ƙarami wata f1-score na 96%.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Nang trabah iki, kita ngubah ngerasai tanggal nggawe barang urip nggawe barang-urip ning resuran Digital Media (SMM4H) 2020 1 Tarjamahan sing berarti Anyone here Ndoleh-Ndoleh sing wis ngerasai bener tentang kanggo kalagayaan nggawe gerakan kelas telu, dadi f1 sing ditambah 24%, dadi mper dadi kapan kelas telu, dadi f1 sing ditambah 22% lan 31%. section Tulungi, nggambar nggambar sistem menehi nggawe BERT model nggo task 6: Kelaseki Covideo-19 tuyte sing dikanggambar barang sembaran, sing wis aswih sabên kotang nggawe mentegan f1 sing uwong de Nine%.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་གནས་སྟངས་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་དྲ་རྒྱ་ནག་གི་དབར་སྤྲོད་ཀྱི་གནས་སྟངས་ལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་མཐུན་གྱི་གོ་སྐབས་ཡིག་གཟུགས་ཐད་མིན་དུ་ལས་གནོད་ཐད་ཚོར་ཞིབ་བྱས་པ་ཡིན། ང་ཚོའི་བཟོ་ཚིག་ནི་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་བཟོ་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ལས་ཀ་ཡིན་ཚད་ལྡན་གྱིས་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་སྟངས་ཀྱང་ཚད་གཅིག་ལས་མཐུན་སྒྲིག་འགོད་པ་ཡིན། ང་ཚོའི་བརྟག་ཞིག་ཀྱང་ཕྱོགས་སྡུད་ཚན་ཆེ་བའི་ཚད་རྐྱེན་པས་བྱས་ཟུར་བ་མང་ཙམ་བྱུང་བ་ཡིན་པས་རྐྱེན་སྒྲིག་ཆ་གཞི་རྩན་འབྲེལ་བ མཐའ་མཇུག་དུ་འུ་ཚོས་ཀྱིས་ཞིབ་དཔྱད་སྒྲུབ་གྱི་དབྱེ་རིམ་གྱི་དཔེ་བརྗོད་པ་ཞིག་འཇུག་བྱས།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>בעבודה הזו אנחנו מתארים את ההעבדות שלנו למכרת מדיה חברתית לבריאות (SMM4H) משימה משותפת 2021. חקרנו את היעילות של גישת אימון משותפת למשימה 1, במיוחד מסווג, חולץ ונורמליזציה הגישה שלנו ביצעה היטב במשימת הנורמליזציה, השיגה נקודת f1 מעל ממוצע ממוצע של 24%, אך פחות ככה בקשר להקליטה ולחטיפה, עם נקודות f1 של 22% ו-37% בהתאם. Our experiments also showed that a larger dataset with more negative results led to stronger results than a smaller more balanced dataset, even when both datasets have the same positive examples.  סוף סוף שלחנו גם מודל BERT מתאים למשימה 6: שיגור של טוויטים Covid-19 שמכילים סימפטומים, אשר השיג נקודת F1 מעל ממוצע ממוצע של 96%.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Identification of profession &amp; occupation in Health-related Social Media using tweets in Spanish<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>panish</title>
      <author><first>Victoria</first><last>Pachón</last></author>
      <author><first>Jacinto</first><last>Mata Vázquez</last></author>
      <author><first>Juan Luís</first><last>Domínguez Olmedo</last></author>
      <pages>105–107</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we present our approach and system description on Task 7a in ProfNer-ST : Identification of profession &amp; occupation in Health related Social Media. Our main contribution is to show the effectiveness of using BETO-Spanish BERT as a model based on transformers pretrained with a Spanish Corpus for classification tasks. In our experiments we compared several <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_architecture">architectures</a> based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transformer">transformers</a> with others based on classical <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning algorithms</a>. With this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_development_process">approach</a>, we achieved an F1-score of 0.92 in the evaluation process.</abstract>
      <url hash="eef81079">2021.smm4h-1.20</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.20</doi>
      <bibkey>pachon-etal-2021-identification</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>UoB at ProfNER 2021 : Data Augmentation for Classification Using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">Machine Translation</a><fixed-case>U</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>B</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>P</fixed-case>rof<fixed-case>NER</fixed-case> 2021: Data Augmentation for Classification Using Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Frances Adriana</first><last>Laureano De Leon</last></author>
      <author><first>Harish</first><last>Tayyar Madabushi</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Lee</last></author>
      <pages>115–117</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the participation of the UoB-NLP team in the ProfNER-ST shared subtask 7a. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> was aimed at detecting the mention of professions in social media text. Our team experimented with two methods of improving the performance of pre-trained models : Specifically, we experimented with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_augmentation">data augmentation</a> through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Translation">translation</a> and the merging of multiple language inputs to meet the objective of the task. While the best performing model on the test data consisted of mBERT fine-tuned on augmented data using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Back-translation">back-translation</a>, the improvement is minor possibly because multi-lingual pre-trained models such as mBERT already have access to the kind of information provided through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Back-translation">back-translation and bilingual data</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="a1cb734e">2021.smm4h-1.23</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.23</doi>
      <bibkey>laureano-de-leon-etal-2021-uob</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>PAII-NLP at SMM4H 2021 : Joint Extraction and Normalization of Adverse Drug Effect Mentions in Tweets<fixed-case>PAII</fixed-case>-<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>SMM</fixed-case>4<fixed-case>H</fixed-case> 2021: Joint Extraction and Normalization of Adverse Drug Effect Mentions in Tweets</title>
      <author><first>Zongcheng</first><last>Ji</last></author>
      <author><first>Tian</first><last>Xia</last></author>
      <author><first>Mei</first><last>Han</last></author>
      <pages>126–127</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our system developed for the subtask 1c of the sixth Social Media Mining for Health Applications (SMM4H) shared task in 2021. The aim of the subtask is to recognize the adverse drug effect (ADE) mentions from tweets and normalize the identified mentions to their mapping MedDRA preferred term IDs. Our system is based on a neural transition-based joint model, which is to perform <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_vision">recognition</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normalization_(statistics)">normalization</a> simultaneously. Our final two submissions outperform the average F1 score by 1-2 %.</abstract>
      <url hash="0fa069ec">2021.smm4h-1.26</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.smm4h-1.26</doi>
      <bibkey>ji-etal-2021-paii</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>