<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="J17">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Computational Linguistics, Volume 43, Issue 1 - <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>pril 2017</booktitle>
      <publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
      <address>Cambridge, MA</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <bibkey>cl-2017-linguistics</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>A Statistical, Grammar-Based Approach to Microplanning</title>
      <author><first>Claire</first><last>Gardent</last></author>
      <author><first>Laura</first><last>Perez-Beltrachini</last></author>
      <abstract>Although there has been much work in recent years on data-driven natural language generation, little attention has been paid to the fine-grained interactions that arise during microplanning between aggregation, surface realization, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_segmentation">sentence segmentation</a>. In this article, we propose a hybrid symbolic / statistical approach to jointly model the constraints regulating these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interaction_(statistics)">interactions</a>. Our approach integrates a small handwritten grammar, a statistical hypertagger, and a surface realization algorithm. It is applied to the verbalization of knowledge base queries and tested on 13 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_base">knowledge bases</a> to demonstrate domain independence. We evaluate our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tactic_(method)">approach</a> in several ways. A quantitative analysis shows that the hybrid approach outperforms a purely symbolic approach in terms of both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speed">speed</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coverage_(telecommunication)">coverage</a>. Results from a human study indicate that users find the output of this hybrid statistic / symbolic system more fluent than both a template-based and a purely symbolic grammar-based approach. Finally, we illustrate by means of examples that our approach can account for various factors impacting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aggregate_data">aggregation</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_segmentation">sentence segmentation</a>, and surface realization.</abstract>
      <pages>1-30</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00273</doi>
      <url hash="ac887648">J17-1001</url>
      <bibkey>gardent-perez-beltrachini-2017-statistical</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>A Game-Theoretic Approach to Word Sense Disambiguation</title>
      <author><first>Rocco</first><last>Tripodi</last></author>
      <author><first>Marcello</first><last>Pelillo</last></author>
      <abstract>This article presents a new model for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_sense_disambiguation">word sense disambiguation</a> formulated in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evolutionary_game_theory">evolutionary game theory</a>, where each word to be disambiguated is represented as a node on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(discrete_mathematics)">graph</a> whose edges represent word relations and senses are represented as classes. The words simultaneously update their class membership preferences according to the senses that neighboring words are likely to choose. We use distributional information to weigh the influence that each word has on the decisions of the others and semantic similarity information to measure the strength of compatibility among the choices. With this information we can formulate the word sense disambiguation problem as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constraint_satisfaction_problem">constraint satisfaction problem</a> and solve it using tools derived from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_theory">game theory</a>, maintaining the textual coherence. The model is based on two ideas : Similar words should be assigned to similar classes and the meaning of a word does not depend on all the words in a text but just on some of them. The article provides an in-depth motivation of the idea of modeling the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word-sense_disambiguation">word sense disambiguation problem</a> in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_theory">game theory</a>, which is illustrated by an example. The conclusion presents an extensive analysis on the combination of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Similarity_measure">similarity measures</a> to use in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_framework">framework</a> and a comparison with state-of-the-art systems. The results show that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> outperforms state-of-the-art algorithms and can be applied to different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a> and in different scenarios.</abstract>
      <pages>31-70</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00274</doi>
      <url hash="b79d9681">J17-1002</url>
      <bibkey>tripodi-pelillo-2017-game</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Multilingual Metaphor Processing : Experiments with Semi-Supervised and Unsupervised Learning</title>
      <author><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Shutova</last></author>
      <author><first>Lin</first><last>Sun</last></author>
      <author><first>Elkin</first><last>Darío Gutiérrez</last></author>
      <author><first>Patricia</first><last>Lichtenstein</last></author>
      <author><first>Srini</first><last>Narayanan</last></author>
      <abstract>Highly frequent in language and communication, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metaphor">metaphor</a> represents a significant challenge for Natural Language Processing (NLP) applications. Computational work on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metaphor">metaphor</a> has traditionally evolved around the use of hand-coded knowledge, making the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> hard to scale. Recent years have witnessed a rise in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistics">statistical approaches</a> to metaphor processing. However, these approaches often require extensive human annotation effort and are predominantly evaluated within a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_(biology)">limited domain</a>. In contrast, we experiment with weakly supervised and unsupervised techniqueswith little or no annotationto generalize higher-level mechanisms of metaphor from distributional properties of concepts. We investigate different levels and types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervisor">supervision</a> (learning from linguistic examples vs. learning from a given set of metaphorical mappings vs. learning without annotation) in flat and hierarchical, unconstrained and constrained clustering settings. Our aim is to identify the optimal type of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervisor">supervision</a> for a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">learning algorithm</a> that discovers patterns of metaphorical association from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_(literary_theory)">text</a>. In order to investigate the scalability and adaptability of our models, we applied them to data in three languages from different language groupsEnglish, Spanish, and Russianachieving state-of-the-art results with little supervision. Finally, we demonstrate that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistics">statistical methods</a> can facilitate and scale up cross-linguistic research on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metaphor">metaphor</a>.</abstract>
      <pages>71-123</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00275</doi>
      <url hash="224e6445">J17-1003</url>
      <bibkey>shutova-etal-2017-multilingual</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Argumentation Mining in User-Generated Web Discourse</title>
      <author><first>Ivan</first><last>Habernal</last></author>
      <author><first>Iryna</first><last>Gurevych</last></author>
      <abstract>The goal of argumentation mining, an evolving research field in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics">computational linguistics</a>, is to design methods capable of analyzing people’s argumentation. In this article, we go beyond the state of the art in several ways. (i) We deal with actual Web data and take up the challenges given by the variety of registers, multiple domains, and unrestricted noisy user-generated Web discourse. (ii) We bridge the gap between normative argumentation theories and argumentation phenomena encountered in actual data by adapting an argumentation model tested in an extensive annotation study. (iii) We create a new gold standard corpus (90k tokens in 340 documents) and experiment with several machine learning methods to identify argument components. We offer the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a>, source codes, and annotation guidelines to the community under free licenses. Our findings show that argumentation mining in user-generated Web discourse is a feasible but challenging task.</abstract>
      <pages>125-179</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00276</doi>
      <url hash="9f356eaa">J17-1004</url>
      <bibkey>habernal-gurevych-2017-argumentation</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ukp">UKP</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Hashtag Sense Clustering Based on Temporal Similarity</title>
      <author><first>Giovanni</first><last>Stilo</last></author>
      <author><first>Paola</first><last>Velardi</last></author>
      <abstract>Hashtags are creative labels used in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microblogging">micro-blogs</a> to characterize the topic of a message / discussion. Regardless of the use for which they were originally intended, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hashtag">hashtags</a> can not be used as a means to cluster messages with similar content. First, because <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hashtag">hashtags</a> are created in a spontaneous and highly dynamic way by users in multiple languages, the same topic can be associated with different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hashtag">hashtags</a>, and conversely, the same <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hashtag">hashtag</a> may refer to different topics in different time periods. Second, contrary to common words, hashtag disambiguation is complicated by the fact that no <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word-sense_disambiguation">sense catalogs</a> (e.g., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia">Wikipedia</a> or WordNet) are available ; and, furthermore, hashtag labels are difficult to analyze, as they often consist of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acronym">acronyms</a>, concatenated words, and so forth. A common way to determine the meaning of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hashtag">hashtags</a> has been to analyze their context, but, as we have just pointed out, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hashtag">hashtags</a> can have multiple and variable meanings. In this article, we propose a temporal sense clustering algorithm based on the idea that semantically related hashtags have similar and synchronous usage patterns.</abstract>
      <pages>181-200</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00277</doi>
      <url hash="ea9e95f2">J17-1005</url>
      <bibkey>stilo-velardi-2017-hashtag</bibkey>
    <title_ar>Hashtag Sense Clustering استنادًا إلى التشابه الزمني</title_ar>
      <title_es>Agrupación de Hashtag Sense basada en similitud temporal</title_es>
      <title_fr>Clustering de sens de hashtag basé sur la similitude temporelle</title_fr>
      <title_pt>Clustering do Hashtag Sense com base na similaridade temporal</title_pt>
      <title_ja>時間的類似性に基づくハッシュタグセンスのクラスタリング</title_ja>
      <title_zh>盖时相似性之标签感知聚类</title_zh>
      <title_hi>अस्थायी समानता पर आधारित हैशटैग सेंस क्लस्टरिंग</title_hi>
      <title_ru>Смысловая кластеризация хештегов на основе временного сходства</title_ru>
      <title_ga>Cnuasú Hashtag Sense Bunaithe ar Chosúlacht Ama</title_ga>
      <title_el>Συγκέντρωση αισθήσεων Hashtag με βάση την χρονική ομοιότητα</title_el>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Hashtag érzékelési klaszterezés időbeli hasonlóságon alapul</title_hu>
      <title_it>Clustering del senso di Hashtag basato sulla somiglianza temporale</title_it>
      <title_kk>Температуралық ұқсас сияқтығына негізделген Hashtag сезім кластері</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Hashtag jutimo klasifikavimas, pagrįstas laikinu panašumu</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Групирање на чувства за хаштаг базирано на привремена сличност</title_mk>
      <title_ml>ഹാഷ്ട്ടാഗ് സെന്‍സ് ക്ലൂസ്റ്റര്‍ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തിലുള്ള ഹാഷ്ട്രാഗ് സമമാണ്</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Pemkumpulan Sensa Hashtag Berdasarkan Kesamaan Temporal</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Raggruppament tas-Sens Hashtag ibbażat fuq Similarità Temporali</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Хаштаг мэдрэмжтэй кластеринг Температурын төстэй</title_mn>
      <title_no>Hashtag- følelsesklassering basert på mellombels likning</title_no>
      <title_pl>Klastrowanie zmysłu Hashtag oparte na podobieństwie czasowym</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Gruparea simțurilor Hashtag bazată pe similaritatea temporală</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Hashtag Sense Clustering Based on Temporary Similarity</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_sv>Hashtag Sense Clustering baserat på tidsmässig likhet</title_sv>
      <title_ta>தற்காலிக ஒற்றைப்படையில் அடிப்படையிலான ஹாஷ்டாக் உணர்வு கொள்கை</title_ta>
      <title_so>Hashtag Sense Clustering Based on Mid-Waqti Similarity</title_so>
      <title_ur>ہشٹاگ سنس کلاسترینگ Temporal Similarity Based on Hashtag Sense Clustering</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Comment</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Cảm xúc của Đức Chúa trời</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Клъстериране на сензора на хаштаг въз основа на времевата прилика</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Hashtag Sense Clustering Na temelju Temporalne sličnosti</title_hr>
      <title_da>Hashtag Sense Clustering Baseret på Temporal lighed</title_da>
      <title_nl>Hashtag Sense Clustering gebaseerd op tijdelijke gelijkenis</title_nl>
      <title_de>Hashtag Sense Clustering basierend auf temporaler Ähnlichkeit</title_de>
      <title_id>Hashtag Sense Clustering Berdasarkan Simulasi Temporal</title_id>
      <title_ko>시간 유사성을 바탕으로 하는 Hashtag 의미 집합</title_ko>
      <title_fa>تنظیم حس هشتاگ بر اساس شباهت Temporary</title_fa>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_sq>Hashtag Sense Clustering Based on Temporal Similarity</title_sq>
      <title_sw>Kiungo cha habari cha Sense kinachotumiwa na Usalama wa muda mfupi</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Wagtlaýyn Görnöşiligi Buýruk</title_tr>
      <title_am>ዶሴ `%s'ን ማስፈጠር አልተቻለም፦ %s</title_am>
      <title_hy>Comment</title_hy>
      <title_bn>টেম্পুরাল সমতার উপর হ্যাশট্যাগ সেন ক্লাস্টারিং ভিত্তিক</title_bn>
      <title_az>Qıssız Similatına dayanan Hashtag Sense Clustering</title_az>
      <title_bs>Hashtag Sense Clustering Based on Temporary Similarity</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Agrupament de Sensos Hashtag basat en la Simulació Temporal</title_ca>
      <title_et>Hashtagi sense klastrid põhinevad ajalisel sarnasusel</title_et>
      <title_cs>Hashtag Sense Clustering založené na časové podobnosti</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Hashtag Sense Clustering perustuu ajalliseen samankaltaisuuteen</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Language</title_jv>
      <title_he>מסגרת תחושות האשטג מבוססת על דמיון זמני</title_he>
      <title_sk>Združevanje zaznavanja Hashtag na podlagi časovne podobnosti</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>མཐའ་དབྱིབས་ལྡུས་སྟངས་དང་གཞི་བརྟེན་ནས་མཚོན་རྟགས་མཚམས</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>Hashtags هي علامات إبداعية تُستخدم في المدونات الصغيرة لتوصيف موضوع الرسالة / المناقشة. بغض النظر عن الاستخدام الذي كانت مخصصة له في الأصل ، لا يمكن استخدام علامات التصنيف كوسيلة لتجميع الرسائل ذات المحتوى المماثل. أولاً ، نظرًا لأن علامات التصنيف يتم إنشاؤها بطريقة تلقائية وديناميكية للغاية من قبل المستخدمين بلغات متعددة ، يمكن ربط نفس الموضوع بعلامات تصنيف مختلفة ، وعلى العكس من ذلك ، قد تشير علامة التصنيف نفسها إلى مواضيع مختلفة في فترات زمنية مختلفة. ثانيًا ، على عكس الكلمات الشائعة ، فإن توضيح علامة التصنيف معقد بسبب عدم توفر كتالوجات منطقية (على سبيل المثال ، Wikipedia أو WordNet) ؛ علاوة على ذلك ، يصعب تحليل علامات التصنيف ، لأنها غالبًا ما تتكون من الاختصارات والكلمات المتسلسلة وما إلى ذلك. كانت إحدى الطرق الشائعة لتحديد معنى علامات التصنيف هي تحليل سياقها ، ولكن ، كما أشرنا للتو ، يمكن أن يكون لعلامات التصنيف معانٍ متعددة ومتغيرة. في هذه المقالة ، نقترح خوارزمية تجميع الإحساس الزمني بناءً على فكرة أن علامات التجزئة ذات الصلة الدلالية لها أنماط استخدام متشابهة ومتزامنة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Los hashtags son etiquetas creativas que se utilizan en los microblogs para caracterizar el tema de un mensaje/debate. Independientemente del uso al que se destinaron originalmente, los hashtags no se pueden usar como un medio para agrupar mensajes con contenido similar. En primer lugar, dado que los usuarios crean hashtags de forma espontánea y altamente dinámica en varios idiomas, el mismo tema puede asociarse con diferentes hashtags y, a la inversa, el mismo hashtag puede referirse a diferentes temas en diferentes períodos de tiempo. En segundo lugar, a diferencia de las palabras comunes, la desambiguación de las etiquetas se complica por el hecho de que no hay catálogos de sentido (por ejemplo, Wikipedia o WordNet) disponibles; y, además, las etiquetas de las etiquetas son difíciles de analizar, ya que a menudo consisten en acrónimos, palabras concatenadas, etc. Una forma común de determinar el significado de los hashtags ha sido analizar su contexto, pero, como acabamos de señalar, los hashtags pueden tener significados múltiples y variables. En este artículo, proponemos un algoritmo de clustering de sentido temporal basado en la idea de que los hashtags relacionados semánticamente tienen patrones de uso similares y sincrónicos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Hashtags são rótulos criativos usados em microblogs para caracterizar o tema de uma mensagem/discussão. Independentemente do uso para o qual foram originalmente destinadas, as hashtags não podem ser usadas como meio de agrupar mensagens com conteúdo semelhante. Primeiro, porque as hashtags são criadas de forma espontânea e altamente dinâmica por usuários em vários idiomas, o mesmo tópico pode ser associado a diferentes hashtags e, inversamente, a mesma hashtag pode se referir a diferentes tópicos em diferentes períodos de tempo. Em segundo lugar, ao contrário das palavras comuns, a desambiguação de hashtag é complicada pelo fato de que não há catálogos de sentido (por exemplo, Wikipedia ou WordNet) disponíveis; e, além disso, os rótulos de hashtag são difíceis de analisar, pois geralmente consistem em siglas, palavras concatenadas e assim por diante. Uma maneira comum de determinar o significado das hashtags tem sido analisar seu contexto, mas, como acabamos de apontar, as hashtags podem ter significados múltiplos e variáveis. Neste artigo, propomos um algoritmo de agrupamento de sentido temporal baseado na ideia de que hashtags semanticamente relacionadas possuem padrões de uso semelhantes e síncronos.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_fr>Les hashtags sont des étiquettes créatives utilisées dans les micro-blogs pour caractériser le sujet d'un message/discussion. Quelle que soit l'utilisation pour laquelle ils étaient initialement destinés, les hashtags ne peuvent pas être utilisés comme moyen de regrouper des messages ayant un contenu similaire. Tout d'abord, étant donné que les hashtags sont créés de manière spontanée et très dynamique par des utilisateurs dans plusieurs langues, le même sujet peut être associé à différents hashtags, et inversement, le même hashtag peut faire référence à différents sujets à différentes périodes. Deuxièmement, contrairement aux mots courants, la désambiguïsation des hashtags est compliquée par le fait qu'aucun catalogue de sens (par exemple, Wikipédia ou WordNet) n'est disponible ; et, en outre, les étiquettes de hashtag sont difficiles à analyser, car elles sont souvent constituées d'acronymes, de mots concaténés, etc. Une méthode courante pour déterminer la signification des hashtags consiste à analyser leur contexte, mais, comme nous venons de le souligner, les hashtags peuvent avoir des significations multiples et variables. Dans cet article, nous proposons un algorithme de clustering de sens temporel basé sur l'idée que les hashtags sémantiquement liés ont des modèles d'utilisation similaires et synchrones.</abstract_fr>
      <abstract_zh>题者,微博中之创意标签,所以述消息/论题也。 主题标初欲何用,主题标签皆不可。 先题者,用户以多种语言自发与高动相应,故同题而相关,同题而异时间段者也。 其次,与常用词相反,题标消除歧义无义目录(例,维基百科WordNet)可而变得复杂。 又题标难析,盖首字母缩略词联单词等也。 立题之义,析其上下文,如新指之,可以多可变之义。 本文中,我们发出一种时间感知聚类算法,该算法基于语义相关的主题标签有相似和同步的用式。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ja>ハッシュタグは、メッセージ/ディスカッションのトピックを特徴付けるためにマイクロブログで使用されるクリエイティブラベルです。 ハッシュタグは、元々どのような用途を意図していたかにかかわらず、同様の内容のメッセージをクラスター化する手段として使用することはできません。 まず、ハッシュタグは、複数の言語のユーザーによって自発的かつ非常にダイナミックな方法で作成されるため、同じトピックは、異なるハッシュタグに関連付けることができ、逆に、同じハッシュタグは、異なる期間の異なるトピックを参照することができる。 第２に、一般的な単語とは逆に、ハッシュタグの曖昧さ解消は、センスカタログ（例えば、ＷｉｋｉｐｅｄｉａまたはＷｏｒｄＮｅｔ ）が利用可能でないという事実によって複雑であり、さらに、ハッシュタグラベルは、多くの場合、頭字語、連結された単語などからなるため、分析することが困難である。 ハッシュタグの意味を決定する一般的な方法は、コンテキストを分析することですが、先ほど指摘したように、ハッシュタグには複数の意味があり、さまざまな意味があります。 この記事では、意味的に関連するハッシュタグが類似した同期的な使用パターンを持つという考えに基づいて、時間感覚クラスタリングアルゴリズムを提案します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ru>Хештеги - это творческие метки, используемые в микроблогах для характеристики темы сообщения/обсуждения. Независимо от того, для какого использования они изначально предназначались, хэштеги не могут использоваться в качестве средства для кластеризации сообщений со схожим контентом. Во-первых, поскольку хэштеги создаются спонтанно и динамично пользователями на нескольких языках, одна и та же тема может быть связана с разными хэштегами, и, наоборот, один и тот же хэштег может относиться к разным темам в разные периоды времени. Во-вторых, в отличие от обычных слов, дезагрегирование хэштегов осложняется тем, что нет доступных каталогов смысла (например, Википедии или WordNet); и, кроме того, метки хэштегов трудно анализировать, поскольку они часто состоят из акронимов, объединенных слов и так далее. Обычным способом определения значения хэштегов был анализ их контекста, но, как мы только что отметили, хэштеги могут иметь несколько и переменные значения. В этой статье мы предлагаем алгоритм кластеризации во времени, основанный на идее, что семантически связанные хэштеги имеют похожие и синхронные шаблоны использования.</abstract_ru>
      <abstract_hi>हैशटैग एक संदेश / चर्चा के विषय को चिह्नित करने के लिए माइक्रो-ब्लॉग में उपयोग किए जाने वाले रचनात्मक लेबल हैं। उपयोग के बावजूद जिसके लिए वे मूल रूप से इरादा थे, हैशटैग का उपयोग समान सामग्री वाले संदेशों को क्लस्टर करने के साधन के रूप में नहीं किया जा सकता है। सबसे पहले, क्योंकि हैशटैग कई भाषाओं में उपयोगकर्ताओं द्वारा एक सहज और अत्यधिक गतिशील तरीके से बनाए जाते हैं, एक ही विषय को विभिन्न हैशटैग के साथ जोड़ा जा सकता है, और इसके विपरीत, एक ही हैशटैग अलग-अलग समय अवधि में विभिन्न विषयों को संदर्भित कर सकता है। दूसरा, आम शब्दों के विपरीत, हैशटैग बहुविकल्पित इस तथ्य से जटिल है कि कोई भी अर्थ कैटलॉग (जैसे, विकिपीडिया या वर्डनेट) उपलब्ध नहीं हैं; और, इसके अलावा, हैशटैग लेबल का विश्लेषण करना मुश्किल है, क्योंकि वे अक्सर संक्षिप्त शब्दों, concatenated शब्दों, और इतने आगे से मिलकर बनते हैं। हैशटैग के अर्थ को निर्धारित करने का एक सामान्य तरीका उनके संदर्भ का विश्लेषण करना है, लेकिन, जैसा कि हमने अभी बताया है, हैशटैग के कई और परिवर्तनीय अर्थ हो सकते हैं। इस लेख में, हम इस विचार के आधार पर एक अस्थायी भावना क्लस्टरिंग एल्गोरिथ्म का प्रस्ताव करते हैं कि शब्दार्थ से संबंधित हैशटैग में समान और तुल्यकालिक उपयोग पैटर्न हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Is lipéid chruthaitheacha iad haischlibeanna a úsáidtear i micreabhloganna chun topaic na teachtaireachta/na bplé a shainiú. Is cuma cén úsáid a bhí beartaithe dóibh ar dtús, ní féidir hashtags a úsáid mar mhodh chun teachtaireachtaí a bhfuil ábhar comhchosúil iontu a bhraisliú. Ar an gcéad dul síos, toisc go gcruthaíonn úsáideoirí i dteangacha iolracha hashtags ar bhealach spontáineach agus an-dinimiciúil, is féidir an t-ábhar céanna a nascadh le haischlibeanna éagsúla, agus os a choinne sin, féadfaidh an hashtag céanna tagairt a dhéanamh d’ábhair éagsúla i dtréimhsí ama éagsúla. Ar an dara dul síos, contrártha d’fhocail choitianta, is casta an dí-athbhrí ar an hashtag toisc nach bhfuil catalóga ciall ar bith (m.sh. Vicipéid nó WordNet) ar fáil; agus, ina theannta sin, is deacair anailís a dhéanamh ar lipéid haischlibeanna, mar is minic a chuimsíonn siad acrainmneacha, focail chomhcheangailte, agus mar sin de. Bealach coitianta chun brí na hashtags a chinneadh ná anailís a dhéanamh ar a gcomhthéacs, ach, mar a thugamar le fios, is féidir le bríonna iolracha agus athraitheacha a bheith ag hashtags. San Airteagal seo, molaimid algartam braislithe ama bunaithe ar an smaoineamh go bhfuil patrúin úsáide comhchosúla agus shioncrónacha ag hashtags a bhaineann go séimeantach.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჰაქტიგები არის კრეატიური ლაბექტები, რომელიც მიკრობლოგში გამოყენებულია შეტყობინება/დისუქტის თემის განსაკუთრებისთვის. არაფერი, რომლის გამოყენება, რომელსაც ისინი პირველურად იყენებულია, ჰექტაქტები არ შეიძლება გამოყენება როგორც სხვადასხვა შემდგომარებისთვის. პირველი, რადგან ჰექტაქტები სპონტანურად და ძალიან დინამიკურად გამოყენებელი მრავალ ენაში შექმნა, იგივე თემა შეიძლება განსხვავებული ჰექტაქტებით დაკავშირება, და განსხვავებული დროის პერიოდში ი მეორე, საერთო სიტყვების განმავლობაზე, hashtag განმავლობა კომპლექტიურია ფაქტიდან, რომ არაფერი სიტყვების კარალოგები (მაგალითად, Wikipedia ან WordNet) არსებობს; და დამატებით, ჰექტაგის ნიშანები ძალიან რთულია ანალიზაცია, რადგან ისინი ზოგიერთად აკრონიმებით, სხვადასხვა სიტყვებით და ასე. საერთო გზა, როგორც ჩვენ აჩვენეთ, ჰექტაქტების ნიშნალის განსაზღვრება იყო, რომ მათი კონტექსტის ანალიზაცია, მაგრამ, როგორც ჩვენ აჩვენეთ, ჰექტაქტები შეიძ ამ წილაკში, ჩვენ მინდომებით სამყარო სისტერმის ალგორიტიმა, რომელიც სამყაროდ დაკავშირებული ჰექტატები აქვს სხვადასხვა და სინქრონური გამოყენება.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A Hashtag-ok kreatív címkék, amelyeket mikroblogokban használnak, hogy jellemezzék az üzenet/vita témáját. Függetlenül attól, hogy milyen használatra szánták őket eredetileg, a hashtag-ek nem használhatók hasonló tartalmú üzenetek fürtözésére. Először is, mivel a hashtag-eket a felhasználók spontán és rendkívül dinamikus módon hozzák létre több nyelven, ugyanazt a témát különböző hashtag-ekkel lehet társítani, és fordítva, ugyanaz a hashtag különböző témákra utalhat különböző időszakokban. Másodszor, a közönséges szavakkal ellentétben a hashtag egyértelműségét bonyolítja az a tény, hogy nincs értelmi katalógus (pl. Wikipédia vagy WordNet) elérhető; Továbbá a hashtag címkéket nehéz elemezni, mivel gyakran rövidítésekből, összefüggő szavakból és így tovább állnak. A hashtag jelentésének meghatározásának egyik leggyakoribb módja az volt, hogy elemezzük a kontextust, de amint éppen rámutattunk, a hashtag-ek többféle és változó jelentésűek lehetnek. Ebben a cikkben egy időérzéki klaszterezési algoritmust javasolunk, amely azon az elképzelésen alapul, hogy a szemantikailag kapcsolódó hashtag-ek hasonló és szinkron használati mintákkal rendelkeznek.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Τα hashtags είναι δημιουργικές ετικέτες που χρησιμοποιούνται σε μικροblogs για να χαρακτηρίσουν το θέμα ενός μηνύματος/συζήτησης. Ανεξάρτητα από τη χρήση για την οποία προορίζονταν αρχικά, δεν μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν ως μέσο ομαδοποίησης μηνυμάτων με παρόμοιο περιεχόμενο. Πρώτον, επειδή δημιουργούνται με αυθόρμητο και ιδιαίτερα δυναμικό τρόπο από χρήστες σε πολλές γλώσσες, το ίδιο θέμα μπορεί να συσχετιστεί με διαφορετικά και αντίστροφα, το ίδιο μπορεί να αναφέρεται σε διαφορετικά θέματα σε διαφορετικές χρονικές περιόδους. Δεύτερον, σε αντίθεση με τις κοινές λέξεις, η αποσαφήνιση με hashtag περιπλέκεται από το γεγονός ότι δεν υπάρχουν κατάλογοι λογικών (π.χ. Βικιπαίδεια ή WordNet). και, επιπλέον, οι ετικέτες hashtag είναι δύσκολο να αναλυθούν, καθώς συχνά αποτελούνται από ακρωνύμια, αλληλουχημένες λέξεις και ούτω καθεξής. Ένας κοινός τρόπος για να καθοριστεί η σημασία των hashtags ήταν η ανάλυση του πλαισίου τους, αλλά, όπως μόλις επισημάναμε, οι hashtags μπορούν να έχουν πολλαπλές και μεταβλητές έννοιες. Σε αυτό το άρθρο, προτείνουμε έναν αλγόριθμο συσσώρευσης χρονικών αισθήσεων βασισμένο στην ιδέα ότι σημασιολογικά συνδεδεμένα hashtags έχουν παρόμοια και συγχρόνως πρότυπα χρήσης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Gli hashtag sono etichette creative utilizzate nei micro-blog per caratterizzare l'argomento di un messaggio/discussione. Indipendentemente dall'uso per cui erano originariamente destinati, gli hashtag non possono essere utilizzati come mezzo per raggruppare messaggi con contenuti simili. In primo luogo, poiché gli hashtag sono creati in modo spontaneo e altamente dinamico dagli utenti in più lingue, lo stesso argomento può essere associato a hashtag diversi, e viceversa, lo stesso hashtag può riferirsi a argomenti diversi in periodi di tempo diversi. In secondo luogo, contrariamente alle parole comuni, la disambiguazione degli hashtag è complicata dal fatto che non sono disponibili cataloghi di senso (ad esempio Wikipedia o WordNet); e, inoltre, le etichette di hashtag sono difficili da analizzare, in quanto spesso consistono di acronimi, parole concatenate, e così via. Un modo comune per determinare il significato degli hashtag è stato analizzare il loro contesto, ma, come abbiamo appena sottolineato, gli hashtag possono avere significati multipli e variabili. In questo articolo, proponiamo un algoritmo di clustering temporale basato sull'idea che gli hashtag semanticamente correlati abbiano modelli di utilizzo simili e sincroni.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Hashtagai yra kūrybinės etiketės, naudojamos mikrobloguose pranešimo ir (arba) diskusijos temai apibūdinti. Nepaisant naudojimo, kuriam jie iš pradžių buvo skirti, hashtagai negali būti naudojami kaip panašaus turinio pranešimų grupavimo priemonė. Pirma, kadangi naudotojai įvairiomis kalbomis savanoriškai ir labai dinamiškai sukuria hashtagus, ta pati tema gali būti susijusi su skirtingais hashtagus, o atvirkščiai, ta pati hashtag a gali būti susijusi su skirtingomis temomis skirtingais laiko laikotarpiais. Antra, priešingai nei įprasti žodžiai, hashto nesuaiškinimas yra sudėtingas dėl to, kad nėra jokių prasmių katalogų (pvz., Wikipedia arba WordNet); Be to, hashtag etiketes sunku analizuoti, nes dažnai sudaro akronimai, sutrumpinti žodžiai ir pan. Bendras būdas nustatyti hashtagų reikšmę buvo analizuoti jų kontekstą, tačiau, kaip ką tik pažymėjome, hashtagai gali turėti įvairių ir kintamų reikšmių. Šiame straipsnyje siūlome laiką suvienodinti algoritmą, pagrįstą idėja, kad semantiškai susiję hashtagai turi panašius ir sinchroninius naudojimo modelius.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Хаштаговите се креативни етикети кои се користат во микроблоговите за да ја карактеризираат темата на порака/дискусија. Без оглед на употребата за која се наменети, хаштаговите не можат да се користат како средство за групирање пораки со слична содржина. First, because hashtags are created in a spontaneous and highly dynamic way by users in multiple languages, the same topic can be associated with different hashtags, and conversely, the same hashtag may refer to different topics in different time periods.  Второ, спротивно на обичните зборови, раздвојувањето на хаштагот е комплицирано од фактот дека нема смислени каталоги (на пример, Википедија или WordNet) достапни; Покрај тоа, тешко е да се анализираат хашташките етикети, бидејќи често се состојат од акроними, концентрирани зборови и така натаму. Заедничкиот начин да се одреди значењето на хаштаговите е анализирањето на нивниот контекст, но, како што штотуку истакнавме, хаштаговите можат да имаат многуте и променливи значења. Во оваа статија, предложуваме температурна смисла за групирање алгоритам базиран на идејата дека семантично поврзаните хаштагови имаат слични и синхронични шеми на употреба.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Хаттар - мәтін/ дискуссияның нақышын таңдау үшін микро- блогтарда қолданылатын жарлық жарлықтары. Бастапқы мақсаттарының қолдануына қарамастан, хаттар ұқсас мазмұнымен хаттарды кластерлеу үшін қолданылмайды. Біріншіден, бірнеше тілде пайдаланушылар қолданатын жазулар автоматты және өте динамикалық түрде құрылған себебі, бір нақышы әртүрлі жазулармен байланысты болады, және әртүрлі, бір жазу әртүрлі уақыт кезінде әртүрлі на Екіншіден, жалпы сөздерге қарсы, hashtag дисамбивуациясы, сезімді каталогтар (мысалы, Википедия не WordNet) қол жеткізбеген факт қолданылмайды. Сонымен қатар, хаттар жарлықтарын анализ ету қиын болады, себебі олар көбінде акронимдерден, сәйкес сөздерден тұрады. Хаттардың мазмұнын анықтау жалпы жолы - олардың контексті анықтау, бірақ біз тек көрсетілгенде хаттар бірнеше және айнымалы мазмұнын анықтауға болады. Бұл мақалада біз уақытша сезімді кластер алгоритміне ұқсас және синхрондық пайдалану үлгілері бар идеясына негізделген.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Hashtags adalah label kreatif yang digunakan dalam mikroblog untuk mengukur topik mesej/diskusi. Walaupun penggunaan yang dimaksudkan pada awalnya, hashtag tidak boleh digunakan sebagai cara untuk kumpulkan mesej dengan kandungan yang sama. Pertama, kerana hashtag dicipta secara spontan dan sangat dinamik oleh pengguna dalam berbagai bahasa, topik yang sama boleh dikaitkan dengan hashtag yang berbeza, dan sebaliknya, hashtag yang sama boleh rujuk kepada topik yang berbeza dalam masa yang berbeza. Kedua, bertentangan dengan perkataan biasa, penyelesaian hashtag adalah rumit dengan fakta bahawa katalog tidak masuk akal (cth. Wikipedia atau WordNet) tersedia; dan, selain itu, label hashtag sukar untuk dianalisis, kerana ia sering terdiri dari akronim, kata-kata yang terkongsi, dan sebagainya. Cara umum untuk menentukan makna hashtag adalah untuk menganalisis konteks mereka, tetapi, seperti yang kita baru sahaja menunjukkan, hashtag boleh mempunyai makna berbilang dan pembolehubah. Dalam artikel ini, kami cadangkan algoritma pengkumpulan sementara berdasarkan idea bahawa hashtag berkaitan semantik mempunyai corak penggunaan yang sama dan sinkronik.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>മൈക്രോ- ബ്ലഗുകളില്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന ഹാഷ്ട്രാഗ്സുകള്‍ സൃഷ്ടിക്കുന്ന ചിത്രങ്ങളാണ്. ഒരു സന്ദേശം/സംസാരിക്ക ആദ്യമായി ഉദ്ദേശിച്ചിരിക്കുന്ന ഉപയോഗങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് ഉപയോഗിച്ചിട്ടില്ലെങ്കില്‍, ഇതുപോലുള്ള വസ്തുക്കളുമായി സന്ദേ ആദ്യം, കാരണം ഹാഷ്ട്ടാഗുകള്‍ സ്പെയിനിയമമായും വളരെ dynamic രീതിയില്‍ സൃഷ്ടിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. പല ഭാഷകളില്‍ ഉപയോക്താക്കള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കുന്നു. അതേ വ്യത്യസ്ത ഹാഷ്ട രണ്ടാമത്, സാധാരണ വാക്കുകളെ വിരോധമാക്കുന്നു, ഹാഷ്ടാഗിന്റെ വിക്ഷേപങ്ങള്‍ കുഴപ്പമുണ്ടാക്കുന്നു. വിക്കിപീഡിയ അല്ലെങ്കില്‍ വാര അതിനുശേഷം, ഹാഷ്ട്ടാഗ് ലേബിളുകള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കാന്‍ ബുദ്ധിമുട്ടുന്നു. അതുകൊണ്ട് പലപ്പോഴും അക്രോണിമിനുകളില്‍ ഉള്ള വാക്ക ഹാഷ്ടാഗിന്റെ അര്‍ത്ഥം തീരുമാനിക്കാന്‍ ഒരു സാധാരണമായ രീതിയാണ് അവയുടെ കൂട്ടത്തില്‍ പരിശോധിക്കേണ്ടത്. പക്ഷെ ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഇപ്പോള്‍ പറഞ്ഞുകൊണ ഈ ലേഖനത്തില്‍, നമ്മള്‍ ആല്‍ഗോരിതം സംസാരിക്കുന്ന ഒരു സമയത്തെ മനസ്സിലാക്കുന്നു. സെമാന്റിക്കല്‍ ബന്ധപ്പെട്ട ഹാഷ്ട്ടാഗുകള്‍ക്ക് ഒരു</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Il-hashtags huma tikketti kreattivi użati fil-mikroblogs biex jikkaratterizzaw is-suġġett ta’ messaġġ/diskussjoni. Irrispettivament mill-użu li għalih kienu maħsuba oriġinarjament, il-hashtags ma jistgħux jintużaw bħala mezz biex jinġabru flimkien messaġġi b’kontenut simili. L-ewwel nett, minħabba li l-hashtags jinħolqu b’mod spontanju u dinamiku ħafna mill-utenti f’diversi lingwi, l-istess suġġett jista’ jkun assoċjat ma’ hashtags differenti, u bil-maqlub, l-istess hashtag jista’ jirreferi għal suġġetti differenti f’perjodi ta’ żmien differenti. It-tieni, g ħall-kuntrarju tal-kliem komuni, id-diżambigwazzjoni tal-hashtag hija kkumplikata mill-fatt li l-ebda katalgi sensittivi (pereżempju Wikipedia jew WordNet) mhumiex disponibbli; and, furthermore, hashtag labels are difficult to analyze, as they often consist of acronyms, concatenated words, and so forth.  Mod komuni biex jiġi ddeterminat it-tifsira tal-hashtags kien li jiġi analizzat il-kuntest tagħhom, iżda, kif għadna kif enfasizzaw, l-hashtags jista’ jkollhom tifsiriet multipli u varjabbli. F’dan l-artikolu, qed nipproponu sens temporali ta’ raggruppament ta’ algoritmu bbażat fuq l-idea li hashtags relatati semantikament għandhom xejriet simili u sinkroniċi ta’ użu.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Hashtagi to kreatywne etykiety używane w mikroblogach do charakteryzowania tematu komunikatu/dyskusji. Niezależnie od zastosowania, do którego były one pierwotnie przeznaczone, hashtagi nie mogą być używane jako środek do klastrowania wiadomości o podobnej treści. Po pierwsze, ponieważ hashtagi są tworzone w sposób spontaniczny i bardzo dynamiczny przez użytkowników w wielu językach, ten sam temat może być powiązany z różnymi hashtagami, a odwrotnie, ten sam hashtag może odnosić się do różnych tematów w różnych okresach czasu. Po drugie, w przeciwieństwie do zwykłych słów, rozproszenie hashtagów jest komplikowane przez fakt, że nie są dostępne katalogi sensu (np. Wikipedia czy WordNet); Co więcej, etykiety hashtagów są trudne do analizy, ponieważ często składają się z akronimów, połączonych słów i tak dalej. Częstym sposobem określenia znaczenia hashtagów była analiza ich kontekstu, ale, jak właśnie wskazaliśmy, hashtagi mogą mieć wiele i zmiennych znaczeń. W tym artykule proponujemy algorytm klastrowania zmysłów czasowych oparty na idei, że semantycznie powiązane hashtagi mają podobne i synchroniczne wzorce użytkowania.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Hashtags-urile sunt etichete creative folosite în micro-bloguri pentru a caracteriza subiectul unui mesaj / discuție. Indiferent de utilizarea pentru care au fost destinate inițial, hashtagurile nu pot fi utilizate ca mijloc de a grupa mesaje cu conținut similar. În primul rând, deoarece hashtagurile sunt create într-un mod spontan și extrem de dinamic de către utilizatori în mai multe limbi, același subiect poate fi asociat cu hashtaguri diferite, iar invers, același hashtag poate face referire la subiecte diferite în perioade de timp diferite. În al doilea rând, contrar cuvintelor obișnuite, dezambiguizarea hashtag-urilor este complicată de faptul că nu sunt disponibile cataloage de sens (de exemplu, Wikipedia sau WordNet); și, în plus, etichetele hashtag-urilor sunt dificil de analizat, deoarece constau adesea din acronime, cuvinte concatenate și așa mai departe. O modalitate comună de a determina semnificația hashtagurilor a fost de a analiza contextul lor, dar, după cum tocmai am subliniat, hashtagurile pot avea semnificații multiple și variabile. În acest articol, propunem un algoritm de clusterizare a simțurilor temporale bazat pe ideea că hashtagurile legate semantic au modele de utilizare similare și sincrone.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mn>Хаттагууд нь бичил-блогуудын тухай санаа/ярилцлагын тухай харуулахын тулд хэрэглэгддэг бүтээлч загварууд юм. Эхлээд зориулагдсан хэрэглээний тухай ч хамаагүй, адилхан бүтээгдэхүүнтэй холбоотой хавтасуудыг цуглуулахад ашиглаж чадахгүй. Эхлээд, яагаад гэвэл олон хэл дээр хэрэглэгчдийн хувьд хавтасуудыг өөр өөр хэлбэртэй холбоотой болохоор хавтасуудыг өөр өөр хэлбэрээр бий болгосон учраас ижил хавтасуудыг өөр хэлбэрээр харуулж болно. Хоёрдугаар, нийтлэг үгсийн эсрэг, хашгийг хэсгүйсгэх нь мэдрэмжтэй каталогууд (жишээ нь Wikipedia эсвэл WordNet) байхгүй гэсэн үг юм. Харин хашгийн etiketүүд нь ихэвчлэн акронимууд, мөн адилхан үгнүүд байдаг учраас шинжилгээнд хэцүү. Хэтэтгүүдийн утгыг тодорхойлох ерөнхий арга нь тэдний тодорхойлолтыг шинжилгээ хийх юм. Гэхдээ бид саяхан тодорхойлсон шиг хэлбэрүүдийн утгыг олон, өөрчлөлтийн утгыг гаргаж болно. Энэ хэвлэлд бид цаг хугацааны мэдрэмжтэй алгоритм гэсэн санаанд төстэй, ижил хэрэглэх хэлбэртэй гэдгийг сануулдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Hashtag er kreativ merkelapp bruka i mikro-bloggar for å teikna emnet på ei melding/diskusjon. I tillegg til bruken av dei opphavleg målet, kan ikkje hashtagane brukast som ein måte for å gruppa meldingar med liknande innhald. Først, fordi brukarar i fleire språk lagar ein spontan og ganske dynamisk hashtag, kan det same emnet vera tilknytta med ulike hashtag, og samme hashtag kan referera til ulike emner i ulike tidsperioder. Andre, motsatt til vanlege ord, er desambiguasjonen av hashtag komplisert av faktum at ingen følelseskatalogar (f.eks. Wikipedia eller WordNet) er tilgjengeleg; og Det er likevel vanskeleg å analysere hashtag, sidan dei ofte inneheld av akronymar, samsvarte ord og så videre. Eit vanleg måte å bestemme betydninga på hashtagane er å analysera konteksten sine, men som vi nettopp har vist, kan hashtagane ha fleire og variabele betydningar. I denne artikkelen foreslår vi ein mellombels algoritme for klassering av sentrum basert på ideen at semantisk relaterte hashtag har liknande og synkroniske bruksmønster.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_si>පණිවිඩය/කතා කරන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් විශේෂය කරන්න හැෂ්ටැග්ස් සෘද්ධික ලේබල් වල භාවිත කරන්න. ඔවුන් මුලින්ම ඉලක්ෂා කරලා තියෙන ප්‍රයෝජනය ගැන හැස්ටග්ස් විදිහට ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න බැරි විදිහක් විදිහට ප මුලින්, හැස්ටැග්ස් ස්පොන්ටන් හා විශේෂ භාෂාවක් වල භාෂාවක් වල භාෂාවක් නිර්මාණය කරලා තියෙන හැස්ටැග්ස් වලින් සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න දෙවෙනි වෙනුවෙන්, සාමාන්‍ය වචන වලට විරුද්ධයෙන්, හැස්ටැග් අසංක්‍රීයාවක් සංක්‍රීය වෙනුවෙන් ඇත්තටම සංක්‍රීය වෙනුව ඒ වගේම, හැස්ටැග් ලේබල් විශ්ලේෂනය කරන්න අමාරුයි, ඒ වගේම ඔවුන් සමහර විශ්ලේෂණය කරලා තියෙන්නේ ඇක්රෝනිම් වච හැස්ටැග්ස් අදහසක් නිර්ධාරණය කරන්න සාමාන්‍ය විදිහයක් තියෙන්නේ ඔවුන්ගේ සංවේදනය විශ්ලේෂණය කරන්න, ඒත්, අපි දැන් පෙන මේ ලේඛනයේදී, අපි සාමාන්තික සම්බන්ධතාවක් සහ සම්බන්ධතාවක් ප්‍රයෝජනයක් තියෙනවා කියලා අදහසට ආධාරණය කරනවා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Hashtagyada waxaa lagu isticmaalaa alaabta abuurka ah ee lagu isticmaali karo micro-blog si loo sawiro mada warqada/discussion. Si kastaba ha ahaatee isticmaalka ay ugu horeysay loogu talagalay, hashtagga laguma isticmaali karo sida qaab loogu soo bandhigi karo warqadaha ku qoran waxyaabaha isku mid ah. Marka ugu horeysa, sababtoo ah hashtagga waxaa lagu sameeyaa qaab aad u dhaqdhaqaaqsan oo isticmaalayaal luuqado kala duduwan, isla mada waxaa la xiriiri karaa isku wasakh oo la xiriira alaabta kala duduwan, isla hashtagga waxaa loola jeedi karaa maadooyin kala duduwan waqtiyada kala duwan. Second, oo ka gees ah hadallada caadiga ah, kaluumeysiga shabakadda waxaa ku adag in aysan helin kataaradaha maanka ah (tusaale ahaan Wikipedia ama WordNet) and, furthermore, hashtag labels are difficult to analyze, as they often consist of acronyms, concatenated words, and so forth.  Wadada caadiga ah oo ku saabsan waxyaabaha hagaajiyada waa in lagu kala fakaraa xaaladooda, laakiin sida aan haatan ku qornay, hashtagyadu waxay heli karaan micno kala duduwan oo kala bedelan. Markaas waxan warqaddan ku qoran, waxaynu soo jeedaynaa fikrada lagu soo bandhigi karo qoraalka, taasoo ku saleysan fikrada alaabta la xiriira halka ah waxay leeyihiin qaab u eg iyo isku mid ah isticmaalka.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Hashtags är kreativa etiketter som används i mikrobloggar för att karakterisera ämnet för ett meddelande/diskussion. Oavsett vilken användning de ursprungligen var avsedda för kan hashtaggar inte användas som ett sätt att klustra meddelanden med liknande innehåll. För det första, eftersom hashtaggar skapas på ett spontant och mycket dynamiskt sätt av användare på flera språk, kan samma ämne associeras med olika hashtaggar, och omvänt kan samma hashtag hänvisa till olika ämnen under olika tidsperioder. För det andra, i motsats till vanliga ord, är hashtaggsdisambiguation komplicerad av det faktum att inga meningskataloger (t.ex. Wikipedia eller WordNet) finns tillgängliga; och dessutom är hashtagg etiketter svåra att analysera, eftersom de ofta består av akronymer, sammankopplade ord och så vidare. Ett vanligt sätt att avgöra betydelsen av hashtags har varit att analysera deras sammanhang, men som vi just har påpekat kan hashtags ha flera och varierande betydelser. I den här artikeln föreslår vi en temporal sense clustering algoritm baserad på idén att semantiskt relaterade hashtags har liknande och synkrona användningsmönster.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Hashtags su kreativne etikete koje se koriste u mikro-blogu kako bi karakterizirale tema poruke/diskusije. Bez obzira na korištenje koje su originalno nameravane, hashtage se ne mogu koristiti kao sredstvo za skupljanje poruka sa sličnim sadržajem. Prvo, zato što su hashtagi stvoreni spontanom i visoko dinamičnim putem korisnika na višestrukim jezicima, isti tema može biti povezan sa različitim hashtagama, a u suprotnom, isti hashtag može da se odnosi na različite teme u različitim vremenskim periodima. Drugo, suprotno zajedničkim rečima, disambiguacija hashtaga je komplikovana činjenicom da nisu dostupni ni katalog osjećaja (npr. Wikipedia ili WordNet); Osim toga, etikete hashtaga su teško analizirati, jer se često sastoje od akronima, potvrđenih reči i tako dalje. Običan način da odredimo smisao hashtaga je analiziranje njihovog konteksta, ali, kako smo upravo pokazali, hashtage mogu imati višestruke i varijantne značenje. U ovom članku predlažemo privremeni algoritam skupljanja osjećaja na osnovu ideje da semantički povezani hashtagi imaju slične i sinhronizne obrasce korištenja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>செய்தி/விவாதத்தின் தலைப்பை தனிப்படுத்துவதற்கு மைக்ரோ தொகுதிகளில் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட சிட்டைகள் உருவாக்கும். முதலில் தாங்கள் தேவைப்பட்ட பயன்பாட்டை பயன்படுத்தவில்லை முதலில், ஏனெனில் பயனர்கள் பல மொழிகளால் தானாகவே மற்றும் மிகவும் தனிப்பட்ட மற்றும் தனிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட தேவையான வழியில் ஹாஷ்டாக்குகள் உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, அதே தலைப்பு வே இரண்டாவது, பொதுவான வார்த்தைகளுக்கு எதிராக, விகிபிடியா அல்லது வார்த்தைட்டு நெட்டில் கிடைக்கவில்லை அதற்கு மேலும், ஹாஷ்டாக்கு சிட்டைகளை ஆய்வு செய்ய கடுமையாக இருக்கிறது, அது பெரும்பாலும் குறிப்பிட்ட வார்த்தைகள் உள்ளன, ம ஹாஷ்டாக்ஸின் அர்த்தத்தை தீர்வு செய்ய ஒரு பொதுவான வழி அளபுருவை ஆய்வு செய்யலாம், ஆனால் நாம் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளோம் என்பது போல், ஹாஷ இந்த கட்டுரையில், நாம் ஒரு காலாவதியான உணர்வு தொடர்பு அல்gorithm அடிப்படையில் முன்நிரூபிக்கிறோம் அர்த்தமான தொடர்பு ஹாஷ்டாக்காக்கள</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہشٹاگ ایک پیغام/بحث کے موضوع کو تعریف کرنے کے لئے میکرو-بلاگ میں استعمال کیا جاتا ہے. جس کے لئے وہ پہلی بار مقرر کیا گیا تھا اچھا بھی، ہشتاگ اس طرح استعمال نہیں کیا جائے گا کہ پیغام کو اس طرح کے منزل کے ساتھ کلسٹر کریں۔ پہلے، کیونکہ ہشتاگ بہت سی زبانوں میں استعمال کرنے والوں کے ذریعہ ایک سپانٹن اور بہت سی ڈینامیک طریقے سے پیدا کئے جاتے ہیں، ایک ہی موضوع مختلف ہشتاگ کے ساتھ مل سکتا ہے، اور مختلف وقت کے وقت میں ایک ہی ہشتاگ مختلف موضوع کا ارتباط کرسکتا ہے. دوسرا، مشترک کلمات کے مقابلہ میں، ہشتگ نامبیواٹ کی تعلق اس حقیقت سے پیچیدہ ہے کہ کوئی حس کاٹلوگ (جیسے ویکپیڈیا یا WordNet) موجود نہیں ہے۔ اور اس کے علاوہ ہستگ لیبل تحقیق کرنے کے لئے مشکل ہے، جیسے وہ اکثر اکرونیم، مشترک کلمات اور اس کے علاوہ ہیں. ہشتاگ کا معنی مقرر کرنے کے لئے ایک مشترک طریقہ ہے کہ ان کے متصلہ کا تحلیل کرنا ہے، لیکن، جیسا ہم نے دھمکے طور پر اشارہ کیا ہے، ہشتاگ بہت سے اور متغیر معنی ہوسکتا ہے. اس مقالہ میں ہم ایک موقت احساس کلسٹر الگوریتم کو پیشنهاد کرتے ہیں جو اس ایڈیوں پر بنیاد ہے کہ سیمنٹی رابطہ دار ہشتاگ برابر اور سینکرون استعمال الگوریتم ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name @ info: whatsthis Birinchi, chunki hashtaglar har xil tilda foydalanuvchilar bilan avto- va juda dynamik usulda yaratiladi, bitta mavzu boshqa hashtaglar bilan bogʻlanishi mumkin, va bir xil vaqtda bitta hashtagga bir xil mavzularga qarshi mumkin. Ikkinchi so'z bilan biroza so'zlar bilan bogʻliq, hashtagni ajratish murakkab qilinadi. Masalan "Wikipedia yoki WordNet" mavjud emas. Va keyin, hash teglarini analyzer juda qiyin, chunki ular ko'pincha acronymlar, bir nechta so'zlarni birlashtirish mumkin. Xatchoʻplarning ma'nosini aniqlash uchun umumiy usuli ularning tarkibini aniqlash mumkin, lekin biz hozir koʻrsatilganda, hashtaglar bir necha va oʻzgaruvchining ma'nosi bo'lishi mumkin. Bu maqolada, biz bir vaqt orqali algoritni tasavvur qilamiz va semantik bog'liq hashtaglarda bir xil va synchron foydalanish usullari bor.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Những dấu vết là những nhãn hiệu sáng tạo được dùng trong vi blog để diễn tả chủ đề của tin nhắn/thảo luận. Không biết chúng được dùng cho loại nào, thì không thể dùng dấu vân tay này như một phương tiện để tải các thông điệp có nội dung tương tự. Thứ nhất, bởi vì các dấu vết Hasit được tạo ra theo một cách tự phát và rất năng động bởi người dùng trong nhiều ngôn ngữ, cùng một chủ đề có thể được kết hợp với các loại Hastag khác nhau, và ngược lại, nó có thể liên quan đến các chủ đề khác nhau trong các thời gian khác nhau. Thứ hai, trái với những từ phổ biến, sự biến biến của hashtag phức tạp bởi việc không có danh mục cảm (v.d., Wikipedia hay WordNet). Và, thêm nữa, các nhãn hashtag rất khó phân tích, vì chúng bao gồm các tạp âm, từ ngữ được gắn kết, v.v. Một cách phổ biến để xác định ý nghĩa của dấu vân tay là phân tích bối cảnh của chúng, nhưng, như chúng tôi vừa chỉ ra, dấu vân tay có thể có nhiều ý nghĩa biến. Trong bài báo này, chúng tôi đề xuất một thuật toán gắn kết cảm thái về thời gian dựa trên ý tưởng rằng các dấu vết riêng biệt có mô hình sử dụng tương tự và đồng bộ.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_da>Hashtags er kreative etiketter, der bruges i mikroblogs til at karakterisere emnet for en besked / diskussion. Uanset hvilken anvendelse de oprindeligt var beregnet til, kan hashtags ikke bruges som et middel til at klynge meddelelser med lignende indhold. For det første, fordi hashtags oprettes på en spontan og meget dynamisk måde af brugere på flere sprog, kan det samme emne associeres med forskellige hashtags, og omvendt kan det samme hashtag henvise til forskellige emner i forskellige tidsperioder. For det andet, i modsætning til almindelige ord, er hashtag-disambiguation kompliceret af det faktum, at der ikke er nogen mening kataloger (f.eks. Wikipedia eller WordNet) tilgængelige; og desuden er hashtag etiketter vanskelige at analysere, da de ofte består af akronymer, sammenkoblede ord osv. En almindelig måde at bestemme betydningen af hashtags har været at analysere deres kontekst, men som vi lige har påpeget, hashtags kan have flere og variable betydninger. I denne artikel foreslår vi en temporal sense clustering algoritme baseret på den idé, at semantisk relaterede hashtags har lignende og synkrone brugsmønstre.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Hashtags zijn creatieve labels die worden gebruikt in microblogs om het onderwerp van een boodschap/discussie te karakteriseren. Ongeacht het gebruik waarvoor ze oorspronkelijk bedoeld waren, kunnen hashtags niet worden gebruikt om berichten met vergelijkbare inhoud te clusteren. Ten eerste, omdat hashtags op een spontane en zeer dynamische manier worden gemaakt door gebruikers in meerdere talen, kan hetzelfde onderwerp worden geassocieerd met verschillende hashtags, en omgekeerd, dezelfde hashtag kan verwijzen naar verschillende onderwerpen in verschillende periodes. Ten tweede, in tegenstelling tot veel voorkomende woorden, wordt hashtag verduidelijking gecompliceerd door het feit dat er geen zintuigencatalogs (bijvoorbeeld Wikipedia of WordNet) beschikbaar zijn; Bovendien zijn hashtag labels moeilijk te analyseren, omdat ze vaak bestaan uit acroniemen, aaneengesloten woorden, enzovoort. Een veel voorkomende manier om de betekenis van hashtags te bepalen is om hun context te analyseren, maar, zoals we net hebben opgemerkt, kunnen hashtags meerdere en variabele betekenissen hebben. In dit artikel stellen we een temporal sense clustering algoritme voor gebaseerd op het idee dat semantisch gerelateerde hashtags vergelijkbare en synchrone gebruikspatronen hebben.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Хаштаговете са креативни етикети, използвани в микроблоговете за характеризиране на темата за съобщение / дискусия. Независимо от употребата, за която са били първоначално предназначени, хаштаговете не могат да се използват като средство за групиране на съобщения с подобно съдържание. Първо, тъй като хаштаговете се създават спонтанно и силно динамично от потребители на няколко езика, една и съща тема може да бъде свързана с различни хаштагове и обратно, един и същ хаштаг може да се отнася до различни теми в различни периоди от време. Второ, за разлика от често срещаните думи, разграничението на хаштаговете се усложнява от факта, че няма налични каталози за смисъл (например Уикипедия или WordNet); Освен това етикетите на хаштаговете са трудни за анализ, тъй като често се състоят от акроними, обвързани думи и т.н. Често срещан начин да се определи значението на хаштаговете е да се анализира техния контекст, но, както току-що посочихме, хаштаговете могат да имат множество и променливи значения. В тази статия предлагаме алгоритъм за клъстериране на времеви сетива, базиран на идеята, че семантично свързани хаштагове имат сходни и синхронни модели на използване.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Etikete su kreativne etikete koje se koriste u mikro-blogovima kako bi karakterizirale temu poruke/diskusije. Bez obzira na primjenu za koju su originalno namjereni, hashtage se ne mogu koristiti kao sredstvo za skupljanje poruka s sličnim sadržajem. Prvo, jer su hashtagi stvoreni spontanom i visoko dinamičnim načinom korisnici na višestrukim jezicima, isti tema se može povezati s različitim hashtagama, a u suprotnom, isti hashtag može odnijeti na različite teme u različitim vremenskim periodima. Drugo, suprotno čestitim riječima, disambiguacija hashtaga je komplikovana činjenicom da nema kataloga osjećaja (npr. Wikipedia ili WordNet) na raspolaganju; Osim toga, etikete hashtaga su teško analizirati, jer često se sastoje od akronima, potvrđenih riječi i tako dalje. Običan način za određivanje značenja hashtaga je analiziranje njihovog konteksta, ali, kako smo upravo pokazali, hashtage mogu imati višestruke i varijantne značenje. U ovom članku predlažemo privremeni algoritam skupljanja osjećaja na temelju ideje da semantički povezani hashtagi imaju slične i sinhronizne obrasce korištenja.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_ko>Hashtags는 마이크로 블로그에서 메시지/토론 주제를 묘사하는 창의적인 라벨이다.그것들의 최초의 용도가 무엇이든지hashtag는 유사한 내용을 가진 소식을 한데 모으는 수단으로 사용할 수 없다.먼저, 다중 언어 사용자가 자발적이고 고도의 동태적인 방식으로 탭을 만들었기 때문에 같은 주제는 다른 탭과 연결될 수 있고, 반대로 같은 탭은 서로 다른 시간대에 서로 다른 주제를 인용할 수 있다.둘째, 상용어와 반대로 의미 디렉터리(예를 들어 위키백과나WordNet)가 없기 때문에 라벨의 변조가 복잡해진다.이 밖에 라벨은 보통 알파벳 줄임말, 연결어 등으로 구성되기 때문에 분석하기 어렵다.hashtag의 의미를 확정하는 흔히 볼 수 있는 방법은 그들의 상하문을 분석하는 것이다. 그러나 우리가 방금 지적한 바와 같이hashtag는 여러 가지와 변할 수 있는 의미를 가진다.본고에서 우리는 의미와 관련된hashtag이 유사하고 동기화된 사용 모델을 가진 사상을 바탕으로 시제 감지 분류 알고리즘을 제시했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>Hashtags sind kreative Labels, die in Mikroblogs verwendet werden, um das Thema einer Nachricht/Diskussion zu charakterisieren. Unabhängig von der Verwendung, für die sie ursprünglich vorgesehen waren, können Hashtags nicht als Mittel zum Clustern von Nachrichten mit ähnlichen Inhalten verwendet werden. Erstens, da Hashtags spontan und hochdynamisch von Benutzern in mehreren Sprachen erstellt werden, kann dasselbe Thema mit verschiedenen Hashtags verknüpft werden, und umgekehrt kann sich derselbe Hashtag auf verschiedene Themen in verschiedenen Zeiträumen beziehen. Zweitens wird die Hashtag-Begriffsklärung im Gegensatz zu herkömmlichen Wörtern dadurch erschwert, dass keine sinnvollen Kataloge (z.B. Wikipedia oder WordNet) verfügbar sind; Außerdem sind Hashtag-Labels schwer zu analysieren, da sie oft aus Akronymen, verketteten Wörtern usw. bestehen. Eine gängige Methode, um die Bedeutung von Hashtags zu bestimmen, war die Analyse ihres Kontextes, aber wie wir gerade bemerkt haben, können Hashtags mehrere und variable Bedeutungen haben. In diesem Artikel schlagen wir einen zeitlichen Sinn Clustering Algorithmus vor, der auf der Idee basiert, dass semantisch verwandte Hashtags ähnliche und synchrone Nutzungsmuster haben.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Hashtags adalah label kreatif yang digunakan dalam mikroblog untuk mengkaraterisasikan topik pesan/diskusi. Terlepas dari penggunaan yang mereka inginkan pada awalnya, hashtag tidak dapat digunakan sebagai cara untuk mengumpulkan pesan dengan isi yang sama. Pertama, karena hashtag diciptakan secara spontan dan sangat dinamik oleh pengguna dalam berbagai bahasa, topik yang sama dapat diassokasikan dengan hashtag yang berbeda, dan sebaliknya, hashtag yang sama dapat merujuk ke topik yang berbeda dalam periode waktu yang berbeda. Kedua, bertentangan dengan kata-kata umum, penyelesaian hashtag rumit dengan fakta bahwa katalog tidak masuk akal (misalnya Wikipedia atau WordNet) tersedia; dan, selain itu, label hashtag sulit untuk dianalisis, karena mereka sering terdiri dari akronim, kata-kata konkritasi, dan sebagainya. Cara umum untuk menentukan arti hashtag adalah untuk menganalisis konteks mereka, tapi, seperti yang baru kita tunjukkan, hashtag dapat memiliki arti berbilang dan variabel. In this article, we propose a temporal sense clustering algorithm based on the idea that semantically related hashtags have similar and synchronous usage patterns.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>برچسب‌ها برچسب‌های خلاقی در میکروبلوگ استفاده می‌شوند تا موضوع پیغام/بحث را تعریف کند. با توجه به استفاده از آن که در ابتدای مقرر شده‌اند، هشتگ‌ها به عنوان وسیله‌ای برای گروه پیام‌ها با محتوای مشابه استفاده نمی‌شوند. اول، به خاطر اینکه هشتگ‌ها در یک طریق استفاده کننده‌ها در زبان‌های متعدد و بسیار داینامیک ایجاد می‌شوند، همان موضوع می‌تواند با هشتگ‌های متفاوت ارتباط داشته باشد، و در عوض، همان هشتگ می‌تواند به موضوع متفاوت در مدت‌های زمان متفاوت دوم، بر خلاف کلمات مشترک، نامبوغ کردن hashtag با این حقیقت پیچیده شده است که هیچ کاتالوگ حسی (مثال ویکیپدییا یا WordNet) در دسترس نیست. و علاوه بر این، نقاشی‌های hashtag برای تحلیل سخت است، همانطور که اغلب از آکرونیم‌ها، کلمات متقابل و غیر از آن است. راهی مشترک برای تعیین معنی هشتگ‌ها این بود که محیط آنها را تحلیل کنیم، اما همانطور که ما تازه اشاره کرده ایم، هشتگ‌ها می‌توانند معنی چندین و متغیر داشته باشند. در این مقاله، ما پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که الگوریتم جمع کردن حس موقتی بر اساس ایده‌ای که هشتگ‌های مربوط به semantically ارتباط دارند الگوهای استفاده‌های مشابه و مشابه دارند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>etiketler mikro-bloglarda mesaj/diskusiýanyň meýdanyny karakter etmek üçin ullanýan döredijili etiketlerdir. Ilkinji meýilleşdirýän işlenmesi üçin ullanylşyna raýrsyz, etiketleri meýilleşdirýän mesajlary göçürmek üçin ullanylamaz. Ilkinji gezek, isleýänler üçin etiketler birnäçe dilde spontan we dynamik şeklinde döredildi, birnäçe etiketler bilen bir meýdança hashtag döredilebilir we görä görä, şol hashtag başga wagtlar içinde üýtgeşip biler. Ikinjisi, umumy sözleriň garşynda, hashtag boşluşyklamak (meselâ, Wikipedia ýa WordNet) hiç hili duýgun kataloglar bar däldir; çünki bu ýerde hiç hili hashtag boşluşyk ýok. Munuň üçin hashtag etiketleriň analyzasy kyn, akronymlaryň, konkretler sözleriň we şeýle däldir. Hashtarlaryň nähilini takyklamak üçin bir orta yöntemi olaryň kontekstlerini çözümlemek bolandy, ýöne biz diňe takyklaýan ýaly hashtatlaryň birnäçe we üýtgeşik wajyplary bar. Bu makaleda, semantik bilen baglanýan hashtatlar ýaly we sinhron ulanma nusgalarynyň bardygyny düşünmesine daýan bir wagt duýgulanmasy algoritmini teklip edip görýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Alama za viungo vinavyotumiwa kwenye blogu micro ili kuweka mada ya ujumbe/mjadala. Bila kujali matumizi hayo yaliyolengwa kwanza, alama ishara hizo haziwezi kutumika kama njia ya kuunganisha ujumbe wenye maudhui yanayofanana. Kwanza, kwa sababu alama hizo zinatengenezwa kwa njia ya kujitegemea na yenye nguvu sana na watumiaji katika lugha mbalimbali, mada hiyo inaweza kuhusiana na alama tofauti, na kwa mujibu wa twita, alama hiyo hiyo inaweza kumaanisha mada tofauti katika kipindi fulani. Pili, kinyume na maneno ya kawaida, ubaguzi wa alama ishara ni tatizo na ukweli kwamba hakuna maana (kwa mfano, Wikipedia au WordNet) unapatikana; na zaidi ya hayo, alama ishara za kiungo ni vigumu kupata uchambuzi, kwa sababu mara nyingi hujumuisha alama, maneno yanayotengenezwa, na kadhalika. Njia ya kawaida ya kutambua maana ya alama hizo ni kuchambua muktadha wao, lakini, kama tulivyoonyesha, alama habari zinaweza kuwa na maana mbadala na mabadiliko. In this article, we propose a temporal sense clustering algorithm based on the idea that semantically related hashtags have similar and synchronous usage patterns.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Hashtags is kreatiewe etikette gebruik in mikro-blogs om die onderwerp van 'n boodskap/diskusie te karakteriseer. Ongelyks van die gebruik waarmee hulle oorspronklik bedoel was, kan hashtags nie gebruik word as 'n bedoel om boodskappe te cluster met gelyke inhoud. Eerste, omdat hashtags geskep word in 'n spontanee en baie dinamiese manier deur gebruikers in veelvuldige tale, kan dieselfde onderwerp geassosieer word met verskillende hashtags, en omgeskakel, dieselfde hashtag kan verwys na verskillende onderwerpe in verskillende tydsperiode. Tweede, teen gemeenskaplike woorde, die hashtag-ontsammings is kompliseer deur die feit dat geen sin katalogs (bv. Wikipedia of WordNet) beskikbaar is nie; en en, daarna, hashtag etikette is moeilik om te analiseer, omdat hulle dikwels bestaan van akronime, samelekteerde woorde en so. 'n Gewone manier om die betekening van hashtags te bepaal is om hul konteks te analiseer, maar soos ons net aanwys het, hashtags kan veelvuldige en veranderlike betekenings hê. In hierdie artikel, voorstel ons 'n tydelike sin clustering algoritme gebaseer op die idee dat semantiese verwante hashtags gelykbaar en sinkrone gebruik patrone het.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>ሐሽታግሮች የመልዕክት/ውይይት ጉዳዩ እንዲያስተካክሉ በሚኮራ-ጦማር ውስጥ የሚጠቀሙት አዲስ ምልክቶች ናቸው፡፡ በመጀመሪያ የተሰበሰቡት ተጠቃሚ ቢሆንም፣ ሐሽታግሮች በመልእክት በተለያዩ ይታሰሩ ዘንድ አይችሉም፡፡ First, because hashtags are created in a spontaneous and highly dynamic way by users in multiple languages, the same topic can be associated with different hashtags, and conversely, the same hashtag may refer to different topics in different time periods.  ሁለተኛው በተቃዋሚ ቃላት ተቃዋሚ፣ የህትመት ማቀናቀል አካላት (ምሳሌ Wikipedia ወይም WordNet) እንዳይገኝ ነው፡፡ ደግሞም የሐሽታግል ምልክቶች መተረምሩ አስቸጋሪ ነው፤ ብዙ ጊዜም በተጨማሪው ቃላት፣ እንደዚህም ወዲህ ነው፡፡ የሐሽታክ አካባቢ ማድረግ ትክክለኛውን ለመፍጠር የሚቻል መንገድ ነው፤ ነገር ግን አሁን እንዳሳየነው በሐሽታክ ብዙ እና የተለየ ማህበረሰብ ይችላል፡፡ በዚህ ጽሑፍ ውስጥ፣ በsemantically የተገኘ ሐሽታግሮች የተመሳሳይ እና የሲንክሮን መጠቀሚያ መስመር እንዲኖሩ የአልgoritምን ማቀናቀል እናስባለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>İsmarış/müzakirə məsələsini tanımlamaq üçün mikro-bloglarda istifadə edilən yaratıcı etiketlər. Əvvəlcə məqsədilə istifadə edildiklərinə baxmayaraq, etiketlər bənzər məlumatı ilə mesajları qoparmaq üçün istifadə edilə bilməz. Əvvəlcə, çoxlu dillərdə istifadəçilər tarafından spontane və çox dinamik kimi hashtag yaradılır, bu məsəl farklı hashtag ilə bağlanılır və, tersi tərəfində, aynı hashtag müxtəlif vaxt müddətlərində fərqli məsələlərə danışır. İkincisi, ortaq sözlərin əleyhinə, hashtag disambiguasyonu heç bir hiss katalogu (məsələn, Wikipedia və WordNet) faydalanmadığı təqdirdə karmaşdırılmışdır; Buna görə də hashtag etiketləri analizi çətindir, çünki onlar çox acronymlardan, müxtəlif sözlərdən olub. Hashtaqların anlamını təyin etmək üçün ortaq yolu onların kontekstlərini analizə etmək idi, amma biz də belə göstərdik ki, hashtaqların çoxlu və dəyişiklik anlamı olar. Bu məlumatda, semantik olaraq əlaqəli hashtaqların bənzər və sinkron istifadə modellərinin olduğu fikirlərə dayanan temporal sense klastering algoritmi təklif edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>মাইক্রো-ব্লগে হ্যাশট্যাগ ব্যবহার করা হয়েছে একটি বার্তা/আলোচনার বিষয়টিকে চিহ্নিত করার জন্য। প্রাথমিকভাবে তাদের উদ্দেশ্যের ব্যবহারের ব্যাপারেই হ্যাশট্যাগ ব্যবহার করা যায় না কেন, একই ধরনের বিষয়বস্তু নিয়ে  প্রথমত, কারণ হ্যাশট্যাগ ব্যবহারকারীদের স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে এবং অত্যন্ত প্রান্তিক ভাষায় তৈরি করা হয়েছে, একই বিষয় বিভিন্ন হ্যাশট্যাগের সাথে যুক্ দ্বিতীয়, সাধারণ শব্দের বিরুদ্ধে হ্যাশট্যাগ বিভ্রান্ত করা বাস্তবতা জটিল যে কোন মানসিক ক্যাটালগ (যেমন উইকিপিডিয়া বা ওয়ার্ডন এবং এছাড়াও হ্যাশট্যাগের লেবেল বিশ্লেষণ কঠিন, যেহেতু তারা প্রায়শই এক্রোনিম, একত্রিত শব্দের মধ্যে রয়েছে। হ্যাশট্যাগের মানে নির্ধারণের একটি সাধারণ উপায় হচ্ছে তাদের প্রেক্ষাপট বিশ্লেষণ করার জন্য, কিন্তু আমরা শুধু উল্লেখ করেছি যে হ্যাশট্য এই প্রবন্ধটিতে আমরা একটি মাধ্যমের মানসিক মূল্য প্রস্তাব করছি যে সেম্পেন্টিক্যালের সাথে সম্পর্কিত হ্যাশট্যাগগুলো একই রকম এবং সিক্রো</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Հեշտագները ստեղծագործական պիտակներ են, որոնք օգտագործվում են միկրոբլոգերում հաղորդագրության և քննարկության թեման բնորոշման համար: Չնայած այն օգտագործմանը, որի համար դրանք նախկինում նախատեսված էին, հաշտակները չեն կարող օգտագործվել որպես միջոց նման պարունակությամբ հաղորդագրություններ խմբագրելու համար: Առաջինը, քանի որ հաշատագները ստեղծվում են ինքնաբուխ և շատ դինամիկ կերպով բազմալեզվով օգտագործողների կողմից, նույն թեման կարող է կապված լինել տարբեր հաշատագների հետ, և հակառակը, նույն հաշատագն կարող է վերաբերվել տարբեր թեմաներին տարբեր ժամանակահատվածներում Երկրորդ, հակառակ ընդհանուր բառերին, հաշվի առնելը բարդ է այն պատճառով, որ ոչ մի իմաստային կատալոգ (օրինակ Վիքիփեդիա կամ WordNet) հասանելի չէ: Ավելին, հաշթագ պիտակները դժվար է վերլուծել, քանի որ դրանք հաճախ կազմված են ակրոնիմներից, կոնկրետացված բառերից և այլն: Հաշտագների իմաստը հասարակ ձևն էր վերլուծել նրանց կոնտեքստը, բայց ինչպես արդեն նշեցինք, հաշտագները կարող են ունենալ բազմաթիվ և փոփոխական իմաստ: Այս հոդվածի մեջ մենք առաջարկում ենք ժամանակական զգացում խմբավորելու ալգորիթմ, հիմնված այն գաղափարի վրա, որ սեմանտիկապես կապված հաշաթեգները ունեն նման և սինկրոն օգտագործման կաղապարներ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_cs>Hashtagy jsou kreativní etikety používané v mikroblogech k charakterizaci tématu zprávy/diskuse. Bez ohledu na použití, pro které byly původně určeny, nelze hashtagy použít jako prostředek k clusteru zpráv s podobným obsahem. Za prvé, protože hashtagy jsou vytvářeny spontánním a vysoce dynamickým způsobem uživateli ve více jazycích, stejné téma může být spojeno s různými hashtagy a naopak stejný hashtag může odkazovat na různá témata v různých časových obdobích. Za druhé, na rozdíl od běžných slov, rozšíření hashtagů je komplikováno skutečností, že nejsou k dispozici žádné smyslové katalogy (např. Wikipedie nebo WordNet); a navíc, hashtagové štítky jsou obtížně analyzovatelné, protože se často skládají z zkratek, řetězců slov a tak dále. Běžným způsobem určení významu hashtagů bylo analyzovat jejich kontext, ale jak jsme právě zdůraznili, hashtagy mohou mít více a variabilních významů. V tomto článku navrhujeme algoritmus shlukování časového smyslu založený na myšlence, že sémanticky související hashtagy mají podobné a synchronní vzorce použití.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>Els hashtags són etiquetes creatives utilitzades en micro blogs per caracteritzar el tema d'un missatge/discussió. Malgrat l'ús per a què es destinaven originalment, els hashtags no es poden utilitzar com a mitjà per agrupar missatges amb continguts similars. En primer lloc, perquè els usuaris en múltiples llengües creen hashtags espontàniament i molt dinàmicament, el mateix tema es pot associar amb diferents hashtags, i en canvi, el mateix hashtag pot referir-se a diferents temes en diferents períodes de temps. Segon, al contrari de les paraules comunes, la desambiguació de l'hashtag és complicada pel fet que no hi ha cap sentit a dispondre de catòlegs (per exemple Wikipedia o WordNet); i, a més, les etiquetes de hashtag són difícils d'analitzar, com sovint consisteixen en acronimes, paraules concatenades, etc. Una manera comú de determinar el significat dels hashtags ha estat analitzar el seu context, però, com acabem de dir, els hashtags poden tenir significats múltiples i variables. In this article, we propose a temporal sense clustering algorithm based on the idea that semantically related hashtags have similar and synchronous usage patterns.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>Etikete su kreativne etikete koje se koriste u mikro-blogu kako bi karakterizirale temu poruke/diskusije. Bez obzira na korištenje za koju su originalno nameravani, hashtage se ne mogu koristiti kao sredstvo za skupljanje poruka sa sličnim sadržajem. Prvo, zato što su hashtagi stvoreni spontanom i visoko dinamičnim načinom korisnici na višem jezicima, isti tema se može povezati sa različitim hashtagama, a u suprotnom, isti hashtag može odnijeti na različite teme u različitim vremenskim periodima. Drugo, suprotno zajedničkim riječima, disambiguacija hashtaga je komplikovana činjenicom da nema kataloga osjećaja (npr. Wikipedia ili WordNet) na raspolaganju; Osim toga, etikete hashtaga su teško analizirati, jer često se sastoje od akronima, potvrđenih riječi i tako dalje. Zajednički način da utvrdimo smisao hashtaga je analizirati njihov kontekst, ali, kako smo upravo pokazali, hashtage mogu imati višestruke i varijantne značenje. U ovom članku predlažemo privremeni algoritam skupljanja osjećaja na temelju ideje da semantički povezani hashtagi imaju slične i sinhronizne obrasce korištenja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Hashtagid on loomingulised sildid, mida kasutatakse mikroblogides sõnumi/arutelu teema iseloomustamiseks. Sõltumata sellest, milliseks kasutuseks need algselt ette nähtud olid, ei saa hashtage kasutada vahendina sarnase sisuga sõnumite klastritamiseks. Esiteks, kuna hashtagid on loodud spontaanselt ja väga dünaamiliselt mitmes keeles kasutajate poolt, võib sama teema seostada erinevate hashtagidega ja vastupidi, sama hashtag võib viidata erinevatele teemadele erinevatel ajavahemikel. Teiseks, vastupidiselt tavalistele sõnadele, on hashtagi eristamine keeruline asjaolu, et mõttekataloogid (nt Wikipedia või WordNet) ei ole kättesaadavad; Lisaks on hashtagi silte raske analüüsida, sest need koosnevad sageli akronüümidest, seotud sõnadest jne. Üks levinud viis hashtagide tähenduse kindlaksmääramiseks on olnud nende konteksti analüüsimine, kuid nagu me just märkisime, võivad hashtagid olla mitu ja muutuvat tähendust. Selles artiklis pakume välja ajalise tähenduse klastritamise algoritmi, mis põhineb ideel, et semantiliselt seotud hashtagidel on sarnased ja sünkroonsed kasutusmustrid.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Hashtagit ovat luovia tunnisteita, joita käytetään mikroblogeissa kuvaamaan viestin/keskustelun aihetta. Riippumatta siitä, mihin käyttötarkoitukseen ne alun perin oli tarkoitettu, hashtageja ei voida käyttää keinona ryhmitellä viestejä, joissa on samankaltaista sisältöä. Ensinnäkin, koska käyttäjät luovat hashtagit spontaanilla ja erittäin dynaamisella tavalla useilla kielillä, sama aihe voidaan yhdistää erilaisiin hashtageihin ja päinvastoin sama hashtag voi viitata eri aiheisiin eri aikoina. Toiseksi, toisin kuin tavalliset sanat, hashtagin erottelua vaikeuttaa se, että mitään järkeviä luetteloita (esim. Wikipedia tai WordNet) ei ole saatavilla; Lisäksi hashtag-tunnisteita on vaikea analysoida, koska ne koostuvat usein lyhenteistä, yhdistetyistä sanoista jne. Yhteinen tapa määrittää hashtagien merkitys on ollut analysoida niiden kontekstia, mutta kuten olemme juuri huomauttaneet, hashtageilla voi olla useita ja vaihtelevia merkityksiä. Tässä artikkelissa ehdotamme aikaaistiklusterointialgoritmia, joka perustuu ajatukseen, että semanttisesti liittyvillä hashtageilla on samanlaiset ja synkroniset käyttötavat.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sq>Hashtags janë etiketa krijuese të përdorura në mikrobloge për të karakterizuar temën e një mesazhi/diskutimi. Pavarësisht nga përdorimi për të cilin ishin të synuar fillimisht, hashtags nuk mund të përdoren si një mjet për të grupuar mesazhe me përmbajtje të ngjashme. Së pari, sepse hashtags krijohen në një mënyrë spontane dhe shumë dinamike nga përdoruesit në gjuhë të shumta, e njëjta temë mund të lidhet me hashtags të ndryshëm, dhe në të kundërtën, e njëjta hashtag mund të referohet në temë të ndryshme në periudha kohore të ndryshme. Së dyti, në kundërshtim me fjalët e zakonshme, çambiguacioni i hashtagut është i komplikuar nga fakti se nuk ka katalogë kuptimi (për shembull Wikipedia apo WordNet) në dispozicion; dhe, gjithashtu, etiketat hashtag janë të vështira për të analizuar, pasi ato shpesh përbëhen nga akronime, fjalë të shkurtra, etj. Një mënyrë e përbashkët për të përcaktuar kuptimin e hashtagëve ka qenë të analizojmë kontekstin e tyre, por, siç sapo kemi vënë në dukje, hashtagët mund të kenë kuptime të shumta dhe të ndryshme. Në këtë artikull, propozojmë një sens të përkohshëm të grupimit të algoritmit bazuar në idenë se hashtaget semantike kanë modele të ngjashme dhe të përdorimit sinkronik.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_sk>Hashtage so ustvarjalne oznake, ki se uporabljajo v mikroblogih za označevanje teme sporočila/razprave. Ne glede na uporabo, za katero so bile prvotno namenjene, hashtage ni mogoče uporabiti kot sredstvo za grozdje sporočil s podobno vsebino. Prvič, ker so hashtage ustvarjene spontano in zelo dinamično s strani uporabnikov v več jezikih, se lahko isto temo poveže z različnimi hashtagi, nasprotno pa se lahko ista hashtaga nanaša na različne teme v različnih časovnih obdobjih. Drugič, v nasprotju z običajnimi besedami je razločitev hashtag zapletena zaradi dejstva, da ni na voljo nobenih smiselnih katalogov (npr. Wikipedija ali WordNet); Poleg tega je oznake hashtag težko analizirati, saj pogosto sestavljajo kratice, povezane besede in tako naprej. Pogost način določanja pomena hashtagov je analiza njihovega konteksta, vendar imajo lahko hashtage, kot smo pravkar poudarili, več in spremenljivih pomenov. V tem članku predlagamo časovni algoritem grozdenja, ki temelji na ideji, da imajo semantično povezane hashtage podobne in sinhrone vzorce uporabe.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Hashtags are wasu labels mai halin da ake amfani da cikin micro-logogi dõmin su ƙayyade madaidaitan wani message/jayayya. Bai kula da amfani da wanda aka ƙayyade su a farko, ba za'a yi amfani da hashtags ba kamar wani hanyor ya ƙara message da tsarin mai kama da shi. Kayya, kwance, an halitta hashtags cikin shirin mai farat da mai sauran da masu amfani da shi cikin wasu harshe masu yawa, kan kuma an haɗa wannan madaidaici da hashtagn dabam-daba, kuma, a sami, hashtagn haske guda, yana iya ƙayyade hashtagn, yana iya ƙayyade wasu madaidaita cikin mudan dabam-dabam. Dukkan, a motsa da kalmõmi masu haɗuwa, yana da rabo alama na hashtagn ayuka, kuma yana mai ƙunci da gaskiyar kalkata (misali, Wikimedia ko KaldNet) ba'a iya sãmun; kuma da haka, alama hashtagun sun yi ƙunci a kan analyza, kamar da ko da yake cikin akronymi, da kalmõmi da aka samu'a, da kuma a gaba. Kuma hanyar ɗabi'a da za'a ƙayyade fassaran hashtagun shine an analyza mazaɓansu, kuma amma kamar da muka nuna, alama-hashtags yana iya da manyan mutane da waɗancan. Daga wannan makala, Munã goyyar da wani mantin da za'a sami algoritm a cikin lokaci, ana bincike da idãnun da hashtagn masu husũma da semantiki sun sami da misãlai ga amfani da shi mai daidai.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>#a11y &lt;joanie&gt; hello!&lt;joanie&gt; hello! Inga Jejaring Awal dhéwé, soalé tanggal nggawe ning saben rawe lan akeh dumadhi iki, nik akeh dumadhi kanggo langa sing luwih basa, sing titik dhéwé nggawe hash-hash gak, lan uga sing nggawe, hash-hash sing berale iso nggawe Tema sing gak dhéwé ning imperator sing gak nggawe Siji-siji, manggadahi gambaran, nglanggar-nambah etiket sing komplikasi karo ngono pakan karo ndelok sanes (adil.nj, Wipedipedya karo Word net) sing bisa nariyan; yo sampeyan Nambah, etiket hashash kuwi susah kanggo ditambah, dadi ngomong sak sembarang akuronim, kelangan, lan uga. section Nang artiklu iki, kita supoyo sistem kelas 'clustering Algorithm' sing basa dadi iki dadi, akeh sematik alam sing basalan tambah akèh karo akeh operasi sistem Anyar.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>הסטגים הם תוויות יצירתיות שמשתמשות במיקרו-בלוגים כדי לתייצב את נושא ההודעה/דיון. ללא קשר לשימוש שהם היו מתכוונים למקור, האשטגים לא יכולים להשתמש כאמצע לאסוף הודעות עם תוכן דומה. ראשית, מכיוון שהאשטגים יוצרים באופן ספונטני ודינמיקלי ביותר על ידי משתמשים בשפות רבות, אותו נושא יכול להיות קשור להאשטגים שונים, ובהשפך, אותו האאשטג יכול להתייחס לנושאים שונים בתקופות זמן שונות. שנית, בניגוד למילים משותפות, ניתוח ההשט מסובך על ידי העובדה שאין קטלוגים הגיוניים (למשל ויקיפדיה או WordNet) זמינים; וחוץ מזה, קשה לנתח את תוויות האשטג, כיוון שהן לעתים קרובות מורכבות מאקרונימים, מילים משותפות וכן הלאה. דרך משותפת לקבוע את המשמעות של האשטגים הייתה לנתח את הקשר שלהם, אבל, כפי שהצבענו הרגע, האשטגים יכולים להיות משמעות רבות ושתנות. במאמר הזה, אנו מציעים תחושה זמנית לאלגוריתם מבוסס על הרעיון שיש להאשטגים קשורים סמנטית דפוסים משימוש דומים וסינכרונים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག་བྱང་འདི་དག་གི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་དང་གླེང་སྒྲོམ་གྱི་གནད་དོན་ཡིན་ཆ་ནང་སྤྱོད་པའི་གསར་བསྐྲུན་པའི་ཤོག་བྱང་། ཡིན་ཡང་མིན་ན་འདི་དག་གི་སྔོན་ལ་དམིགས་ཡུལ དང་པོ་དེ་རྒྱུ་མཚན་ནི། ཤོག་བྱང་ཐོག་ནི་སྐད་རིགས་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་རྣམ་པ་ལ་རང་བཞིན་དང་མཐུན་གྱིས་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ནང་བྱུང་ཡོད་པ Second, contrary to common words, hashtag disambiguation is complicated by the fact that no sense catalogs (e.g., Wikipedia or WordNet) are available; see http://www.google.com/search?ie=UTF-8oe=UTF-8 Furthermore, hashtag labels are difficult to analyze, as they often consist of acronyms, concatenated words, and so forth. A common way to determine the meaning of hashtags has been to analyze their context, but as we have just pointed out, hashtags can have multiple and variable meanings. འོག</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    </volume>
  <volume id="2">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Computational Linguistics, Volume 43, Issue 2 - June 2017</booktitle>
      <publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
      <address>Cambridge, MA</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <bibkey>cl-2017-linguistics-43</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>A Comprehensive Analysis of Bilingual Lexicon Induction</title>
      <author><first>Ann</first><last>Irvine</last></author>
      <author><first>Chris</first><last>Callison-Burch</last></author>
      <abstract>Bilingual lexicon induction is the task of inducing word translations from monolingual corpora in two languages. In this article we present the most comprehensive analysis of bilingual lexicon induction to date. We present experiments on a wide range of languages and data sizes. We examine translation into English from 25 foreign languages : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albanian_language">Albanian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Azerbaijani_language">Azeri</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bengali_language">Bengali</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bosnian_language">Bosnian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulgarian_language">Bulgarian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cebuano_language">Cebuano</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gujarati_language">Gujarati</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hungarian_language">Hungarian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesian_language">Indonesian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latvian_language">Latvian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nepali_language">Nepali</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romanian_language">Romanian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serbian_language">Serbian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slovak_language">Slovak</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Somali_language">Somali</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_language">Spanish</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swedish_language">Swedish</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_language">Turkish</a>, Ukrainian, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uzbek_language">Uzbek</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vietnamese_language">Vietnamese</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welsh_language">Welsh</a>. We analyze the behavior of bilingual lexicon induction on low-frequency words, rather than testing solely on high-frequency words, as previous research has done. Low-frequency words are more relevant to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_machine_translation">statistical machine translation</a>, where systems typically lack translations of rare words that fall outside of their training data. We systematically explore a wide range of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a> and phenomena that affect the quality of the translations discovered by bilingual lexicon induction. We provide illustrative examples of the highest ranking translations for orthogonal signals of translation equivalence like contextual similarity and temporal similarity. We analyze the effects of frequency and burstiness, and the sizes of the seed bilingual dictionaries and the monolingual training corpora. Additionally, we introduce a novel discriminative approach to bilingual lexicon induction. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discriminative_model">discriminative model</a> is capable of combining a wide variety of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> that individually provide only weak indications of translation equivalence.</abstract>
      <pages>273–310</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00284</doi>
      <url hash="ac50ccab">J17-2001</url>
      <bibkey>irvine-callison-burch-2017-comprehensive</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Greedy Transition-Based Dependency Parsing with Stack LSTMs<fixed-case>LSTM</fixed-case>s</title>
      <author><first>Miguel</first><last>Ballesteros</last></author>
      <author><first>Chris</first><last>Dyer</last></author>
      <author><first>Yoav</first><last>Goldberg</last></author>
      <author><first>Noah A.</first><last>Smith</last></author>
      <abstract>We introduce a greedy transition-based parser that learns to represent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_(computer_science)">parser states</a> using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recurrent_neural_network">recurrent neural networks</a>. Our primary innovation that enables us to do this efficiently is a new control structure for sequential neural networksthe stack long short-term memory unit (LSTM). Like the conventional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stack_(abstract_data_type)">stack data structures</a> used in transition-based parsers, elements can be pushed to or popped from the top of the stack in constant time, but, in addition, an LSTM maintains a continuous space embedding of the stack contents. Our model captures three facets of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a>’s state : (i) unbounded look-ahead into the buffer of incoming words, (ii) the complete history of transition actions taken by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a>, and (iii) the complete contents of the stack of partially built tree fragments, including their internal structures. In addition, we compare two different word representations : (i) standard word vectors based on look-up tables and (ii) character-based models of words. Although standard word embedding models work well in all languages, the character-based models improve the handling of out-of-vocabulary words, particularly in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphology_(linguistics)">morphologically rich languages</a>. Finally, we discuss the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oracle_machine">dynamic oracles</a> in training the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a>. During <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training</a>, dynamic oracles alternate between sampling parser states from the training data and from the model as it is being learned, making the model more robust to the kinds of errors that will be made at test time. Training our model with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oracle_machine">dynamic oracles</a> yields a linear-time greedy parser with very competitive performance.</abstract>
      <pages>311–347</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00285</doi>
      <url hash="857e3f6c">J17-2002</url>
      <bibkey>ballesteros-etal-2017-greedy</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Statistical Models for Unsupervised, Semi-Supervised Supervised Transliteration Mining</title>
      <author><first>Hassan</first><last>Sajjad</last></author>
      <author><first>Helmut</first><last>Schmid</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexander</first><last>Fraser</last></author>
      <author><first>Hinrich</first><last>Schütze</last></author>
      <abstract>We present a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_model">generative model</a> that efficiently mines <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transliteration">transliteration pairs</a> in a consistent fashion in three different settings : unsupervised, semi-supervised, and supervised transliteration mining. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> interpolates two sub-models, one for the generation of transliteration pairs and one for the generation of non-transliteration pairs (i.e., noise). The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> is trained on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noisy_data">noisy unlabeled data</a> using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EM_algorithm">EM algorithm</a>. During training the transliteration sub-model learns to generate transliteration pairs and the fixed non-transliteration model generates the noise pairs. After training, the unlabeled data is disambiguated based on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posterior_probability">posterior probabilities</a> of the two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">sub-models</a>. We evaluate our transliteration mining system on data from a transliteration mining shared task and on parallel corpora. For three out of four language pairs, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> outperforms all semi-supervised and supervised systems that participated in the NEWS 2010 shared task. On word pairs extracted from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_text">parallel corpora</a> with fewer than 2 % <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transliteration">transliteration pairs</a>, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> achieves up to 86.7 % F-measure with 77.9 % <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">precision</a> and 97.8 % <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a>.</abstract>
      <pages>349–375</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00286</doi>
      <url hash="0102b781">J17-2003</url>
      <bibkey>sajjad-etal-2017-statistical</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Identifying and Avoiding Confusion in Dialogue with People with Alzheimer’s Disease<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>lzheimer’s Disease</title>
      <author><first>Hamidreza</first><last>Chinaei</last></author>
      <author><first>Leila Chan</first><last>Currie</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrew</first><last>Danks</last></author>
      <author><first>Hubert</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Tejas</first><last>Mehta</last></author>
      <author><first>Frank</first><last>Rudzicz</last></author>
      <abstract>Alzheimer’s disease (AD) is an increasingly prevalent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_disorder">cognitive disorder</a> in which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memory">memory</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">language</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executive_functions">executive function</a> deteriorate, usually in that order. There is a growing need to support individuals with AD and other forms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dementia">dementia</a> in their daily lives, and our goal is to do so through speech-based interaction. Given that 33 % of conversations with people with middle-stage AD involve a breakdown in communication, it is vital that automated dialogue systems be able to identify those breakdowns and, if possible, avoid them. In this article, we discuss several linguistic features that are verbal indicators of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confusion">confusion</a> in AD (including vocabulary richness, parse tree structures, and acoustic cues) and apply several <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning algorithms</a> to identify dialogue-relevant confusion from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech">speech</a> with up to 82 % accuracy. We also learn dialogue strategies to avoid <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confusion">confusion</a> in the first place, which is accomplished using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Partially_observable_Markov_decision_process">partially observable Markov decision process</a> and which obtains accuracies (up to 96.1 %) that are significantly higher than several baselines. This work represents a major step towards automated dialogue systems for individuals with dementia.</abstract>
      <pages>377–406</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00290</doi>
      <url hash="991b7296">J17-2004</url>
      <bibkey>chinaei-etal-2017-identifying</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Framing QA as Building and Ranking Intersentence Answer Justifications<fixed-case>QA</fixed-case> as Building and Ranking Intersentence Answer Justifications</title>
      <author><first>Peter</first><last>Jansen</last></author>
      <author><first>Rebecca</first><last>Sharp</last></author>
      <author><first>Mihai</first><last>Surdeanu</last></author>
      <author><first>Peter</first><last>Clark</last></author>
      <abstract>We propose a question answering (QA) approach for standardized science exams that both identifies correct answers and produces compelling human-readable justifications for why those answers are correct. Our method first identifies the actual information needed in a question using psycholinguistic concreteness norms, then uses this information need to construct answer justifications by aggregating multiple sentences from different knowledge bases using syntactic and lexical information. We then jointly rank answers and their justifications using a reranking perceptron that treats <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory_of_justification">justification quality</a> as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latent_variable">latent variable</a>. We evaluate our method on 1,000 multiple-choice questions from elementary school science exams, and empirically demonstrate that it performs better than several strong baselines, including neural network approaches. Our best configuration answers 44 % of the questions correctly, where the top justifications for 57 % of these correct answers contain a compelling human-readable justification that explains the inference required to arrive at the correct answer. We include a detailed characterization of the justification quality for both our method and a strong <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline</a>, and show that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_aggregation">information aggregation</a> is key to addressing the information need in complex questions.</abstract>
      <pages>407–449</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00287</doi>
      <url hash="52beb243">J17-2005</url>
      <bibkey>jansen-etal-2017-framing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Squib : Effects of Cognitive Effort on the Resolution of Overspecified Descriptions<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>quib: Effects of Cognitive Effort on the Resolution of Overspecified Descriptions</title>
      <author><first>Ivandré</first><last>Paraboni</last></author>
      <author><first>Alex Gwo Jen</first><last>Lan</last></author>
      <author><first>Matheus Mendes</first><last>de Sant’Ana</last></author>
      <author><first>Flávio Luiz</first><last>Coutinho</last></author>
      <abstract>Studies in referring expression generation (REG) have shown different effects of referential overspecification on the resolution of certain descriptions. To further investigate effects of this kind, this article reports two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eye-tracking">eye-tracking</a> experiments that measure the time required to recognize target objects based on different kinds of information. Results suggest that referential overspecification may be either helpful or detrimental to identification depending on the kind of information that is actually overspecified, an insight that may be useful for the design of more informed hearer-oriented REG algorithms.</abstract>
      <pages>451–459</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00288</doi>
      <url hash="59ddaba8">J17-2006</url>
      <bibkey>paraboni-etal-2017-squib</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
  <volume id="3">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Computational Linguistics, Volume 43, Issue 3 - September 2017</booktitle>
      <publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
      <address>Cambridge, MA</address>
      <month>September</month>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <bibkey>cl-2017-linguistics-43-issue</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Hybrid Grammars for Parsing of Discontinuous Phrase Structures and Non-Projective Dependency Structures</title>
      <author><first>Kilian</first><last>Gebhardt</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark-Jan</first><last>Nederhof</last></author>
      <author><first>Heiko</first><last>Vogler</last></author>
      <abstract>We explore the concept of hybrid grammars, which formalize and generalize a range of existing frameworks for dealing with discontinuous syntactic structures. Covered are both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discontinuity_(linguistics)">discontinuous phrase structures</a> and non-projective dependency structures. Technically, hybrid grammars are related to synchronous grammars, where one grammar component generates linear structures and another generates hierarchical structures. By coupling <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_item">lexical elements</a> of both components together, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discontinuity_(linguistics)">discontinuous structures</a> result. Several types of hybrid grammars are characterized. We also discuss <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammar_induction">grammar induction</a> from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebanks</a>. The main advantage over existing frameworks is the ability of hybrid grammars to separate discontinuity of the desired structures from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">time complexity</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parsing</a>. This permits exploration of a large variety of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parsing algorithms</a> for discontinuous structures, with different properties. This is confirmed by the reported experimental results, which show a wide variety of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">running time</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a>, and frequency of parse failures.</abstract>
      <pages>465–520</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00291</doi>
      <url hash="b0a3e8db">J17-3001</url>
      <bibkey>gebhardt-etal-2017-hybrid</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/penn-treebank">Penn Treebank</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Translation Divergences in ChineseEnglish Machine Translation : An Empirical Investigation<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese–<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish Machine Translation: An Empirical Investigation</title>
      <author><first>Dun</first><last>Deng</last></author>
      <author><first>Nianwen</first><last>Xue</last></author>
      <abstract>In this article, we conduct an empirical investigation of translation divergences between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> relying on a parallel treebank. To do this, we first devise a hierarchical alignment scheme where Chinese and English parse trees are aligned in a way that eliminates conflicts and redundancies between word alignments and syntactic parses to prevent the generation of spurious translation divergences. Using this Hierarchically Aligned ChineseEnglish Parallel Treebank (HACEPT), we are able to semi-automatically identify and categorize the translation divergences between the two languages and quantify each type of translation divergence. Our results show that the translation divergences are much broader than described in previous studies that are largely based on anecdotal evidence and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistics">linguistic knowledge</a>. The distribution of the translation divergences also shows that some high-profile translation divergences that motivate previous research are actually very rare in our data, whereas other translation divergences that have previously received little attention actually exist in large quantities. We also show that HACEPT allows the extraction of syntax-based translation rules, most of which are expressive enough to capture the translation divergences, and point out that the syntactic annotation in existing treebanks is not optimal for extracting such translation rules. We also discuss the implications of our study for attempts to bridge translation divergences by devising shared semantic representations across languages. Our quantitative results lend further support to the observation that although it is possible to bridge some translation divergences with semantic representations, other translation divergences are open-ended, thus building a semantic representation that captures all possible translation divergences may be impractical.</abstract>
      <pages>521–565</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00292</doi>
      <url hash="405354c6">J17-3002</url>
      <bibkey>deng-xue-2017-translation</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/amr-bank">AMR Bank</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/penn-treebank">Penn Treebank</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>A Kernel Independence Test for Geographical Language Variation</title>
      <author><first>Dong</first><last>Nguyen</last></author>
      <author><first>Jacob</first><last>Eisenstein</last></author>
      <abstract>Quantifying the degree of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spatial_dependence">spatial dependence</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependent_and_independent_variables">linguistic variables</a> is a key task for analyzing dialectal variation. However, existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methods_of_detecting_exoplanets">approaches</a> have important drawbacks. First, they are based on parametric models of dependence, which limits their power in cases where the underlying parametric assumptions are violated. Second, they are not applicable to all types of linguistic data : Some approaches apply only to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frequency">frequencies</a>, others to boolean indicators of whether a linguistic variable is present. We present a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> for measuring geographical language variation, which solves both of these problems. Our approach builds on Reproducing Kernel Hilbert Space (RKHS) representations for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonparametric_statistics">nonparametric statistics</a>, and takes the form of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_statistic">test statistic</a> that is computed from pairs of individual geotagged observations without aggregation into predefined geographical bins. We compare this test with prior work using synthetic data as well as a diverse set of real data sets : a corpus of Dutch tweets, a Dutch syntactic atlas, and a data set of letters to the editor in North American newspapers. Our proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_hypothesis_testing">test</a> is shown to support robust inferences across a broad range of scenarios and types of data.</abstract>
      <pages>567–592</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00293</doi>
      <url hash="a5da865a">J17-3003</url>
      <bibkey>nguyen-eisenstein-2017-kernel</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/dongpng/geo-independence-testing" additional="false">dongpng/geo-independence-testing</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>AutoExtend : Combining Word Embeddings with Semantic Resources<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>uto<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>xtend: Combining Word Embeddings with Semantic Resources</title>
      <author><first>Sascha</first><last>Rothe</last></author>
      <author><first>Hinrich</first><last>Schütze</last></author>
      <abstract>We present AutoExtend, a system that combines word embeddings with semantic resources by learning embeddings for non-word objects like synsets and entities and learning word embeddings that incorporate the semantic information from the resource. The method is based on encoding and decoding the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embeddings</a> and is flexible in that it can take any <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embeddings</a> as input and does not need an additional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training corpus</a>. The obtained <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embedding">embeddings</a> live in the same <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_space">vector space</a> as the input word embeddings. A sparse tensor formalization guarantees efficiency and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallelizability">parallelizability</a>. We use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordNet">WordNet</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GermaNet">GermaNet</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freebase">Freebase</a> as semantic resources. AutoExtend achieves state-of-the-art performance on Word-in-Context Similarity and Word Sense Disambiguation tasks.</abstract>
      <pages>593–617</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00294</doi>
      <url hash="bb9fa638">J17-3004</url>
      <bibkey>rothe-schutze-2017-autoextend</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Parsing Argumentation Structures in Persuasive Essays</title>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Stab</last></author>
      <author><first>Iryna</first><last>Gurevych</last></author>
      <abstract>In this article, we present a novel approach for parsing argumentation structures. We identify argument components using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequence_labeling">sequence labeling</a> at the token level and apply a new joint model for detecting argumentation structures. The proposed model globally optimizes argument component types and argumentative relations using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integer_linear_programming">Integer Linear Programming</a>. We show that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> significantly outperforms challenging heuristic baselines on two different types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse">discourse</a>. Moreover, we introduce a novel corpus of persuasive essays annotated with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argumentation_theory">argumentation structures</a>. We show that our annotation scheme and annotation guidelines successfully guide human annotators to substantial agreement.</abstract>
      <pages>619–659</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00295</doi>
      <url hash="2006196c">J17-3005</url>
      <bibkey>stab-gurevych-2017-parsing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>The Agreement Measure cat a Complement to   Focused on Categorization of a Continuum</title>
      <author><first>Yann</first><last>Mathet</last></author>
      <abstract>Agreement on unitizing, where several annotators freely put units of various sizes and categories on a continuum, is difficult to assess because of the simultaneaous discrepancies in positioning and categorizing. The recent agreement measure   offers an overall solution that simultaneously takes into account positions and categories. In this article, I propose the additional coefficient cat, which complements   by assessing the agreement on categorization of a continuum, putting aside positional discrepancies. When applied to pure categorization (with predefined units), <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cat">cat</a> behaves the same way as the famous dedicated Krippendorff’s, even with missing values, which proves its consistency. A variation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cat">cat</a> is also proposed that provides an in-depth assessment of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Categorization">categorizing</a> for each individual category. The entire family of   coefficients is implemented in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_software">free software</a>.</abstract>
      <pages>661–681</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00296</doi>
      <url hash="f7241c3a">J17-3006</url>
      <bibkey>mathet-2017-agreement</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
  <volume id="4">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Computational Linguistics, Volume 43, Issue 4 - <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ecember 2017</booktitle>
      <publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
      <address>Cambridge, MA</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2017</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <bibkey>cl-2017-linguistics-43-issue-4</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Discourse Structure in Machine Translation Evaluation</title>
      <author><first>Shafiq</first><last>Joty</last></author>
      <author><first>Francisco</first><last>Guzmán</last></author>
      <author><first>Lluís</first><last>Màrquez</last></author>
      <author><first>Preslav</first><last>Nakov</last></author>
      <abstract>In this article, we explore the potential of using sentence-level discourse structure for machine translation evaluation. We first design discourse-aware similarity measures, which use all-subtree kernels to compare discourse parse trees in accordance with the Rhetorical Structure Theory (RST). Then, we show that a simple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_combination">linear combination</a> with these measures can help improve various existing machine translation evaluation metrics regarding correlation with human judgments both at the segment level and at the system level. This suggests that discourse information is complementary to the information used by many of the existing evaluation metrics, and thus it could be taken into account when developing richer evaluation metrics, such as the WMT-14 winning combined metric DiscoTKparty. We also provide a detailed analysis of the relevance of various discourse elements and relations from the RST parse trees for machine translation evaluation. In particular, we show that (i) all aspects of the RST tree are relevant, (ii) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuclearity">nuclearity</a> is more useful than relation type, and (iii) the similarity of the translation RST tree to the reference RST tree is positively correlated with translation quality.</abstract>
      <pages>683–722</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00298</doi>
      <url hash="18904d86">J17-4001</url>
      <bibkey>joty-etal-2017-discourse</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wmt-2014">WMT 2014</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Adapting to Learner Errors with Minimal Supervision</title>
      <author><first>Alla</first><last>Rozovskaya</last></author>
      <author><first>Dan</first><last>Roth</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Sammons</last></author>
      <abstract>This article considers the problem of correcting errors made by English as a Second Language writers from a machine learning perspective, and addresses an important issue of developing an appropriate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training paradigm</a> for the task, one that accounts for error patterns of non-native writers using minimal supervision. Existing training approaches present a trade-off between large amounts of cheap data offered by the native-trained models and additional knowledge of learner error patterns provided by the more expensive method of training on annotated learner data. We propose a novel training approach that draws on the strengths offered by the two standard training paradigmsof training either on native or on annotated learner dataand that outperforms both of these standard methods. Using the key observation that parameters relating to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Errors_and_residuals">error regularities</a> exhibited by non-native writers are relatively simple, we develop models that can incorporate knowledge about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Errors_and_residuals">error regularities</a> based on a small annotated sample but that are otherwise trained on native English data. The key contribution of this article is the introduction and analysis of two methods for adapting the learned models to error patterns of non-native writers ; one method that applies to generative classifiers and a second that applies to discriminative classifiers. Both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> demonstrated state-of-the-art performance in several text correction competitions. In particular, the Illinois system that implements these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> ranked at the top in two recent CoNLL shared tasks on error correction.1 We conduct further evaluation of the proposed approaches studying the effect of using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Error_detection_and_correction">error data</a> from speakers of the same native language, languages that are closely related linguistically, and unrelated languages.</abstract>
      <pages>723–760</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00299</doi>
      <url hash="4373f1eb">J17-4002</url>
      <bibkey>rozovskaya-etal-2017-adapting</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/fce">FCE</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>HyperLex : A Large-Scale Evaluation of Graded Lexical Entailment<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>yper<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ex: A Large-Scale Evaluation of Graded Lexical Entailment</title>
      <author><first>Ivan</first><last>Vulić</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniela</first><last>Gerz</last></author>
      <author><first>Douwe</first><last>Kiela</last></author>
      <author><first>Felix</first><last>Hill</last></author>
      <author><first>Anna</first><last>Korhonen</last></author>
      <abstract>We introduce HyperLexa data set and evaluation resource that quantifies the extent of the semantic category membership, that is, type-of relation, also known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyponymy_and_hypernymy">hyponymyhypernymy</a> or lexical entailment (LE) relation between 2,616 concept pairs. Cognitive psychology research has established that typicality and category / class membership are computed in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_memory">human semantic memory</a> as a gradual rather than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_relation">binary relation</a>. Nevertheless, most <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP research</a> and existing large-scale inventories of concept category membership (WordNet, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DBPedia">DBPedia</a>, etc.) treat category membership and LE as binary. To address this, we asked hundreds of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_language">native English speakers</a> to indicate typicality and strength of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Categorization">category membership</a> between a diverse range of concept pairs on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crowdsourcing">crowdsourcing platform</a>. Our results confirm that category membership and LE are indeed more gradual than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_relation">binary</a>. We then compare these human judgments with the predictions of automatic systems, which reveals a huge gap between human performance and state-of-the-art LE, distributional and representation learning models, and substantial differences between the models themselves. We discuss a pathway for improving semantic models to overcome this discrepancy, and indicate future application areas for improved graded LE systems.</abstract>
      <pages>781–835</pages>
      <doi>10.1162/COLI_a_00301</doi>
      <url hash="099e7e5d">J17-4004</url>
      <bibkey>vulic-etal-2017-hyperlex</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hyperlex">HyperLex</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/dbpedia">DBpedia</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/imagenet">ImageNet</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/yago">YAGO</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>