<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="U18">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Australasian Language Technology Association Workshop 2018</booktitle>
      <url hash="d16bf8c3">U18-1</url>
      <editor><first>Sunghwan Mac</first><last>Kim</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Xiuzhen (Jenny)</first><last>Zhang</last></editor>
      <address>Dunedin, New Zealand</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2018</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="5802d99e">U18-1000</url>
      <bibkey>alta-2018-australasian</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Improved Neural Machine Translation using Side Information</title>
      <author><first>Cong Duy Vu</first><last>Hoang</last></author>
      <author><first>Gholamreza</first><last>Haffari</last></author>
      <author><first>Trevor</first><last>Cohn</last></author>
      <pages>6–16</pages>
      <url hash="46593160">U18-1001</url>
      <abstract>In this work, we investigate whether side information is helpful in neural machine translation (NMT). We study various kinds of side information, including topical information, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trait_theory">personal trait</a>, then propose different ways of incorporating them into the existing NMT models. Our experimental results show the benefits of side information in improving the NMT models.</abstract>
      <bibkey>hoang-etal-2018-improved</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/pattr">PatTR</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Development of Natural Language Processing Tools for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cook_Islands">Cook Islands</a> Mori<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ook <fixed-case>I</fixed-case>slands <fixed-case>M</fixed-case>āori</title>
      <author><first>Rolando Coto</first><last>Solano</last></author>
      <author><first>Sally Akevai</first><last>Nicholas</last></author>
      <author><first>Samantha</first><last>Wray</last></author>
      <pages>26–33</pages>
      <url hash="f4845959">U18-1003</url>
      <abstract>This paper presents three ongoing projects for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cook_Islands_Māori">Cook Islands Maori</a> : Untrained Forced Alignment (approx. 9 % error when detecting the center of words), speech-to-text (37 % WER in the best trained models) and POS tagging (92 % accuracy for the best performing model). Included as part of these projects are new resources filling in a gap in Australasian languages, including gold standard POS-tagged written corpora, transcribed speech corpora, time-aligned corpora down to the level of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phoneme">phonemes</a>. These are part of efforts to accelerate the documentation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cook_Islands_Māori">Cook Islands Maori</a> and to increase its vitality amongst its users.</abstract>
      <bibkey>solano-etal-2018-development</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Specifying Conceptual Models Using Restricted Natural Language</title>
      <author><first>Bayzid Ashik</first><last>Hossain</last></author>
      <author><first>Rolf</first><last>Schwitter</last></author>
      <pages>44–52</pages>
      <url hash="5269a4f3">U18-1005</url>
      <abstract>The key activity to design an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_system">information system</a> is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model_(computer_science)">conceptual modelling</a> which brings out and describes the general knowledge that is required to build a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>. In this paper we propose a novel approach to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model_(computer_science)">conceptual modelling</a> where the domain experts will be able to specify and construct a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model_(computer_science)">model</a> using a restricted form of natural language. A restricted natural language is a subset of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language">natural language</a> that has well-defined computational properties and therefore can be translated unambiguously into a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_language">formal notation</a>. We will argue that a restricted natural language is suitable for writing precise and consistent specifications that lead to executable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model_(computer_science)">conceptual models</a>. Using a restricted natural language will allow the domain experts to describe a scenario in the terminology of the application domain without the need to formally encode this scenario. The resulting textual specification can then be automatically translated into the language of the desired <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model_(computer_science)">conceptual modelling framework</a>.</abstract>
      <bibkey>hossain-schwitter-2018-specifying</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Cluster Labeling by Word Embeddings and WordNet’s Hypernymy<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ord<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>et's Hypernymy</title>
      <author><first>Hanieh</first><last>Poostchi</last></author>
      <author><first>Massimo</first><last>Piccardi</last></author>
      <pages>66–70</pages>
      <url hash="e98a71c5">U18-1008</url>
      <abstract>Cluster labeling is the assignment of representative labels to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cluster_analysis">clusters</a> obtained from the organization of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_management_system">document collection</a>. Once assigned, the labels can play an important role in applications such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navigation">navigation</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_search_engine">search</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_classification">document classification</a>. However, finding appropriately descriptive labels is still a challenging task. In this paper, we propose various approaches for assigning labels to word clusters by leveraging <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embeddings</a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synonym">synonymity</a> and hypernymy relations in the WordNet lexical ontology. Experiments carried out using the WebAP document dataset have shown that one of the approaches stand out in the comparison and is capable of selecting labels that are reasonably aligned with those chosen by a pool of four human annotators.</abstract>
      <bibkey>poostchi-piccardi-2018-cluster</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>A Comparative Study of Embedding Models in Predicting the Compositionality of Multiword Expressions</title>
      <author><first>Navnita</first><last>Nandakumar</last></author>
      <author><first>Bahar</first><last>Salehi</last></author>
      <author><first>Timothy</first><last>Baldwin</last></author>
      <pages>71–76</pages>
      <url hash="3d7aad37">U18-1009</url>
      <abstract>In this paper, we perform a comparative evaluation of off-the-shelf embedding models over the task of compositionality prediction of multiword expressions(MWEs). Our experimental results suggest that character- and document-level models capture knowledge of MWE compositionality and are effective in modelling varying levels of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compositionality">compositionality</a>, with the advantage over word-level models that they do not require token-level identification of MWEs in the training corpus.</abstract>
      <bibkey>nandakumar-etal-2018-comparative</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Overview of the 2018 ALTA Shared Task : Classifying Patent Applications<fixed-case>ALTA</fixed-case> Shared Task: Classifying Patent Applications</title>
      <author><first>Diego</first><last>Mollá</last></author>
      <author><first>Dilesha</first><last>Seneviratne</last></author>
      <pages>84–88</pages>
      <url hash="b16206b8">U18-1011</url>
      <abstract>We present an overview of the 2018 ALTA shared task. This is the 9th of the series of shared tasks organised by ALTA since 2010. The task was to classify Australian patent classifications following the sections defined by the International Patient Classification (IPC), using data made available by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_Australia">IP Australia</a>. We introduce the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a>, describe the data and present the results of the participating teams. Some of the participating teams outperformed state of the art.</abstract>
      <bibkey>molla-seneviratne-2018-overview</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Classifying Patent Applications with Ensemble Methods</title>
      <author><first>Fernando</first><last>Benites</last></author>
      <author><first>Shervin</first><last>Malmasi</last></author>
      <author><first>Marcos</first><last>Zampieri</last></author>
      <pages>89–92</pages>
      <url hash="fe24ec3a">U18-1012</url>
      <abstract>We present methods for the automatic classification of patent applications using an annotated dataset provided by the organizers of the ALTA 2018 shared task-Classifying Patent Applications. The goal of the task is to use computational methods to categorize patent applications according to a coarse-grained taxonomy of eight classes based on the International Patent Classification (IPC). We tested a variety of approaches for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> and the best results, 0.778 micro-averaged F1-Score, were achieved by SVM ensembles using a combination of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word">words</a> and characters as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a>. Our team, BMZ, was ranked first among 14 teams in the competition.</abstract>
      <bibkey>benites-etal-2018-classifying</bibkey>
    <title_ar>تصنيف طلبات براءات الاختراع بطرق التجميع</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Classificação de pedidos de patente com métodos de conjunto</title_pt>
      <title_es>Clasificación de las solicitudes de patente con métodos conjuntos</title_es>
      <title_ja>アンサンブル法による特許出願の分類</title_ja>
      <title_zh>用集成法分专利申请</title_zh>
      <title_hi>Ensemble तरीकों के साथ पेटेंट अनुप्रयोगों को वर्गीकृत करना</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Feidhmchláir Paitinne a Aicmiú le Modhanna Ensemble</title_ga>
      <title_ka>პეტენტის პროგრამების კლასიფიკაცია გამოყენებული მეტისთან</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A szabadalmi bejelentések osztályozása együttes módszerekkel</title_hu>
      <title_kk>Көрсетілетін әдістерді патенттерді классификациялау қолданбалары</title_kk>
      <title_it>Classificazione delle domande di brevetto con metodi Ensemble</title_it>
      <title_lt>Patent ų paraiškų klasifikavimas pagal vienodus metodus</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Класификување на апликации за патенти со ансембелни методи</title_mk>
      <title_el>Ταξινόμηση αιτήσεων ευρεσιτεχνίας με μεθόδους συνόλου</title_el>
      <title_ms>Menaklasifikasikan Aplikasi Paten dengan Kaedah Terwujud</title_ms>
      <title_ml>സെമിബിള്‍ മാറ്റങ്ങളുമായി പാറ്റെന്റ് പ്രയോഗങ്ങള്‍ ക്ലാസിക്ക് ചെയ്യുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_no>Klassifiserer patentprogram med metodar</title_no>
      <title_ro>Clasificarea cererilor de brevet cu metode de ansamblu</title_ro>
      <title_mt>Il-Klassifikazzjoni tal-Applikazzjonijiet tal-Privattivi b’Metodi Ensemble</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Хэрэглэгдэх аргаар патент програмуудыг классифицировах</title_mn>
      <title_si>සම්බන්ධ විධානය සඳහා පැටෙන්ට් විධානය ලැබීම</title_si>
      <title_sv>Klassificering av patentansökningar med ensemblemetoder</title_sv>
      <title_pl>Klasyfikowanie zgłoszeń patentowych metodami zespołowymi</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Klasificirajući patentne aplikacije sa metodama proizvodnje</title_sr>
      <title_ur>پٹینٹ اپنا کارسازی مہینسمبل طریقے کے ساتھ کلاسیفٹ کرتا ہے</title_ur>
      <title_ta>வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட தோற்றம் பயன்பாடுகள்</title_ta>
      <title_so>Codsiyada qaabilsan ee ku saabsan qaababka bukaanka</title_so>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>KCharselect unicode block name</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Класификация на заявленията за патенти с ансамбълни методи</title_bg>
      <title_da>Klassificering af patentansøgninger med Ensemble Metoder</title_da>
      <title_de>Klassifizierung von Patentanmeldungen mit Ensemble-Methoden</title_de>
      <title_nl>Classificatie van octrooiaanvragen met behulp van ensemblemethoden</title_nl>
      <title_fa>کاربردهای patents با روش‌های خریدن</title_fa>
      <title_id>Classifying Patent Applications with Ensemble Methods</title_id>
      <title_tr>Södlemeler Metini bilen Taýýarlama</title_tr>
      <title_ko>집적 방법 으로 특허 신청 을 분류 하다</title_ko>
      <title_af>Klassifiseer Patente Programme met Ensemble Metodes</title_af>
      <title_sq>Klasifikimi i aplikacioneve të patentave me metoda të përbashkëta</title_sq>
      <title_sw>Applications for Classification Patients with Ensemable methods</title_sw>
      <title_hr>Klasificirajući patentne aplikacije s metodama uključenja</title_hr>
      <title_am>ፋይል sን መክፈት አልቻለም፦ %s፦ %s</title_am>
      <title_hy>Պարտոնագրական ծրագրեր դասավորելը հավասար մեթոդներով</title_hy>
      <title_bn>প্যাটেন্টের অ্যাপ্লিকেশনName</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Classificar les aplicacions de brevets amb mètodes agrupables</title_ca>
      <title_az>Ensemble Methods ilə Patent Uygulamaları</title_az>
      <title_fi>Patenttihakemusten luokittelu Ensemble-menetelmin</title_fi>
      <title_cs>Klasifikace patentových přihlášek pomocí souborových metod</title_cs>
      <title_bs>Klasificirajući patentne aplikacije sa metodama proizvodnje</title_bs>
      <title_et>Patenditaotluste klassifitseerimine ansambli meetoditega</title_et>
      <title_jv>UTC</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Razvrščanje patentnih prijav z ansambelnimi metodami</title_sk>
      <title_ha>Classifying Patent Applications with Ensemble Methods</title_ha>
      <title_he>מסווג תוכניות פטנטים עם שיטות מסוגלות</title_he>
      <title_bo>ཆ་མཚོན་རུང་བའི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་སྤྱོད་པའི་བསམ་རིས་སྤྱོད་དབྱེ་བ</title_bo>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos métodos para la clasificación automática de solicitudes de patente utilizando un conjunto de datos anotado proporcionado por los organizadores de la tarea compartida de ALTA 2018: Clasificación de solicitudes de patente. El objetivo de la tarea es utilizar métodos computacionales para clasificar las solicitudes de patente de acuerdo con una taxonomía de grano grueso de ocho clases basada en la Clasificación Internacional de Patentes (CIP). Probamos una variedad de enfoques para esta tarea y los mejores resultados, una puntuación F1 micropromediada de 0.778, se lograron con conjuntos de SVM que usaron una combinación de palabras y caracteres como características. Nuestro equipo, BMZ, ocupó el primer lugar entre 14 equipos de la competencia.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم طرقًا للتصنيف التلقائي لطلبات براءات الاختراع باستخدام مجموعة بيانات مشروحة مقدمة من منظمي مهمة ALTA 2018 المشتركة - تصنيف تطبيقات براءات الاختراع. الهدف من المهمة هو استخدام الأساليب الحسابية لتصنيف طلبات البراءات وفقًا لتصنيف دقيق الحبيبات لثماني فئات بناءً على التصنيف الدولي للبراءات (IPC). اختبرنا مجموعة متنوعة من الأساليب لهذه المهمة وتم تحقيق أفضل النتائج ، 0.778 متوسط درجة F1 متوسطة ، بواسطة مجموعات SVM باستخدام مجموعة من الكلمات والأحرف كميزات. احتل فريقنا BMZ المرتبة الأولى من بين 14 فريقًا في المسابقة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos métodos para a classificação automática de pedidos de patente usando um conjunto de dados anotado fornecido pelos organizadores da tarefa compartilhada ALTA 2018 - Classificação de pedidos de patente. O objetivo da tarefa é usar métodos computacionais para categorizar os pedidos de patentes de acordo com uma taxonomia grosseira de oito classes com base na Classificação Internacional de Patentes (IPC). Testamos uma variedade de abordagens para esta tarefa e os melhores resultados, 0,778 micro-média F1-Score, foram alcançados por conjuntos SVM usando uma combinação de palavras e caracteres como recursos. Nossa equipe, BMZ, ficou em primeiro lugar entre 14 equipes da competição.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>我々は、ALTA 2018共通タスク-特許出願の分類の主催者によって提供される注釈付きデータセットを使用して、特許出願を自動的に分類するための方法を提示する。課題の目標は、国際特許分類（ ＩＰＣ ）に基づく８つのクラスの粗粒度分類法に従って、特許出願を分類するために計算方法を使用することである。私たちはこのタスクのためにさまざまなアプローチをテストし、最高の結果、0.778マイクロ平均化されたF 1スコアは、単語と文字の組み合わせを特徴として使用するSVMアンサンブルによって達成されました。私たちのチーム、BMZは、コンペティションの14チームの中で1位でした。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>臣等言用ALTA 2018共享 - 专利申请类组织者带注之数集对专利申请自分之法。 凡任事者,用算法,以国际专利之类(IPC)八类之粗粒度分类法分专利申请。 试之多方,而合之以单词符,SVM融合为上,0.778微均F1得分。 团队BMZ在比赛中14支队中第一。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम ALTA 2018 साझा कार्य के आयोजकों द्वारा प्रदान किए गए एक एनोटेट डेटासेट का उपयोग करके पेटेंट अनुप्रयोगों के स्वचालित वर्गीकरण के लिए विधियां प्रस्तुत करते हैं - पेटेंट अनुप्रयोगों को वर्गीकृत करना। कार्य का लक्ष्य अंतर्राष्ट्रीय पेटेंट वर्गीकरण (आईपीसी) के आधार पर आठ वर्गों के मोटे-दाने वाले वर्गीकरण के अनुसार पेटेंट अनुप्रयोगों को वर्गीकृत करने के लिए कम्प्यूटेशनल तरीकों का उपयोग करना है। हमने इस कार्य के लिए विभिन्न दृष्टिकोणों का परीक्षण किया और सर्वोत्तम परिणाम, 0.778 माइक्रो-औसत F1-स्कोर, विशेषताओं के रूप में शब्दों और वर्णों के संयोजन का उपयोग करके एसवीएम ensembles द्वारा प्राप्त किए गए थे। हमारी टीम, बीएमजेड, प्रतियोगिता में 14 टीमों के बीच पहले स्थान पर थी।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid modhanna i láthair chun iarratais ar phaitinn a aicmiú go huathoibríoch ag baint úsáide as tacar sonraí anótáilte arna soláthar ag eagraithe tasc comhroinnte ALTA 2018 - Feidhmchláir Paitinne a Aicmiú. Is é sprioc an taisc modhanna ríomhaireachtúla a úsáid chun iarratais ar phaitinn a chatagóiriú de réir tacsanomaíochta garbh-ghráinneach d’ocht n-aicme bunaithe ar Aicmiú Idirnáisiúnta na bPaitinní (IPC). Rinneamar tástáil ar éagsúlacht cur chuige don tasc seo agus bhain ensembles SVM na torthaí is fearr, 0.778 micrea-mheánmhéid F1-Scór, ag baint úsáide as meascán de fhocail agus de charachtair mar ghnéithe. Rangaíodh ár bhfoireann, BMZ, sa chéad áit i measc 14 fhoireann sa chomórtas.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Bemutatjuk a szabadalmi bejelentések automatikus osztályozásának módszereit az ALTA 2018 közös feladat szervezői által biztosított, jegyzetelt adatkészlet segítségével - Szabadalmi bejelentések osztályozása. A feladat célja számítástechnikai módszerek alkalmazása a szabadalmi bejelentések nemzetközi szabadalmi osztályozás (IPC) alapján nyolc osztályból álló durva szemű taxonómia szerint történő kategóriába sorolása. Különböző megközelítéseket teszteltünk ehhez a feladathoz, és a legjobb eredményeket, 0,778 mikro-átlagos F1-pontszámot, az SVM együttesek szavak és karakterek kombinációjával érték el. Csapatunk, a BMZ az első helyen állt a versenyen 14 csapat közül.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε μεθόδους για την αυτόματη ταξινόμηση των αιτήσεων διπλωμάτων ευρεσιτεχνίας χρησιμοποιώντας ένα σχολιασμένο σύνολο δεδομένων που παρέχεται από τους διοργανωτές της κοινής εργασίας με τίτλο Ταξινόμηση αιτήσεων διπλωμάτων ευρεσιτεχνίας. Στόχος του έργου είναι η χρήση υπολογιστικών μεθόδων για την κατηγοριοποίηση των αιτήσεων ευρεσιτεχνίας σύμφωνα με μια χονδροειδής ταξινομία οκτώ κατηγοριών βασισμένη στη Διεθνή Ταξινόμηση Διπλωμάτων Ευρεσιτεχνίας (IPC). Δοκιμάσαμε μια ποικιλία προσεγγίσεων για αυτό το έργο και τα καλύτερα αποτελέσματα, 0.778 μικρομεσαίου βαθμού, επιτεύχθηκαν από σύνολα χρησιμοποιώντας έναν συνδυασμό λέξεων και χαρακτήρων ως χαρακτηριστικά. Η ομάδα μας, BMZ, κατατάχθηκε πρώτη από τις 14ες ομάδες στον διαγωνισμό.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo metodi per la classificazione automatica delle domande di brevetto utilizzando un dataset annotato fornito dagli organizzatori del compito condiviso ALTA 2018 - Classificazione delle domande di brevetto. L'obiettivo del compito è quello di utilizzare metodi computazionali per classificare le domande di brevetto secondo una tassonomia a grana grossa di otto classi basata sulla classificazione internazionale dei brevetti (IPC). Abbiamo testato una varietà di approcci per questo compito e i migliori risultati, 0,778 micro-media F1 Score, sono stati raggiunti dagli ensemble SVM utilizzando una combinazione di parole e caratteri come caratteristiche. Il nostro team, BMZ, si è classificato primo tra 14 squadre della competizione.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ აჩვენებთ პოტენტის პროგრამების ავტომატური კლასიფიკაციის მეტოვები გამოყენებული მონაცემების კონტიფიკაციის გამოყენება, რომელიც ALTA 2018-ის გაყოფილი მონაცემების ორგანიზატო პარამეტრის მიზეზი არის გამოყენება კომპუტაციალური მეტოვების გამოყენება პოტენტის პროგრამების კატეგორიზაციის გამოყენება 8 კლასის რაკონომის შესახებ ინტერსონაციო პოტენტი ჩვენ ამ დავალებისთვის განსხვავებული მიღებების შემოწმება და უკეთესი შედეგი შედეგი, 0.778 მიკრო-განსხვავებული F1-სკონტი, SVM-სკენმბულების გამოყენება სიტყვების და სიმბოლოების სიმბოლოები ნაქთჲრ ვკთო, ბვმჱთ, ბვქვ ოყპგჲ პვნდთპან ჲრ 14 რთოა გ კჲნკპვნუთწრა.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_ms>Kami perkenalkan kaedah untuk kelasukan automatik aplikasi paten menggunakan set data yang dicatat disediakan oleh pengatur tugas terkongsi ALTA 2018 - Kelasukan Aplikasi Paten. The goal of the task is to use computational methods to categorize patent applications according to a coarse-grained taxonomy of eight classes based on the International Patent Classification (IPC).  Kami menguji pelbagai pendekatan untuk tugas ini dan keputusan terbaik, 0.778 skor F1 berrata-rata-mikro, dicapai oleh ensemble SVM menggunakan kombinasi kata-kata dan aksara sebagai ciri-ciri. Pasukan kita, BMZ, dipilih pertama diantara 14 pasukan dalam pertandingan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_lt>Patent ų paraiškų automatinio klasifikavimo metodai pateikiami naudojant anotuotą duomenų rinkinį, kurį pateikė bendros užduoties ALTA 2018 organizatoriai - Patentų paraiškų klasifikavimas. Šios užduoties tikslas – taikyti skaičiavimo metodus patent ų paraiškoms suskirstyti į kategorijas pagal a štuonių klasių, pagrįstų Tarptautine patentų klasifikacija (IPC), grubiagrūdinę taksonomiją. Mes išbandėme įvairius šios užduoties metodus ir geriausius rezultatus, 0,778 mikrovidutinio F1 balas, pasiekti SVM ensembles naudojant žodžių ir simbolių derinį kaip savybes. Mūsų komanda, BMZ, buvo pirmoji iš 14 komandų konkurse.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Біз патенттік қолданбаларды автоматты түрде шектеу әдістерін ALTA 2018 ортақ тапсырманың ортақтастырушылары бойынша белгіленген деректер жиынын қолдануға арналған әдістерін таңдаймыз. Тапсырманың мақсаты - халықаралық патенттер классификациясы (IPC) негізінде 8 классының тексономиясынан бағытталған патенттер қолданбаларын санаттау үшін есептеу әдістерін қолдану. Бұл тапсырма үшін бірнеше әртүрлі жағдайларды тексердік және ең жақсы нәтижелер, 0,778 микро- орташа F1- нәтижелері, SVM символдары сөздер мен таңбаларды мүмкіндіктер ретінде біріктіреді. Біздің командамыз, BMZ, 14 командалардың бірінші ретінде орындалды.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ml>അല്‍ടാഎ 2018 വിഭാഗിക്കപ്പെട്ട ജോലിയുടെ സംഘടനക്കാര്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ച് പാറ്റെന്റ് പ്രയോഗങ്ങളുടെ സ്വയമായ വിഭവങ്ങള്‍ക്കുള്ള രീതികള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍  ഈ ജോലിയുടെ ലക്ഷ്യം ആന്തരാഷ്ട്രീയ പാറ്റെന്റിന്റെ പ്രയോഗങ്ങള്‍ വിഭാഗമാക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള കണക്കുണ്ടാക്കുന്ന രീതികള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുക എന്നത ഈ ജോലിയ്ക്കുള്ള വ്യത്യസ്ത പരീക്ഷണങ്ങള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ പരീക്ഷിച്ചിട്ടുണ്ട്. ഏറ്റവും നല്ല ഫലങ്ങള്‍, 0. 778 മൈക്രോ സ്കോര്‍ എഫ്‌1-സ്കോര്‍, എസ്‌വിഎം എണ്‍സ്പെമ ഞങ്ങളുടെ ടീം ബിഎംസ്, പ്രതിയോഗിക്കുന്ന 14 ടീം കൂട്ടത്തില്‍ ആദ്യം റെഞ്ച് ചെയ്യപ്പെട്ടു.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nippreżentaw metodi għall-klassifikazzjoni awtomatika tal-applikazzjonijiet għall-privattivi bl-użu ta' sett ta' dejta annotat ipprovdut mill-organizzaturi tal-kompitu kondiviż ALTA 2018 - Klassifikazzjoni tal-Applikazzjonijiet għall-Privattivi. L-għan tal-kompitu huwa li jintużaw metodi komputattivi biex jiġu kkategorizzati l-applikazzjonijiet għall-privattivi skont tassonomija bi ħbub gross ta’ tmien klassijiet ibbażata fuq il-Klassifikazzjoni Internazzjonali tal-Privattivi (IPC). Ittestjna varjetà ta’ approċċi għal dan il-kompitu u l-a ħjar riżultati, 0.778 punteġġ F1 b’medja mikro, inkisbu minn ensembles SVM bl-użu ta’ kombinazzjoni ta’ kliem u karattri bħala karatteristiċi. It-tim tagħna, BMZ, kien ikklassifikat l-ewwel fost 14-il tim fil-kompetizzjoni.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mk>Презентираме методи за автоматска класификација на апликациите за патенти користејќи анотиран датотек обезбеден од организаторите на заедничката задача ALTA 2018 - класификација на апликациите за патенти. The goal of the task is to use computational methods to categorize patent applications according to a coarse-grained taxonomy of eight classes based on the International Patent Classification (IPC).  Тестиравме различни пристапи за оваа задача и најдобрите резултати, 0,778 микро-просечни F1-оценки, беа постигнати од страна на SVM ансембли користејќи комбинација на зборови и карактери како карактеристики. Нашиот тим, БМЗ, беше рангиран прв меѓу 14 тимови на натпреварот.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mn>Бид АЛТА 2018 оны хуваалтын ажил зохион байгуулагчид ашиглан патент програмуудын автоматически хуваалцах арга загварыг тайлбарлаж байна. Үүний зорилго бол олон улсын патент классификацийн (IPC) дээр үндсэн найм классын давхар татекономикийн хувьд патент хэрэгжүүлэлтийг категоричлахын тулд тооны арга хэрэглэх юм. Бид энэ ажил дээр олон арга зам шалгаж, хамгийн сайн үр дүнг нь 0.778 бичил дундаж F1-Score-д олон арга зам шалгаж байлаа. Бидний баг, BMZ, өрсөлдөөнд 14 багийн хамтдаа анх дүрслэгдсэн.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Prezentăm metode de clasificare automată a cererilor de brevet folosind un set de date adnotate furnizat de organizatorii sarcinii comune ALTA 2018 - Clasificarea cererilor de brevet. Scopul sarcinii este de a utiliza metode computaționale pentru a clasifica cererile de brevet în funcție de o taxonomie grosieră de opt clase bazată pe Clasificarea Internațională a Brevetelor (IPC). Am testat o varietate de abordări pentru această sarcină și cele mai bune rezultate, 0.778 micro-medii F1-Score, au fost obținute de ansamblurile SVM folosind o combinație de cuvinte și caractere ca caracteristici. Echipa noastră, BMZ, s-a clasat pe primul loc printre cele 14 echipe din competiție.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Predstavljamo metode za automatsku klasifikaciju patentnih aplikacija koristeći annotiranu kompletu podataka koju su organizatori zajedničkog zadatka ALTA 2018 - klasifikacija patentnih aplikacija. Cilj zadataka je da koristimo računalne metode za kategoriju patenata u skladu sa taksonomijom od osam klasa na osnovu Međunarodne klasifikacije patenata (IPC). Testirali smo različite pristupe ovom zadatku i najbolje rezultate, 0,778 mikro-srednji F1-Score, postigli su SVM ensembli koristeći kombinaciju riječi i karaktera kao karakteristike. Naš tim, BMZ, bio je prvi od 14 tima na konkurenciji.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu soo bandhignaa qaabab u baaraandegista iskuulka dalbashada macluumaadka ah ee loo isticmaalayo sawirida macluumaadka ee qabanqaabiyaha shaqada ee ALTA 2018 qayb u dhigay - Xisaamiya codsiga bukaanka. Ujeedada shaqadu waa in lagu isticmaalo qaabab xisaabta ah si uu u kala qeybeeyo codsiga farshaxanka siddeed fasaladood oo ku saleysan fasalka caalamiga ah ee baaritaanka bukaanka (IPC). Shaqadan waxaan imtixaannay qaabooyin kala duduwan iyo arimaha ugu fiican, 0.778 micro-Score, waxaa soo gaadhay SVM imtixaan, si ay u isticmaalaan hadal iyo qalab. Kooxdayaga BMZ ayaa marka ugu horeysa koox 14 koox oo ka mid ah qasbidda.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>අපි ස්වයංක්‍රියාත්මක විශේෂණය සඳහා පැටෙන්ට් යුද්ධකයේ ස්වයංක්‍රියාත්මක විශේෂණය සඳහා ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විශ රස්සාවේ අරමුණය තමයි පරිගණනය විධානය භාවිතා කරන්න පැටෙන්ට් විධානය කරන්න පැටෙන්ට් විධානය කරන්න පැටෙන්ට් විධානය කරන්නේ අන් අපි මේ වැඩේ සඳහා හොඳම ප්‍රතිචාරය, 0.778 මායික්‍රෝම- ස්කෝර් සම්පූර්ණය F1- ස්කෝර් සඳහා විවිධ ප්‍රවේශයක් පරීක්ෂා කරලා තියෙනවා  අපේ කණ්ඩායම, BMZ, පලවෙනි කණ්ඩායම් 14ක් අතර පටන් ගත්තා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer metodar for automatisk klassifikasjon av patentprogram med eit notasjonssett som oppgjeven av organisatorene av delt oppgåve ALTA 2018 – klassifiserer patentprogram. Målet på oppgåva er å bruka kalkulasjonsmetodar for å kategorisera patentprogram etter ein taksonom med åtte klassar basert på internasjonale patentklassifikasjon (IPC). Vi prøvde mange tilnærmingar for denne oppgåva, og dei beste resultatene, 0,778 mikro gjennomsnittsfarge F1- poeng, ble oppnådd av SVM- ensembler med kombinasjon av ord og teikn som funksjonar. Gruppen vårt BMZ var først rankert blant 14 grupper i konkurransen.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar metoder för automatisk klassificering av patentansökningar med hjälp av en antecknad datauppsättning tillhandahållen av arrangörerna av ALTA 2018 delade uppgift - Klassificering av patentansökningar. Syftet med uppgiften är att använda beräkningsmetoder för att kategorisera patentansökningar enligt en grovkornig taxonomi av åtta klasser baserad på International Patent Classification (IPC). Vi testade en mängd olika tillvägagångssätt för denna uppgift och de bästa resultaten, 0,778 mikro-genomsnittlig F1-Score, uppnåddes av SVM ensembler med en kombination av ord och tecken som funktioner. Vårt team, BMZ, rankades först bland 14 lag i tävlingen.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_pl>Przedstawiamy metody automatycznej klasyfikacji zgłoszeń patentowych z wykorzystaniem adnotacji zbioru danych dostarczonych przez organizatorów wspólnego zadania ALTA 2018 Klasyfikacja zgłoszeń patentowych. Celem zadania jest wykorzystanie metod obliczeniowych do kategoryzacji zgłoszeń patentowych według gruboziarnistej taksonomii ośmiu klas opartej na Międzynarodowej Klasyfikacji Patentowej (IPC). Przetestowaliśmy różne podejścia do tego zadania, a najlepsze wyniki, 0.778 mikro-średni F1-Score, zostały osiągnięte przez zespoły SVM wykorzystujące kombinację słów i znaków jako cech. Nasz zespół, BMZ, zajął pierwszy miejsce wśród czternastu drużyn w konkursie.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ta>நாங்கள் தானாகவே பாதுகாப்பு பயன்பாடுகளை வகைப்படுத்தும் முறைகளை கொண்டு ALTA 2018 கூட்டிய செயல்பாட்டின் அமைப்பாளர் வழங்கப்பட்ட தகவல் அமைப் செயலின் இலக்கு என்னவென்றால் அனைத்து இணைப்பு வகுப்பினை அடிப்படையில் அடிப்படையான மாதிரியை கொண்டு 8 வகுப்பு இந்த செயலுக்கான பல்வேறு வழிகளையும் சோதித்தோம், சிறந்த முடிவு எங்கள் குழு, BMZ, போட்டியில் 14 குழுக்களில் முதலில் நிறுவப்பட்டது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم آلتا ۲۰۱۸ شریک کار کا سازمان کرنے والوں کے ذریعہ ایک نوٹ ڈیٹ سٹ کے مطابق پیٹ انٹ اپنا کارشناسی کے آٹوٹ کلسٹ کے مطابق طریقے پیش کرتے ہیں۔ اس کام کا موقع یہ ہے کہ آٹھ کلاس کے آٹھ کالسوں کی کمپیوٹریشن طریقوں کا استعمال کرنا ہے کہ پاٹینٹ کے کاروباروں کو کاٹریزی کریں (IPC) پر بنیادی آٹھ کلاس کے مطابق آٹھ کالسوں کی تاکسنومی کے مطابق۔ ہم نے اس کام کے لئے مختلف طریقے کی آزمائش کی اور بہترین نتیجے، 0.778 میکرومتوسط F1-Score، SVM کے ذریعہ ایک کلمات اور شخصیتوں کی تعبیر کے مطابق پہنچ گئے۔ ہمارے ٹیم، BMZ، مسابقات میں 14 ٹیموں میں پہلے درجے کی گئی۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>@ info: whatsthis The goal of the task is to use computational methods to categorize patent applications according to a coarse-grained taxonomy of eight classes based on the International Patent Classification (IPC).  Biz shu vazifa uchun ko'pchilik usullarni sinab ko'proq qildik va eng yaxshi natijalar, 0.778 mikro- darajasi F1- darajasi bo'lgan SVM asboblari bilan soʻzlar va harflarni moslamalar sifatida birlashtirish mumkin. Bizning birinchi guruhimiz BMZ'ning 14 guruhidagi birinchi tashkilotga kiritdi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi có các phương pháp phân loại tự động ứng dụng bằng bằng một bộ dữ liệu được ghi chú cung cấp bởi các tổ chức của giao dịch ước mơ ước lượng. Nhiệm vụ này nhằm mục đích là sử dụng các phương pháp tính to án để phân loại các ứng dụng bằng sáng chế theo một loại thuế dày nhất thuộc tám lớp dựa trên Các hạng I.P.C. Chúng tôi đã thử một số phương pháp khác nhau cho nhiệm vụ này và kết quả tốt nhất, 0.778 thu nhỏ F1-Score, đã được thành lập bởi các tập hợp SVM dùng một kết hợp từ và kí tự như các tính năng. Đội của chúng tôi, BMZ, được xếp hạng đầu tiên trong hàng 14 trong cuộc đua.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме методи за автоматична класификация на заявленията за патент с помощта на анотиран набор от данни, предоставен от организаторите на споделената задача на АЛАТА 2018 - Класификация на заявленията за патент. Целта на задачата е да се използват изчислителни методи за категоризиране на заявленията за патенти според грубозърнеста таксономия от осем класа въз основа на Международната патентна класификация (ИПК). Изпробвахме различни подходи за тази задача и най-добрите резултати, 0.778 микро-средни резултати, бяха постигнати от ансамбли използвайки комбинация от думи и знаци като функции. Екипът ни БМЗ се класира на първо място сред 14 отбора в състезанието.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_de>Wir stellen Methoden zur automatischen Klassifizierung von Patentanmeldungen anhand eines kommentierten Datensatzes vor, der von den Organisatoren der gemeinsamen ALTA 2018-Aufgabe Klassifizierung von Patentanmeldungen bereitgestellt wird. Ziel der Aufgabe ist es, mithilfe von computergestützten Methoden Patentanmeldungen nach einer grobkörnigen Taxonomie von acht Klassen basierend auf der Internationalen Patentklassifikation (IPC) zu kategorisieren. Wir haben eine Vielzahl von Ansätzen für diese Aufgabe getestet und die besten Ergebnisse, 0.778 mikrogemittelter F1-Score, wurden von SVM-Ensembles mit einer Kombination von Wörtern und Zeichen als Merkmale erzielt. Unser Team, BMZ, wurde unter den 14-Teams im Wettbewerb an erster Stelle platziert.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren methoden voor de automatische classificatie van octrooiaanvragen met behulp van een geannoteerde dataset verstrekt door de organisatoren van de gedeelde ALTA 2018 taak Classification Patent Applications. Het doel van de taak is om met behulp van computationele methoden octrooiaanvragen te categoriseren volgens een grove taxonomie van acht klassen op basis van de International Patent Classification (IPC). We hebben een verscheidenheid aan benaderingen voor deze taak getest en de beste resultaten, 0.778 microgemiddelde F1-Score, werden bereikt door SVM ensembles met behulp van een combinatie van woorden en tekens als kenmerken. Ons team, BMZ, stond op de eerste plaats onder de veertien teams in de competitie.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer metoder til automatisk klassificering af patentansøgninger ved hjælp af et annoteret datasæt leveret af arrangørerne af ALTA 2018 delte opgave - Klassificering af patentansøgninger. Formålet med opgaven er at anvende beregningsmetoder til at kategorisere patentansøgninger efter en grovkornet taksonomi på otte klasser baseret på International Patent Classification (IPC). Vi testede en række forskellige tilgange til denne opgave, og de bedste resultater, 0,778 mikrogennemsnit F1-Score, blev opnået af SVM ensembler ved hjælp af en kombination af ord og tegn som funktioner. Vores team, BMZ, blev rangeret første blandt 14 hold i konkurrencen.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Kami mempersembahkan metode untuk klasifikasi otomatis aplikasi paten menggunakan set data annotasi yang disediakan oleh organisasi tugas berbagi ALTA 2018 - Klasifikasi aplikasi paten. The goal of the task is to use computational methods to categorize patent applications according to a coarse-grained taxonomy of eight classes based on the International Patent Classification (IPC).  We tested a variety of approaches for this task and the best results, 0.778 micro-averaged F1-Score, were achieved by SVM ensembles using a combination of words and characters as features.  Our team, BMZ, was ranked first among 14 teams in the competition.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>ALTA 2018 공유 임무-특허출원 분류 조직자가 제공한 주석이 달린 데이터 집합을 이용하여 특허출원을 자동으로 분류하는 방법을 소개했다.이 임무의 목표는 계산 방법을 사용하여 국제특허분류(IPC) 기반의 8가지 굵은 입도 분류법에 따라 특허 신청을 분류하는 것이다.우리는 SVM 통합을 통해 단어와 문자를 특징으로 조합하여 0.778의 미평균 F1 점수를 얻은 다양한 방법을 테스트했습니다.우리 팀 BMZ는 14개 참가팀 중 1위다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_tr>Biz 2018-nji paylaşyk görevi programleriniň otomatik klasifikasyny çykarýarys. Bu zadyň maksady şudyr: Halkara Patent klasifikasyna (IPC) tabanly sekiz klaslaryň üstünde patent programlerini kategoriýarlamak üçin hesaplamak metodlaryny ullamakdyr. Biz bu zadyň üçin bir näçe golaýy bardyk we gowy netijesi 0.778 mikro ortalanmış F1-Score tarapyndan ýeňildik. Biziň topamyz BMZ, ýaryşykda ilkinji gezek 14 toparda düzüldi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Ons voorsien metodes vir die outomatiese klasifikasie van patenttoepassings met gebruik van 'n notateerde datastel wat deur die organiseerders van die ALTA 2018 gedeelde taak verskaf word - Klassifiseer Patenttoepassings. Die doel van die taak is om rekenaarske metodes te gebruik om patenttoepassings te kategoriseer volgens 'n kors-graan taksonomie van agt klasse gebaseer op die internasionale patentklassifikasie (IPC). Ons het 'n verskillende toegang tot hierdie taak en die beste resultate, 0.778 mikro- gemiddelde F1- Tel, was bereik deur SVM ensembles deur 'n kombinasie van woorde en karakters as funksies te gebruik. Ons span, BMZ, is eerste rang onder 14 teams in die samenskap.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hr>Mi predstavljamo metode za automatsku klasifikaciju patentnih aplikacija koristeći annotiranu kompletu podataka koju su organizatori zajedničkog zadatka ALTA 2018 - klasifikacija patentnih aplikacija. Cilj zadatka je koristiti računalne metode za kategoriju patenata u skladu s taksonomijom od osam klasa na temelju Međunarodne klasifikacije patenata (IPC). Testirali smo različite pristupe ovom zadatku i najbolji rezultati, 0,778 mikro-srednji F1-Score, postigli su SVM ensembli koristeći kombinaciju riječi i znakova kao karakteristike. Naš tim, BMZ, bio je prvi od 14 tima na natjecanju.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_fa>ما روش‌هایی برای برنامه‌های استفاده از یک مجموعه‌ی داده‌های نوشته‌شده‌ای که توسط سازمان‌کنندگان کار مشترک ALTA ۲۰۱۸ داده می‌شود را برای برنامه‌های استفاده‌کننده‌ی خودکار نشان می‌دهیم. هدف این کار این است که از روش‌های محاسبه استفاده کنیم تا پرونده‌های پرونده‌های پرونده‌ای را با توجه به تاکسونوم‌ای از هشت کلاس بر اساس کلاس‌شناسی پرونده‌های بین‌المللی (IPC) تقسیم کنیم. ما از طریق‌های مختلف برای این کار و بهترین نتیجه‌های 0.778 میکرومتوسط F1-Score آزمایش کردیم، توسط نمره‌های SVM با استفاده از ترکیب کلمات و شخصیت‌ها به عنوان ویژه‌های موجود شد. تیم ما، BMZ، اول از ۱۴ تیم در مسابقه رقابت قرار گرفته بود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaweza kuweka mbinu za usambazaji wa zana za patatibu kwa kutumia seti ya taarifa zilizotolewa na waandaaji wa jukumu la ALTA 2018 - Kutoa maombi ya Wagonjwa. Lengo la kazi ni kutumia mbinu za kompyuta za kugawanya matumizi ya patatibu kwa mujibu wa utamaduni wa kodi wa darasa nane kwa msingi wa Taifa la Kimataifa la Patients (IPC). Tulijaribu mbinu mbalimbali za kazi hii na matokeo bora zaidi, kwa wastani wa kipindi cha F1-0.778, yalifanikiwa na vifaa vya SVM kwa kutumia muunganiko wa maneno na wahusika kama sifa. Timu yetu, BMZ, ilitengenezwa kwanza miongoni mwa timu 14 katika mashindano hayo.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_am>በALTA 2018 አካባቢዎች ላይ የተሰናከረውን የዳታ ሳጥን በመጠቀም የፖስታ ፕሮግራሞች ማቀናቀፍ ሥርዓቶችን እናስቀምጣለን - መተላለፊያ ፕሮግራሞች እናስቀምጣለን፡፡ የስራው ጉዳዩ የዓለምአቀፍ Patent Classification (IPC) የተመሳሳይ ስምንት ክፍሎች የተመሳሳይ ፕሮግራሞች እንዲያካክሉ ቁጥጥር ማድረግ ነው፡፡ ለዚህ ስራ የተለየ መልዕክቶች እና የተሻለ ፍሬዎችን ሞከርን፤ 0.778 ሚክሮግራዊ F1-ነጥብ፣ የSVM ነጥቦች በንግግር እና የፊደሎችን አካባቢ በጥቅረት አግኝተዋል፡፡ የብኤምዘር ቡድሞቻችን አስቀድሞ 14 ጭፍሮች መካከል ተለይቷል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা প্যাটেন্ট অ্যাপ্লিকেশনের স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে পরিচিতির পদ্ধতি উপস্থাপন করি এলিটা ২০১৮ সালের প্রতিষ্ঠাতাদের দ্বারা প্রদান করা একটি বিস The goal of the task is to use computational methods to categorize patent applications according to a coarse-grained taxonomy of eight classes based on the International Patent Classification (IPC).  আমরা এই কাজের জন্য বিভিন্ন ধরনের উপায় পরীক্ষা করেছি এবং সেরা ফলাফল, ০. ৭৭৮ মাইক্রো স্কোর, এসভিএম এনসেম্পেল ব্যবহার করেছিলাম বৈশিষ্ট্য এবং অক্ষরের ব্ আমাদের দল বিএমজের প্রতিযোগিতায় প্রথম ১৪ টি দলের মধ্যে রান্না করা হয়েছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Predstavljamo metode za automatsku klasifikaciju patentnih aplikacija koristeći annotiranu kompletu podataka koju organizatori zajedničkog zadatka ALTA 2018-a pružaju klasifikaciju patentnih aplikacija. Cilj zadatka je koristiti računalne metode za kategoriju patenata u skladu s taksonomijom od osam klasa na temelju Međunarodne klasifikacije patenata (IPC). Testirali smo različite pristupe ovom zadatku i najbolje rezultate, 0,778 mikro-srednji F1-Score, postigli su SVM ensembli koristeći kombinaciju riječi i znakova kao karakteristike. Naš tim, BMZ, bio je prvi od 14 tima na konkurenciji.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim metoda për klasifikimin automatik të aplikacioneve të patentave duke përdorur një set të dhënash të anotuar të ofruar nga organizatorët e detyrës së përbashkët ALTA 2018 - Klasifikimi i aplikacioneve të patentave. Qëllimi i detyrës është të përdoret metoda llogaritëse për të kategorizuar aplikimet e patentave sipas një taksonomie të ngrohtë të tetë klasave bazuar në Klasifikimin Ndërkombëtar të Patent ëve (IPC). Ne testuam një shumicë metodash për këtë detyrë dhe rezultatet më të mira, 0.778 mikro-mesatare F1-Score, u arritën nga ansamblet SVM duke përdorur një kombinim fjalësh dhe karakteresh si karaktere. Our team, BMZ, was ranked first among 14 teams in the competition.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_ca>Presentam mètodes de classificació automàtica de les aplicacions de patents utilitzant un conjunt de dades anotats proporcionat pels organitzadors de la tasca compartida ALTA 2018 - Classificant les aplicacions de patents. L'objectiu de la tasca és utilitzar mètodes computacionals per categoritzar les aplicacions de patents segons una taxonomia grossa de vuit classes basada en la Classificació Internacional de Patents (IPC). Vam provar una varietat d'enfocaments per aquesta tasca i els millors resultats, 0,778 micro-mitjans de puntuació F1, van ser aconseguits pels conjunts SVM fent servir una combinació de paraules i caràcters com a característiques. El nostre equip, BMZ, va ser el primer entre 14 equips de la competició.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Tutvustame patenditaotluste automaatse klassifitseerimise meetodeid, kasutades ALTA 2018 jagatud ülesande - Patenditaotluste klassifitseerimine korraldajate antud märgitud andmekogumit. Ülesande eesmärk on kasutada arvutusmeetodeid patenditaotluste kategooriaks rahvusvahelise patendiklassifikatsiooni (IPC) alusel kaheksa klassi jämeda teralise taksonoomia järgi. Testisime selle ülesande jaoks erinevaid lähenemisviise ja parimad tulemused, 0,778 mikrokeskmist F1-skoori, saavutasid SVM ansamblid, kasutades sõnade ja tähemärkide kombinatsiooni funktsioonidena. Meie meeskond BMZ oli võistlusel 14 meeskonna seas esimene.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_hy>We present methods for the automatic classification of patent applications using an annotated dataset provided by the organizers of the ALTA 2018 shared task - Classifying Patent Applications.  Այս խնդրի նպատակն է օգտագործել հաշվարկների մեթոդներ, որպեսզի բացատրենք բացատրական ծրագրերը ըստ ութ դասարանների դասարանի դասակարգման, որը հիմնված է միջազգային բացատրական դասակարգման (IPC). Մենք փորձարկեցինք այս խնդրի համար տարբեր մոտեցումներ, և լավագույն արդյունքները, 0.778 միկրոմիջին F1-Սկորը, ստացվեցին ԱՎՄ-ի համակարգերի միջոցով՝ օգտագործելով բառերի և հերոսների համադրությունը որպես առանձնահատկություններ: Մեր թիմը, ԲՄԶ-ը, առաջինը դասակարգեց մրցակցության 14 թիմի մեջ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme metody automatické klasifikace patentových přihlášek pomocí anotovaného datového souboru poskytnutého organizátory sdíleného úkolu ALTA 2018 Klasifikace patentových přihlášek. Cílem práce je pomocí výpočetních metod kategorizovat patentové přihlášky podle hrubozrnné taxonomie osmi tříd založené na Mezinárodní patentové klasifikaci (IPC). Testovali jsme různé přístupy k tomuto úkolu a nejlepších výsledků, mikroprůměrné F1-skóre 0.778, byly dosaženy soubory SVM pomocí kombinace slov a znaků jako vlastností. Náš tým BMZ se v soutěži dostal na první místo mezi čtrnácti týmy.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Esittelemme menetelmiä patenttihakemusten automaattiseen luokitteluun käyttäen ALTA 2018 -yhteistehtävän – Patenttihakemusten luokittelun järjestämisen järjestäjien antamaa merkintäaineistoa. Työn tavoitteena on käyttää laskennallisia menetelmiä patenttihakemusten luokitteluun kansainvälisen patenttiluokituksen (IPC) perusteella kahdeksan luokan karkean taksonomian mukaisesti. Testasimme erilaisia lähestymistapoja tähän tehtävään ja parhaat tulokset, 0,778 mikrokeskiarvoa F1-pisteellä, saavutettiin SVM-kokoonpanoilla käyttäen sanoja ja merkkejä yhdistelmänä ominaisuuksia. Joukkueemme BMZ sijoittui ensimmäisenä 14 joukkueen joukossa kilpailussa.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_az>Biz patent proqramlarńĪn automatsk klasifikasyonu, ALTA 2018 paylaŇüdńĪrńĪlmńĪŇü iŇül…ôrin organizatorlarńĪ il…ô bildirilmiŇü veril…ôn quruluŇü vasit…ôsil…ô istifad…ô edirik. Bu iŇüin m…ôqs…ôdi, ńįptal Patent KlasifikasńĪna (IPC) dayanan sekiz sńĪnńĪf taxonomiyasńĪna g√∂r…ô patent proqramlarńĪnńĪ kategoriyasiyalamaq √ľ√ß√ľn hesaplama metodlarńĪnńĪ istifad…ô etm…ôkdir. Biz bu iŇüin m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôrzl…ôrini sńĪnańüa √ß…ôkdik v…ô …ôn yaxŇüńĪ sonu√ßlarńĪ, 0.778 mikro-ortalamalńĪ F1-Score, SVM ensembl…ôl…ôri s√∂zl…ôrin v…ô karakterl…ôrin birl…ôŇüdirilm…ôsini t…ôŇükil etdik. Bizim ekibimiz BMZ, m√ľharib…ôd…ô ilk d…ôf…ô 14 d…ôst…ôd…ô s…ôf verildi.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna ƙayyade shiryoyin ayukan shiryoyin ayukan ayukan ayuka na mutane da ke amfani da wani shirin da aka sanar da shi na shirin mai haɗa aikin AITA 2018 - Shirin Ayuka na Classify. Gagon aikin ni ne ya yi amfani da hanyoyin lissafi dõmin su rara shiryoyin ayuka masu shiryuwa da kuma a daidaita taxnomi na kurs takwas a kan IPC. Lalle ne, Mun jarraba wasu hanyõyi masu amfani da wannan aikin, kuma matsalan mafi kyaun matsayi, an cika 0.778 micro-score F1-score, kuma an sami SvM da komkoma da wasu kalmõmi da takardar da ke cikin haske. Ga jamiyarmu BMZ, an ranar ta farkon jama'a 14 a cikin shinin.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>אנחנו מציגים שיטות להקליטה אוטומטית של בקשות פטנטים באמצעות קבוצת נתונים מועטפת שנוספת על ידי המארגנים של המשימה המשותפת של ALTA 2018 - להקליט בקשות פטנטים. המטרה של המשימה היא להשתמש בשיטות מחשביות כדי לקטגוריה ביקשות פטנטים לפי טקסונומיה עצומה של שמונה כיסות מבוססת על קליфікаציה בינלאומית של פטנטים (IPC). We tested a variety of approaches for this task and the best results, 0.778 micro-averaged F1-Score, were achieved by SVM ensembles using a combination of words and characters as features.  הצוות שלנו, BMZ, היה ראשון בין 14 קבוצות בתחרות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo metode avtomatske klasifikacije patentnih prijav z uporabo označenih podatkovnih nizov organizatorjev skupne naloge ALTA 2018 – Klasifikacija patentnih prijav. Cilj naloge je uporaba računalniških metod za kategorizacijo patentnih prijav po grobo zrnati taksonomiji osmih razredov, ki temelji na Mednarodni patentni klasifikaciji (IPC). Preizkusili smo različne pristope za to nalogo in najboljše rezultate, 0,778 mikropovprečnega F1-Score, so dosegli zasedbe SVM s kombinacijo besed in znakov kot funkcije. Naša ekipa, BMZ, je bila uvrščena na prvo mesto med 14 ekipami na tekmovanju.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé éntuk sistem kanggo nggawe sistem automatik kanggo aplikasi paten sing digawe dataset nggawe barang nggawe ngubah akeh barang nggawe barang akeh Alta 2020 'ndaftar nggawe task - goal Awak dhéwé énesten akeh sampeyan kanggo nggawe nggawe lan akeh barêng-barêng, 0. Awakmu dhéwé, EMZ, lak sawetara tualke sampeyan 14 sing mesthi nang patimbang.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་རང་འགུལ་གྱིས་patent ཉེར་སྤྱོད་ཀྱི་དབྱེ་རིམ་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་སྤྱོད་ནས་གསལ་བཤད་ཡོད་པའི་གནད་སྡུད་རྣམ་པ་ སྤྱད་རྣམ་གྲངས་སྒྲིག་ དམིགས་ཡུལ་ནི་རྩིས་འཁོར་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་སྤྱོད་པ་དེ་གནད་དོན་རྙིགས་སྤྱོད་ཀྱི་རྩིས་རྩིས་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་སྤྱོད་ནང་། We tested a variety of approaches for this task and the best results, 0.778 micro-averaged F1-Score, were achieved by SVM ensembles using a combination of words and characters as features. ང་ཚོའི་མཁའ་དབུགས་BMZ་འདི་རྒྱལ་སྤྱིའི་དོན་ལས་ཀྱང་ཆེན་༡༤་ནང་གི་སྔོན་འཛུགས་ཡོད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Universal Language Model Fine-tuning for Patent Classification</title>
      <author><first>Jason</first><last>Hepburn</last></author>
      <pages>93–96</pages>
      <url hash="5e044eeb">U18-1013</url>
      <abstract>This paper describes the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> used for the 2018 ALTA Shared Task. The task this year was to automatically classify <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Australian_patent_law">Australian patents</a> into their main International Patent Classification section. Our final submission used a Support Vector Machine (SVM) and Universal Language Model with Fine-tuning (ULMFiT). Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> achieved the best results in the student category.</abstract>
      <bibkey>hepburn-2018-universal</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>