<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2019.lilt">
  <volume id="17">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Linguistic Issues in Language Technology, Volume 17, 2019</booktitle>
      <publisher>CSLI Publications</publisher>
      <year>2019</year>
    </meta>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Argument alternations in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complex_predicate">complex predicates</a> : an LFG+glue perspective<fixed-case>LFG</fixed-case>+glue perspective</title>
      <author><first>John J.</first><last>Lowe</last></author>
      <abstract>Vaidya et al. (2019) discuss argument alternations in Hindi complex predicates, and propose an analysis within an LTAG framework, comparing this with an LFG analysis of complex predicates. In this paper I clarify the inadequacies in existing LFG analyses of complex predicates, and show how the LFG+glue approach proposed by Lowe (2015) can both address these inadequacies and provide a relatively simple treatment of the phenomena discussed by Vaidya et al.</abstract>
      <issue>2</issue>
      <url hash="72b6155f">2019.lilt-17.2</url>
      <bibkey>lowe-2019-argument</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Complex predicates : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structure">Structure</a>, potential structure and underspecification</title>
      <author><first>Stefan</first><last>Müller</last></author>
      <abstract>This paper compares a recent TAG-based analysis of complex predicates in Hindi / Urdu with its HPSG analog. It points out that TAG combines actual structure while HPSG (and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Categorial_grammar">Categorial Grammar</a> and other valence-based frameworks) specify valence of lexical items and hence potential structure. This makes it possible to have light verbs decide which arguments of embedded heads get realized, somthing that is not possible in TAG. TAG has to retreat to disjunctions instead. While this allows straight-forward analyses of active / passive alternations based on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_verb">light verb</a> in valence-based frameworks, such an option does not exist for TAG and it has to be assumed that preverbs come with different sets of arguments.</abstract>
      <issue>3</issue>
      <url hash="c763c515">2019.lilt-17.3</url>
      <bibkey>muller-2019-complex</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Complex Predicates and Multidimensionality in Grammar</title>
      <author><first>Miriam</first><last>Butt</last></author>
      <abstract>This paper contributes to the on-going discussion of how best to analyze and handle complex predicate formations, commenting in particular on the properties of Hindi N-V complex predicates as set out by Vaidya et al. I highlight features of existing LFG analyses and focus in particular on the modular architecture of LFG, its attendant multidimensional lexicon and the analytic consequences which follow from this. I point out where the previously existing LFG proposals have been misunderstood as viewed from the lens of theories such as LTAG and HPSG, which assume a very different architectural set-up and provide a comparative discussion of the issues.</abstract>
      <issue>4</issue>
      <url hash="ebab151e">2019.lilt-17.4</url>
      <bibkey>butt-2019-complex</bibkey>
    <title_ar>المسندات المعقدة وتعدد الأبعاد في القواعد</title_ar>
      <title_es>Predicados complejos y multidimensionalidad en gramática</title_es>
      <title_pt>Predicados Complexos e Multidimensionalidade na Gramática</title_pt>
      <title_ja>文法における複雑な述語と多次元性</title_ja>
      <title_zh>语法中杂谓词多维性</title_zh>
      <title_hi>व्याकरण में जटिल Predicates और बहुआयामीता</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Réamhthuartha Coimpléascacha agus Iltoiseachacht sa Ghramadach</title_ga>
      <title_el>Πολύπλοκα προκαθορισμένα και πολυδιάστατη στη γραμματική</title_el>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Komplex előrejelzések és többdimenziós nyelvtan</title_hu>
      <title_kk>Грамматтың толық бөлшектері мен көпөлшемдері</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Sudėtingos prognozės ir daugiapakopis grafikas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Комплексни предикати и мултидимензионалност во грама</title_mk>
      <title_it>Predicati complessi e multidimensionalità in grammatica</title_it>
      <title_ml>ഗ്രാമാരിലെ കോമ്പ്ലെക്സ് പ്രിഡിക്റ്റേറ്റുകളും പല ഡിമിഷനേഷനിറ്റിയും</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Томъёогүй хэмжээсүүд болон олон хэмжээсүүд</title_mn>
      <title_ms>Complex Predicates and Multidimensionality in Grammar</title_ms>
      <title_pl>Złożone predykaty i wielowymiarowość w gramatyce</title_pl>
      <title_no>Komplekt foredikt og fledimensjonalitet i grammar</title_no>
      <title_ro>Predicate complexe și multidimensionalitate în gramatică</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Kompleks predikati i multidimenzionalnost u Grammaru</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>Qorshaha tababarka</title_so>
      <title_sv>Komplexa förutsägelser och flerdimensionell grammatik</title_sv>
      <title_ur>Name</title_ur>
      <title_ta>வரிசையில் சிக்கல் முன்னுரிமைகள் மற்றும் பல்பரிமாணப்படுத்தல்</title_ta>
      <title_mt>Predikati kumplessi u Multidimensjonalità fil-Grammar</title_mt>
      <title_uz>Comment</title_uz>
      <title_vi>KCharselect unicode block name</title_vi>
      <title_da>Komplekse forudsætninger og multidimensionalitet i grammatik</title_da>
      <title_de>Komplexe Prädikate und Multidimensionalität in der Grammatik</title_de>
      <title_bg>Комплексни предшественици и многоизмерност в граматиката</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Complexe predicaten en multidimensionaliteit in grammatica</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Kompleksi predikati i multidimenzionalnost u Grammaru</title_hr>
      <title_ko>복잡한 술어와 문법의 다차원성</title_ko>
      <title_fa>پیشنهاد پیچیده و تعداد زیادی در گرم</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Grammar</title_tr>
      <title_af>Kompleks voordekens en Multidimensionaliteit in Grammar</title_af>
      <title_id>Predikasi Kompleks dan Multidimensionalitas dalam Grammar</title_id>
      <title_sq>Parashikimet komplekse dhe shumëdimensionaliteti në grammë</title_sq>
      <title_am>ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_hy>Բազմաչափ կանխատեսումներ և գրամամայում</title_hy>
      <title_bn>গ্রামারের কমপ্লেক্স প্রিডিকেট এবং বহুমাত্রিকভাবে</title_bn>
      <title_az>Grammar'da kompleks Predikt və Multidimensionality</title_az>
      <title_bs>Kompleksi predikati i multidimenzionalnost u Grammaru</title_bs>
      <title_sw>Tamko la Complex</title_sw>
      <title_ca>Predicats complexes i multidimensionalitat en grama</title_ca>
      <title_et>Keerukad ennustused ja mitmemõõtmelisus grammatikas</title_et>
      <title_cs>Komplexní predikáty a multidimenzionalita v gramatice</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Moniulotteisuus kieliopissa ja moniulotteisuus</title_fi>
      <title_jv>politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>מוקדמות מורכבות ומדיות רבות בגרמה</title_he>
      <title_sk>Kompleksni predikati in večdimenzionalnost v slovnici</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Grammar ནང་དུ་ཚོར་བ་སྔོན་སྒྲིག་ཆ་དང་ཆེ་རུང་དག</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تساهم هذه الورقة في المناقشة الجارية حول أفضل السبل لتحليل والتعامل مع تكوينات المسند المعقدة ، والتعليق بشكل خاص على خصائص المسندات المعقدة الهندية N-V على النحو المنصوص عليه من قبل Vaidya et al. (2019). ألقي الضوء على ميزات تحليلات LFG الحالية وأركز بشكل خاص على البنية المعيارية لـ LFG ، ومعجمها متعدد الأبعاد المصاحب والنتائج التحليلية التي تلي ذلك. أشير إلى حيث أسيء فهم مقترحات LFG الموجودة سابقًا كما يُنظر إليها من منظور نظريات مثل LTAG و HPSG ، والتي تفترض تكوينًا معماريًا مختلفًا للغاية وتوفر مناقشة مقارنة للقضايا.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo contribui para a discussão em curso sobre a melhor forma de analisar e lidar com formações de predicados complexos, comentando em particular sobre as propriedades dos predicados complexos Hindi N-V, conforme estabelecido por Vaidya et al. (2019). Destaco características das análises de LFG existentes e foco em particular na arquitetura modular do LFG, seu léxico multidimensional e as consequências analíticas que se seguem disso. Aponto onde as propostas de LFG anteriormente existentes foram mal compreendidas, vistas a partir das lentes de teorias como LTAG e HPSG, que assumem uma configuração arquitetônica muito diferente e fornecem uma discussão comparativa das questões.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo contribuye a la discusión en curso sobre la mejor manera de analizar y manejar las formaciones de predicados complejos, comentando en particular las propiedades de los predicados del complejo N-V en hindi según lo establecido por Vaidya et al. (2019). Destaco las características de los análisis LFG existentes y me centro en particular en la arquitectura modular de LFG, su léxico multidimensional concomitante y las consecuencias analíticas que se derivan de ello. Señalo dónde las propuestas LFG existentes anteriormente se han malinterpretado desde el punto de vista de teorías como LTAG y HPSG, que asumen una configuración arquitectónica muy diferente y proporcionan una discusión comparativa de los problemas.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_zh>本文最善析理杂谓词之论,特Vaidya等(2019)印地语N-V杂谓词之论也。 余调今LFG析之性,特关LFG之模块化架构,随之多维词典及由此生者也。 余指前所存LFG提案误解为LTAG、HPSG诸论,假设殊架构,较之讨论。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ja>この論文は、複雑な述語形成を分析し、処理する最善の方法についての現在進行中の議論に貢献しており、特にVaidya et al .( 2019)が述べたヒンディー語N - V複雑述語の性質についてコメントしている。既存のLFG分析の特徴を強調し、特にLFGのモジュールアーキテクチャ、それに伴う多次元辞書、およびそれに続く分析結果に焦点を当てています。以前に存在したLFGの提案が、LTAGやHPSGのような非常に異なるアーキテクチャ設定を前提とし、課題の比較考察を提供する理論のレンズから見たものと誤解されている箇所を指摘する。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर इस बात की चल रही चर्चा में योगदान देता है कि जटिल विधेय संरचनाओं का विश्लेषण और संभालना सबसे अच्छा कैसे है, विशेष रूप से हिंदी एन-वी जटिल विधेय के गुणों पर टिप्पणी करता है जैसा कि वैद्य एट अल द्वारा निर्धारित किया गया है। मैं मौजूदा एलएफजी विश्लेषण की विशेषताओं को उजागर करता हूं और विशेष रूप से एलएफजी के मॉड्यूलर आर्किटेक्चर, इसके परिचर बहुआयामी शब्दकोश और विश्लेषणात्मक परिणामों पर ध्यान केंद्रित करता हूं जो इससे अनुसरण करते हैं। मैं इंगित करता हूं कि पहले से मौजूद एलएफजी प्रस्तावों को गलत समझा गया है जैसा कि एलटीएजी और एचपीएसजी जैसे सिद्धांतों के लेंस से देखा गया है, जो एक बहुत ही अलग वास्तुशिल्प सेट-अप मानते हैं और मुद्दों की तुलनात्मक चर्चा प्रदान करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cuidíonn an páipéar seo leis an bplé leanúnach ar conas is fearr anailís a dhéanamh ar fhoirmíochtaí casta tuartha agus iad a láimhseáil, ag trácht go háirithe ar airíonna réamh-mheastacháin choimpléascacha Hindi NV mar atá leagtha amach ag Vaidya et al. (2019). Tarraingím aird ar ghnéithe na n-anailísí LFG atá ann cheana féin agus dírím go háirithe ar ailtireacht mhodúlach LFG, an foclóir iltoiseach a ghabhann leis agus na hiarmhairtí anailíse a leanann as seo. Tugaim aird ar na háiteanna ina ndearnadh míthuiscint ar na tograí LFG a bhí ann cheana mar a fheictear ó lionsa na dteoiricí ar nós LTAG agus HPSG, a ghlacann le leagan amach ailtireachta an-difriúil agus a sholáthraíonn plé comparáideach ar na saincheisteanna.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ეს დოკუმენტი დამატებით, როგორ საუკეთესო განსაზღვრება და გამოყენება კომპლექსიკური ფორმაციების განსაზღვრება, განსაზღვრებით ინდი N-V კომპლექსიკური პრედიკატების განსაზღვრებაზე,  მე აღწერს მსგავსი LFG ანალიზების განსაზღვრებების და განსაზღვრებული LFG-ის მოდულური აქტიქტიქტურის, მისი მრავალეთემენტიური ლექსიკონის და ანალიზიკური შედეგების განსაზღვ მე აჩვენებს, სადაც მხოლოდ არსებობს LFG პროგრამები, როგორც აჩვენებულია ტერიოების ლენსიდან, როგორც LTAG და HPSG, რომლებიც ძალიან განსხვავებული არქიტექტური შესაძლებლობა და შესაძლებელია კომპორაციული გან</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία συμβάλλει στη συνεχιζόμενη συζήτηση σχετικά με τον καλύτερο τρόπο ανάλυσης και χειρισμού πολύπλοκων σχηματισμών προδικαστικών στοιχείων, σχολιάζοντας ειδικότερα τις ιδιότητες των συνθηκών συμπλοκών των Χίντι όπως ορίζονται από τον κ.λ. (2019). Επισημαίνομαι χαρακτηριστικά των υφιστάμενων αναλύσεων και επικεντρώνομαι ειδικότερα στην αρθρωτή αρχιτεκτονική του, το αντίστοιχο πολυδιάστατο λεξικό και τις αναλυτικές συνέπειες που προκύπτουν από αυτό. Επισημαίνομαι όπου οι προηγούμενες προτάσεις των LFG έχουν παρεξηγηθεί ως προς το πρίσμα θεωριών όπως LTAG και HPSG, οι οποίες υποθέτουν μια πολύ διαφορετική αρχιτεκτονική δομή και παρέχουν μια συγκριτική συζήτηση των ζητημάτων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a tanulmány hozzájárul ahhoz a folyamatban lévő vitához, hogy miként lehet a legjobban elemezni és kezelni komplex predikátumokat, különösen a Vaidya et al. (2019) által meghatározott hindi N-V komplex predikátumok tulajdonságait. Kiemelem a meglévő LFG elemzések jellemzőit, és különösen az LFG moduláris architektúrájára, annak többdimenziós lexikonjára és az ebből következő analitikai következményekre összpontosítok. Rámutatok arra, hogy a korábban meglévő LFG javaslatokat félreértették az olyan elméletek lencséjéből, mint az LTAG és a HPSG, amelyek nagyon eltérő építészeti felépítést feltételeznek és összehasonlító vitát nyújtanak a kérdésekről.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo contribuisce alla discussione in corso su come analizzare e gestire al meglio le formazioni predicate complesse, commentando in particolare le proprietà dei predicati complessi N-V hindi come definiti da Vaidya et al. (2019). Sottolineo le caratteristiche delle analisi esistenti di LFG e mi concentro in particolare sull'architettura modulare di LFG, il relativo lessico multidimensionale e le conseguenze analitiche che ne derivano. Sottolineo dove le proposte di LFG precedentemente esistenti sono state fraintese come viste dalla lente di teorie come LTAG e HPSG, che assumono un assetto architettonico molto diverso e forniscono una discussione comparativa dei problemi.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз Vaidya et al. (2019) бағдарламасының индий N-V комплексті предикаттардың қасиеттері туралы жақсы пішімдерді анализ және қалай жақсы пішімдерді қалай басқаруға көмектеседі. Мен бар LFG анализацияларының мүмкіндіктерін таңдап, осындай-ақ LFG модульдер архитектурасына, оның қатысушыларының көп өлшемді лексиканы және оның аналитикалық нәтижелерін таңдап көр Бірінші LFG ұсыныстары LTAG және HPSG секілді теориялардың линзиясынан қайта түсініп, олар архитектуралық орнатылып, мәселелерді салыстыру үшін қайта түсінілген.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>This paper contributes to the on-going discussion of how best to analyze and handle complex predicate formations, commenting in particular on the properties of Hindi N-V complex predicates as set out by Vaidya et al. (2019).  Ги истакнувам карактеристиките на постојните анализи на ЛФГ и се фокусирам особено на модуларната архитектура на ЛФГ, нејзиниот присуствен мултидимензионален лексикон и аналитичките последици кои следат од ова. Јас истакнувам каде претходно постоечките предлози за ЛФГ се погрешно разбрани како што се гледаат од lenteта на теориите како што се ЛТАГ и ХПСГ, кои претпоставуваат многу различна архитектурна поставка и обезбедуваат споредлива дискусија за прашањата.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Šis dokumentas prisideda prie nuolatinės diskusijos, kaip geriausiai analizuoti ir tvarkyti sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas sudėtingas Pabrėžiu esamų LFG analizių ypatumus ir ypač dėmesį skiriau modulinei LFG architektūrai, jos dalyvaujančiam daugiametiam lexikonui ir iš to kylantiems analitiniams padariniams. Noriu atkreipti dėmesį į tai, kad anksčiau galiojantys LFG pasiūlymai buvo neteisingai suprasti, kaip matyti iš tokių teorijų, kaip LTAG ir HPSG, kurie turi labai skirtingą architektūrinę struktūrą ir teikia lyginamąją diskusiją apie klausimus.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തിന്റെ പേപ്പ് വായിദ്യാ എറ്റ് അല്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നതിന്റെ പ്രത്യേകിച്ച് വിശ്വസിച്ചിരിക്കുന്ന ഹിന്ദി N-V പ്രശ്നങ്ങളുടെ പ്രശ് നിലവിലുള്ള LFG അന്വേഷണങ്ങളുടെ വിശേഷതകള്‍ ഞാന്‍ പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. പ്രത്യേകിച്ച് ലെഫ്ജിയുടെ സ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ ശ്രദ്ധിക്കുന്നു മുമ്പുണ്ടായിരുന്ന LFG പ്രായണങ്ങള്‍ എവിടെയാണ് തെറ്റായി മനസ്സിലാക്കിയിരിക്കുന്നതെന്ന് ഞാന്‍ പറയുന്നു. എല്‍ടാജിയും ഹെപ്പിസിജിയും പോലുള്ള തിയോറികള</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jikkontribwixxi għad-diskussjoni li għaddejja dwar kif l-aħjar jiġu analizzati u mmaniġġjati formazzjonijiet predikati kumplessi, billi jikkummenta b’mod partikolari dwar il-karatteristiċi tal-predikati kumplessi N-V Indjani kif stabbiliti minn Vaidya et al. (2019). Jiena tenfasizza l-karatteristiċi tal-analiżi eżistenti tal-LFG u niffoka b’mod partikolari fuq l-arkitettura modulari tal-LFG, il-lexicon multidimensjonali tiegħu u l-konsegwenzi analitiċi li ġejjin minn dan. Jiena ninnota fejn il-proposti eżistenti preċedentement tal-LFG ġew mifhuma ħa żin kif meqjusa mil-lenti ta’ teoriji bħall-LTAG u l-HPSG, li jassumu struttura arkitettonika differenti ħafna u jipprovdu diskussjoni komparattiva tal-kwistjonijiet.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Kertas ini menyumbangkan kepada perbincangan yang sedang berlangsung tentang bagaimana terbaik untuk menganalisis dan mengendalikan formasi predikat kompleks, berkomentar terutama tentang ciri-ciri predikat N-V kompleks Hindi seperti yang ditetapkan oleh Vaidya et al. (2019). Saya menyatakan ciri-ciri analisis LFG yang ada dan fokus terutama pada arkitektur modular LFG, leksikon berbilang dimensi yang hadir dan konsekuensi analitik yang muncul dari ini. Saya menunjukkan di mana cadangan LFG yang terdapat sebelumnya telah salah faham seperti dipandang dari lens a teori seperti LTAG dan HPSG, yang menganggap seting arkitektur yang sangat berbeza dan menyediakan perbandingan perbandingan isu-isu.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret bidrar til diskusjonen om korleis best å analysere og handtere komplekse predikat formateringar, som kommentarer spesielt om eigenskapane til hindiske N-V komplekse predikatar som er sett av Vaidya et al. (2019). Eg markerer funksjonar for eksisterande LFG-analyser og fokuserer spesielt på modulararkitekturen av LFG, deltakaren sin multidimensjonal leksikon og analyske konsekvensar som følgjer frå dette. Eg viser kor dei førre eksisterande LFG-forslag har misforstått som viste frå lensen av teorier som LTAG og HPSG, som antar eit svært anna arkitektursoppsett og gjer ei sammenlignbare diskusjon om problemene.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł przyczynia się do toczącej się dyskusji na temat sposobu najlepszej analizy i obsługi złożonych formacji predykatów predykatów złożonych N-V, komentując w szczególności właściwości predykatów złożonych w Hindi, określonych przez Vaidya et al. (2019). Podkreślam cechy istniejących analiz LFG i skupiam się w szczególności na modułowej architekturze LFG, związanej z nim wielowymiarowym leksykonie oraz konsekwencjach analitycznych, jakie z tego wynikają. Wskazuję, gdzie istniejące wcześniej propozycje LFG zostały źle zrozumiane z perspektywy teorii takich jak LTAG i HPSG, które zakładają zupełnie odmienną strukturę architektoniczną i zapewniają porównawczą dyskusję na te kwestie.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare contribuie la discuția continuă despre modul în care se analizează și se gestionează cel mai bine formațiunile predicate complexe, comentând în special proprietățile predicatelor complexe N-V hindi așa cum sunt stabilite de Vaidya et al. (2019). Evidențiez caracteristicile analizelor existente ale LFG și mă concentrez în special pe arhitectura modulară a LFG, pe lexiconul multidimensional asociat acestuia și pe consecințele analitice care rezultă din aceasta. Subliniez în cazul în care propunerile existente anterior LFG au fost înțelese greșit privind din lentilele teoriilor precum LTAG și HPSG, care presupun o configurație arhitecturală foarte diferită și oferă o discuție comparativă a problemelor.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас нь Vaidya et al-д гаргасан хинди N-V комплекс хэлбэрийн шинжлэх ухааны талаар хэрхэн хамгийн сайн талаар шинжлэх, удирдлагатай талаар ярилцдаг. Би суурилсан LFG шинжилгээний тодорхойлолтуудыг тайлбарлаж, ялангуяа LFG-ийн модуль архитектурын тухай анхаарлаа төвлөрүүлж, олон хэмжээст хэмжээст лексикон болон энэ дараагийн шинжилгээний үр дүн дээр анхаар Би өмнө байгаа LFG зөвлөгөө нь LTAG болон HPSG зэрэг теорийн линзийн хувьд буруу ойлгомжтой байсан бөгөөд энэ нь маш өөр архитектур зохион байгуулалт гэж үздэг бөгөөд асуудлын харьцуулалт гаргадаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir doprinosi na nastavku rasprave o tome kako je najbolje analizirati i rešiti kompleksne predikatne formacije, komentarajući posebno na vlasništva indijskih N-V kompleksnih predikata kao što je navela Vaidya et al. (2019). Oslanjam karakteristike postojećih analiza LFG-a i fokusiram se posebno na modularnu arhitekturu LFG-a, njezinu prisustvovačku multidimenzionalnu leksikonu i analitičke posledice koje slijede od ovoga. Pokazujem gde su prethodno postojeći prijedlogi LFG pogrešno shvaćeni kao što su pogrešno shvaćeni iz lens a teorija poput LTAG i HPSG-a, koji preduzimaju veoma različite arhitekturološke uspostave i pružaju komparativnu diskusiju o pitanjima.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ පැත්තේ ප්‍රයෝජනය විශ්ලේෂණය සහ ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න හොඳම විශ්ලේෂණය සහ ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න ප්‍රයෝජනය සඳහා ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා, විශේෂයෙන් හ මම තියෙන්නේ LFG විශ්ලේෂණය සහ විශේෂයෙන් අවධානය කරනවා LFG ගේ මොඩියෝලාර් ස්ථාපනය, ඒ ගැන අංශ්‍ය විශේෂණය සහ විශේ මම ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙනවා කොහෙද ඉඳලා තියෙන්නේ LFG ප්‍රශ්නයක් වැරැද්දක් තියෙන්නේ LTAG සහ HPSG වගේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් වගේ ලෙන්ස් වලින් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වගේ ප</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats bidrar till den pågående diskussionen om hur man bäst kan analysera och hantera komplexa predikatformationer, och kommenterar särskilt egenskaperna hos hindi N-V komplex predikat enligt Vaidya et al. (2019). Jag lyfter fram egenskaper hos befintliga LFG-analyser och fokuserar särskilt på LFG:s modulära arkitektur, dess tillhörande flerdimensionella lexikon och de analytiska konsekvenser som följer av detta. Jag vill påpeka var de tidigare befintliga LFG-förslagen missförståtts utifrån teorier som LTAG och HPSG, som antar en helt annan arkitektonisk struktur och ger en jämförande diskussion om frågorna.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Warqaddaas ayaa ka faa’iidaysa baaritaanka sii socda sida aad ugu wanaagsan u baaritaan oo aad u qabsato noocyada adag ee la xiriiray, si gaar ah oo ku saabsan xuquuqda dhibaatada ku saabsan ee uu qoray Vaidya et al (2019). Waxaan tusaa baaritaanka LFG ee joogta iyo si gaar ah ugu fiirsanayaa dhismaha qaabilsan ee LFG, kaas oo ka mid ah lexicon multidimensional iyo dhammaadka analyada ee ka soo socda. Waxaan fiirsanayaa meeshii horay la soo jeeday proposals LFG oo hore lagu khiyaaneeyey oo laga fiiriyey tiyaatarada, tusaale ahaan LTAG iyo HPSG, taasoo u malaynaya dhismo kale oo aad u kala duduwan oo ay sameynayso su'aalaha kala duduwan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதம் எவ்வாறு சிக்கல் முன்கூறு வடிவமைப்புகளை ஆய்வு மற்றும் கையாள வேண்டும் என்பதை எவ்வாறு சிறந்த விவாட்டியா மற்றும் அல் அமைத்து வைத்திருக்கு நான் இருக்கும் LFG ஆய்வுகள் மற்றும் குறிப்பாக LFG கட்டுப்பாட்டின் மாதிரியில் கவனத்தை முன்னிலைப்படுத்துகிறேன், அதன் பங்கீட்டு பல்வேறு  நான் குறிப்பிடுகிறேன் முந்தைய இருக்கும் LFG பரிந்துரைகள் தவறாக புரிந்து கொண்டிருக்கிறது LTAG மற்றும் HPSG போன்ற திட்டங்களிலிருந்து பார்க்கப்பட்டு</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>یہ کاغذ چلنے والے بحث کی حفاظت میں سزاوار ہے کہ کس طرح بہترین تحلیل اور تحلیل کرنا چاہے، اور مخصوصاً ہندی N-V complex predicates کے خصوصے پر مطلب کرنا چاہے، جیسے Vaidya et al (2019) کے ذریعہ مقرر کیا گیا ہے۔ میں نے موجود LFG تحقیقات اور مخصوصا LFG کے موڈولر معماری پر تمرکز کیا ہے، اس کے موجود multidimensional lexicon اور اس کی تحقیقات کے نتائج پر۔ مجھے اشارہ کرتا ہے کہ پہلے موجود LFG پیشنهادوں کو غلط سمجھا گیا ہے جیسے LTAG اور HPSG کے لینز سے دیکھا گیا ہے، جو ایک بہت مختلف معماری سازی سمجھتے ہیں اور مسائل کے مقابلہ میں ایک مقابلہ بحث دیتے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu qogʻoz Vaidya et al (2019) tomonidan boshlangan murakkablar formatlarini aniqlash va boshqarish uchun yaxshi taʼminlovchiga ega bo'ladi. Men mavjud LFG analyzerlarini ko'rsatmoqchiman va ammo LFG'ning modulyasi arxituvchisi, uning bir multidimensional leksisini va bu yerdan keladigan analytika natijalariga foydalanaman. Bu yerda oldingi mavjud LFG proposals misol qilingan, LTAG va HPSG kabi nazarlaridan ko'rinishga tushunmagan, bu muammolar haqida juda boshqa muammolar tuzilishini anglatadi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này góp phần vào cuộc thảo luận về cách phân tích và xử lý giải pháp khó khăn phức tạp nhất, bình luận đặc biệt về tính chất của giai đoạn khó khăn phức tạp của Hindi N-V, như được phỏng vấn bởi Vaidya et al. Tôi nhấn mạnh tính chất của các phân tích LFG hiện tại và tập trung vào cấu trúc theo chế độ theo chiều theo LFG, từ ngôn ngữ đa chiều liên tiếp của nó và kết quả phân tích sau nó. Tôi chỉ ra nơi mà những đề nghị LFG trước đây đã bị hiểu lầm theo góc độ của các giả thuyết như LPGG, cho rằng họ có một cấu trúc kiến trúc rất khác nhau và tổ chức một cuộc thảo luận tương đối về các vấn đề.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel draagt bij aan de lopende discussie over hoe complexe predicaatformaties het beste kunnen worden geanalyseerd en behandeld, waarbij met name wordt ingegaan op de eigenschappen van Hindi N-V complexe predicaten zoals uiteengezet door Vaidya et al. (2019). Ik belicht kenmerken van bestaande LFG-analyses en richt me in het bijzonder op de modulaire architectuur van LFG, het bijbehorende multidimensionale lexicon en de analytische gevolgen die hieruit voortvloeien. Ik wijs erop dat de eerder bestaande LFG-voorstellen verkeerd zijn begrepen vanuit de lens van theorieën als LTAG en HPSG, die een heel andere architecturale opzet aannemen en een vergelijkende discussie over de kwesties bieden.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel bidrager til den igangværende diskussion af, hvordan man bedst analyserer og håndterer komplekse prædikatformationer, og kommenterer især egenskaberne af Hindi N-V komplekse prædikater som beskrevet af Vaidya et al. (2019). Jeg fremhæver træk ved eksisterende LFG-analyser og fokuserer især på LFG's modulære arkitektur, dets tilhørende multidimensionale leksikon og de analytiske konsekvenser heraf. Jeg gør opmærksom på, hvor de tidligere eksisterende LFG-forslag er blevet misforstået set ud fra teorier som LTAG og HPSG, der antager en meget anderledes arkitektonisk opsætning og giver en sammenlignende diskussion af spørgsmålene.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>Тази статия допринася за текущата дискусия за това как най-добре да се анализират и обработват сложни предикатни образувания, коментирайки по-специално свойствата на хинди Н-В комплекс предикати, както са изложени от Вайдя и др. (2019). Подчертавам характеристиките на съществуващите анализи и се фокусирам по-специално върху модулната архитектура на ЛФГ, придружаващия го многоизмерен лексикон и аналитичните последици, които произтичат от това. Посочвам случаите, в които досега съществуващите предложения за ЛФГ са били погрешно разбрани от гледна точка на теории като LTAG и HPSG, които приемат много различна архитектурна структура и осигуряват сравнително обсъждане на проблемите.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir doprinosi na nastavku rasprave o tome kako je najbolje analizirati i riješiti kompleksne predikatne formacije, komentarati posebno o o svojstvima indijskih N-V kompleksnih predikata kako je navedena Vaidya et al. (2019). Osjećam karakteristike postojećih analiza LFG-a i fokusiram se posebno na modularnu arhitekturu LFG-a, njezinu prisustvovačku multidimenzionalnu leksikonu i analitičke posljedice koje slijede od ovoga. Pokazujem gdje su prethodno postojeći prijedlogi LFG pogrešno shvaćeni kao što su gledani iz lens a teorija poput LTAG i HPSG-a, koji preduzimaju veoma različite arhitekturološke uspostave i pružaju usporednu diskusiju o pitanjima.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ به بحث ادامه می دهد که چگونه بهترین برای تحلیل و کنترل شکل پیچیده‌های پیچیده‌ای است، با توجه به ویدیا و الی، ویژه‌ای از ویدیا و الی‌های پیچیده‌های پیچیده‌های هندی N-V توصیف می‌کند. من ویژگی‌هایی از تحلیل LFG موجود را مشخص می‌کنم و مخصوصاً تمرکز می‌کنم روی معماری مدول LFG، زبان‌های متعددی و نتایج‌های تحلیل که از آن پیروی می‌کنند. من مشخص می‌کنم که پیشنهاد LFG پیش از این به طور اشتباه درک شده‌اند که از لینک نظریه‌های مانند LTAG و HPSG نگاه شده‌اند، که یک ساختمان معماری بسیار متفاوت می‌گیرند و یک بحث مقایسه‌ای از مسائل را پیشنهاد می‌دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 복잡한 술어의 형성을 어떻게 가장 잘 분석하고 처리하는지, 특히 바디야 등(2019)이 제기한 인도어 N-V 복잡한 술어의 성질을 계속 토론하는 데 도움이 된다.나는 기존 LFG 분석의 특징을 강조하고 특히 LFG의 모듈화 체계 구조, 그에 수반되는 다차원 어휘와 이로 인해 발생하는 분석 결과를 주목했다.나는 LTAG와 HPSG 등 이론의 관점에서 이전에 존재했던 LFG 제안이 오해된 부분을 지적하는데 이런 이론들은 매우 다른 구조 설정을 가설하고 이런 문제들을 비교 토론했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag trägt zur laufenden Diskussion darüber bei, wie man komplexe Prädikatformationen am besten analysieren und handhaben kann, indem er insbesondere die Eigenschaften von Hindi N-V Komplexprädikaten kommentiert, wie sie von Vaidya et al. (2019) dargelegt wurden. Ich beleuchte Merkmale bestehender LFG-Analysen und konzentriere mich insbesondere auf die modulare Architektur von LFG, das dazugehörige mehrdimensionale Lexikon und die daraus resultierenden analytischen Konsequenzen. Ich weise darauf hin, dass die bisher bestehenden LFG-Vorschläge aus der Perspektive von Theorien wie LTAG und HPSG missverstanden wurden, die eine sehr unterschiedliche architektonische Aufstellung voraussetzen und eine vergleichende Diskussion der Fragestellungen ermöglichen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>This paper contributes to the on-going discussion of how best to analyze and handle complex predicate formations, commenting in particular on the properties of Hindi N-V complex predicates as set out by Vaidya et al. (2019).  Saya memperhatikan ciri-ciri dari analisis LFG yang ada dan fokus terutama pada arsitektur modular LFG, lexikon multidimensi yang hadir dan konsekuensi analitis yang mengikuti ini. Saya menunjukkan di mana cadangan LFG yang ada sebelumnya telah salah paham seperti dipandang dari lens a teori seperti LTAG dan HPSG, yang mengasumsikan seting arsitektur yang sangat berbeda dan menyediakan diskusi perbandingan tentang isu-isu.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier bydra by die aangaande diskusie van hoe beste om komplekse predikaat formasies te analyseer en te handteer, wat in besonderhede van die eienskappe van Hindi N-V komplekse predikate te kommentaar soos deur Vaidya et al. (2019). Ek verlig eienskappe van bestaande LFG analiseer en fokus in besonderhede op die modulare arkitektuur van LFG, sy aanvaardige multidimensionale leksikon en die analitiese konsekvens wat van hierdie af volg. Ek wys waar die voorheen bestaande LFG-voorstelle verkeerd verstaan is soos gesien is van die lense van teoriee soos LTAG en HPSG, wat 'n baie ander arkitektuur-opstelling aanvaar en 'n vergelykbare diskusie van die probleme verskaf.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sw>Gazeti hili linachangia majadiliano yanayoendelea kuhusu jinsi bora ya uchambuzi na kukabiliana na miundo magumu ya utabiri, na kutoa maoni hasa kuhusu utafiti wa tatizo la India N-V kama ilivyotengenezwa na Vaidya et al. (2019). Ninaonyesha vipande vya uchambuzi wa LFG uliopo na hususani kwenye ujenzi wa asili wa LFG, mwajiri wake wa lexico ya muda mrefu na matokeo ya uchambuzi yanayofuata. Ninaonyesha wapi mapendekezo yaliyopo hapo awali ya LFG yamekuwa yakifahamika vibaya kutokana na misingi ya nadharia kama vile LTAG na HPSG, ambayo inadhani kuanzishwa kwa ujenzi tofauti na kutoa mjadala wa kulinganisha kuhusu masuala haya.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_am>ይህም ገጽ እንዴት ያህል ትክክለኛ ፍሬዎችን ለማስተማርና ለመቀበል የሚችል ውይይት ያሳያል፡፡ በተለየ ዋዲያ እና አል በተለየው የሄንዲ N-V ውጤት ውጤቶች ላይ እንዲያስተካክሉ፡፡ የአሁኑን LFG ማረፊያ እና በተለይ የLFG መሠረት አካውንት፣ የአገራቢው ብዙአዊ ሊክሲኮን እና ከዚህ በኋላ የሚከተሉትን አስተያየት ፍለጎቶችን አቆይቻለሁ፡፡ የቀድሞው የLFG ፕሮጀክቶች እንደ LTAG እና ኤፕሲጂ ከደረጃ ደረጃዎች የተመለከቱት የት እንደሆነ የተሳሳቱ ናቸው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz Vaidya et al tarafından düzenlenen Hindi N-V kompleks predikatlaryň hasaplarynda nähili gowy çözümlenmesini we çözümlenmesini saýlamak üzere kömekleyär. Men bar LFG analyzlarynyň özelliklerini ýagtylapdyryn we özellikle LFG modul arhitekturynyň, onuň gaty multidimensional leksikony we bunyň ardyndan soňra gelen analitik netijesini ýagtylapdyryn. Men öňki bolan LFG teklibleriniň LTAG we HPSG ýaly teoriýanyň lenslerinden düşünülen ýerde ýalňyş düşünildigini a ýdýaryn. Bu tema örän başga arhitekturlyk düzenlemesi we meselelerden howsalaşyk edendir.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Ky dokument kontribuon në diskutimin në vazhdim të mënyrës më të mirë për të analizuar dhe trajtuar formacionet komplekse të predikuara, duke komentuar veçanërisht mbi pronësitë e predikuarve komplekse N-V të Hindi, siç janë përcaktuar nga Vaidya et al. (2019). Unë theksoj karakteristikat e analizave ekzistuese të LFG-së dhe përqëndrohem në veçanti në arkitekturën modulare të LFG-së, lexikonin e saj shumëdimensional dhe pasojat analitike që vijnë nga kjo. I point out where the previously existing LFG proposals have been misunderstood as viewed from the lens of theories such as LTAG and HPSG, which assume a very different architectural set-up and provide a comparative discussion of the issues.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটি বিশেষ করে ভায়েদিয়া এবং আল-এর নির্ধারিত বিষয়বস্তু বিশেষ করে বিশেষ করে হিন্দি N-V জটিল বৈশিষ্ট্যের বৈশিষ্ট্য সম্পর্কে মন্তব্য করেছে। আমি বিদ্যমান এলএফজি বিশ্লেষণ এবং বিশেষ করে এলএফজির মডিউলিয়াল কাঠামোর উপর মনোযোগ দিচ্ছি, তার অংশগ্রহণকারী মাল্ডিমেন্সিয়াল ল লেক্সিকোন এবং  আমি উল্লেখ করেছি কোথায় পূর্বে বিদ্যমান এলএফজি প্রস্তাবনা ভুল বোঝা গেছে যেমন এলটাজি এবং এইচপিজি-এর লাইন থেকে দেখা যাচ্ছে, যা অনুমান করে একটি খুব ভিন্ন আর্কিটারি</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt Vaidya et al. (2019) ilə müəyyən edilmiş Hindi N-V kompleks predikatların özellikləri barəsində müzakirə edir. Mən həmin LFG analizilərin özlərini aydınlaşdırır və özlərinə də LFG'nin modular arhitektarına, onun çox ölçülü leksikonu və bunun ardınca gələn analitik sonuçlarına odaqlayıram. Mən əvvəlkilərin LFG təbliğlərinin LTAG və HPSG kimi teoriyaların lensi ilə görünməsi kimi yanlış anlaşılmadığını belə göstərirəm ki, bu çox farklı arhitektür qurması və məsələlər barəsində müqayisədə mübahisə edir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_hy>Այս աշխատանքը ներդրում է շարունակական քննարկում այն մասին, թե ինչպես լավագույնը վերլուծել և վարել բարդ նախադասություններ, հատկապես մեկնաբանելով Հինդիայի N-V բարդ նախադասությունների առանձնահատկությունների մասին, ինչպես որոշել է Վայդիան և այլն. (2019 թ․․․։ Ես ներկայացնում եմ գոյություն ունեցող LFG-ի վերլուծությունների առանձնահատկությունները և հատկապես կենտրոնանում եմ LFG-ի մոդուլյար ճարտարապետության վրա, նրա մոդուլյար բազմաչափ լեքսիկոնի և դրանից հետևող վերլուծությունների վրա: Ես ուզում եմ նշել, թե որտեղ են նախկինում գոյություն ունեցող LFG-ի առաջարկները սխալ հասկացվել, ինչպես տեսնում են այնպիսի տեսությունների ոսպնյակից, ինչպիսիք են LTAԳ-ը և ՀՊՍԳ-ը, որոնք ենթադրում են շատ տարբեր ճարտարապետական կառուցվածք և ապահովում են հարցե</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest paper contribueix a la discussió en curso sobre com és millor analitzar i manejar formations predicates complexes, comentant en particular sobre les propietats dels predicats complexes N-V Hindi, tal com van descriure Vaidya et al. (2019). Destaco les característiques dels anàlisis existents de LFG i em concentro en especial en l'arquitectura modular de LFG, el seu lexicó multidimensional que hi ha, i les conseqüències analítiques que en deriven. Recordo on les propostes anteriorment existents de LFG han estat mal entendues com es veu a partir de la lent de teories com LTAG i HPSG, que suposen una estructura arquitectònica molt diferent i proporcionen una discussió comparativa sobre els problemes.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek přispívá k probíhající diskusi o tom, jak nejlépe analyzovat a zpracovat složité predikátové formace, přičemž komentuje zejména vlastnosti hindských N-V komplexních predikátů, jak stanovili Vaidya et al. (2019). Upozorňuji na vlastnosti stávajících LFG analýz a zaměřuji se zejména na modulární architekturu LFG, její doprovodný multidimenzionální lexikon a analytické důsledky, které z toho plynou. Upozorňuji na to, kde byly dříve existující návrhy LFG nepochopeny z hlediska teorií, jako jsou LTAG a HPSG, které předpokládají velmi odlišné architektonické uspořádání a poskytují srovnávací diskusi o těchto otázkách.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolev töö aitab kaasa käimasolevale arutelule, kuidas kõige paremini analüüsida ja käsitleda keerukaid predikaatide moodustusi, kommenteerides eelkõige hindi N-V kompleksi predikaatide omadusi, nagu on sätestatud Vaidya jt. (2019). Rõhutan olemasolevate LFG analüüside omadusi ja keskendun eelkõige LFG modulaarsele arhitektuurile, sellega kaasnevale mitmemõõtmelisele leksikonile ja sellest tulenevatele analüütilistele tagajärgedele. Ma juhin tähelepanu asjaolule, kus varem olemasolevaid LFG ettepanekuid on valesti mõistetud selliste teooriate nagu LTAG ja HPSG vaatenurgast, mis eeldavad väga erinevat arhitektuurilist ülesehitust ja pakuvad võrdlevat arutelu teemade üle.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir doprinosi na nastavku rasprave o tome kako je najbolje analizirati i riješiti kompleksne predikatne formacije, komentarajući posebno o o svojstvima kompleksnih predikata Hindija N-V, kako je navedena Vaidya et al. (2019). Oslanjam karakteristike postojećih analiza LFG-a i fokusiram se posebno na modularnu arhitekturu LFG-a, njezinu prisustvovačku multidimenzionalnu leksikonu i analitičke posljedice koje slijede od ovoga. Pokazujem gdje su prethodno postojeći prijedlogi LFG pogrešno shvaćeni kao što su pogrešno shvaćeni iz lens a teorija poput LTAG i HPSG-a, koji preduzimaju veoma različite arhitekturološke uspostave i pružaju usporednu diskusiju o pitanjima.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_fi>Tämä artikkeli edistää meneillään olevaa keskustelua siitä, miten parhaiten analysoidaan ja käsitellä monimutkaisia predikaattimuotoja, kommentoimalla erityisesti Hindi N-V-kompleksin predikaattien ominaisuuksia Vaidya et al. (2019). Korostan olemassa olevien LFG-analyysien ominaisuuksia ja keskityn erityisesti LFG:n modulaariseen arkkitehtuuriin, siihen liittyvään moniulotteiseen sanastoon ja siitä aiheutuviin analyyttisiin seurauksiin. Huomautan, että aiemmin olemassa olevia LFG-ehdotuksia on ymmärretty väärin LTAG:n ja HPSG:n kaltaisten teorioiden näkökulmasta, joissa otetaan huomioon hyvin erilainen arkkitehtuurinen rakenne ja tarjotaan vertaileva keskustelu kysymyksistä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Perintah iki nyumbang nggunakake perusahaan kanggo masalah sing luwih apik karo hal dadi karo hal-hal versi sing komplikasi sing larang, terus-komentar kanggo ngerasakno karo perusahaan karo perusahaan dha N-V sing dibutuhke deplikasi lan tambah karo Vady et al (2011). Aku ngubanjur cara-cara sing dibutuhke LFG karo akeh basa gambar karo architecture modulare kanggo LFG, dadi langkung akeh multi-dimansiyon lan sak akeh banjure sak dadi sing sumulakno iki. Aku mudhake ono, opo sing paling nggawe LFG dumadhi iki luwih apik kayong nguasai paten sing pernik dipunakno karo LTARG karo HPG, sing sumulakno akeh sistem arquitekat dumadhi iki ngono akeh dumadhi sing paling dhéwé.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Wannan karatun yana ƙara wa muhalli da ke tafiyar da jãyayya a kan ko da ya fi analyza kuma ka yi amfani da tsarin masu adadi, mai ƙayyade haske a kan properties na N-V wanda aka ƙayyade na da Waidya et al. (2019). Ina nuna haske masu fassarar LFG masu jira da kuma ana fokus, game da matsayin modular na LFG, da mataimaki multi-mutane leksisin da fassara masu ƙaranci daga wannan. Ina nuna inda da aka misfahimta masu gabani na lokaci na LFG kamar an gane shi daga misalin littafan misãlai kamar LTAG da HPSG, wanda yana yi zato da wani abu mai daban matsayi na tsari da kuma ya bãyar da rabo masu husũma.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Prispevek prispeva k tekoči razpravi o tem, kako najbolje analizirati in obravnavati kompleksne predikatne formacije, pri čemer predvsem komentira lastnosti hindijskih N-V kompleksnih predikatov, kot so jih določili Vaidya et al. (2019). Poudarjam značilnosti obstoječih analiz LFG in se osredotočam predvsem na modularno arhitekturo LFG, večdimenzionalni leksikon in analitične posledice, ki izhajajo iz tega. Poudarjam, kje so bili prej obstoječi predlogi LFG napačno razumljeni z vidika teorij, kot sta LTAG in HPSG, ki prevzemata zelo drugačno arhitekturno ureditev in zagotavljata primerjalno razpravo o vprašanjih.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>העבודה הזו תורמת לדיון הממשיך על כיצד לנתח ולטפל במצבים מסובכים, ומביעה במיוחד על תכונות המצבים של N-V מסובכים הינדי, כפי שהוציאו על ידי Vaidya et al. (2019). אני מתייחס לאיכויים של ניתוחים LFG קיימים ומתמקד במיוחד בארכיטקטורה המודולרית של LFG, הלקסיקון multidimensional הנוכחי שלה וההשלכות האנליטיות שמוצאות מזה. אני מצביע איפה הצעות הקודמות של LFG נבנו לא נכון כפי שנראה מהעדשה של תיאוריות כמו LTAG ו HPSG, אשר לוקחים סדר ארכיטקטורני מאוד שונה ומספקים דיון משווה על הנושאים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>This paper contributes to the on-going discussion of how best to analyze and handle complex predicate formations, commenting in particular on the properties of Hindi N-V complex predicates as set out by Vaidya et al. (2019). I highlight existing LFG analyzes and focus specifically on the modular architecture of LFG, its attendant multidimensional lexicon and the analytic consequences which follow from this. I point out where the previously existing LFG proposals have been misunderstood as viewed from the lens of theories such as LTAG and HPSG, which assume a very different architectural set-up and provide a comparative discussion of the issues.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
  </volume>
  <volume id="18">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Linguistic Issues in Language Technology, Volume 18, 2019 - Exploiting Parsed Corpora: Applications in Research, Pedagogy, and Processing</booktitle>
      <publisher>CSLI Publications</publisher>
      <year>2019</year>
      <month>Jul</month>
    </meta>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Building a Chinese AMR Bank with Concept and Relation Alignments<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese <fixed-case>AMR</fixed-case> Bank with Concept and Relation Alignments</title>
      <author><first>Bin</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <author><first>Yuan</first><last>Wen</last></author>
      <author><first>Li</first><last>Song</last></author>
      <author><first>Weiguang</first><last>Qu</last></author>
      <author><first>Nianwen</first><last>Xue</last></author>
      <abstract>Abstract Meaning Representation (AMR) is a meaning representation framework in which the meaning of a full sentence is represented as a single-rooted, acyclic, directed graph. In this article, we describe an on-going project to build a Chinese AMR (CAMR) corpus, which currently includes 10,149 sentences from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usenet_newsgroup">newsgroup</a> and weblog portion of the Chinese TreeBank (CTB). We describe the annotation specifications for the CAMR corpus, which follow the annotation principles of English AMR but make adaptations where needed to accommodate the linguistic facts of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a>. The CAMR specifications also include a systematic treatment of sentence-internal discourse relations. One significant change we have made to the AMR annotation methodology is the inclusion of the alignment between word tokens in the sentence and the concepts / relations in the CAMR annotation to make it easier for automatic parsers to model the correspondence between a sentence and its meaning representation. We develop an annotation tool for CAMR, and the inter-agreement as measured by the Smatch score between the two annotators is 0.83, indicating reliable annotation. We also present some quantitative analysis of the CAMR corpus. 46.71 % of the AMRs of the sentences are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(discrete_mathematics)">non-tree graphs</a>. Moreover, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abbreviation">AMR</a> of 88.95 % of the sentences has concepts inferred from the context of the sentence but do not correspond to a specific word.</abstract>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <url hash="e48846f0">2019.lilt-18.2</url>
      <bibkey>li-etal-2019-building</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/amr-bank">AMR Bank</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/groningen-meaning-bank">Groningen Meaning Bank</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Probing the nature of an island constraint with a parsed corpus</title>
      <author><first>Yusuke</first><last>Kubota</last></author>
      <author><first>Ai</first><last>Kubota</last></author>
      <abstract>This paper presents a case study of the use of the NINJAL Parsed Corpus of Modern Japanese (NPCMJ) for syntactic research. NPCMJ is the first phrase structure-based treebank for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese</a> that is specifically designed for application in linguistic (in addition to NLP) research. After discussing some basic methodological issues pertaining to the use of treebanks for theoretical linguistics research, we introduce our case study on the status of the Coordinate Structure Constraint (CSC) in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_language">Japanese</a>, showing that NPCMJ enables us to easily retrieve examples that support one of the key claims of Kubota and Lee (2015): that the CSC should be viewed as a pragmatic, rather than a syntactic constraint. The corpus-based study we conducted moreover revealed a previously unnoticed tendency that was highly relevant for further clarifying the principles governing the empirical data in question. We conclude the paper by briefly discussing some further methodological issues brought up by our case study pertaining to the relationship between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistics">linguistic research</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corpus_linguistics">corpus development</a>.</abstract>
      <issue>3</issue>
      <url hash="e8eee2a0">2019.lilt-18.4</url>
      <bibkey>kubota-kubota-2019-probing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>