<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.alvr">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-06-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Advances in Language and Vision Research</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Xin</first><last>Wang</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jesse</first><last>Thomason</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ronghang</first><last>Hu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Xinlei</first><last>Chen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Peter</first><last>Anderson</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Qi</first><last>Wu</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Asli</first><last>Celikyilmaz</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jason</first><last>Baldridge</last></editor>
      <editor><first>William Yang</first><last>Wang</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <url hash="7f4feb1f">2020.alvr-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="30a10a5a">2020.alvr-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>alvr-2020-advances</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Visual Question Generation from Radiology Images</title>
      <author><first>Mourad</first><last>Sarrouti</last></author>
      <author><first>Asma</first><last>Ben Abacha</last></author>
      <author><first>Dina</first><last>Demner-Fushman</last></author>
      <pages>12–18</pages>
      <abstract>Visual Question Generation (VQG), the task of generating a question based on image contents, is an increasingly important area that combines <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_vision">computer vision</a>. Although there are some recent works that have attempted to generate questions from images in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_domain">open domain</a>, the task of VQG in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medical_imaging">medical domain</a> has not been explored so far. In this paper, we introduce an approach to generation of visual questions about radiology images called VQGR, i.e. an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a> that is able to ask a question when shown an image. VQGR first generates new training data from the existing examples, based on contextual word embeddings and image augmentation techniques. It then uses the variational auto-encoders model to encode images into a latent space and decode natural language questions. Experimental automatic evaluations performed on the VQA-RAD dataset of clinical visual questions show that VQGR achieves good performances compared with the baseline system. The source code is available at https://github.com/sarrouti/vqgr.</abstract>
      <url hash="0dcc0d39">2020.alvr-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.alvr-1.3</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929760" />
      <bibkey>sarrouti-etal-2020-visual</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/sarrouti/vqgr" additional="false">sarrouti/vqgr</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>On the role of effective and referring questions in GuessWhat? !<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>uess<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>hat?!</title>
      <author><first>Mauricio</first><last>Mazuecos</last></author>
      <author><first>Alberto</first><last>Testoni</last></author>
      <author><first>Raffaella</first><last>Bernardi</last></author>
      <author><first>Luciana</first><last>Benotti</last></author>
      <pages>19–25</pages>
      <abstract>Task success is the standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metric</a> used to evaluate referential visual dialogue systems. In this paper we propose two new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metrics</a> that evaluate how each question contributes to the goal. First, we measure how effective each question is by evaluating whether the question discards objects that are not the referent. Second, we define referring questions as those that univocally identify one object in the image. We report the new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metrics</a> for human dialogues and for state of the art publicly available <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> on GuessWhat? !. Regarding our first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metric</a>, we find that successful dialogues do not have a higher percentage of effective questions for most <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a>. With respect to the second <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metric</a>, humans make questions at the end of the dialogue that are referring, confirming their guess before guessing. Human dialogues that use this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy">strategy</a> have a higher task success but models do not seem to learn it.</abstract>
      <url hash="61627744">2020.alvr-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.alvr-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>mazuecos-etal-2020-role</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Latent Alignment of Procedural Concepts in Multimodal Recipes</title>
      <author><first>Hossein</first><last>Rajaby Faghihi</last></author>
      <author><first>Roshanak</first><last>Mirzaee</last></author>
      <author><first>Sudarshan</first><last>Paliwal</last></author>
      <author><first>Parisa</first><last>Kordjamshidi</last></author>
      <pages>26–31</pages>
      <abstract>We propose a novel alignment mechanism to deal with procedural reasoning on a newly released multimodal QA dataset, named RecipeQA. Our model is solving the textual cloze task which is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reading_comprehension">reading comprehension</a> on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recipe">recipe</a> containing images and instructions. We exploit the power of attention networks, cross-modal representations, and a latent alignment space between instructions and candidate answers to solve the problem. We introduce constrained max-pooling which refines the max pooling operation on the alignment matrix to impose disjoint constraints among the outputs of the model. Our evaluation result indicates a 19 % improvement over the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baselines</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="1aa3a317">2020.alvr-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.alvr-1.5</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929759" />
      <bibkey>rajaby-faghihi-etal-2020-latent</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/HLR/LatentAlignmentProcedural" additional="false">HLR/LatentAlignmentProcedural</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/recipeqa">RecipeQA</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>المحاذاة الكامنة للمفاهيم الإجرائية في الوصفات متعددة الوسائط</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Alinhamento Latente de Conceitos Processuais em Receitas Multimodais</title_pt>
      <title_es>Alineación latente de conceptos procedimentales en recetas multimodales</title_es>
      <title_ja>マルチモーダルレシピにおける手順概念の潜在的な整列</title_ja>
      <title_hi>मल्टीमॉडल व्यंजनों में प्रक्रियात्मक अवधारणाओं का अव्यक्त संरेखण</title_hi>
      <title_zh>多模式配方中程序的对齐</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Ailíniú Folaigh ar Choincheapa Nós Imeachta in Oidis Ilmhódúla</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Multimodal Recipes</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Az eljárási koncepciók későbbi összehangolása multimodális receptekben</title_hu>
      <title_el>Στιγμιαία ευθυγράμμιση των διαδικαστικών εννοιών σε Πολυμεταφορές Συνταγές</title_el>
      <title_it>Allineamento latente dei concetti procedurali nelle ricette multimodali</title_it>
      <title_kk>КөпModal Recipes- де процедурлық концепциялардың соңғы түрлендіру</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Vėlesnis daugiarūšio režimo receptų procedūrinių koncepcijų suderinimas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Подоцна израмнување на процедуралните концепти во мултимодилните рецепти</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Penjajaran Terlambat Koncept Prosedural dalam Reċipit Multimodal</title_ms>
      <title_ml>പലമോഡല്‍ റിസിപ്പുകളില്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങളുടെ അടുത്തേക്കുള്ള ചേര്‍ത്തുനില്‍ക്കുക</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Allinjament Latent ta’ Kunċetti Proċedurali f’Reċipjenti Multimodali</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Олон загварын ойлголтын дараагийн түгжүүлэлт</title_mn>
      <title_no>Siste justering av prosedyrarne konseptar i fleire mottakar</title_no>
      <title_sr>Posljednje ispravljanje procesuralnih koncepcija u multimodalnim recepcijama</title_sr>
      <title_pl>Latentne dostosowanie koncepcji proceduralnych w recepturach multimodalnych</title_pl>
      <title_si>ගොඩමෝඩාල් රිසිපස්සේ ප්‍රධාන සංස්කරණය</title_si>
      <title_ro>Alinierea latentă a conceptelor procedurale în rețetele multimodale</title_ro>
      <title_sv>Latent Alignment of Procedureal Concepts in Multimodal Recept</title_sv>
      <title_so>Soo saarista dhaqdhaqaalaha takoorida ee macluumaadka kala duduwan</title_so>
      <title_ur>Multimodal Recipes</title_ur>
      <title_ta>பெரும்பொருள்களில் செயல்படுத்தும் செயல்பாடுகளின் சமீபத்தில் ஒழுங்குபடுத்தல்</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Latent Alignment of Procedural Concepts in Multimodal Recipes</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Liên kết tạm thời các ý tưởng theo quy trình đa phương</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Латентно подравняване на процесуалните концепции в мултимодалните рецепти</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Latente afstemming van procedurele concepten in multimodale recepten</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Posljednje ispravljanje postupnih koncepcija u multimodalnim recepcijama</title_hr>
      <title_da>Latent Alignment of Procedural Concepts in Multimodal Recipes</title_da>
      <title_fa>تنظیم اخیر نظریه‌های پردازشی در رسانه‌های چندین مدل</title_fa>
      <title_id>Penjajaran Terlambat Koncep Prosedural dalam Resip Multimodal</title_id>
      <title_de>Latente Ausrichtung von Verfahrenskonzepten in multimodalen Rezepturen</title_de>
      <title_ko>다중모드 설계도에서 프로그램 개념의 잠재적 일치성</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Hivi karibuni Uwezeshaji wa Matokeo ya Utawala katika Makasiliano mengi</title_sw>
      <title_tr>_Mazmunlar</title_tr>
      <title_af>Laat Oplyn van Procedurale Koncepsies in Multimodaal Recipes</title_af>
      <title_sq>Rregullimi i fundit i koncepteve procedurale në recetat multimodale</title_sq>
      <title_am>ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_hy>Բազմամոդալ բաղադրամիջոցների պրոցեդուրային գաղափարների վերջին հարմարեցումը</title_hy>
      <title_bn>বহুমোডাল রিসিপিপের প্রক্রিয়াল কনসেপ্টের সম্প্রতি সীমাবদ্ধতা</title_bn>
      <title_az>Daha √ßoxlu modal Recipl…ôrd…ô procedural fikirl…ôri</title_az>
      <title_bs>Posljednje ispravljanje procesuralnih koncepcija u multimodalnim recepcijama</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Llavor allinjament dels conceptes de procediment en receptes multimodals</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Latentní zarovnání procesních konceptů v multimodálních recepturách</title_cs>
      <title_et>Mitmeliigiliste retseptide menetluslike kontseptsioonide hilinenud ühtlustamine</title_et>
      <title_fi>Menettelykäsitteiden viimeaikainen yhdenmukaistaminen multimodaalisissa resepteissä</title_fi>
      <title_jv>structural navigation</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Latentna usklajenost postopkovnih konceptov v multimodalnih receptih</title_sk>
      <title_he>התאמה מאוחרת של רעיונות הנהליים במקבלים רבים</title_he>
      <title_bo>ནང་དུ་ཕལ་ཆེ་རྣམ་གྲངས་སྒྲིག་ཀྱི་ལས་སྦྱོར་བའི་གྲལ་སྒྲིག་སྟངས</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقترح آلية محاذاة جديدة للتعامل مع التفكير الإجرائي على مجموعة بيانات QA متعددة الوسائط التي تم إصدارها حديثًا ، تسمى RecipeQA. يعمل نموذجنا على حل مهمة cloze النصية وهي فهم مقروء لوصفة تحتوي على صور وتعليمات. نحن نستغل قوة شبكات الانتباه ، والتمثيلات متعددة الوسائط ، ومساحة المحاذاة الكامنة بين التعليمات والإجابات المرشحة لحل المشكلة. نقدم الحد الأقصى للتجميع المقيد الذي يعمل على تحسين عملية التجميع القصوى في مصفوفة المحاذاة لفرض قيود منفصلة بين مخرجات النموذج. تشير نتيجة التقييم لدينا إلى تحسن بنسبة 19٪ مقارنة بخطوط الأساس.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Proponemos un mecanismo de alineación novedoso para tratar el razonamiento procedimental en un conjunto de datos de control de calidad multimodal recientemente publicado, denominado RecipeQA. Nuestro modelo está resolviendo la tarea de cloze textual, que es una comprensión lectora de una receta que contiene imágenes e instrucciones. Para resolver el problema, aprovechamos el poder de las redes de atención, las representaciones intermodales y un espacio de alineación latente entre las instrucciones y las respuestas de los candidatos. Introducimos la agrupación máxima restringida que refina la operación de agrupación máxima en la matriz de alineación para imponer restricciones disjuntas entre las salidas del modelo. El resultado de nuestra evaluación indica una mejora del 19% con respecto a las líneas de base.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Propomos um novo mecanismo de alinhamento para lidar com o raciocínio processual em um conjunto de dados de QA multimodal recém-lançado, chamado RecipeQA. Nosso modelo está resolvendo a tarefa de cloze textual que é uma compreensão de leitura em uma receita contendo imagens e instruções. Exploramos o poder das redes de atenção, representações multimodais e um espaço de alinhamento latente entre instruções e respostas candidatas para resolver o problema. Introduzimos o max-pooling restrito que refina a operação max pooling na matriz de alinhamento para impor restrições disjuntas entre as saídas do modelo. Nosso resultado de avaliação indica uma melhora de 19% em relação às linhas de base.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_zh>建一新对齐机制以处新出多模式QA数据集(名为RecipeQA)程序推理。 吾模方解文本塞,此含象食谱之读解也。 因注意力网络之力,跨模态示及指选对案之间潜于对齐之间。 引入大池化,优化齐矩阵之大池化,以施不交之约。 我评结果表明,比基线增 19%。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ja>RecipeQAと名付けられた新しくリリースされたマルチモーダルQAデータセットの手続き的推論に対処するための新たなアラインメントメカニズムを提案します。私たちのモデルは、画像と指示を含むレシピの読み取り理解であるテキストクローズタスクを解決しています。私たちは、問題を解決するために、注意ネットワーク、クロスモーダル表現、および命令と候補者の回答の間の潜在的なアライメントスペースの力を利用します。アライメント行列の最大プーリング演算を絞り込み、モデルの出力間に不連続な制約を課す制約付き最大プーリングを導入しました。当社の評価結果は、ベースラインよりも19 ％改善しています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>हम एक नए जारी किए गए मल्टीमॉडल क्यूए डेटासेट पर प्रक्रियात्मक तर्क से निपटने के लिए एक उपन्यास संरेखण तंत्र का प्रस्ताव करते हैं, जिसे रेसिपीक्यूए नाम दिया गया है। हमारा मॉडल पाठ्य क्लोज़ कार्य को हल कर रहा है जो छवियों और निर्देशों वाले एक नुस्खा पर एक पढ़ने की समझ है। हम ध्यान नेटवर्क, क्रॉस-मोडल अभ्यावेदन, और समस्या को हल करने के लिए निर्देशों और उम्मीदवार के जवाबों के बीच एक अव्यक्त संरेखण स्थान की शक्ति का शोषण करते हैं। हम सीमित अधिकतम-पूलिंग पेश करते हैं जो मॉडल के आउटपुट के बीच असंयुक्त बाधाओं को लागू करने के लिए संरेखण मैट्रिक्स पर अधिकतम पूलिंग ऑपरेशन को परिष्कृत करता है। हमारा मूल्यांकन परिणाम बेसलाइन पर 19% सुधार को इंगित करता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Molaimid meicníocht nua ailínithe chun déileáil le réasúnaíocht nós imeachta ar thacar sonraí ilmhódúil QA nua-eisithe, darb ainm RecipeQA. Tá ár múnla ag réiteach an taisc théacsúla, is é sin léamhthuiscint ar oideas ina bhfuil íomhánna agus treoracha. Bainimid leas as cumhacht na ngréasán aird, léirithe trasmhódúla, agus as spás ailínithe folaigh idir treoracha agus freagraí iarrthóra chun an fhadhb a réiteach. Tugaimid isteach uas-chomhthiomsú srianta a mhionchoigeartaíonn an oibríocht uasta chomhthiomsaithe ar an maitrís ailínithe chun srianta dícheangailte a fhorchur i measc aschuir na samhla. Léiríonn toradh ár meastóireachta feabhas 19% thar na bunlínte.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ პროცესტური პარამენტის პროცესტური პარამენტის შესახებ ახალგაზრდა მლიტიმოდიალური QA მონაცემების სახებ RecipeQA. ჩვენი მოდელი ტექსტულური კლოზის დავალება, რომელიც კითხვის შესახებ რესპეტის შესახებ სურათები და ინსტუქციები. ჩვენ გამოვიყენებთ ინსტრუქციების და კანდიდენტის პასუხების ძალიან, მრავალური გამოსახულებების, და მრავალური განსახულებების განსახულება. ჩვენ ჩვენ შევცვალოთ მაქსი დაბრუნებული მაქსი დაბრუნება, რომელიც მაქსი დაბრუნება მაქსი დაბრუნება მაქსი დაბრუნება მაქსი დაბრუნების მარტიკის დაბრუნება, რომ მოდელის გადას ჩვენი განსაზღვრების შედეგი იცის, რომ 19% უფრო მეტადება ბაზის ხაზებით.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Új összehangolási mechanizmust javasolunk egy újonnan kiadott multimodális minőségbiztosítási adatkészleten, RecipeQA néven. Modellünk a képeket és utasításokat tartalmazó receptre vonatkozó olvasási megértés megoldása. Kihasználjuk a figyelemhálózatok erejét, a transzmodális reprezentációkat, valamint az utasítások és a jelölt válaszok közötti látens összehangolási teret a probléma megoldására. Bevezetjük a korlátozott maximális pooling műveletet, amely finomítja a maximális pooling műveletet az igazítási mátrixon, hogy a modell kimenetei között diszjunktív korlátozásokat írjon elő. Az értékelési eredményeink 19%-os javulást mutatnak a kiindulási értékekhez képest.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Προτείνουμε έναν νέο μηχανισμό ευθυγράμμισης για την αντιμετώπιση της διαδικαστικής συλλογιστικής σε ένα πρόσφατα κυκλοφορημένο πολυμορφικό σύνολο δεδομένων QA, που ονομάζεται RecipeQA. Το μοντέλο μας λύνει το κείμενο που είναι μια κατανόηση ανάγνωσης σε μια συνταγή που περιέχει εικόνες και οδηγίες. Εκμεταλλευόμαστε τη δύναμη των δικτύων προσοχής, των διαστροφικών αναπαραστάσεων, και ενός λανθάνοντος διαστήματος ευθυγράμμισης μεταξύ των οδηγιών και των υποψήφιων απαντήσεων για την επίλυση του προβλήματος. Εισαγωγή περιορισμένης μέγιστης συγκέντρωσης η οποία βελτιώνει τη λειτουργία μέγιστης συγκέντρωσης στη μήτρα ευθυγράμμισης για να επιβάλει διαφορετικούς περιορισμούς μεταξύ των εξόδων του μοντέλου. Το αποτέλεσμα της αξιολόγησης μας δείχνει 19% βελτίωση σε σχέση με τις γραμμές βάσης.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_kk>Біз, RecipeQA деген жаңа шығарылған көптеген QA деректер жинағында процессуалдық түсініктемелерді шешу механизмін таңдаймыз. Біздің үлгіміз кескіндер мен мәліметтер бар рецептерді оқу үшін мәтін салау тапсырмасын шешу. Мәселеді шешу үшін біз қызықтық желілердің қуатын, көп модалдық түрлендіруді және мәселелерді шешу үшін келесі мәліметтер мен кандидаттардың жауаптарының арасындағы Біз үлгісінің шығындағы шектерді шектеу үшін шектеу үшін максималдық жинақтау операциясын түзету матрициясының максималдығын келтіреміз. Бағалау нәтижесіміз негізгі жолдарда 19% жақсарту дегенді көрсетеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Siūlome naują suderinimo mechanizmą, kuriuo būtų sprendžiamas naujai paskelbto daugiarūšio QA duomenų rinkinio, vadinamo RecipeQA, procedūrinis pagrindimas. Mūsų model is išsprendžia tekstinę užduotį, kuri yra skaitymo supratimas recepte, kuriame yra vaizdų ir instrukcijų. Mes naudojame dėmesio tinklų galią, įvairiarūšio transporto atstovavimą ir latentišką instrukcijų ir kandidatų atsakymų derinimo erdvę problemai spręsti. We introduce constrained max-pooling which refines the max pooling operation on the alignment matrix to impose disjoint constraints among the outputs of the model.  Mūsų vertinimo rezultatai rodo 19 proc. pagerėjimą palyginti su bazinėmis linijomis.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>Proponiamo un nuovo meccanismo di allineamento per affrontare il ragionamento procedurale su un set di dati multimodali QA recentemente rilasciato, denominato RecipeQA. Il nostro modello sta risolvendo il compito di cloze testuale che è una comprensione di lettura su una ricetta contenente immagini e istruzioni. Sfruttamo la potenza delle reti di attenzione, rappresentazioni cross-modali e uno spazio di allineamento latente tra istruzioni e risposte candidate per risolvere il problema. Introducemo il max-pooling vincolato che affina l'operazione di max pooling sulla matrice di allineamento per imporre vincoli disgiunti tra le uscite del modello. Il nostro risultato di valutazione indica un miglioramento del 19% rispetto alle linee di riferimento.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Предложуваме нов механизам за приспособување за да се справи со процедуралното размислување за ново објавен мултимодилен компјутер податоци за QA, наречен Рецепт QA. Нашиот модел ја решава текстуалната задача за затворање која е разбирање за читање на рецептот кој содржи слики и инструкции. Ја искористуваме моќта на мрежите на внимание, крстомодалните претставувања, и тајниот простор за приспособување помеѓу инструкциите и одговорите на кандидатите за решавање на проблемот. Ние воведуваме ограничено максимално спојување кое ја рафинира максималната операција на спојување на матрицата за наметнување на ограничувања помеѓу излезите на моделот. Нашиот резултат на проценката покажува подобрување од 19 отсто во однос на основните линии.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami cadangkan mekanisme penyesuaian baru untuk menangani alasan prosedur pada set data QA multimodal yang baru dibebaskan, bernama RecipeQA. Model kami memecahkan tugas penutup teks yang merupakan pemahaman pembacaan pada resep yang mengandungi imej dan arahan. Kami mengeksploitasi kuasa rangkaian perhatian, perwakilan transmodal, dan ruang penyesuaian tersembunyi antara arahan dan jawapan calon untuk menyelesaikan masalah. Kami memperkenalkan pengumpulan maksimum terhalang yang menyempurnakan operasi pengumpulan maksimum pada matriks penyesuaian untuk memaksa kewajiban pengumpulan diantara output model. Hasil penilaian kami menunjukkan peningkatan 19% atas garis dasar.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>പുതിയ പുതിയ വിവരങ്ങളുടെ കാര്യത്തില്‍ ക്യൂഎ ഡാറ്റാസറ്റെറ്റിനെ കൈകാര്യം ചെയ്യാനുള്ള പ്രക്രിയയുടെ കാര്യത്തില്‍ നോ ഞങ്ങളുടെ മോഡല്‍ ചിത്രങ്ങളും ഉപദേശങ്ങളും ഉള്ള റെസിപ്പില്‍ വായിക്കുന്ന ഒരു വായിക്കുന്ന ജോലി പരിഹരിക്കുന്നു. നമ്മള്‍ ശ്രദ്ധിക്കുന്ന നെറ്റുകളുടെ ശക്തിയും, ക്രിസ്മോഡല്‍ പ്രതിനിധികളും, പ്രശ്നം തീരുമാനിക്കുന്നതിനുമിടയില്‍ നിര്‍ദേ നിര്‍ബന്ധിതമായ ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതല്‍ പൂളിങ്ങ് പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. മോഡലിന്റെ പുറത്തുള്ള വിഭവങ്ങള്‍ക്കിടയില്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ ന നമ്മുടെ വിലാസങ്ങളുടെ ഫലം അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ 19% മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്തിയിരിക്കുന്നു.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Бид шинэ нэр дэвшүүлсэн олон моделийн QA өгөгдлийн санг RecipeQA гэж нэрлэсэн процессуал шалтгааныг зохицуулахын тулд шинэ зохицуулах механизм санал дэвшүүлнэ. Бидний загвар нь зураг болон заавал агуулдаг зураг болон унших загварыг шийдэх юм. Бид анхаарал төвлөрүүлэх сүлжээний эрх мэдэлийг ашиглаж, олон төрлийн үзүүлэлтийг ашиглаж, заавал болон удирдагчийн хариултуудын хоорондох хоорондох зай ашиглаж байна. Бид загварын үр дүнд холбогдох хязгаарлагдсан максимум цуглуулалт хийдэг. Энэ нь загварын үр дүнд холбогдох хязгаарлалт хийх максимум цуглуулалт. Бидний оюутнуудын үр дүнд суурь шугам дээр 19% улам сайжруулсан байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nipproponu mekkaniżmu ġdid ta' allinjament biex jittratta r-raġunament proċedurali fuq sett ta' dejta multimodali QA li għadu kif ġie rilaxxat, imsejjaħ ir-Reċipjent QA. Il-mudell tagħna qed isolvi l-kompitu ta’ għeluq testwali li huwa fehim tal-qari fuq riċetta li fiha stampi u struzzjonijiet. We exploit the power of attention networks, cross-modal representations, and a latent alignment space between instructions and candidate answers to solve the problem.  Aħna nintroduċu aggregazzjoni massima ristretta li tirrifletti l-operazzjoni ta’ aggregazzjoni massima fuq il-matriċi tal-allinjament biex jiġu imposti restrizzjonijiet ta’ disjoint fost ir-riżultati tal-mudell. Ir-riżultat tal-evalwazzjoni tagħna jindika titjib ta’ 19 % fuq il-linji bażi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Vi foreslår eit nytt justeringsmekanisme for å handtera prosessorsursursurs på ein nytt utgjeven multimodal QA- dataset, kalla « RecipeQA ». Modellen vårt løyser oppgåva for tekstklose som er ei lesingsforståelse på ei oppskrift som inneheld bilete og instruksjonar. Vi bruker makten på oppmerksnettverk, krysmodal representasjonar, og ein latent justeringsplass mellom instruksjonar og kandidatsvar for å løysa problemet. Vi introduserer begrensede maksimal pooling som refiner maksimal pooling- operasjonen på justeringsmatrisen for å setja forskjellige begrensningar mellom utdata av modellen. Ver evalueringsresultatet tyder på at 19 % forbetringa er over grunnlinjene.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Proponujemy nowy mechanizm dostosowania do rozumowania proceduralnego na nowo wydanym multimodalnym zbiorze danych o nazwie RecipeQA. Nasz model rozwiązuje zadanie zamknięcia tekstowego, czyli rozumienie czytania na recepturze zawierającej obrazy i instrukcje. Do rozwiązania problemu wykorzystujemy moc sieci uwagi, reprezentacji crossmodalnych i ukrytej przestrzeni dostosowania instrukcji do odpowiedzi kandydatów. Wprowadzamy ograniczone maksymalne pooling, które dopracowuje operację maksymalnego poolingu na macierzy wyrównania, aby narzucić dyspólne ograniczenia między wyjściami modelu. Nasz wynik oceny wskazuje na 19% poprawy w stosunku do linii bazowych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_si>අපි අළුත් ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක QA දත්ත සෙට් එක්ක අලුත් ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක සඳහා ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක ක්‍රියාත්මක විද අපේ මොඩේලය පින්තූර සහ උපදේශය තියෙන පින්තූර සඳහා පින්තූර සඳහා කියවන්න පුළුවන් ක්‍ලෝස් වැඩේ විස අපි අවධානය ජාලය, ප්‍රශ්නයක් විසඳන්න අවධානය සහ ප්‍රශ්නයක් විසඳන්න ප්‍රතිචාරයක් අතර ප්‍රයෝජනයේ බලය ප්‍රය අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍ර අපේ විශ්ලේෂණ ප්‍රතිචාරය ප්‍රතිචාරයක් තියෙනවා අධාරණ ප්‍රතිචාරයේ 19% වැඩිය.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ro>Propunem un nou mecanism de aliniere pentru a aborda raționamentul procedural al unui set de date multimodal de QA nou lansat, denumit RecipeQA. Modelul nostru rezolvă sarcina de închidere textuală care este o înțelegere a lecturii pe o rețetă conținând imagini și instrucțiuni. Exploatăm puterea rețelelor de atenție, a reprezentărilor transmodale și a unui spațiu latent de aliniere între instrucțiuni și răspunsuri candidate pentru a rezolva problema. Introducem un maxim-pooling constrâns care rafinează operațiunea de pooling maxim pe matricea de aliniere pentru a impune constrângeri disjuncte între ieșirile modelului. Rezultatele evaluării noastre indică o îmbunătăţire de 19% faţă de liniile de referinţă.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu soo jeedaynaa mekaniisa isbedelka saxda si aan u kala macaamiloono sababta soo socota ee la xiriira macluumaadka cusub ee QA oo la yidhaahdo RecipeQA. Tusaalkayagu wuxuu xallinayaa shuqulka kooxaha dhaqanka ee qoraalka ah, kaas oo ah kooxaha akhriska oo ku qoran sawirro iyo hagitaan. Waxaynu isticmaalnaa xoogga shabakada daryeelka, noocyada kala duwan, iyo meel u dhaxaysa hagitaanka iyo jawaabaha kandidada si ay u xalliyaan dhibaatada. Waxaynu soo bandhignaynaa baaritaanka caadiga ah oo ku sawiraya hawlaha dhaqaalaha ee ugu badnaan ee la soconayo matrix isbedelka si uu u dhigo xadhiidyo wadajirka midowga. Abaalkeena qiimeynta waxaa looga jeedaa 19% kordhin saldhigyada.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Vi föreslår en ny justeringsmekanism för att hantera procedurresonemang på ett nyligen släppt multimodalt QA-dataset, kallat RecipeQA. Vår modell löser den textmässiga cloze uppgiften som är en läsförståelse på ett recept innehållande bilder och instruktioner. Vi utnyttjar kraften i uppmärksamhetsnätverk, tvärmodala representationer och ett latent anpassningsutrymme mellan instruktioner och kandidatsvar för att lösa problemet. Vi introducerar begränsad max-pooling som förfinar max pooling operationen på justeringsmatsen för att införa splittrade begränsningar mellan modellernas utgångar. Vårt utvärderingsresultat indikerar en 19% förbättring jämfört med baslinjen.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Predlažemo novi mehanizam usklađenja da se suoči sa proceduralnim razumijevanjem o novom oslobođenom multimodalnom kompletu podataka QA, po imenu RecipeQA. Naš model rešava tekstualni kloz zadatak koji je razumijevanje čitanja o recepu koji sadrži slike i upute. Koristimo moć pažnje mreža, međumodalnih predstavljanja i latentno usklađenje prostora između instrukcija i odgovora kandidata za rešenje problema. Predstavljamo ograničene maksimalne skupljanje koje refinira maksimalnu operaciju skupljanja na matrici usklađivanja kako bi postavili nesavršene ograničenje među ishodima modela. Naš rezultat procjene ukazuje na poboljšanje od 19%.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ur>ہم نے ایک نئی مکانیسم کا پیشنهاد کرتا ہے کہ ایک نئی مکانیسمڈال QA ڈیٹ سٹ کے ذریعے ایک مکانیسم کے ساتھ پردازشی منظورات کے ساتھ بحث کریں، جس کا نام RecipeQA ہے. ہماری مدل تخلیق کلوز کے کام کو حل کر رہی ہے جو تصاویر اور نصیحت کے بارے میں ایک پڑھنے کی سمجھ ہے ہم توجه کے نیٹورک کے طاقت کو استعمال کرتے ہیں، کرسٹ موڈال نمونات، اور مشکل حل کے لئے ایک لاٹینٹ سیٹرنگ فضا کے درمیان استعمال کرتے ہیں. ہم مضبوط مضبوط پولینگ کو معلوم کرتے ہیں جو مضبوط موڈل کے نتائج کے درمیان مضبوط محدودیت رکھنے کے لئے مضبوط مضبوط پولینگ عملیات کو پاک کرتا ہے ہمارے ارزیابی کا نتیجہ بنیاس لینوں پر 19 درصد اضافہ ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>நாம் புதிய வெளிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட புதிய கியூஏ தரவுத்தளத்தின் காரணத்தை நிர்ணயிக்க ஒரு புதிய புதிய ஒழுங்குபடுத்தல் முறைம எங்கள் மாதிரி உரை மூடும் பணியை தீர்வு செய்கிறது இது பிம்பங்கள் மற்றும் கட்டளைகள் உள்ள ஒரு நிறுவனத்தில் படிக்கும் கூ நாங்கள் கவனத்தின் வலைப்பின்னல்களின் சக்தியைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறோம், கிடைக்கும் மாறுபாடுகள் மற்றும் கட்டளைகள் மற்றும் சார்ந நாம் கட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்ட அதிகபட்ச தூக்கத்தை குறிப்பிடுகிறோம் அது ஒழுங்குபடுத்தும் மத்தியில் செயல்பாட்டை மாதிரியின் வெளியீடு நம்முடைய மதிப்பு முடிவு அடிப்படைகளில் 19% முன்னேற்றத்தை குறிப்பிடுகிறது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Biz yangi ajratilgan QA maʼlumotlar tarkibini boshqarish uchun novel tasdiqlash mechaniyasini tahlil qilamiz. Bizning modelimiz rasm va ruxsat bilan olish muvaffaqiyatlarini aniqlaydi. Biz murakkab qilish uchun foydalanuvchi tarmoqlar, cross-modal representlari, va yangi taʼminlovchi soʻzni va kandida javoblarni ishlatamiz. Biz modelning tashkilotlariga birlashtirish uchun eng maksimal suhbat operatsiyasini aniqlashimiz mumkin. Bizning qiymatimiz natijasi asosiy sonlaridan 19% yaxshi o'zgarishni anglatadi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi đề xuất một cơ chế định vị mới để xử lý các lập trình về một tập tin QA đa chiều mới được công bố, có tên là RecpeQA. Phần mềm của chúng ta là giải quyết công việc đo đồng, đó là sự hiểu biết về công thức có chứa ảnh và hướng dẫn. Chúng tôi tận dụng sức mạnh của các mạng chú ý, các biểu lộ khác phương, và một khoảng cách sắp xếp thần kỳ giữa hướng dẫn và các câu trả lời ứng cử viên để giải quyết vấn đề. Chúng tôi giới thiệu khả năng tối đa bị hạn chế, tinh chỉnh thao tác tối đa trên ma trận phối hợp để áp đặt các ràng buộc chia rẽ giữa các kết xuất của mô-đun. Kết quả đánh giá của chúng ta cho thấy sự cải thiện 97.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Предлагаме нов механизъм за привеждане в съответствие с процедурните разсъждения на новоиздаден мултимодален набор от данни за оценка на качеството, наречен RecipeQA. Нашият модел е решаване на задачата за текстово блокиране, която е разбиране за четене на рецепта, съдържаща изображения и инструкции. Ние използваме силата на мрежите за внимание, интермодалните представяния и латентното пространство за подравняване между инструкциите и отговорите на кандидатите за решаване на проблема. Въвеждаме ограничено максимално обединяване, което рафинира максималната операция на обединяване на матрицата за подравняване, за да наложи дискомфортни ограничения между изходите на модела. Резултатът от нашата оценка показва 19% подобрение спрямо базовите линии.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We stellen een nieuw alignment mechanisme voor om procedurele redenering te behandelen op een nieuw vrijgegeven multimodale QA dataset, genaamd RecipeQA. Ons model is het oplossen van de tekstuele cloze taak, een leesbegrip op een recept met afbeeldingen en instructies. We benutten de kracht van aandachtsnetwerken, crossmodale representaties en een latente uitlijningsruimte tussen instructies en kandidaat-antwoorden om het probleem op te lossen. We introduceren beperkte max-pooling die de max pooling operatie op de uitlijningsmatrix verfijnt om disjoint beperkingen op te leggen tussen de outputs van het model. Ons evaluatieresultaat wijst op een 19% verbetering ten opzichte van de baselines.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Predlažemo novi mehanizam usklađivanja kako bi se suočili sa proceduralnim razumijevanjem o novom objavljenom multimodalnom kompletu podataka QA, po imenu RecipeQA. Naš model rješava tekstualni kloz zadatak koji je razumijevanje čitanja o recepu koji sadrži slike i upute. Koristimo moć pažnje mreža, međumodalnih predstavljanja i latentno usklađenje prostora između instrukcija i odgovora kandidata za rješavanje problema. Predstavljamo ograničeno maksimalno skupljanje koje refinira maksimalnu operaciju skupljanja na matrici usklađivanja kako bi stavili nesavršene ograničenje među ishodama modela. Naš rezultat procjene ukazuje na poboljšanje od 19% na početne linije.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi foreslår en ny justeringsmekanisme til at håndtere proceduremæssige ræsonnementer på et nyligt udgivet multimodalt QA datasæt, kaldet RecipeQA. Vores model løser den tekstlige cloze opgave, som er en læseforståelse på en opskrift indeholdende billeder og instruktioner. Vi udnytter kraften i opmærksomhedsnetværk, tværmodale repræsentationer og et latent tilpasningsrum mellem instruktioner og kandidatsvar for at løse problemet. Vi indfører begrænset maks-pooling, som forfiner maks-pooling operationen på justering matrix for at pålægge disjoint begrænsninger mellem udgangene af modellen. Vores evalueringsresultat indikerer en forbedring på 19% i forhold til basislinjerne.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Kami mengusulkan mekanisme penyesuaian baru untuk berurusan dengan alasan prosedur pada set data QA multimodal yang baru dibebaskan, bernama RecipeQA. Model kami adalah memecahkan tugas penutup teks yang merupakan pemahaman pembacaan pada resep yang mengandung gambar dan instruksi. Kami mengeksploitasi kekuatan jaringan perhatian, representation transmodal, dan ruang penyesuaian tertutup antara instruksi dan jawaban kandidat untuk memecahkan masalah. Kami memperkenalkan penggabungan maksimum yang memperbaiki operasi penggabungan maksimum pada matriks penyesuaian untuk memaksa penggabungan di antara hasil model. Hasil evaluasi kami menunjukkan 19% peningkatan atas garis dasar.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Wir schlagen einen neuartigen Alignment-Mechanismus vor, um die prozedurale Argumentation auf einem neu veröffentlichten multimodalen QA-Datensatz namens RecipeQA zu behandeln. Unser Modell löst die textuelle Cloze-Aufgabe, also ein Leseverständnis auf einem Rezept, das Bilder und Anweisungen enthält. Wir nutzen die Kraft von Aufmerksamkeitsnetzwerken, crossmodalen Darstellungen und einem latenten Ausrichtungsraum zwischen Anweisungen und Kandidaten Antworten, um das Problem zu lösen. Wir führen eingeschränktes Max-Pooling ein, das die maximale Pooling-Operation auf der Ausrichtungsmatrix verfeinert, um disjunkte Einschränkungen zwischen den Ausgängen des Modells aufzuerlegen. Unser Bewertungsergebnis weist auf eine 19% Verbesserung gegenüber den Basislinien hin.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 새로운 정렬 메커니즘을 제시하여 새로 발표된 다중모드 QA 데이터 집합 RecipeQA의 과정 추리를 처리했다.우리의 모델은 텍스트의 빈칸을 채우는 임무를 해결하는 것이다. 이것은 이미지와 설명이 포함된 식단에 대한 읽기와 이해이다.우리는 주의 네트워크, 크로스 모드 표시와 지령과 후보 답안 사이의 잠재적인 일치 공간을 이용하여 문제를 해결한다.우리는 모델의 출력 사이에 교차하지 않는 제약을 가하기 위해 정렬 행렬의 최대 탱크 조작을 개선했다.우리의 평가 결과는 기선보다 19퍼센트 높아졌다는 것을 나타냈다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>ما پیشنهاد می‌کنیم یک مکانیسم تنظیم نوی برای حل با دلیل‌های پردازشی در یک مجموعه داده‌های چندیmodal QA جدید آزاد شده، به نام RecipeQA. مدل ما این کار را حل می‌کند که یک درس خواندن درباره یک فرصت که دارد تصاویر و دستورات است. ما قدرت شبکه‌های توجه، نمایش‌های مختلف مدال و فضای تطبیعی latent بین دستورات و جواب‌های کاندیدا برای حل مشکل استفاده می‌کنیم. ما مجازات max-pooling محدودیت را معرفی می‌کنیم که عملیات max pooling را بر ماتریکس تنظیم می‌کند تا محدودیت متصل در بین نتیجه‌های مدل قرار دهد. نتیجه ارزیابی ما به عنوان توسعه ۱۹ درصد بر خط زیرزمین نشان می دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Ons voorstel 'n roman alignment mechanism om met prosedureel redensie te behandel op 'n nuwe verlos multimodaal QA datastel, genaamd RecipeQA. Ons model is die verlos van die tekstuele klose taak wat 'n lees verstanding is op 'n resep wat beelde en instruksies bevat. Ons gebruik die krag van aandagnetwerke, kruismodale voorstellings, en 'n latente oplyn spasie tussen instruksies en kandidate antwoorde om die probleem te los. Ons introduseer beperkte maksimale pooling wat die maksimale pooling operasie op die lyn matriks herstel om ondersteunde beheinings onder die uitvoerdes van die model te imposseer. Ons evalueringsresultaat wys 'n 19% verbetering oor die basilyne.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Biz prosedürler razylygy täze bir multimodal QA datasetinde çykmak üçin bir taýýarlama mehanizmini teklip edýäris. Biziň modelimiz suratlar we görkezmeler bar bir resimde düşünýän tekstiň klosiň täblisini çözýär. Biz üns a ňlaryň güýji, çarpyş modal temsilleri we meseläni çözmek üçin ýüz çykyş gapynyň arasynda geçişik gabdalygyny ulanýarys. Biz, modelin çizgileri arasında son derece birleştirme matrisine son derece azaltılan maksimum birleşme işlemini tanıtıyoruz. Taýýarlanmamyzyň netijesi baseçiklerde 19% gelişmegi ýagdaýyny görkezýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Ne propozojmë një mekanizëm të ri të përshtatjes për të trajtuar arsyetimin procedural mbi një grup të dhënash QA multimodal të lëshuar sapo, të quajtur RecipeQA. Modeli ynë është zgjidhja e detyrës së mbylljes tekstuale që është një kuptim leximi në një recetë që përmban imazhe dhe udhëzime. Ne shfrytëzojmë fuqinë e rrjeteve të vëmendjes, përfaqësimet ndërmodali dhe një hapësirë të fshehtë të përshtatjes midis udhëzimeve dhe përgjigjeve të kandidatëve për të zgjidhur problemin. Ne futim maksimum-pooling të kufizuar që rafinon operacionin maksimum pooling në matricën e alignment për të imponuar kufizime disjoint midis rezultateve të modelit. Rezultati ynë i vlerësimit tregon një përmirësim prej 19% mbi linjat bazë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_sw>Tunazipendekeza mfumo wa usambazaji wa riwaya kupambana na sababu za utaratibu kuhusu seti ya data mpya ya QA, inayoitwa RecipeQA. Mfano wetu ni kutatua jukumu la kufungiwa kwa mfumo ambao ni ufahamu wa kusoma kwenye picha na maelekezo. Tunatumia nguvu ya mitandao ya ufuatiliaji, uwakilishi wa mitandao mbalimbali, na nafasi ya usafirishaji wa hivi karibuni kati ya maelekezo na majibu ya wagombea ili kutatua tatizo. Tunawasilisha upunguaji wa kiwango kikubwa ambao unaonyesha operesheni ya mabadiliko ya kiasi kikubwa kwenye viwanda vya upasuaji ili kuweka vikwazo vya pamoja miongoni mwa matokeo ya modeli. Matokeo yetu yanaonyesha maendeleo ya asilimia 19 zaidi ya misingi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք առաջարկում ենք նոր հարմարեցման մեխանիզմ, որպեսզի վերաբերվենք նորից հրատարակված բազմամոդալ QA տվյալների համակարգի, որը կոչվում է "Պատկեր"։ Մեր մոդելը լուծում է տեքստալ փակցման խնդիրը, որը պատկերներ և հրահանգներ պարունակող բաղադրատոմի ընթերցման ընկալում է: Մենք օգտագործում ենք ուշադրության ցանցերի ուժը, խաչմոդալ ներկայացումները, և խնդիրը լուծելու համար հրահանգների և թեկնածու պատասխանների միջև թաքնված համապատասխանման տարածքը: Մենք ներկայացնում ենք սահմանափակ մաքսային հավաքածու, որը բարելավում է մաքսային հավաքածու գործողությունը հավաքածու մատրիքսի վրա, որպեսզի պարտադրենք անհավաքածու սահմանափակումներ մոդելի արդյունքների մեջ: Մեր գնահատման արդյունքը ցույց է տալիս 19 տոկոս բարելավում հիմնական գծերի համեմատ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>አዲስ በተፈታው የQA ዳታተር የተባለውን አዲስ አዲስ በተለየ የQA ዳታ ማሰናከል የመረጃ አካላትን ለመቀናቀል እናስባለን፡፡ ሞዴሌያችን ምስሎች እና ትምህርት በሚይዙ መዝገብ ላይ የሚነበብ ድምፅ ነው፡፡ የጥያቄ መረብ ኃይል፣ የክፍለ ሥልጣናዎች እና የመግለጫ እና በጭንቀት መቆጣጠርን ለመፍታት የሚችሉትን ስልጣናት እናጠይቃለን፡፡ በሞላው ውጤቶች መካከል የተለየ ግንኙነት እንዲያሳርፍ የቁጥጥር ማህበረሰብ ማድረግ በሚያሳየው አካባቢ ጉዳይ እናስገድዳለን፡፡ ምርጫው ፍጻሜያችን በመሠረት ላይ 19 በመቶ ክፍተት የሚያሳየው ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Biz yeni çıxarılmış çoxlu modal QA veri qutusu, RecipeQA adlı proseqül dəyişiklikləri ilə çəkmək üçün yeni bir tərəfləmə mehanizmini təklif edirik. Bizim modelimiz şəkillər və öyrətmələr barəsində oxuyan məlumatları çəkir. Biz bu problemi çəkmək üçün gözləmə a ğlarının, çoxlu modal göstəricilərin gücünü və təsirlərin və kandidat cevaplarının arasındakı uzaqlaşdırmaq üçün istifadə edirik. Biz müəyyən edilmiş max-pooling işlətməsini modelinin çıxışları arasında müəyyən etmək üçün müəyyən edilmiş max-pooling işlətməsini təmizləyirik. Bizim təcrübəmiz sonuçlarımız baz çətinlərin üstündə 19%-ni yaxşılaşdırmağı göstərir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>We propose a novel alignment mechanism to deal with procedural reasoning on a newly released multimodal QA dataset, named RecipeQA.  আমাদের মডেল হচ্ছে টেক্সুয়াল ক্লোজের কাজ সমাধান করছে যা ছবি এবং নির্দেশ রয়েছে একটি রেসিপির উপর পড়তে পারে। আমরা মনোযোগ নেটওয়ার্ক, ক্রাস-মডেল প্রতিনিধিত্ব এবং সাম্প্রতিক নির্দেশ এবং প্রার্থীদের উত্তর সমাধানের জন্য একটি স্থান ব্যবহার আমরা নিষিদ্ধ ব্যবস্থার ব্যাপারে পরিচিতি দেখাচ্ছি যা মডেলের আউটপুটের মধ্যে সর্বোচ্চ পুলিং কার্যক্রম প্রতিষ্ঠানের প্রতিষ্ঠানের মা আমাদের মূল্যায়নের ফলাফল নির্দেশ করে যে ১৯% বেসারেন্টের উপর উন্নতি প্রদান করা হয়েছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Predlažemo novi mehanizam usklađivanja da se suoči sa proceduralnim razumijevanjem o novom objavljenom multimodalnom kompletu podataka QA, po imenu RecipeQA. Naš model rješava tekstualni kloz zadatak koji je razumijevanje čitanja o recepu koji sadrži slike i upute. Koristimo moć pažnje mreža, međumodalnih predstavljanja i latentno usklađenje prostora između instrukcija i odgovora kandidata za rješavanje problema. Predstavljamo ograničeno maksimalno skupljanje koje refinira maksimalnu operaciju skupljanja na matrici usklađivanja kako bi stavili nesavršene ograničenje među ishodama modela. Naš rezultat procjene ukazuje na poboljšanje od 19% na osnovne linije.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Proposem un nou mecanisme d'allinjament per abordar el raonament procedimental d'un nou conjunt de dades multimodals QA, anomenat RecipeQA. El nostre model és resoldre la tasca de cloze textual que és una comprensió de lectura en una receta que conté imatges i instruccions. Exploitem el poder de les xarxes d'atenció, les representacions transmodals i un espai latent d'allinjament entre instruccions i respostes candidates per resoldre el problem a. Introduïm una combinació màxima restringida que refina l'operació de combinació màxima a la matriu d'allinjament per imposar restriccions de descomposició entre els productes del model. El resultat de la nostra evaluació indica una millora del 19% sobre les línies de base.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Navrhujeme nový mechanismus alignace pro řešení procesního uvažování na nově vydaném multimodálním datovém souboru QA s názvem RecipeQA. Náš model řeší textovou cloze úlohu, což je porozumění čtení receptu obsahující obrázky a instrukce. K řešení problému využíváme sílu pozornostních sítí, crossmodálních reprezentací a latentního prostoru zarovnání mezi instrukcemi a kandidátskými odpověďmi. Představujeme omezené max-pooling, které upřesňuje operaci maximálního poolingu na zarovnávací matici tak, aby mezi výstupy modelu byla uložena disjunkční omezení. Výsledek hodnocení ukazuje na 19% zlepšení oproti základním liniím.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Me pakume v瓣lja uue koosk繭lastamismehhanismi, et k瓣sitleda menetluslikku arutlust 瓣sja avaldatud mitmeliigilise kvaliteedi tagamise andmekogumi RecipeQA puhul. Meie mudel lahendab tekstilise sulgemise 羹lesande, mis on kujutisi ja juhiseid sisaldava retsepti lugemine. Probleemi lahendamiseks kasutame t瓣helepanuv繭rgustike, modaalsete representatsioonide j繭udu ning latentset joondusruumi juhiste ja kandidaadivastuste vahel. Me v繭tame kasutusele piiratud maksimaalse koondamise, mis t瓣psustab maksimaalset koondamise operatsiooni joondamismaatriksis, et kehtestada dis羹hised piirangud mudeli v瓣ljundite vahel. Meie hindamistulemus n瓣itab 19% paranemist v繭rreldes l瓣htetasemega.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Ehdotamme uutta linjausmekanismia, jolla käsitellään menettelyjä äskettäin julkaistussa multimodaalisessa laadunvarmistustiedossa nimeltä RecipeQA. Mallimme ratkaisee tekstuaalisen cloze-tehtävän eli lukuymmärryksen reseptistä, joka sisältää kuvia ja ohjeita. Hyödynnämme huomion verkostojen, multimodaalisten esitysten voimaa ja piilevää linjaustilaa ohjeiden ja ehdokasvastausten välillä ongelman ratkaisemiseksi. Otamme käyttöön rajoitetun max-pooling-toiminnon, joka tarkentaa max-pooling-toimintoa linjausmatriisin asettamiseksi disjoint restrictions mallin tuotoksille. Arviointituloksemme osoittavat 19 prosentin parannuksen lähtötasoon verrattuna.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé nggunakake perusahaan nggawe barang nggawe barang manipulan sing beraksi dadi multimodal modellus Awak dhéwé nglanggar aturan tambah, gambar perusahaan modal, lan tambah banter perusahaan langgar sampek iso nggawe tarjamahan lan tambah banter kebijakan tenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Rasané awakdhéwé éntuk kanggo ngerasahan kanggo ngerasahan kanggo ngerasah 19%.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Tune goyyar da wani matsayin juyi na yanzu don ka yi aiki da abun aiki a kan tsarin QA da aka saka wata na yanzu-yanzu masu tsẽre na QA da sunan RecipeQA. MisalinMu yana yin rabo ga aikin kullum na rubutu, wannan yana da fansar karatun karatun a kan wata motsi wanda yana da zane da shiryarwa. Munã amfani da ƙarfin mitandaki masu kiyaye, masu wakin-masu kore-modal, da fili mai sauya a yanzu a tsakanin shiryoyin da kuma masu kandida dõmin su sola mataimaki. Tuna ƙara shi da aka ƙudura maki-poolin da ke ƙara aikin makõmi a kan matrix a juyi dõmin ya lazimta da taƙaitacce a cikin matabbatan motel. Matarinmu na ƙaddara yana indiyar mafarinta 19% a bincike.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>אנו מציעים מנגנון התאמה חדש כדי להתמודד עם הסיבה הניתוחית על קבוצת מידע QA multimodal שפורסמה חדשה, בשם RecipeQA. הדוגמא שלנו פותרת את משימה הסגירה הטקסטולית, שהיא הבנה קריאה על מתכון שמכיל תמונות וההוראות. אנחנו מנצלים את הכוח של רשתות תשומת לב, מייצגים דרך מודל, וחלל התאמה מוסתר בין ההוראות לתשובות המועמדים לפתור את הבעיה. אנחנו מציגים מחסום מקס-בריצה שממשיך את מבצע המקס-בריצה על מטריקס ההתאמה כדי להכריח מחסומים מחוסרים בין יציאות המודל. תוצאות הערכה שלנו מצביעות על שיפור של 19% מעל קווי הבסיס.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Predlagamo nov mehanizem usklajevanja za obravnavanje procesnih razlogov na novo objavljenem multimodalnem naboru podatkov o zagotavljanju kakovosti, imenovanem RecipeQA. Naš model je reševanje naloge besedilnega bloza, ki je bralno razumevanje recepta, ki vsebuje slike in navodila. Za rešitev problema izkoriščamo moč mrež pozornosti, medmodalnih reprezentacij in latentnega poravnavanega prostora med navodili in kandidatnimi odgovori. Uvedli smo omejeno max-pooling, ki izboljšuje največjo operacijo združevanja na poravnalni matriki, da bi uvedli ločene omejitve med izhodi modela. Rezultat naše ocene kaže na 19-odstotno izboljšanje v primerjavi z izhodiščnimi vrednostmi.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་གསར་བ་སྒྲིག་གི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་དང་ལས་སྦྱོར་བའི་རྒྱུ་རྐྱེན་ཀྱི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག་ཆ ང་ཚོའི་མ་དབྱིབས ང་ཚོས་དྲ་དམངས་ཀྱི་སྟོབས་ཤུགས་སྟོན་དང་། ཐབས་ལམ་ལུགས་པའི་ངོས་འཛིན་བྱེད་ཀྱི་གནས་སྟངས་དང་ཆ་རྐྱེན་པའི་མཐུན་སྒྲིག ང་ཚོས་གཞུང་ཕྱོགས་ཀྱི་max-pooling སྒྲིག་ཐག་ཡོད་པའི་ཆེ་ཤོས་མཉམ་གྱི་བཀོད་སྒྲིག་གི་matrix ལ་ཆེ་ཤོས་མཉམ་དུ་བཞག་ཡོད། ང་ཚོའི་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་ཀྱི་རྐྱེན་འབྲས་ནི་གཞུང་གཞིའི་ཕྱོགས་ཀྱི་རྒྱལ་ཁབ་༡༩་ཡར་རྒྱས་རྒྱས་གཏོང་།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>