<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nlpcovid19">
  <volume id="acl" ingest-date="2020-10-13">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> for <fixed-case>COVID-19</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>ACL</fixed-case> 2020</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Karin</first><last>Verspoor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kevin Bretonnel</first><last>Cohen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mark</first><last>Dredze</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Emilio</first><last>Ferrara</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jonathan</first><last>May</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Robert</first><last>Munro</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Cecile</first><last>Paris</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Byron</first><last>Wallace</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="fddac610">2020.nlpcovid19-acl.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp-covid19-2020-nlp</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Document Classification for COVID-19 Literature<fixed-case>COVID-19</fixed-case> Literature</title>
      <author><first>Bernal</first><last>Jiménez Gutiérrez</last></author>
      <author><first>Juncheng</first><last>Zeng</last></author>
      <author><first>Dongdong</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Ping</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Yu</first><last>Su</last></author>
      <abstract>The global pandemic has made it more important than ever to quickly and accurately retrieve relevant scientific literature for effective consumption by researchers in a wide range of fields. We provide an analysis of several multi-label document classification models on the LitCovid dataset. We find that pre-trained language models outperform other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> in both low and high data regimes, achieving a maximum F1 score of around 86 %. We note that even the highest performing models still struggle with label correlation, distraction from introductory text and CORD-19 generalization. Both data and code are available on GitHub.</abstract>
      <url hash="e5936d8e">2020.nlpcovid19-acl.3</url>
      <bibkey>jimenez-gutierrez-etal-2020-document-classification</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Self-supervised context-aware COVID-19 document exploration through atlas grounding<fixed-case>COVID-19</fixed-case> document exploration through atlas grounding</title>
      <author><first>Dusan</first><last>Grujicic</last></author>
      <author><first>Gorjan</first><last>Radevski</last></author>
      <author><first>Tinne</first><last>Tuytelaars</last></author>
      <author><first>Matthew</first><last>Blaschko</last></author>
      <abstract>In this paper, we aim to develop a self-supervised grounding of Covid-related medical text based on the actual spatial relationships between the referred anatomical concepts. More specifically, we learn to project sentences into a physical space defined by a three-dimensional anatomical atlas, allowing for a visual approach to navigating Covid-related literature. We design a straightforward and empirically effective training objective to reduce the curated data dependency issue. We use BERT as the main building block of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> and perform a quantitative analysis that demonstrates that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> learns a context-aware mapping. We illustrate two potential use-cases for our approach, one in interactive, 3D data exploration, and the other in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_retrieval">document retrieval</a>. To accelerate research in this direction, we make public all trained models, codebase and the developed tools, which can be accessed at https://github.com/gorjanradevski/macchina/.</abstract>
      <url hash="ea5b60e4">2020.nlpcovid19-acl.5</url>
      <bibkey>grujicic-etal-2020-self</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/gorjanradevski/macchina" additional="false">gorjanradevski/macchina</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Estimating the effect of COVID-19 on mental health : Linguistic indicators of depression during a global pandemic<fixed-case>COVID-19</fixed-case> on mental health: Linguistic indicators of depression during a global pandemic</title>
      <author><first>JT</first><last>Wolohan</last></author>
      <abstract>This preliminary analysis uses a deep LSTM neural network with fastText embeddings to predict population rates of depression on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reddit">Reddit</a> in order to estimate the effect of COVID-19 on mental health. We find that year over year, depression rates on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reddit">Reddit</a> are up 50 %, suggesting a 15-million person increase in the number of depressed Americans and a $ 7.5 billion increase in depression related spending. This finding suggests that utility in NLP approaches to longitudinal public-health surveillance.</abstract>
      <url hash="9bd09de3">2020.nlpcovid19-acl.12</url>
      <bibkey>wolohan-2020-estimating</bibkey>
    <title_ar>تقدير تأثير COVID-19 على الصحة النفسية: المؤشرات اللغوية للاكتئاب أثناء جائحة عالمي</title_ar>
      <title_es>Estimación del efecto de COVID-19 en la salud mental: indicadores lingüísticos de la depresión durante una pandemia mundial</title_es>
      <title_pt>Estimando o efeito do COVID-19 na saúde mental: indicadores linguísticos de depressão durante uma pandemia global</title_pt>
      <title_ja>新型コロナウイルスの精神衛生への影響の推定：世界的なパンデミック中のうつ病の言語学的指標</title_ja>
      <title_zh>度COVID-19心理健康:全球大行抑郁症语指标</title_zh>
      <title_hi>मानसिक स्वास्थ्य पर कोविड-19 के प्रभाव का आकलन: वैश्विक महामारी के दौरान अवसाद के भाषाई संकेतक</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Éifeacht COVID-19 ar mheabhairshláinte a mheas: Táscairí teanga an dúlagar le linn paindéime domhanda</title_ga>
      <title_ka>COVID-19 ეფექტის განსაზღვრება მეგონიკალური ჯანმრთზე: დეპრესიის ლინგისტიკური ინდექტორი გლობალური ონდემიკის განმავლობაში</title_ka>
      <title_el>Εκτίμηση της επίδρασης του στην ψυχική υγεία: Γλωσσολογικοί δείκτες κατάθλιψης κατά τη διάρκεια μιας παγκόσμιας πανδημίας</title_el>
      <title_hu>A COVID-19 mentális egészségre gyakorolt hatásának becslése: A depresszió nyelvi mutatói egy globális járvány alatt</title_hu>
      <title_it>Stimare l'effetto del COVID-19 sulla salute mentale: indicatori linguistici della depressione durante una pandemia globale</title_it>
      <title_kk>COVID-19 психикалық саулықтың эффектін есептеу: Глобалдық пандемияда депрессия лингвистикалық индикаторы</title_kk>
      <title_lt>COVID-19 poveikio psichikos sveikatai įvertinimas. Kalbų rodikliai, susiję su depresija pasaulinės pandemijos metu</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Проценка на ефектот на COVID-19 на менталното здравје: Лингвистичките индикатори на депресија за време на глобалната пандемија</title_mk>
      <title_ml>മാനസിക ആരോഗ്യത്തിന്റെ പ്രഭാവം കോവിഡി-19-ന്റെ എണ്ണിമിടുക്കുന്നു: ഗ്ലോബല്‍ പാന്‍ഡെമിക്കിനുള്ള സമയത്ത്</title_ml>
      <title_mn>COVID-19-ын сэтгэл санааны эрүүл мэндийн нөлөөг тооцоолж байна: Дэлхийн пандемикийн үед депрессийн хэлбэрийн үзүүлэлт</title_mn>
      <title_ms>Penghargaan kesan COVID-19 pada kesihatan mental: Indikator bahasa depresi semasa pandemi global</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Stima tal-effett ta’ COVID-19 fuq is-saħħa mentali: Indikaturi lingwistiċi tad-depressjoni matul pandemija globali</title_mt>
      <title_no>Estemer effekten av COVID-19 på mentale helse: Lingstyske indikatorer for depresjon under ein globalt pandemisk</title_no>
      <title_pl>Ocena wpływu COVID-19 na zdrowie psychiczne: Językowe wskaźniki depresji w czasie globalnej pandemii</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Procjenjujući učinak COVID-19 na mentalno zdravlje: Lingistički indikatori depresije tokom globalne pandemije</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Estimarea efectului COVID-19 asupra sănătății mintale: Indicatori lingvistici ai depresiei în timpul unei pandemii globale</title_ro>
      <title_si>COVID-19 ප්‍රතිකාරය අනුමාණය කරනවා මානසික ස්වාස්ථාවට: ලිංග්‍යිස්ටික සංකේතකයේ සාමාන්‍ය ප්‍රතිකාරයේ</title_si>
      <title_so>Estimating the effect of COVID-19 on mental health: Linguistic indicators of depression during a global pandemic</title_so>
      <title_sv>Beräkning av effekten av COVID-19 på psykisk hälsa: Språkliga indikatorer på depression under en global pandemi</title_sv>
      <title_ta>COVID-19 தாக்கத்தின் விளைவை கணக்கிடுகிறது: உலக புனைத்தோற்றத்தின் காலத்தில் உள்ள நெருக்கம் குறிப்புகளின் வரிசை</title_ta>
      <title_ur>COVID-19 کی مذہنی سلامتی پر اثر کا ارزش کیا گیا ہے: گروئیل پانڈمیک کے موقع افسردگی کی لینگیسٹی نشانیاں</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Khả năng dự đoán tác động của COVID-19 lên hệ thống thần kinh: Chỉ số ngôn ngữ trầm cảm trong một đại dịch toàn cầu</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Оценка на ефекта на КОВИД-19 върху психичното здраве: лингвистични показатели за депресия по време на глобална пандемия</title_bg>
      <title_da>Vurdering af virkningen af COVID-19 på mental sundhed: Sproglige indikatorer for depression under en global pandemi</title_da>
      <title_nl>Het effect van COVID-19 op de geestelijke gezondheid schatten: Taalkundige indicatoren van depressie tijdens een wereldwijde pandemie</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Procjenjujući učinak COVID-19 na mentalno zdravlje: Lingistički indikatori depresije tijekom globalne pandemije</title_hr>
      <title_de>Abschätzung der Auswirkungen von COVID-19 auf die psychische Gesundheit: Sprachliche Indikatoren für Depressionen während einer globalen Pandemie</title_de>
      <title_fa>تحریف تاثیر COVID-19 بر سلامت روانی: نشانه‌های لینگیستیک افسردگی در طول یک پاندمیک جهانی</title_fa>
      <title_id>Penghargaan efek COVID-19 pada kesehatan mental: indikator bahasa depresi selama pandemi global</title_id>
      <title_ko>코로나가 심리건강에 미치는 영향 추정: 팬데믹(세계적 대유행) 기간 우울증의 언어지표</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Inakadiria madhara ya COVID-19 juu ya afya ya akili: indicators of linguistic depression during a gonjwa la dunia</title_sw>
      <title_sq>Estimating the effect of COVID-19 on mental health: Linguistic indicators of depression during a global pandemic</title_sq>
      <title_af>Die effek van COVID-19 op geestelike gesondheid: Linguistiese indikators van depresiër tydens 'n globaal pandemie</title_af>
      <title_tr>COVID-19'nin akıl sağlığına etkisini tahmin ediyor:</title_tr>
      <title_hy>COVID-19-ի ազդեցությունը հոգեկան առողջության վրա գնահատելը. դեպրեսիայի լեզվական ցուցանիշները գլոբալ պանդեմիայի ընթացքում</title_hy>
      <title_am>የCOVID-19 የmental ጤና ውጤትን በመቆጣጠር: ዓለምአቀፍ ደዌብ ውስጥ የድምፅ ግንኙነት ማሳየት</title_am>
      <title_az>COVID-19'nin psihini sağlığına təsir edildiyini təmin edir: küresel pandemik sırasında depresiyanın Linguistik göstəricisi</title_az>
      <title_bn>মানসিক স্বাস্থ্যের উপর কভিড-১৯ প্রভাব হিসেবে গণনা করা: বিশ্বের বিপর্যয়ের সময় বিশ্বের দুর্দশার সময় লিঙ্গিস্ট</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Procjenjujući učinak COVID-19 na mentalno zdravlje: Lingistički indikatori depresije tokom globalne pandemije</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Estimating the effect of COVID-19 on mental health: Linguistic indicators of depression during a global pandemic</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Odhad vlivu COVID-19 na duševní zdraví: Jazykové ukazatele deprese během globální pandemie</title_cs>
      <title_et>COVID-19 mõju hindamine vaimsele tervisele: depressiooni keelelised näitajad ülemaailmse pandeemia ajal</title_et>
      <title_fi>COVID-19:n vaikutus mielenterveyteen: Kielelliset indikaattorit masennuksesta maailmanlaajuisen pandemian aikana</title_fi>
      <title_ha>Ina ƙaddara Effekt of COV-19 on wata aikin akin aikin ƙwarai: Linguistic indicts of depression during a global bukati</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Ocena učinka COVID-19 na duševno zdravje: jezikovni kazalniki depresije med globalno pandemijo</title_sk>
      <title_he>הערכה של השפעה של COVID-19 על בריאות נפשית: מדריכים לינגוליים של דיכאון במהלך פנדמיה גלובלית</title_he>
      <title_jv>tau</title_jv>
      <title_bo>COVID-19 ནུས་ཡོད་ཚད་ལྟར་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་ནུས་ཡོད།</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>يستخدم هذا التحليل الأولي شبكة LSTM العصبية العميقة المزودة بزفاف سريع للنصوص للتنبؤ بمعدلات اكتئاب السكان على Reddit من أجل تقدير تأثير COVID-19 على الصحة العقلية. وجدنا أنه عامًا بعد عام ، ارتفعت معدلات الاكتئاب في Reddit بنسبة 50٪ ، مما يشير إلى زيادة قدرها 15 مليون شخص في عدد الأمريكيين المصابين بالاكتئاب وزيادة 7.5 مليار دولار في الإنفاق المرتبط بالاكتئاب. تشير هذه النتيجة إلى أن المنفعة في مناهج البرمجة اللغوية العصبية لترصد الصحة العامة الطولية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Este análisis preliminar utiliza una red neuronal LSTM profunda con incrustaciones de FastText para predecir las tasas de depresión de la población en Reddit con el fin de estimar el efecto de COVID-19 en la salud mental. Descubrimos que año tras año, las tasas de depresión en Reddit han subido un 50%, lo que sugiere un aumento de 15 millones de personas en el número de estadounidenses deprimidos y un aumento de $7.5 mil millones en el gasto relacionado con la depresión. Este hallazgo sugiere que la utilidad de los enfoques de PNL para la vigilancia longitudinal de la salud pública.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Esta análise preliminar usa uma rede neural LSTM profunda com embeddings fastText para prever as taxas populacionais de depressão no Reddit, a fim de estimar o efeito do COVID-19 na saúde mental. Descobrimos que, ano após ano, as taxas de depressão no Reddit aumentaram 50%, sugerindo um aumento de 15 milhões de pessoas no número de americanos deprimidos e um aumento de US $ 7,5 bilhões nos gastos relacionados à depressão. Esta descoberta sugere que a utilidade das abordagens de PNL para a vigilância longitudinal da saúde pública.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>この予備分析では、新型コロナウイルス感染症（ COVID -19 ）の精神的健康への影響を推定するために、高速テキスト埋め込みを備えた深層LSTMニューラルネットワークを使用して、Redditのうつ病の集団率を予測します。Redditのうつ病率は昨年比で50 ％上昇しており、うつ病のアメリカ人の数は1500万人増加し、うつ病関連の支出は75億ドル増加していることが示唆されています。この調査結果は、NLPにおけるユーティリティが縦断的な公衆衛生監視にアプローチすることを示唆している。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>其初析用带fastText嵌之深LSTM神经网络以占Reddit上抑郁症群发病率,以度COVID-19之心理健康也。 臣伏见Reddit上抑郁症发病率累年升50%,明抑郁症美国人数增1500万,抑郁症关支益75亿美元也。 此见明NLP,公共卫生监测之效也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>यह प्रारंभिक विश्लेषण मानसिक स्वास्थ्य पर कोविड -19 के प्रभाव का अनुमान लगाने के लिए रेडिट पर अवसाद की जनसंख्या दर की भविष्यवाणी करने के लिए फास्टटेक्स्ट एम्बेडिंग के साथ एक गहरे एलएसटीएम तंत्रिका नेटवर्क का उपयोग करता है। हम पाते हैं कि साल-दर-साल, रेडिट पर अवसाद की दर 50% ऊपर है, जो उदास अमेरिकियों की संख्या में 15 मिलियन व्यक्ति की वृद्धि और अवसाद से संबंधित खर्च में $ 7.5 बिलियन की वृद्धि का सुझाव देती है। इस खोज से पता चलता है कि एनएलपी में उपयोगिता अनुदैर्ध्य सार्वजनिक स्वास्थ्य निगरानी के लिए दृष्टिकोण करती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Úsáideann an réamhanailís seo líonra néarúil LSTM domhain le leabaithe fastText chun rátaí dúlagar daonra ar Reddit a thuar chun éifeacht COVID-19 ar mheabhairshláinte a mheas. Faighimid amach go bhfuil rátaí dúlagar ar Reddit suas 50% bliain i ndiaidh bliana , rud a thugann le tuiscint go bhfuil méadú 15-milliún duine ar líon na Meiriceánaigh dúlagar agus méadú $7.5 billiún ar chaiteachas a bhaineann le dúlagar. Tugann an toradh seo le fios go gcuireann áirgiúlacht i NLP chuige maidir le faireachas sláinte poiblí fadaimseartha.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ეს პირველი ანალიზი გამოიყენება LSTM ნეიროლური ქსელი, რომელიც FastText-ის შებრუნებულებებით, რომ რედიტის მოსახლეობის დიპრესციის სიმაღლე წარმოიდგინოთ, რომ COVID-19 ეფექტის მეცნიერო სი ჩვენ მივიღეთ ეს წლის შემდეგ, რედიტის დეპრესციის რაოდენობა 50%, რომელიც 15 მილიონის ადამიანის განმავლობაში აღმოჩენა ევპრესციული ამერიკანეთების და 7,5 მილიონი დოლარის განმავლობაში. ეს აღმოჩნევა, რომ NLP-ში სუტილიტება მოხდება დიდინალური საზოგადოებო-ჯანმრთელო დანახვა.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Ez az előzetes elemzés egy mély LSTM neurális hálózatot használ gyorsText beágyazásokkal a Redditen depresszió populációs arányának előrejelzésére annak érdekében, hogy becsüljük a COVID-19 mentális egészségre gyakorolt hatását. Azt tapasztaltuk, hogy évről évre a Reddit depressziós rátája 50%-kal emelkedett, ami arra utal, hogy 15 millió emberrel növekszik a depressziós amerikaiak száma és 7,5 milliárd dollárral növekszik a depressziós kiadások. Ez a megállapítás arra utal, hogy az NLP-ben hasznos megközelítések a hosszanti közegészségügyi felügyelet.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Αυτή η προκαταρκτική ανάλυση χρησιμοποιεί ένα βαθύ νευρωνικό δίκτυο με ενσωμάτωση γρήγορου κειμένου για να προβλέψει τα ποσοστά κατάθλιψης του πληθυσμού στο Reddit προκειμένου να εκτιμηθεί η επίδραση του στην ψυχική υγεία. Διαπιστώνουμε ότι χρόνο με το χρόνο, τα ποσοστά κατάθλιψης στο Reddit αυξάνονται 50% , γεγονός που υποδηλώνει μια αύξηση 15-εκατομμυρίων ατόμων στον αριθμό των καταθλιπτικών Αμερικανών και μια αύξηση $7,5 δισεκατομμυρίων δαπανών που σχετίζονται με την κατάθλιψη. Αυτό το εύρημα υποδηλώνει ότι η χρησιμότητα της NLP προσεγγίζει τη διαμήκη επιτήρηση της δημόσιας υγείας.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Questa analisi preliminare utilizza una rete neurale LSTM profonda con incorporazioni FastText per prevedere i tassi di depressione della popolazione su Reddit al fine di stimare l'effetto del COVID-19 sulla salute mentale. Troviamo che anno dopo anno, i tassi di depressione su Reddit sono aumentati del 50%, suggerendo un aumento di 15 milioni di persone nel numero di americani depressi e un aumento di 7,5 miliardi di dollari nella spesa legata alla depressione. Questa constatazione suggerisce che l'utilità nel PNL si avvicina alla sorveglianza longitudinale della sanità pubblica.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>This preliminary analysis uses a deep LSTM neural network with fastText embeddings to predict population rates of depression on Reddit in order to estimate the effect of COVID-19 on mental health.  Matome, kad per metus Reddit depresijos lygis padidėjo 50 proc., o tai rodo, kad 15 mln. žmonių padidėjo depresijos amerikiečių skaičius ir 7,5 mlrd. dolerių padidėjo su depresija susijusios išlaidos. Iš šių išvadų matyti, kad NLP naudinga taikyti išilginę visuomenės sveikatos priežiūrą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл алдыңғы анализ түсті LSTM невралды желіне тез ендіру үшін Редит депрессиясының депрессия жиілігін көрсету үшін, психикалық саулығына COVID- 19 эффектін бағалау үшін қолданылады. Біз оны жылдан бастап таптық, Редит депрессиясының депрессиясы 50% - көтеріп, 15 миллион адамдардың депрессиялық американдық санына көтеріп, 7,5 миллион доллар депрессиялық зарядтарына көтеріп жатыр. Бұл табу NLP құрылғысының көпшілік саулық бақылау үшін көпшілікті көпшілікті бақылау мүмкіндігін жасайды.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Analisis awal ini menggunakan rangkaian saraf LSTM dalam dengan penyampaian teks pantas untuk meramalkan kadar penduduk depresi pada Reddit untuk menghargai kesan COVID-19 pada kesehatan mental. Kami mendapati bahawa tahun-tahun, kadar depresi pada Reddit meningkat 50%, mencadangkan 15 juta orang meningkat bilangan orang Amerika depresi dan meningkat 7.5 bilion dolar dalam menghabiskan berkaitan depresi. Penemuan ini menunjukkan bahawa utiliti dalam NLP mendekati pengawasan kesehatan awam longitudinal.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Оваа прелиминарна анализа користи длабока нервна мрежа на ЛСТМ со брзи текстови внесувања за да се предвидат стапките на популација на депресија на Редит со цел да се процени ефектот на COVID-19 на менталното здравје. Најдовме дека годината, стапките на депресија на Редит се зголемија за 50 отсто, што предлага зголемување на бројот на депресивни Американци од 15 милиони лица и зголемување на трошоците поврзани со депресијата од 7,5 милијарди американски долари. Оваа заклучка покажува дека корисноста во НЛП се приближува до долгитудиналното набљудување на јавното здравје.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ ആദ്യ വിശ്വാസം വെളുത്ത ടെക്സ്റ്റ് എസ്റ്റം ന്യൂറല്‍ നെറുല്‍ നെറുല്‍ നെറ്റര്‍ നെറ്റ്‌വര്‍ക്ക് ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു. റെഡിറ്റില്‍ വിപത്തിന്റെ  വര്‍ഷത്തിനു മുഴുവന്‍ വര്‍ഷത്തില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടെത്തുന്നു, റെഡിഡിറ്റിന്റെ വിപത്തിന്റെ വിലപ്പെടുത്തുന്ന വിലപ്പെടുത്തുന്ന വിലപ്പെടുത്ത This finding suggests that utility in NLP approaches to longitudinal public-health surveillance.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Din l-analiżi preliminari tuża netwerk newrali fond ta’ LSTM b’inkorporazzjonijiet rapidiText biex tipprevedi r-rati ta’ depressjoni tal-popolazzjoni fuq Reddit sabiex jiġi stmat l-effett ta’ COVID-19 fuq is-saħħa mentali. Issibu li sena wara sena, ir-rati ta’ depressjoni fuq Reddit żdiedu b’50 %, li jissuġġerixxu żieda ta’ 15-il miljun persuna fin-numru ta’ Amerikani depressi u żieda ta’  $7.5 biljun fl-infiq relatat mad-depressjoni. This finding suggests that utility in NLP approaches to longitudinal public-health surveillance.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ анхны шинжилгээ нь ЛСТМ мэдрэлийн сэтгэл санааны эрүүл мэнд COVID-19-ын нөлөөг тооцоолох үед хүн амын депрессийн хурдыг Reddit-д тооцоолж, FastText-тэй гүн гүнзгий мэдрэлийн сүлжээг ашигладаг. Бид тэр жилийн хугацаанд Reddit-ийн депресс хувьд 50%-аар нэмэгдсэн байна. 15 сая хүн депресс Америкчуудын тоо нэмэгдсэн ба 7.5 тэрбум долларын депресс зардалд нэмэгдсэн байна. Энэ шийдэл нь NLP-ын урт хугацаанд нийтийн эрүүл мэндийн удирдлагын тулд хэрэглээний тусламжтай байдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Denne førehandsvisinga brukar ein dyp LSTM- neuralnettverk med raskt innbygging av tekst for å foregå befolkningsrate av depresjon på Reddit for å vurdere effekten COVID- 19 på mentalshelse. Vi finn det året over år, avskriftsrate på Reddit er opp 50%, som fører til at 15 millioner personer øk i antallet depreserte amerikanar og 7,5 milliardar dollar øk i depresjonsrelaterte utgifter. Dette oppdaginga tyder på at verktøyet i NLP nærmer seg til langsiktig offentlige-helseovervåking.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Această analiză preliminară utilizează o rețea neuronală LSTM profundă cu încorporări FastText pentru a prezice ratele populației depresiei pe Reddit pentru a estima efectul COVID-19 asupra sănătății mintale. Descoperim că, an de an, ratele depresiei pe Reddit au crescut cu 50%, sugerând o creștere de 15 milioane de persoane a numărului de americani deprimați și o creștere de 7,5 miliarde de dolari a cheltuielilor legate de depresie. Această constatare sugerează că utilitatea în PNL abordează supravegherea longitudinală a sănătății publice.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejsza wstępna analiza wykorzystuje głęboką sieć neuronową LSTM z osadzeniami fastText do przewidywania wskaźników depresji populacji na Reddit w celu oszacowania wpływu COVID-19 na zdrowie psychiczne. Odkrywamy, że z roku na rok wskaźnik depresji na Reddit wzrasta 50% , co sugeruje 15-milionowy wzrost liczby osób w depresji oraz $7,5 miliardy wydatków związanych z depresją. Wyniki te sugerują, że użyteczność NLP podejścia do wzdłużnego nadzoru zdrowia publicznego jest użyteczna.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_sr>Ova preliminarna analiza koristi duboku LSTM neuralnu mrežu sa fastText integracijama kako bi predvidjela stope depresije na Reddit kako bi procenila učinak COVID-19 na mentalno zdravlje. Pronašli smo te godine preko godine, stope depresije na Reddit povećavaju 50%, sugerirajući povećanje broja depresivnih Amerikanaca i povećanje troškova povezanih s depresijom od 7,5 milijardi dolara. Ovaj nalaz ukazuje na to da korisnost u NLP-u pristupi dužinskom nadzoru javnog zdravlja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ ප්‍රධාන විශ්ලේෂණය භාවිතා කරනවා ගොඩක් LSTM න්‍යූරල් ජාලය, FastText Embdings සඳහා ප්‍රධාන විශ්ලේෂණයක් ප්‍රශ්නය කරනවා Rededit වල ජාතික අපි ඒ අවුරුද්දේ අවුරුද්දෙන් හොයාගත්තා, රෙඩිට්ට් එක්ක අවුරුද්ධ විශාලය 50% විතරයි, අවුරුද්ධ විශාලයෙන් අමරිකානු මිලි මේ හොයාගන්න පුළුවන් විදිහට NLP වලින් ප්‍රයෝජනයක් ලොකු ජාතික ස්වාස්ත්වය බලන්න පුළුවන්.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Denna preliminära analys använder ett djupt LSTM neuralt nätverk med fastText inbäddningar för att förutsäga populationsfrekvensen av depression på Reddit för att uppskatta effekten av COVID-19 på psykisk hälsa. Vi finner att depression på Reddit år över år är upp med 50%, vilket tyder på en 15 miljoner människor ökning av antalet deprimerade amerikaner och en ökning på 7,5 miljarder dollar i depressionsrelaterade utgifter. Detta resultat tyder på att nyttan i NLP närmar sig longitudinell folkhälsoövervakning.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Analyskaas hore wuxuu isticmaalaa shabakad aad u weyn oo LSTM neural ah oo ku yaala fast Text embeddings si uu u hor mariyo qiimeynta kharashka depression ee Reddit si uu u qiimeeyo saamaynta COVID-19 ee caafimaadka dhimirka. Sannadaas sanad ka badan, qiimaha cashuurta cashuurta cashuurta cashuurta cashuurta Reddit waxay qaadaneysaa 50 boqolkiiba, taasoo looga jeedaa in qofka 15 milyan oo qof ka korodo tirada dadka mareykanka aad u dhibaataysay, waxayna korodhsadaan 7,5 billion oo dollar oo kharashka kharashka ku saabsan kharashka. Baaritaankaas waxaa loola jeedaa in isticmaalka NLP uu u dhowaado ilaalinta caafimaadka dhaadheerka ah ee dadweynaha.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த முதல் ஆய்வு ஒரு ஆழமான LSTM புதிய வலைப்பின்னலை பயன்படுத்துகிறது fast Text embeddings to predict population rate of depression on Reddit on to predict COVID-19 on mental health. நாம் அந்த வருடத்திற்கு மேல் கண்டுபிடிக்கிறோம், ரெட்டிட் விகிதம் 50 சதவிகிதம் அதிகமாக இருக்கும், ஒரு 15 மில்லியன் நபர் ஆழ்ந்த அமெரிக்காவின் எண்ணி இந்த கண்டுபிடிப்பு NLP யில் பயன்பாடு நீண்ட பொது நலம் கண்காணிப்பு நெருங்குகிறது என்று தெரிவிக்கிறது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>اس سے پہلے تحقیقات کا استعمال کرتا ہے ایک عمیق LSTM نیورال نیورل نیٹ ورک کے ساتھ FastText embeddings کے ساتھ روڈیٹ پر جمعیت کے درجے کی پیش بینی کرنے کے لئے روانی سلامتی پر COVID-19 کے اثر کا ارزش کرنا۔ ہم نے اس سال سے زیادہ پایا ہے کہ ریڈیٹ پر افسردگی رخصت 50% بڑی ہوتی ہے، جو 15 میلیون شخص افسردگی امریکائن کی تعداد میں اضافہ کرتا ہے اور 7.5 میلیارد دلار افسردگی کی خرچ میں اضافہ کرتا ہے۔ یہ پیدا کرنا مشورہ کرتا ہے کہ NLP میں فائدہ دولتی عمومی سلامتی نظارت کے لئے پہنچ جاتا ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Text embeddinglari bilan boshqa tarmoqni ishlatish uchun oddiy tarmoqni qo'yish uchun Reddit'ning boshqaruvchisi chegarasini koʻrsatish uchun COVID-19 o'zgarishni anglatadi. Biz yili yildan ko'p o'tganimiz Reddit'da o'zgarishni 50%ko'payapmiz, o'ylab, 15 millionlab odamning soni ko'payishi va 7.5 milliard dollari o'zgartiradi. Bu aniqlash imkoniyatini, NLP'ning foydalanishi o'zgarishni o'zgartiradi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Phân tích sơ bộ này sử dụng một hệ thống thần kinh LSD sâu với sự nhúng lót nhanh Nhãn để dự đoán tỉ lệ suy sụp dân số trên Reddit để dự đoán hiệu quả của COVID-19 trên sức khỏe tinh thần. Chúng tôi thấy rằng năm qua năm, tỉ lệ trầm cảm trên Reddit đã cao hơn 500kg, cho thấy có một số người tăng lên 15-triệu người trong số lượng dân Mỹ suy sụp và một tỷ suất tăng lên trong chi tiêu phụ thuộc trầm cảm. Việc tìm kiếm này cho thấy hữu ích trong lập trình NLP nên theo dõi sức khỏe cộng đồng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>Deze voorlopige analyse maakt gebruik van een diep LSTM neuraal netwerk met fastText embeddings om populatiepercentages van depressie op Reddit te voorspellen om het effect van COVID-19 op de geestelijke gezondheid te schatten. We vinden dat jaar na jaar, depressiepercentages op Reddit stijgen 50% , wat suggereert een 15-miljoen mensen toename in het aantal depressieve Amerikanen en een $7,5 miljard stijging in depressieve uitgaven. Deze bevinding suggereert dat nut in NLP benadert longitudinale volksgezondheidssurveillance.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Ova preliminarna analiza koristi duboku LSTM neuralnu mrežu s fastText integracijama kako bi predvidjela stopu populacije depresije na Reddit kako bi procijenila učinak COVID-19 na mentalno zdravlje. Pronađemo te godine preko godine, stope depresije na Reddit povećavaju 50%, što ukazuje na povećanje broja depresivnih Amerikanaca od 15 milijuna osoba i povećanje troškova povezanih s depresijom od 7,5 milijardi dolara. Ovaj nalaz ukazuje na to da korisnost u NLP-u pristupi dužinskom nadzoru javnog zdravlja.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Този предварителен анализ използва дълбока невронна мрежа с вграждания за прогнозиране на процентите на депресия в Редит, за да се оцени ефектът на COVID-19 върху психичното здраве. Откриваме, че година след година процентът на депресия в Редит се покачва с 50%, което предполага 15 милиона души увеличение на броя на депресираните американци и 7,5 милиарда долара увеличение на разходите, свързани с депресията. Тази констатация предполага, че полезността при НЛП подходи към надлъжното обществено здравно наблюдение.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Denne foreløbige analyse bruger et dybt LSTM neuralt netværk med fastText-indlejringer til at forudsige populationsfrekvenser af depression på Reddit for at estimere effekten af COVID-19 på mental sundhed. Vi finder, at år over år, depression rater på Reddit er steget med 50%, hvilket tyder på en 15 millioner mennesker stigning i antallet af deprimerede amerikanere og en $ 7,5 milliarder stigning i depression relaterede udgifter. Denne konklusion tyder på, at nytten i NLP nærmer sig langsgående overvågning af folkesundheden.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Diese vorläufige Analyse verwendet ein tiefes LSTM neuronales Netzwerk mit fastText Einbettungen, um Bevölkerungsraten von Depressionen auf Reddit vorherzusagen, um den Effekt von COVID-19 auf die psychische Gesundheit abzuschätzen. Wir stellen fest, dass die Depressionsraten auf Reddit Jahr über 50% steigen, was auf einen 15-Millionen-Anstieg der Zahl der depressiven Amerikaner und einen Anstieg der Ausgaben in Bezug auf Depression hindeutet. Diese Erkenntnis legt nahe, dass NLP Ansätze zur longitudinalen Überwachung der öffentlichen Gesundheit sinnvoll sind.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>این تحلیل پیشینیانی از شبکه عصبی LSTM عمیق با سرعت تغییرات متن استفاده می‌کند تا نرخ جمعیت افسردگی روی Reddit را پیش بینی کند تا تاثیر COVID-19 بر سلامت روانی ارزیابی کند. ما آن سال را در طول سال پیدا کردیم، درجه افسردگی روی ردیدت 50 درصد بالا می‌شود، پیشنهاد می‌دهد که افزایش تعداد افسردگی آمریکایی‌های ۱۵ میلیون دلار و افزایش هزینه‌ی میلیارد دلار در هزینه‌های افسردگی رابطه دار این پیدا پیشنهاد می‌دهد که استفاده از NLP به مراقبت سلامت عمومی در طول برسد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Analisis awal ini menggunakan jaringan saraf LSTM dalam dengan daftar teks cepat untuk memprediksi tingkat populasi depresi pada Reddit untuk memperkirakan efek COVID-19 pada kesehatan mental. Kami menemukan bahwa tahun-tahun, tingkat depresi pada Reddit meningkat 50% , menyarankan 15 juta orang meningkat jumlah orang Amerika yang depresi dan meningkat 7,5 miliar dolar pada biaya yang berkaitan dengan depresi. Penemuan ini menunjukkan bahwa utilitas di NLP mendekati pengawasan kesehatan publik panjang.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>이 초기 분석은 코로나가 심리 건강에 미치는 영향을 가늠하기 위해 패스트텍트가 박힌 심층 LSTM 신경 네트워크를 사용했다.지난해 같은 기간과 비교해 레딧의 우울증 발병률이 50% 상승한 것은 미국 우울증 환자 수가 1천500만명, 우울증 관련 지출이 75억달러 증가한 것을 보여준다.이 발견은 NLP 방법이 수직 공중보건 모니터링에서의 실용성을 나타낸다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Uchambuzi huu wa awali unatumia mtandao wa neura wa LSTM wenye matokeo ya haraka kutabiri kiwango cha idadi ya watu wa mawasiliano kwenye Reddit ili kutathmini athari ya COVID-19 juu ya afya ya akili. We find that year over year, depression rates on Reddit are up 50% , suggesting a 15-million person increase in the number of depressed Americans and a $7.5 billion increase in depression related spending.  Ugunduzi huu unapendekeza kuwa matumizi ya NLP yanakaribia kufuatiliwa kwa muda mrefu wa afya ya umma.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Bu öňki analizi moda, günahsy saglygyna COVID-19 täsirini takmynmak üçin adamlaryň ýigrimini çaklamak üçin tizlikleri bilen alçan LSTM neural neteýäni ullanýar Bu ýyldan bäri pikir edýäris, Reddit'yň depresiýasynyň azalyşy 50%-den artyk bolýar, 15 milliýon adam depresiýaly Amerikalylaryň sanynyň azalyşy we 7,5 milliýon dolar ýagdaýda harplary artyk diýip çaklaýar. Bu tapmak NLP'yň ýüzünlik-saglygyň gözlemegine golaýlaşyny maslahat berýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>This preliminary analysis uses a deep LSTM neural network with fastText embeddings to predict population rates of depression on Reddit in order to estimate the effect of COVID-19 on mental health.  በዚያች ዓመት በዓመቱ ላይ፣ የድምጽ ቁጥር 50 በመቶ ያነሳል፣ የአሜሪካውያንን ቁጥር 15 ሚሊዮን ሰው ያበዛል፡፡ ይህም ማግኘት የNLP ጥቅምነት የህዝብ ጤናዊ ግልጾችን ለመግኘት ይገልጣል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie vorige analisie gebruik 'n diep LSTM neuralnetwerk met fastText inbettings om bevolking tempo van depresiëring op Reddit te voorskou om die effek van COVID- 19 op mentale gesondheid te evalueer. Ons vind daardie jaar oor jaar, depresiër tempo op Reddit is 50%, wat 'n 15-miljoen persoon vergroot in die aantal depresiërde Amerikaanse en 'n $7,5 biljoen vergroot in depresiër verwante spesifikasie. Hierdie vinding stel voorstel dat nuttigheid in NLP toegang tot langste openbare-gesondige onderhouering.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Այս նախաձեռնական վերլուծությունը օգտագործում է LSMT-ի խորը նյարդային ցանց արագ տեքստի ներդրումներով Reddit-ի դեպրեսիայի բնակչության մակարդակի կանխատեսելու համար COVID-19 ազդեցությունը հոգեկան առողջության վրա: Մենք հայտնաբերում ենք, որ տարիների ընթացքում Reddit-ի դեպրեսիայի մակարդակը 50 տոկոսով բարձրանում է, և առաջարկում է, որ դեպրեսիայի հետ կապված ծախսերի թիվը 15 միլիոն մարդ աճի և 7.5 միլիարդ դոլար աճի: This finding suggests that utility in NLP approaches to longitudinal public-health surveillance.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu ilk analizi FastText in şalları ilə LSTM nöral şəbəkəsini Reddit'in nümunələrinin depresiyanın dərəcəsini təmin etmək üçün CVID-19'nin səhnə sağlamlığının etkisini təmin etmək üçün istifadə edir. Biz bu il üstündə Reddit'in depresiya oranı 50%-dən artır və 15 milyon insanın depresiya Amerikalıların sayısını artırmağını və depresiya bağlı xərcləmələrini 7,5 milyard dolar artırmağını iddia edirik. Bu tapışma NLP'də uzun-uzun halkı sağlığı gözləməyə yaxınlaşır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>এই প্রাথমিক বিশ্লেষণ মানসিক স্বাস্থ্যের উপর কভিড-১৯ এর প্রভাব হিসেবে গভীর এলস্টিএম নিউরেল নেটওয়ার্ক ব্যবহার করে। আমরা বছরের বেশি বছর পাই, রেডিডিটের দুর্দশার হার ৫০ শতাংশ, যার পরামর্শ দেয়া হচ্ছে যে দুর্দশা আমেরিকানদের সংখ্যায় ১৫ লক্ষ লোক বৃদ্ধি করে এবং দুঃখের ব এই খুঁজে পাওয়ার পরামর্শ প্রদান করে যে এনএলপির ব্যবহার দীর্ঘদিনের জনস্বাস্থ্য পর্যবেক্ষণের কাছে আসছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Tato předběžná analýza využívá hlubokou LSTM neuronovou síť s vložením fastText k predikci populačních mír deprese na Redditu s cílem odhadnout vliv COVID-19 na duševní zdraví. Zjišťujeme, že rok v průběhu roku stoupá míra deprese na Redditu 50% , což naznačuje nárůst počtu depresivních Američanů o patnáct milionů lidí a zvýšení výdajů souvisejících s depresemi $7,5 miliardy. Toto zjištění naznačuje, že užitečnost NLP přístupu k podélnému dohledu veřejného zdraví.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_sq>Kjo analizë paraprake përdor një rrjet nervor të thellë LSTM me përfshirje të shpejtë Teksti për të parashikuar normat e popullsisë të depresionit në Reddit me qëllim që të vlerësohet efekti i COVID-19 në shëndetin mendor. Ne e gjejmë atë vit gjatë vitit, normat e depresionit në Reddit janë në rritje 50%, duke sugjeruar një rritje prej 15 milion njerëzish në numrin e amerikanëve të depresionuar dhe një rritje prej 7.5 miliardë dollarësh në shpenzimet e lidhura me depresionin. Ky gjetje sugjeron se shërbimi në NLP afrohet mbikqyrjes longitudinale të shëndetit publik.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_ca>Aquesta anàlisi preliminar utilitza una xarxa neuronal LSTM profunda amb incorporacions de text ràpid per predir el índex de depressió de població en Reddit per estimar l'efecte de COVID-19 en la salut mental. Trobem que aquest any a l'any, els índics de depressió en Reddit augmenten del 50%, suggerent un increment de 15 milions de persones en el nombre d'americans deprimit i un increment de 7,5 mil milions de dòlars en gastos relacionats amb la depressió. This finding suggests that utility in NLP approaches to longitudinal public-health surveillance.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>T채ss채 alustavassa analyysiss채 k채ytet채채n syv채채 LSTM-neuroverkkoa fastText-upotuksineen ennustamaan masennuksen v채est철m채채r채채 Redditiss채 arvioidakseen COVID-19:n vaikutusta mielenterveyteen. Havaitsemme, ett채 vuosi vuodelta masennusluvut Redditiss채 ovat nousseet 50%, mik채 viittaa 15 miljoonan ihmisen kasvuun masentuneiden amerikkalaisten lukum채채r채ss채 ja 7,5 miljardin dollarin kasvuun masennukseen liittyviss채 menoissa. T채m채 havainto viittaa siihen, ett채 NLP:ss채 hy철dynnet채채n pitkitt채ist채 kansanterveyden seurantaa.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Selles esialgses analüüsis kasutatakse sügavat LSTM neurovõrku koos fastTexti manustamisega, et ennustada populatsiooni depressiooni määra Redditis, et hinnata COVID-19 mõju vaimsele tervisele. Me leiame, et aasta-aastaselt on depressiooni määr Redditis tõusnud 50%, mis viitab 15 miljoni inimese suurenemisele depressioonis ameeriklaste arvus ja 7,5 miljardi dollari suurusele depressiooniga seotud kulutuste suurenemisele. See järeldus näitab, et uue õppekava kasulikkus läheneb rahvatervise pikisuunalisele seirele.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>Ova preliminarna analiza koristi duboku LSTM neuralnu mrežu s fastText integracijama kako bi predvidjela stopu populacije depresije na Reddit kako bi procenila učinak COVID-19 na mentalno zdravlje. Pronađemo te godine preko godine, stope depresije na Reddit povećavaju 50%, što ukazuje na povećanje broja depresivnih Amerikanaca i povećanje troškova povezanih s depresijom od 7,5 milijardi dolara. Ovaj nalaz ukazuje na to da korisnost u NLP-u pristupi dužinskom nadzoru javnog zdravlja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_jv>text embedding Awak dhéwé tauh luwih nèng tau matan, dadine kuwi rasané dipunangé dipunangé dolar sing katêpakan liman budharé, supoyo cah sabané tanggal dolar kanggo kowé Ndheke nggawe iki supoyo kanggo ngerasakno kanggo ngilanggar NdLP kuwi nggawe barang langgar-langgar barang popokoan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Ta predhodna analiza uporablja globoko LSTM nevronsko omrežje z vdelavami fastText za napovedovanje populacijskih stopenj depresije na Redditu, da bi ocenili učinek COVID-19 na duševno zdravje. Ugotovili smo, da so stopnje depresije na Redditu letno naraščale za 50%, kar kaže na 15 milijonov ljudi povečanje števila depresivnih Američanov in 7,5 milijarde dolarjev povečanje porabe, povezane z depresijo. Ta ugotovitev kaže, da uporabnost pri novem programu pristopa k vzdolžnemu nadzoru javnega zdravja.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Text embeddings to prophesy the rates of depression on Rededit to estimate the Effekt of COV-19 on shida mentally. Munã sãmu wato a shekara kodi a shekara kodi Rededit na ƙari 50%, yana madaidaitar an ƙara ƙidãyar mutane da tarakin amerikaneki 15 kuma a ƙara $7.5 billion in dola za'a ga matuƙar da taƙaitacce. Wannan gandin yana son cẽwa amfani da ke cikin NLP yana kusa a ƙara tsarin tsarin mafaka na umma.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>This preliminary analysis uses a deep LSTM neural network with fastText embeddings to predict population rates of depression on Reddit in order to estimate the effect of COVID-19 on mental health. ང་ཚོས་ལོ་འདི་ལྟར་མཇུག་བསྡུ་ཡོད། བསྐྱེད་ཚད་དཔལ་འཛོམས་ཀྱི་ཚད་ཕྱུར་འགྲོ་བཞིན་ཡོད། རྙེད་སྐབས་འདི་ནི་(NLP)ནང་གི་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་རྒྱུ་དངོས་མི་མང་གི་སྐྱོན་བརྗོད་ལྟ་སྟངས་ལ་ཕན་གནང་བ་རེད།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>ניתוח קודמי זה משתמש ברשת עצבית LSTM עמוקה עם תוספות טקסט מהיר כדי לחזות שיעורי הדיכאון של אוכלוסיה על רדיט כדי להעריך את ההשפעה של COVID-19 על בריאות נפשית. אנחנו מוצאים ששנה במהלך השנה, שיעורי הדיכאון על רדיט עלו ב-50 אחוזים, מה שמציע עליה של 15 מיליון אנשים במספר אמריקאים מדוכאים ועלייה של 7.5 מיליארד דולר בהוצאות קשורות לדיכאון. המצאה הזו מצביעה כי שימושי ב NLP מתקרב למעקב ציבורי-בריאות ארוך.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Exploration of Gender Differences in COVID-19 Discourse on Reddit<fixed-case>COVID-19</fixed-case> Discourse on <fixed-case>R</fixed-case>eddit</title>
      <author><first>Jai</first><last>Aggarwal</last></author>
      <author><first>Ella</first><last>Rabinovich</last></author>
      <author><first>Suzanne</first><last>Stevenson</last></author>
      <abstract>Decades of research on differences in the language of men and women have established postulates about the nature of lexical, topical, and emotional preferences between the two genders, along with their sociological underpinnings. Using a novel dataset of male and female linguistic productions collected from the Reddit discussion platform, we further confirm existing assumptions about gender-linked affective distinctions, and demonstrate that these distinctions are amplified in social media postings involving emotionally-charged discourse related to COVID-19. Our analysis also confirms considerable differences in topical preferences between male and female authors in pandemic-related discussions.</abstract>
      <url hash="a2380764">2020.nlpcovid19-acl.13</url>
      <bibkey>aggarwal-etal-2020-exploration</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ellarabi/covid19-demography" additional="false">ellarabi/covid19-demography</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/rwwd">RWWD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Cross-lingual Transfer Learning for COVID-19 Outbreak Alignment<fixed-case>COVID-19</fixed-case> Outbreak Alignment</title>
      <author><first>Sharon</first><last>Levy</last></author>
      <author><first>William Yang</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <abstract>The spread of COVID-19 has become a significant and troubling aspect of society in 2020. With millions of cases reported across countries, new outbreaks have occurred and followed patterns of previously affected areas. Many disease detection models do not incorporate the wealth of social media data that can be utilized for modeling and predicting its spread. It is useful to ask, can we utilize this knowledge in one country to model the outbreak in another? To answer this, we propose the task of cross-lingual transfer learning for epidemiological alignment. Utilizing both macro and micro text features, we train on Italy’s early COVID-19 outbreak through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a> and transfer to several other countries. Our experiments show strong results with up to 0.85 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spearman_correlation">Spearman correlation</a> in cross-country predictions.</abstract>
      <url hash="b944647e">2020.nlpcovid19-acl.15</url>
      <bibkey>levy-wang-2020-cross</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>NLP-based Feature Extraction for the Detection of COVID-19 Misinformation Videos on YouTube<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case>-based Feature Extraction for the Detection of <fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 Misinformation Videos on <fixed-case>Y</fixed-case>ou<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>ube</title>
      <author><first>Juan Carlos</first><last>Medina Serrano</last></author>
      <author><first>Orestis</first><last>Papakyriakopoulos</last></author>
      <author><first>Simon</first><last>Hegelich</last></author>
      <abstract>We present a simple NLP methodology for detecting COVID-19 misinformation videos on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube">YouTube</a> by leveraging user comments. We use transfer learning pre-trained models to generate a multi-label classifier that can categorize conspiratorial content. We use the percentage of misinformation comments on each video as a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_feature">feature</a> for video classification.</abstract>
      <url hash="2520463f">2020.nlpcovid19-acl.17</url>
      <bibkey>medina-serrano-etal-2020-nlp</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/JuanCarlosCSE/YouTube_misinfo" additional="false">JuanCarlosCSE/YouTube_misinfo</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
  <volume id="2" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> for <fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 (Part 2) at <fixed-case>EMNLP</fixed-case> 2020</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Karin</first><last>Verspoor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kevin Bretonnel</first><last>Cohen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Michael</first><last>Conway</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Berry</first><last>de Bruijn</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mark</first><last>Dredze</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Rada</first><last>Mihalcea</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Byron</first><last>Wallace</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="27ecd857">2020.nlpcovid19-2.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp-covid19-2020-nlp-covid</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    </volume>
</collection>