<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.gamnlp">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Workshop on Games and Natural Language Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Stephanie M.</first><last>Lukin</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-40-5</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="7f0760eb">2020.gamnlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>gamesandnlp-2020-games</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Creating a Sentiment Lexicon with Game-Specific Words for Analyzing NPC Dialogue in The Elder Scrolls V : Skyrim<fixed-case>NPC</fixed-case> Dialogue in The Elder Scrolls <fixed-case>V</fixed-case>: Skyrim</title>
      <author><first>Thérèse</first><last>Bergsma</last></author>
      <author><first>Judith</first><last>van Stegeren</last></author>
      <author><first>Mariët</first><last>Theune</last></author>
      <pages>1–9</pages>
      <abstract>A weak point of rule-based sentiment analysis systems is that the underlying sentiment lexicons are often not adapted to the domain of the text we want to analyze. We created a game-specific sentiment lexicon for video game Skyrim based on the E-ANEW word list and a dataset of Skyrim’s in-game documents. We calculated sentiment ratings for NPC dialogue using both our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexicon">lexicon</a> and E-ANEW and compared the resulting sentiment ratings to those of human raters. Both lexicons perform comparably well on our evaluation dialogues, but the game-specific extension performs slightly better on the dominance dimension for dialogue segments and the arousal dimension for full dialogues. To our knowledge, this is the first time that a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis lexicon</a> has been adapted to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_game">video game domain</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="4e3a8f74">2020.gamnlp-1.1</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>bergsma-etal-2020-creating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>ClueMeIn : Obtaining More Specific Image Labels Through a Game<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>lue<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>e<fixed-case>I</fixed-case>n: Obtaining More Specific Image Labels Through a Game</title>
      <author><first>Christopher</first><last>Harris</last></author>
      <pages>10–16</pages>
      <abstract>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESP_Game">ESP Game</a> (also known as the Google Image Labeler) demonstrated how the crowd could perform a task that is straightforward for humans but challenging for computers   providing labels for images. The game facilitated the task of basic image labeling ; however, the labels generated were non-specific and limited the ability to distinguish similar images from one another, limiting its ability in search tasks, annotating images for the visually impaired, and training computer vision machine algorithms. In this paper, we describe ClueMeIn, an entertaining web-based game with a purpose that generates more detailed image labels than the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESP_Game">ESP Game</a>. We conduct experiments to generate specific image labels, show how the results can lead to improvements in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of image searches over image labels generated by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ESP_Game">ESP Game</a> when using the same public dataset.</abstract>
      <url hash="7052a434">2020.gamnlp-1.2</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>harris-2020-cluemein</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Cipher : A Prototype Game-with-a-Purpose for Detecting Errors in Text<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ipher: A Prototype Game-with-a-Purpose for Detecting Errors in Text</title>
      <author><first>Liang</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <author><first>Jon</first><last>Chamberlain</last></author>
      <pages>17–25</pages>
      <abstract>Errors commonly exist in machine-generated documents and publication materials ; however, some correction algorithms do not perform well for complex errors and it is costly to employ humans to do the task. To solve the problem, a prototype <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PC_game">computer game</a> called Cipher was developed that encourages people to identify errors in text. Gamification is achieved by introducing the idea of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steganography">steganography</a> as the entertaining game element. People play the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game">game</a> for entertainment while they make valuable annotations to locate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typographical_error">text errors</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prototype">prototype</a> was tested by 35 players in a evaluation experiment, creating 4,764 annotations. After filtering the data, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> detected manually introduced text errors and also genuine errors in the texts that were not noticed when they were introduced into the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game">game</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="7a6ca76c">2020.gamnlp-1.3</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>xu-chamberlain-2020-cipher</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Game Design Evaluation of GWAPs for Collecting Word Associations<fixed-case>GWAP</fixed-case>s for Collecting Word Associations</title>
      <author><first>Mathieu</first><last>Lafourcade</last></author>
      <author><first>Le Brun</first><last>Nathalie</last></author>
      <pages>26–33</pages>
      <abstract>GWAP design might have a tremendous effect on its popularity of course but also on the quality of the data collected. In this paper, a comparison is undertaken between two GWAPs for building term association lists, namely JeuxDeMots and Quicky Goose. After comparing both game designs, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cohen_kappa">Cohen kappa</a> of associative lists in various configurations is computed in order to assess likeness and differences of the data they provide.</abstract>
      <url hash="9e10add5">2020.gamnlp-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>lafourcade-nathalie-2020-game</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>The Challenge of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_show">TV game</a> La Ghigliottina to NLP<fixed-case>TV</fixed-case> game La Ghigliottina to <fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Federico</first><last>Sangati</last></author>
      <author><first>Antonio</first><last>Pascucci</last></author>
      <author><first>Johanna</first><last>Monti</last></author>
      <pages>34–38</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we describe a Telegram bot, Mago della Ghigliottina (Ghigliottina Wizard), able to solve La Ghigliottina game (The Guillotine), the final game of the Italian TV quiz show L’Eredit. Our system relies on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">linguistic resources</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence">artificial intelligence</a> and achieves better results than human players (and competitors of L’Eredit too). In addition to solving a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game">game</a>, Mago della Ghigliottina can also generate new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game">game instances</a> and challenge the users to match the solution.</abstract>
      <url hash="614a5dfa">2020.gamnlp-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>sangati-etal-2020-challenge</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>A 3D Role-Playing Game for Abusive Language Annotation<fixed-case>D</fixed-case> Role-Playing Game for Abusive Language Annotation</title>
      <author><first>Federico</first><last>Bonetti</last></author>
      <author><first>Sara</first><last>Tonelli</last></author>
      <pages>39–43</pages>
      <abstract>Gamification has been applied to many linguistic annotation tasks, as an alternative to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crowdsourcing">crowdsourcing platforms</a> to collect annotated data in an inexpensive way. However, we think that still much has to be explored. Games with a Purpose (GWAPs) tend to lack important elements that we commonly see in commercial games, such as 2D and 3D worlds or a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plot_(narrative)">story</a>. Making GWAPs more similar to full-fledged video games in order to involve users more easily and increase dissemination is a demanding yet interesting ground to explore. In this paper we present a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role-playing_video_game">3D role-playing game</a> for abusive language annotation that is currently under development.</abstract>
      <url hash="2e29f585">2020.gamnlp-1.6</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>bonetti-tonelli-2020-3d</bibkey>
    <title_ar>لعبة ثلاثية الأبعاد لتقمص الأدوار للتعليقات التوضيحية للغة المسيئة</title_ar>
      <title_es>Un juego de rol en 3D para la anotación abusiva del lenguaje</title_es>
      <title_pt>Um jogo de interpretação de papéis 3D para anotação de linguagem abusiva</title_pt>
      <title_hi>अपमानजनक भाषा एनोटेशन के लिए एक 3 डी रोल-प्लेइंग गेम</title_hi>
      <title_ja>3 Dロールプレイングゲーム（罵倒的な言葉によるアノテーション）</title_ja>
      <title_zh>骂詈语言注3D角色扮演戏</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Cluiche Ról-Imeartha 3D maidir le Anótáil Teanga Mhí-úsáide</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>3D szerepjáték a visszaélő nyelvi jegyzékekhez</title_hu>
      <title_el>Ένα τρισδιάστατο παιχνίδι ρόλων για καταχρηστική γλωσσική παρατήρηση</title_el>
      <title_it>Un gioco di ruolo 3D per annotazioni di linguaggio abusivo</title_it>
      <title_lt>Name</title_lt>
      <title_mk>A 3D Role-Playing Game for Abusive Language Annotation</title_mk>
      <title_ms>A 3D Role-Playing Game for Abusive Language Annotation</title_ms>
      <title_kk>Үлкен тілді жаңалықтау үшін 3D роль ойнату ойыныName</title_kk>
      <title_ml>അബൂസിവ് ഭാഷ അറിയിപ്പിനുള്ള മൂന്നാം റോള്‍- കളിയ്ക്കുന്ന കളിName</title_ml>
      <title_no>Name</title_no>
      <title_pl>Gra w odgrywanie ról 3D dla nadużywających języków</title_pl>
      <title_mt>Logħob 3D ta’ Logħob tar-Rwol għall-Annotazzjoni tal-Lingwi Abużivi</title_mt>
      <title_sr>3D igračka igranja za abusivnu jezičku annotaciju</title_sr>
      <title_mn>Хүмүүсийн хэл анзаарлын 3D Role-Playing Game for Abusive Language Annotation</title_mn>
      <title_so>A 3D Role-Play game for Abusive Language Annotation</title_so>
      <title_sv>Ett 3D rollspel för missbrukande språkkommentarer</title_sv>
      <title_ro>Un joc de roluri 3D pentru adnotarea limbajului abuziv</title_ro>
      <title_ur>Name</title_ur>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Trò chơi bóng đường 3D cho chú thích ngôn ngữ lạm dụng</title_vi>
      <title_hr>3D igračka igranja za abusivnu jezičku annotaciju</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Триизмерна ролева игра за анотация на малтретиращ език</title_bg>
      <title_da>Et 3D rollespil til misbrug af sproganmeldelser</title_da>
      <title_de>Ein 3D Rollenspiel für missbräuchliche Sprachannotation</title_de>
      <title_ko>욕설 언어 주석을 위한 3D 롤 플레잉 게임</title_ko>
      <title_id>Permainan Permainan Role 3D untuk Annotasi Bahasa Abusif</title_id>
      <title_sw>Mchezo wa michezo ya mchezo wa 3D kwa ajili ya Tamko la Lugha ya Abusive</title_sw>
      <title_fa>Name</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Abusive Dil A ýatlary üçin 3nji rol oýun</title_tr>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_sq>Një lojë 3D e luajtjes së rolit për anotacionin e gjuhës abuzive</title_sq>
      <title_nl>Een 3D rollenspel voor misbruikende taal annotatie</title_nl>
      <title_am>ጨዋታውን ለጥቂት ጊዜ አሳርፍ</title_am>
      <title_hy>A 3D Role-Playing Game for Abusive Language Annotation</title_hy>
      <title_az>Abusive Dil Annotation üçün 3D Rol Oyunu</title_az>
      <title_bn>অ্যাবুসিভ ভ ভাষার ঘোষণার জন্য ত্রিমাত্রিক রোল- খেলা খেলাName</title_bn>
      <title_bs>3D igračka igranja za abusivnu jezičku annotaciju</title_bs>
      <title_et>3D rollimäng kuritarvitava keele annoteerimiseks</title_et>
      <title_cs>3D hra na role-playing pro zneužívající jazykové anotace</title_cs>
      <title_ca>Un joc 3D de joc de paper per anotació abusiva de llenguatges</title_ca>
      <title_fi>3D-roolipeli v채채rink채ytt채v채채 kielt채 varten</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Tampilan 3 Vol-Daftar Puteran kanggo Anatasi Buffet</title_jv>
      <title_he>A 3D Role-Playing Game for Abusive Language Annotation</title_he>
      <title_ha>Game na Role-Playing game for Abusive language Annonation</title_ha>
      <title_sk>3D igra vlog za opombe zlorabljajočega jezika</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Abusive Language Annotation (A 3D Role-Playing Game for Abusive Language Annotation)</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تم تطبيق Gamification على العديد من مهام التعليقات التوضيحية اللغوية ، كبديل لمنصات التعهيد الجماعي لجمع البيانات المشروحة بطريقة غير مكلفة. ومع ذلك ، نعتقد أنه لا يزال يتعين استكشاف الكثير. تميل الألعاب ذات الغرض (GWAPs) إلى الافتقار إلى العناصر المهمة التي نراها عادة في الألعاب التجارية ، مثل العوالم ثنائية وثلاثية الأبعاد أو القصة. إن جعل GWAPs أكثر تشابهًا مع ألعاب الفيديو الكاملة من أجل إشراك المستخدمين بسهولة أكبر وزيادة النشر هو أرضية متطلبة ولكنها مثيرة للاهتمام لاستكشافها. في هذا البحث ، نقدم لعبة تمثيل الأدوار ثلاثية الأبعاد للتعليقات التوضيحية اللغوية المسيئة قيد التطوير حاليًا.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>La gamificación se ha aplicado a muchas tareas de anotación lingüística, como una alternativa a las plataformas de crowdsourcing para recopilar datos anotados de forma económica. Sin embargo, creemos que aún queda mucho por explorar. Los juegos con un propósito (GWAPs) tienden a carecer de elementos importantes que comúnmente vemos en los juegos comerciales, como los mundos 2D y 3D o una historia. Hacer que los GWAP sean más similares a los videojuegos completos para involucrar más fácilmente a los usuarios y aumentar la difusión es un terreno exigente pero interesante de explorar. En este artículo presentamos un juego de rol en 3D para la anotación de lenguaje abusivo que se encuentra actualmente en desarrollo.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>A gamificação tem sido aplicada a muitas tarefas de anotação linguística, como uma alternativa às plataformas de crowdsourcing para coletar dados anotados de forma barata. No entanto, achamos que ainda há muito a ser explorado. Os jogos com um propósito (GWAPs) tendem a carecer de elementos importantes que comumente vemos em jogos comerciais, como mundos 2D e 3D ou uma história. Tornar os GWAPs mais semelhantes aos videogames completos para envolver os usuários mais facilmente e aumentar a disseminação é um terreno exigente, mas interessante a ser explorado. Neste artigo apresentamos um jogo de interpretação de papéis 3D para anotação de linguagem abusiva que está atualmente em desenvolvimento.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>ゲーミフィケーションは、安価な方法で注釈付きデータを収集するためのクラウドソーシングプラットフォームの代替として、多くの言語注釈タスクに適用されてきました。しかし、私たちはまだ多くのことを探求しなければならないと考えています。目的を持つゲーム（ GWAP ）は、2 Dや3 Dの世界やストーリーなど、商業ゲームで一般的に見られる重要な要素を欠いている傾向があります。ユーザーをより簡単に巻き込み、普及を高めるために、GWAPを本格的なビデオゲームに類似したものにすることは、厳しいながらも興味深い探求の場です。本稿では、現在開発中の濫用的な言語アノテーションのための3 Dロールプレイングゲームを紹介する。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>戏化已宜用诸语言注职,为众包平台代方案,以廉价集注数。 然臣等以为犹多所讨论。 有意之戏(GWAP)往往乏商贾之要,如2D与3D世故事。 使GWAP更类成熟之视频戏,以易入用户而增传之,是求高而有趣者也。 本文中,发一3D角色扮演戏,施于目前滥用语注。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>Gamification को कई भाषाई एनोटेशन कार्यों पर लागू किया गया है, जो एक सस्ती तरीके से एनोटेट किए गए डेटा को इकट्ठा करने के लिए क्राउडसोर्सिंग प्लेटफ़ॉर्म के विकल्प के रूप में है। हालांकि, हमें लगता है कि अभी भी बहुत कुछ पता लगाया जाना है। एक उद्देश्य के साथ खेल (GWAPs) महत्वपूर्ण तत्वों की कमी है कि हम आमतौर पर वाणिज्यिक खेल में देखते हैं, जैसे कि 2 डी और 3 डी दुनिया या एक कहानी के रूप में करते हैं। उपयोगकर्ताओं को अधिक आसानी से शामिल करने और प्रसार बढ़ाने के लिए GWAPs को पूर्ण वीडियो गेम के समान बनाना एक मांग अभी तक दिलचस्प जमीन का पता लगाने के लिए है। इस पेपर में हम अपमानजनक भाषा एनोटेशन के लिए एक 3 डी रोल-प्लेइंग गेम पेश करते हैं जो वर्तमान में विकास के तहत है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cuireadh gamification i bhfeidhm ar go leor tascanna anótála teanga, mar mhalairt ar ardáin sluafhoinsithe chun sonraí anótáilte a bhailiú ar bhealach neamhchostasach. Mar sin féin, is dóigh linn go bhfuil go leor fós le iniúchadh. Is gnách go mbíonn easpa gnéithe tábhachtacha ag cluichí le Cuspóir (GWAPanna) a fheicimid go coitianta i gcluichí tráchtála, mar shaol 2D agus 3D nó scéal. Is ábhar dúshlánach ach suimiúil é GWAPanna a dhéanamh níos cosúla le físchluichí iomlána chun go mbeidh úsáideoirí rannpháirteach ar bhealach níos éasca agus scaipeadh a mhéadú. Sa pháipéar seo cuirimid i láthair cluiche ról-imirt 3D le haghaidh nótaí maslacha teanga atá á fhorbairt faoi láthair.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>დამიფიკაცია ბევრი ლენგურისტიკური ანტორაციის მოქმედებისთვის გამოყენებულია, როგორც ალტენტიფიკაცია მუშაობის პლატატურებისთვის, რომ ამოყენებული მონაცემები არაფექციელი თუმცა, ჩვენ ვფიქრობთ, რომ უფრო მეტი უნდა იყოს განსხვავება. საზოგადომის თამაშები (GWAPs) უნდა იყოს მნიშვნელოვანი ელემენტები, რომლებიც ჩვენ საშუალოდ კომპერიოლური თამაშებში ხედავთ, როგორც 2D და 3D მსოფლიოში ან GWAPs-ს უფრო მსგავსია, რომელიც უფრო ადვილედ მომხმარებელი და უფრო მარტივი გახმარება, უფრო ინტერესური საფუძებაა. ამ დომენტში ჩვენ სამი პროლის თამაში გამოსახულებთ, რომელიც ახლა განვითარებულია.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A gamification számos nyelvi jegyzetelési feladatra alkalmazásra került, mint alternatíva a közösségi források platformjainak, hogy olcsó módon gyűjtsenek jegyzetelt adatokat. Úgy gondoljuk azonban, hogy még sok mindent kell feltárni. A célú játékok (GWAP-k) általában hiányoznak olyan fontos elemek, amelyeket gyakran látunk a kereskedelmi játékokban, mint például a 2D és 3D világok vagy egy történet. A felhasználók könnyebb bevonása és a terjesztés növelése érdekében a GWAP-k hasonlóbbá tétele a teljes értékű videojátékokhoz, igényes, mégis érdekes terület. Jelen tanulmányban bemutatunk egy 3D-s szerepjátékot a sértő nyelvi megjegyzésekre, amely jelenleg fejlesztés alatt áll.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Η Gamification έχει εφαρμοστεί σε πολλές γλωσσικές εργασίες σχολιασμού, ως εναλλακτική λύση στις πλατφόρμες για τη συλλογή σχολιασμένων δεδομένων με φθηνό τρόπο. Ωστόσο, πιστεύουμε ότι πρέπει ακόμα να διερευνηθούν πολλά. Τα παιχνίδια με σκοπό τείνουν να στερούνται σημαντικά στοιχεία που βλέπουμε συνήθως στα εμπορικά παιχνίδια, όπως 2και 3κόσμοι ή μια ιστορία. Το να καταστήσουμε τα GWAP πιο παρόμοια με τα ολοκληρωμένα βιντεοπαιχνίδια προκειμένου να εμπλακούμε ευκολότερα τους χρήστες και να αυξήσουμε τη διάδοση είναι ένα απαιτητικό αλλά ενδιαφέρον πεδίο για εξερεύνηση. Σε αυτή την εργασία παρουσιάζουμε ένα τρισδιάστατο παιχνίδι ρόλων για καταχρηστική γλωσσική σχολιασμό που βρίσκεται υπό ανάπτυξη.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>La gamification è stata applicata a molte attività di annotazione linguistica, in alternativa alle piattaforme di crowdsourcing per raccogliere dati annotati in modo economico. Tuttavia, riteniamo che sia ancora molto da esplorare. I giochi con scopo (GWAP) tendono a mancare di elementi importanti che vediamo comunemente nei giochi commerciali, come mondi 2D e 3D o una storia. Rendere i GWAP più simili ai videogiochi a tutti gli effetti per coinvolgere più facilmente gli utenti e aumentare la diffusione è un terreno impegnativo ma interessante da esplorare. In questo articolo presentiamo un gioco di ruolo 3D per l'annotazione abusiva del linguaggio che è attualmente in sviluppo.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Гамификация көптеген лингвистикалық жазбалар тапсырмаларына қолданылды. Көпшілікті мәліметтерді жинау үшін көптеген мәліметтерді альтернативті ретінде қолданылды. Бірақ біз бұл жерде әлі көп зерттеу керек деп ойлаймыз. Мақсатты (GWAP) ойындары көпшілікті коммерциялық ойындарда, мысалы, 2D және 3D әлемдер немесе оқиға сияқты маңызды элементтер жоқ. GWAPs-ді толық бейне ойындарына ұқсас қылу үшін пайдаланушыларды оңай және тарату үшін көңіл және тарату үшін көңіл көңіл жеткізу - бірақ зерттеу үшін көңіл көң Бұл қағазда біз қазіргі үлкен тілдерді жаңарту үшін 3D роль ойынын көрсетедік.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Gamification has been applied to many linguistic annotation tasks, as an alternative to crowdsourcing platforms to collect annotated data in an inexpensive way.  However, we think that still much has to be explored.  Игрите со цел (ГВАП) имаат тенденција да недостасуваат важни елементи кои често ги гледаме во комерцијалните игри, како што се 2Д и 3Д светови или приказна. Направањето на ГВАП послични на целосните видео игри со цел лесно да ги вклучат корисниците и да се зголеми ширењето е барачко, но интересно место за истражување. Во овој документ претставуваме тридимензионална игра на улога за злоупотреба на јазичките анотации кои моментно се развиваат.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Gamyba buvo taikoma daugeliui kalbinių anotacijų užduočių, kaip alternatyva daugelio išteklių platformoms, kad būtų brangiai renkami anotacijų duomenys. However, we think that still much has to be explored.  Games with a Purpose (GWAPs) tend to lack important elements that we commonly see in commercial games, such as 2D and 3D worlds or a story.  Siekiant lengviau įtraukti naudotojus ir didinti sklaidą, GWAP panašumas į visapusiškus vaizdo žaidimus yra sudėtinga, tačiau įdomu išnagrinėti. Šiame dokumente pristatome 3D vaidmens žaidimą piktnaudžiavimo kalbomis anotacijai, kuri šiuo metu rengiama.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Gamifikasi telah dilaksanakan pada banyak tugas anotasi bahasa, sebagai alternatif kepada platforma crowdsourcing untuk mengumpulkan data anotasi dengan cara yang tidak mahal. Namun, kami fikir bahawa masih banyak yang perlu dikenalpasti. Permainan dengan Tujuan (GWAP) cenderung untuk kekurangan unsur penting yang biasanya kita lihat dalam permainan komersial, seperti dunia 2D dan 3D atau cerita. Membuat GWAP lebih mirip dengan permainan video penuh untuk melibatkan pengguna dengan mudah dan meningkatkan penyebaran adalah tanah yang memerlukan tetapi menarik untuk mengeksplorasi. In this paper we present a 3D role-playing game for abusive language annotation that is currently under development.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഗാമിജിഷന്‍ ഒരുപാട് ഭാഷകങ്ങളുടെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് പ്രയോഗിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. അസാധ്യതയില്ലാത്ത വിവരങ്ങള്‍ സംഘടിപ്പിക്കാന്‍ പ് എങ്കിലും നമുക്ക് തോന്നുന്നു ഇത്രയും പരിശോധിക്കേണ്ടതുണ്ട്. ഒരു പൂപ്പോസുള്ള കളികള്‍ (ജിവ്വാപ്പുകള്‍) പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട മൂലകങ്ങള്‍ കാണുന്നു ഉപയോക്താക്കള്‍ക്ക് കൂടുതല്‍ എളുപ്പമുള്ളതും വിതരണം വര്‍ദ്ധിപ്പിക്കുന്നതും പരിശോധിക്കാന്‍ ഇനിയും രസകരമായ ഭൂമിയാണ് ജിവ്വാപ്പുകള്‍  ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ ഇപ്പോള്‍ വികസിക്കുന്ന ഭാഷയുടെ പ്രശ്നത്തിനായി മൂന്നാം റോള്‍ കളിയാക്കുന്ന ഒരു കളിയെ ക</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Gamifikasjon er brukt på mange lingviske notasjonsoppgåver, som alternativ for crowdsourcing-plattformar for å samla notasjonsdata på eit utrygt måte. Men vi tror at det er fortsatt mye å utforske. Spel med eit mål (GWAPs) har tendens til å mangla viktige elementar som me vanlegvis ser i kommersielle spel, slik som 2D og 3D verda eller ei historie. Å gjera GWAPs meir liknande til fullstendige video-spel for å involvera brukarar lettere og økja disseminasjon er ein følgjande, men interessant grunn for å utforska. I denne papiret presenterer vi eit 3D rollspel for abusive språk-notasjon som er i utviklinga.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_mt>Il-logħob tal-azzard ġie applikat għal ħafna kompiti ta’ annotazzjoni lingwistika, bħala alternattiva għall-pjattaformi ta’ crowdsourcing biex tinġabar dejta annotata b’mod mhux għali. Madankollu, aħna naħsbu li għad iridu jiġu esplorati ħafna. Il-logħob bi skop (GWAPs) għandhom it-tendenza li jonqsu minn elementi importanti li ġeneralment naraw fil-logħob kummerċjali, bħal dinji 2D u 3D jew storja. Li l-GWAPs isiru aktar simili għall-logħob tal-vidjo komplet sabiex l-utenti jiġu involuti aktar faċilment u jiżdied it-tixrid huwa bażi rikjedenti iżda interessanti li għandha tiġi esplorata. In this paper we present a 3D role-playing game for abusive language annotation that is currently under development.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Гамификация олон хэлний анзаарлын даалгавар дээр хэрэглэгдсэн бөгөөд олон хүмүүсийн санхүүжилтийн платформуудын өөрчлөлт нь тодорхойлогдсон өгөгдлийг тооцоолох боломжтой. Гэвч бид олон зүйлийг судлах хэрэгтэй гэж боддог. Цаг зорилготой тоглоомууд бидний худалдааны тоглоомд ихэвчлэн харж буй чухал элементүүд байдаг. Жишээ нь 2D, 3D ертөнц эсвэл түүх. ГВАП-г бүрэн дүүрэн бичлэгийн тоглоомтой илүү төстэй болгох нь хэрэглэгчид илүү амархан, нэмэгдүүлэх нь судалгааны шаардлагатай, сонирхолтой газар юм. Энэ цаасан дээр бид хөгжлийн дотор байгаа хүчирхийллийн хэлний нэр дэвшүүлэлт хийх 3D тоглоомын тоглоом бий болгодог.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Gamifikacja została zastosowana do wielu zadań adnotacyjnych językowych, jako alternatywa dla platform crowdsourcingowych do gromadzenia adnotacji danych w niedrogi sposób. Uważamy jednak, że jeszcze wiele trzeba zbadać. Gry z celem (GWAP) zazwyczaj brakują ważnych elementów, które powszechnie widzimy w grach komercyjnych, takich jak światy 2D i 3D czy historia. Zwiększenie zbliżenia GWAP do pełnoprawnych gier wideo w celu łatwiejszego zaangażowania użytkowników i zwiększenia upowszechniania jest wymagającym, ale ciekawym obszarem do zbadania. W niniejszym artykule przedstawiamy 3D grę role-playingową w zakresie adnotacji językowej, która jest obecnie w trakcie opracowywania.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_si>භාෂාත්මක ක්‍රියාත්මක වැඩකට ගැමිෆිකිෂ්ටන් භාෂාත්මක ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රති ඒත් අපි හිතන්නේ ඒක තවමත් ගොඩක් විශ්වාස කරන්න වෙනවා කියලා. සාමාන්‍ය සෙල්ලම් එක්ක සෙල්ලම් එක්ක (GWAPs) ප්‍රශ්නයක් නැති වෙනවා අපි සාමාන්‍ය ව්‍යාපාරික සෙල්ලම් වල දැක්කොත් වැදග GWAPs විසින් සම්පූර්ණ වීඩියෝ සෙල්ලම් වලට වඩා සම්පූර්ණ වීඩියෝ සෙල්ලම් කරන්න පුළුවන් විසින් පරීක්ෂණය සහ වි මේ පත්තරේ අපි තියෙන්නේ 3D පාලනයක් සෙල්ලම් කරනවා දැන් විකෘතියෙන් ඉන්න භාෂාවට ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ro>Gamificarea a fost aplicată multor sarcini de adnotare lingvistică, ca alternativă la platformele de crowdsourcing pentru a colecta date adnotate într-un mod ieftin. Cu toate acestea, considerăm că mai trebuie explorate multe. Jocurile cu scop (GWAP) tind să lipsească elemente importante pe care le vedem în mod obișnuit în jocurile comerciale, cum ar fi lumile 2D și 3D sau o poveste. Efectuarea GWAP-urilor mai asemănătoare cu jocurile video cu drepturi depline pentru a implica mai ușor utilizatorii și a spori diseminarea este un teren solicitant, dar interesant de explorat. În această lucrare prezentăm un joc de rol 3D pentru adnotări abuzive de limbaj care este în prezent în curs de dezvoltare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Waxaa lagu codsaday ogeysiiska shaqooyin badan oo luuqadaha lagu wacdiyo, taas oo ah mid ka bedel ah jaranjarada kooxaha dadka laga isticmaalo si uu u soo ururiyo macluumaad la caddeeyey si aan hawl lahayn. Si kastaba ha ahaatee waxaynu u malaynaynaa in weli la baadho wax badan. Ciyaaro la yidhaahdo Purpose (GWAPs) waa inta badan u baahan yihiin waxyaabo muhiim ah oo aan inta badan aragno ciyaaraha ganacsiga, tusaale ahaan dunida 2D iyo 3D ama sheeko. Ka sameynta GWAP oo u eg ciyaaro fiidiyowga oo dhan si uu isticmaalayaasha ugu fududaado oo uu u kordhiyo faa’iidada, waa dhul aad u baahan tahay oo aad u xiisaysan karto. Warqaddan waxaynu ku qornaa ciyaar 3D ah oo lagu ciyaaro luqada caafimaadka ah oo hadda la horumarinayo.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Gamification har tillämpats på många språkliga annotationsuppgifter, som ett alternativ till crowdsourcingplattformar för att samla in kommenterade data på ett billigt sätt. Vi anser dock att mycket återstår att utforska. Spel med syfte (GWAP) tenderar att sakna viktiga element som vi vanligtvis ser i kommersiella spel, såsom 2D- och 3D-världar eller en berättelse. Att göra GWAP mer lik fullfjädrade videospel för att lättare involvera användarna och öka spridningen är en krävande men intressant grund att utforska. I denna uppsats presenterar vi ett 3D-rollspel för kränkande språkkommentarer som just nu är under utveckling.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Gamifikacija je primjenjena na mnoge jezičke annotacije, kao alternativa za platforme crowdsourcing za okupljanje annotacijskih podataka na neekspenzivni način. Međutim, mislimo da još uvek mnogo mora biti istraženo. Igre sa ciljem (GWAPs) tendencija su nedostajale važne elemente koje obično vidimo u komercijalnim igricama, poput 2D i 3D sveta ili priče. Učiniti GWAPs sličnijim punim video igrama kako bi se olakšalo uključivalo korisnike i povećala širenje je zahteva još interesantna zemlja za istraživanje. U ovom papiru predstavljamo 3D igračku igru za zlostavljanje jezika koja je trenutno pod razvojom.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ur>بہت سی زبان انٹوریس کے کاموں پر کھیلنا لازم کیا گیا ہے، ایک غیر منطقی طریقہ سے انٹوریٹ ڈیٹا جمع کرنے کے لئے جمع کرنے کے لئے جمع کرنے کے لئے۔ لیکن ہم خیال کرتے ہیں کہ اب بھی بہت سی باتیں اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اچھی طرح اچھی طرح کھیل (GWAP) کے ذریعہ سے اہم عنصر کی کمی ہے جن کو ہم معمولاً تجارت کھیل میں دیکھتے ہیں، جیسے 2D اور 3D دنیا یا یا کہانی. GWAPs کو پورے بھاگنے ویڈیو کھیل کے مطابق زیادہ برابر بنانا ہے کہ کارساز کو زیادہ آسان اور پھیلانے کے لئے زیادہ شامل کرنا ہے یہ ایک اچھی جگہ ہے جہاں تک اچھی جگہ تلاش کرنے کے لئے۔ ہم اس کاغذ میں ایک 3D رول کھیل کھیل کھیل کھیل دیتے ہیں جو اب تک تکامل میں ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>பல மொழி அறிவிப்பு பணிகளுக்கு பாதுகாப்பு செயல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது, மக்கள் மூலங்களில் உள்ள தகவலை சேகரிக்க முடியாத வழியில் குறிப்பிட்ட ஆனால், நாம் இன்னும் அதிகமாக ஆராய்ந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்று நினைக்கிறோம். ஒரு பொருளுடன் விளையாட்டுகள் (GWAPs) பொதுவாக நாம் வியாபாரத்தில் பார்க்கும் முக்கியமான உறுப்புகளை குறைக்கிறது, போன்ற 2D மற்று பயனர்களை சுலபமாக சேர்க்க மற்றும் பரப்பினை அதிகரிக்க GWAPs இன்னும் ஆர்வமுள்ள பூமியாகும். இந்த காகிதத்தில் நாம் தற்போது உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ள மூன்று பங்கு விளையாட்டு விளையாடும் மொழி குறிப்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Name Lekin, biz o'ylaymiz, bu yerda ko'p narsalarni ko'rib chiqarishi kerak. Name Name Bu hujjatda biz hozir taʼminlovchi bo'lgan tilni taqdim qilish uchun 3D role o'ynash oʻyinlarini koʻrsatimiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Bản đánh bạc đã được áp dụng cho nhiều công việc ghi chú ngôn ngữ, như một sự thay thế cho giàn xếp cách thu thập dữ liệu được ghi chú bằng cách rẻ tiền. Tuy nhiên, chúng tôi nghĩ vẫn còn nhiều điều cần phải được khám phá. Trò chơi với mục đích (GWAP) có xu hướng thiếu các yếu tố quan trọng mà chúng ta thường thấy trong các trò chơi thương mại, như thế giới 2D và 3D hoặc một câu chuyện. Làm cho GWAP giống với game to àn diện hơn để dễ dàng lôi kéo người dùng và phát triển hơn là một cơ sở đòi hỏi nhưng thú vị để khám phá. Trong tờ giấy này chúng tôi giới thiệu một trò chơi điện tử về ghi chú ngôn ngữ ngược đãi đang được phát triển.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>Gamification is toegepast op veel taalkundige annotatietaken, als alternatief voor crowdsourcing platforms om geanotateerde gegevens op een goedkope manier te verzamelen. Wij denken echter dat er nog veel moet worden onderzocht. Games with a Purpose (GWAPs) missen vaak belangrijke elementen die we vaak zien in commerciële games, zoals 2D- en 3D-werelden of een verhaal. Het is een veeleisend maar interessant terrein om GWAP's meer op volwaardige videogames te laten lijken om gebruikers gemakkelijker te betrekken en de verspreiding te vergroten. In dit artikel presenteren we een 3D rollenspel voor beledigende taalannotatie dat momenteel in ontwikkeling is.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Гамификацията се прилага за много задачи по лингвистична анотация, като алтернатива на платформите за crowdsourcing за събиране на анотирани данни по евтин начин. Смятаме обаче, че все още много трябва да се проучи. Игрите с цел са склонни да липсват важни елементи, които често виждаме в комерсиалните игри, като 2D и 3светове или история. Да се направи GWAP по-подобен на пълноценните видео игри с цел по-лесно включване на потребителите и увеличаване на разпространението е взискателна, но интересна основа за изследване. В настоящата статия представяме 3ролева игра за анотация на злоупотреби с езика, която в момента е в процес на разработка.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Gamification er blevet anvendt til mange sproglige annoteringsopgaver, som et alternativ til crowdsourcing platforme til at indsamle annoterede data på en billig måde. Vi mener imidlertid, at der stadig skal undersøges meget. Spil med et formål (GWAP'er) har tendens til at mangle vigtige elementer, som vi normalt ser i kommercielle spil, såsom 2D og 3D verdener eller en historie. At gøre GWAP'er mere lig fuldgyldige videospil for nemmere at involvere brugerne og øge formidlingen er et krævende, men interessant område at udforske. I denne artikel præsenterer vi et 3D rollespil til krænkende sproganmærkninger, der i øjeblikket er under udvikling.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Gamifikacija je primjenjena na mnoge zadatke za jezičke annotacije, kao alternativa za platforme crowdsourcing za okupljanje annotacijskih podataka na neizračan način. Međutim, mislimo da još uvijek mnogo mora biti istraženo. Igre s ciljem (GWAPs) tendiraju da nedostaju važne elemente koje obično vidimo u komercijalnim igricama, poput 2D i 3D svijeta ili priče. Učiniti GWAPs sličnijim punim video igrama kako bi se lakše uključivalo korisnike i povećala širenje je zahtjevna i zanimljiva temelja za istraživanje. U ovom papiru predstavljamo 3D utakmicu za zlostavljanje jezika koja je trenutno pod razvojom.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Gamification wurde auf viele linguistische Annotationsaufgaben angewendet, als Alternative zu Crowdsourcing-Plattformen, um annotierte Daten auf kostengünstige Weise zu sammeln. Wir denken jedoch, dass noch viel erforscht werden muss. Games with a Purpose (GWAPs) neigen dazu, wichtige Elemente zu fehlen, die wir häufig in kommerziellen Spielen sehen, wie 2D- und 3D-Welten oder eine Geschichte. Die Annäherung von GWAPs an vollwertige Videospiele, um die Nutzer leichter einzubinden und die Verbreitung zu erhöhen, ist ein anspruchsvoller, aber interessanter Grund, den es zu erforschen gilt. In diesem Beitrag stellen wir ein 3D-Rollenspiel für missbräuchliche Sprachannotation vor, das sich derzeit in der Entwicklung befindet.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>게임화는 이미 많은 언어의 주석 작업에 응용되었고 패키지 플랫폼의 대체 방안으로 저렴한 방식으로 주석 데이터를 수집한다.그러나 우리는 여전히 탐색이 필요하다고 생각한다.목적이 있는 게임(GWAP)은 흔히 상업 게임에서 흔히 볼 수 있는 중요한 요소, 예를 들어 2D와 3D 세계나 이야기가 부족하다.GWAP를 성숙한 비디오 게임과 유사하게 하여 사용자를 더욱 쉽게 참여하게 하고 전파를 늘리는 것은 탐색이 필요한 어렵고 재미있는 분야이다.본고에서 우리는 3D 롤 플레이 게임의 욕설 언어 주석을 제시했고 현재 개발 중이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Ujumbe umetumiwa katika kazi nyingi za matangazo ya lugha, kama mbadala wa jukwaa la vyanzo vya umma ili kukusanya taarifa zilizotajwa kwa njia isiyo na usawa. Hata hivyo, tunadhani bado inapaswa kuchunguzwa. Michezo yenye kurasa (GWAPs) huenda kukosekana vipengele muhimu ambavyo mara nyingi tunaona katika michezo ya kibiashara, kama vile dunia 2D na 3D au hadithi. Making GWAPs more similar to full-fledged video games in order to involve users more easily and increase dissemination is a demanding yet interesting ground to explore.  Katika karatasi hii tunaonyesha mchezo wa rangi ya 3D kwa ajili ya matatizo ya lugha ya unyanyasaji yanayoendelea.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>بازیگری بر بسیاری از کارهای اظهار زبان‌شناسی، به عنوان جایگزینی برای استفاده از استفاده‌های سرمایه‌گذاری مردم برای جمع داده‌های اظهار یادآوری به طریق غیر منفی استفاده شده است. ولی ما فکر می کنیم که هنوز خیلی باید کشف کنیم. بازی‌ها با هدف (GWAP) به عنوان عناصر مهمی که معمولاً در بازی‌های تجاری می‌بینیم، مانند دنیای ۲D و 3D یا داستان، کمبود می‌کنند. ساختن GWAP به بازی های ویدئو کامل شبیه‌تر باشد تا به آسانتری و افزایش گسترش کاربران را درگیر کند، یک زمینه جالبی برای تحقیق است. در این کاغذ ما یک بازی نقش بازی 3D را برای اخطار زبان زبان ناتوانی که در حال حاضر تحت توسعه است نشان می دهیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Ýygymyz köp lingwistiki täzeliklere uygulandy, gaýsyz bir şekilde hasaplanýan maglumatlary toplamak üçin kalam platformlaryna golaýlaşdy. Ýöne biz entägem köp keşfedilmeli diýip pikir edýäris. Mazmunlar (GWAP) oýunlar biziň komersiýa oýunlarda, 2D we 3D dünýä ýa-da hekaýa ýaly görünýän möhüm elementlerimiz ýok. GWAP'leri tam dolu video oyunlara benzeştirmek için kullanıcıları kolaylaştırmak ve dağıtımı artmak için daha ilginç bir yer keşfedmek için gerekli. Bu kagyzda häzirki wagtda ösüşiklik taýýarlanmasy üçin 3D rol oýnuny görkezip otyrýarys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_id>Gamifikasi telah diterapkan untuk banyak tugas annotasi bahasa, sebagai alternatif untuk platform crowdsourcing untuk mengumpulkan data annotasi dengan cara yang tidak mahal. Namun, kami berpikir bahwa masih banyak yang harus dikeksplorasi. Permainan dengan tujuan (GWAP) cenderung untuk kekurangan elemen penting yang biasanya kita lihat dalam permainan komersial, seperti dunia 2D dan 3D atau cerita. Membuat GWAP lebih mirip dengan video game penuh untuk melibatkan pengguna lebih mudah dan meningkatkan penyebaran adalah tanah yang menuntut namun menarik untuk dieksplorasi. Dalam kertas ini kami mempersembahkan permainan permainan peran 3D untuk anotasi bahasa yang kasar yang saat ini sedang dikembangkan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_af>Gamifikasie is aangepas na baie lingwisiese annotasie opdragte, as 'n alternatief vir skapsourcing platforme om annotasie data op 'n ongeekspende manier te samel. Maar ons dink dat nog baie moet ondersoek word. Speletjies met 'n Purpose (GWAPs) tendeer om belangrike elemente te ontbreek wat ons gewoonlik in kommersiespeletjies sien, soos 2D en 3D wêreld of 'n storie. Die maak van GWAP meer gelykbaar aan volledige video speletjies om gebruikers makliker te involveer en verspreiding te vermeerder is 'n nodig interessante grond om te ondersoek. In hierdie papier is ons 'n 3D rolspeletjie voorsien vir abusive taal annotasie wat huidiglik onder ontwikkeling is.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>በብዙ ቋንቋ አዳራሽ ስራዎችን ለመቀበል ተጨማሪ ነው፡፡ ነገር ግን ገና ብዙ ሊመረመር ያስፈልጋል:: የፖርስ አካሄድ (GWAPs) የጨዋታ አካባቢ አካሄድ፣ 2D እና 3D ዓለምን ወይም ታሪክ እንደምናዩት የንግድ ጨዋታ አካላዊ ጉዳዮች ይጎድላሉ፡፡ የGWAP ውጤቶች በሙሉ አካባቢ የቪዲዮ ጨዋታ እንዲያሰናከል ተጠቃሚዎችን በትክክል እና በትክክል እንዲጨምር የሚጠይቅ መሬት ነው፡፡ በዚህ ጋዜጠኛ ውስጥ አሁን እየተነሳቀው ለቋንቋ የሚያስጨንቀውን የ3D ተማሪ ጨዋታዎችን እናቀርባለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Geminik çoxlu dillərin məlumatlarına uyğunlaşdırılmışdır, çoxlu məlumatlarını çoxlu tərzdə toplamaq üçün çoxlu dil məlumatlarına istifadə edilmişdir. Ancaq biz düşünürük ki, hələ də çox keşif edilməlidir. Məqsəd oyunları (GWAP) ilə müəyyən etdiyimiz ticarət oyunlarında, bəlkə 2D və 3D dünyada və ya hekayələrdə gördüyümüz möhüm elementlər yoxdur. GWAP'ləri daha asanlıqla istifadəçiləri ilə daha asanlıqla və dağıtmaq üçün tamamlanmış video oyunlara bənzər etmək is ə istifadəçiləri təşkil etmək üçün çox maraqlı bir yerdir. Bu kağızda, həqiqətən də tədbirləşdirilmək üçün 3D rol oyunu göstəririk.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>অনেক ভাষার শিক্ষার্থীতে গ্যামিজিশন প্রয়োগ করা হয়েছে, যেখানে অযৌক্তিক উপায়ে ব্যাপক তথ্য সংগ্রহ করার জন্য প্লাটফর্মের বিকল্প। তবে আমরা মনে করি এখনও অনেক কিছু খুঁজে বের করা দরকার। একটি পুরস্কার (জিউএপ্যাপ) নিয়ে খেলাগুলো প্রায় গুরুত্বপূর্ণ উপাদানের অভাব রয়েছে যা আমরা বাণিজ্যিক খেলায় দেখতে পাচ্ছি, যেমন ২ডি এব ব্যবহারকারীদের সাথে আরো সহজে জড়িত এবং বিস্তারিত বিভিন্ন ভিডিও খেলার মতো জিওয়াপিকে আরো অনেকের মতো করে তৈরি করা হচ্ছে বিশেষ করে তদন্তের এই কাগজটিতে আমরা একটি ত্রিমিডি ভূমিকা খেলার খেলা উপস্থাপন করছি যা বর্তমানে উন্নয়নের অধীনে আছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_hy>Խաղախաղերը կիրառվել են շատ լեզվաբանական annoտացիայի խնդիրների վրա, որպես այլընտրանք ժողովրդավարման հարթակների համար, որպեսզի գրված տվյալներ անթանկ կերպ հավաքեն: Այնուամենայնիվ, մենք կարծում ենք, որ դեռևս շատ բան պետք է ուսումնասիրել: Նպատակով խաղերը հակված են բացակայել կարևոր տարրեր, որոնք մենք սովորաբար տեսնում ենք առևտրային խաղերում, ինչպիսիք են 2D և 3D աշխարհները կամ պատմությունը: ԳՈՊ-ները ավելի նման դարձնելը լիարժեք վիդեո խաղերի հետ, որպեսզի ավելի հեշտ ներգրավվեն օգտագործողներին և աճեցնեն տարածումը, անհրաժեշտ է, սակայն հետաքրքիր հիմք ուսումնասիրելու համար: Այս թղթի մեջ մենք ներկայացնում ենք երրորդ չափերի դեր խաղ, որն օգտագործում է լեզվի չարաշահույթ նշումներ, որոնք ներկայումս զարգացվում են:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_sq>Gamifikimi është aplikuar në shumë detyra gjuhësore të anotacionit, si një alternativë për platforma crowdsourcing për të mbledhur të dhëna të anotuara në një mënyrë të papërkushtueshme. Megjithatë, ne mendojmë se ende ka shumë për të eksploruar. Games with a Purpose (GWAPs) tend to lack important elements that we commonly see in commercial games, such as 2D and 3D worlds or a story.  Duke bërë GWAPs më të ngjashëm me videolojrat e plota me qëllim që të përfshihen përdoruesit më lehtë dhe të rriten shpërndarjet është një terren kërkues por interesant për të eksploruar. Në këtë letër ne paraqesim një lojë të lojës së rolit 3D për anotacionin e gjuhës abuzive që është në zhvillim aktualisht.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_bs>Gamifikacija je primjenjena na mnoge jezičke obaveze za annotaciju, kao alternativa za platforme crowdsourcing za okupljanje annotacijskih podataka na neiskorišten način. Međutim, mislimo da još uvek mnogo mora biti istraženo. Igre sa ciljem (GWAPs) tendiraju da nedostaju važne elemente koje obično vidimo u komercijalnim igricama, poput 2D i 3D svijeta ili priče. Učiniti GWAPs sličnijim punim video igrama kako bi se olakšalo uključivalo korisnike i povećala širenje je zahtjevna i zanimljiva zemlja za istraživanje. U ovom papiru predstavljamo 3D igračku igru za zlostavljanje jezika koja je trenutno pod razvojom.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Gamifikace byla aplikována na mnoho jazykových anotací, jako alternativa k crowdsourcingovým platformám pro shromažďování anotovaných dat levným způsobem. Domníváme se však, že ještě je třeba mnoho prozkoumat. Hry s účelem (GWAP) mají tendenci postrádat důležité prvky, které běžně vidíme v komerčních hrách, jako jsou 2D a 3D světy nebo příběh. Náročným, ale zajímavým bodem k prozkoumání je zajištění podobnosti GWAP plnohodnotným videohrám s cílem snadněji zapojit uživatele a zvýšit šíření informací. V tomto článku představujeme 3D role-playing hru pro zneužívající jazykovou anotaci, která je v současné době ve vývoji.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Gamifikatsiooni on rakendatud paljude keeleliste annoteerimistegevuste puhul alternatiivina ühishankimise platvormidele, et koguda annoteeritud andmeid odaval viisil. Meie arvates tuleb siiski veel palju uurida. Eesmärgiga mängudel (GWAP) kipuvad puuduma olulised elemendid, mida tavaliselt näeme kommertsmängudes, nagu 2D ja 3D maailmad või lugu. GWAPde muutmine täieõiguslike videomängudega sarnasemaks, et kaasata kasutajaid hõlpsamini ja suurendada levitamist, on nõudlik, kuid huvitav alus uurida. Käesolevas töös tutvustame 3D rollimängu kuritarvitava keele annotatsiooni jaoks, mis on praegu väljatöötamisel.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ca>La gamificació s'ha aplicat a moltes tasques lingüístices d'anotació, com a alternativa a plataformes de crowdsourcing per recollir dades anotates de manera inexpensiva. No obstant això, pensem que encara s'ha d'explorar molt. Games with a Purpose (GWAPs) tend to lack important elements that we commonly see in commercial games, such as 2D and 3D worlds or a story.  Far que els GWAP siguin més semblants als videojocs plens per involucrar més fàcilment els usuaris i augmentar la difusió és un terreny exigent però interessant a explorar. En aquest article presentem un joc de joc de paper en 3D per anotació abusiva de llenguatges que actualment està en desenvolupament.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Pelillistämistä on sovellettu moniin kielellisiin annotointitehtäviin vaihtoehtona crowdsourcing-alustoille kerätä annotoitua dataa edullisesti. Mielestämme on kuitenkin vielä paljon tutkittavaa. Games with a Purpose (GWAP) -peleistä puuttuu usein tärkeitä elementtejä, joita näemme yleisesti kaupallisissa peleissä, kuten 2D- ja 3D-maailmoissa tai tarinassa. GWAP-ohjelmien tekeminen samankaltaisemmaksi kuin täysimittaiset videopelit, jotta käyttäjät saadaan helpommin mukaan ja levitetään enemmän, on vaativa mutta mielenkiintoinen tutkimusalue. Tässä työssä esittelemme parhaillaan kehitteillä olevan 3D-roolipelin väärinkäyttävälle kielelle.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ha>An Apply Gamijini zuwa masu aikin mai sanarwa na lugha masu yawa, kamar wata matsayi wa platform masu danna-sourcen mutane dõmin ya sami data da aka buga wa, cikin wata hanci na kasa. Kayya, tuna zato ba ya kamata an sami ko yawa. Wasanni da wani Rufiya (GWPAs) na zaman su ƙara da ƙanshi na muhimu kamar misali duniya 2D da 3, ko wani lãbãri. Kusami GWPA masu daidai da gamayen video wanda aka samar da shi don ya haɗa masu sauƙi da amfani da shi kuma ya ƙara diffukan shi, yana da wata kashi mai amfani da kwamfyuta. Ga wannan takardan da Muke halatar da wani game da 3-role-play wa zane-zane-zane-zartar da yanzu-yanzu wanda ke ƙaranci.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>Gamification has been applied to many linguistic annotation tasks, as an alternative to crowdsourcing platforms to collect annotated data in an inexpensive way.  בכל אופן, אנחנו חושבים שעדיין צריך לחקור הרבה. משחקים עם מטרה (GWAPs) נוטים לחסר אלמנטים חשובים שאנחנו בדרך כלל רואים במשחקים מסחריים, כמו עולמות שתיים מימדים ושלוש מימדים או סיפור. להפוך את GWAP יותר דומה למשחקי וידאו מלאים כדי לערב משתמשים בקלות יותר ולהגדיל את התפשטות הוא מקום דורש אך מעניין לחקור. בעיתון הזה אנחנו מציגים משחק משחק תפקידים 3D עבור ציון שפה מתעללת שעכשיו מתפתח.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Gamifikacija je bila uporabljena pri številnih nalogah jezikovnega označevanja, kot alternativa platformam množičnega nabora za zbiranje označenih podatkov na poceni način. Vendar menimo, da je treba še veliko raziskati. Igre z namenom (GWAP) ponavadi nimajo pomembnih elementov, ki jih običajno vidimo v komercialnih igrah, kot so 2D in 3D svetovi ali zgodba. Izboljšanje podobnosti GWAP-jem polnopravnim video igram, da bi lažje vključili uporabnike in povečali širjenje širjenja, je zahtevno, vendar zanimivo področje za raziskovanje. V prispevku predstavljamo 3D igro vlog za zlorabljajoče jezikovne opombe, ki je trenutno v razvoju.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>སྐད་ཡིག་གི་འགྲེལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་བྱ་སྤྱོད་མང་པོ་ཞིག་ལ་སྤྱོད་སྤྱད་ཡོད། ཡིན་ནའང་། ང་ཚོས་ད་ལྟ་ཞིབ་བཤེར་བྱེད་དགོས་པ་འདུག རྩེདམོ་ཞིག་ཡོད་པའི་རྩེདམོ་ཞིག་ལ་གལ་ཆེན་དག་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོ་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་རྩེདམོ་ནང་དུ་མཐོང་བའི་གལ་ཆོག་ཉིད་ཡོད། GWAPs་འདི་ལྟ་བུའི་རྩེད་མོའི་ནང་དུ་ཡོངས་བསྡད་པའི་བརྙན་ཐུང་གི་རྩེད་མོ་ཆ་དང་ལས་སླ་གཏོང་ཆེ་ནི་སླ་གཏོང འོག་གི་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་འོང་ཚོར་སྔོན་སྐྱོད་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་འགྲེལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་རྩེད་མོའི་གྲངས་་ཀྱི་</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_jv>Gamification Nanging, dhewe pikir-pikir sedhaya kan isih akeh lanjut. Dolanan sing nganggo Purposition (GWAP) kuwi nggawe alam-alam sing gak bener tentang karo dolanan komersial, kaya ngono 2D lan 3 uwong. GWAP dolanan sing dibutungane gampang video sing gak bener-perusahaan kanggo nguasai luwih apik lan katok disenyong sing diandelah kuwi diandelah ujaran kanggo ngerasai perusahaan sing apik sing apik. Nang pepul iki, kita mulai perusahaan kelas-kelas telu kanggo ngerasakno banget, dadi nggawe barang nggawe ngupakane.</abstract_jv>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>