<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nlptea">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-12-02">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 6th Workshop on Natural Language Processing Techniques for Educational Applications</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Erhong</first><last>YANG</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Endong</first><last>XUN</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Baolin</first><last>ZHANG</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Gaoqi</first><last>RAO</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Suzhou, China</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="b5ddfc36">2020.nlptea-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp-tea-2020-natural</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Integrating BERT and Score-based Feature Gates for Chinese Grammatical Error Diagnosis<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> and Score-based Feature Gates for <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese Grammatical Error Diagnosis</title>
      <author><first>Yongchang</first><last>Cao</last></author>
      <author><first>Liang</first><last>He</last></author>
      <author><first>Robert</first><last>Ridley</last></author>
      <author><first>Xinyu</first><last>Dai</last></author>
      <pages>49–56</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> for the Chinese Grammatical Error Diagnosis (CGED) task in NLPTEA2020. The goal of CGED is to use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing techniques</a> to automatically diagnose <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_grammar">Chinese grammatical errors</a> in sentences. To this end, we design and implement a CGED model named BERT with Score-feature Gates Error Diagnoser (BSGED), which is based on the BERT model, Bidirectional Long Short-Term Memory (BiLSTM) and conditional random field (CRF). In order to address the problem of losing partial-order relationships when embedding continuous feature items as with previous works, we propose a gating mechanism for integrating continuous feature items, which effectively retains the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Partially_ordered_set">partial-order relationships</a> between feature items. We perform LSTM processing on the encoding result of the BERT model, and further extract the sequence features. In the final test-set evaluation, we obtained the highest F1 score at the detection level and are among the top 3 F1 scores at the identification level.</abstract>
      <url hash="7055b8ac">2020.nlptea-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>cao-etal-2020-integrating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>CYUT Team Chinese Grammatical Error Diagnosis System Report in NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task<fixed-case>CYUT</fixed-case> Team <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese Grammatical Error Diagnosis System Report in <fixed-case>NLPTEA</fixed-case>-2020 <fixed-case>CGED</fixed-case> Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Shih-Hung</first><last>Wu</last></author>
      <author><first>Junwei</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <pages>91–96</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports our Chinese Grammatical Error Diagnosis system in the NLPTEA-2020 CGED shared task. In 2020, we sent two runs with two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glossary_of_baseball_(S)">approaches</a>. The first one is a combination of conditional random fields (CRF) and a BERT model deep-learning approach. The second one is a BERT model deep-learning approach. The official results shows that our run1 achieved the highest precision rate 0.9875 with the lowest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/False_positives_and_false_negatives">false positive rate</a> 0.0163 on detection, while run2 gives a more balanced performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="6664e87c">2020.nlptea-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>wu-wang-2020-cyut</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Chinese Grammatical Errors Diagnosis System Based on BERT at NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese Grammatical Errors Diagnosis System Based on <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>NLPTEA</fixed-case>-2020 <fixed-case>CGED</fixed-case> Shared Task</title>
      <author><first>Hongying</first><last>Zan</last></author>
      <author><first>Yangchao</first><last>Han</last></author>
      <author><first>Haotian</first><last>Huang</last></author>
      <author><first>Yingjie</first><last>Yan</last></author>
      <author><first>Yuke</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Yingjie</first><last>Han</last></author>
      <pages>102–107</pages>
      <abstract>In the process of learning <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second-language_acquisition">second language learners</a> may have various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammatical_error">grammatical errors</a> due to the negative transfer of native language. This paper describes our submission to the NLPTEA 2020 shared task on CGED. We present a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hybrid_system">hybrid system</a> that utilizes both detection and correction stages. The detection stage is a sequential labelling model based on BiLSTM-CRF and BERT contextual word representation. The correction stage is a hybrid model based on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N-gram">n-gram</a> and Seq2Seq. Without adding additional features and external data, the BERT contextual word representation can effectively improve the performance metrics of Chinese grammatical error detection and correction.</abstract>
      <url hash="c2ce541f">2020.nlptea-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>zan-etal-2020-chinese</bibkey>
    <title_ar>نظام تشخيص الأخطاء النحوية الصيني المستند إلى BERT في المهمة المشتركة NLPTEA-2020 CGED</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Sistema de diagnóstico de erros gramaticais chinês com base no BERT na tarefa compartilhada NLPTEA-2020 CGED</title_pt>
      <title_es>Sistema de diagnóstico de errores gramaticales chinos basado en BERT en NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_es>
      <title_ja>NLPTEA -2020 CGED共有タスクでのBERTに基づく中国語文法エラー診断システム</title_ja>
      <title_zh>盖BERT之汉语语法错误诊断系统在NLPTEA-2020 CGED共之</title_zh>
      <title_hi>चीनी व्याकरणिक त्रुटियाँ निदान प्रणाली NLPTEA-2020 CGED साझा कार्य पर BERT पर आधारित</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Córas Diagnóisithe Earráidí Gramadaí na Síne Bunaithe ar BERT ag Tasc Comhroinnte CGED NLPTEA-2020</title_ga>
      <title_ka>QFontDatabase</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Kínai nyelvtani hibák diagnosztikai rendszere BERT alapján az NLPTEA-2020 CGED megosztott feladaton</title_hu>
      <title_el>Κινεζικό σύστημα διάγνωσης γραμματικών σφαλμάτων βασισμένο στο Κοινή Εργασία</title_el>
      <title_it>Sistema di diagnosi degli errori grammaticali cinesi basato su BERT al compito condiviso CGED NLPTEA-2020</title_it>
      <title_kk>NLPTEA- 2020 CGED ортақ тапсырмасына негізделген қытайша грамматикалық қателер диагнозы жүйесі</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Kinijos gramatinių klaidų diagnozavimo sistema, pagrįsta BERT NLPTEA-2020 CGED bendroje užduotyje</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Кинескиот систем за дијагностика на граматски грешки базиран на BERT на NLPTEA-2020 CGED споделена задача</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Sistem Diagnosis Ralat Grammatik Cina Berdasarkan BERT pada Tugas Berkongsi NLPTEA-2020 CGED</title_ms>
      <title_ml>NLPTEA- 2020 CGED പങ്കുചേര്‍ത്ത പണിയില്‍ BERT അടിസ്ഥാനമായി അടിസ്ഥാനമായി ചൈനീസ് ഗ്രാമാറ്റിക്കല്‍ പിശകുകള്‍</title_ml>
      <title_mn>НLPTEA-2020 CGED хуваалтын ажил дээр BERT-д багтсан Хятад Грамматикийн алдаа</title_mn>
      <title_mt>Sistema ta’ Dijanjożi ta’ Żbalji Grammatiċi Ċiniżi bbażata fuq BERT f’Kompitu Konġunt NLPTEA-2020 CGED</title_mt>
      <title_ro>Sistemul de diagnosticare a erorilor gramaticale chinezești bazat pe BERT la activitatea partajată CGED NLPTEA-2020</title_ro>
      <title_no>Kinesisk Grammatiske feil Diagnosis System basert på BERT på NLPTEA-2020 CGED delt oppgåve</title_no>
      <title_pl>Chiński system diagnostyki błędów gramatycznych oparty na BERT w NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Kineski sistem za dijagnozu grešaka baziran na BERT na NLPTEA-2020 CGED zajedničkom zadatku</title_sr>
      <title_si>චීනි ග්‍රාම්ටික් වැරදිලි සංඥානය පද්ධතිය NLPTEA-2020දී පද්ධතිය</title_si>
      <title_sv>Kinesiskt grammatiska fel Diagnossystem baserat på BERT vid NLPTEA-2020 CGED delad uppgift</title_sv>
      <title_so>Xiineeya dhibaatooyinka ku saabsan diagnosis System Based on BERT at NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_so>
      <title_ta>Comment</title_ta>
      <title_ur>NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task پر BERT پر بنیاد رکھی چینی گرامٹیکل تخطار</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Hệ thống phân tích biểu đồ học của Trung Quốc</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Система за диагностика на китайски граматични грешки въз основа на споделена задача</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Kineski sistem za dijagnozu grešaka baziran na BERT-u na NLPTEA-2020 CGED zajedničkom zadatku</title_hr>
      <title_da>Kinesisk grammatiske fejldiagnosesystem baseret på BERT ved NLPTEA-2020 CGED delt opgave</title_da>
      <title_nl>Chinese grammaticale fouten diagnosesysteem gebaseerd op BERT bij NLPTEA-2020 CGED Gedeelde taak</title_nl>
      <title_de>Chinesisches Grammatikfehler-Diagnosesystem basierend auf BERT bei NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_de>
      <title_id>Sistem Diagnosis Galat Grammatis Cina Berdasarkan BERT di NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_id>
      <title_ko>BERT 기반 NLPTEA-2020 CGED 공유 작업 중국어 문법 오류 진단 시스템</title_ko>
      <title_fa>سیستم شناسایی خطاهای گرماتیک چینی بر اساس BERT در کار مشترک NLPTEA-2020</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Grammatikal Hatalar</title_tr>
      <title_af>Sjinese Gramatiese Foute Diagnosies Stelsel Gebaseer op BERT by NLPTEA- 2020 CGED Gedeelde Opdrag</title_af>
      <title_sq>Sistemi Kinez i Diagnozës së Gabimeve Gramatike Bazuar në BERT në NLPTEA-2020 CGED Task Shared</title_sq>
      <title_am>Chinese Grammatical Error Diagnosis System Based on NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_am>
      <title_hy>Չինաստանի գրամմատիկ սխալների ախտորոշման համակարգը, հիմնված BER-ի վրա, ՆԼՊՏԵԱ-2020 թվականի CGeD ընդհանուր հանձնարարության ժամանակ</title_hy>
      <title_az>NLPTEA-2020 CGED paylaşdırılmış Gözmə Based on BERT</title_az>
      <title_bn>NLPTEA-2020 CGED ভাগাভাগি করা কাজের উপর ভিত্তিক চীনা গ্রামাটিক্যাল ত্রুটি ডিয়াগনিং সিস্টেম</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Kineski sistem za dijagnozu grešaka baziran na BERT na NLPTEA-2020 CGED zajedničkom zadatku</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Sistema de diagnòstic d'errors gramàtics xinès basat en BERT a NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Čínský systém diagnostiky gramatických chyb založený na BERT na NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_cs>
      <title_sw>Mfumo wa Uchaguzi wa Tamko wa Kichina umetokana na BERT kwenye kazi ya NLPTEA-2020 CGED</title_sw>
      <title_et>Hiina grammatiliste vigade diagnostika süsteem, mis põhineb BERT-il NLPTEA-2020 CGED jagatud ülesanne</title_et>
      <title_fi>Kiinan kielioppivirheiden diagnosointijärjestelmä perustuu BERT-järjestelmään NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task -tapahtumassa</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Chinese Graph Eror</title_jv>
      <title_he>Chinese Grammatical Errors Diagnosis System Based on BERT at NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Kitajski slovnični sistem diagnosticiranja napak na podlagi BERT na skupni nalogi NLPTEA-2020 CGED</title_sk>
      <title_bo>རྒྱ་ནག་གི་Grammatical Errors Diagnosis System Based on BERT at NLPTEA-2020 CGED Shared Task</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>في عملية تعلم اللغة الصينية ، قد يكون لمتعلمي اللغة الثانية أخطاء نحوية مختلفة بسبب النقل السلبي للغة الأم. تصف هذه الورقة تقديمنا إلى المهمة المشتركة لـ NLPTEA 2020 على CGED. نقدم نظامًا هجينًا يستخدم كل من مرحلتي الكشف والتصحيح. مرحلة الاكتشاف عبارة عن نموذج تصنيف متسلسل يعتمد على تمثيل الكلمات السياقية BiLSTM-CRF و BERT. مرحلة التصحيح عبارة عن نموذج هجين يعتمد على n-gram و Seq2Seq. بدون إضافة ميزات وبيانات خارجية إضافية ، يمكن لتمثيل الكلمات السياقية BERT تحسين مقاييس أداء اكتشاف الأخطاء النحوية الصينية وتصحيحها بشكل فعال.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>En el proceso de aprendizaje del chino, los estudiantes de un segundo idioma pueden tener varios errores gramaticales debido a la transferencia negativa de la lengua materna. Este documento describe nuestra presentación a la tarea compartida de la NLPTEA 2020 sobre CGED. Presentamos un sistema híbrido que utiliza etapas de detección y corrección. La etapa de detección es un modelo de etiquetado secuencial basado en la representación de palabras contextuales BILSTM-CRF y BERT. La etapa de corrección es un modelo híbrido basado en n-gram y Seq2Seq. Sin añadir funciones adicionales ni datos externos, la representación contextual de palabras BERT puede mejorar eficazmente las métricas de rendimiento de la detección y corrección de errores gramaticales chinos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>No processo de aprendizagem do chinês, os aprendizes de segunda língua podem ter vários erros gramaticais devido à transferência negativa da língua nativa. Este artigo descreve nossa submissão à tarefa compartilhada NLPTEA 2020 no CGED. Apresentamos um sistema híbrido que utiliza etapas de detecção e correção. A etapa de detecção é um modelo de rotulagem sequencial baseado na representação de palavras contextuais BiLSTM-CRF e BERT. A etapa de correção é um modelo híbrido baseado no n-gram e Seq2Seq. Sem adicionar recursos adicionais e dados externos, a representação de palavras contextuais do BERT pode melhorar efetivamente as métricas de desempenho da detecção e correção de erros gramaticais em chinês.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>中国語を学習する過程で、第二言語の学習者はネガティブな母国語の転送のためにさまざまな文法的誤りを抱える可能性があります。本稿では、CGEDに関するNLPTEA 2020共有タスクへの提出について説明します。検出段階と補正段階の両方を利用するハイブリッドシステムを提示します。検出段階は、ＢｉＬＳＴＭ － ＣＲＦ及びＢＥＲＴ文脈的単語表現に基づく逐次標識モデルである。補正段階は、n - gramとSeq 2 Seqに基づくハイブリッドモデルである。追加機能や外部データを追加することなく、BERTコンテキスト単語表現は、中国語文法のエラー検出と修正のパフォーマンスメトリクスを効果的に改善することができます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>चीनी सीखने की प्रक्रिया में, दूसरी भाषा सीखने वालों में मूल भाषा के नकारात्मक हस्तांतरण के कारण विभिन्न व्याकरणिक त्रुटियां हो सकती हैं। यह पेपर CGED पर NLPTEA 2020 साझा कार्य के लिए हमारे सबमिशन का वर्णन करता है। हम एक हाइब्रिड सिस्टम प्रस्तुत करते हैं जो पता लगाने और सुधार दोनों चरणों का उपयोग करता है। पता लगाने का चरण BiLSTM-CRF और BERT प्रासंगिक शब्द प्रतिनिधित्व के आधार पर एक अनुक्रमिक लेबलिंग मॉडल है। सुधार चरण n-gram और Seq2Seq पर आधारित एक हाइब्रिड मॉडल है। अतिरिक्त सुविधाओं और बाहरी डेटा को जोड़ने के बिना, BERT प्रासंगिक शब्द प्रतिनिधित्व प्रभावी ढंग से चीनी व्याकरणिक त्रुटि का पता लगाने और सुधार के प्रदर्शन मैट्रिक्स में सुधार कर सकते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>学汉语者,母语负面移,第二语言学者或有语法错误。 本文介我NELPTEA 2020交CGED共之。 臣等建一混合系统,当以检测校正之。 检者,BiLSTM-CRFBERT上下文词之序也。 校正者,n-gramSeq2Seq之混形也。 不加特征、外数者,BERT语境词有效汉语语法错误检正之性能指标。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>I bpróiseas foghlama na Síne, d’fhéadfadh go mbeadh earráidí gramadaí éagsúla ag foghlaimeoirí dara teanga mar gheall ar aistriú diúltach na teanga dúchais. Déanann an páipéar seo cur síos ar ár n-aighneacht do thasc roinnte NLPTEA 2020 ar CGED. Cuirimid córas hibrideach i láthair a úsáideann céimeanna braite agus ceartúcháin araon. Múnla lipéadaithe seicheamhach atá sa chéim braite bunaithe ar léiriú focal comhthéacsúla BiLSTM-CRF agus BERT. Samhail hibrideach atá sa chéim cheartúcháin bunaithe ar an n-gram agus an Seq2Seq. Gan gnéithe breise agus sonraí seachtracha a chur leis, is féidir le hionadaíocht focail comhthéacsúla BERT feabhas a chur go héifeachtach ar mhéadracht feidhmíochta braite agus ceartú earráide gramadaí na Síne.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>A kínai tanulás során a második nyelvtanulóknak különböző nyelvtani hibák lehetnek az anyanyelv negatív átadása miatt. Ez a tanulmány bemutatja, hogy benyújtottunk az NLPTEA 2020 közös feladatra a CGED-re. Bemutatunk egy hibrid rendszert, amely mind az észlelési, mind a korrekciós szakaszokat használja. Az észlelési szakasz egy szekvenciális címkézési modell, amely BiLSTM-CRF és BERT kontextuális szóábrázoláson alapul. A korrekciós szakasz egy hibrid modell, amely az n-grammon és Seq2Seq alapul. További funkciók és külső adatok hozzáadása nélkül a BERT kontextuális szóábrázolása hatékonyan javíthatja a kínai nyelvtani hibaészlelés és -korrekció teljesítménymutatóit.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Κατά τη διαδικασία εκμάθησης κινέζικων, οι μαθητές δεύτερης γλώσσας ενδέχεται να έχουν διάφορα γραμματικά λάθη λόγω της αρνητικής μεταφοράς της μητρικής γλώσσας. Η παρούσα εργασία περιγράφει την υποβολή μας στο κοινό έργο του NLPTEA 2020 για την CGED. Παρουσιάζουμε ένα υβριδικό σύστημα που χρησιμοποιεί τόσο τα στάδια ανίχνευσης όσο και διόρθωσης. Το στάδιο ανίχνευσης είναι ένα διαδοχικό μοντέλο επισήμανσης βασισμένο στην αναπαράσταση λέξεων BiLSTM-CRF και BERT. Το στάδιο διόρθωσης είναι ένα υβριδικό μοντέλο βασισμένο στο n-γραμμάριο και το Seq2Seq. Χωρίς προσθήκη πρόσθετων χαρακτηριστικών και εξωτερικών δεδομένων, η απεικόνιση λέξεων στο πλαίσιο μπορεί αποτελεσματικά να βελτιώσει τις μετρήσεις απόδοσης της κινεζικής γραμματικής ανίχνευσης και διόρθωσης σφαλμάτων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ჩინეთის სწავლების პროცესში, მეორე ენის სწავლებელი შესაძლებელია განსხვავებული გრამიმატური შეცდომილებები, რადგან მისი ენის გადატანსტრიქციის განსაკუთრებული ეს დოკუმენტი ჩვენი გახსნა NLPTEA 2020-ის გაყოფილი CGED-ზე. ჩვენ აჩვენებთ ჰიბრიდის სისტემა, რომელიც გამოიყენებს განახლება და კონფიგურაცია. განახლების ფაეზი არის სიტყვების გამოსახულება BiLSTM-CRF და BERT კონტექსტური სიტყვების გამოსახულება. კონფიგურაციის ფაეზია n-გრამის და Seq2Seq-ის დაბაზეული ჰიბრიტის მოდელი. BERT-ის კონტექსტური სიტყვების გამოსახულება შეუძლია წინასწარმოდგენება ჩინეთის გრამიკალური შეცდომის განსახულება და კონტექსტური შეცდომის გამოსახულება.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Nel processo di apprendimento del cinese, gli studenti di seconda lingua possono avere vari errori grammaticali a causa del trasferimento negativo della lingua madre. Questo articolo descrive la nostra presentazione al compito condiviso NLPTEA 2020 su CGED. Presentiamo un sistema ibrido che utilizza sia fasi di rilevamento che di correzione. La fase di rilevamento è un modello di etichettatura sequenziale basato sulla rappresentazione contestuale di parole BiLSTM-CRF e BERT. La fase di correzione è un modello ibrido basato su n-gram e Seq2Seq. Senza aggiungere funzionalità aggiuntive e dati esterni, la rappresentazione contestuale delle parole BERT può migliorare efficacemente le metriche di performance del rilevamento e correzione degli errori grammaticali cinesi.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Mokymosi kinų kalba metu antrosios kalbos mokytojai gali patirti įvairių gramatinių klaidų dėl neigiamo gimtosios kalbos perdavimo. Šiame dokumente apibūdinamas mūsų pranešimas bendrai NLPTEA 2020 uždaviniui CGED. Mes pristatome hibridinę sistemą, kuri naudoja ir aptikimo, ir koregavimo etapus. Nustatymo etapas yra sekos ženklinimo model is, pagrįstas BiLSTM-CRF ir BERT kontekstiniu žodžių vaizdu. Korekcijos etapas yra hibridinis model is, pagrįstas n-gramais ir Seq2Seq. Be papildomų charakteristikų ir išorinių duomenų BERT kontekstinis žodžių atstovavimas gali veiksmingai pagerinti Kinijos gramatinių klaidų nustatymo ir ištaisymo rezultatų rodiklius.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Қытай тілді оқыту процесінде, екінші тілді оқытушылардың негативті тілді аудару үшін грамматикалық қатесі болуы мүмкін. Бұл қағаз NLPTEA 2020 бағытталған тапсырмаға CGED жіберімізді таңдайды. Біз анықтау мен түзету сәттерін қолданатын гибрид жүйесін таңдаймыз. Табу кезегі - BiLSTM- CRF және BERT контекстік сөздерді таңдау үлгісі. Түзету кезегі n- грамма және Seq2Seq негіздеген гибрид моделі. Қосымша мүмкіндіктерді және сыртқы деректерді қосуға болмаса, BERT контексті сөздерді таңдау үшін Қытай грамматикалық қателерді анықтау және түзетуге болады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Во процесот на учење кинески, учениците на вториот јазик можеби имаат различни граматични грешки поради негативниот трансфер на родниот јазик. Овој документ го опишува нашето поднесување на заедничката задача на НЛПТЕА 2020 за ЦГЕД. Презентираме хибриден систем кој ги користи и стадиите на детекција и корекција. Стапата на детекција е секвенцијален модел за означување базиран на БиLSTM-CRF и BERT контекстна претстава на зборовите. Стапата на корекција е хибриден модел базиран на n-грам и Seq2Seq. Без додавање дополнителни карактеристики и надворешни податоци, контекстното претставување на зборовите БЕРТ може ефикасно да ја подобри метриката на резултатите на детекцијата и корекцијата на кинеските граматички грешки.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Dalam proses belajar bahasa Cina, pelajar bahasa kedua mungkin mempunyai pelbagai ralat grammatik disebabkan pemindahan negatif bahasa asli. Kertas ini menjelaskan penghantaran kami kepada tugas kongsi NLPTEA 2020 pada CGED. Kami memperkenalkan sistem hibrid yang menggunakan kedua-dua tahap pengesan dan pembetulan. Tahap pengesan adalah model label sekuensi berdasarkan perwakilan perkataan kontekstual BiLSTM-CRF dan BERT. Tahap penyesuaian adalah model hibrid berdasarkan n-gram dan Seq2Seq. Tanpa menambah ciri-ciri tambahan dan data luaran, perwakilan perkataan kontekstual BERT boleh meningkatkan metrik prestasi pengesan dan perbaikan ralat grammatik Cina.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ചൈനീസ് പഠിക്കുന്ന പ്രക്രിയയില്‍, രണ്ടാമത്തെ ഭാഷ പഠിക്കുന്നവര്‍ക്ക് നേരിട്ട് ഭാഷ മാറ്റുന്നതിനാല്‍ പല ഗ്രാമാ ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ സിജെഡിയില്‍ പങ്കുചേര്‍ത്ത ജോലിയെ നമ്മുടെ നിയന്ത്രണത്തെക്കുറിച്ച് പറയുന്നു. ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഒരു ഹൈബ്രിഡ് സിസ്റ്റം കൊണ്ടുവരുന്നു. അത് കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നതും ശരിയാക്കുന്നതും ഉപയോഗിക്കു ബിഎല്‍എസ്റ്റി- CRF- നെ അടിസ്ഥാനമാക്കിയ ഒരു സാധാരണ ലേബെലിങ്ങ് മോഡലാണ് കണ്ടുപിടിക്കുന്നത്. ബെര്‍ട്ടി നിലവിലുള്ള ന്‍ ഗ്രാമും സെക്ക്2സെക്കും അടിസ്ഥാനമായി ഒരു ഹൈബ്രിഡ് മോഡലാണ്. കൂടുതല്‍ ഗുണഗണങ്ങളും പുറത്തുള്ള വിവരങ്ങളും കൂട്ടിചേര്‍ക്കാതെ, ബെര്‍ട്ടി നിലവിലുള്ള വാക്ക് പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്നത് ചൈനീസ് ഗ്രാമ്ര</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Fil-proċess tat-tagħlim taċ-Ċiniż, l-istudenti tat-tieni lingwa jista’ jkollhom diversi żbalji grammatiċi minħabba t-trasferiment negattiv tal-lingwa nattiva. Dan id-dokument jiddeskrivi s-sottomissjoni tagħna lill-kompitu komuni NLPTEA 2020 dwar is-CGED. Aħna nippreżentaw sistema ibrida li tuża kemm l-istadji ta’ detezzjoni kif ukoll ta’ korrezzjoni. L-istadju ta’ detezzjoni huwa mudell sekwenzjali ta’ tikkettar ibbażat fuq ir-rappreżentazzjoni kuntestwali tal-kelma BiLSTM-CRF u BERT. L-istadju ta’ korrezzjoni huwa mudell ibridu bbażat fuq n-gramma u Seq2Seq. Mingħajr iż-żieda ta’ karatteristiċi addizzjonali u dejta esterna, ir-rappreżentanza tal-kelma kuntestwali BERT tista’ ttejjeb b’mod effettiv il-metriċi tal-prestazzjoni tal-identifikazzjoni u l-korrezzjoni ta’ żbalji grammatiċi Ċiniżi.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Хятад хэлний суралцах үйл явцдаа хоёр дахь хэл сурагчид ээж хэлийн сөрөг шилжүүлэлтийн шалтгаан олон грамматикийн алдаа байж болно. Энэ цаас бидний NLPTEA 2020-ийн CGED-д хуваалцах ажлыг тайлбарладаг. Бид олох болон зөв загварыг ашигладаг гибрид системийг харуулж байна. Тайлбарлах шатан нь BiLSTM-CRF болон BERT контекст үг илэрхийлэх загвар юм. Шулгалтын шатан нь n-грамм болон Seq2Seq-ын үндсэн гибрид загвар юм. Нэг нэмэлт чанар болон гадаад өгөгдлийг нэмэгдэхгүй байвал, BERT-ын орчин үеийн үзүүлэлт нь Хятад грамматикийн алдаа гаргах болон шууд байдлын үйлдвэрлэлтийн метрикийг үр дүнтэй сайжруулж чадн</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>I læring av kinesisk kan andre språkelærar ha ulike grammatiske feil på grunn av negativt overføring av språk. Denne papiret beskriver vårt oppføring til delt oppgåve NLPTEA 2020 på CGED. Vi presenterer eit hybrid system som brukar både oppdaging og rettingsstader. Oppdagingsstaden er ein sekvensisk merkelappemodell basert på BiLSTM-CRF og BERT-kontekstalt ordrepresentasjon. Korrigeringsstaden er ein hybridmodell basert på n-gram og Seq2Seq. Utan å leggja til eksterne funksjonar og eksterne data, kan BERT- kontekst- ordrepresentasjonen effektivt forbedra utviklingsmeterikatoren til kinesisk grammatisk feiloppdaging og retting.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>W procesie nauki chińskiego uczący się języka drugiego mogą mieć różne błędy gramatyczne z powodu negatywnego transferu języka ojczystego. Niniejszy artykuł opisuje nasze zgłoszenie do wspólnego zadania NLPTEA 2020 na CGED. Prezentujemy system hybrydowy, który wykorzystuje zarówno etapy detekcji, jak i korekcji. Etap wykrywania jest sekwencyjnym modelem etykietowania opartym na kontekstowej reprezentacji słów BiLSTM-CRF i BERT. Etap korekcji jest modelem hybrydowym opartym na n-gramie i Seq2Seq. Bez dodawania dodatkowych funkcji i danych zewnętrznych, kontekstowa reprezentacja słów BERT może skutecznie poprawić wskaźniki wydajności chińskiego wykrywania i korekcji błędów gramatycznych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>În procesul de învățare a limbii chineze, cursanții de limbă a doua pot avea diferite erori gramaticale din cauza transferului negativ al limbii materne. Această lucrare descrie prezentarea noastră la sarcina comună NLPTEA 2020 privind CGED. Vă prezentăm un sistem hibrid care utilizează atât etapele de detecție, cât și cele de corecție. Etapa de detectare este un model de etichetare secvențială bazat pe reprezentarea contextuală a cuvintelor BiLSTM-CRF și BERT. Etapa de corecție este un model hibrid bazat pe n-gram și Seq2Seq. Fără a adăuga caracteristici suplimentare și date externe, reprezentarea contextuală a cuvintelor BERT poate îmbunătăți eficient măsurătorile performanței detectării și corectării erorilor gramaticale chinezești.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>U procesu učenja kineskog jezika drugi učitelji mogu imati različite gramatičke greške zbog negativnog prenošenja jezika. Ovaj papir opisuje našu predanost podijeljenom zadatku NLPTEA 2020 o CGED-u. Predstavljamo hibridni sistem koji koristi detektive i korekcije. Stadija otkrivanja je sekvencijski model označavanja na temelju BiLSTM-CRF i BERT kontekstualne reči. Korekcija je hibridni model baziran n a n-gramu i Seq2Seq. Bez dodavanja dodatnih karakteristika i spoljnih podataka, predstavljanje BERT-a kontekstualne reči može učinkovito poboljšati metriku učinkovitosti kineskog gramatičkog otkrivanja i isprave grešaka.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>චීනි භාෂාව ඉගෙන ගන්න ප්‍රකාරයේ දෙවෙනි භාෂාව ඉගෙන ගන්න පුළුවන් විවිධ වැරදිලි තියෙන්න පුළු මේ පැත්තේ අපේ පිළිගන්නේ NLPTEA 2020යි CGED ගැන කැමති වැඩක් විතරයි. අපි හායිබ්‍රිඩ් පද්ධතියක් පෙන්වන්නේ, ඒ වගේම හොයාගන්න සහ සුදුසුම් පද්ධතියක් ප්‍රයෝජන හොයාගන්න ස්ථානය තමයි BiLSTM-CRF සහ BERT සාමාන්‍ය වචන ප්‍රතිනිධානය සඳහා ප්‍රතිනිධානයක් විසින් ලේබිල් මඩ The correction stage is a hybroid Model based on the n-gram and Seq2Seq. විශේෂතාවක් සහ ප්‍රතික්‍රිය දත්ත සම්බන්ධ නොකරලා, BERT සම්බන්ධ වාර්තාවක් වචන ප්‍රතික්‍රියාපනය ප්‍රතික්‍රියාපන</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>I processen att lära sig kinesiska kan andraspråkslärare ha olika grammatiska fel på grund av negativ överföring av modersmål. Denna uppsats beskriver vår inlämning till NLPTEA 2020 delade uppgift om CGED. Vi presenterar ett hybridsystem som använder både detekterings- och korrigeringsstadier. Detektionssteget är en sekventiell märkningsmodell baserad på BiLSTM-CRF och BERT kontextuell ordrepresentation. Korrigeringsfasen är en hybridmodell baserad på n-gram och Seq2Seq. Utan att lägga till ytterligare funktioner och externa data kan BERT:s kontextuella ordrepresentation effektivt förbättra prestandamätningarna för detektering och korrigering av kinesiska grammatiska fel.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Marka lagu jiro barashada Shiino waxaa laga yaabaa in dadka baranaya luqada labaad ay leeyihiin khalad kala duduwan grammatika sababtoo ah wareejinta afka hooyo. This paper describes our submission to the NLPTEA 2020 shared task on CGED.  Waxaan keenaynaa nidaam hibir ah oo isticmaalaya baaritaanka iyo hagitaanka. Xarunta caddeyntu waa model sawir ah oo ku saleysan BiLSTM-CRF iyo BERT oo ku qoran qoraalka xilliga ah. Heerka hagitaanku waa muusikada hybridka oo ku saleysan n-gram iyo Seq2Seq. Xiriir dheeraad ah iyo macluumaad dibadda ah la'aanta, qayb-dhigista erayga joogtada ah ee BERT wuxuu si fiican u beddeli karaa qaababka ku saabsan cadayn iyo hagaajinta khaladda ee Shiino.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>சீன கற்றுக்கொள்ளும் செயல்பாட்டில், இரண்டாவது மொழி கற்றுக்கொள்பவர் This paper describes our submission to the NLPTEA 2020 shared task on CGED.  நாம் கண்டறிதல் மற்றும் திருத்தம் முறைகளை பயன்படுத்தும் ஒரு ஹைப்ரி அமைப்பை காண்பிக்கிறோம். The detection stage is a sequential labelling model based on BiLSTM- CRF and BERT contextual word representation. The correction stage is a hybrid model based on the n- gram and Seq2Seq. கூடுதல் குணங்கள் மற்றும் வெளி தரவுகளை சேர்க்காமல், BERT தற்காலிக வார்த்தை குறிப்பிடுதல் சீனா வரையறை பிழை கண்டுபிடிப்பு மற்றும் திருத</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>چین کی تعلیم کے مطابق دوسری زبان سکھانے والوں کے لئے مختلف گراماتیکی خطا ہوسکتے ہیں ماں کی زبان کی منفی ترافرست کے سبب۔ This paper describes our submission to the NLPTEA 2020 shared task on CGED. ہم ایک ہیبراڈ سیستم کو پیش کریں جو پہچان اور اصلاح مرحلے کو استعمال کرتا ہے۔ آشنا سٹیج BiLSTM-CRF اور BERT contextual word representation پر بنیاد ایک سٹیل لیبلینگ موڈل ہے. اصلاح مرحلہ ایک ہیبراڈ موڈل ہے جو n-گرم اور Seq2Seq پر بنیاد ہے. بغیر اس کے کہ زیادہ ویژگی اور بیرونی ڈیٹا اضافہ نہ کریں، BERT کنٹکسٹیول کلمات کی نمایش چینی گراماتیکی خطا شناسایی اور اصلاح کی عملکرد متریک کو عمدہ کر سکتی ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Xitoycha o'rganishda ikkinchi tillar o'rganishlari natiy tillarining negativ tarjima qilishi sababini boshqa grammatik xatolari bo'lishi mumkin. Bu qogʻoz CGED (NLPTEA 2020) bilan birlashtirilgan vazifani anglatadi. Biz haybrid tizimini aniqlash va toʻgʻrilash holatidan foydalanishimiz. Name Toʻgʻri sahifa - n- gram va Seq2Seq asosida ishlatilgan hybrid modeli. Qoʻshimcha moslamalar va externa maʼlumot qoʻshilmaydi, BERT'ning davomida soʻzni taʼminlashtirish va Xitoycha grammatikal xato aniqlashni va toʻgʻrilishini bajarishi mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Trong quá trình học tiếng Trung, học giả ngôn ngữ thứ hai có thể có lỗi theo ngữ pháp khác nhau do sự chuyển đổi âm tính của ngôn ngữ bản xứ. Tờ giấy này mô tả việc chúng tôi đăng ký vào một nhiệm vụ chung chung NLlái 2020 ở CGEDed. Chúng tôi giới thiệu một hệ thống lai sử dụng cả các giai đoạn phát hiện và sửa chữa. Phát hiện trường là một mô hình mô phỏng sắp xếp dựa trên BiLSTM-CRF và BERT nền đại diện các từ ngữ. Bộ sửa chữa là một mô hình lai dựa trên n-gram và Seq2Seq. Không cần thêm các tính năng và dữ liệu bên ngoài, sự mô tả ngữ cảnh của thiếu sót sót sót sót sót sót của ngôn ngữ học Trung Hoa có thể cải thiện tỉ lệ hiệu quả.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>В процеса на изучаване на китайски, обучаващите се на втори език могат да имат различни граматически грешки поради отрицателния трансфер на родния език. Настоящата статия описва нашето представяне на споделената задача на НЛПТЕА 2020 по ЦЕД. Представяме хибридна система, която използва както етапите на откриване, така и на корекция. Етапът на откриване е модел на последователно етикетиране, базиран на контекстното представяне на думи. Етапът на корекция е хибриден модел, базиран на n-грама и Seq2Seq. Без добавяне на допълнителни функции и външни данни, контекстното представяне на думи може ефективно да подобри показателите за ефективност на откриването и корекцията на китайската граматична грешка.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>I processen med at lære kinesisk, andetsprogslærere kan have forskellige grammatiske fejl på grund af den negative overførsel af modersmål. Denne artikel beskriver vores indsendelse til NLPTEA 2020 delte opgave på CGED. Vi præsenterer et hybridsystem, der bruger både detektions- og korrektionsstadier. Detektionsfasen er en sekventiel mærkningsmodel baseret på BiLSTM-CRF og BERT kontekstuel ordrepræsentation. Korrektionsfasen er en hybridmodel baseret på n-grammet og Seq2Seq. Uden at tilføje yderligere funktioner og eksterne data kan BERT's kontekstuelle ordrepræsentation effektivt forbedre ydelsesmålingerne for registrering og korrektion af kinesisk grammatisk fejl.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Tijdens het leren van Chinees kunnen tweetalige leerlingen verschillende grammaticale fouten hebben als gevolg van de negatieve overdracht van moedertaal. Dit document beschrijft onze inzending aan de NLPTEA 2020 gedeelde taak op CGED. We presenteren een hybride systeem dat zowel detectie- als correctiefasen gebruikt. De detectiefase is een sequentieel labelmodel gebaseerd op BiLSTM-CRF en BERT contextuele woordweergave. De correctiefase is een hybride model gebaseerd op de n-gram en Seq2Seq. Zonder extra functies en externe gegevens toe te voegen, kan de contextuele woordweergave van BERT de prestatiestatistieken van Chinese grammaticale foutdetectie en -correctie effectief verbeteren.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>U procesu učenja kineskog jezika, učitelji drugih jezika mogu imati različite gramatičke greške zbog negativnog prenošenja jezika. Ovaj papir opisuje naše podnošenje zajedničkom zadatku NLPTEA 2020 o CGED-u. Predstavljamo hibridni sustav koji koristi detektive i korekcije. Stadija otkrivanja je sekvencijski model označavanja na temelju BiLSTM-CRF i BERT kontekstualne riječi. Pozor isprave je hibridni model baziran n a n-gramu i Seq2Seq. Bez dodavanja dodatnih karakteristika i vanjskih podataka, predstavljanje BERT-a kontekstualne riječi može učinkovito poboljšati provedbenu metriku kineskog gramatičkog otkrivanja i isprave grešaka.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Während des Lernens von Chinesisch können Zweitsprachenlerner aufgrund des negativen Transfers der Muttersprache verschiedene grammatikalische Fehler haben. Dieses Papier beschreibt unsere Einreichung zur gemeinsamen Aufgabe NLPTEA 2020 auf CGED. Wir präsentieren ein Hybridsystem, das sowohl Detektions- als auch Korrekturstufen nutzt. Die Erkennungsstufe ist ein sequentielles Beschriftungsmodell basierend auf BiLSTM-CRF und BERT kontextueller Wortdarstellung. Die Korrekturstufe ist ein Hybridmodell basierend auf dem n-Gramm und Seq2Seq. Ohne zusätzliche Funktionen und externe Daten hinzuzufügen, kann die BERT kontextbezogene Wortdarstellung die Leistungskennzahlen der chinesischen grammatischen Fehlererkennung und -korrektur effektiv verbessern.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>중국어를 배우는 과정에서 모국어의 마이너스 변화로 인해 제2언어 학습자는 각종 문법 오류가 발생할 수 있다.이 문서에서는 NLPTEA 2020 CGED 공유 임무에 제출된 상황을 설명합니다.우리는 검측과 교정 단계를 이용한 혼합 시스템을 제시했다.체크 단계는 BiLSTM CRF 및 BERT 컨텍스트 단어를 기반으로 하는 순차 태그 모델입니다.교정 단계는 n-gram과 Seq2Seq를 기반으로 한 혼합 모델이다.BERT 컨텍스트 단어는 추가 피쳐와 외부 데이터를 추가하지 않고도 중국어 구문 오류를 효과적으로 감지하고 수정할 수 있는 성능 지표를 나타냅니다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_id>Dalam proses belajar bahasa Cina, para pelajar bahasa kedua mungkin memiliki beberapa kesalahan grammatik karena transfer negatif bahasa asli. Kertas ini menjelaskan pengiriman kita ke NLPTEA 2020 tugas berbagi di CGED. Kami mempersembahkan sistem hibrid yang menggunakan kedua tahap deteksi dan koreksi. The detection stage is a sequential labelling model based on BiLSTM-CRF and BERT contextual word representation.  Stadium koreksi adalah model hibrid berdasarkan n-gram dan Seq2Seq. Tanpa menambahkan karakteristik tambahan dan data luar, representasi kata kontekstual BERT dapat secara efektif meningkatkan metrik prestasi dari deteksi dan koreksi kesalahan grammatik Cina.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>در فرایند یادگیری چینی، دانش‌آموزان دوم زبان ممکن است اشتباه‌های گرامیک مختلف داشته باشد به سبب انتقال منفی زبان مادری. این کاغذ تحویل ما به کار مشترک NLPTEA 2020 در CGED توصیف می‌کند. ما یک سیستم هیبرید را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که از مرحله‌های شناسایی و اصلاح استفاده می‌کند. مرحله شناسایی یک مدل نقاشی دنباله بر اساس نمایش کلمات متوسط BiLSTM-CRF و BERT است. مرحله اصلاح یک مدل hybrid بر اساس n-gram و Seq2Seq است. بدون اضافه کردن ویژگی‌های اضافه و داده‌های خارجی، نمایش کلمه‌های متوسط BERT می‌تواند به طور تاثیر متریک عملکرد خطاهای گراماتیکی چینی را دریافت و درست کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Katika mchakato wa kujifunza Kichina, wanafunzi wa lugha ya pili wanaweza kuwa na makosa mbalimbali ya kiuchumi kutokana na uhamishaji hasi wa lugha ya asili. Gazeti hili linaelezea ujumbe wetu wa NLPTEA 2020 uliosambazwa na kazi ya CGED. We present a hybrid system that utilizes both detection and correction stages.  Jukwaa la kutambua ni modeli ya maambukizi inayohusiana na BiLSTM-CRF na uwakilishi wa maneno ya wakati wa BERT. Jukwaa la uharibifu ni modeli ya hybrid inayotumiwa n a n-gram na Seq2Seq. Bila kuongezea vipengele vya ziada na takwimu za nje, uwakilishi wa maneno ya sasa ya BERT yanaweza kuboresha mbinu za uchunguzi wa makosa ya kiuchumi nchini China na kuharibiwa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Çinçe öwrenmek procesinde, ikinji dil öwrenmeýänleriň ene diliniň göçürmesi üçin dürli gramatik hatalarynyň bolup biler. Bu kagyz NLPTEA 2020-nji ýygnagymyzy CGED barada paýlaşýar. Biz bir hybrid sistemini tanyş we düzeltmek sahypalaryny ulanýan Bu deteksion sahnesi BiLSTM-CRF we BERT tesbitli kelime temsiline dayanan bir sıralan etiketleme modeldir. Düzeltmek sahypasy n-gram we Seq2Seq-a dayanan hybrid nusgasydir. Eger özellikler we daşarydaky maglumatlary eklemeýän bolsa, BERT senesasy sözleriň üýtgetmesi Çinçe gramatik hatalaryň tanymasynyň we düzeltmeginin üstine çykaryp biler.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Në procesin e mësimit të kinezës, mësuesit e gjuhës së dytë mund të kenë gabime të ndryshme grammatike për shkak të transferimit negativ të gjuhës natyrore. Ky dokument përshkruan paraqitjen tonë në detyrën e përbashkët të NLPTEA 2020 për CGED. Ne prezantojmë një sistem hibridë që përdorë si fazat e zbulimit, ashtu edhe të korrigjimit. Faza e zbulimit është një model shequencial etiketash bazuar në përfaqësimin kontekstual të fjalëve BiLSTM-CRF dhe BERT. Faza e korrigjimit është një model hibridë bazuar n ë n-gram dhe Seq2Seq. Pa shtimin e karakteristikave shtesë dhe të dhënave të jashtme, përfaqësimi kontekstual i fjalëve BERT mund të përmirësojë efektivisht metrikat e performancës të zbulimit dhe korrektimit të gabimeve grammatike kineze.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>ቻይና በተማሩ ክፍል፣ ሁለተኛው ቋንቋ ተማሪዎቹ በአገሪው ቋንቋ መዘዋወር ምክንያት የግራማዊ ስህተት ይኖራል፡፡ ይህ ገጽ በCGED ላይ 2020 የNLPTEA አካባቢነታችንን ይናገራል፡፡ የኬብሪድ ስርዓት እና ማስታወቂያውን እና ማስታወቂያውን የሚጠቀም ነው፡፡ በቢLSTM-CRF እና BERT በተገኘ ቃላት መልዕክት ላይ የተመሳሳይ የጽሑፍ ሞዴል ነው፡፡ የ-ግራም እና Seq2Seq የተመሠረተ የኬብሪድ ሞዴል ነው፡፡ ባይጨመር ምርጫዎች እና ውጭ ዳታ ባይጨመር፣ የBERT የአሁኑን ቃል መልዕክት የቻይና የግራማሲካዊ ስህተት ማግኘት እና ማስተካከል ማድረግ ይችላል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>In die proses van die leer van Sjinese, tweede taal leerders mag verskeie grammatiese foute hê vanweë die negatiewe oordrag van die taal. Hierdie papier beskrywe ons onderskrywing aan die NLPTEA 2020 deel taak op CGED. Ons stel 'n hybrid stelsel wat gebruik word beide opdekking en korreksie stadige. Die opdekking stadium is 'n sekwensielle etiketting model gebaseer op BiLSTM- CRF en BERT konteksual woord voorsiening. Die korreksie stadium is 'n hibridmodel gebaseer op die n-gram en Seq2Seq. Sonder om addisionele funksies en eksterne data byvoeg te voeg, kan die BERT contextual woord verteenwoording effektief die prestasie metries van Sjinese grammatiese fout opdecking en korreksie verbeter.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Չինաստանի ուսումնասիրության ընթացքում երկրորդ լեզվի ուսանողները կարող են ունենալ տարբեր գրամատիկ սխալներ՝ ծննդյան լեզվի բացասական փոխանցման պատճառով: Այս հոդվածը նկարագրում է մեր ներկայացումը ՆԼՊՏԵԱ 2020-ի ընդհանուր հանձնարարությանը CGeD-ի մասին: Մենք ներկայացնում ենք հիբրիդ համակարգ, որը օգտագործում է բացահայտումների և ուղղումների փուլերը: Բացահայտության փուլը հաջորդական պիտակագրման մոդել է, որը հիմնված է ԲիLSԹՄ-ԿՌՖ և ԲԵԹ-ի կոնտեքստային բառերի ներկայացման վրա: Կարգավորման փուլը հիբրիդ մոդել է, որը հիմնված է n-գրամի և SeQ2SeQ-ի վրա: Առանց ավելացնելու առանձնահատկություններ և արտաքին տվյալներ, BER-ի կոնտեքստիկ բառերի ներկայացումը կարող է արդյունավետ բարելավել չինական գրամատիկ սխալների հայտնաբերման և ուղղումների արտադրողականության չափում</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>চীনা শিক্ষা প্রক্রিয়ায় দ্বিতীয় ভাষা শিক্ষার্থীদের স্থানীয় ভাষার নেতিবাচক পরিবর্তনের কারণে বিভিন্ন গ্রামাট এই পত্রিকাটি সিজেডিতে আমাদের এনএলপিটেয়া ২০২০ সালের প্রতি আমাদের প্রতিষ্ঠান বর্ণনা করেছে। আমরা একটা হাইব্রিড সিস্টেম উপস্থাপন করছি যা আবিষ্কার এবং সংস্কারের মাধ্যমে ব্যবহার করে। বিএলস্টিএম-CRF এবং বিবের্টি প্রতিনিধিত্বের উপর ভিত্তিক একটি পরবর্তী লেবেলিং মডেল। ন-গ্রাম এবং সেক২সেকের উপর ভিত্তিক একটি হাইব্রিড মডেল। অতিরিক্ত বৈশিষ্ট্য এবং বাইরের তথ্য যোগ করা ছাড়াই বিবেরেটি প্রতিনিধিত্ব বিভিন্ন শব্দের প্রতিনিধিত্বে চীনা গ্রাম্যাটিক্যাল ত্র</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Çinli dilləri öyrənmək üçün ikinci dil öyrənənənçilərin yerli dillərin negatif tərəfindən müxtəlif qrammatik xətaları olar. Bu kağıt bizim NLPTEA 2020 CGED barəsində paylaşdığımız işləri tarif edir. Biz hər ikisini tanıma və düzəltmə fərqlərini istifadə edən hibrid sistemini göstəririk. İnternet sahəsi BiLSTM-CRF və BERT müxtəlif söz göstəricisinə dayanan sıralar etiketləmə modelidir. Düzeltme sahəsi n-gram və Seq2Seq üzərində dayanan hibrid modelidir. Əlavə fərqli və dış məlumatları əlavə etmədən, BERT müxtəlif sözlərin göstəricisi Çin qrammatik xətaların keşfini və düzəltməsini etkili olaraq daha yaxşılaşdıra bilər.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>U procesu učenja kineskog jezika, učitelji drugih jezika mogu imati različite gramatične greške zbog negativnog prenošenja jezika. Ovaj papir opisuje našu predanost podijeljenom zadatku NLPTEA 2020 o CGED-u. Predstavljamo hibridni sistem koji koristi detektive i korekcije. Stadija otkrivanja je sekvencijski model označavanja na temelju BiLSTM-CRF i BERT kontekstualne riječi. Korekcija je hibridni model baziran n a n-gramu i Seq2Seq. Bez dodavanja dodatnih karakteristika i vanjskih podataka, predstavljanje BERT-a kontekstualne riječi može učinkovito poboljšati metriku učinkovitosti kineskog gramatičkog otkrivanja i isprave grešaka.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>In the process of learning Chinese, second language learners may have various grammatical errors due to the negative transfer of native language.  Aquest paper descriu la nostra presentació a la tasca compartida NLPTEA 2020 sobre CGED. Presentam un sistema híbrid que utilitza les etapes de detecció i correcció. L'etapa de detecció és un model d'etiquetage seqüencial basat en la representació contextual de paraules BiLSTM-CRF i BERT. L'etapa de correcció és un model híbrid basat en n-gram i Seq2Seq. Sense afegir característiques adicionals i dades externes, la representació contextual de paraules BERT pot millorar efectivament les mètriques de rendiment de la detecció i correcció d'errors gramàtics xinesos.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Během výuky čínštiny mohou studenti druhého jazyka mít různé gramatické chyby v důsledku negativního přenosu rodného jazyka. Tento článek popisuje náš předložení sdíleného úkolu NLPTEA 2020 na CGED. Představujeme hybridní systém, který využívá jak detekční, tak korekční fáze. Detekční fáze je sekvenční model značení založený na kontextové reprezentaci slov BiLSTM-CRF a BERT. Korekční fáze je hybridní model založený na n-gramu a Seq2Seq. Bez přidávání dalších funkcí a externích dat může kontextová reprezentace slov BERT efektivně zlepšit výkonnostní metriky čínské gramatické chyby detekce a opravy.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Toisen kielen oppijoilla voi olla erilaisia kieliopillisia virheitä äidinkielen negatiivisen siirron vuoksi. Tässä artikkelissa kuvataan osallistumismme NLPTEA 2020:n yhteiseen tehtävään CGED:ssä. Esittelemme hybridijärjestelmän, joka hyödyntää sekä havaitsemis- että korjausvaihetta. Havaintovaihe on BiLSTM-CRF- ja BERT-kontekstuaaliseen sanaesitykseen perustuva perättäinen merkintämalli. Korjausvaihe on hybridimalli, joka perustuu n-grammiin ja Seq2Seq. Ilman lisäominaisuuksia ja ulkoista dataa BERT-kontekstuaalinen sanaesitys voi tehokkaasti parantaa kiinalaisten kielioppivirheiden havaitsemisen ja korjaamisen suorituskykymittareita.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Hiina keele õppimisel võivad teise keele õppijatel olla emakeele negatiivse ülekande tõttu erinevad grammatikavead. Käesolevas dokumendis kirjeldatakse meie esitamist NLPTEA 2020 jagatud ülesandele CGED. Esitleme hübriidsüsteemi, mis kasutab nii tuvastamise kui ka parandamise etappi. Avastamisetapp on järjestikuse märgistuse mudel, mis põhineb BiLSTM-CRF ja BERT kontekstipõhisel sõnaesitusel. Korrigeerimisetapp on hübriidmudel, mis põhineb n-grammil ja Seq2Seq-il. Täiendavaid funktsioone ja välisandmeid lisamata saab BERT kontekstipõhine sõnaesitus tõhusalt parandada hiina grammatiliste vigade tuvastamise ja parandamise jõudlusnäitajaid.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>Nang pengguna sampeyan Cines, sampeyan tanggal saiki unyak gak bener Perintah iki rambarang nggawe nyimpen NLPMEA 2020 nganggo CGED Awak dhéwé éntuk sistem sing wis ana ing nggo tahirno karo Ngubah Sayensi Kampèng rection kuwi model HyBridge sing basa ning n-gram karo Seq2Seq. Nanging nambah peringatan tambah lan data anyar, gambar BERT contextual</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>V procesu učenja kitajščine imajo učenci drugega jezika lahko različne slovnične napake zaradi negativnega prenosa maternega jezika. Ta prispevek opisuje našo predložitev skupni nalogi NLPTEA 2020 na CGED. Predstavljamo hibridni sistem, ki uporablja tako stopnjo odkrivanja kot korekcije. Stopnja odkrivanja je model zaporednega označevanja, ki temelji na kontekstni predstavitvi besed BiLSTM-CRF in BERT. Korekcijska faza je hibridni model, ki temelji na n-gramu in Seq2Seq. Brez dodajanja dodatnih funkcij in zunanjih podatkov lahko kontekstna predstavitev besed BERT učinkovito izboljša meritve učinkovitosti kitajskega slovničnega odkrivanja in popravljanja napak.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Haƙĩƙa, a cikin jararin da aka karanta wa China, masu kara na lugha na ƙarƙashin, watau su iya da wasu ɓatattu masu karatun grammaci ne sababin shige-motsi na lugha native. This paper describes our submission to the NLPTEA 2020 shared task on CGED.  Muna halatar da wani na'ura da ya yi amfani da duk ganin da za'a sani. Halin da za'a gane shi wata salon mai biyayyar bayãni ne a kan bincike BiLStM-CRF da maɓallin maganar da BERT. Halin da aka daidaita shi yana wata salon zaɓani n a n-gram da Seq2Seq. Bai ƙara da wasu hushi da data masu ƙaranci, mai gaya maganar BERT na koma, yana iya amfani da gyarata metric mai gyarawa na ganin ɓata na grammati na China.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>རྒྱ་ནག་གི་སློབ་བརྗོད་ཀྱི་ལས་སྦྱོར་ནང་ན་སྐད་རིགས་ཤེས་པ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་ནོར ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་ང་ཚོའི་རྗེས་སུ་NLPTEA 2020་ལ་མཉམ་དུ་གཏོང་གི་བྱ་རིམ་CGED་དུ་བཤད་པ ང་ཚོས་རྟོགས་དང་བདེ་འཇགས་ཀྱི་ཆེན་གཉིས་ལས་སྤྱོད་པའི་ཆ་རྐྱེན་གྱི་མ་ལག་གི་སྟོན་པ་ཞིག་འཆར་ཡོད། The detection stage is a sequential labelling model based on BiLSTM-CRF and BERT contextual word representation. The correction stage is a hybrid model based on the n-gram and Seq2Seq. Without adding additional features and external data, the BERT contextual word representation can effectively improve the performance metrics of Chinese grammatical error detection and correction.</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>In the process of learning Chinese, second language learners may have various grammatical errors due to the negative transfer of native language.  העיתון הזה מתאר את ההעברה שלנו למשימה משותפת NLPTEA 2020 על CGED. אנחנו מציגים מערכת היברידית שמשתמשת בשלבי גילוי ותיקון. The detection stage is a sequential labelling model based on BiLSTM-CRF and BERT contextual word representation.  שלב התיקון הוא מודל היברידי מבוסס על n-גרם וסקק2Seq. Without adding additional features and external data, the BERT contextual word representation can effectively improve the performance metrics of Chinese grammatical error detection and correction.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>SEMA : Text Simplification Evaluation through Semantic Alignment<fixed-case>SEMA</fixed-case>: Text Simplification Evaluation through Semantic Alignment</title>
      <author><first>Xuan</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Huizhou</first><last>Zhao</last></author>
      <author><first>KeXin</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Yiyang</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <pages>121–128</pages>
      <abstract>Text simplification is an important branch of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing</a>. At present, methods used to evaluate the semantic retention of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_simplification">text simplification</a> are mostly based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/String_matching">string matching</a>. We propose the SEMA (text Simplification Evaluation Measure through Semantic Alignment), which is based on semantic alignment. Semantic alignments include complete alignment, partial alignment and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyponymy_and_hypernymy">hyponymy alignment</a>. Our experiments show that the evaluation results of SEMA have a high consistency with human evaluation for the simplified corpus of Chinese and English news texts.</abstract>
      <url hash="8ab0302a">2020.nlptea-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>zhang-etal-2020-sema</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>