<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.parlaclarin">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Second ParlaCLARIN Workshop</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Darja</first><last>Fišer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Maria</first><last>Eskevich</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Franciska</first><last>de Jong</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-47-4</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9b50da83">2020.parlaclarin-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>parlaclarin-2020-parlaclarin</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Compiling Czech Parliamentary Stenographic Protocols into a Corpus<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>zech Parliamentary Stenographic Protocols into a Corpus</title>
      <author><first>Barbora</first><last>Hladka</last></author>
      <author><first>Matyáš</first><last>Kopp</last></author>
      <author><first>Pavel</first><last>Straňák</last></author>
      <pages>18–22</pages>
      <abstract>The Parliament of the Czech Republic consists of two chambers : the Chamber of Deputies (Lower House) and the Senate (Upper House). In our work, we focus on agenda and documents that relate to the Chamber of Deputies exclusively. We pay particular attention to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shorthand">stenographic protocols</a> that record the Chamber of Deputies’ meetings. Our overall goal is to (1) compile the protocols into a ParlaCLARIN TEI encoded corpus, (2) make this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> accessible and searchable in the TEITOK web-based platform, (3) annotate the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> using the modules available in TEITOK, e.g. detect and recognize <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named_entity">named entities</a>, and (4) highlight the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotations</a> in TEITOK. In addition, we add two more goals that we consider innovative : (5) update the corpus every time a new stenographic protocol is published online by the Chambers of Deputies and (6) expose the annotations as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linked_open_data">linked open data</a> in order to improve the protocols’ interoperability with other existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linked_open_data">linked open data</a>. This paper is devoted to the goals (1) and (5).</abstract>
      <url hash="c9a1f422">2020.parlaclarin-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>hladka-etal-2020-compiling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Who mentions whom? Recognizing political actors in proceedings</title>
      <author><first>Lennart</first><last>Kerkvliet</last></author>
      <author><first>Jaap</first><last>Kamps</last></author>
      <author><first>Maarten</first><last>Marx</last></author>
      <pages>35–39</pages>
      <abstract>We show that it is straightforward to train a state of the art named entity tagger (spaCy) to recognize political actors in Dutch parliamentary proceedings with high accuracy. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tag_(metadata)">tagger</a> was trained on 3.4 K manually labeled examples, which were created in a modest 2.5 days work. This resource is made available on github. Besides proper nouns of persons and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_party">political parties</a>, the tagger can recognize quite complex definite descriptions referring to cabinet ministers, ministries, and parliamentary committees. We also provide a demo search engine which employs the tagged entities in its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_engine_results_page">SERP</a> and result summaries.</abstract>
      <url hash="0d61d348">2020.parlaclarin-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>kerkvliet-etal-2020-mentions</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Querying a large annotated corpus of parliamentary debates</title>
      <author><first>Sascha</first><last>Diwersy</last></author>
      <author><first>Giancarlo</first><last>Luxardo</last></author>
      <pages>75–79</pages>
      <abstract>The TAPS corpus makes it possible to share a large volume of French parliamentary data. The TEI-compliant approach behind its design choices facilitates the publishing and the interoperability of data, but also the implementation of exploratory data analysis techniques in order to process institutional or political discourse. We demonstrate its application to the debates occurred in the context of a specific legislative process, which generated a strong opposition.</abstract>
      <url hash="553ad4c1">2020.parlaclarin-1.13</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>diwersy-luxardo-2020-querying</bibkey>
    <title_ar>الاستعلام عن مجموعة كبيرة مشروحة من المناقشات البرلمانية</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Consultando um grande corpus anotado de debates parlamentares</title_pt>
      <title_es>Consulta de un amplio corpus comentado de debates parlamentarios</title_es>
      <title_ja>議会討論の大規模な注釈付きコーパスの照会</title_ja>
      <title_zh>大询带注议会辩语料库</title_zh>
      <title_hi>संसदीय बहस के एक बड़े एनोटेटेड कॉर्पस से पूछताछ</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Corpas mór anótáilte de dhíospóireachtaí parlaiminte a cheistiú</title_ga>
      <title_ka>პოლმანტიური დიბუტების დიბუტების დიბუტების დიბუტების შესახებ</title_ka>
      <title_kk>Парламенттік дискуссиялардың үлкен жаңалық корпус сұрауы</title_kk>
      <title_el>Ερώτηση ενός μεγάλου σχολιασμένου σώματος κοινοβουλευτικών συζητήσεων</title_el>
      <title_hu>A parlamenti viták nagy jegyzetekkel ellátott korpuszának lekérdezése</title_hu>
      <title_mk>Прашање на голем анотиран корпус парламентарни дебати</title_mk>
      <title_it>Interrogare un ampio corpus annotato di dibattiti parlamentari</title_it>
      <title_ms>Meminta korpus besar dibahas parlemen yang dicatat</title_ms>
      <title_lt>Klausimas dėl didelio užrašyto parlamentinių diskusijų korpuso</title_lt>
      <title_ml>ഒരു വലിയ വിവാദങ്ങള്‍ ചോദിക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mt>It-talba għal korpus kbir annotat ta' dibattiti parlamentari</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Парламентын тухай ярилцлагуудын маш олон сэтгэл татсан корпус</title_mn>
      <title_sr>Pitanje velikog annotiranog korpusa parlamentarnih debata</title_sr>
      <title_no>Spør om ein stor annotated corpus av parlamentære debatter</title_no>
      <title_pl>Pytanie o duży, adnotacyjny korpus debat parlamentarnych</title_pl>
      <title_so>Wargelinta baarlamaanka baarlamaanka baarlamaanka</title_so>
      <title_sv>Fråga en stor kommenterad samling parlamentariska debatter</title_sv>
      <title_ro>Interogarea unui corpus larg adnotat de dezbateri parlamentare</title_ro>
      <title_si>පාලමින්ටර් වාර්තාවේ විශාල ප්‍රශ්නයක් අහන්න</title_si>
      <title_ta>ஒரு பெரிய அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட பங்கார விவாதத்தைக் கேட்கிறது</title_ta>
      <title_ur>پارلمانٹر کی بحث کی ایک بڑی اظہار کی جگہ پوچھ رہی ہے</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Парламент баҳсламаларининг катта ҳужжатларини сўраб турибди</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Đang tranh chấp cả một loạt các cuộc tranh luận.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Запитване на голям анотиран корпус от парламентарни разисквания</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Pitanje velikog annotiranog korpusa parlamentarnih debata</title_hr>
      <title_de>Abfrage eines großen kommentierten Korpus parlamentarischer Debatten</title_de>
      <title_id>Querying a large annotated corpus of parliamentary debates</title_id>
      <title_ko>주석이 달린 의회 변론 자료 라이브러리를 대량으로 조회하다</title_ko>
      <title_nl>Een groot geannoteerd corpus parlementaire debatten opvragen</title_nl>
      <title_fa>درخواست یک شرکت بزرگی از بحث های پارلمانتری</title_fa>
      <title_da>Forespørgsler om et stort, kommenteret korpus af parlamentariske debatter</title_da>
      <title_sw>Kuuliza viungo vikubwa vya majadiliano ya bunge</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Parlamenteriň debatlarynyň uly nusgalan korpusyny sorap</title_tr>
      <title_af>Vra 'n groot annotated corpus van parlamentêre debate</title_af>
      <title_sq>Duke kërkuar një korpus të madh të anotuar debatesh parlamentare</title_sq>
      <title_am>የፓርላማዊ ጥያቄ ጥያቄ ሲጠይቁ</title_am>
      <title_hy>Խոսելով խորհրդարական քննարկումների մի մեծ նշումներ ունեցող մարմին,</title_hy>
      <title_az>Parlament müzakirələrinin böyük xəbərdar korpusu soruşmaq</title_az>
      <title_bn>সংসদীয় বিতর্কের বিরুদ্ধে একটি বিশাল বিক্ষোভ প্রশ্ন করেছে</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Pitanje velikog annotiranog korpusa parlamentarnih debata</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Querying a large annotated corpus of parliamentary debates</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Dotaz na rozsáhlý anotovaný korpus parlamentních debat</title_cs>
      <title_et>Suure selgitusega parlamentaarsete arutelude korpuse pärimine</title_et>
      <title_fi>Laajan selityksin varustetun parlamentaarisen keskustelun kysely</title_fi>
      <title_ha>Suna tambayar jayaya mai girma</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Povpraševanje po velikem korpusu parlamentarnih razprav z oznakami</title_sk>
      <title_jv>Yalêsêh ngilangno akeh durung malah dumadhi kayané debané pêlaré</title_jv>
      <title_bo>སྡོང་ཁང་གི་བསྟུན་གྱི་གཏམ་གླེང་སྡོམ་ཁང་ཆེན་པོ་ཞིག་གིས་</title_bo>
      <title_he>מבקש ממחלקה גדולה של דיון פרלמנטרי</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>تتيح مجموعة TAPS إمكانية مشاركة حجم كبير من البيانات البرلمانية الفرنسية. النهج المتوافق مع TEI وراء خيارات التصميم الخاصة به يسهل نشر البيانات وقابلية التشغيل البيني ، ولكن أيضًا تنفيذ تقنيات تحليل البيانات الاستكشافية من أجل معالجة الخطاب المؤسسي أو السياسي. نظهر تطبيقه على المناقشات التي جرت في سياق عملية تشريعية محددة ، والتي ولدت معارضة قوية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>El corpus TAPS permite compartir un gran volumen de datos parlamentarios franceses. El enfoque compatible con TEI detrás de sus elecciones de diseño facilita la publicación y la interoperabilidad de los datos, pero también la implementación de técnicas exploratorias de análisis de datos para procesar el discurso institucional o político. Demostramos su aplicación a los debates ocurridos en el contexto de un proceso legislativo específico, que generó una fuerte oposición.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>O corpus TAPS permite compartilhar um grande volume de dados parlamentares franceses. A abordagem compatível com TEI por trás de suas escolhas de design facilita a publicação e a interoperabilidade de dados, mas também a implementação de técnicas exploratórias de análise de dados para processar o discurso institucional ou político. Demonstramos sua aplicação aos debates ocorridos no contexto de um processo legislativo específico, o que gerou forte oposição.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>TAPSコーパスは、大量のフランスの議会データを共有することを可能にします。その設計選択の背後にあるTEI準拠のアプローチは、データの公開と相互運用性を促進するだけでなく、制度的または政治的な議論を処理するための探索的データ分析技術の実装も促進します。私たちは、強い反対を引き起こした特定の立法プロセスの中で発生した議論への適用を実証します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>TAPS语料库使分享法国议会数为可也。 其设意择背之TEI兼容之数而互操作性之,亦趣探索性数据分析术之行,以处官司政治之言。 吾明用于特定立法之背景,而强非也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>TAPS कॉर्पस फ्रांसीसी संसदीय डेटा की एक बड़ी मात्रा को साझा करना संभव बनाता है। अपने डिजाइन विकल्पों के पीछे टीईआई-अनुरूप दृष्टिकोण डेटा के प्रकाशन और इंटरऑपरेबिलिटी की सुविधा प्रदान करता है, लेकिन संस्थागत या राजनीतिक प्रवचन को संसाधित करने के लिए अन्वेषणात्मक डेटा विश्लेषण तकनीकों के कार्यान्वयन की भी सुविधा प्रदान करता है। हम एक विशिष्ट विधायी प्रक्रिया के संदर्भ में हुई बहस के लिए इसके आवेदन का प्रदर्शन करते हैं, जिसने एक मजबूत विरोध उत्पन्न किया।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Leis an gcorpas TAPS is féidir líon mór sonraí parlaiminte na Fraince a roinnt. Éascaíonn an cur chuige a chomhlíonann TEI a roghanna dearaidh foilsiú agus idir-inoibritheacht sonraí, agus éascaítear freisin cur chun feidhme teicnící taiscéalaíoch anailíse sonraí chun dioscúrsa institiúideach nó polaitiúil a phróiseáil. Léirímid gur cuireadh i bhfeidhm é ar na díospóireachtaí a tharla i gcomhthéacs próisis reachtaíochta ar leith, rud a chruthaigh freasúra láidir.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>TAPS კორპუსი შეუძლებელია გაყოფილი ფრანგული ოლაპლიმანტიური მონაცემების დიდი ზომის გაყოფილი. TEI-კომპლიენტიური პროგრამა განსაზღვრების შესაძლებლობა მონაცემების გამოყენება და ინტერსტუალური განსაზღვრების შესაძლებლობა, მაგრამ განსაზღვრების ინტერსტუალური ანალიზის ტექნოგიების გამო ჩვენ მისი პროგრამის გამოყენება დებასტებში მოხდა სპეციფიკალური legislative პროცესის კონტექსტში, რომელიც შექმნა ძალიან ოპორციაცია.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A TAPS korpusza lehetővé teszi a francia parlamenti adatok nagy mennyiségének megosztását. A tervezési választások mögött álló TEI-kompatibilis megközelítés megkönnyíti az adatok közzétételét és interoperabilitását, valamint a feltáró adatelemzési technikák bevezetését az intézményi vagy politikai diskurzus feldolgozása érdekében. Bemutatjuk annak alkalmazását egy konkrét jogalkotási folyamat keretében zajlott vitákra, amelyek erőteljes ellenzéket keltettek.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_kk>TAPS корпус французша парламенттік деректерін үлкен бөліске мүмкіндік береді. TEI-дің дизайны таңдаудың артындағы тәртібі деректерді басып шығаруға және істеу мүмкіндігін көмектеседі, сондай-ақ институциялық не саяси дискурстарды өзгерту үшін зерттеу деректерді анализ техникалары Біз оның қолданбаларын дискуссияларға көрсету керек заң шығару процесінің контексті болды. Бұл күшті оппозициялық құрылды.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>TAPS korpus leidžia dalytis dideliu kiekiu Prancūzijos parlamentinių duomenų. Atsižvelgiant į TEI reikalavimus atitinkantį požiūrį, kuris grindžiamas jos projektavimo pasirinkimais, palengvinamas duomenų skelbimas ir sąveika, taip pat tiriamųjų duomenų analizės metodų įgyvendinimas siekiant tvarkyti institucinę ar politinę diskursą. Mes parodome, kad ji taikoma diskusijoms, įvyko vykstant konkrečiam teisėkūros procesui, kuris sukėltvirtą prieštaravimą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_el>Το σώμα του επιτρέπει την κοινή χρήση μεγάλου όγκου γαλλικών κοινοβουλευτικών δεδομένων. Η σύμφωνη προς το ΤΕΙ προσέγγιση πίσω από τις επιλογές σχεδιασμού διευκολύνει τη δημοσίευση και τη διαλειτουργικότητα των δεδομένων, αλλά και την εφαρμογή ερευνητικών τεχνικών ανάλυσης δεδομένων προκειμένου να επεξεργαστεί θεσμικό ή πολιτικό διάλογο. Αποδεικνύουμε ότι η εφαρμογή της στις συζητήσεις πραγματοποιήθηκε στο πλαίσιο μιας συγκεκριμένης νομοθετικής διαδικασίας, η οποία προκάλεσε έντονη αντίθεση.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Il corpus TAPS consente di condividere un grande volume di dati parlamentari francesi. L'approccio TEI-compliant alla base delle sue scelte progettuali facilita la pubblicazione e l'interoperabilità dei dati, ma anche l'implementazione di tecniche di analisi esplorativa dei dati al fine di elaborare discorsi istituzionali o politici. Dimostriamo la sua applicazione ai dibattiti avvenuti nel contesto di uno specifico processo legislativo, che ha generato una forte opposizione.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ml>ടാപ്സ് കോര്‍പ്പുസ് ഫ്രെഞ്ച് സംഘത്തിന്റെ വലിയ വോള്‍ഡ് പങ്കുചേര്‍ക്കാന്‍ സാധിക്കുന്നു. അതിന്റെ ഡിസൈന്‍ തിരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുന്ന തെരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുന്നതിന്റെ പിന്നിലുള്ള ടെയിഐ-പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട പ്രസിദ്ധത്തിനും വിവരങ്ങളുടെ ഇടപെട ഒരു പ്രത്യേക നിയമപ്രക്രിയയുടെ പ്രക്രിയയില്‍ സംഭവിച്ച വിവാദങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് അതിന്‍റെ പ്രയോഗത്തെ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചു തര്‍ക്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mk>Корпусот на ТАПС овозможува да се сподели голем број француски парламентарни податоци. The TEI-compliant approach behind its design choices facilitates the publishing and the interoperability of data, but also the implementation of exploratory data analysis techniques in order to process institutional or political discourse.  Ние ја демонстрираме неговата апликација на дебатите се случи во контекст на специфичен легислативен процес, кој создаде силна опозиција.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mt>Il-korpus TAPS jippermetti li jinqasam volum kbir ta’ dejta parlamentari Franċiża. L-approċċ konformi mat-TEI wara l-għażliet tad-disinn tiegħu jiffaċilita l-pubblikazzjoni u l-interoperabbiltà tad-dejta, iżda wkoll l-implimentazzjoni ta’ tekniki esploratorji ta’ analiżi tad-dejta sabiex jiġi pproċessat diskors istituzzjonali jew politiku. We demonstrate its application to the debates occurred in the context of a specific legislative process, which generated a strong opposition.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Korpus TAPS memungkinkan untuk berkongsi volum besar data parlemen Perancis. pendekatan yang sesuai dengan TEI di belakang pilihan rancangannya memudahkan penerbitan dan interoperabiliti data, tetapi juga pelaksanaan teknik analisis data esploratori untuk memproses diskors institusi atau politik. Kami menunjukkan aplikasinya kepada perdebatan berlaku dalam konteks proses undang-undang tertentu, yang menghasilkan lawan yang kuat.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_pl>Korpus TAPS umożliwia udostępnianie dużej ilości danych parlamentarnych francuskich. Podejście zgodne z TEI stojące za jego wyborami projektowymi ułatwia publikowanie i interoperacyjność danych, ale także wdrażanie technik analizy badawczej danych w celu przetwarzania dyskursu instytucjonalnego lub politycznego. Pokazujemy, że jego zastosowanie do debat odbyło się w kontekście konkretnego procesu legislacyjnego, który wywołał silny sprzeciw.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>ТаPS корпус Француз парламентын өгөгдлийг маш их хэмжээний хуваалцах боломжтой болгодог. TEI-ын загварын сонголтын ард байгаа арга зам нь өгөгдлийн хэвлэл болон харилцаа ашиглах боломжтой боломжтой боломжтой боломжтой, мөн институцийн эсвэл улс төрийн яриаг үйлдвэрлэхийн тулд судалгааны өгөгдлийн шинжилгээний тех Бид үүнийг зөрчилдөөнд хэрэглэх нь тодорхой хуулийн үйл явцын тухай харуулсан. Энэ нь хүчтэй эсрэг үүсгэсэн.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sr>TAPS korpus omogućava da podijeli veliki volum francuskih parlamentarnih podataka. Pristup koji odgovara TEI iza svojih izbora dizajna olakšava objavljivanje i interoperabilnost podataka, kao i provedbu tehnika analize istraživačkih podataka kako bi se procesirala institucionalni ili politički diskursi. Pokazali smo njegovu primjenu na rasprave u kontekstu određenog zakonodavnog procesa, koji je izazvao jaku opoziciju.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ro>Corpusul TAPS permite partajarea unui volum mare de date parlamentare franceze. Abordarea conformă TEI din spatele opțiunilor sale de proiectare facilitează publicarea și interoperabilitatea datelor, dar și implementarea tehnicilor de analiză a datelor exploratorii în vederea procesării discursului instituțional sau politic. Demonstrăm aplicarea sa la dezbaterile avute loc în contextul unui proces legislativ specific, care a generat o opoziție puternică.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_no>TAPS corpus gjer det mogleg å dele ein stor volum av fransk parlamentære data. Tilnærminga med TEI-tilnærming bak utformingsvala tilgjengeleg publisering og samoperabilitet av data, men også implementeringa av utforskingsskrivelsesteknikkar for å handtera institusjonelle eller politiske diskursar. Vi viser programmet til debattane i konteksten av ein spesifikke lovgivning, som laga ein sterk motsetjing.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_si>TAPS කොර්පස් එක ප්‍රශ්නය කරනවා ෆ්‍රෑන්ස් පාලමිනේටර් දත්තේ ලොකු විශාල දත්ත කොටස් කරන්න. TEI-සම්බන්ධ විශ්ලේෂණ විශ්ලේෂණ විකල්පයක් පස්සේ ප්‍රකාශනය සහ දත්ත සම්බන්ධ විකල්පයක් පරීක්ෂණය කරනවා, ඒත් පරීක්ෂණ විශ අපි ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරනවා එයාගේ වැඩසටහන් විශේෂ නීතික ප්‍රක්‍රියාවක් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සිද්ධ වුනා, ඒකෙන් ශක්</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Qasabka TAPS waxaa suurtogal ah in aad qeyb ka dhigto macluumaad badan oo baarlamaanka Faraansiis ah. Dhaqdhaqaaqa ku waajibka ah ee TEI ka dib doorashada qorshaha waxaa ka caawinaya baaritaanka iyo faa’iidada macluumaadka, laakiin waxaa sidoo kale lagu sameeyaa teknikada baaritaanka data si ay u baaraandegaan hadalka asalka ama siyaasada. Waxaannu muujinnaa codsigiisa debaanku ay ku dhaceen xaalada sharciga cayiman, taasoo sababtay difaac xoog leh.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>TAPS-korpusen gör det möjligt att dela en stor mängd franska parlamentariska uppgifter. Det TEI-kompatibla tillvägagångssättet bakom dess designval underlättar publicering och interoperabilitet av data, men också genomförandet av undersökande dataanalystekniker för att bearbeta institutionell eller politisk diskurs. Vi visar att den tillämpades på de debatter som ägde rum inom ramen för en särskild lagstiftningsprocess, vilket gav upphov till ett starkt motstånd.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>TAPS குறிப்புகள் அது பிரஞ்சு தொகுதியின் பெரிய ஒலியளவை பகிர்ந்து கொள்ள முடியும். வடிவமைப்பு தேர்வுகளுக்கு பின்னால் TEI பொருத்தமான செயல்பாடு நிறுவனம் அல்லது அரசியல் பேச்சினை செயல்படுத்துவதற்கு தகவல் வெளியிடும் இடையேற்றம்  நாங்கள் விவாதத்திற்கு அதன் பயன்பாட்டை காட்டுகிறோம் ஒரு குறிப்பிட்ட சட்டத்தில் நடந்தது, அது ஒரு வலிமையான எதிர்ப்ப</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ٹاپیس کورپوس نے فرانسوی پارلمانٹر ڈیٹا کا بڑا آواز شریک کرنے کا امکان رکھا ہے. TEI-compliant approach behind its design choices facilitates the publishing and interoperability of data, but also the implementation of exploratory data analysis techniques to process institutional or political discussions. ہم نے اس کے درخواست کو بحث کے لئے دکھایا ہے ایک مخصوص قوانین پرسس کے بارے میں، جس نے ایک سخت مخالفت پیدا کی۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Name Biz bu debatlarning dasturini ko'rsatdik, bu juda katta qanday rivojlanishni yaratdi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tập đoàn TAPS làm cho việc chia sẻ một lượng lớn dữ liệu của Quốc hội Pháp. Cách tiếp cận theo khả năng thiết kế của nó giúp việc xuất bản và kết hợp các dữ liệu, nhưng cũng hỗ trợ việc sử dụng các kỹ thuật phân tích dữ liệu thăm dò để xử lý các cuộc tranh luận về nội bộ hay chính trị. Chúng tôi đã chứng minh nó áp dụng cho cuộc tranh luận trong một quy trình lập pháp cụ thể, tạo nên sự phản đối mạnh mẽ.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Корпусът дава възможност за споделяне на голям обем френски парламентарни данни. Съответстващият на ТЕИ подход зад избора на дизайн улеснява публикуването и оперативната съвместимост на данните, но също така и прилагането на изследователски техники за анализ на данните с цел обработка на институционалния или политически дискурс. Ние демонстрираме прилагането му към разискванията, проведени в контекста на конкретен законодателен процес, който предизвика силна опозиция.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Het TAPS-corpus maakt het mogelijk om een grote hoeveelheid Franse parlementaire gegevens te delen. De TEI-conforme aanpak achter de ontwerpkeuzes vergemakkelijkt de publicatie en interoperabiliteit van data, maar ook de implementatie van verkennende data-analysetechnieken om institutioneel of politiek discours te verwerken. We tonen aan dat de toepassing ervan op de debatten plaatsvond in het kader van een specifiek wetgevingsproces, dat een sterke oppositie heeft opgeleverd.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>TAPS corpus omogućava podijeliti veliki volum francuskih parlamentarnih podataka. Pristup koji odgovara TEI iza svojih izbora dizajna olakšava objavljivanje i interoperabilnost podataka, kao i provedbu tehnika analize istraživačkih podataka kako bi se obradila institucionalni ili politički diskursi. Pokazali smo njegovu primjenu na rasprave u kontekstu određenog zakonodavnog procesa, koji je izazvao jaku opoziciju.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>TAPS korpus gør det muligt at dele en stor mængde franske parlamentariske data. Den TEI-kompatible tilgang bag designvalgene letter udgivelsen og interoperabiliteten af data, men også implementeringen af eksperimenterende dataanalyseteknikker for at behandle institutionel eller politisk diskurs. Vi demonstrerer dens anvendelse på de debatter, der fandt sted i forbindelse med en bestemt lovgivningsproces, som skabte en stærk modstand.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Das TAPS-Korpus ermöglicht es, eine große Menge französischer parlamentarischer Daten zu teilen. Der TEI-konforme Ansatz hinter seinen Designentscheidungen erleichtert die Veröffentlichung und Interoperabilität von Daten, aber auch die Implementierung explorativer Datenanalysetechniken, um institutionelle oder politische Diskurse zu verarbeiten. Wir zeigen, dass seine Anwendung auf die Debatten im Rahmen eines spezifischen Gesetzgebungsprozesses stattfand, der starke Opposition hervorrief.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Korpus TAPS memungkinkan untuk berbagi volum besar data parlamentar Perancis. pendekatan yang sesuai dengan TEI di balik pilihan desainnya memudahkan penerbitan dan interoperabilitas data, tetapi juga implementasi teknik analisis data esploratori untuk memproses diskors institusi atau politik. Kami menunjukkan aplikasinya pada debat terjadi dalam konteks proses legislatif spesifik, yang menghasilkan oposisi yang kuat.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>TAPS 자료고는 대량의 프랑스 의회 데이터를 공유하는 것을 가능하게 했다.그 디자인 선택 뒤에 있는 TEI 호환 방법은 데이터의 발표와 상호작용성에 도움이 되지만 탐색적인 데이터 분석 기술을 실시하여 기구나 정치적 언어를 처리하는 데도 도움이 된다.우리는 그것이 특정 입법 과정에서 발생한 변론에서 응용되는 것을 보여 주었기 때문에 강렬한 반대를 불러일으켰다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>کورپوس TAPS امکان می‌دهد که یک مقدار زیادی از داده‌های پارلمانتری فرانسه را به اشتراک بگیرد. دستور TEI-compliant پشت انتخاب طراحی‌اش برای پرداخت سخنرانی‌های موسیقی یا سیاسی آسان می‌کند که انتخاب‌های طراحی‌اش را آسان می‌کند، و همچنین عملکرد تکنیک‌های تحلیل داده‌های تحقیق‌کننده برای پرداخت سخنرانی‌های موسیق ما درخواست آن را به بحث ها نشان می دهیم در محیط یک فرآیند قانونی خاصی اتفاق افتاد که یک مخالفت قوی باعث شد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>TAPS korpusy Fransuz parlamentary maglumatlarynyň uly bölümini paýlaşyp biler. TEI-nyň taslama saýlawlarynyň arkasynda ýakynlaşyk çykyş we maglumatlaryň çarpyşylygyny bejermek üçin kömekleýär, ýöne institucional ýa-da syýasy gürrüňleri işlemek üçin keşfedilýän maglumatlaryň analýşim teknikleriniň implementasiýasy. Biz özüniň uygulamasyny debatlara görkezip ýagdaýlaryň belli bir leýletli prosesden bäri bolandygyny görkeýäris we ol güýçli bir garşy döredi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Kampuni ya TAPS inawezesha kushirikisha kura kubwa ya data za bunge la Ufaransa. Matokeo makubaliano ya TEI nyuma ya uchaguzi wake wa ubunifu yanasaidia kuchapisha na usambazaji wa taarifa, lakini pia utekelezaji wa mbinu za uchambuzi wa taarifa ili kuchukua mazungumzo ya taasisi au kisiasa. Tunaonyesha maombi yake kwa mdahalo ulitokea katika muktadha wa mchakato maalum wa sheria, ambao ulisababisha upinzani mkali.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>The TAPS corpus makes it possible to share a large volume of French parliamentary data.  Përqasja në përputhje me TEI pas zgjedhjeve të dizajnit të saj lehtëson botimin dhe interoperabilitetin e të dhënave, por gjithashtu zbatimin e teknikave eksploruese të analizës së të dhënave me qëllim që të procesohet diskursi institucional apo politik. Ne demonstrojmë aplikimin e tij ndaj debateve ndodhi në kontekstin e një procesi legjislativ të posaçëm, i cili gjeneroi një opozitë të fortë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>የTAPS ኮርፓስ የፍረንሳይኛ ፓርላማዊ ዳታ ትልቅ volume ማጋራት ይችላል፡፡ የTEI-አካባቢ ሥርዓት ከዲጅን ምርጫው በኋላ የዳታ አካባቢ እና በሥርዓት ወይም የፖለቲካ ንግግር ለመሥራት የዳታ አዳራሲ አዳራሲ ምክረቶችን ለመጠቀም የሚችል ነው፡፡ በተለያዩ ሕግ ፕሮጀክት ውስጥ ጥያቄውን እናሳየዋለን፣ ብርቱ ተቃውሞ ያሳየው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>ՏԱՊՍ-ի կորպուսը հնարավորություն է տալիս կիսել ֆրանսիական պարլմենտական տվյալներ: TEI-ի համապատասխանատու մոտեցումը իր դիզայնի ընտրությունների ետևում հեշտացնում է տվյալների հրատարակությունը և փոխկապակցվածությունը, ինչպես նաև հետազոտող տվյալների վերլուծության տեխնիկաների կիրառումը ինստիտուցիոնալ կամ քաղաքական քննարկումն Մենք ցույց ենք տալիս, որ դրա կիրառումը քննարկումների դեպքում տեղի ունեցավ որոշակի օրենսդրական գործընթացի կոնտեքստում, որը ստեղծեց ուժեղ հակառակցություն:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>TAPS korpusu Fransız parlamentari məlumatlarının böyük səviyyəsini paylaşdırmağa mümkün edir. TEI-nin dizayn seçimlərinin arxasındakı yaxınlıq məlumatların yayınlamasını və müxtəlif işləri olaraq, həmçin in institucional və siyasi danışmalarını işlədirmək üçün keşif məlumatların analizi tekniklərinin istifadəsini olaraq olar. Biz onun müzakirələrə uyğulanmasını göstərdik ki, bu müzakirələrə möhkəm bir təcavüz yaratdı.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_af>Die TAPS corpus maak dit moontlik om 'n groot volume van Franse parlamentêre data te deel. Die TEI-voldoende toegang agter sy ontwerp-keuses maak die publikasie en die interoperabiliteit van data, maar ook die implementasie van uitvoer-data-analiseerde teknike om institusiele of politieke diskursie te proses. Ons wys sy aansoek aan die debate in die konteks van 'n spesifieke wetgewing proses wat 'n sterk teenstelling genereer het.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_bs>TAPS korpus omogućava da podijeli veliki volum francuskih parlamentarnih podataka. Pristup koji odgovara TEI iza svojih izbora dizajna olakšava objavljivanje i interoperabilnost podataka, kao i provedbu tehnika analize istraživačkih podataka kako bi se procesirala institucionalni ili politički diskursi. Pokazali smo njegovu primjenu na rasprave u kontekstu određenog zakonodavnog procesa, koji je izazvao jaku opoziciju.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_bn>টাপিএস কোর্পাস ফ্রেঞ্চ সংসদীয় তথ্য শেয়ার করতে পারে। তার ডিজাইন নির্বাচনের পেছনে টেআই-প্রতিযোগিতার প্রযুক্তি সুবিধা প্রকাশ এবং তথ্যের কার্যকলাপের সুযোগ প্রদান করে, কিন্তু প্রতিষ্ঠান অথবা রাজন আমরা বিতর্কের প্রতি তার প্রতিক্রিয়া প্রদর্শন করি একটি নির্দিষ্ট আইন প্রক্রিয়ার প্রেক্ষাপটে বিতর্কের প্রতি বিতর্কের প</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Korpus TAPS umožňuje sdílet velký objem francouzských parlamentních dat. Přístup, který splňuje TEI, usnadňuje publikování a interoperabilitu dat, ale také implementaci průzkumných technik analýzy dat za účelem zpracování institucionálního či politického diskurzu. Ukazujeme, že jeho uplatnění v rozpravách proběhlo v kontextu konkrétního legislativního procesu, který vyvolal silnou opozici.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_ca>El corps TAPS permet compartir un gran volum de dades parlamentars franceses. L'enfocament conforme al TEI darrere de les seves eleccions de disseny facilita la publicació i l'interoperabilitat de les dades, però també la implementació de tècniques exploratories d'anàlisi de dades per processar discurs institucional o polític. Demonstrem que la seva aplicació als debats va tenir lloc en el context d'un procés legislatiu específic, que va generar una forta oposició.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>TAPS korpus võimaldab jagada suurt hulka Prantsusmaa parlamentaarseid andmeid. TEI-le vastav lähenemisviis selle disainivalikute taga hõlbustab andmete avaldamist ja koostalitlusvõimet, kuid ka uurivate andmeanalüüsimeetodite rakendamist institutsioonilise või poliitilise diskursi töötlemiseks. Näitame selle rakendamist aruteludele, mis toimusid konkreetse seadusandliku protsessi kontekstis, mis tekitas tugeva vastuseisu.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>TAPS-korpus mahdollistaa suuren määrän Ranskan parlamentin tietoja. Suunnitteluvalintojen taustalla oleva TEI-yhteensopiva lähestymistapa helpottaa tietojen julkaisemista ja yhteentoimivuutta, mutta myös tutkivien tietojen analyysitekniikoiden käyttöönottoa institutionaalisen tai poliittisen keskustelun käsittelemiseksi. Osoitamme sen soveltamisen keskusteluihin, joita käytiin tietyn lainsäädäntöprosessin yhteydessä ja jotka aiheuttivat vahvaa vastustusta.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Gosoko-konoh SUP kuwi wis dipoleh iso ngejaraké diumbane soko data sing mbribèni Perancis. Tenggo-nggunakake sing beraksi sing dibenakake perusahaan mruput kanggo ngilanggar nggambar obah-obah lan akeh operasi dadi, ngusate kiper ngewehke operasi teknik beraksi dadi kanggo nggawe gerakan diolah institusi uwong sing beraksi barêng-barêng politik. Awak dhéwé éntuk aplikasi kanggo debasar iki dadi nêmên ning aturan sing beraksi perusahaan winih sing dikarepaké, sing ujaran ketemukno sing gak bênêr.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Korpus TAPS omogoča izmenjavo velikega obsega francoskih parlamentarnih podatkov. Pristop, skladen s TEI, ki temelji na oblikovalskih izbirah, olajšuje objavljanje in interoperabilnost podatkov, pa tudi izvajanje tehnik raziskovalne analize podatkov za obdelavo institucionalnega ali političnega diskurza. Pokazujemo njeno uporabo v razpravah, ki so potekale v okviru posebnega zakonodajnega postopka, ki je povzročil močno nasprotovanje.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>KCharselect unicode block name Mataimakin TeI da adadi a bayan zaɓen hanyarsa yana da amfani da fassarar data, kuma amma an yi amfani da masu fassara masu fassarar data, da kuma an yi amfani da masu fassarar zance da za'a yi aiki da magana na'asa ko kisa. We demonstrate its application to the debates occurred in the context of a specific legislative process, which generated a strong opposition.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>הקורפוס של TAPS מאפשר לחלוק כמות גדולה של נתונים פרלמנטריים צרפתיים. הגישה המתאימת ל-TEI מאחורי בחירות העיצוב שלה מקדימה את הפרסום והשיתוף הפוליטי של נתונים, אך גם את ההפעלה של טכניקות ניתוח נתונים חקירתיות We demonstrate its application to the debates occurred in the context of a specific legislative process, which generated a strong opposition.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>སྡོང་འབུལ་གྱི་དབང་ཆ་(TAPS)སྔོན་སྒྲིག་དབང་ཆ་གཅིག་སྡུད་ཆེན་པོ་ཞིག་ཏུ་སྤྱད་ཐུབ་པ་ཡིན། The TEI-compliant approach behind its design choices facilitates the publishing and the interoperability of data, but also the implementation of exploratory data analysis techniques in order to process institutional or political discourse. འུ་ཅག་གིས་ཉེར་སྤྱོད་འདི་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་ལ་བྱུང་བའི་སྲིད་གཞུང་དམིགས་ཀྱི་ལས་སྦྱོར་ཅིག་ནང་དུ་བྱུང་བ་རེད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>