<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.law">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 14th Linguistic Annotation Workshop</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Stefanie</first><last>Dipper</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Amir</first><last>Zeldes</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Barcelona, Spain</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9dfacf09">2020.law-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>law-2020-linguistic</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Cookpad Parsed Corpus : Linguistic Annotations of Japanese Recipes<fixed-case>J</fixed-case>apanese Recipes</title>
      <author><first>Jun</first><last>Harashima</last></author>
      <author><first>Makoto</first><last>Hiramatsu</last></author>
      <pages>87–92</pages>
      <abstract>It has become increasingly common for people to share <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recipe">cooking recipes</a> on the Internet. Along with the increase in the number of shared recipes, there have been corresponding increases in recipe-related studies and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a>. However, there are still few <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> that provide linguistic annotations for the recipe-related studies even though such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotations</a> should form the basis of the studies. This paper introduces a novel recipe-related dataset, named Cookpad Parsed Corpus, which contains linguistic annotations for Japanese recipes. We randomly extracted 500 recipes from the largest recipe-related dataset, the Cookpad Recipe Dataset, and annotated 4 ; 738 sentences in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recipe">recipes</a> with morphemes, named entities, and dependency relations. This paper also reports benchmark results on our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> for Japanese morphological analysis, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Named-entity_recognition">named entity recognition</a>, and dependency parsing. We show that there is still room for improvement in the analyses of recipes.</abstract>
      <url hash="e48d0c1d">2020.law-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>harashima-hiramatsu-2020-cookpad</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/microsoft-research-multimodal-aligned-recipe">Microsoft Research Multimodal Aligned Recipe Corpus</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>PASTRIE : A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English<fixed-case>PASTRIE</fixed-case>: A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in <fixed-case>R</fixed-case>eddit International <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish</title>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Kranzlein</last></author>
      <author><first>Emma</first><last>Manning</last></author>
      <author><first>Siyao</first><last>Peng</last></author>
      <author><first>Shira</first><last>Wein</last></author>
      <author><first>Aryaman</first><last>Arora</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathan</first><last>Schneider</last></author>
      <pages>105–116</pages>
      <abstract>We present the Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English (PASTRIE) corpus, a new dataset containing manually annotated preposition supersenses of English data from presumed speakers of four L1s : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language">French</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_language">Spanish</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotations</a> are comprehensive, covering all preposition types and tokens in the sample. Along with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a>, we provide analysis of distributional patterns across the included <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corpus_linguistics">L1s</a> and a discussion of the influence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corpus_linguistics">L1s</a> on L2 preposition choice.</abstract>
      <url hash="0eaf4d40">2020.law-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>kranzlein-etal-2020-pastrie</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/nert-nlp/pastrie" additional="false">nert-nlp/pastrie</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/pastrie">PASTRIE</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>المعكرونة: مجموعة من حروف الجر مشروحة بعلامات Supersense في Reddit International English</title_ar>
      <title_ja>PASTRIE: A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_ja>
      <title_es>PASTRIE: Un corpus de preposiciones anotadas con etiquetas supersense en inglés internacional de Reddit</title_es>
      <title_pt>PASTRIE: Um corpus de preposições anotado com tags Supersense no Reddit International English</title_pt>
      <title_ga>PASTRIE: Corpas Réamhfhocal atá Anótáilte le Supersense Clibeanna i Reddit International English</title_ga>
      <title_zh>PASTRIE:于Reddit国际英语中超感标注介词料库</title_zh>
      <title_hi>PASTRIE: Reddit अंतर्राष्ट्रीय अंग्रेजी में Supersense टैग के साथ एनोटेट Prepositions का एक कॉर्पस</title_hi>
      <title_ka>PASTRIE: Prepositions Corpus Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_ka>
      <title_el>ΠΑΤΡΙΟ: Ένα Σώμα Προθέσεων που σχολιάζεται με Ετικέτες στα Αγγλικά</title_el>
      <title_hu>PASTRIE: A Corpus of Prepositions kommentated with Supersenze Tags in Reddit International Magyar</title_hu>
      <title_it>PASTRIE: Un Corpo di Preposizioni Annotato con Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_it>
      <title_lt>PASTRIE: A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_lt>
      <title_kk>PASTRIE: Редит халықаралық ағылшын тіліндегі Supersense тегтерімен белгіленген Prepositions Corpus</title_kk>
      <title_ms>PASTRIE: A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_ms>
      <title_mk>ПАСТРИЈА: Корпус на препозиции анотиран со суперсенсни ознаки на Reddit International English</title_mk>
      <title_ml>പാസ്റ്രീ: റെഡിറ്റ് ഇന്റര്‍നാഷണല്‍ ഇംഗ്ലീഷിലെ സൂപ്പര്‍സെന്‍സ് ടാഗുകളുമായി പ്രിസിഷനുകളുടെ ഒരു കോര്‍പ</title_ml>
      <title_mt>PASTRIE: Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_mt>
      <title_mn>PASTRIE: Суперsense тегтэйгээр нэрлэгдсэн аль хэдийн нөхцөлд</title_mn>
      <title_ro>PATRIE: Un corp de prepoziții adnotat cu etichete Supersense în Reddit International English</title_ro>
      <title_no>Constellation name (optional)</title_no>
      <title_pl>PASTRIA: Korpus wstępnych pozycji zapisanych tagami Supersense w Reddit International English</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Korpus prepozicija Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>PASTRIE: A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International Ingiriis</title_so>
      <title_sv>PASTRIE: En korps av förpositioner kommenterad med Supersense Taggar i Reddit International English</title_sv>
      <title_ur>پاسٹریس: ریڈیٹ بین المللی انگلیسی میں سوپرسنس ٹاگ کے ساتھ نوٹی ہوئی پرپوسٹ کی کورپوس</title_ur>
      <title_ta>பாஸ்ட்ரியா: செட்டிட் ஆங்கிலம் ஆங்கிலத்தில் மேலான ஒட்டுகளுடன் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட ஒரு முன்னேற்புகளின் கா</title_ta>
      <title_uz>PASTRIE: Reddit International Inglizchada Supersense Tags bilan ajratilgan Prepositions Corpus</title_uz>
      <title_vi>PASA3: một tập thể của những vị trí trước chú ý với thẻ siêu cảm ở Reddit International English</title_vi>
      <title_bg>ПАСТРИЕ: Корпус от предпозиции, анотиран с етикети за супер разум в Редит</title_bg>
      <title_hr>PASTRIE: Korpus predstava Annotirana s znakovima Supersense na Reddit International Engleskom</title_hr>
      <title_nl>PASTRIE: Een korpus van vooroordelen geannoteerd met Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_nl>
      <title_da>PASTRIE: Et korpus af forpositioner kommenteret med Supersense Tags i Reddit International English</title_da>
      <title_de>PASTRIE: Ein Korpus von Präpositionen mit Supersense Tags kommentiert in Reddit International English</title_de>
      <title_id>A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_id>
      <title_ko>PASTRIE: Reddit 국제 영어의 프리미엄 태그가 있는 미디어 라이브러리</title_ko>
      <title_fa>PASTRIE: یک کورپ از پیش‌موقعیت‌ها با برچسب‌های سوپرسنس در انگلیسی بین‌المللی Reddit</title_fa>
      <title_sw>PASTRIE: Makosa ya Mashindano yaliyotangazwa na mabango ya Upasuaji katika Kiingereza cha Reddit International</title_sw>
      <title_af>Constellation name (optional)</title_af>
      <title_am>PASTRIE: የፕሮግራሞች ክሮፓስ እና Supersense Tags ውስጥ Reddit International Ingirical</title_am>
      <title_hy>ՊԱՍՏԻ՝ Ռեդիթ միջազգային անգլերենում գրված նախադիրքների մի կորպուս,</title_hy>
      <title_bn>প্যাস্ট্রিই: রেডিটি ইন্টারন্যাশনাল ইংরেজিতে সুপারেন্স ট্যাগের সাথে সংবাদ প্রদান করা একটি প্রেসিশন অফ</title_bn>
      <title_bs>PASTRIE: Korpus prepozicija Annotirana sa znakovima Supersense na Reddit International Engleskom</title_bs>
      <title_sq>Një korpus parapozitave të anotuar me etiketa Supersensi në Reddit International English</title_sq>
      <title_az>PASTRIE: Reddit uluslararası İngilizce dili ilə Supersense etiketləri ilə Annotated Prepositions Corpus</title_az>
      <title_ca>Un Corpus de Preposicions anotat amb Etiquetes Supersens en Reddit International English</title_ca>
      <title_fi>PASTRIE: A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_fi>
      <title_cs>PASTRIE: Korpus předpokladů anotovaný značkami Supersense v Reddit International English</title_cs>
      <title_et>PASTRIE: Eespositsioonide korpus, mis on märgitud supersense sildidega Reddit International English</title_et>
      <title_tr>Uçmak:</title_tr>
      <title_sk>PASTRIE: Korpus predpozicij z oznakami supersmisla v Reddit International English</title_sk>
      <title_jv>PATOR:</title_jv>
      <title_he>PASTRIE: A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>PASTRIE: A Corpus of Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقدم حروف الجر المشروحة بعلامات Supsersense في مجموعة Reddit الدولية للغة الإنجليزية ("PASTRIE") ، وهي مجموعة بيانات جديدة تحتوي على حروف الجر المشروحة يدويًا من البيانات الإنجليزية من المتحدثين المفترضين لأربعة L1s: الإنجليزية والفرنسية والألمانية والإسبانية. التعليقات التوضيحية شاملة ، وتغطي جميع أنواع حروف الجر والرموز المميزة في العينة. إلى جانب المجموعة ، نقدم تحليلًا لأنماط التوزيع عبر L1s المضمنة ومناقشة تأثير L1s على اختيار حرف الجر L2.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Presentamos el corpus Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags in Reddit International English («PASTRIE»), un nuevo conjunto de datos que contiene suposiciones de preposiciones anotadas manualmente de datos en inglés de presuntos hablantes de cuatro L1: inglés, francés, alemán y español. Las anotaciones son exhaustivas y cubren todos los tipos de preposiciones y símbolos de la muestra. Junto con el corpus, proporcionamos un análisis de los patrones de distribución en las L1 incluidas y una discusión de la influencia de las L1 en la elección de la preposición L2.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Apresentamos o corpus Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English (“PASTRIE”), um novo conjunto de dados contendo supersensos de preposições anotados manualmente de dados em inglês de supostos falantes de quatro L1s: inglês, francês, alemão e espanhol. As anotações são abrangentes, cobrindo todos os tipos de preposição e tokens na amostra. Junto com o corpus, fornecemos uma análise dos padrões de distribuição entre as L1s incluídas e uma discussão sobre a influência das L1s na escolha da preposição da L2.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>Reddit International英語（「PASTRIE」）コーパスのSupsersenseタグで注釈付けされた前置詞は、手動で注釈付けされた前置詞スーパーセンスを含む新しいデータセットです。英語、フランス語、ドイツ語、スペイン語の4つのL 1の推定スピーカーからの英語データを含んでいます。注釈は包括的で、サンプルのすべての前置詞タイプとトークンをカバーします。コーパスとともに、私たちは、含まれるL 1 s全体の分布パターンの分析と、L 2前置詞選択に対するL 1 sの影響の議論を提供します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_ga>Cuirimid na Réamhfhocail Anótáilte le Supsersense Clibeanna i láthair i gcorpas Reddit International English ("PASTRIE"), tacar sonraí nua ina bhfuil forshuíomhanna réamhfhocal anótáilte de láimh de shonraí Béarla ó chainteoirí toimhdithe ceithre L1: Béarla, Fraincis, Gearmáinis agus Spáinnis. Tá na nótaí cuimsitheacha, agus clúdaíonn siad gach cineál réamhfhocal agus comharthaí sa sampla. Mar aon leis an gcorpas, cuirimid anailís ar phatrúin dáileacháin ar fud na L1anna san áireamh agus plé ar thionchar na L1anna ar rogha na réamhfhocal T2.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_zh>臣等于Reddit国际英语("PASTRIE")语料库中呈用Supsersense标注之介词,此一新数集,其包自四L1假用者英语数手动注介词超感:英语,法语,德语、西班牙语。 注甚该,涵盖示例中诸介词表识。 非语料库,供 L1 布式之分,而论 L1 L2 介词之化。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम Reddit International English ("PASTRIE") कॉर्पस में Supsersense Tags के साथ Annotated Prepositions पेश करते हैं, एक नया डेटासेट जिसमें मैन्युअल रूप से एनोटेट किए गए प्रीपोज़िशन सुपरसेंस होते हैं, जिसमें चार L1s के अनुमानित वक्ताओं से अंग्रेजी डेटा का एनोटेट किया गया है: अंग्रेजी, फ्रेंच, जर्मन और स्पेनिश। एनोटेशन व्यापक हैं, जो नमूने में सभी पूर्वसर्ग प्रकार और टोकन को कवर करते हैं। कॉर्पस के साथ- साथ, हम शामिल L1s में वितरण पैटर्न का विश्लेषण और L2 preposition विकल्प पर L1s के प्रभाव की चर्चा प्रदान करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_el>Παρουσιάζουμε τα Προθέσεις σχολιασμένα με ετικέτες Supsersense στο σώμα του ένα νέο σύνολο δεδομένων που περιέχει χειροκίνητα σχολιασμένες υπεραισθήσεις προθέσεων Αγγλικών δεδομένων από υποτιθέμενους ομιλητές τεσσάρων γλωσσών: Αγγλικά, Γαλλικά, Γερμανικά και Ισπανικά. Οι σχολιασμοί είναι περιεκτικές, καλύπτοντας όλους τους τύπους προθέσεων και τα σήματα στο δείγμα. Μαζί με το σώμα, παρέχουμε ανάλυση των διανεμητικών προτύπων σε όλα τα συμπεριλαμβανόμενα και μια συζήτηση της επιρροής των L1 στην επιλογή προθέσεων L2.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ აჩვენებთ პრეპოზიციები, რომლებიც რედიტის ინტერნეციონალური ინგლისური (PASTRIE)) კორპუსში, ახალი მონაცემების კოპუზიცია, რომლებიც პირად ანგლისური მონაცემების სუპერსუზიცია ინგლისური მონაცემების მონაც ამონიტაციები ყველაფერი, ყველაფერი მონიშნულების ტიპები და მონიშნები ჩატვირთში. ჩვენ კორპუსთან ერთად განვითარებთ განსაზღვრებული სტრუქტურების ანალიზაციას, რომელიც შეიყვანეთ L1s და განსაზღვრება L1s-ის განსაზღვრებისთვის.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpusban bemutatjuk az új adatkészletet, amely négy L1s feltételezett beszélőjétől (angol, francia, német és spanyol) származó angol nyelvű adatok manuálisan jegyzetelt szuperérzékeit tartalmazza. A megjegyzések átfogóak, lefedik a mintában szereplő összes előpozíciótípust és tokent. A korpuszon kívül elemzést nyújtunk az L1s eloszlási mintáinak az elemzéséről és beszélgetünk arról, hogy az L1s milyen hatással van az L2 prepozíció választására.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_kk>Біз Редит халықаралық ағылшын тіліндегі Supsersense тегтері (PASTRIE) корпуса арқылы жаңа деректер жиынын көрсетедік. Бұл қолмен ағылшын тілінің препозицияларының суперсенсулері бар: ағылшын, француз, неміс және испан тіліндегі төрт Бұл жазбалар үлгісінде барлық препозициялық түрлерді және белгілерді жазылады. Корпус және бөлім үлгілерін L1 және L1 және L2 препозициясының таңдау үшін L1 және L1 және L1 және L2 және бөлім үлгілерін анализ береміз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_it>Presentiamo i Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags nel corpus Reddit International English ('PASTRIE'), un nuovo dataset contenente i supersensi di preposizione annotati manualmente di dati inglesi provenienti da presunti parlanti di quattro L1: inglese, francese, tedesco e spagnolo. Le annotazioni sono complete, coprendo tutti i tipi di preposizione e token nel campione. Insieme al corpus, forniamo analisi dei modelli distributivi tra le L1 incluse e una discussione sull'influenza delle L1 sulla scelta della preposizione L2.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Mes pristatome Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, naują duomenų rinkinį, kuriame yra rankiniu būdu annotuoti preposition supersenses of English data from presumed speakers of four L1s: English, French, German and Spanish. Pastabos išsamios, apimančios visus mėginio išankstinio įdėjimo tipus ir ženklus. Kartu su korpusu teikiame paskirstymo modelių analizę tarp įtrauktų L1s ir diskusiją apie L1s įtaką L2 pasirengimo pasirinkimui.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Ги претставуваме препозициите Anoted with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') корпус, нов податок кој содржи рачно анотирани препозициски суперсензии на англиски податоци од претпоставени говорници од четири L1: англиски, француски, германски и шпански. Нотациите се комплетни, покривајќи ги сите типови на препозиција и знаци во примерокот. Заедно со корпусот, обезбедуваме анализа на дистрибуционалните шеми низ вклучените Л1 и дискусија за влијанието на Л1 на предпозицискиот избор на Л2.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mt>We present the Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, a new dataset containing manually annotated preposition supersenses of English data from presumed speakers of four L1s: English, French, German, and Spanish.  L-annotazzjonijiet huma komprensivi, li jkopru t-tipi kollha ta’ prepożizzjoni u t-tokens fil-kampjun. Flimkien mal-korpus, nagħtu analiżi ta’ xejriet ta’ distribuzzjoni madwar l-L1s inklużi u diskussjoni dwar l-influwenza tal-L1s fuq l-għa żla ta’ prepożizzjoni tal-L2.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Kami perkenalkan Preposisi yang Dianotasi dengan Tag Supsersense dalam Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, set data baru yang mengandungi supersenses preposition annotasi secara manual bagi data Inggeris dari penutup anggap empat L1s: Inggeris, Perancis, Jerman, dan Sepanyol. Anotasi adalah meliputi, meliputi semua jenis preposisi dan token dalam sampel. Bersama dengan korpus, kami menyediakan analisis corak distribusi di seluruh termasuk L1s dan diskusi tentang pengaruh L1s pada pilihan preposisi L2.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>റെഡിഡിറ്റ് ഇന്ത്രാഷ്ട്രീല്‍ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് ('PASTRIE') കോര്‍പ്പസില്‍ സുപ്രസെന്‍സ് ടാഗുകളുമായി അറിയിക്കപ്പെട്ട പ്രിസ്റ്റേഷനുകള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു. നാല് എംഗ്ലീഷ മാമ്പിളിലുള്ള എല്ലാ തരത്തെയും അടയാളങ്ങളെയും പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായി പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. കോര്‍പ്പുസിന്‍റെ കൂടെയും, L1കളില്‍ ഉള്‍പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്ന വിതരണ മാതൃകങ്ങളുടെ വിശദീകരണവും, L2 പ്രിസ്റ്റോഷന്‍ തെരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുന</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Бид Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') корпус дээрх англи хэлний супер мэдээллийн тухай англи хэлний өгөгдлийн супер мэдээллийг гараараа англи хэлний мэдээллийн супер мэдээллүүдийг тайлбарлаж байна. Дэлхий дээрх бүх хүлээн зөвшөөрөх төрлүүд болон тодорхойлолтууд дүүрэн байдаг. Корпус хоёрын хамт бид L1с-г дамжуулан хуваарилах хэлбэрийн шинжилгээг, L1с-ын нөлөө үзүүлэлтийн тухай ярилцлага өгдөг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Przedstawiamy prepozycje Annotated with Supsersense Tags w korpusie Reddit International English ('PASTRIE'), nowy zestaw danych zawierający ręcznie adnotacyjne superzmysły przyimków danych angielskich od domniemanych użytkowników czterech L1: angielskiego, francuskiego, niemieckiego i hiszpańskiego. Annotacje są kompleksowe, obejmujące wszystkie typy przyimków i tokeny w próbce. Wraz z korpusem przeprowadzamy analizę wzorców rozkładu wśród zawartych L1 oraz omówienie wpływu L1 na wybór przyimków L2.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Prezentăm Prepozițiile adnotate cu etichete supersense în corpul Reddit International English ('PASTRIE'), un nou set de date care conține suprasențuri de prepoziție adnotate manual ale datelor în limba engleză de la presupușii vorbitori ai patru L1s: engleză, franceză, germană și spaniolă. Adnotările sunt cuprinzătoare, acoperind toate tipurile de prepoziție și tokenii din eșantion. Împreună cu corpul, oferim analiza modelelor de distribuție în cadrul L1s incluse și o discuție a influenței L1s asupra alegerii prepoziției L2.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Prepozicije koje su najavljene sa "Supsersense Tags" na "Reddit International English" (PASTRIE") korpusu, novi komplet podataka koji sadrži manuelno annotirane prepoznavanje supersensa engleskih podataka od pretpostavljenih govornika četiri L1s: engleski, francuski, njemački i španjolski. Notacije su sveobuhvatljive, pokrivajući sve vrste prepoznavanja i znakove u uzorku. Zajedno s korpusom pružamo analizu distribucijskih obrazaca širom uključenih L1s i diskusiju o utjecaju L1s na izbor prepoznavanja L2.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අපි ප්‍රතිස්ථානයට ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය කරන්න ප්‍රතිස්ථානයක් ඇතුළත් කරන්නේ සුප්සර්ස් ටැග් වල Rededit International English ('PASTRIE') Corpus, අලුත් දත්ත සම්බන්ධයෙන් ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය කරනවා ඇ ප්‍රවේශනය සම්පූර්ණයි, සියළුම ප්‍රවේශනය සහ ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සංවේශනය. කොර්පුස් එක්ක, අපි L1s වලින් විතරයේ ප්‍රවේශනයේ විශ්ලේෂණය සහ L1s වලින් ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා L2s වලින් ප්‍රවේශනය තෝරණය</abstract_si>
      <abstract_no>Vi presenterer føreposisjonane Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English (« PASTRIE ») corpus, a new dataset containing manually annotated preposition supersenses of English data from presumed speakers of four L1s: English, French, German, and Spanish. Notasjonane er omfattige, og dekkar alle prepositionstypar og teikn i prøvet. I tillegg til korpusen tilbyr vi analyse av distribusjonsmønsterene over dei inkluderte L1s og diskusjon om påvirkninga av L1s på valet L2 for preposition.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_so>We present the Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International Ingiriis ('PASTRIE') corpus, a new dataset containing manually annotated preposition supersenses of English data from four L1s speakers presumed: Ingiriis, French, German, and Spanish. Tusaalada waxaa ku qoran calaamado oo dhan. Sidoo kale baaritaanka kooxda waxaynu sameynaa qaababka kala qaybsan ee ku jira L1s iyo sheekeysi saameyn ku saabsan doorashada hore ee L2.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Vi presenterar Prepositions Annotated with Supersense Tags i Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, en ny datauppsättning som innehåller manuellt kommenterade preposition supersensor av engelska data från förmodade talare av fyra L1s: engelska, franska, tyska och spanska. Noteringarna är omfattande och täcker alla prepositionstyper och tokens i urvalet. Tillsammans med korpusen ger vi analys av fördelningsmönster över de inkluderade L1s och en diskussion om L1s påverkan på L2 prepositionsval.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாங்கள் நான்கு L1கள் எண்ணிக்கப்பட்ட பேச்சாளர்களில் இருந்து ஆங்கிலம், பிரெஞ்சு, ஜெர்மன், மற்றும் ஸ்பானிஷ் பேச்சாளர்களில் இருந்து முன்நிலைப்படுத்தப்பட்ட புதிய தகவல் அமைப் மாதிரியில் உள்ள அனைத்து முன் நிலைமை வகைகளையும் மற்றும் குறிகளையும் மூடும் அறிவிப்புகள் சூழ்நில L1கள் முழுவதும் L1களின் விளிவாக்கத்தையும் L2 முன் தேர்வு தேர்ந்தெடுப்பில் L1களின் விளைவுகளையும் பற்றி ஒரு விளக்கமாக்கு</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم نے رسڈیٹ منطنی انگلیسی (PASTRIE) کورپوس میں Supsersense ٹاگ کے ساتھ مطلع کئے ہیں، ایک نئی ڈاٹ سٹ کے ذریعہ مطلع کئے ہوئے انگلیسی ڈاٹ کے سامنے مطلع کئے گئے ہیں چار L1s: انگلیسی، فرانسوی، جرمانی اور اسپانیایی کے متعلق مطلع کرنے والوں سے۔ نمونہ میں تمام نشانیاں اور نشانیاں پوشیدہ ہیں. کورپوس کے ساتھ، ہم نے L1s کے درمیان تقسیم الگو کی تحلیل دے دی ہے اور L1s کے تاثیر کا تحقیق L2 کے انتخاب پر ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Biz Reddit International Inglizcha (PASTRIE) kompyuterda Supsersensense taglari bilan taʼminlovchi joylarni hozir qilamiz. Engliz, Fransuzcha, Olmoncha va Ispanchadan qoʻlbola tahlil qiladigan yangi maʼlumotlar tarkibini qoʻlbola qiladigan ingliz tilidagi ingliz tilidagi tarkib soʻzlari. Name Kopus bilan biz murakkab tarqatish shakllarini tarjima qilamiz va L1'ning muammolari L2 preposition tanlangan muammolari haqida javob beramiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi giới thiệu những vị trí trước đã được ghi chú với Supsersense Tags ở Reddit International English (PADTE) Corpus, một tập tin mới có chứa chứa các đơn vị quảng cáo được ghi chú bằng tay của người Anh từ những người được cho là người nói của bốn I1: Anh, Pháp, Đức, và Tây Ban Nha. Các chú thích đã được ghi chú đầy đủ, bao gồm tất cả các loại quảng cáo và vật trưng trong mẫu. Cùng với tập thể, chúng tôi cung cấp phân tích các mô hình phân phát trong các trường hợp có liên quan tới L1s và một cuộc thảo luận về ảnh hưởng của L1s lên sự lựa chọn quảng cáo L2.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Представяме предпозициите, анотирани с тагове в корпуса на Нов набор от данни, съдържащ ръчно анотирани предлози на английски данни от предполагаеми говорители на четири лева: английски, френски, немски и испански. Анотациите са изчерпателни, обхващащи всички типове prepозиции и символи в извадката. Наред с корпуса, ние предлагаме анализ на разпределителните модели в включените L1s и дискусия за влиянието на L1s върху избора на предлог L2.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>We presenteren de Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, een nieuwe dataset met handmatig geanotateerde voorzetsels superzintuigen van Engelse gegevens van vermoedelijke sprekers van vier L1's: Engels, Frans, Duits en Spaans. De annotaties zijn uitgebreid en bestrijken alle voorzetsels en tokens in de steekproef. Samen met het corpus bieden we analyse van distributiepatronen over de opgenomen L1's en een discussie over de invloed van L1's op de keuze van L2 voorzetsels.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Wir präsentieren die Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags im Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') Korpus, einen neuen Datensatz, der manuell annotierte Präpositionsübersinne englischer Daten von mutmaßlichen Sprechern von vier L1 enthält: Englisch, Französisch, Deutsch und Spanisch. Die Anmerkungen sind umfassend und decken alle Präpositionentypen und Token im Sample ab. Zusammen mit dem Korpus analysieren wir Verteilungsmuster über die enthaltenen L1 und diskutieren den Einfluss von L1 auf die Wahl der L2 Präpositionen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>Reddit International English(PASTRIE) 어료 라이브러리에 Supsersense로 주석을 표시한 개사를 보여줍니다. 이것은 4개의 L1(영어, 프랑스어, 독일어, 스페인어)에서 사용자의 수동 주석을 가정한 개사가 영어 데이터를 초과한 새로운 데이터 집합입니다.주석은 매우 전면적이어서 견본의 모든 개사 유형과 표기를 포함한다.자료 라이브러리를 제외하고 우리는 포함된 l1의 분포 모델을 분석하고 l1이 이중 언어 개사 선택에 미친 영향을 토론했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_hr>Prikazujemo predstave navedene s znakovima supsersense na Reddit International Engleskom korpusu ('PASTRIE'), novi komplet podataka koji sadrži manuelno annotirane prepoznavanje nadčula engleskih podataka od pretpostavljenih govornika četiri L1s: engleskog, francuskog, njemačkog i španjolskog. Notacije su sveobuhvatljive, pokrivajući sve vrste prepoznavanja i znakove u uzorku. Zajedno s korpusom pružamo analizu distribucijskih obrazaca širom uključenih L1s i raspravu o utjecaju L1s na izbor prepoznavanja L2.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi præsenterer Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags i Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') korpus, et nyt datasæt, der indeholder manuelt anmærkede preposition supersensor af engelske data fra formodede talere af fire L1s: engelsk, fransk, tysk og spansk. Anmærkningerne er omfattende og dækker alle prepositionstyper og tokens i prøven. Sammen med korpusset giver vi analyse af fordelingsmønstre på tværs af de inkluderede L1s og en diskussion af indflydelsen af L1s på L2 preposition valg.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_fa>ما پیش‌موقعیت‌هایی که با برچسب‌های Supsersense در انگلیسی Reddit International (PASTRIE) نشان دادیم، یک مجموعه‌ی داده‌های جدید که در دستاویز آشنایی‌های سوپرسنس‌های داده‌های انگلیسی از گفته‌کننده‌های پنجره‌ای از چهار L1s: انگلیسی، فرانسوی، آلمانی و اسپانیایی است را توضیح‌ها در نمونه‌ها بسیار گسترده‌اند و همه نوع شناسایی و نشانه‌ها را پوشانده می‌شوند. همراه با کورپوس، ما تحلیل الگوهای تقسیم را در جمله L1s و یک بحث درباره تاثیر L1s بر انتخاب توصیف L2 پیشنهاد می کنیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_tr>Biz Reddit Halkara Iňlis dili ('PASTRIE') köpüsi bilen duýdylýan ýerleri bilen tanyşýarys. Täze bir sanat seti iňlis maglumatynyň üstüni elle tanyşýan hasaplanýar. Dönüşenler dahil bölümde, örneklerde hemme prepoznasyon türleri we bellekleri kaplıyorlar. Korpus bilen birlikte, L1s'i dahil eden dağıtım örneklerini analyze edip, L1s'in L2 tanyş seçgisinde etkileşim hakkında çözümleşip duruyoruz.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_id>Kami mempersembahkan Preposisi Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, sebuah set data baru yang mengandung preposition supersenses annotasi secara manual dari data Inggris dari presumed pembicara dari empat L1: Inggris, Perancis, Jerman, dan Spanyol. Anotasinya komprensif, meliputi semua tipe preposisi dan token dalam sampel. Bersama dengan corpus, kami menyediakan analisis pola distribusi di seluruh termasuk L1s dan diskusi tentang pengaruh L1s pada pilihan preposisi L2.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_am>በReddit International (PASTRIE) ካርፓስ የተባለው አዲስ ዳታ ማዕከላዊ የኢንጂል ዳታዎችን በአራቱ L1 በተለዩ ቋንቋዎች ላይ የኢንግሊዝኛ ድረ-አካባቢዎች ላይ የተመሳሳይ የፊደል ድረ ገጾችን አቀረብን፡፡ በምሳሌ ውስጥ የሚኖሩትን እና ምልክቶች የሚሸፍኑት አካባቢዎች ናቸው፡፡ Along with the corpus, we provide analysis of distributional patterns across the included L1s and a discussion of the influence of L1s on L2 preposition choice.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Ne paraqesim parapozicionet e anotuara me Etiketat Supsersense në Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, një grup të ri të dhënash që përmban dorërisht superndjenjat e parapozicioneve të të dhënave angleze nga folësit e supozuar të katër L1: anglisht, francez, gjerman dhe spanjoll. Anotacionet janë komplekse, duke mbuluar të gjitha llojet e paracaktimit dhe shenjat në moshë. Së bashku me korpusin, ne ofrojmë analizë të modeleve shpërndarëse nëpër L1s përfshirë dhe një diskutim mbi ndikimin e L1s në zgjedhjen e paravendosjes L2.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք ներկայացնում ենք Reddit միջազգային անգլերենի ('ՊԱՍՏՌԻ') կորպոսը, մի նոր տվյալների համակարգ, որը պարունակում է անգլերենի 4 L1-ի ենթադրված խոսնակների՝ անգլերենի, ֆրանսերենի, գերմաներենի և իսպաներենի, ձեռքով ենթադրված ենթադրված ենթադրված ենթադրություններ: Նոտացիաները ամբողջական են, որոնք ներառում են նմուշի բոլոր տեսակները և նշանները: Կորպուսի հետ միասին մենք կատարում ենք բաշխման կաղապարների վերլուծություն ներառված L1s-ի միջև և քննարկում L1s-ի ազդեցության մասին L2 նախադրական ընտրության վրա:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Biz Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English corpus, a new data set containing manually annotated preposition supersenses of English data from presumed speakers of four L1s: English, French, German and Spanish. V…ôziyy…ôtl…ôr n√ºmun…ôd…ôki b√ºt√ºn m…ôlumatlar v…ô m√∂c√ºz…ôl…ôri √∂rt√ºl√ºr. Korpus il…ô birlikd…ô, L1s v…ô L2 preposition se√ßiml…ôrind…ô L1s t…ôsirl…ôrinin t…ôsiri bar…ôsind…ô daƒüƒ±tƒ±≈ü √∂rt√ºkl…ôrinin analizi t…ômin edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_sw>Tunawasilisha nafasi zilizotangazwa na mabango ya Kiingereza ya Reddit International ('PASTRIE'), seti mpya yenye taarifa zinazozungumza vifaa vya taarifa za Kiingereza kutoka kwa wazungumzaji wanne wa L1: Kiingereza, Kifaransa, Kijerumani na Kihispania. Tangazo hilo lina jumla, linaloshughulikia aina zote za nafasi na alama za sampuli. Pamoja na makampuni hayo, tunatoa uchambuzi wa mitindo ya usambazaji katika maeneo yote yaliyojumuisha L1 na mjadala wa ushawishi wa L1 kwenye chaguo la awali la L2.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা রেডিডিট ইন্টারন্যাশনাল ইংরেজিতে সুপারসেনসেন্স ট্যাগ নিয়ে প্রেসিডেশনের সাথে উপস্থাপন করেছি। এটি একটি নতুন ডাটাসেট, যার মধ্যে রয়েছে হিসেবে চারটি এল১-এর ভাষাকারীদের এই চিহ্নিত বিষয়টি সম্পূর্ণ, নমুনালের সকল প্রাপ্ত অবস্থান এবং চিহ্ন কাভার করে। কোর্পাসের সাথে আমরা এল১ এর মধ্যে বিতরণের প্রতিনিধির বিশ্লেষণ এবং এল১ এর প্রভাব এল২ প্রাথমিক পছন্দের উপর আলোচনা করি।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_af>Ons stel die voorafposisies aangeteken met Supsersense etikette in Reddit Internasionale Engels ('Pastrie') corpus, 'n nuwe datastel bevat hand aangeteken preposeesie supersenses van Engelske data van voorgestelde sprekkers van vier L1s: Engels, Frans, Duits en Spaanse. Die notasies is omheerlik, oordek alle preposeesie tipes en tekens in die voorbeeld. En saam met die korpus, verskaf ons analiseer van verspreidingspatrone oor die insluitende L1s en 'n diskusie van die influens van L1s op L2-rekening keuse.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_bs>Prepozicije koje su navedene na "Supsersense Tags" na "Reddit International English" (PASTRIE") korpusu predstavljamo, novi komplet podataka koji sadrži manuelno annotirane prepoznavanje supersensa engleskih podataka od pretpostavljenih govornika četiri L1s: engleski, francuski, njemački i španjolski. Notacije su sveobuhvatljive, pokrivajući sve vrste prepoznavanja i znakove u uzorku. Zajedno s korpusom pružamo analizu distribucijskih obrazaca širom uključenih L1-a i diskusiju o utjecaju L1-a na izbor prepoznavanja L2-a.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Presentam les Preposicions anotats amb Etiquetes Supsersens en Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, un nou conjunt de dades que conté supersenses prepositius anotats manualment de dades angleses de presumpts parlants de quatre L1: anglès, francès, alemany i espanyol. Les anotacions són completas, que cobreixen tots els tipus de préposició i fitxes de la mostra. Juntament amb el cos, proporcionem anàlisis de patrons de distribució a través dels L1s inclosos i una discussió sobre l'influència dels L1s en l'elecció de préposició L2.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Představujeme novou datovou sadu obsahující manuálně anotované supersmysly předložek anglických dat od předpokládaných mluvčích čtyř L1: angličtiny, francouzštiny, němčiny a španělštiny. Anotace jsou komplexní a pokrývají všechny typy předložek a tokeny ve vzorku. Spolu s korpusem poskytujeme analýzu distribučních vzorů napříč zahrnutými L1 a diskusi o vlivu L1 na výběr předložek L2.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Tutvustame Reddit International English korpuses ("PASTRIE"), uut andmekogumit, mis sisaldab käsitsi annoteeritud prepositsiooni supermeeli nelja L1-i eeldatavalt kõnelejalt: inglise, prantsuse, saksa ja hispaania keelt. Anotatsioonid on põhjalikud, hõlmavad kõiki proovis olevaid prepositsioonitüüpe ja märke. Koos korpusega analüüsime jaotusmustreid läbi kaasatud L1de ja arutleme L1de mõju L2 prepositsiooni valikule.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Esittelemme Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English (PASTRIE) -korpus, uuden aineiston, joka sisältää manuaalisesti annotoidut preposition superaistit englanninkielisistä tiedoista oletetuista neljän L1:n puhujista: englanti, ranska, saksa ja espanja. Huomautukset ovat kattavia ja kattavat kaikki näytteen prepositiotyypit ja merkit. Korpusen rinnalla analysoimme jakauman kuvioita eri L1:ien välillä ja keskustelemme L1:n vaikutuksesta L2-preposition valintaan.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>We present the preposition Awak dhéwé éntuk luwih akeh akeh, lan akeh onèh dikenakno lan token ning bisa sampler. Dhewe nganggo cara-cara, kita nyimpen akeh edah pancen kanggo nyebuturan L1s lan nganggo perusahaan kanggo nggawe L1s kanggo Kemerdekaan L2.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>We present the Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, a new dataset containing manually annotated preposition supersenses of English data from presumed speakers of four L1s: English, French, German, and Spanish.  Ana samun sunan da ke rufe duk nau'i da alamomi cikin misali. Ga kuma da mabaransa, Munã samar da Ana yi anadi ga misãlai masu cikin shirin L1s da ke haɗa shi da kuma wata jayayya game da muhimmar L1s kan zãɓen gabanin L2.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Predstavljamo predloge z oznakami Supsense v korpusu Reddit International English ("PASTRIE"), nov nabor podatkov, ki vsebuje ročno označene predloge nad angleškimi podatki domnevnih govornikov štirih L1: angleščine, francoščine, nemščine in španščine. Opombe so celovite in zajemajo vse vrste predlogov in žetone v vzorcu. Skupaj s korpusom zagotavljamo analizo distribucijskih vzorcev med vključenimi L1 in razpravo o vplivu L1 na izbiro predlogov L2.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>אנו מציגים את הנתונים הקדמיים שנעטפו עם תוויות סביבה באנגלית רדיט בינלאומית ('PASTRIE'), קופוס, קבוצת נתונים חדשה שמכילה סביבי הנתונים הקדמיים שנעטפו באופן ידני של נתונים אנגליים מארבע דוברים הנאמנים של L1: אנגלית, צרפתית, גרמנית וספרדית. ההערות כוללות, מכסה את כל סוגי ההתחלה והסימנים בדגימה. יחד עם הקורפוס, אנחנו מספקים ניתוח של דפוסים פיצוצים ברחבי L1s כולל ודיון על ההשפעה של L1s על בחירת התערבות L2.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>We present the Prepositions Annotated with Supsersense Tags in Reddit International English ('PASTRIE') corpus, a new data set containing manually annotated preposition supersenses of English data from presumed speakers of four L1s: English, French, German, and Spanish.  གསལ་བཤད་འདི་ལ་ཡོད་མེད་བཟོ་ཚང་མའི་སྣང་ཚུལ་གྲངས་ཡོད་པ་དང་མཚོན་རྟགས་ཡོད། མཁའ་དབུགས་དང་མཉམ་དུ་ང་ཚོའི་དབུགས་གཟུགས་རིས་བཀོད་པའི་དབུགས་ཀྱི་དཔྱད་ཞིབ་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། L1s་གཟུགས་བརྗོད་ཐོག་གདམ་ཀྱི་ག</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Querent Intent in Multi-Sentence Questions</title>
      <author><first>Laurie</first><last>Burchell</last></author>
      <author><first>Jie</first><last>Chi</last></author>
      <author><first>Tom</first><last>Hosking</last></author>
      <author><first>Nina</first><last>Markl</last></author>
      <author><first>Bonnie</first><last>Webber</last></author>
      <pages>138–147</pages>
      <abstract>Multi-sentence questions (MSQs) are sequences of questions connected by relations which, unlike sequences of standalone questions, need to be answered as a unit. Following Rhetorical Structure Theory (RST), we recognise that different question discourse relations between the subparts of MSQs reflect different speaker intents, and consequently elicit different answering strategies. Correctly identifying these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_relation">relations</a> is therefore a crucial step in automatically answering MSQs. We identify five different types of MSQs in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, and define five novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_relation">relations</a> to describe them. We extract over 162,000 MSQs from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stack_Exchange">Stack Exchange</a> to enable future research. Finally, we implement a high-precision baseline classifier based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">surface features</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="28023456">2020.law-1.13</url>
      <bibkey>burchell-etal-2020-querent</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/laurieburchell/multi-sentence-questions" additional="false">laurieburchell/multi-sentence-questions</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Annotating Coherence Relations for Studying Topic Transitions in Social Talk</title>
      <author><first>Alex</first><last>Luu</last></author>
      <author><first>Sophia A.</first><last>Malamud</last></author>
      <pages>174–179</pages>
      <abstract>This study develops the strand of research on topic transitions in social talk which aims to gain a better understanding of interlocutors’ conversational goals. Lu and Malamud (2020) proposed that one way to identify such transitions is to annotate coherence relations, and then to identify utterances potentially expressing new topics as those that fail to participate in these relations. This work validates and refines their suggested annotation methodology, focusing on annotating most prominent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coherence_(linguistics)">coherence relations</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Face-to-face_interaction">face-to-face social dialogue</a>. The result is a publicly accessible gold standard corpus with efficient and reliable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation</a>, whose broad coverage provides a foundation for future steps of identifying and classifying new topic utterances.</abstract>
      <url hash="1576a7ca">2020.law-1.17</url>
      <bibkey>luu-malamud-2020-annotating</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>