<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.cogalex">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Workshop on the Cognitive Aspects of the Lexicon</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Michael</first><last>Zock</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Emmanuele</first><last>Chersoni</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alessandro</first><last>Lenci</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Enrico</first><last>Santus</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="54df1291">2020.cogalex-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>cogalex-2020-cognitive</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Individual corpora predict fast memory retrieval during reading</title>
      <author><first>Markus J.</first><last>Hofmann</last></author>
      <author><first>Lara</first><last>Müller</last></author>
      <author><first>Andre</first><last>Rölke</last></author>
      <author><first>Ralph</first><last>Radach</last></author>
      <author><first>Chris</first><last>Biemann</last></author>
      <pages>1–11</pages>
      <abstract>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a>, from which a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Predictive_modelling">predictive language model</a> is trained, can be considered the experience of a semantic system. We recorded everyday reading of two participants for two months on a tablet, generating individual corpus samples of 300/500 K tokens. Then we trained word2vec models from individual corpora and a 70 million-sentence newspaper corpus to obtain individual and norm-based long-term memory structure. To test whether individual corpora can make better predictions for a cognitive task of long-term memory retrieval, we generated stimulus materials consisting of 134 sentences with uncorrelated individual and norm-based word probabilities. For the subsequent eye tracking study 1-2 months later, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_analysis">regression analyses</a> revealed that individual, but not norm-corpus-based word probabilities can account for first-fixation duration and first-pass gaze duration. Word length additionally affected gaze duration and total viewing duration. The results suggest that corpora representative for an individual’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long-term_memory">long-term memory structure</a> can better explain reading performance than a norm corpus, and that recently acquired information is lexically accessed rapidly.</abstract>
      <url hash="fc19dd91">2020.cogalex-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>hofmann-etal-2020-individual</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Less is Better : A cognitively inspired unsupervised model for language segmentation</title>
      <author><first>Jinbiao</first><last>Yang</last></author>
      <author><first>Stefan L.</first><last>Frank</last></author>
      <author><first>Antal</first><last>van den Bosch</last></author>
      <pages>33–45</pages>
      <abstract>Language users process utterances by segmenting them into many cognitive units, which vary in their sizes and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">linguistic levels</a>. Although we can do such unitization / segmentation easily, its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognition">cognitive mechanism</a> is still not clear. This paper proposes an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unsupervised_learning">unsupervised model</a>, Less-is-Better (LiB), to simulate the human cognitive process with respect to language unitization / segmentation. LiB follows the principle of least effort and aims to build a lexicon which minimizes the number of unit tokens (alleviating the effort of analysis) and number of unit types (alleviating the effort of storage) at the same time on any given corpus. LiB’s workflow is inspired by empirical cognitive phenomena. The design makes the mechanism of LiB cognitively plausible and the computational requirement light-weight. The lexicon generated by LiB performs the best among different types of lexicons (e.g. ground-truth words) both from an information-theoretical view and a cognitive view, which suggests that the LiB lexicon may be a plausible proxy of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mental_lexicon">mental lexicon</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="57dc6bea">2020.cogalex-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>yang-etal-2020-less</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/ray306/lib" additional="false">ray306/lib</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>The CogALex Shared Task on Monolingual and Multilingual Identification of Semantic Relations<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>og<fixed-case>AL</fixed-case>ex Shared Task on Monolingual and Multilingual Identification of Semantic Relations</title>
      <author><first>Rong</first><last>Xiang</last></author>
      <author><first>Emmanuele</first><last>Chersoni</last></author>
      <author><first>Luca</first><last>Iacoponi</last></author>
      <author><first>Enrico</first><last>Santus</last></author>
      <pages>46–53</pages>
      <abstract>The shared task of the CogALex-VI workshop focuses on the monolingual and multilingual identification of semantic relations. We provided training and validation data for the following languages : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_language">German</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_language">Chinese</a>. Given a word pair, systems had to be trained to identify which relation holds between them, with possible choices being <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synonym">synonymy</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opposite_(semantics)">antonymy</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyponymy_and_hypernymy">hypernymy</a> and no relation at all. Two test sets were released for evaluating the participating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a>. One containing pairs for each of the training languages (systems were evaluated in a monolingual fashion) and the other proposing a surprise language to test the crosslingual transfer capabilities of the systems. Among the submitted systems, top performance was achieved by a transformer-based model in both the monolingual and in the multilingual setting, for all the tested languages, proving the potentials of this recently-introduced neural architecture. The shared task description and the results are available at https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract>
      <url hash="179b23b8">2020.cogalex-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>xiang-etal-2020-cogalex</bibkey>
    <title_ar>مهمة CogALex المشتركة حول تحديد العلاقات الدلالية بلغة واحدة ومتعددة اللغات</title_ar>
      <title_pt>A Tarefa Compartilhada CogALex sobre Identificação Monolíngue e Multilíngue de Relações Semânticas</title_pt>
      <title_es>La tarea compartida de CogaLex sobre la identificación monolingüe y multilingüe de las relaciones semánticas</title_es>
      <title_ja>セマンティックリレーションの単一言語および多言語識別に関するCogALex共有タスク</title_ja>
      <title_hi>CogALex शब्दार्थ संबंधों की मोनोलिंगुअल और बहुभाषी पहचान पर साझा कार्य</title_hi>
      <title_zh>CogALex语义之单语,与多言之共同任务</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Tasc Comhroinnte CogALex ar Shainaithint Aonteangach agus Ilteangach ar Chaidreamh Séimeantach</title_ga>
      <title_ka>CogALex shared task on Monolingual and Multilingual Identification of Semantic Relations</title_ka>
      <title_el>Η Κοινή Εργασία για τον Μονογλωσσικό και Πολυγλωσσικό προσδιορισμό Σημαντικών Σχέσεων</title_el>
      <title_hu>A CogALex megosztott feladata a szemantikus kapcsolatok egynyelvű és többnyelvű azonosításáról</title_hu>
      <title_it>Il compito condiviso CogALex sull'identificazione monolingue e multilingue delle relazioni semantiche</title_it>
      <title_lt>CogALex bendra užduotis, susijusi su monokalbiniu ir daugiakalbiniu Semantinių santykių identifikavimu</title_lt>
      <title_kk>CogALex ортақ тапсырмасы бір тілді және бірнеше тілді қатынастарды анықтау</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Tugas Berkongsi CogALex mengenai Pengenalan Monolingual dan Berberbilang Bahasa Hubungan Semantik</title_ms>
      <title_mk>Соделена задача на CogALex за монолингуална и мултијазична идентификација на семантичките односи</title_mk>
      <title_ml>സെമാന്റിക് ബന്ധങ്ങളുടെ കോഗാലെക്സ് മോണോളില്‍ഭാഷ, പല ഭാഷയുടെയും തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നതില്‍ പങ്കെടുത്ത പണി</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Il-Kompitu Konġunt tal-CogALex dwar l-Identifikazzjoni Monolingwali u Multilingwi tar-Relazzjonijiet Semantiċi</title_mt>
      <title_no>CogALex-delt oppgåve på monolingsk og fleirspråk identifisering av semiantiske relasjonar</title_no>
      <title_ro>Sarcina comună CogALex privind identificarea monolingvă și multilingvă a relațiilor semantice</title_ro>
      <title_mn>CogALex Хувь хэлний, олон хэлний харилцааны танихын тулд</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Wspólne zadanie CogALex dotyczące jednojęzycznej i wielojęzycznej identyfikacji relacji semantycznych</title_pl>
      <title_si>The CogALex shared Job on Monolingual and Multilanguage ID of semantic ties</title_si>
      <title_so>Shaqada loo sharciyey CogALex oo ku saabsan aqoonsiga afka Monolingual iyo luqadaha kala duduwan ee xiriirka galmada</title_so>
      <title_sr>CogALex zajednički zadatak o monolingviskoj i multijezičkoj identifikaciji semantičkih odnosa</title_sr>
      <title_sv>CogALex delade uppgift om enspråkig och flerspråkig identifiering av semantiska relationer</title_sv>
      <title_ta>CogALex பகிர்ந்த பணி</title_ta>
      <title_ur>The CogALex Shared Task on Monolingual and Multilingual Identification of Semantic Relations</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Công việc chia sẻ CogALex về Mật ngôn ngữ và đa ngôn ngữ</title_vi>
      <title_da>CogALex delte opgave om ensproget og flersproget identifikation af semantiske relationer</title_da>
      <title_nl>De gezamenlijke taak van CogALex inzake eentalige en meertalige identificatie van semantische relaties</title_nl>
      <title_hr>CogALex zajednički zadatak o monojezičkoj i višejezičkoj identifikaciji semantičkih odnosa</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Споделена задача за едноезично и многоезично идентифициране на семантичните отношения</title_bg>
      <title_ko>CogAlex는 단어와 다중 언어의 의미 관계 식별 임무를 공유했다</title_ko>
      <title_de>Die gemeinsame Aufgabe von CogALex zur ein- und mehrsprachigen Identifikation semantischer Beziehungen</title_de>
      <title_fa>وظیفه مشترک CogALex در مورد شناسایی یک زبان و چندین زبان رابطه‌های متوسط</title_fa>
      <title_id>The CogALex Shared Task on Monolingual and Multilingual Identification of Semantic Relations</title_id>
      <title_sw>CogALex ilishiriki kazi katika utambulisho wa lugha za KiMonolinguli na Utambulisho wa Kimataifa</title_sw>
      <title_sq>Detyra e përbashkët e CogALex për identifikimin monolingvist dhe shumëgjuhës të marrëdhënieve Semantike</title_sq>
      <title_tr>CogALex Semantik İlişkilerin Monoli Dili ve Çoklu Dilli Kimlik Görevi</title_tr>
      <title_af>Die CogALex Gedeelde Opdrag op Monolingueel en Veelvuldige Identifikasie van Semantiese Relasies</title_af>
      <title_hy>COgALex-ի կիսված առաջադրանքը սեմանտիկ հարաբերությունների միալեզու և բազլեզու հայտնաբերման մասին</title_hy>
      <title_am>የCogALex ስራ በMonolingual እና Multilingual Identification of Semantic Relations</title_am>
      <title_az>CogALex, Semantik ńįliŇükil…ôrin Monoli Dili v…ô √áoxlu Dili ńįliŇükil…ôrin ńįŇül…ôri</title_az>
      <title_bn>কোগালেক্স সেমান্টিক সম্পর্কের সাথে মোনোলিভাল এবং বহুভাষার পরিচয় নিয়ে কোগালেক্স শেয়ার করা কাজ</title_bn>
      <title_ca>La tasca compartida CogALex sobre la identificació monolingüa i multilingüa de les relacions semàntiques</title_ca>
      <title_bs>CogALex zajednički zadatak o monojezičkoj i multijezičkoj identifikaciji semantičkih odnosa</title_bs>
      <title_et>CogALexi ühine ülesanne semantiliste suhete ühekeelse ja mitmekeelse tuvastamise kohta</title_et>
      <title_cs>Společný úkol CogALex o jednojjazyčné a vícejazyčné identifikaci sémantických vztahů</title_cs>
      <title_fi>CogALexin yhteinen tehtävä semanttisten suhteiden yksiselitteisestä ja monikielisestä tunnistamisesta</title_fi>
      <title_ha>The CogALex Shared Task on Monolingual and Multilingual Identification of Semantic Relations</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Skupna naloga CogALex o enojezičnem in večjezičnem prepoznavanju semantičnih odnosov</title_sk>
      <title_he>המשימה המשותפת של CogALex על זיהוי מונולינגולי ומרבות שפות של יחסים סמנטיים</title_he>
      <title_jv>CogAlex Sambah Taaksi kanggo Monolngual lan Multi-Linguial ID Kemerdekaan Samantar</title_jv>
      <title_bo>CogALex Semantic Relations ཐོག་འབྲེལ་གྱི་རྩིས་ཐོག་དང་སྐད་རིགས་དབྱེ་བའི་བྱ་བ་དེ་</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تركز المهمة المشتركة لورشة عمل CogALex-VI على تحديد العلاقات الدلالية بلغة واحدة ومتعددة اللغات. قدمنا بيانات التدريب والتحقق من الصحة للغات التالية: الإنجليزية والألمانية والصينية. بالنظر إلى زوج من الكلمات ، كان لابد من تدريب الأنظمة على تحديد العلاقة التي تربط بينها ، مع كون الخيارات الممكنة مرادفًا ، وتضادًا ، وتضاربًا ، وعدم وجود علاقة على الإطلاق. تم إصدار مجموعتين من الاختبارات لتقييم الأنظمة المشاركة. يحتوي أحدهما على أزواج لكل لغة من لغات التدريب (تم تقييم الأنظمة بطريقة أحادية اللغة) والآخر يقترح لغة مفاجئة لاختبار قدرات النقل عبر اللغات للأنظمة. من بين الأنظمة المقدمة ، تم تحقيق أعلى أداء من خلال نموذج قائم على المحولات في كل من لغة أحادية اللغة وفي بيئة متعددة اللغات ، لجميع اللغات التي تم اختبارها ، مما يثبت إمكانات هذه البنية العصبية التي تم تقديمها مؤخرًا. يتوفر وصف المهمة المشتركة والنتائج على https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>A tarefa compartilhada do workshop CogALex-VI concentra-se na identificação monolíngue e multilíngue de relações semânticas. Fornecemos dados de treinamento e validação para os seguintes idiomas: inglês, alemão e chinês. Dado um par de palavras, os sistemas tiveram que ser treinados para identificar qual relação se mantém entre eles, com escolhas possíveis sendo sinonímia, antonímia, hipernímia e nenhuma relação. Dois conjuntos de teste foram lançados para avaliar os sistemas participantes. Um contendo pares para cada uma das línguas de treinamento (os sistemas foram avaliados de forma monolíngue) e o outro propondo uma língua surpresa para testar a capacidade de transferência entre os sistemas. Entre os sistemas apresentados, o melhor desempenho foi alcançado por um modelo baseado em transformador tanto no ambiente monolíngue quanto no multilíngue, para todos os idiomas testados, comprovando o potencial dessa arquitetura neural recém-introduzida. A descrição da tarefa compartilhada e os resultados estão disponíveis em https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>La tarea compartida del taller de Cogalex-VI se centra en la identificación monolingüe y multilingüe de las relaciones semánticas. Proporcionamos datos de capacitación y validación para los siguientes idiomas: inglés, alemán y chino. Dado un par de palabras, los sistemas tenían que ser entrenados para identificar qué relación mantenía entre ellos, siendo las posibles opciones sinonimia, antonimia, hipernima y ninguna relación en absoluto. Se publicaron dos conjuntos de pruebas para evaluar los sistemas participantes. Uno contiene pares para cada uno de los idiomas de entrenamiento (los sistemas se evaluaron de manera monolingüe) y el otro propuso un idioma sorpresa para probar las capacidades de transferencia interlingüística de los sistemas. Entre los sistemas presentados, se logró el máximo rendimiento mediante un modelo basado en transformadores tanto en el entorno monolingüe como en el multilingüe, para todos los idiomas probados, lo que demuestra el potencial de esta arquitectura neuronal recientemente introducida. La descripción de la tarea compartida y los resultados están disponibles en https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>CogALex - VIワークショップの共有タスクは、セマンティック関係の単語と多言語の識別に焦点を当てています。 英語、ドイツ語、中国語のトレーニングと検証データを提供しました。 単語ペアを考慮すると、システムは、どちらの関係を保持しているかを識別するようにトレーニングする必要があり、選択肢は同義語、対義語、ハイパーニミーであり、関係はまったくありません。 参加システムを評価するための2つの試験装置がリリースされた。 各トレーニング言語（システムは単一言語で評価された）のペアを含む1つの言語と、システムのクロスリンガル転送能力をテストするためのサプライズ言語を提案するもう1つの言語。 提出されたシステムの中で最高のパフォーマンスを達成したのは、単一言語と多言語の両方での変圧器ベースのモデルであり、テストされたすべての言語について、この最近導入されたニューラルアーキテクチャの可能性を証明しました。 共有タスクの説明と結果は、https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/でご覧いただけます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>CogALex-VI研讨会之共同任务侧重于语义关系单语多言识。 臣等具下语培训验数:英语、德语、中文。 给定一单词者,统必练而识之,或择同义词反义词,hypernymy本无伤也。 发二试集,以质其统。 一包每种训练语言的配对(系统以单语法评估),一个发一种令人惊讶的言语来测试系统的跨语移能。 凡提交之统,变压器形于单语、多言之间,尽测试语言之最善,证近引之神经架构力。 共功在 https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>CogaLex-VI कार्यशाला का साझा कार्य शब्दार्थ संबंधों की मोनोलिंगुअल और बहुभाषी पहचान पर केंद्रित है। हमने निम्नलिखित भाषाओं के लिए प्रशिक्षण और सत्यापन डेटा प्रदान किया: अंग्रेजी, जर्मन और चीनी। एक शब्द जोड़ी को देखते हुए, सिस्टम को यह पहचानने के लिए प्रशिक्षित किया जाना था कि उनके बीच कौन सा संबंध है, संभावित विकल्प पर्यायवाची, विलोम, हाइपरनीमी और कोई संबंध नहीं है। भाग लेने वाली प्रणालियों का मूल्यांकन करने के लिए दो परीक्षण सेट जारी किए गए थे। एक प्रशिक्षण भाषाओं में से प्रत्येक के लिए जोड़े (सिस्टम का मूल्यांकन मोनोलिंगुअल फैशन में किया गया था) और दूसरा सिस्टम की क्रॉसलिंगुअल ट्रांसफर क्षमताओं का परीक्षण करने के लिए एक आश्चर्यजनक भाषा का प्रस्ताव करता है। प्रस्तुत प्रणालियों में, शीर्ष प्रदर्शन मोनोलिंगुअल और बहुभाषी सेटिंग दोनों में एक ट्रांसफॉर्मर-आधारित मॉडल द्वारा प्राप्त किया गया था, सभी परीक्षण की गई भाषाओं के लिए, इस हाल ही में पेश किए गए तंत्रिका वास्तुकला की क्षमताओं को साबित करता है। साझा कार्य विवरण और परिणाम https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/ पर उपलब्ध हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Díríonn tasc comhroinnte na ceardlainne CogALex-VI ar shainaithint aonteangach agus ilteangach an chaidrimh shéimeantaigh. Chuireamar oiliúint agus sonraí bailíochtaithe ar fáil do na teangacha seo a leanas: Béarla, Gearmáinis agus Sínis. Nuair a chuirtear péire focal san áireamh, b’éigean córais a oiliúint chun an gaol atá eatarthu a aithint, agus b’iad na roghanna a d’fhéadfadh a bheith ann ná comhchiall, frithchiall, hipearainmíocht agus gan gaol ar bith. Eisíodh dhá thacar tástála chun na córais rannpháirteacha a mheas. Ceann acu ina raibh péirí do gach ceann de na teangacha oiliúna (measúnaíodh córais ar bhealach aonteangach) agus an ceann eile ag moladh teanga iontasach chun cumas aistrithe trasteangacha na gcóras a thástáil. I measc na gcóras a cuireadh isteach, baineadh an fheidhmíocht is fearr amach trí mhúnla bunaithe ar chlaochladán sa suíomh aonteangach agus ilteangach, do na teangacha go léir a tástáladh, rud a chruthaigh acmhainneacht na hailtireachta néarúla seo a tugadh isteach le déanaí. Tá cur síos ar an tasc roinnte agus na torthaí ar fáil ag https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Το κοινό έργο του εργαστηρίου επικεντρώνεται στην μονογλωσσική και πολύγλωσση ταυτοποίηση σημασιολογικών σχέσεων. Παρέχουμε δεδομένα κατάρτισης και επικύρωσης για τις ακόλουθες γλώσσες: Αγγλικά, Γερμανικά και Κινέζικα. Δεδομένου ενός ζεύγους λέξεων, τα συστήματα έπρεπε να εκπαιδευτούν για να προσδιορίσουν ποια σχέση υπάρχει μεταξύ τους, με πιθανές επιλογές να είναι συνώνυμη, αντωνυμία, υπερνυμία και καμία απολύτως σχέση. Δύο σετ δοκιμών κυκλοφόρησαν για την αξιολόγηση των συμμετεχόντων συστημάτων. Το ένα περιέχει ζεύγη για κάθε μία από τις γλώσσες εκπαίδευσης (τα συστήματα αξιολογήθηκαν μονογλωσσικά) και το άλλο προτείνει μια γλώσσα έκπληξης για να εξετάσει τις δυνατότητες διασυνοριακής μεταφοράς των συστημάτων. Μεταξύ των υποβαλλόμενων συστημάτων, η κορυφαία απόδοση επιτεύχθηκε με ένα μοντέλο βασισμένο σε μετασχηματιστή τόσο στο μονογλωσσικό όσο και στο πολυγλωσσικό περιβάλλον, για όλες τις δοκιμασμένες γλώσσες, αποδεικνύοντας τις δυνατότητες αυτής της πρόσφατα εισαγόμενης νευρωνικής αρχιτεκτονικής. Η κοινή περιγραφή εργασιών και τα αποτελέσματα είναι διαθέσιμα στη διεύθυνση https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A CogALex-VI workshop közös feladata a szemantikai kapcsolatok egynyelvű és többnyelvű azonosítására összpontosít. Képzési és validálási adatokat nyújtottunk a következő nyelvekre: angol, német és kínai. Egy szópár alapján a rendszereket arra kellett képezni, hogy azonosítsák, melyik kapcsolat áll köztük, lehetséges választások szinonimák, antonimia, hipernímia és egyáltalán nincs kapcsolat. Két tesztkészlet került kiadásra a résztvevő rendszerek értékelésére. Az egyik párokat tartalmaz az egyes képzési nyelvekhez (a rendszereket egynyelvű módon értékelték), a másik pedig meglepetési nyelvet javasol a rendszerek nyelvi transzfer képességeinek tesztelésére. A benyújtott rendszerek közül a legjobb teljesítményt egy transzformátor alapú modell érte el mind egynyelvű, mind többnyelvű környezetben, valamennyi tesztelt nyelven, bizonyítva ennek a nemrégiben bevezetett neurális architektúrának lehetőségeit. A megosztott tevékenység leírása és az eredmények a következő oldalon érhetők el: https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>CogALex-VI სამუშაო სამუშაო დავამყოფილი დავალება მონოლენგური და მრავალენგური განსაზღვრებაზე. ჩვენ განვითარებით მონაცემები და გადაწყვეტილების მონაცემები, ანგლისური, გერმანური და ჩინეთი. სიტყვების ორიდან, სისტემები უნდა იყოს განაცნობა, რომელიც შესაძლებელი გამოყენება შორის, ანტონიმია, ჰიპერნიმია და არაფერი შესახებ. ორი ტესტის კონფიგურაცია გადასრულებული სისტემის განსაზღვრებისთვის. ერთი, რომელიც ყველა საკუთარი საკუთარი ენაზე (სისტემები მონოლენგური ფორმაში გაუმუშავებულია) და მეორე, რომელიც საკუთარი ენაზე გაუმუშავებს სისტემების კრისილენგური გადატანსტრე ჩემუშავებული სისტემების შორის უფრო მეტი კონფიგურაცია მოდელეში მონოლენგური და მრავალენგური კონფიგურაციაში, ყველა შემოწმებული ენებისთვის, რომლებიც ახლა შეიცვალოთ ამ ახლა შეიცვალობ გაყოფილი დავალების გამოსახულება და შედეგი შესაძლებელია https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_lt>Bendra CogALex-VI seminaro užduotis sutelkiama į semantinių santykių vienkalbį ir daugiakalbį nustatymą. Pateikėme mokymo ir patvirtinimo duomenis šioms kalboms: anglų, vokiečių ir kinų. Atsižvelgiant į žodžių porą, reikėjo parengti sistemas, kad būtų galima nustatyti, koks ryšys tarp jų yra, o galimi pasirinkimai yra sinonimija, antonimija, hipernimija ir jokių ryšių. Dalyvaujančioms sistemoms įvertinti išleisti du bandymų rinkiniai. Viena, kurioje yra poros kiekvienai mokymo kalbai (sistemos buvo vertinamos vienkalbiškai), kita, kuria siūloma nustebinta kalba, kad būtų išbandyti sistemų tarpkalbiniai perdavimo gebėjimai. Iš pateiktų sistemų didžiausias veiksmingumas buvo pasiektas naudojant transformatoriumi grindžiamą model į tiek vienakalbėje, tiek daugiakalbėje aplinkoje visoms išbandytoms kalboms, įrodantį šios neseniai įdiegtos neurologinės architektūros potencialą. The shared task description and the results are available at  https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>Il compito condiviso del workshop CogALex-VI si concentra sull'identificazione monolingue e multilingue delle relazioni semantiche. Abbiamo fornito dati di formazione e convalida per le seguenti lingue: inglese, tedesco e cinese. Data una coppia di parole, i sistemi dovevano essere addestrati per identificare quale relazione abbia tra di loro, con possibili scelte come sinonimia, antonimia, ipernimia e nessuna relazione. Sono stati rilasciati due set di test per valutare i sistemi partecipanti. Una contiene coppie per ciascuna delle lingue di formazione (i sistemi sono stati valutati in modo monolingue) e l'altra propone una lingua a sorpresa per testare le capacità di trasferimento translinguale dei sistemi. Tra i sistemi presentati, le massime prestazioni sono state raggiunte da un modello basato su trasformatori sia in ambito monolingue che multilingue, per tutte le lingue testate, dimostrando le potenzialità di questa architettura neurale recentemente introdotta. La descrizione dell'attività condivisa e i risultati sono disponibili all'indirizzo https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>The shared task of the CogALex-VI workshop focuses on the monolingual and multilingual identification of semantic relations.  We provided training and validation data for the following languages: English, German and Chinese.  Со оглед на зборот пар, системите мораа да бидат обучени да идентификуваат која врска има меѓу нив, со можни избори да бидат синонимија, анонимија, хипернимија и воопшто без врска. Два тестови беа објавени за проценка на учествувачките системи. Еден кој содржи парови за секој од јазиците за обука (системите беа проценети на монојазичен начин) и другиот кој предлага изненадувачки јазик за тестирање на прекујазичните трансферентни способности на системите. Меѓу поднесените системи, највисоката резултат беше постигната со модел базиран на трансформатор во монојазичното и мултијазичното место, за сите тестирани јазици, докажувајќи ги потенцијалите на оваа неодамна воведена нервна архитектура. Описот на заедничката задача и резултатите се достапни на https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>CogALex-VI жұмысының ортақ тапсырмасы semantic қатынасын бірнеше тілді және бірнеше тілді идентификациясына назар береді. Біз келесі тілдер үшін оқу және тексеру деректерін келтірдік: ағылшын, неміс және қытайша. Сөздің екі сөзде, жүйелер арасындағы қай қатынас бар екенін анықтау үшін оқыту керек, мүмкін таңдаулар синоними, антоними, гиперними және қатынасыз болуы мүмкін. Қатысушылық жүйелерді бағалау үшін екі сынақтар жинақталды. Біріншісі бір тілдерге (жүйелер бірнеше тілдерге тең етілген) жүйелердің бірнеше тілдеріне аудару мүмкіндігін тексеру үшін қызықтық тілді қолданады. Келтірілген жүйелердің ортасында жоғарғы әрекеттері монолингі және көптілік параметрлерінде түрлендіруші үлгісі барлық сыналған тілдер үшін, соңғы келтірілген невралдық архитектурасының мүмкіндіктерін көрсетеді. Ортақ тапсырманың сипаттамасы мен нәтижелері бар https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Tugas berkongsi workshop CogALex-VI fokus pada pengenalan satu bahasa dan berbilang bahasa hubungan semantik. Kami menyediakan data latihan dan pengesahihan untuk bahasa berikut: Bahasa Inggeris, Jerman dan Cina. Berikan pasangan kata, sistem perlu dilatih untuk mengenalpasti hubungan mana yang ada di antara mereka, dengan pilihan yang mungkin adalah sinonimi, antonimi, hipernimi dan tiada hubungan sama sekali. Dua set ujian dibebaskan untuk mengevaluasi sistem yang berpartisipasi. Satu mengandungi pasangan untuk setiap bahasa latihan (sistem diteliti dalam cara monobahasa) dan yang lain melaporkan bahasa kejutan untuk menguji kemampuan pemindahan salib bahasa sistem. Di antara sistem yang dihantar, prestasi terbaik dicapai oleh model berdasarkan pengubah dalam seting monobahasa dan berbilang bahasa, untuk semua bahasa yang diuji, membuktikan potensi arkitektur saraf yang baru-baru ini diperkenalkan. Huraian tugas berkongsi dan keputusan tersedia di https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mn>CogALex-VI хийх мэргэжлийн хуваалцааны ажил нь semantic relations-ын ганц хэл болон олон хэл хэлний тодорхойлолтыг анхаарна. Бид дараагийн хэл дээр суралцах, үнэлгээ өгүүлсэн: Англи, Герман, Хятад. Хоёр үг хэлэхэд, систем нь тэдний хоорондын хамааралтай холбоотой хамааралтай байдгийг мэдэхэд сургалтын тулд, боломжгүй сонголтууд нь синоним, антоним, гиперним, харилцаа байхгүй. Хоёр шалгалт нь оролцогчдын системийг үнэлэхэд гаргасан. Сургуулийн хэл бүрт хоёр байдаг (систем нь нэг хэл хэлбэртэй дүрслэгдсэн) бас нэг хэл нь системийн давхар хэл шилжүүлэх чадварыг шалгахад гайхалтай хэл болгож байна. Олон хэлний болон олон хэлний суурьдаа шилжүүлэгч загвар дээрх үйл ажиллагааны тухай шалгалтын бүх хэлний хувьд шилжүүлэгч загвар нь олон хэлний суурьдаа гарч ирсэн. Холбоотой ажлын тодорхойлолт болон үр дүн нь https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ml>കോഗാലെക്സ്-VI വര്‍ക്ക്‌ഷോപ്പിന്‍റെ പങ്കാളിയുള്ള ജോലിയാണ് സെമാന്റിക് ബന്ധങ്ങളുടെ സംബന്ധിച്ചുള്ള മോണോളില്‍ഭാ നമ്മള്‍ തിരഞ്ഞെടുക്കുന്ന ഭാഷകള്‍ക്ക് പരിശീലനവും പരിശീലനവും വിവരങ്ങളും നല്‍കി: ഇംഗ്ലീഷ്, ജര്‍മ്മന്‍  ഒരു വാക്ക് രണ്ട് ജോട്ടുകാര്‍ കൊണ്ട്, അവയ്ക്കിടയിലുള്ള ബന്ധം തിരിച്ചറിയാന്‍ സിസ്റ്റത്തില്‍ പഠിപ്പിക്കേണ്ടി വന്നിരുന്നു. സാധ്യ പങ്കുചേര്‍ക്കുന്ന സിസ്റ്റം വിലാസപ്പെടുത്താന്‍ രണ്ട് ടെസ്റ്റ് സെറ്റുകള്‍ വിട്ടുപ ഓരോ ട്രെയിനിങ്ങളുടെയും ഭാഷകള്‍ക്കും ജോടികളുണ്ട് (സിസ്റ്റമുകള്‍ മോണോളില്‍ ഭാഷകളില്‍ പരിശോധിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരുന്നു) മറ്റൊരു അത്ഭുതഭാഷ പരിശോധ സമര്‍പ്പിക്കപ്പെട്ട സിസ്റ്റത്തില്‍ മുകളില്‍ പ്രകടനം മാറ്റുന്നത് മോണോളില്‍ ഭാഷകളിലും പല ഭാഷകളിലുമുള്ള മാതൃകയാണ്. പരീക്ഷിക്കപ്പെട്ട എല്ലാ ഭാഷകള്‍ക്കും ഈ അടു പങ്കാളിയുള്ള ജോലിയുടെ വിവരണങ്ങളും ഫലങ്ങളും ലഭ്യമാകുന്നു https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Den delte oppgåva av arbeidsområdet CogALex-VI fokuserer på monospråk og fleirspråk identifisering av semantiske forhold. Vi oppgav opplæring og validating for dei følgjande språka: engelsk, tysk og kinesisk. Gjennomsiktig eit ordpar må systemet verta trent til å identifisera kva forholdet er mellom dei, med moglege val som er synonym, antonym, hypernimum og ingen forhold. To testsett vart sletta for å evaluera deltakende systema. Ein som inneheld par for kvar av øvingsspråk (systemet er evaluert i ein monospråk) og den andre foreslår eit overraska språk for å test a dei krysspråkskapasitetene for systemet. Mellom dei sendte systema vart det oppnådd ein transformeringsbasert modell i både monospråk og i fleirspråk innstillingane, for alle teste språka, som viser potensialene for denne nyleg innførte neuralarkitekturen. Delt oppgåvebeskriving og resultatet er tilgjengeleg på https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_mt>Il-kompitu komuni tal-workshop CogALex-VI jiffoka fuq l-identifikazzjoni monolingwi u multilingwi tar-relazzjonijiet semantiċi. Aħna pprovdejna dejta ta’ taħriġ u validazzjoni għall-lingwi li ġejjin: Ingliż, Ġermaniż u Ċiniż. Minħabba pari ta’ kliem, is-sistemi kellhom jitħarrġu biex jidentifikaw liema relazzjoni tinsab bejniethom, bl-għa żliet possibbli kienu sinonimja, antonimja, ipernimija u l-ebda relazzjoni. Ġew rilaxxati żewġ settijiet ta’ testijiet għall-evalwazzjoni tas-sistemi parteċipanti. Wieħed li fih pari għal kull waħda mil-lingwi ta’ taħriġ (is-sistemi ġew evalwati b’mod monolingwi) u l-ieħor li jipproponi lingwa sorpriża biex jittestjaw il-kapaċitajiet ta’ trasferiment translingwi tas-sistemi. Among the submitted systems, top performance was achieved by a transformer-based model in both the monolingual and in the multilingual setting, for all the tested languages, proving the potentials of this recently-introduced neural architecture.  Id-deskrizzjoni kondiviża tal-kompitu u r-riżultati huma disponibbli fuq https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Wspólne zadanie warsztatów CogALex-VI skupia się na jednojęzycznej i wielojęzycznej identyfikacji relacji semantycznych. Dostarczyliśmy dane szkoleniowe i walidacyjne dla następujących języków: angielskiego, niemieckiego i chińskiego. Biorąc pod uwagę parę słów, systemy musiały być przeszkolone, aby zidentyfikować, która relacja istnieje między nimi, a możliwymi wyborami była synonim, antonimia, hipernimia i żadna relacja. Wydano dwa zestawy testowe do oceny uczestniczących systemów. Jeden zawierający pary dla każdego z języków szkoleniowych (systemy zostały ocenione w sposób jednojęzyczny), a drugi proponujący język niespodzianki, aby sprawdzić możliwości transferu między językami systemów. Wśród przedłożonych systemów najwyższą wydajność osiągnął model oparty na transformatorze zarówno w otoczeniu jednojęzycznym, jak i wielojęzycznym, dla wszystkich testowanych języków, potwierdzając potencjały tej niedawno wprowadzonej architektury neuronowej. Opis wspólnego zadania i wyniki są dostępne na stronie internetowej https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Sarcina comună a atelierului CogALex-VI se concentrează pe identificarea monolingvă și multilingvă a relațiilor semantice. Am furnizat date de instruire și validare pentru următoarele limbi: engleză, germană și chineză. Având în vedere o pereche de cuvinte, sistemele trebuiau instruite pentru a identifica relația dintre ele, posibilele alegeri fiind sinonime, antonimie, hipernimie și nicio relație. Au fost lansate două seturi de teste pentru evaluarea sistemelor participante. Una conține perechi pentru fiecare dintre limbile de formare (sistemele au fost evaluate în mod monolingv) și cealaltă propune o limbă surpriză pentru a testa capacitățile de transfer translingv ale sistemelor. Printre sistemele prezentate, performanța maximă a fost obținută printr-un model bazat pe transformator atât în cadrul monolingv, cât și în cadrul multilingv, pentru toate limbile testate, dovedind potențialul acestei arhitecturi neurale recent introduse. Descrierea activității partajate și rezultatele sunt disponibile la https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Shaqooyinka koogALex-VI waxay ku qoran yihiin aqoonsiga afka hooyo iyo aqoonsiga luuqadaha kala duduwan ee xiriirka semantika. Macluumaadyada waxbarashada iyo shaqeynta waxaan u siinay luuqadaha soo socda: Ingiriis, Jarmal iyo Shiino. Sida lagu siiyo hadal labo ah, waxaa habboon in nidaamka la tababariyo si uu u ogaado xiriirka dhexdooda, oo ay doorasho suurtagal ah u yihiin synonymimo, antonimo, hypernymi iyo xiriir la’aan. Waxaa la furay laba kooxood oo imtixaan ah si loo qiimeeyo nidaamka qayb-gelinta. Mid waxaa ku jira laba noocyo oo ku qoran luqada waxbarashada (nidaamka waxaa lagu qiimeeyaa qaab af muuqasho ah) tan kalena waxaa lagu soo jeedaa luqada yaab leh in lagu imtixaamo awoodaha isbedelka nidaamka. Isticmaalka la soo dhiibay waxaa ka mid ah sameynta horumarka lagu beddelay tusaale-qaab ah oo lagu beddelay labada luuqadood oo af kala duduwan, si ay u caddayso dhammaan afka la tijaabiyey, waxayna caddeysaa awoodka dhismahan neurada ee ugu dhow la soo bandhigay. Tilmaamaha shaqada ee wadajirka ah iyo resultinta waxaa laga helaa https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>Podijeljeni zadatak radionice CogALex-VI fokusira se na monojezičku i multijezičku identifikaciju semantičkih odnosa. Mi smo pružili podatke o obuci i validaciji za sljedeće jezike: engleski, nemački i kineski. S obzirom na parove reči, sistemi su morali biti obučeni da identifikuju kakvu vezu ima između njih, sa mogućim izborima da su sinonimi, antonimi, hipernimi i uopšte bez veze. Dva testa su otpuštena za procjenu sudjelujućih sustava. Jedan koji sadrži par za svaki jezik obuke (sistemi su procjenjivani na monojezički način) a drugi predlaže iznenađeni jezik kako bi testirali sposobnosti prevođenja kroz jezik sistema. Među podignutim sistemima, vrhunska funkcija je postignuta od transformatorskog model a na monojezičkom i multijezičkom postavljanju, za sve testovane jezike, dokazujući potencijale ove nedavno uvedene neuralne arhitekture. Описане задача и резултати су доступни на https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Den gemensamma uppgiften för CogALex-VI-workshopen fokuserar på enspråkig och flerspråkig identifiering av semantiska relationer. Vi tillhandahöll utbildnings- och valideringsdata för följande språk: engelska, tyska och kinesiska. Med tanke på ett ordpar måste system utbildas för att identifiera vilken relation som finns mellan dem, med möjliga val som synonymer, antonymi, hypernymmi och ingen relation alls. Två testset släpptes för utvärdering av de deltagande systemen. Det ena innehöll par för vart och ett av utbildningsspråken (systemen utvärderades på ett enspråkigt sätt) och det andra innehöll ett överraskningsspråk för att testa systemens transspråkliga överföringsförmåga. Bland de inlämnade systemen uppnåddes toppprestanda genom en transformatorbaserad modell i både enspråkig och flerspråkig miljö, för alla testade språk, vilket bevisade potentialen i denna nyligen introducerade neurala arkitektur. Den delade uppgiftsbeskrivningen och resultaten finns tillgängliga på https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>CogALex-VI වැඩසටහන්ගේ සම්බන්ධ වැඩසටහන් එක භාෂාවක් සහ ගොඩක් භාෂාවක් සම්බන්ධ සම්බන්ධ පරීක්ෂණය සඳ අපි පස්සේ භාෂාවට ප්‍රශ්නය සහ විශ්ලේෂණ දත්ත දුන්නා: ඉංග්‍රීසි, ජර්මන් සහ චීනියා වචනයක් දෙන්න පුළුවන්, පද්ධතියක් ඔවුන්ගේ අතර කොච්චර සම්බන්ධයක් තියෙන්නේ කියලා පුළුවන් තීරණය කරනවා, පුළුවන් තීරණය සම පරීක්ෂණ සෙට් දෙකක් ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විශ්වාස කරන්න. ප්‍රධාන භාෂාවල් එක්කෙනෙක් සම්බන්ධ කරනවා (පද්ධතියක් එක්ක භාෂාවක් විදියට පරීක්ෂණය කරනවා) අනිත් භාෂාවක් ප්‍රශ්න පිළිබඳු පද්ධතිය අතර, උපරිම ක්‍රියාත්මක ප්‍රමාණයක් ප්‍රමාණය කරලා තියෙන්නේ එක භාෂාවක් වගේම වගේම වගේම වගේම වගේම භාෂාවක් වලින් ව සමාගත වැඩක් විස්තර සහ ප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිපත https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>CogALex-VI کارشاپ کا مشترک کام سیمانٹی رابطہ کی ایک زبان اور بہت زبان کی شناسایی پر تمرکز کرتا ہے. ہم نے انگلیسی، جرمن اور چینی کے لئے آموزش اور تحقیق دینے کے لئے اطلاعات دی۔ ایک کلمہ جوڑے کے ذریعہ، سیستم کی تعلیم کی جاتی تھی کہ ان کے درمیان کس تعلق ہے، اس کے ساتھ ممکن انتخاب کے ساتھ سینونیمی، آنٹنی، hypernymy اور کوئی تعلق نہیں ہے. دو امتحان سٹے شرکت سیستموں کے مطالعہ کے لئے آزاد کئے گئے۔ ایک تعلیم زبانوں کے لئے جو جوڑے ہیں (سیستموں کو ایک زبان کی روش میں مطالبہ کیا گیا تھا) اور دوسری زبان کو ایک عجیب زبان کی پیشنهاد کرتا ہے کہ سیستموں کی کروسٹ زبان ترنسیٹ قابلیت کو امتحان کرے۔ تحویل کیے گئے سیستموں کے درمیان، بالا عملکرد ایک تغییر بوسیدہ موڈل سے پہنچائی گئی، دونوں ایک زبان اور بہت سی زبان تنظیم میں، تمام آزمائش زبانوں کے لئے، اس اخیر سے پہنچائی نئورل معماری کی طاقت ثابت کر رہی تھی۔ مشترک دنیا کا سفارش اور نتیجے موجود ہیں https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>CogALex-VI பணியின் பகிர்ந்த பணி நாங்கள் பின்வரும் மொழிகளுக்கு பயிற்சி மற்றும் சரிபார்ப்பு தகவல்களை வழங்கினோம்: ஆங்கிலம், ஜெர் ஒரு வார்த்தை ஜோடி கொடுத்தால், அமைப்புகளுக்கு எந்த உறவு இடையே இருக்கிறது என்பதை கண்டுபிடி பங்கு அமைப்புகளை மதிப்பிடுவதற்காக இரண்டு சோதனை அமைப்புகள் வெளியிடப்பட்டது. One containing pairs for each of the training languages (systems were evaluated in a monolingual fashion) and the other proposing a surprise language to test the crosslingual transfer capabilities of the systems.  கொடுக்கப்பட்ட அமைப்புகளில், மேல் செயல்பாடு மாற்றும் மாதிரி மாதிரியால் மாற்றும் மாதிரி மாற்றம் மற்றும் பல மொழி அமைப்பில், அனைத்து சோதிக்கப்பட்ட மொழிகள பகிர்ந்த பணியின் விளக்கம் மற்றும் முடிவுகள் கிடைக்கும் https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>The shared task of the CogALex-VI workshop focuses on the monolingual and multilingual identification of semantic relations.  Biz quyidagi tillar uchun taʼminlovchi va haqiqiqiylik maʼlumotni yaratdik: Inglizcha, Olmon va Xitoycha. Bir so'z bilan bir so'z bo'lgan bo'lsa, ularning orasidagi munosabatlarni aniqlash uchun tizimni o'rganish kerak. Signoni, antoniya, hypernemiya va hech qanday aloqa emas. @ info: whatsthis Birinchi tilning bir xil tilida (tizimlar monolik tilda qiymat qilinadi) va boshqa bir tashqi tilni tizimning qo'shish imkoniyatini sinash uchun ajoyib tilni anglatadi. Joʻnatilgan tizimlardan bir yuqori bajarish monolingual asosiy modeli va ko'plab tillar moslamalarida, hamma sinab qilingan tillar uchun, bu yaqinda ishga tushirilgan neural arxituvning imkoniyatlarini aniqlaydi. @ info: status https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Việc chia sẻ của xưởng nghiên cứu CogALex-VI tập trung vào việc nhận dạng ngôn ngữ và đa dạng các quan hệ theo ngữ pháp. Chúng tôi cung cấp dữ liệu huấn luyện và xác nhận cho các ngôn ngữ: Anh, Đức và Trung Quốc. Dựa vào một cặp từ, hệ thống phải được huấn luyện để xác định mối quan hệ nào giữa họ, với các lựa chọn có thể là đồng nghĩa, antoonyy, Hypernymy và không có liên quan gì cả. Hai bộ thử được phát ra để đánh giá hệ thống tham gia. Một cặp chứa hợp cho mỗi ngôn ngữ huấn luyện (các hệ thống được đánh giá bằng một cách ngôn ngữ độc đáo) và một bên đề xuất một ngôn ngữ ngạc nhiên để thử khả năng truyền tải xuyên ngôn ngữ của hệ thống. Trong các hệ thống được gửi đến, khả năng cao được đạt được nhờ một mô hình người biến đổi cả ngôn ngữ và chung ngôn ngữ, cho tất cả các ngôn ngữ được thử nghiệm, cho thấy khả năng của kiến trúc thần kinh được giới thiệu gần đây. Mô tả công việc chia sẻ và kết quả có mặt tại https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Споделената задача на семинара се фокусира върху едноезичното и многоезичното идентифициране на семантичните отношения. Предоставяме данни за обучение и валидиране на следните езици: английски, немски и китайски. Като се има предвид двойка думи, системите трябваше да бъдат обучени да идентифицират коя връзка има между тях, като възможните избори бяха синоними, антоними, хипернимия и никаква връзка. Бяха пуснати два теста за оценка на участващите системи. Единият съдържа двойки за всеки от обучителните езици (системите са оценени едноезично), а другият предлага изненадващ език за тестване на междуезичните възможности за трансфер на системите. Сред представените системи максимална производителност беше постигната чрез трансформаторен модел както в едноезична, така и в многоезична обстановка, за всички тествани езици, доказвайки потенциала на тази неотдавна въведена невронна архитектура. Описание на споделената задача и резултатите са достъпни на https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>De gezamenlijke taak van de CogALex-VI workshop richt zich op de eentalige en meertalige identificatie van semantische relaties. We hebben trainings- en validatiegegevens verstrekt voor de volgende talen: Engels, Duits en Chinees. Gezien een woordenpaar moesten systemen getraind worden om te identificeren welke relatie tussen hen bestaat, waarbij mogelijke keuzes synoniem, antoniem, hypernymie en helemaal geen relatie waren. Twee testsets werden uitgebracht voor het evalueren van de deelnemende systemen. De ene bevat paren voor elk van de trainingstalen (systemen werden in een eentalige manier geëvalueerd) en de andere stelt een verrassingstal voor om de meertalige overdrachtsmogelijkheden van de systemen te testen. Van de ingediende systemen werden topprestaties bereikt door een transformatorgebaseerd model, zowel in de eentalige als in de meertalige omgeving, voor alle geteste talen, wat de mogelijkheden van deze recent geïntroduceerde neurale architectuur aantoont. De gedeelde taakbeschrijving en de resultaten zijn beschikbaar op: https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Den fælles opgave for CogALex-VI workshop fokuserer på ensproget og flersproget identifikation af semantiske relationer. Vi leverede trænings- og valideringsdata for følgende sprog: engelsk, tysk og kinesisk. I betragtning af et ordpar måtte systemer trænes til at identificere, hvilken relation der er mellem dem, idet mulige valg var synonymer, antonymi, hypernymi og slet ingen relation. Der blev udgivet to testsæt til evaluering af de deltagende systemer. Det ene indeholder par for hvert af uddannelsessprogene (systemerne blev evalueret på ensproget måde), og det andet foreslår et overraskelsessprog for at teste systemernes tværsprogede overførselsevne. Blandt de indsendte systemer blev topydelsen opnået ved hjælp af en transformer-baseret model i både ensprogede og flersprogede omgivelser, for alle de testede sprog, hvilket beviste potentialet i denne nyligt introducerede neurale arkitektur. Beskrivelsen af den delte opgave og resultaterne er tilgængelige på https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Zajednički zadatak radionice CogALex-VI fokusira se na monojezičku i multijezičku identifikaciju semantičkih odnosa. Mi smo pružili podatke o obuci i validaciji za sljedeće jezike: engleski, njemački i kineski. S obzirom na parove riječi, sustavi su morali biti obučeni kako bi identifikovali kakva je veza između njih, s mogućim izborima sinonim, antonimijom, hipernimum i nikakvom vezom. Dvije testne sete su objavljene za procjenu sudjelujućih sustava. Jedan koji sadrži par za svaki jezik obuke (sustavi su procijenjeni na monojezički način) a drugi predlaže iznenađenim jezikom kako bi testirali sposobnosti prevođenja preko jezika sustava. Među podanim sustavima, vrhunski učinkovit postignuo je model koji se temelji na transformaciji na monojeziku i na multijezičkom postavljanju, za sve testirane jezike, dokazujući potencijale ove nedavno uvedene neuralne arhitekture. Opis zajedničkog zadatka i rezultati su dostupni na https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_id>Tugas berbagi dari workshop CogALex-VI fokus pada identifikasi monobahasa dan multibahasa hubungan semantis. Kami menyediakan data pelatihan dan validasi untuk bahasa berikut: Bahasa Inggris, Jerman dan Cina. Berdasarkan sepasang kata, sistem harus dilatih untuk mengidentifikasi hubungan mana antara mereka, dengan kemungkinan pilihan adalah sinonimi, antonimi, hipernimi dan tidak ada hubungan sama sekali. Dua set tes dibebaskan untuk mengevaluasi sistem yang berpartisipasi. Salah satu mengandung pasangan untuk setiap bahasa latihan (sistem diteliti dengan cara monobahasa) dan yang lain melaporkan bahasa kejutan untuk menguji kemampuan transfer saling bahasa sistem. Di antara sistem yang dihantar, prestasi terbaik dicapai oleh model berdasarkan transformer dalam kedua monobahasa dan dalam pengaturan multibahasa, untuk semua bahasa yang diuji, membuktikan potensi arsitektur saraf yang baru-baru ini diperkenalkan. Deskripsi tugas berbagi dan hasilnya tersedia di https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Die gemeinsame Aufgabe des CogALex-VI Workshops konzentriert sich auf die ein- und mehrsprachige Identifikation semantischer Beziehungen. Wir haben Trainings- und Validierungsdaten für folgende Sprachen bereitgestellt: Englisch, Deutsch und Chinesisch. Bei einem Wortpaar mussten Systeme trainiert werden, um zu erkennen, welche Beziehung zwischen ihnen besteht, wobei mögliche Entscheidungen Synonym, Antonym, Hypernymie und überhaupt keine Beziehung waren. Zur Evaluierung der teilnehmenden Systeme wurden zwei Testsets veröffentlicht. Die eine enthält Paare für jede der Ausbildungssprachen (die Systeme wurden einsprachig bewertet) und die andere schlägt eine Überraschungssprache vor, um die sprachübergreifenden Transferfähigkeiten der Systeme zu testen. Unter den eingereichten Systemen wurde die Spitzenleistung durch ein transformatorbasiertes Modell sowohl im monolingualen als auch im multilingualen Setting für alle getesteten Sprachen erreicht, das die Potenziale dieser kürzlich eingeführten neuronalen Architektur belegt. Die gemeinsame Aufgabenbeschreibung und die Ergebnisse finden Sie unter https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>CogAlex VI 워크숍의 공동 임무는 의미 관계의 단일 언어와 다중 언어 식별에 집중된다.우리는 다음과 같은 언어의 교육과 검증 데이터를 제공했다. 영어, 독일어, 중국어.한 쌍의 단어를 정하려면 시스템은 반드시 훈련을 거쳐 그들 간의 관계를 확정해야 한다. 가능한 선택은 동의어, 반의어, 초의어와 전혀 관계가 없다.참여 시스템을 평가하기 위한 두 세트의 테스트 집합을 발표했다.하나는 각 훈련 언어를 포함하는 짝짓기(시스템은 단어로 평가), 다른 하나는 깜짝 언어를 제시하여 시스템의 다중 언어 이동 능력을 테스트했다.제출된 시스템에서 모든 테스트 언어에 대해 변환기를 바탕으로 하는 모델은 단일 언어와 다중 언어 환경에서 최상의 성능을 얻었고 최근에 도입된 신경 구조의 잠재력을 증명했다.공유 작업 설명과 결과는https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>وظیفه مشترک کارگاه CogALex-VI روی شناسایی یک زبان و چندین زبان رابطه‌های semantic تمرکز می‌کند. ما داده های آموزش و تصدیق دادیم برای زبانهای زیر: انگلیسی، آلمانی و چینی. با وجود یک جفت کلمه، سیستم‌ها باید آموزش داده شود تا شناسایی که کدام رابطه بین آنها دارد، با انتخاب‌های ممکن همسانی، آنتونی، هیپرنیمی و هیچ رابطه‌ای ندارد. دو مجموعه آزمایش برای ارزیابی سیستم مشارکت آزاد شد. یکی که برای هر زبان آموزش (سیستم‌ها در یک روش تک زبان ارزیابی می‌شوند) و دیگری که زبان سورپرایز می‌کند تا توانایی انتقال کل زبان‌های سیستم‌ها را امتحان کند. بین سیستم‌های تحویل داده شده، عملکرد بالا توسط یک مدل تغییر دهنده در هر دو تنظیم یک زبان و یک تنظیم بسیاری زبان، برای همه زبان‌های آزمایش، ثابت کردن توانایی این معماری عصبی که تازگی معرفی شده است، به دست آورده شد. توضیح کار مشترک و نتیجه‌ها در دسترس هستند https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Die gedeelde taak van die CogALex-VI werkshop fokus op die monolinglike en multilinglike identifikasie van semantiese verwantings. Ons verskaf onderwerp en geldigheidsdata vir die volgende tale: Engels, Duits en Sjinees. Omdat 'n woord paar gegee het, moet stelsels onderwerp word om te identifiseer wat verwanting tussen hulle hou, met moontlik keuses synonyme, antonyme, hypernimum en geen verwanting. Twee toets stel is verlos vir evaluering van die deelnadende stelsels. Een bevat paar vir elke van die onderwerp tale (stelsels was in 'n monolinglike modus evalueer) en die ander voorstel 'n verrassing taal om die kruistale oordrag kapabiliteite van die stelsels te toets. onder die voorgestuurde stelsels was die bo-prestasie bereik deur 'n transformeerder-gebaseerde model in beide die monolinglike en in die multilinglike opstelling, vir al die toets tale, die potensielle van hierdie onlangs-ingestelde neurale arkitektuur te bevestig. Die gedeelde taak beskrywing en die resultate is beskikbaar by https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sw>Kazi ya kushirikiana katika warsha ya CogALex-VI imejikita kwenye utambulisho wa lugha na lugha mbalimbali wa mahusiano ya kimapenzi. Tulifanya taarifa za mafunzo na uhakika kwa lugha ifuatayo: Kiingereza, Kijerumani na Kichina. Kutokana na neno la majina wawili, mifumo ilipaswa kufundishwa kutambua uhusiano gani kati yao, na chaguo zilizowezekana kuwa na ushirikiano, ubaguzi, ukarimu na hakuna uhusiano wowote. Mitando mawili ya majaribio yalitolewa kwa ajili ya kutathmini mfumo wa ushiriki. Mmoja ambao una ndoa kwa kila moja ya lugha za mafunzo (mifumo ilipitishwa kwa namna ya lugha ya kiutaifa) na mwingine anayependekeza lugha ya kushangaza ili kujaribu uwezo wa usafirishaji wa lugha za lugha. Miongoni mwa mifumo iliyotolewa, utendaji wa juu ulifanikiwa na muundo wa mabadiliko katika mazingira ya lugha na katika mazingira ya lugha mbalimbali, kwa lugha zote zilizojaribiwa, unaonyesha uwezekano wa ujenzi huu wa kijamii ulioanzishwa hivi karibuni. Maelezo yanayoshirikishwa na matokeo yanapatikana katika https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>CogALex-VI çalışmanyň paylaşyk işi semantik baglaýyşlaryň monodil we köp dillerini tanyşdyrmak üçin üns berýär. Biz indiki diller üçin öwrenme we taýýarlama maglumatlary berdik: Iňlisçe, Almança we Çinçe. Bir söz çift bolsa sistemalar olaryň arasyndaky haýsy baglaýyşyny tanamak üçin bilinmeli bolmaly. Mümkin seçmeler synonymy, antonimi, hipernimi we hiç hili bir baglaýyşyk ýok. Şahsy sistemleri çykmak üçin iki synag çykyldy. Eğitim dilleriniň her biri üçin çift bar (sistemalar monolingüň şeklinde deňlendirildi) we beýlekisi sistemalaryň karrolyk dillerini barlamak üçin geň bir dil teklip edýär. Iňki gönderilen sistemlerde, üst täsirler monolingüň we multilingüň düzümlerinde , üst täsirler bolan nuýral arhitekturyň mümkinçiliklerini barlap başarmady. Paýlanan täblisaň waspy we netijesi meňzeş bar https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Detyra e përbashkët e seminarit CogALex-VI përqëndrohet në identifikimin monogjuhësor dhe shumëgjuhësor të marrëdhënieve semantike. Kemi dhënë të dhëna për trajnimin dhe vlerësimin e gjuhëve të ardhshme: anglisht, gjermanisht dhe kinez. Duke dhënë një çift fjalësh, sistemet duhej të trajnuar për të identifikuar se cili lidhje mban mes tyre, me zgjedhje të mundshme që ishin sinonimi, antonimi, hipernimi dhe asnjë lidhje fare. Dy grupe testesh u lëshuan për vlerësimin e sistemeve pjesëmarrëse. Një që përmban çifte për secilin nga gjuhët e trajnimit (sistemet u vlerësuan në një mënyrë monogjuhësore) dhe tjetri që propozon një gjuhë surprizë për të testuar aftësitë e transferimit ndërgjuhësor të sistemeve. Midis sistemeve të paraqitura, shfaqja më e lartë u arrit nga një model i bazuar në transformues si në një mjedis monogjuhës, ashtu edhe në një mjedis shumëgjuhës, për të gjitha gjuhët e testuara, duke provuar potencialet e kësaj arkitekture nervore të paraqitur kohët e fundit. Përshkrimi i detyrës së përbashkët dhe rezultatet janë në dispozicion në https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_az>CogALex-VI çalışmalarının paylaşılan işi semantik əlaqələrinin monodil və çoxlu dil tanımasına odaqlanır. Biz indiki dillər üçün təhsil və təhsil verilən məlumatları təyin etdik: İngilizce, Alman və Çin. Bir söz çift sayılırsa, sistemlərin aralarında hansı ilişkisi olduğunu tanıtmaq üçün təhsil edilməli idi, mümkün seçimlər sinonimi, antonimi, hipernimi və heç bir ilişkisi olmayan. İki sınama qurğuları iştirak sistemlərini değerləşdirmək üçün yayınlandı. Hər təhsil dillərinin cütləri içərik (sistemləri monodil modunda değerlendirildi) və digəri sistemlərin qarşılıq dillərin transfer qabiliyyətini imtahana çəkmək üçün təəccüblü dili təklif edir. İmzalanmış sistemlərin arasında, ən yüksək performansı monodil və çoxlu dil ayarlarında transformer-tabanlı modeli ilə, müxtəlif dillər üçün, yenidən tanınmış bu nöral arhitektarının potensiallarını təsdiqləyir. Bölüşdürülən işlər təsbiqi və sonuçlar faydalanır https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_hy>The shared task of the CogALex-VI workshop focuses on the monolingual and multilingual identification of semantic relations.  Մենք տրամադրեցինք ուսուցման և հավասարման տվյալներ հետևյալ լեզուների համար՝ անգլերեն, գերմաներեն և չինարեն: Երկու բառ պարունակելով, համակարգերը ստիպված էին ուսուցանել, որպեսզի հասկանան, թե որն է իրենց միջև կապը, և հնարավոր ընտրությունները սինոնիմիա, անտոնիմիա, հիպերնիմիա և ոչ մի կապ: Երկու փորձարկումներ արձակեցին մասնակցության համակարգերի գնահատման համար: Մեկը պարունակում է զույգեր յուրաքանչյուր ուսուցման լեզու համար (համակարգերը գնահատվել են միալեզվով) իսկ մյուսը առաջարկում է զարմանալի լեզու, որպեսզի ստուգեն համակարգերի խաչլեզվով փոխանցման ունակությունները: Հաշվի առնելու համակարգերի միջոցով լավագույն արդյունքը հասավ մեկլեզու և բազլեզու մոդելի միջոցով, բոլոր փորձարկված լեզուների համար, ապացուցելով վերջերս ներկայացված նյարդային ճարտարապետության պոտենցիալը: Համադրված խնդիրների նկարագրությունը և արդյունքները հասանելի են https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>የCogALex-VI ሰርቨርስቲ ስራ በሞሎልቋንቋ እና በብዙ ቋንቋ ግንኙነት ላይ ማሳየት ነው፡፡ ለመግለጫ እና ማረጋገጫ ዳታዎችን ለመግለጫ ቋንቋዎች: እንግሊዝኛ፣ ጀርመን እና ቻይና ሰጠን፡፡ አንዲት ቃላት የተሰጠ፣ የስርዓት ግንኙነት ምን እንደሆነ ማረጋገጥ ያስተምራል ነበር፤ ምንም ግንኙነት የለውም፡፡ ሁለት የሞክራዊ ተሟጋቾች ሲስተምሩ ተፈትተዋል፡፡ አንዱ ለሁሉም ትምህርት ቋንቋዎች ሁለት ዓይነቶች የሚኖሩት (ስርዓቶች በሞላዊ ቋንቋ እንደሚሸክሙ) ሁለተኛውም የበደነቂው ቋንቋ የስርዓቱን መዘዋወር ችሎታዎችን ለመፈትነው የሚያስፈልግ ነው፡፡ በተዘጋጀው ስርዓቶች ውስጥ፣ የደረጃው ስርዓት በሞሎ ቋንቋ እና በብዙ ቋንቋ በተፈታተኑት ቋንቋዎች ሁሉ፣ ለዚህ የቀድሞው የኒጀር መሠረት ስርዓት የሚችሉትን ችሎታዎችን ያስታውቃል፡፡ የአሁኑን ፋይል አስቀምጥ https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>কগালেক্স-ভিআই কর্মশালার শেয়ার কর্মশালার দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি এবং সেমান্টিক সম্পর্কের প্রতি বহুভাষার পরিচিতির উপর মনোযোগ দিয়ে আমরা নিম্নলিখিত ভাষার জন্য প্রশিক্ষণ ও বৈধ তথ্য প্রদান করেছি: ইংরেজি, জার্মান এবং চীনা। একটি শব্দ জোড়া দিয়ে সিস্টেম চিহ্নিত করার জন্য প্রশিক্ষণ প্রদান করা উচিত ছিল যে তাদের মধ্যে কোন সম্পর্ক আছে, যেখানে সম্ভাব্য সিনোনিমি, এন্টোনি অংশগ্রহণকারী সিস্টেম মূল্যায়নের জন্য দুই পরীক্ষা সেট মুক্তি প্রদান করা হয়েছে। প্রশিক্ষণের প্রত্যেকটি ভাষার জন্য জোড়া আছে (সিস্টেম মূল্যায়ন করা হয়েছে) এবং অন্যটি ব্যবস্থার ক্রস্ভাষাভাষী পরীক্ষা করার জন্য এক বিস্ময়কর ভাষা প্ জবাব দিয়েছে সিস্টেমের মধ্যে সেরা প্রদর্শনীর মাধ্যমে একটি পরিবর্তনের ভিত্তিক মডেল দ্বারা অর্জন করা হয়েছে, যা সাম্প্রতিক পরীক্ষার জন্যে এই নিউরুল ভাষার প্রতিষ্ঠান শেয়ার করা কাজের বর্ণনা এবং ফলাফল পাওয়া যায় https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Zajednički zadatak radionice CogALex-VI fokusira se na monojezičku i multijezičku identifikaciju semantičkih odnosa. Mi smo pružili podatke o obuci i validaciji za sljedeće jezike: engleski, nemački i kineski. S obzirom na parove riječi, sistemi su morali biti obučeni da identifikuju kakvu vezu ima između njih, s mogućim izborima da su sinonimi, antonimi, hipernimi i uopšte bez veze. Dva testa su otpuštena za procjenu sustava sudjelovanja. Jedan koji sadrži par za svaki jezik obuke (sistemi su procjenjivani na monojezički način) a drugi predlaže iznenađeni jezik kako bi testirali sposobnosti prevođenja preko jezika sustava. Među podignutim sustavima, vrhunska funkcija je ostvarila model koji se osnovao na transformaciji i na monojezičkom, i na multijezičkom setu, za sve testirane jezike, dokazujući potencijale ove nedavno uvedene neuralne arhitekture. Podijeljeni opis zadataka i rezultati su dostupni na https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>La tasca compartida del taller CogALex-VI es centra en la identificació monolingüe i multilingüe de les relacions semàntiques. We provided training and validation data for the following languages: English, German and Chinese.  Dant un parell de paraules, els sistemes havien de ser entrenats per identificar quina relació hi ha entre ells, les opcions possibles eren sinonimia, antonimia, hipernimi i cap relació. Es van alliberar dos grups d'exàmens per avaluar els sistemes participants. Un contenent parells per cada una de les llengües d'entrenament (els sistemes van ser evaluats de forma monolingüa) i l'altre proposant un llenguatge sorprenent per provar les capacitats de transfer ència translingüística dels sistemes. Entre els sistemes submetits, el millor rendiment va ser aconseguit amb un model basat en transformadors en un entorn monolingüe i multilingüe, per a totes les llengües provades, demostrant el potencial d'aquesta arquitectura neuronal recentment introduïda. La descripció compartida de la tasca i els resultats estan disponibles en https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Společný úkol workshopu CogALex-VI se zaměřuje na jednojjazyčnou a vícejazyčnou identifikaci sémantických vztahů. Poskytli jsme školení a validační údaje pro následující jazyky: angličtinu, němčinu a čínštinu. Vzhledem k páru slov bylo nutné systémy trénovat, aby identifikovaly, který vztah mezi nimi drží, přičemž možné volby byly synonymie, antonymie, hypernymie a vůbec žádný vztah. Pro hodnocení zúčastněných systémů byly vydány dva testovací sady. Jeden obsahuje páry pro každý z výcvikových jazyků (systémy byly hodnoceny jednojzyčně) a druhý navrhuje překvapivý jazyk pro otestování schopností přenosu mezi jazyky systémů. Mezi předloženými systémy bylo dosaženo špičkového výkonu modelu založeného na transformátoru v jednojzyčném i vícejazyčném prostředí pro všechny testované jazyky, což dokazuje potenciál této nedávno zavedené neuronové architektury. Popis sdíleného úkolu a výsledky jsou k dispozici na adrese https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>CogALex-VI seminari ühine ülesanne keskendub semantiliste suhete ühekeelsele ja mitmekeelsele tuvastamisele. Pakkusime koolitus- ja valideerimisandmeid järgmistes keeltes: inglise, saksa ja hiina keel. Sõnade paari puhul tuli süsteeme koolitada, et teha kindlaks, milline seos nende vahel on, võimalikud valikud on sünonüümia, antonüümia, hüpernüümia ja mitte mingit seost. Osalevate süsteemide hindamiseks anti välja kaks testikomplekti. Üks sisaldab paare igale koolituskeele (süsteeme hinnati ühekeelselt) ja teine pakkus välja üllatuskeele, et testida süsteemide keeleülekande võimet. Esitatud süsteemide hulgas saavutati tipptasemel jõudlus transformaatoril põhineva mudeliga nii ühe- kui ka mitmekeelses keskkonnas kõigi testitud keelte puhul, tõestades hiljuti kasutusele võetud närviarhitektuuri potentsiaali. Ühisülesande kirjeldus ja tulemused on kättesaadavad aadressil https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>CogALex-VI -työpajan yhteinen tehtävä keskittyy semanttisten suhteiden yksikieliseen ja monikieliseen tunnistamiseen. Tarjoamme koulutus- ja validointitietoja seuraaville kielille: englanti, saksa ja kiina. Kun otetaan huomioon sanapari, järjestelmiä oli koulutettava tunnistamaan, mikä suhde niiden välillä on, ja mahdolliset valinnat ovat synonyymi, antonyymi, hypernyymi ja mitään suhdetta. Osallistuvien järjestelmien arviointia varten julkaistiin kaksi testisarjaa. Toisessa oli pareja kullekin koulutuskielelle (järjestelmät arvioitiin yksikielisesti) ja toisessa ehdotettiin yllätyskieltä järjestelmien monikielisen siirtokyvyn testaamiseksi. Esitetyistä järjestelmistä huippusuorituskyky saavutettiin muuntajapohjaisella mallilla sekä yksikielisessä että monikielisessä ympäristössä kaikilla testattavilla kielillä, mikä osoitti tämän hiljattain käyttöön otetun neuroarkkitehtuurin potentiaalit. Jaetun tehtävän kuvaus ja tulokset ovat saatavilla osoitteessa https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Awak dhéwé nggawe gerakno CogAlex-Vl kuwi nggawe gerakno kanggo langgar sapa-langgar lan akeh langgar sampek kudu winih. Awak dhéwé ngewehke karo data nggawe kanggo langgambar kapen: Inggris, alaman lan Cines. Sing kelas telas telas, sistem diangkat ono luwih nggawe geranggap perusahaan karo perusahaan karo hal-hal iki dadi, lan akeh iso nguasai sinanyomi, antanymi, akeranim lan akeh barêng-barêng. Display Suara ing sembarang panjur kanggo sabên langga turuné (sistem kuwi nggawe gerampen karo modalité sing kotak ingkang) lan nganggep sistem sing sabên seneng pisan bangsa kanggo ujian sistem kuwi kapat kanggo tukang nggawe luwih apik. Jejaring wong https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Skupna naloga delavnice CogALex-VI se osredotoča na enojezično in večjezično identifikacijo semantičnih odnosov. Zagotovili smo podatke o usposabljanju in potrjevanju za naslednje jezike: angleščina, nemščina in kitajščina. Glede na par besed je bilo treba sisteme usposobiti, da bi ugotovili, katera relacija je med njimi, pri čemer so možne izbire sinonimija, antonimija, hipernimija in sploh nobena relacija. Za ocenjevanje sodelujočih sistemov sta bila izdana dva testna sklopa. Eden vsebuje pare za vsak jezik usposabljanja (sistemi so bili ovrednoteni enojezično), drugi pa predlaga jezik presenečenja za testiranje zmogljivosti medjezičnega prenosa sistemov. Med predloženimi sistemi smo najboljšo zmogljivost dosegli s transformatorskim modelom v enojezičnem in večjezičnem okolju za vse preizkušene jezike, kar dokazuje potenciale te nedavno uvedene nevronske arhitekture. Opis opravila v skupni rabi in rezultati so na voljo na spletni strani https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Suna da raban aikin CogalEx-6 na fokus kan shaidar masu mutane da multilafu. Mun bãyar da data na tsari da inganci wa lugha da ke jẽre: Ingiriya, Jarman da China. Given a word pair, systems had to be trained to identify which relation holds between them, with possible choices being synonymy, antonymy, hypernymy and no relation at all.  An saka matsali biyu dõmin an evaluate tsarin shirin ayuka. Wani mai ƙunsa da nau'i biyu ga kowace harshen mafarin aiki (an evaluate system'ura cikin shirin ayuka da aka yi wa rabo) da ɗayan na'anar da wata lugha mai ban sha'awa dõmin ya jarraba abincin transfer na'urar-harshen na'ura. Daga cikin shirin ayukan da aka shigar shi, ya cika mafarinsa da wata motsi mai shawara a cikin shirin ayuka da aka bada shi, da kuma a cikin tsarin mulki-lingui, na jarraba muhimmin wannan na'urar aikin da aka farata a yanzu-yanzu. Ana samun rabon aiki da ake share da matsala da https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>המשימה המשותפת של מסעדה CogALex-VI מתמקדת על זיהוי יחסים סמנטיים מונושפתיים ומרבות שפתיים. סיפקנו מידע אימון ואישור לשפות הבאות: אנגלית, גרמנית וסינית. בהתחשב בזוג מילים, מערכות נאלצו לאמן לזהות איזה קשר יש ביניהם, עם אפשרויות בחירות הן סינונימיה, אנטונימיה, היפרנימיה ולא שום קשר בכלל. שני קבוצות בדיקות שוחררו כדי להעריך את המערכות המשתתפות. One containing pairs for each of the training languages (systems were evaluated in a monolingual fashion) and the other proposing a surprise language to test the crosslingual transfer capabilities of the systems.  Among the submitted systems, top performance was achieved by a transformer-based model in both the monolingual and in the multilingual setting, for all the tested languages, proving the potentials of this recently-introduced neural architecture.  תיאור המשימה המשותף והתוצאות זמינים ב https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>CogALex-VI ལས་འགན་སྤྱོད་ཀྱི་ལས་འགན་སྤྱད་ནི་སྐད་ཡིག་དང་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་རྣམས་ལ་མཐུན་གཏོང་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་གཤམ་གྱི་སྐད་རིགས་ལ་སློབ་ཐག་གཙོ་རིམ། སྐད་རིགས། དཔེ་དབྱིན་དང་། སྐད་ཡིག་དང་། རྒྱ་ནག་ ཐ་སྙད་གཉིས་པ་ཞིག་གིས་མཐུན་དགོས་པ་ལས། མ་ལག་གིས་དེ་ཚོ་དང་མཐུན་འབྲེལ་བ་གང་འདྲ་ཡིན་མིན་ན་དགོས་པ་ལས། རྒྱལ་སྐྱོར་མ་ལག་ལ་བསྟར་པར་བརྟག་ཞིབ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་སྒྲིག་འགོད་བྱས་པ སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་རེ་རེའི་ནང་དུ་གཉིས་ཆ་གཅིག་ལ་སྨྱུག་གཏོང་གི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལུགས་གཅིག་མཐུན་བཟོ་ཡོད། གཞན་པ་ནི་སྐད་ཡིག་གཞན་ཞིག་ལ་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་ས དབྱིབས་འཆར་བཀོད་ཡོད་པའི་མ་ལག་གི་ནང་དུ་མཐོ་རིམ་ལུགས་པའི་རྣམ་པ་ཞིག་ནི་ཕན་ཚུན་གཅིག་སྐད་ཡིག་དང་འདྲ་བའི་སྒྲིག་སྟངས་གཉིས་ལས་བཟོ་བཅོས མཉམ་སྤྱོད་པའི་བྱ་འགུལ་འགྲེལ་བཤད་དང་ཐོག་འབྲས་མངོན་པ https://sites.google.com/site/cogalexvisharedtask/.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>CogALex-VI Shared Task : Transrelation-A Robust Multilingual Language Model for Multilingual Relation Identification<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>og<fixed-case>AL</fixed-case>ex-<fixed-case>VI</fixed-case> Shared Task: Transrelation - A Robust Multilingual Language Model for Multilingual Relation Identification</title>
      <author><first>Lennart</first><last>Wachowiak</last></author>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Lang</last></author>
      <author><first>Barbara</first><last>Heinisch</last></author>
      <author><first>Dagmar</first><last>Gromann</last></author>
      <pages>59–64</pages>
      <abstract>We describe our submission to the CogALex-VI shared task on the identification of multilingual paradigmatic relations building on XLM-RoBERTa (XLM-R), a robustly optimized and multilingual BERT model. In spite of several experiments with data augmentation, data addition and ensemble methods with a Siamese Triple Net, Translrelation, the XLM-R model with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_classifier">linear classifier</a> adapted to this specific task, performed best in testing and achieved the best results in the final evaluation of the shared task, even for a previously unseen language.</abstract>
      <url hash="f6c6dda6">2020.cogalex-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>wachowiak-etal-2020-cogalex</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/Text2TCS/Transrelation" additional="false">Text2TCS/Transrelation</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Translating Collocations : The Need for Task-driven Word Associations</title>
      <author><first>Oi Yee</first><last>Kwong</last></author>
      <pages>112–116</pages>
      <abstract>Existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dictionary">dictionaries</a> may help collocation translation by suggesting associated words in the form of collocations, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thesaurus">thesaurus</a>, and example sentences. We propose to enhance them with task-driven word associations, illustrating the need by a few scenarios and outlining a possible approach based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_embedding">word embedding</a>. An example is given, using pre-trained word embedding, while more extensive investigation with more refined methods and resources is underway.</abstract>
      <url hash="ac742e0a">2020.cogalex-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>kwong-2020-translating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Characterizing Dynamic Word Meaning Representations in the Brain</title>
      <author><first>Nora</first><last>Aguirre-Celis</last></author>
      <author><first>Risto</first><last>Miikkulainen</last></author>
      <pages>117–128</pages>
      <abstract>During <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_comprehension">sentence comprehension</a>, humans adjust <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meaning_(linguistics)">word meanings</a> according to the combination of the concepts that occur in the sentence. This paper presents a neural network model called CEREBRA (Context-dEpendent meaning REpresentation in the BRAin) that demonstrates this process based on fMRI sentence patterns and the Concept Attribute Rep-resentation (CAR) theory. In several experiments, CEREBRA is used to quantify conceptual combination effect and demonstrate that it matters to humans. Such context-based representations could be used in future <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing systems</a> allowing them to mirror human performance more accurately.</abstract>
      <url hash="274a0291">2020.cogalex-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>aguirre-celis-miikkulainen-2020-characterizing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Contextualized Word Embeddings Encode Aspects of Human-Like Word Sense Knowledge</title>
      <author><first>Sathvik</first><last>Nair</last></author>
      <author><first>Mahesh</first><last>Srinivasan</last></author>
      <author><first>Stephan</first><last>Meylan</last></author>
      <pages>129–141</pages>
      <abstract>Understanding context-dependent variation in word meanings is a key aspect of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentence_processing">human language comprehension</a> supported by the lexicon. Lexicographic resources (e.g., WordNet) capture only some of this context-dependent variation ; for example, they often do not encode how closely senses, or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_change">discretized word meanings</a>, are related to one another. Our work investigates whether recent advances in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a>, specifically contextualized word embeddings, capture human-like distinctions between English word senses, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polysemy">polysemy</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homonym">homonymy</a>. We collect data from a behavioral, web-based experiment, in which participants provide judgments of the relatedness of multiple WordNet senses of a word in a two-dimensional spatial arrangement task. We find that participants’ judgments of the relatedness between senses are correlated with distances between senses in the BERT embedding space. Specifically, homonymous senses (e.g., bat as mammal vs. bat as sports equipment) are reliably more distant from one another in the embedding space than polysemous ones (e.g., chicken as animal vs. chicken as meat). Our findings point towards the potential utility of continuous-space representations of sense meanings.</abstract>
      <url hash="57e59d12">2020.cogalex-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>nair-etal-2020-contextualized</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>