<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.wac">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 12th Web as Corpus Workshop</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Adrien</first><last>Barbaresi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Felix</first><last>Bildhauer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Roland</first><last>Schäfer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Egon</first><last>Stemle</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-68-9</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="62332e65">2020.wac-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>wac-2020-web</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Current Challenges in Web Corpus Building</title>
      <author><first>Miloš</first><last>Jakubíček</last></author>
      <author><first>Vojtěch</first><last>Kovář</last></author>
      <author><first>Pavel</first><last>Rychlý</last></author>
      <author><first>Vit</first><last>Suchomel</last></author>
      <pages>1–4</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we discuss some of the current challenges in web corpus building that we faced in the recent years when expanding the corpora in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sketch_Engine">Sketch Engine</a>. The purpose of the paper is to provide an overview and raise discussion on possible solutions, rather than bringing ready solutions to the readers. For every issue we try to assess its severity and briefly discuss possible mitigation options.</abstract>
      <url hash="41af0837">2020.wac-1.1</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>jakubicek-etal-2020-current</bibkey>
    <title_ar>التحديات الحالية في بناء مجموعة الويب</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Desafios atuais na construção de Web Corpus</title_pt>
      <title_es>Retos actuales en la creación de corpus web</title_es>
      <title_ja>ウェブコーパス構築の現在の課題</title_ja>
      <title_hi>वेब कॉर्पस बिल्डिंग में वर्तमान चुनौतियां</title_hi>
      <title_zh>Web 语料库构挑战</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Dúshláin Reatha i dTógáil Corpas Gréasáin</title_ga>
      <title_ka>მიმდინარე შეცდომები ვებ კორპუსის შექმნა</title_ka>
      <title_el>Τρέχουσες προκλήσεις στην οικοδόμηση ιστού Corpus</title_el>
      <title_hu>Jelenlegi kihívások a Web Corpus építésében</title_hu>
      <title_it>Sfide attuali nel Web Corpus Building</title_it>
      <title_kk>Веб корпус құрылғысында назардағы шақырулар</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Dabartiniai interneto korpuso pastato uždaviniai</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Сегашни предизвици во зградата на веб корпус</title_mk>
      <title_mt>Sfidi Attwali fil-Bini tal-Web Corpus</title_mt>
      <title_ms>Cabaran Semasa dalam Bina Corpus Web</title_ms>
      <title_ml>നിലവിലുള്ള വെബ് കോര്‍പ്പുസ് ബില്‍ഡിങ്ങിങിലുള്ള ചല്ലങ്ങള്‍</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Веб корпус барилгын одоогийн сорилтууд</title_mn>
      <title_no>Gjeldande utfordringar i nettkorpusbygging</title_no>
      <title_pl>Aktualne wyzwania w Web Corpus Building</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Provocările actuale în construirea corpurilor web</title_ro>
      <title_si>වෙබ් කෝර්පුස් නිර්මාණයේ ප්‍රස්තූත ප්‍රශ්නයක්</title_si>
      <title_sr>Trenutne izazove u zgradi web korpusa</title_sr>
      <title_sv>Aktuella utmaningar i webbkorpsbyggandet</title_sv>
      <title_so>Ururka ku yaal Web Corpus Building</title_so>
      <title_ur>ویب کورپوس بنیاد میں موجود چالینگ</title_ur>
      <title_ta>இணைய கார்புஸ் கட்டுதலில் தற்போதைய சிக்கல்கள்</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Thi đấu hiện thời trên Web Corpus Building</title_vi>
      <title_hr>Trenutne izazove u zgradi web korpusa</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Настоящи предизвикателства в изграждането на уеб корпус</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Huidige uitdagingen in Web Corpus Building</title_nl>
      <title_da>De aktuelle udfordringer i webkorpusbygningen</title_da>
      <title_de>Aktuelle Herausforderungen im Web Corpus Building</title_de>
      <title_id>tantangan saat ini dalam gedung Web Corpus</title_id>
      <title_ko>현재 인터넷 자료 라이브러리 건설이 직면한 도전</title_ko>
      <title_fa>چالش‌های فعلی در ساختمان کورپوس وب</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Web köpüsünde häzirki çäreler</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Changamoto la sasa katika jengo la Web Corpus</title_sw>
      <title_sq>Sfidat aktuale në ndërtimin e web Corpus</title_sq>
      <title_af>Huidige Challenges in Web Corpus Building</title_af>
      <title_am>የአሁኑ ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_hy>Վեբ Կորպուսի կառուցվածքի ներկայիս մարտահրավերները</title_hy>
      <title_az>Web Corpus BinasÄ±nda HazÄ±rkÄ± Ă‡Ă¶zĂ¼mlÉ™r</title_az>
      <title_bn>ওয়েব কোর্পাস বিল্ডিং-এর বর্তমান চ্যালেঞ্জ</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Trenutne izazove u zgradi web korpusa</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Current Challenges in Web Corpus Building</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Aktuální výzvy v budování webových korpusů</title_cs>
      <title_et>Praegused väljakutsed Web Corpuse ehitamisel</title_et>
      <title_fi>Web Corpus Buildingin nykyiset haasteet</title_fi>
      <title_sk>Trenutni izzivi pri gradnji spletnega korpusa</title_sk>
      <title_jv>Gambar Daerah kanggo Bukak web corpus</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>ད་ལྟོའི་ཁ་མགོ་ཁྱེར་ནང་དུ་ཡོད་པའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ལ་འཛུགས་པ</title_bo>
      <title_he>האתגרים הנוכחים בבניין רשת קורפוס</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>في هذه الورقة نناقش بعض التحديات الحالية في بناء مجموعات الويب التي واجهناها في السنوات الأخيرة عند توسيع المجموعة في Sketch Engine. الغرض من الورقة هو تقديم نظرة عامة وإثارة النقاش حول الحلول الممكنة ، بدلاً من تقديم حلول جاهزة للقراء. نحاول تقييم مدى خطورتها لكل قضية ونناقش بإيجاز خيارات التخفيف الممكنة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Neste artigo discutimos alguns dos desafios atuais na construção de corpus web que enfrentamos nos últimos anos ao expandir os corpora no Sketch Engine. O objetivo do artigo é fornecer uma visão geral e levantar a discussão sobre possíveis soluções, em vez de trazer soluções prontas para os leitores. Para cada problema, tentamos avaliar sua gravidade e discutir brevemente possíveis opções de mitigação.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>En este artículo discutimos algunos de los desafíos actuales en la creación de corpus web que enfrentamos en los últimos años al expandir los corpora en Sketch Engine. El propósito del documento es proporcionar una visión general y suscitar el debate sobre posibles soluciones, en lugar de ofrecer soluciones listas para los lectores. Para cada problema, tratamos de evaluar su gravedad y analizar brevemente las posibles opciones de mitigación.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、Sketch Engineでコーパスを拡張する際に近年直面しているWebコーパス構築の現在の課題について説明します。この論文の目的は、読者に準備の整った解決策をもたらすのではなく、概要を提供し、考えられる解決策について議論を提起することです。すべての問題について、その深刻度を評価し、緩和の選択肢について簡単に話し合うよう努めています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>于本文中,议近年于Sketch Engine中扩语料库时于Web语料库构中遇之。 本文者概述可以解决方案论,非所以供见成之解决方案也。 每事必试估其严重性,约论缓方。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>इस पेपर में हम वेब कॉर्पस बिल्डिंग में कुछ वर्तमान चुनौतियों पर चर्चा करते हैं जो हमने हाल के वर्षों में स्केच इंजन में कॉर्पोरेट का विस्तार करते समय सामना किया था। पेपर का उद्देश्य एक सिंहावलोकन प्रदान करना और पाठकों के लिए तैयार समाधान लाने के बजाय संभावित समाधानों पर चर्चा करना है। प्रत्येक मुद्दे के लिए हम इसकी गंभीरता का आकलन करने की कोशिश करते हैं और संक्षेप में संभावित शमन विकल्पों पर चर्चा करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Sa pháipéar seo pléimid cuid de na dúshláin reatha i dtógáil corpais gréasáin a bhí os ár gcomhair le blianta beaga anuas agus an corpas á leathnú in Sketch Engine. Is é cuspóir an pháipéir forbhreathnú a sholáthar agus plé a ardú ar réitigh fhéideartha, seachas réitigh réidh a thabhairt do na léitheoirí. Déanaimid iarracht measúnú a dhéanamh ar dhéine gach saincheiste agus pléifimid go hachomair roghanna maolaithe féideartha.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დომენტში ჩვენ განსაკუთრებით მიმდინარე გამოცდილებების საბოლო კოპპუსში, რომლებიც ჩვენ შემდეგ ბოლო წლის შემდეგ, როდესაც კოპორას Sketch Engine-ში გაფართოდი დოკუმენტის მიზეზი არის გავაკეთება და გავაკეთება შესაძლებელი განსახულებების შესაძლებელი განსახულებების შესაძლებელი განსახულებების შესაძლებელი განსახულებების შესაძლებელ გჟვკთ ოპჲბლვმ ჟვ ჲოთრგამვ ეა ჲუვნთმვ ნვდჲგარა რვზნჲჟრ თ ეა პაჱდჲგჲპთმვ გყჱმჲზნთ ჲოაჟთთ ჱა მალკთპაŒვ.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Σε αυτή την εργασία συζητάμε μερικές από τις τρέχουσες προκλήσεις στην οικοδόμηση ιστοσελίδων που αντιμετωπίσαμε τα τελευταία χρόνια κατά την επέκταση των σωμάτων στη μηχανή Sketch. Σκοπός της εργασίας είναι να παρέχει μια επισκόπηση και να εγείρει συζήτηση για πιθανές λύσεις, αντί να φέρει έτοιμες λύσεις στους αναγνώστες. Για κάθε ζήτημα προσπαθούμε να αξιολογήσουμε τη σοβαρότητά του και να συζητήσουμε εν συντομία πιθανές επιλογές μετριασμού.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Ebben a tanulmányban megvitatjuk néhány jelenlegi kihívást a webkorpusz építésében, amelyekkel az elmúlt években szembesültünk a korpuszok bővítése során a Sketch Engine-ben. A tanulmány célja, hogy áttekintést nyújtson és vitatkozzon a lehetséges megoldásokról, ahelyett, hogy kész megoldásokat hozzon az olvasóknak. Minden probléma esetében megpróbáljuk felmérni annak súlyosságát, és röviden megvitatjuk a lehetséges enyhítési lehetőségeket.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>In questo articolo discutiamo alcune delle sfide attuali nella costruzione di corpus web che abbiamo affrontato negli ultimi anni quando abbiamo ampliato i corpora in Sketch Engine. Lo scopo dell'articolo è quello di fornire una panoramica e sollevare la discussione sulle possibili soluzioni, piuttosto che portare soluzioni pronte ai lettori. Per ogni questione cerchiamo di valutarne la gravità e discutere brevemente le possibili opzioni di mitigazione.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente diskutuojame apie kai kuriuos dabartinius uždavinius interneto korpuso pastate, su kuriais susidūrėme pastaraisiais metais plėsdami korporą Sketch Engine. Dokumento tikslas – pateikti apžvalgą ir pradėti diskusijas dėl galimų sprendimų, o ne parengti sprendimus skaitytojams. For every issue we try to assess its severity and briefly discuss possible mitigation options.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағазда біз Sketch тетігінің корпорасын кеңейту үшін соңғы жылдар бойынша көтерген веб корпус құрылымының көбірек жағдайларын талқыладық. Қағаздың мақсаты оқушыларға дайын шешімдерді беру орнына, мүмкін шешімдерді қарау және дискуссиялау. Әрбір мәселе үшін біз оның қаттығын оқу және мүмкін көшірмелеу параметрлерін қысқартуға тырыстық.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Во овој весник разговараме за некои од актуелните предизвици во зградата на веб корпус со кои се соочивме во последниве години кога ја проширувавме корпората во Sketch Engine. Целта на весникот е да обезбеди преглед и да подигне дискусија за можните решенија, наместо да им даде подготвени решенија на читателите. За секое прашање се обидуваме да ја процениме неговата сериозност и кратко да разговараме за можните опции за олеснување.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ വെബ് കോര്‍പ്പുസ് കെട്ടിടത്തില്‍ നിന്നും ചില വ്യാല്‍ക്കുകള്‍ സംസാരിക്കുന്നു. അടുത്ത വര്‍ഷങ്ങളില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ സ് പേപ്പറിന്റെ ലക്ഷ്യം വായിക്കുന്നവര്‍ക്ക് തയ്യാറായ പരിഹാരം കൊണ്ടുവരുന്നതിനെക്കാള്‍ സാധ്യതയുള്ള പരിചയങ്ങള്‍ കൂ എല്ലാ പ്രശ്നങ്ങള്‍ക്കും നമ്മള്‍ അതിന്‍റെ ഗുരുതരമായി പരിഗണിക്കുവാന്‍ ശ്രമിക്കുന്നു. അതിന്‍റെ സാധ്യതകള്‍ മ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаасан дээр бид шинэ сорилтуудын тухай ярилцаж байгаа вэб корпус барилгын тухай ярилцаж байна. Сүүлийн жилүүдэд бид Sketch Engine-д корпора нэмэгдсэн. Цагийн зорилго нь уншигчдад бэлэн шийдэл өгөхийн оронд, боломжтой шийдэл дээр талаар ярилцлага өгөх боломжтой. Ямар ч асуудал тутамд бид түүний хүчтэй байдлыг тодорхойлж, боломжтой багасгах боломжтой сонголтуудыг багасгахыг хичээдэг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>I denne papiret diskuterer vi noen av dei gjeldande utfordringane i webkorpusbygginga som vi oppstod i de siste årene når korporen utvidar i Sketch- motoren. Målet på papiret er å gje ei oversikt og oppretta diskusion om moglege løysing, i staden for å gjera klare løysing til lesarane. For kvar problem prøver vi å vurdere viktigheten, og kort snart diskutera mulige målsettingsval.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>În această lucrare discutăm câteva dintre provocările actuale în construirea corpurilor web cu care ne-am confruntat în ultimii ani când am extins corpurile în Sketch Engine. Scopul lucrării este de a oferi o imagine de ansamblu și de a ridica discuțiile asupra posibilelor soluții, mai degrabă decât de a aduce soluții gata cititorilor. Pentru fiecare problemă încercăm să evaluăm gravitatea acesteia și să discutăm pe scurt posibilele opțiuni de atenuare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>U ovom papiru razgovaramo o nekim trenutnim izazovima u zgradi web korpusa sa kojom smo se suočili u poslednjih godina kada smo proširili korporu u Sketch motoru. Svrha papira je pružati pregled i podizati diskusiju o mogućim rješenjima, umjesto donošenja spremnih rješenja čitačima. Za svaki problem pokušavamo da procenimo njegovu težinu i kratko raspravljamo o mogućim opcijama smanjenja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_mt>In this paper we discuss some of the current challenges in web corpus building that we faced in the recent years when expanding the corpora in Sketch Engine.  L-għan tad-dokument huwa li jipprovdi ħarsa ġenerali u jqajjem diskussjoni dwar soluzzjonijiet possibbli, minflok ma jġib soluzzjonijiet lesti lill-qarrejja. Għal kull kwistjoni nippruvaw jivvalutaw is-severità tagħha u niddiskutu fil-qosor l-għażliet possibbli ta’ mitigazzjoni.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Dalam kertas ini kita membincangkan beberapa cabaran semasa dalam bangunan web corpus yang kita hadapi pada tahun-tahun terakhir apabila mengembangkan corpora dalam enjin Sketch. Tujuan kertas adalah untuk menyediakan pandangan ringkasan dan meningkatkan perbincangan tentang penyelesaian yang mungkin, daripada membawa penyelesaian sedia kepada pembaca. Untuk setiap isu kita cuba untuk menilai kejahatannya dan membincangkan secara singkat pilihan perlawanan yang mungkin.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_so>Warqaddan waxaynu ka sheekaynaynaa dhibaatooyin joogta ah ee ku yaala dhismaha internetka ee baabuurta, kaas oo aynu u u hor jeednay sanadkii ugu dambeeyey markii aan korporada ku kordhinayo mashiinka Sketch. Ujeedada warqaddu waa in la siiyo wax la soo jeedo oo la kordhiyo hadal ku saabsan xalal suurtagal ah, iyadoo aan ahayn in loo keeno xalal diyaar ah kuwa akhriya. Maxaa yeelay, waxaan isku daynaa in aan qiimeynayo daryeelka aad u adag, si fudud ayaannu uga sheekeysanaynaa doorashooyinka suurtagalka ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_pl>W niniejszym artykule omówimy niektóre z aktualnych wyzwań w budowaniu korpusów internetowych, z którymi borykaliśmy się w ostatnich latach podczas rozbudowy korpusów w Sketch Engine. Celem artykułu jest zapewnienie przeglądu i podniesienie dyskusji na temat możliwych rozwiązań, a nie przedstawienie gotowych rozwiązań czytelnikom. Dla każdego problemu staramy się ocenić jego powagę i krótko omówić możliwe opcje łagodzenia.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ur>اس کاغذ میں ہم نے ویب کورپوس بنیاد میں موجود چالوں میں سے کچھ بحث کیا جو ہم نے اگلے سالوں میں ملاقات کی جب اسکیچ انجنی میں کورپورا پھیلایا تھا۔ کاغذ کا مطالبہ یہ ہے کہ پڑھنے والوں کے لئے تیار حل لانے کے بغیر ایک اوربور نظر اور بحث کے ساتھ اضافہ کرنا۔ ہم ہر مسئلہ کے لئے اس کی سختی کا امتحان کرنا چاہتے ہیں اور بہت تھوڑی سی موجودات کے ذریعہ مشورہ کرنا چاہتے ہیں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_sv>I den här uppsatsen diskuterar vi några av de aktuella utmaningarna inom webbkorpusbyggandet som vi stötte på under de senaste åren när vi expanderade korporan i Sketch Engine. Syftet med uppsatsen är att ge en överblick och väcka diskussion om möjliga lösningar, snarare än att föra färdiga lösningar till läsarna. För varje fråga försöker vi bedöma dess svårighetsgrad och kortfattat diskutera möjliga mildringsalternativ.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>මේ පත්තරයේ අපි වෙබ් කොර්පුස් ගොඩනැගිල්ලේ ප්‍රස්තූත ප්‍රශ්නයක් කතා කරනවා මේ අවුරුද්ධ අවුරුද්ධ අවුරුද්ධ ව පැත්තගේ අරමුණ තමයි ප්‍රවේශනයක් දෙන්න සහ ප්‍රවේශනයක් ප්‍රවේශනය කරන්න, පාළුවන් විසිද්ධ විසිද්ධ විසි හැම ප්‍රශ්නයක්ම අපි හැම ප්‍රශ්නයක්ම හොයාගන්න උත්සාහ කරනවා එයාගේ ශක්තිමත් විශ්වාස කරනවා සහ ප</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தில் நாம் தற்போதைய சில சவால்பங்களை விவாதம் செய்கிறோம். நாங்கள் சமீபத்தில் சென்ற வருடங்களில் நாங்கள் முகம் நேர்ந காகிதத்தின் தலைப்பு படிப்பாளர்களுக்கு தயாரான தீர்வுகளை கொண்டு வருவதற்கு பதிலாக ஒரு மேலோட்டம் மற்றும் சாத்தியம ஒவ்வொரு பிரச்சனைக்கும் நாம் அதன் கடுமையான மதிப்பிட முயற்சிக்கிறோம் மற்றும் சிறிது விளைவு முடிய</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Bu qogʻozda biz Veb Korpus quriligidagi bir necha qanday murakkab qilamiz. Yaqinda biz Sketch Enginesidagi kompaniya ko'paytirilganda ko'rib chiqqamiz. Qogʻozning maqsadi o'qituvchilarga tayyorli usullarni olib tashlash mumkin. Har bir muammo uchun biz ularning alvorligini qiymatga harakat qilamiz va qisqacha cheksiz suhbat parametrlarini o'rganamiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Trong bài báo này chúng ta thảo luận về những thử thách hiện nay trong công trình tụ tập trên mạng mà chúng ta đã phải đối mặt trong những năm gần đây khi mở rộng tập đoàn máy Sketch. Mục đích của tờ giấy là cung cấp thông tin và thảo luận về những giải pháp có thể, thay vì đưa ra giải pháp sẵn sàng cho độc giả. Với mỗi vấn đề chúng tôi cố gắng đánh giá mức độ nghiêm trọng của nó và thảo luận ngắn gọn các lựa chọn có thể giảm bớt.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>В настоящата статия обсъждаме някои от настоящите предизвикателства в изграждането на уеб корпус, пред които се изправихме през последните години при разширяването на корпорите в Скеч Engine. Целта на доклада е да предостави обзор и да предизвика дискусия за възможни решения, вместо да донесе готови решения на читателите. За всеки проблем се опитваме да оценим сериозността му и накратко да обсъдим възможните възможности за смекчаване.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>I denne artikel diskuterer vi nogle af de aktuelle udfordringer inden for webkorpusbygning, som vi stod over for i de seneste år, da vi udvidede korpuserne i Sketch Engine. Formålet med artiklen er at give et overblik og skabe diskussion om mulige løsninger frem for at bringe færdige løsninger til læserne. For hvert spørgsmål forsøger vi at vurdere dens alvor og kort diskutere mulige afbødningsmuligheder.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>U ovom papiru razgovaramo o nekim trenutnim izazovima u građevini web korpusa s kojom smo se suočili u posljednjih godina kada smo proširili korporu u Sketch motoru. Cilj papira je pružati pregled i podizati diskusiju o mogućim rješenjima, umjesto donošenja spremnih rješenja čitačima. Za svaki problem pokušavamo procijeniti njegovu težinu i kratko razgovarati o mogućim opcijama smanjenja.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>In dit artikel bespreken we enkele van de huidige uitdagingen in het bouwen van webcorpus die we de afgelopen jaren tegenkwamen bij het uitbreiden van de corpora in Sketch Engine. Het doel van het artikel is om een overzicht te geven en discussie op gang te brengen over mogelijke oplossingen, in plaats van kant-en-klare oplossingen aan de lezers te brengen. Voor elk probleem proberen we de ernst ervan te beoordelen en bespreken we kort mogelijke mitigatiemogelijkheden.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>In diesem Beitrag diskutieren wir einige der aktuellen Herausforderungen beim Aufbau von Webkorpus, mit denen wir in den letzten Jahren beim Ausbau der Korpora in Sketch Engine konfrontiert waren. Ziel des Aufsatzes ist es, einen Überblick zu geben und Diskussionen über mögliche Lösungen anzuregen, anstatt den Lesern fertige Lösungen vorzustellen. Für jedes Problem versuchen wir, seine Schwere einzuschätzen und kurz mögliche Minderungsoptionen zu diskutieren.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>본고에서 우리는 최근 몇 년 동안 Sketch Engine에서 자료 라이브러리를 확장할 때 웹 자료 라이브러리 구축에 직면한 도전에 대해 토론했다.본고의 목적은 개술을 제공하고 가능한 해결 방안에 대해 토론하는 것이지 독자에게 기존의 해결 방안을 제공하는 것이 아니다.모든 문제에 대해 우리는 그 심각성을 평가하고 가능한 완화 방안을 간략하게 토론하려고 한다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>در این کاغذ ما در مورد بعضی از چالش‌های فعلی در ساختمان کارپوس وب که در سال‌های اخیر روبرو شدیم در مورد گسترش کارپورا در موتور اسکیچ صحبت کردیم. هدف کاغذ این است که یک نگاه پیش‌بینی و بحث در مورد راه حل‌های ممکن، به جای اینکه راه‌حل‌های آماده برای خوانندگان را پیش‌بینی کنیم. برای هر موضوع سعی می کنیم سختی آن را ارزیابی کنیم و در کوتاه در مورد انتخابات‌های کوتاهی ممکن صحبت کنیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Dalam kertas ini kita mendiskusikan beberapa tantangan saat ini di gedung web corpus yang kita hadapi di tahun-tahun terakhir ketika memperluas corpora di Sketch Engine. Tujuan kertas adalah untuk menyediakan panjang dan meningkatkan diskusi tentang solusi yang mungkin, daripada membawa solusi siap untuk pembaca. Untuk setiap isu kita mencoba untuk menilai kerasnya dan mendiskusikan secara singkat mungkin pilihan penambahan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>In this paper we discuss some of the current challenges in web corpus building that we faced in the recent years when expanding the corpora in Sketch Engine.  Lengo la gazeti ni kutoa mtazamo na kuongeza mjadala kuhusu ufumbuzi unaowezekana, badala ya kuleta suluhisho zilizo tayari kwa wasomaji. Kwa kila suala tunajaribu kutathmini hali ngumu yake na kujadili kwa muda mfupi chaguo za utoaji wa mitandao.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyzda bolup ge챌en 첵yllar i챌inde, Sketch Motoryny흫 k철p체si 첵a힊yndaky h채zirki kyn챌ylyklary흫 k채birleri barada g체rr체흫 ed첵채ris. Bu gazetin maksady o첵lanlara ta첵첵ar 챌철z체mler getirmek we m체mkin 챌철z체mler barada diskusi첵a bermek. Her mesele 체챌in biz 철z kyn챌ylygyny 챌ykarmak we gysga m체mkin azaltmak se챌eneklerini g철r체힊mek 체챌in synany힊첵arys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>In hierdie papier bespreek ons sommige van die huidige uitdagings in web korpus gebou wat ons in die onlangse jaar aangesig het wanneer die korpora in Sketch-masjien uitbrei. Die doel van die papier is om 'n oorskou te verskaf en diskusie op moontlike oplossing te verhoog, eerder as om gereed oplossing aan die lesers te bring. Vir elke aangaande probeer ons om sy grigtigheid te vurk en kort om moontlike vermindering opsies te bespreek.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Në këtë letër diskutojmë disa nga sfidat e tanishme në ndërtimin e web corpus që përballemi në vitet e fundit kur zgjerojmë korprën në Sketch Engine. Qëllimi i gazetës është të ofrojë një përmbledhje dhe të ngrejë diskutim mbi zgjidhjet e mundshme, në vend që t'u sjellë zgjidhje të gatshme lexuesve. Për çdo çështje përpiqemi të vlerësojmë rëndësinë e saj dhe të diskutojmë shkurt opsionet e mundshme të lehtësimit.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>በዚህ ካላት ውስጥ የኮርፖርት ኮርፖርት በSketch እንቅልቃን በመዘረጋ ጊዜ የድረብ ኮርፓስ ግንኙነት ላይ የቆይተን አንዳንዶችን ጥላቻዎች እናሳውቃለን፡፡ የጋዜጠው ጉዳዩ ለአንባቢዎች የተዘጋጀውን መፍትሄ ማሳየት እና በተቻለው መፍትሄቶችን ማሳየት ነው፡፡ ለሁሉም ጉዳይ ግማሹን እናሳውቃለን እና የሚቻለውን የመግለጫ ምርጫዎች በጥቂት ጊዜ እናሳውቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Այս թղթի մեջ մենք քննարկում ենք վեբ-կորպուսի կառուցվածքի ներկայիս մարտահրավերները, որոնք մենք հանդիպեցինք վերջին տարիների ընթացքում, երբ ընդլայնեցինք Sketch-ի մեքենայի կառուցվածքը: The purpose of the paper is to provide an overview and raise discussion on possible solutions, rather than bringing ready solutions to the readers.  For every issue we try to assess its severity and briefly discuss possible mitigation options.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıtda, Sketch Motorunun korporasını genişlədiyimiz son illərdə qarşılaşdığımız web korpus binasında müzakirə etdik. Kağıt məqsədi oxuyanlara hazırlanmış çözümlər gətirmək və mümkün çözümlər barəsində mübahisə etmək. Hər məsələnin ağırlığını təsdiqləməyə çalışırıq və mümkün azaltma seçimlərini qısa dəfə mübahisə edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>এই কাগজটিতে আমরা ওয়েব কোর্পাস বিল্ডিং-এ বর্তমান চ্যালেঞ্জ আলোচনা করি যা সাম্প্রতিক বছরে আমরা স্কেচ ইঞ্জিনে কর্পোরা বিস্তৃত হওয়ার সময়ে  কাগজের উদ্দেশ্য হচ্ছে পাঠকদের কাছে প্রস্তুত সমাধান নিয়ে সম্ভাব্য সমাধান নিয়ে আলোচনা প্রদান করা এবং সম্ভবত আলোচনা বাড়া প্রত্যেক বিষয়ের জন্য আমরা তার গুরুত্বপূর্ণ মূল্যের চেষ্টা করছি এবং সামান্যে সম্ভাব্য মিশিশন অপশন নিয়ে আলো</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>En aquest article discutem alguns dels reptes actuals en l'edifici web corpus que ens vam enfrontar en els últims anys quan vam expandir el corpora a Sketch Engine. The purpose of the paper is to provide an overview and raise discussion on possible solutions, rather than bringing ready solutions to the readers.  Per cada tema intentem evaluar la seva gravetat i discutir breument les opcions de mitigació possibles.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>V tomto článku diskutujeme některé z aktuálních výzev v oblasti tvorby webových korpusů, kterým jsme v posledních letech čelili při rozšiřování korpusů v Sketch Engine. Cílem příspěvku je poskytnout přehled a podněcovat diskusi o možných řešeních spíše než přinášet připravená řešení čtenářům. U každého problému se snažíme posoudit jeho závažnost a stručně diskutovat o možnostech zmírnění.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas artiklis arutleme mõningaid praegusi väljakutseid veebikorpuste ehitamisel, millega oleme viimastel aastatel silmitsi seisnud, kui laiendasime korpuseid Sketch Engines. Töö eesmärk on anda ülevaade ja tõsta arutelu võimalike lahenduste üle, mitte tuua valmislahendusi lugejateni. Iga probleemi puhul püüame hinnata selle tõsidust ja arutada lühidalt võimalikke leevendusvõimalusi.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>U ovom papiru razgovaramo o nekim trenutnim izazovima u zgradi web korpusa sa kojom smo se suočili u posljednjih godina kada smo proširili korporu u Sketch motoru. Svrha papira je pružati pregled i podizati diskusiju o mogućim rješenjima, umjesto donošenja spremnih rješenja čitačima. Za svaki problem pokušavamo procijeniti njegovu težinu i kratko razgovarati o mogućim opcijama smanjenja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_fi>Tﾃ､ssﾃ､ artikkelissa kﾃ､sittelemme joitain nykyisiﾃ､ haasteita web-korpusrakentamisessa, joita olemme kohdanneet viime vuosina laajentaessamme korpusia Sketch Enginessﾃ､. Artikkelin tarkoituksena on antaa yleiskatsaus ja herﾃ､ttﾃ､ﾃ､ keskustelua mahdollisista ratkaisuista eikﾃ､ tuoda valmiita ratkaisuja lukijoille. Pyrimme arvioimaan jokaisen ongelman vakavuutta ja keskustelemme lyhyesti mahdollisista lieventﾃ､misvaihtoehdoista.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Nang pepul iki, kita cobagian ngomong nek perbudhakan yakulang liyane ing sak nguasai sak cara web sing dumadhi iki ning acara sing dumadhi iki bakal ngelambang barang ngenggo dolanan karo mulalah dumadhi iki Nambah aparat kanggo ngilanggar oleh banjure nggawe perusahaan bakal bisa diangkat oleh Nyong saben kesempatan awak dhéwé nggunakake severity lan nganggep nggawe ngubah cara sing apik dhéwé.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku obravnavamo nekatere aktualne izzive pri gradnji spletnih korpusov, s katerimi smo se soočali v zadnjih letih pri širitvi korpusov v Sketch Engineu. Namen prispevka je zagotoviti pregled in spodbuditi razpravo o možnih rešitvah, namesto da bi bralcem prinesli pripravljene rešitve. Za vsako vprašanje poskušamo oceniti njegovo resnost in na kratko razpravljati o možnostih ublažitve.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>בעיתון הזה אנחנו מדברים על חלק מהאתגרים הנוכחים בבניין קרפוס האינטרנט שעמדנו בפני בשנים האחרונות כשהרחבנו את הקופורה במנוע סקץ. המטרה של העיתון היא לספק מבט כללי ולהעלות דיון על פתרונות אפשריים, במקום להביא פתרונות מוכנים לקוראים. For every issue we try to assess its severity and briefly discuss possible mitigation options.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>A cikin wannan takarda, Munã jãyayya masu cikin wasu masu kanzu masu cikin shirin kwamfyuta na web, wadda muka haɗu da shi a cikin shekarar nan da suka sani a lokacin da za'a buɗe koropa a cikin mashine ya Sskaetch. The purpose of the paper is to provide an overview and raise discussion on possible solutions, rather than bringing ready solutions to the readers.  Ga kõwane masu al'amarin da Muke jarraba ka ƙaddara alherinsa kuma munã yi jayayya a kan zaɓen cire.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོས་ད་ལྟོའི་གདོང་ལེན་པ་ཚོའི་ནང་གི་མཐུད་སྣེ་གསར་དུ་གཏོང་བ་ཡོད། ཡིག་ཆའི་དམིགས་ཡུལ་ནི་ཡིག་ཆའི་དོན་ལ་ཡིག་ཆ་གསར་བསྐྲུན་ཡོད་པ་དང་ཐུབ་སྲིད་པའི་ཐབས་ཤེས་ཀྱི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡོད་ཚད་ལྟ་ དོན་ལ་གནད་དོན་ཡོད་ཚད་ལ་ང་ཚོས་དུས་གཏོང་བ་ཞིབ་འཇུག་བྱེད་འདོད་པ་ལས་ཕལ་མེད་དུ་གཏོང</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>The ELTE.DH Pilot Corpus   Creating a Handcrafted Gigaword Web Corpus with Metadata<fixed-case>ELTE</fixed-case>.<fixed-case>DH</fixed-case> Pilot Corpus – Creating a Handcrafted <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>igaword Web Corpus with Metadata</title>
      <author><first>Balázs</first><last>Indig</last></author>
      <author><first>Árpád</first><last>Knap</last></author>
      <author><first>Zsófia</first><last>Sárközi-Lindner</last></author>
      <author><first>Mária</first><last>Timári</last></author>
      <author><first>Gábor</first><last>Palkó</last></author>
      <pages>33–41</pages>
      <abstract>In this article, we present the method we used to create a middle-sized corpus using targeted web crawling. Our corpus contains news portal articles along with their metadata, that can be useful for diverse audiences, ranging from digital humanists to NLP users. The method presented in this paper applies rule-based components that allow the curation of the text and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata">metadata content</a>. The curated data can thereon serve as a reference for various tasks and measurements. We designed our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Workflow">workflow</a> to encourage modification and customisation. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept">concept</a> can also be applied to other genres of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portal_(architecture)">portals</a> by using the discovered <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattern">patterns</a> in the architecture of the portals. We found that for a systematic creation or extension of a similar corpus, our method provides superior <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> and ease of use compared to The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wayback_Machine">Wayback Machine</a>, while requiring minimal manpower and computational resources. Reproducing the corpus is possible if changes are introduced to the text-extraction process. The standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_Encoding_Initiative">TEI format</a> and Schema.org encoded metadata is used for the output format, but we stress that placing the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> in a digital repository system is recommended in order to be able to define semantic relations between the segments and to add rich annotation.</abstract>
      <url hash="1ac0dd2e">2020.wac-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>indig-etal-2020-elte</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>