<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nli">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-06-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Natural Language Interfaces</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ahmed Hassan</first><last>Awadallah</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yu</first><last>Su</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Huan</first><last>Sun</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Scott Wen-tau</first><last>Yih</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <url hash="fed11dde">2020.nli-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="175d8ef8">2020.nli-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nli-2020-natural</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Answering Complex Questions by Combining Information from Curated and Extracted Knowledge Bases</title>
      <author><first>Nikita</first><last>Bhutani</last></author>
      <author><first>Xinyi</first><last>Zheng</last></author>
      <author><first>Kun</first><last>Qian</last></author>
      <author><first>Yunyao</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <author><first>H.</first><last>Jagadish</last></author>
      <pages>1–10</pages>
      <abstract>Knowledge-based question answering (KB_QA) has long focused on simple questions that can be answered from a single knowledge source, a manually curated or an automatically extracted KB. In this work, we look at answering complex questions which often require combining information from multiple sources. We present a novel KB-QA system, Multique, which can map a complex question to a complex query pattern using a sequence of simple queries each targeted at a specific KB. It finds simple queries using a neural-network based model capable of collective inference over textual relations in extracted KB and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ontology_(information_science)">ontological relations</a> in curated KB. Experiments show that our proposed system outperforms previous KB-QA systems on benchmark datasets, ComplexWebQuestions and WebQuestionsSP.</abstract>
      <url hash="0a910fed">2020.nli-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nli-1.1</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929797" />
      <bibkey>bhutani-etal-2020-answering</bibkey>
    <title_ar>الإجابة على الأسئلة المعقدة عن طريق الجمع بين المعلومات من قواعد المعرفة المنظمة والمستخرجة</title_ar>
      <title_es>Responder a preguntas complejas mediante la combinación de información de bases de conocimiento seleccionadas y extraídas</title_es>
      <title_pt>Respondendo a perguntas complexas combinando informações de bases de conhecimento selecionadas e extraídas</title_pt>
      <title_ja>キュレーションおよび抽出されたナレッジベースからの情報を組み合わせて複雑な質問に答える</title_ja>
      <title_hi>क्यूरेटेड और निकाले गए नॉलेज बेस से जानकारी के संयोजन से जटिल प्रश्नों का उत्तर देना</title_hi>
      <title_zh>以组自精选及取知识库信息以对杂问</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Ceisteanna Coimpléascacha a Fhreagairt trí Fhaisnéis ó Bhunáiteanna Eolais Choimeádta agus Bainte a Chomhcheangail</title_ga>
      <title_ka>კომპლექტური კითხვების პასუხის გასაგება ინფორმაციის კომპლექტირებული და გამოგექტირებული მეცნიერების ბაზებიდან</title_ka>
      <title_el>Απάντηση σε σύνθετες ερωτήσεις συνδυάζοντας πληροφορίες από επεξεργασμένες και εξαγόμενες βάσεις γνώσης</title_el>
      <title_hu>Összetett kérdések megválaszolása a gyógyított és kivont tudásbázisokból származó információk kombinációjával</title_hu>
      <title_it>Rispondere a domande complesse combinando informazioni da basi di conoscenza curate ed estratte</title_it>
      <title_kk>Мәліметті тіркелген және тарқатылған білім негізінен біріктіру арқылы толық сұрақтарды жауап беру</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Одговарање на комплексни прашања со комбинација на информации од излечени и извадени бази на знаење</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Atsakyti į sudėtingus klausimus derinant informaciją iš apdorotų ir ištrauktų žinių bazių</title_lt>
      <title_mt>It-tweġiba għal mistoqsijiet kumplessi permezz tal-Kombinazzjoni ta’ Informazzjoni minn Bażijiet ta’ Għarfien Kurat u Estratt</title_mt>
      <title_ml>പരിജ്ഞാനത്തിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനങ്ങളില്‍ നിന്നും വിവരങ്ങള്‍ കൂട്ടിചേര്‍ക്കുന്നതിനാല്‍ കോമ്പ്ലെക്സ് ചോദ്യങ്</title_ml>
      <title_ms>Jawab soalan kompleks dengan Menggabungkan Maklumat dari Pangkalan Pengetahuan Diubah dan Diekstrak</title_ms>
      <title_mn>Хариулт нь Хоригдсан, Хоригдсан мэдлэг суурь дээр мэдээллийг нийлүүлж</title_mn>
      <title_no>Svar komplekse spørsmål ved å kombinerera informasjon frå kjennebaser</title_no>
      <title_pl>Odpowiedź na złożone pytania poprzez łączenie informacji z kuratorskich i wydobytych baz wiedzy</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Odgovor na kompleksno pitanje povezanim informacijama iz proklete i izvučene baze znanja</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Răspunsul la întrebări complexe prin combinarea informațiilor din bazele de cunoștințe curate și extrase</title_ro>
      <title_si>ප්‍රශ්න සම්පූර්ණ ප්‍රශ්න ප්‍රශ්න ප්‍රශ්නය ප්‍රතිච්චාර කරලා තොරතුරු සම්බන්ධ කරලා සහ</title_si>
      <title_so>Questions Complex by Combining Information from Cursed and Extracted Knowledge Bases</title_so>
      <title_sv>Svara på komplexa frågor genom att kombinera information från kuraterade och extraherade kunskapsbaser</title_sv>
      <title_ta>அறிவிப்பு அடிப்படைகளிலிருந்து சேர்த்து தகவலை சேர்த்து சிக்கல் கேள்விகளுக்கு பதில் அளிக்கிறது</title_ta>
      <title_ur>مکمل سوال جواب دینے کے ذریعہ لعنت اور نکالا گیا علم بنسس سے معلومات ترکیب کرنے کے ذریعہ</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Trả lời phức tạp câu hỏi bằng cách kết hợp thông tin từ những nhà khoa học</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Отговаряне на сложни въпроси чрез комбиниране на информация от курирани и извлечени бази от знания</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Odgovor na kompleksnih pitanja povezanim informacijama iz proklete i izvučene baze znanja</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Complexe vragen beantwoorden door informatie uit gecureerde en geëxtraheerde kennisbases te combineren</title_nl>
      <title_da>Besvarelse af komplekse spørgsmål ved at kombinere oplysninger fra kurerede og ekstraherede vidensbaser</title_da>
      <title_de>Beantwortung komplexer Fragen durch Kombination von Informationen aus kuratierten und extrahierten Wissensbasen</title_de>
      <title_id>Jawab Pertanyaan Kompleks dengan Menggabungkan Informasi dari Baza Pengetahuan Terkurung dan Ekstraksi</title_id>
      <title_ko>기획과 추출된 지식 라이브러리의 정보를 결합하여 복잡한 문제에 대답하다</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Answering Complex Questions by Combining Information from Curated and Extracted Knowledge Bases</title_sw>
      <title_af>Antwoord Volledige Vragate deur Kombineer Informasie van Verwyder en uitgepak kennis Basies</title_af>
      <title_sq>Përgjigja pyetjeve komplekse duke kombinuar informacionin nga bazat e njohurive të kuruara dhe të nxjerra</title_sq>
      <title_am>Answering Complex Questions by Combining Information from Curated and Extracted Knowledge Bases</title_am>
      <title_az>Yaxınlıq və çıxarılan Bilim Üstündən Malümatı Birleşdirən Komplex Soruları cavab verir</title_az>
      <title_hy>Պատասխանել բարդ հարցերին՝ համադրելով բուժված և դուրս հանված գիտելիքի հիմքերից տեղեկատվությունը</title_hy>
      <title_bn>সম্পূর্ণ এবং বহিস্কৃত জ্ঞানের ভেস থেকে তথ্য কমান্ডিং করে কমপ্লেক্স প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিয়েছে</title_bn>
      <title_tr>Gizli we Açmak Bilim Baselerinden Maglumat Birleşerek Tamamlary Soraglary jogap berdi</title_tr>
      <title_cs>Odpověď na komplexní otázky kombinováním informací z vyléčených a extrahovaných znalostních bází</title_cs>
      <title_ca>Respondre a preguntes complexes combinant informació de bases de coneixements curades i extraides</title_ca>
      <title_fa>جواب سوالات کامل با ترکیب اطلاعات از پایگاه‌های دانش‌های لعنتی و خارج شده</title_fa>
      <title_bs>Odgovor na kompleksnih pitanja povezanim informacijama iz proklete i izvučene baze znanja</title_bs>
      <title_et>Keerulistele küsimustele vastamine, kombineerides teavet kureeritud ja väljavõetud teadmistebaasidest</title_et>
      <title_fi>Monimutkaisiin kysymyksiin vastaaminen yhdistämällä tietoa kuratoiduista ja poimituista tietokantoista</title_fi>
      <title_he>עונה על שאלות מורכבות על ידי שילוב מידע מבסיסי ידע מושלמים ומוציאים</title_he>
      <title_jv>Ngubah Gambar Kelangang Puteran Perangkat Kenaljut Informasi Suara lan Ngawe Perintah Panjenengan</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Odgovarjanje na kompleksna vprašanja s kombinacijo informacij iz kuriranih in pridobljenih baz znanja</title_sk>
      <title_bo>མཐུན་སྒྲིག་དང་ཕྱིར་འདོན་པའི་ཤེས་ཚོགས་གཞི་རྟེན་ནས་མཉམ་དུ་བསྡུས་པའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག་གི་འདྲི་ཚུལ་ལ་ལན་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>لطالما ركزت الإجابة على الأسئلة المستندة إلى المعرفة (KB_QA) على الأسئلة البسيطة التي يمكن الإجابة عليها من مصدر معرفة واحد ، أو قاعدة المعارف المنسقة يدويًا أو المستخرجة تلقائيًا. في هذا العمل ، ننظر في الإجابة على الأسئلة المعقدة التي تتطلب غالبًا دمج المعلومات من مصادر متعددة. نقدم نظام KB-QA الجديد ، Multique ، والذي يمكنه تعيين سؤال معقد إلى نمط استعلام معقد باستخدام سلسلة من الاستعلامات البسيطة التي تستهدف كل منها قاعدة بيانات محددة. يجد استعلامات بسيطة باستخدام نموذج قائم على الشبكة العصبية قادر على الاستدلال الجماعي على العلاقات النصية في KB المستخرج والعلاقات الأنطولوجية في KB المنسق. تظهر التجارب أن نظامنا المقترح يتفوق في الأداء على أنظمة KB-QA السابقة في مجموعات البيانات المعيارية و ComplexWebQuestions و WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>A resposta a perguntas com base em conhecimento (KB_QA) há muito se concentra em perguntas simples que podem ser respondidas a partir de uma única fonte de conhecimento, uma base de conhecimento selecionada manualmente ou extraída automaticamente. Neste trabalho, procuramos responder a perguntas complexas que muitas vezes exigem a combinação de informações de várias fontes. Apresentamos um novo sistema KB-QA, Multique, que pode mapear uma questão complexa para um padrão de consulta complexo usando uma sequência de consultas simples, cada uma direcionada a um KB específico. Ele encontra consultas simples usando um modelo baseado em rede neural capaz de inferência coletiva sobre relações textuais em KB extraídas e relações ontológicas em KB com curadoria. Os experimentos mostram que nosso sistema proposto supera os sistemas KB-QA anteriores em conjuntos de dados de referência, ComplexWebQuestions e WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>La respuesta a preguntas basadas en el conocimiento (KB_QA) se ha centrado durante mucho tiempo en preguntas sencillas que pueden responderse desde una única fuente de conocimiento, una base de conocimientos seleccionada manualmente o extraída automáticamente. En este trabajo, buscamos responder a preguntas complejas que a menudo requieren combinar información de múltiples fuentes. Presentamos un novedoso sistema de KB-QA, Multique, que puede asignar una pregunta compleja a un patrón de consulta complejo utilizando una secuencia de consultas simples, cada una dirigida a una KB específica. Encuentra consultas simples utilizando un modelo basado en redes neuronales capaz de inferencia colectiva sobre las relaciones textuales en la base de datos extraída y las relaciones ontológicas en la base de datos seleccionada. Los experimentos muestran que nuestro sistema propuesto supera a los sistemas anteriores de KB-QA en conjuntos de datos de referencia, ComplexWebQuestions y WebQuestionSSP.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>ナレッジベースの質問に対する回答（ KB_QA ）は、単一のナレッジソース、手動でキュレーションされた質問、または自動抽出された質問から回答できる簡単な質問に長い間焦点を当ててきました。この研究では、複数の情報源からの情報を組み合わせる必要があることが多い複雑な質問に答えることに焦点を当てています。新しいKB - QAシステムMultiqueを提示します。これは、特定のKBを対象とした一連の単純なクエリを使用して、複雑な質問を複雑なクエリパターンにマッピングすることができます。抽出されたKBのテキスト関係とキュレーションされたKBのオントロジー関係を対象とした集合的推論が可能なニューラルネットワークベースのモデルを使用して、単純なクエリを見つけることができます。ベンチマークデータセット、ComplexWebQuestions、WebQuestionsSPでは、提案されているシステムがこれまでのKB - QAシステムを上回っていることが実験で示されています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>对曰:(KB_QA)久专于约,可以知源,手动谋自取之知识库以对。 吾将究其所以对杂,常须合数息。 新KB-QA系统Multice,可以一系特定KB,参以杂问。 其用神经网络也简,其取 KB 也,与选 KB 集体推理。 实验言系统在基准数集,ComplexWebQuestions与WebQuestionsSP上优于前KB-QA系统。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>ज्ञान-आधारित प्रश्न उत्तर (KB_QA) ने लंबे समय से सरल प्रश्नों पर ध्यान केंद्रित किया है जो एकल ज्ञान स्रोत, मैन्युअल रूप से क्यूरेट किए गए या स्वचालित रूप से निकाले गए KB से उत्तर दिए जा सकते हैं। इस काम में, हम जटिल प्रश्नों के उत्तर देने पर विचार करते हैं जिन्हें अक्सर कई स्रोतों से जानकारी के संयोजन की आवश्यकता होती है। हम एक उपन्यास KB-QA सिस्टम, Multique प्रस्तुत करते हैं, जो एक विशिष्ट KB पर लक्षित सरल क्वेरीज़ के अनुक्रम का उपयोग करके एक जटिल क्वेरी पैटर्न के लिए एक जटिल प्रश्न को मैप कर सकता है। यह एक तंत्रिका-नेटवर्क आधारित मॉडल का उपयोग करके सरल प्रश्नों को पाता है जो क्यूरेटेड केबी में निकाले गए केबी और ऑन्टोलॉजिकल संबंधों में पाठ्य संबंधों पर सामूहिक अनुमान लगाने में सक्षम है। प्रयोगों से पता चलता है कि हमारी प्रस्तावित प्रणाली बेंचमार्क डेटासेट, ComplexWebQuestions और WebQuestionsSP पर पिछले KB-QA सिस्टम को मात देती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Le fada an lá dhírigh freagra ceisteanna atá bunaithe ar eolas (KB_QA) ar cheisteanna simplí is féidir a fhreagairt ó fhoinse amháin eolais, ó KB a dhéantar de láimh nó ó KB a bhaintear go huathoibríoch. Sa saothar seo, féachaimid ar cheisteanna casta a fhreagairt a mbíonn gá acu le faisnéis ó fhoinsí iolracha a chomhcheangal go minic. Cuirimid córas nua KB-QA i láthair, Multique, ar féidir leis ceist chasta a mhapáil go patrún casta ceisteanna trí úsáid a bhaint as seicheamh fiosrúchán simplí gach ceann díobh dírithe ar KB ar leith. Faigheann sé fiosrúcháin shimplí ag baint úsáide as múnla néar-líonra-bhunaithe atá in ann tátail chomhchoiteann a dhéanamh ar chaidreamh téacsúil i KB asbhainte agus i gcaidreamh ontological i KB coimeádta. Léiríonn turgnaimh go sáraíonn ár gcóras atá beartaithe na córais KB-QA a bhí ann roimhe seo ar thacair thacair thacair thacair, ComplexWebQuestions agus WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η απάντηση σε ερωτήσεις βασισμένες στη γνώση έχει επικεντρωθεί εδώ και καιρό σε απλές ερωτήσεις που μπορούν να απαντηθούν από μια ενιαία πηγή γνώσης, μια μη αυτόματη επιμέλεια ή μια αυτόματα εξαγόμενη ΚΒ. Στην εργασία αυτή, εξετάζουμε την απάντηση σε πολύπλοκες ερωτήσεις που συχνά απαιτούν συνδυασμό πληροφοριών από πολλαπλές πηγές. Παρουσιάζουμε ένα νέο σύστημα ΚΒ-QA, το οποίο μπορεί να χαρτογραφήσει μια σύνθετη ερώτηση σε ένα σύνθετο μοτίβο ερωτήματος χρησιμοποιώντας μια ακολουθία απλών ερωτημάτων το καθένα στοχεύει σε μια συγκεκριμένη ΚΒ. Βρίσκει απλά ερωτήματα χρησιμοποιώντας ένα μοντέλο βασισμένο σε νευρωνικό δίκτυο ικανό να συναχθεί συλλογικά σε σχέσεις κειμένου σε εξαγόμενες ΚΒ και οντολογικές σχέσεις σε επιμελημμένες ΚΒ. Τα πειράματα δείχνουν ότι το προτεινόμενο σύστημα ξεπερνά τα προηγούμενα συστήματα ΚΒ-QA σε σύνολα δεδομένων αναφοράς, ComplexWebQuestions και WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A tudásalapú kérdések megválaszolása (KB_QA) régóta olyan egyszerű kérdésekre összpontosít, amelyekre egyetlen tudásforrásból, manuálisan kiválasztott vagy automatikusan kivont KB-ból válaszolhatunk. Ebben a munkában olyan összetett kérdésekre válaszolunk, amelyek gyakran több forrásból származó információk kombinációját igénylik. Bemutatunk egy új KB-QA rendszert, a Multique-t, amely komplex kérdéseket bonyolult lekérdezési mintához képes lekérdezni egy adott KB-ra irányuló egyszerű lekérdezések sorozatával. Egyszerű lekérdezéseket talál egy neurális hálózat alapú modell segítségével, amely képes kollektív következtetést kérni a kivont KB szövegkapcsolatokra és ontológiai kapcsolatokra a kurátorozott KB-ban. A kísérletek azt mutatják, hogy javasolt rendszerünk felülmúlja a korábbi KB-QA rendszereket a benchmark adatkészletek, a ComplexWebQuestions és a WebQuestionsSP esetében.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>La risposta alle domande basate sulla conoscenza (KB_QA) si concentra da tempo su domande semplici a cui rispondere da una singola fonte di conoscenza, da una KB curata manualmente o da una KB estratta automaticamente. In questo lavoro, guardiamo a rispondere a domande complesse che spesso richiedono la combinazione di informazioni provenienti da più fonti. Presentiamo un nuovo sistema KB-QA, Multique, che può mappare una domanda complessa a un modello di query complesso utilizzando una sequenza di query semplici, ognuna mirata a una specifica KB. Trova semplici query utilizzando un modello basato su reti neurali in grado di inferenza collettiva sulle relazioni testuali in KB estratte e relazioni ontologiche in KB curated. Gli esperimenti dimostrano che il nostro sistema proposto supera i precedenti sistemi KB-QA su set di dati benchmark, ComplexWebQuestions e WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ka>Name ამ სამუშაოში, ჩვენ დავხედავთ კომპლექსიკური კითხვების პასუხი, რომლებიც ზოგიერთად უნდა გამოყენება ინფორმაციას რამდენიმე ფორ ჩვენ პრომენტის KB-QA სისტემი, Multique, რომელიც შეუძლიათ კომპლექსი კითხვის შესახებ კომპლექსიკური სისტემის შესახებ სპექსიკური კითხვის სისტემის შესახებ, რო ის აღმოიძებნა სახითო კითხვები, რომლებიც ნეიროლური ქსელის მუშაობის მოდელის გამოყენება, რომლებიც კოლექტური შესახებ ტექსტური შესახებ გამოყენებული KB და კონ ექსპერიმენტები გამოჩვენება, რომ ჩვენი პროგრამებული სისტემი წინა KB-QA სისტემის ბენქმარკის მონაცემების, ComplexWebQuestions და WebQuestionsSP-ზე გავაკეთება.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_kk>Білім негіздеген сұрақ жауап (KB_ QA) бір білім көзінен, қолмен өзгертілген немесе автоматты түрде тарқатылатын KB көзінен жауап беруге болатын қарапайым сұрақтардың көзіне көзд Бұл жұмыс ішінде біз бірнеше көпшіліктен мәліметті біріктіру керек комплекс сұрақтарды жауап береміз. Біз KB-QA жүйесі, Multique- тің романын таңдаймыз. Бұл комплексті сұрақ үлгісіне комплексті сұрақ үлгісін көмектесе алады. Әрбір көмектесетін KB- тің қарапайым сұрақтардың Бұл КБ және КБ бағытталған онтологиялық қатынастарында жалпы мәтіндік қатынастарды көшірмелеу үлгісін қолданатын неврал желінің негіздеген үлгісін табылады. Тәжірибелер жүйеміздің алдыңғы KB- QA деректер қорлары, ComplexWebQuestions және WebQuestionsSP арқылы өткен KB- QA жүйелерін жасайды дегенді көрсетеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Atsakymai į žiniomis pagrįstus klausimus (KB_QA) jau seniai buvo sutelkti į paprastus klausimus, kuriuos galima atsakyti iš vieno žinių šaltinio, rankiniu būdu sureguliuoto arba automatiškai ištraukto KB. Šiame darbe nagrinėjame atsakymus į sudėtingus klausimus, kuriems dažnai reikia sujungti informaciją iš įvairių šaltinių. Mes pristatome naują KB-QA sistemą Multique, kuri gali paversti sudėtingą klausimą sudėtingu klausimo modeliu naudojant paprastų klausimų seką, kiekvieną nukreiptą į konkrečią KB. Ji ieško paprastų klausimų naudojant nerviniu tinklu pagrįstą model į, galintį kolektyvinę išvadą apie tekstinius santykius ekstrahuotoje KB ir ontologinius santykius kuruojamoje KB. Eksperimentai rodo, kad mūsų siūloma sistema yra didesnė už ankstesnes KB-QA sistemas, susijusias su lyginamųjų duomenų rinkiniais, kompleksiniais internetiniais klausimais ir internetiniais klausimais.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ms>Jawapan soalan berdasarkan pengetahuan (KB_QA) mempunyai fokus panjang pada soalan sederhana yang boleh dijawab dari sumber pengetahuan tunggal, dikurasi secara manual atau KB secara automatik. Dalam kerja ini, kita melihat menjawab soalan kompleks yang sering memerlukan penggabungan maklumat dari sumber berbilang. Kami perkenalkan sistem KB-QA baru, Multique, yang boleh peta soalan kompleks ke corak pertanyaan kompleks menggunakan urutan pertanyaan sederhana setiap sasaran pada KB tertentu. Name Eksperimen menunjukkan bahawa sistem kami diusulkan melampaui batas sistem KB-QA terdahulu pada set data benchmark, ComplexWebQuestions dan WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Одговорите на прашања базирани на знаење (KB_QA) долго време се фокусираат на едноставни прашања кои можат да бидат одговорени од еден извор на знаење, рачно куриран или автоматски изваден KB. Во оваа работа гледаме на одговорите на сложени прашања кои често бараат комбинација на информации од повеќе извори. Презентираме нов KB-QA систем, Мултике, кој може да го мапира комплексното прашање на комплексен образец на прашање користејќи секвенца на едноставни прашања кои секој се насочува кон конкретен KB. Наоѓа едноставни прашања со користење на модел базиран на неурална мрежа способен за колективна конференција околу текстуалните односи во извадени КБ и онтологични односи во курирани КБ. Експериментите покажуваат дека нашиот предложен систем ги надминува претходните системи на КБ-КА за податочните сети за benchmark, ComplexWebQuestions и WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mt>It-tweġiba għall-mistoqsijiet ibbażati fuq l-għarfien (KB_QA) ilha tiffoka fuq mistoqsijiet sempliċi li jistgħu jitwieġbu minn sors wieħed ta’ għarfien, KB ikkurat manwalment jew estratt awtomatikament. F’dan ix-xogħol, inħarsu lejn it-tweġibiet għal mistoqsijiet kumplessi li ta’ spiss jeħtieġu l-kombinazzjoni ta’ informazzjoni minn sorsi multipli. Aħna nippreżentaw sistema KB-QA ġdida, Multique, li tista’ timmappa mistoqsija kumplessa għal mudell kumpless ta’ mistoqsijiet bl-użu ta’ sekwenza ta’ mistoqsijiet sempliċi kull waħda mmirata lejn KB speċifiku. Hija ssib mistoqsijiet sempliċi bl-użu ta’ mudell ibbażat fuq netwerk newrali kapaċi ta’ inferenza kollettiva fuq ir-relazzjonijiet testwali f’KB estratt u relazzjonijiet ontoloġiċi f’KB ikkurat. L-esperimenti juru li s-sistema proposta tagħna tirrispetta s-sistemi KB-QA preċedenti dwar settijiet ta’ dejta ta’ parametri referenzjarji, Mistoqsijiet Komplessi u Mistoqsijiet fuq il-WebSP.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>അറിവ് അടിസ്ഥാനമായ ചോദ്യങ്ങളുടെ ഉത്തരം (കെബി ക്യൂഎ) ഒരു ജ്ഞാന സ്രോതസ്സില്‍ നിന്നും ഉത്തരം നല്‍കാന്‍ സാധിക്കുന്ന സാധ്യതയുള്ള ചോദ ഈ ജോലിയില്‍, നമ്മള്‍ ചില ചില ചോദ്യങ്ങളുടെ ഉത്തരം പറയുന്നത് നോക്കുന്നു. പല സ്രോതസ്സുകളില്‍ നിന്നും വിവരങ്ങള്‍  ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഒരു നോവല്‍ കെബി- ക്യൂഎ സിസ്റ്റത്തെ കാണിച്ചുകൊടുക്കുന്നു. അത് പ്രത്യേക ക കെബിയില്‍ നിന്നും ലക്ഷ്യമാക്കുന്ന ഒരു സാധാരണ ചോദ്യത്തി കെബിയില്‍ നിന്നും പുറത്തെടുക്കപ്പെട്ട ട ടെക്സ്കൂള്‍ ബന്ധങ്ങള്‍ക്കും മേല്‍ സാധ്യതയുള്ള ന്യൂറല്‍ നെറുല്‍ നെറുല്‍ നെറ്റോവര്‍ക്ക് അടിസ പരീക്ഷണങ്ങള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു നമ്മുടെ പ്രൊദ്ദേശിച്ച സിസ്റ്റം മുമ്പ് കെബി- ക്യൂഎ സിസ്റ്റുകള്‍ ബെന്‍ച്മാര്‍ക്ക് ഡേറ്റാ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Мэдлэгийн үндсэн асуулт хариулт (KB_QA) нь нэг мэдлэгийн эх үүсвэрээс хариулт өгөх энгийн асуултуудад урт хугацаанд анхаарлаа хандуулсан, гараар шингээгдсэн, эсвэл автоматаар нэмэгдсэн КБ-ээс хандуулсан. Энэ ажил дээр бид олон эх үүсвэрээс мэдээллийг нэгтгэх хэрэгтэй комплекс асуултуудыг харж байна. Бид KB-QA зохиолын систем, Multique-г харуулж байна. Энэ нь комплекс асуултыг КБ-д зориулагдсан бүх энгийн query-ын дарааллыг ашиглаж болно. Энэ нь мэдрэлийн сүлжээний суурилсан загварыг хэрэглэж буй энгийн квадратуудыг КБ болон КБ-ын контрологик харилцаанд хамтын харилцааны нийлбэр халдвар авч чадна. Түүнчлэл бидний санал өгөгдлийн сангууд, ComplexWebQuestions, WebQuestionsSP дээр өмнөх KB-QA системүүдийг ажилладаг гэдгийг харуулдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Odpowiedzi na pytania oparte na wiedzy (KB_QA) od dawna koncentrują się na prostych pytaniach, na które można odpowiedzieć z jednego źródła wiedzy, ręcznie kurowanej lub automatycznie ekstraktowanej KB. W niniejszej pracy przyglądamy się odpowiedzi na złożone pytania, które często wymagają łączenia informacji z wielu źródeł. Przedstawiamy nowy system KB-QA, Multique, który może odwzorować złożone pytanie do złożonego wzorca zapytań za pomocą sekwencji prostych zapytań, z których każde ukierunkowane jest na konkretną KB. Znajduje proste zapytania za pomocą modelu opartego na sieci neuronowej zdolnego do zbiorowego wnioskowania relacji tekstowych w ekstraktowanej KB oraz relacji ontologicznych w kuratorskiej KB. Eksperymenty pokazują, że nasz proponowany system przewyższa poprzednie systemy KB-QA w odniesieniu do zbiorów danych referencyjnych, ComplexWebQuestions i WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Name I dette arbeidet ser vi på å svara på komplekse spørsmål som ofte krev å kombinere informasjon frå fleire kilder. Vi presenterer eit roman KB-QA-system, Multique, som kan kartera eit kompleks spørsmønster til eit kompleks spørsmønster med ein rekkjefølgje enkle spørsmønster kvar mål på ein spesifikk KB. Det finn enkle spørsmål ved å bruka eit neuralnettverksbasert modell som kan kopla infeksjon over tekstrelasjonar i ekstrahert KB- og ontologiske relasjonar i korta KB. Eksperimentar viser at vårt foreslått systemet utfører tidlegare KB-QA-systemar på benchmarkdatasett, ComplexWebQuestions og WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Răspunsul la întrebări bazat pe cunoaștere (KB_QA) s-a concentrat mult timp pe întrebări simple care pot fi răspunse dintr-o singură sursă de cunoștințe, dintr-o KB curată manual sau extrasă automat. În această lucrare, ne uităm la răspunsul la întrebări complexe care necesită adesea combinarea informațiilor din mai multe surse. Vă prezentăm un nou sistem KB-QA, Multique, care poate mapa o întrebare complexă la un model complex de interogare folosind o secvență de interogări simple, fiecare direcționată către un anumit KB. Acesta găsește interogări simple folosind un model bazat pe rețea neurală capabil de deducere colectivă asupra relațiilor textuale în KB extrase și relațiile ontologice în KB curatate. Experimentele arată că sistemul nostru propus depășește sistemele KB-QA anterioare pe seturi de date de referință, ComplexWebQuestions și WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>Name මේ වැඩේ අපි බලන්නේ ප්‍රශ්ණ ප්‍රශ්ණ ප්‍රශ්ණ ප්‍රශ්ණ ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වගේම සාමාන අපි කතාවක් KB-QA පද්ධතියක්, Multique විශේෂ ප්‍රශ්නයක් සංසුද්ධ ප්‍රශ්නයක් පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන් විදිහට සරල ප්‍රශ්නයක්  Name පරීක්ෂණය පෙන්වන්නේ අපේ ප්‍රශ්නය කරපු පද්ධතිය බෙන්චමාර්ක් දත්ත සැට, සම්පූර්ණ වෙබ් ප්‍රශ්නය සහ Webප්‍රශ්</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sr>Odgovor na pitanju na osnovu znanja (KB_QA) dugo se fokusirao na jednostavna pitanja koja se može odgovoriti iz jednog izvora znanja, ručno izložena ili automatski izvlačena KB. U ovom poslu, gledamo na odgovore na složena pitanja koja često zahteva kombinaciju informacija iz višestrukih izvora. Predstavljamo roman KB-QA sistem, Multique, koji može mapirati kompleksno pitanje kompleksnom obrazom pitanja koristeći sekvencu jednostavnih pitanja svakog ciljanog na određenom KB-u. Nalazi se jednostavna pitanja koristeći model na osnovu neuralne mreže sposoban za kolektivnu infekciju nad tekstualnim odnosima u izvlačenim KB-om i ontološkim odnosima u zakrivenom KB-u. Eksperimenti pokazuju da naš predloženi sistem nadmašuje prethodne KB-QA sisteme na standardnim setima podataka, ComplexWebQuestions i WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>jawaabta su'aalaha aqoonta ku saleysan (KB_QA) waxay waqti dheer focus ugu leedahay su'aalo fudud oo laga jawaabi karo sourceed aqoonta oo keliya, qof gacmo u qoran ama si gaar ah loo soo saaro KB. Markaas waxan shaqada, waxaynu fiirinnaa jawaabta su'aalaha adag, kuwaas oo marar badan u baahan inay macluumaad ka soo ururiyaan sourceo badan. We present a novel KB-QA system, Multique, which can map a complex question to a complex query pattern using a sequence of simple queries each targeted at a specific KB.  Shaqooyin fudud oo isticmaalaya model ku saleysan shabakadda neural-network oo awoodi karta cudur collective ah oo ka sarraysa xiriirka dhaqanka ee ka soo baxay KB iyo xiriirka ontological ee curated KB. Imtixaanka waxaa muuqda in systemkeeni la soo jeeday ay uu soo saaray horay kamid ah KB-QA system on benchmark datasets, ComplexWebQuestions and WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Kunskapsbaserat frågesvar (KB_QA) har länge fokuserat på enkla frågor som kan besvaras från en enda kunskapskälla, en manuellt kuraterad eller en automatiskt extraherad KB. I detta arbete tittar vi på att besvara komplexa frågor som ofta kräver att man kombinerar information från flera källor. Vi presenterar ett nytt KB-QA-system, Multique, som kan kartlägga en komplex fråga till ett komplext frågemönster med hjälp av en sekvens av enkla frågor riktade till en specifik KB. Den hittar enkla frågor med hjälp av en neuralt nätverksbaserad modell som kan leda kollektiv inferens över textrelationer i extraherade KB och ontologiska relationer i kuraterade KB. Experiment visar att vårt föreslagna system överträffar tidigare KB-QA-system på benchmarkdatauppsättningar, ComplexWebQuestions och WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>علم based question replying (KB_ QA) has long focused on simple questions that can be answered from a single knowledge source, a manually curated or a automatically extracted KB. اس کام میں ہم پیچیدہ سوال کی جواب دیتے ہیں جو بہت سی سورجوں سے معلومات جمع کرنے کی ضرورت ہے۔ ہم ایک نوم KB-QA سیسٹم، Multique کو پیش کریں گے، جو ایک پیچیدہ سوال کو ایک پیچیدہ سؤال پٹرنے کے ذریعے ایک ساده سؤال کے سفارش کے مطابق مخلوط کرسکتا ہے، ہر ایک کو ایک مطابق KB میں نشان دی جاتی ہے. یہ ساده سؤال پاتا ہے کہ ایک نئورل-نیٹورک کی بنیادی موڈل کو استعمال کرتا ہے جو ٹیکسٹل رابطہ پر استعمال کر سکتا ہے کیب اور کنٹولوژیکی رابطہ کرتی ہے کیب میں. آزمائش دکھاتے ہیں کہ ہماری پیشنهاد سیستم پہلے کی KB-QA سیستموں کو بنچم مارک ڈیٹسٹ، ComplexWebQuestions اور WebQuestionsSP پر کامل کرتا ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>அறிவு அடிப்படையான கேள்வி பதில் (KB_ QA) ஒரே அறிவு மூலத்திலிருந்து, கைமுறையாக வளர்க்கப்பட்ட அல்லது தானாகவே வெளியேற்றப்பட்ட கேள்விகளை க இந்த வேலையில், நாம் சிக்கல் கேள்விகளுக்கு பதில் கூறுவதை பார்க்கிறோம். அது பெரும்பாலாகவே பல மூலங்களிலி நாம் ஒரு புதிய KB- QA அமைப்பை கொண்டு வரைகிறோம், அது ஒரு சிக்கலான கேள்வி வடிவத்திற்கு வரைபடமாகும், ஒரு சிக்கலான கேள்வி வடிவமைப்பை பயன்படுத்து It finds simple queries using a neural-network based model capable of collective inference over textual relations in extracted KB and ontological relations in curated KB.  முந்தைய KB- QA அமைப்புகள் பென்க்மார்க் தரவுத்தளத்தில், குறிப்பிட்ட வலை கேள்விகள் மற்றும் வலை கேள்விகள் SP மேல் செய்யும்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Maʼlumot asosida savol javobi (KB_QA) bir xil manba, qoʻllanmalar qoʻllanmalangan yoki avtomatik chiqarish mumkin oddiy savollariga qarang. Bu ishda, biz ko'pincha manbalar bilan ma'lumotni birlashtirish kerak murakkab savollariga javob beramiz. Biz KB- QA tizimni koʻrsatimiz, Multique, bu bir murakkab savollarni qidirish modelidagi oddiy soʻrov soʻrovlari bilan bir xil KB bilan foydalanish mumkin. Name Name</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Câu hỏi dựa trên kiến thức trả lời (KB'u QA) luôn tập trung vào những câu hỏi đơn giản có thể trả lời từ một nguồn hiểu biết đơn giản, một nhà quản lý bằng tay hoặc một KB tự động được chiết xuất. Trong công việc này, chúng tôi xem xét việc trả lời các câu hỏi phức tạp mà thường cần kết hợp thông tin từ nhiều nguồn tin. Chúng tôi giới thiệu một hệ thống KB-QA mới, đa năng, nó có thể vẽ một câu hỏi phức tạp thành một mô hình truy vấn phức tạp, sử dụng một chuỗi các truy vấn đơn giản mỗi loại nhắm vào một trình KB cụ thể. Nó tìm kiếm các câu hỏi đơn giản bằng một mô hình mạng thần kinh có khả năng phủ nhận kết cấu các mối quan hệ kết cấu trong KB đã được phân tích lại. Các thí nghiệm cho thấy hệ thống được đề xuất vượt qua hệ thống trước của KB-QA về các nhà dữ liệu chuẩn, phức tạp WebQuestS.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Отговарянето на въпроси въз основа на знанието отдавна се фокусира върху прости въпроси, на които може да се отговори от един източник на знание, ръчно подбран или автоматично извлечен КБ. В тази работа разглеждаме отговорите на сложни въпроси, които често изискват комбиниране на информация от множество източници. Представяме нова система, която може да картографира сложен въпрос към сложен модел на заявки, използвайки последователност от прости заявки, всяка насочена към конкретен КБ. Той намира прости заявки, използващи модел, базиран на невронна мрежа, способен на колективно заключение върху текстови връзки в извлечени КБ и онтологични отношения в курирани КБ. Експериментите показват, че нашата предложена система превъзхожда предишните системи за оценка на качеството на базовите бази данни, КомплексWebQuestions и WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Odgovor na pitanju na temelju znanja (KB_QA) dugo se fokusirao na jednostavna pitanja koja se može odgovoriti iz jednog izvora znanja, ručno izložena ili automatski izvlačena KB. U ovom poslu gledamo odgovore na složena pitanja koje često zahtijevaju kombinaciju informacija iz višestrukih izvora. Predstavljamo roman KB-QA sistem, Multique, koji može mapirati kompleksno pitanje kompleksnom obrascu pitanja koristeći sekvencu jednostavnih pitanja svakog ciljanog na određenom KB-u. Nalazi se jednostavna pitanja koristeći model na osnovu neuralne mreže sposoban kolektivnom infekcijom preko tekstualnih odnosa u izvlačenim KB-om i ontološkim odnosima u zaključenim KB-om. Eksperimenti pokazuju da naš predloženi sistem nadmašuje prethodne KB-QA sustave na standardnim setima podataka, ComplexWebQuestions i WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Knowledge-based question responsing (KB_QA) richt zich al lang op eenvoudige vragen die kunnen worden beantwoord vanuit één enkele kennisbron, een handmatig samengestelde of een automatisch geëxtraheerde KB. In dit werk kijken we naar het beantwoorden van complexe vragen waarbij vaak informatie uit meerdere bronnen moet worden gecombineerd. We presenteren een nieuw KB-QA-systeem, Multique, dat een complexe vraag kan toewijzen aan een complex querypatroon met behulp van een reeks eenvoudige query's die elk gericht zijn op een specifieke KB. Het vindt eenvoudige query's met behulp van een neuraal-netwerk gebaseerd model dat in staat is collectieve conclusies te trekken over tekstuele relaties in geëxtraheerde KB en ontologische relaties in gecureerde KB. Experimenten tonen aan dat ons voorgestelde systeem beter presteert dan eerdere KB-QA systemen op benchmark datasets, ComplexWebQuestions en WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Wissensbasierte Fragebeantwortung (KB_QA) konzentriert sich seit langem auf einfache Fragen, die aus einer einzigen Wissensquelle, einer manuell kuratierten oder einer automatisch extrahierten Wissensdatenbank beantwortet werden können. In dieser Arbeit beschäftigen wir uns mit der Beantwortung komplexer Fragen, bei denen häufig Informationen aus mehreren Quellen kombiniert werden müssen. Wir präsentieren ein neuartiges KB-QA-System, Multique, das eine komplexe Frage einem komplexen Abfragemuster zuordnen kann, indem eine Sequenz einfacher Abfragen verwendet wird, die jeweils auf eine bestimmte KB ausgerichtet sind. Es findet einfache Abfragen mithilfe eines neuronalen Netzwerkmodells, das in der Lage ist, kollektive Schlussfolgerungen über textuelle Beziehungen in extrahierten KB und ontologische Beziehungen in kuratierter KB zu ziehen. Experimente zeigen, dass unser vorgeschlagenes System bisherige KB-QA-Systeme auf Benchmark-Datensätzen, ComplexWebQuestions und WebQuestionsSP übertrifft.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Jawaban pertanyaan berdasarkan pengetahuan (KB_QA) telah lama fokus pada pertanyaan sederhana yang dapat dijawab dari sumber pengetahuan tunggal, dikurasi secara manual atau KB yang secara otomatis diekstraksi. Dalam pekerjaan ini, kami melihat menjawab pertanyaan kompleks yang sering membutuhkan kombinasi informasi dari berbagai sumber. Kami mempersembahkan sistem KB-QA baru, Multique, yang dapat memetakan pertanyaan kompleks ke pola pertanyaan kompleks menggunakan urutan pertanyaan sederhana masing-masing ditujukan pada KB spesifik. Hal ini menemukan pertanyaan sederhana menggunakan model berasaskan jaringan saraf yang mampu membuat kesimpulan kolektif atas hubungan tekstual dalam KB ekstraksi dan hubungan ontologi dalam KB kurasi. Eksperimen menunjukkan bahwa sistem yang diusulkan kita melampaui batas sistem KB-QA sebelumnya pada set data benchmark, ComplexWebQuestions dan WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_da>Videnbaseret spørgsmålsbesvarelse (KB_QA) har længe fokuseret på enkle spørgsmål, der kan besvares fra en enkelt videnkilde, en manuelt kurateret eller en automatisk udpakket KB. I dette arbejde ser vi på at besvare komplekse spørgsmål, som ofte kræver at kombinere oplysninger fra flere kilder. Vi præsenterer et nyt KB-QA-system, Multique, som kan kortlægge et komplekst spørgsmål til et komplekst forespørgselsmønster ved hjælp af en række enkle forespørgsler, der hver især er rettet mod en bestemt KB. Den finder enkle forespørgsler ved hjælp af en neural-netværksbaseret model, der er i stand til kollektiv inference over tekstlige relationer i ekstraherede KB og ontologiske relationer i kuraterede KB. Eksperimenter viser, at vores foreslåede system overgår tidligere KB-QA-systemer på benchmark datasæt, ComplexWebQuestions og WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_ko>지식 기반 질의응답(Knowledge-based question answering, KB -QA)은 단일 지식 소스, 수동으로 기획된 지식 라이브러리 또는 자동으로 추출된 지식 라이브러리로 대답할 수 있는 간단한 질문에 오랫동안 집중해 왔다.이 업무에서 우리는 복잡한 문제에 대답하는 데 착안하는데, 이런 문제들은 보통 여러 출처에서 온 정보를 결합시켜야 한다.우리는 일련의 간단한 검색을 사용하여 복잡한 문제를 복잡한 검색 모델에 비추고 모든 검색이 특정한 KB를 대상으로 하는 새로운 KB-QA 시스템 Multique를 제시했다.이는 신경 네트워크를 바탕으로 하는 모델을 이용하여 간단한 조회를 발견하고 이 모델은 추출된 지식 라이브러리의 텍스트 관계와 기획된 지식 라이브러리의 본체 관계를 집단적으로 추리할 수 있다.실험에 의하면 우리가 제시한 시스템은 기준 데이터 집합,ComplexWebQuestions와WebQuestions SP에서의 성능이 이전의 KB-QA 시스템보다 우수하다는 것을 알 수 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_af>Die kennis-gebaseerde vraag antwoord (KB_QA) het lank fokus op eenvoudige vrae wat kan wees geantwoord van 'n enkele kennis bron, 'n Hand uitgevoer of 'n automaties uitgevoer Kb. In hierdie werk kyk ons na antwoord van komplekse vrae wat dikwels nodig om inligting uit veelvuldige bronne te kombinerer. Ons stel 'n roman KB- QA stelsel, Multique, wat kan kaart 'n kompleks vraag na' n kompleks navraag patroon deur te gebruik 'n volgorde van eenvoudige navraag elke doel op' n spesifieke Kb. Dit vind eenvoudige vrae gebruik van 'n neural- netwerk gebaseerde model wat moontlik is om kolektiewe inferensie oor tekstuele relasies in uitgevoer Kb en ontologiese relasies in gekruisigde Kb. Name Eksperimente wys dat ons voorgestelde stelsel uitvoer vorige KB- QA stelsels op benchmark datastelle, ComplexWebVrades en WebVrades SP.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Knowledge-based question answering (KB_QA) has long focused on simple questions that can be answered from a single knowledge source, a manually curated or an automatically extracted KB.  Në këtë punë, ne shohim përgjigjen për pyetje komplekse që shpesh kërkojnë kombinimin e informacionit nga burime të shumta. Ne paraqesim një sistem të ri KB-QA, Multique, i cili mund të hartojë një pyetje komplekse në një modelin kompleks pyetjeje duke përdorur një sekuencë pyetjesh të thjeshta secili të synuar në një KB të caktuar. It finds simple queries using a neural-network based model capable of collective inference over textual relations in extracted KB and ontological relations in curated KB.  Eksperimentet tregojnë se sistemi ynë i propozuar ekziston më shumë se sistemet e mëparshëm KB-QA në bazat e të dhënave të referuara, ComplexWebQuestions dhe WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_fa>پاسخ سوال بر اساس علم (KB_ QA) به سوال ساده‌ها تمرکز می‌کند که می‌توانند از یک منبع دانش تنها جواب داده شود، یک کوتاه‌ی دستی یا یک کوتاه‌ی خودکار خارج شوند. در این کار، ما به جواب سوالات پیچیده نگاه می کنیم که اغلب نیاز به ترکیب اطلاعات از منبع های متعدد است. ما یک سیستم رمانی KB-QA، Multique را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که می‌تواند سوال پیچیده را به یک الگوی پرسیدن پیچیده با استفاده از دسته‌های سوال ساده هر کدام را در یک کیب خاص هدف می‌دهد. این سؤال ساده را با استفاده از یک مدل بر پایه شبکه عصبی قادر به آلودگی مجموعه بر روی رابطه‌های متن در KB و رابطه‌های متن‌لوژیک در KB متصل می‌شود. تجربه‌ها نشان می‌دهند که سیستم پیشنهاد ما سیستم‌های قبلی KB-QA را بر مجموعه‌های داده‌های ابزار، سوال‌های کامل وب و WebQuestionsSP انجام می‌دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_am>የእውቀት ጥያቄ መልስ (KB_QA) በአንድ እውቀት ምንጭ፣ በእጅነት የተመሳሳይ ወይም በራሳቸው የተወለደውን KB በሚመልሱ ቀላል ጥያቄዎችን አስጠንክሮአል፡፡ በዚህ ሥራ፣ ብዙ ጊዜ ከብዙ ምንጮች መረጃዎችን ማሰናከል የሚፈልገውን ትክክለኛ ጥያቄዎችን በመመልስ እናየዋለን፡፡ የKB-QA ስርዓት፣ ብዙክ፣ የጥያቄ ጥያቄን ለመቀላቀል ትክክለኛ የጥያቄ ጥያቄ ማሳመር ይችላል፡፡ ጥያቄዎች በKB እና በኦንቶሎጂ ግንኙነት ላይ የተሰበሰቡ የጽሑፍ ግንኙነትን በመጠቀም የሚችሉትን የናውሬል-መረብ-መሠረት ሞዴል ይታገኛል፡፡ ፈተናዎች የሞከሩ ስርዓታችን የቀድሞውን KB-QA ስርዓቶች በbenchmark datasets፣ ComplexWebQuestions እና WebQueonsSP ላይ እንዲያሳየው ያሳያል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sw>Knowledge-based question answering (KB_QA) has long focused on simple questions that can be answered from a single knowledge source, a manually curated or an automatically extracted KB.  Katika kazi hii, tunaangalia kujibu maswali ya tatizo ambayo mara nyingi inahitaji kuunganisha taarifa kutoka vyanzo vingi. Tunaweza kuweka mfumo wa riwaya wa KB-QA, Multique, ambao unaweza ramani swali tata kwa mtindo wa utafiti mgumu kwa kutumia mfululizo wa maswali rahisi kila linalolengwa kwenye KB maalum. Inapatia maswali rahisi kwa kutumia muundo wa mtandao wa neurali unaoweza kuwa na uwezo wa mgonjwa mkusanyiko juu ya mahusiano ya msingi katika KB na mahusiano ya kiutaalamu katika KB. Majaribio yanaonyesha kwamba mfumo wetu unapendekezwa unafanya mifumo ya zamani ya KB-QA kwenye seti za benchmark, Maswali ya komplexWeb na Questions SP.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_hy>Գիտությամբ հիմնված հարցերի պատասխանը (KO_QA) երկար ժամանակ կենտրոնացված է պարզ հարցերի վրա, որոնք կարող են պատասխանվել մեկ գիտելիքի աղբյուրից, ձեռքով կառավարվող կամ ինքնաբերաբար հանված ԿԲ-ից: Այս աշխատանքի ընթացքում մենք նայում ենք բարդ հարցերին պատասխանելուն, որոնք հաճախ պահանջում են բազմաթիվ աղբյուրներից տեղեկատվություն համադրելու: We present a novel KB-QA system, Multique, which can map a complex question to a complex query pattern using a sequence of simple queries each targeted at a specific KB.  Այն գտնում է պարզ հարցեր, որոնք օգտագործում են նյարդային ցանցի հիմնված մոդել, որը կարողանում է հավաքական եզրակացություն ունենալ տեքստային հարաբերությունների վերաբերյալ ստացված ԿԲ-ում և կորտերացված ԿԲ-ում գտնվո Experiments show that our proposed system outperforms previous KB-QA systems on benchmark datasets, ComplexWebQuestions and WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_tr>Bilim-tabanly soraglaryň jogapy Bu işde biz karmaşık soraglaryň jogabyna seredýäris. Köplenç birnäçe çeşmeden malümaty birleştirmek gerek. Biz KB-QA sistemi, Multique, bir roman görkezip soragy karmaşık bir sorag nusgasyna görkezip bileris, her kişi spesifik bir KB'de hedeflenen basit soraglaryň dizini ullanýar. Bu sistemden çykyş KB we ontolojik baglaýyşlarda çykyş edilen tekstual baglaýyşlaryň üstünde toplam hasaplanjak üçin nural-a ýdan tabanly nural netijesi ullanýan soraglary tapýar. Testler biziň teklip eden sistemimiziň benchmark veri setirlerinde, ComplexWebSoraglaryň we WebSoraglaryň SP üstine çykýandygyny görkezýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_bs>Odgovor na pitanju na temelju znanja (KB_QA) dugo se fokusirao na jednostavna pitanja koje se mogu odgovoriti iz jednog izvora znanja, ručno iskrivenog ili automatski izvlačenog KB-a. U ovom poslu gledamo odgovore na složena pitanja koje često zahtijevaju kombinaciju informacija iz višestrukih izvora. Predstavljamo roman KB-QA sistem, Multique, koji može mapirati kompleksno pitanje kompleksnom obrazom pitanja koristeći sekvencu jednostavnih pitanja svakog ciljanog na određenom KB-u. Nalazi se jednostavna pitanja koristeći model na osnovu neuralne mreže sposoban za kolektivnu infekciju nad tekstualnim odnosima u izvlačenim KB-om i ontološkim odnosima u zakrivenom KB-u. Eksperimenti pokazuju da naš predloženi sistem nadmašuje prethodne KB-QA sisteme na standardnim setima podataka, ComplexWebQuestions i WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>La resposta a preguntes basades en el coneixement (KB_QA) s'ha centrat molt temps en preguntes senzilles que es poden respondre d'una sola font de coneixement, un KB curat manualment o extraït automàticament. En aquest treball, mirem respondre a preguntes complexes que sovint requereixen combinar informació de múltiples fonts. We present a novel KB-QA system, Multique, which can map a complex question to a complex query pattern using a sequence of simple queries each targeted at a specific KB.  It finds simple queries using a neural-network based model capable of collective inference over textual relations in extracted KB and ontological relations in curated KB.  Experiments show that our proposed system outperforms previous KB-QA systems on benchmark datasets, ComplexWebQuestions and WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_az>Bilim-tabanlńĪ sual cevapńĪ (KB_QA) t…ôk bilgi m…ônb…ôsind…ôn cavab ver…ô bil…ôc…ôk basit suallara √ßox uzun zaman fokus edildi, …ôlli t…ômizl…ôn…ôn v…ô ya avtomatik √ßńĪxarńĪlan KB. Bu iŇüd…ô √ßoxlu m…ônb…ôl…ôrd…ôn m…ôlumatlarńĪ birl…ôŇüdirm…ôk lazńĪm olan kompleks suallara cavab veririk. Biz yeni KB-QA sistemi, Multique'i t…ôŇükil edirik ki, bu kompleks bir soruŇüu kompleks bir soruŇüma modelini h…ôr…ôk…ôt ed…ô bil…ôr ki, h…ôr k…ôsin m√ľ…ôyy…ôn bir KB-d…ô t…ôŇükil edilmiŇü basit soruŇüu se√ßm…ôsini istifad…ô edir. Bu, KB-d…ôn √ßńĪxarńĪlmńĪŇü v…ô ontolojik …ôlaq…ôl…ôrind…ô qovulmuŇü KB-d…ôn birl…ôŇüdir…ô bil…ôn bir n√∂ral-a ńü modeli istifad…ô ed…ôr…ôk basit soruŇümalar tapńĪr. T…ôr…ôb…ôl…ôr bizim t…ôblińü etdiyimiz sistemimiz ke√ßmiŇü KB-QA sisteml…ôrinin benchmark veri qurularńĪ, ComplexWebQuestions v…ô WebQuestionsSP'da istifad…ô edir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_cs>Odpověď na otázky založené na znalostech (KB_QA) se dlouho zaměřuje na jednoduché otázky, na které lze odpovědět z jediného zdroje znalostí, ručně kurátované nebo automaticky extrahované KB. V této práci se zabýváme zodpovězením složitých otázek, které často vyžadují kombinaci informací z více zdrojů. Představujeme nový KB-QA systém Multique, který dokáže mapovat komplexní otázku do komplexního dotazového vzoru pomocí sekvence jednoduchých dotazů zaměřených na konkrétní KB. Najde jednoduché dotazy s využitím modelu založeného na neuronové síti schopného kolektivně odvozovat textové vztahy v extrahované KB a ontologické vztahy v kurátorované KB. Experimenty ukazují, že náš navrhovaný systém překonává předchozí KB-QA systémy na benchmarkových datových sadách, ComplexWebQuestions a WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Teadmistepõhine küsimustele vastamine (KB_QA) on juba ammu keskendunud lihtsatele küsimustele, millele saab vastata ühest teadmisallikast, käsitsi kureeritud või automaatselt ekstraheeritud KB-st. Käesolevas töös vaadeldakse keerukatele küsimustele vastamist, mis sageli nõuavad mitmest allikast pärit teabe kombineerimist. Esitleme uudset KB-QA süsteemi Multique, mis suudab kaardistada keerulise küsimuse keerulise päringumustriga, kasutades lihtsate päringute jada, mis on suunatud konkreetsele KB-le. See leiab lihtsaid päringuid, kasutades neurovõrgul põhinevat mudelit, mis võimaldab kollektiivselt järeldada tekstisuhteid ekstraheeritud KB-s ja ontoloogilisi suhteid kureeritud KB-s. Eksperimentid näitavad, et meie kavandatud süsteem ületab varasemaid KB-QA süsteeme võrdlusandmekogumite, ComplexWebQuestions ja WebQuestionsSP puhul.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bn>জ্ঞান ভিত্তিক প্রশ্নের উত্তর (কেবি_কিউএ) দীর্ঘদিন ধরে সাধারণ প্রশ্নের উপর মনোযোগ দিয়েছে যা একটি জ্ঞান উৎস থেকে উত্তর দিতে পারে, একটি হাতি In this work, we look at answering complex questions which often require combining information from multiple sources.  We present a novel KB-QA system, Multique, which can map a complex question to a complex query pattern using a sequence of simple queries each targeted at a specific KB.  এটি একটি নিউরেল-নেটওয়ার্ক ভিত্তিক মডেল ব্যবহার করে সাধারণ প্রশ্ন খুঁজে পায় যা কেবির বের করে যাওয়ার ক্ষেত্রে টেক্সুয়াল সম্পর্কের উপর সংক্ পরীক্ষাগুলো দেখাচ্ছে যে আমাদের প্রস্তাবিত সিস্টেম বেঞ্চার্ক ডাটাসেট, কমপ্লেক্সওয়েব প্রশ্ন এবং ওয়েব প্রশ্ন এসপি</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_fi>Knowledge based quest answer (KB_QA) on pitkään keskittynyt yksinkertaisiin kysymyksiin, joihin voidaan vastata yhdestä tietolähteestä, manuaalisesti kuratoidusta tai automaattisesti poimitusta KB:stä. Tässä työssä tarkastellaan monimutkaisiin kysymyksiin vastaamista, jotka usein edellyttävät tiedon yhdistämistä useista lähteistä. Esittelemme uuden KB-QA-järjestelmän, Multique, joka pystyy kartoittamaan monimutkaisen kysymyksen monimutkaiseen kyselymalliin käyttämällä yksinkertaisten kyselyjen sarjaa, joista jokainen on kohdistettu tiettyyn KB:hen. Se löytää yksinkertaisia kyselyjä käyttämällä neuroverkkopohjaista mallia, joka kykenee kollektiiviseen päättelyyn tekstuaalisista suhteista poimitussa KB:ssä ja ontologisista suhteista kuratoidussa KB:ssä. Kokeet osoittavat, että ehdotettu järjestelmämme on parempi kuin aiemmat KB-QA-järjestelmät vertailuaineistoissa, ComplexWebQuestions- ja WebQuestionsSP-kyselyissä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_he>תשובה על שאלות מבוססת על ידע (KB_ QA) ממוקדת ארוכה על שאלות פשוטות שאפשר לענות ממקור ידע אחד, קיבלה מיד או קיבלה אוטומטית. בעבודה הזו, אנו מסתכלים על עונות על שאלות מורכבות שדורשות לעתים קרובות שילוב מידע ממקורים רבים. אנחנו מציגים מערכת KB-QA חדשה, Multique, שיכולה למפות שאלה מורכבת לתבנית שאלות מורכבת בשימוש רצף של שאלות פשוטות כל אחד ממוקד ב KB מסויימת. הוא מוצא שאלות פשוטות באמצעות מודל מבוסס על רשת עצבית מסוגל למסקנה קולקטיבית על מערכות יחסים טקסטאליות בקי.בי. ניסויים מראים שהמערכת המוצעת שלנו מתגברת על מערכות KB-QA קודמות על קבוצות נתונים רמזי, WebQuestions Complexו ו WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Odgovarjanje na vprašanja na podlagi znanja (KB_QA) se že dolgo osredotoča na preprosta vprašanja, na katera je mogoče odgovoriti iz enega vira znanja, ročno izbranega ali samodejno izvlečenega KB. V tem delu obravnavamo odgovore na kompleksna vprašanja, ki pogosto zahtevajo kombiniranje informacij iz več virov. Predstavljamo nov sistem KB-QA Multique, ki lahko kompleksno vprašanje preslika v kompleksni vzorec poizvedbe z uporabo zaporedja preprostih poizvedb, ki so usmerjene na določen KB. Poišče preproste poizvedbe z uporabo nevronsko-omrežnega modela, ki je sposoben kolektivnega sklepanja o besedilnih relacijah v ekstrahirani KB in ontoloških relacijah v kurirani KB. Eksperimenti kažejo, da naš predlagani sistem presega prejšnje sisteme KB-QA pri referenčnih naborih podatkov, ComplexWebQuestions in WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Jami'ar tambayar da aka ƙayyade wajen sani (KB_QA) ya yi zura ido a kan tambayar su masu sauƙi, da za'a iya karɓa daga source guda, da wani tsarin da hannayen aka nuna ko kuma an nuna KB farat ɗaya. Daga wannan aikin, Munã dũbi zuwa mu karɓa wa masu tambayi masu husũma da wasu mutane da ke buƙata da haɗuwa da information daga sourcen wasu. Tuna halatar da wata matsayi na KB-QA, Multque, wanda zai iya karta wata maswali mai tsanani zuwa wani motsi na tambayi masu husu da amfani da wani sauri na sakan tambayi masu sauƙi da aka ƙayyade kowace KB na ƙayyade. Yana sãmu tambayi masu sauƙi da amfani da misãlan-tarayya na neural wanda ke iya iya iya iya samar da aikin haɗi wa matsayi masu cikin masu haɗi na KB da haɗi na ontologi cikin kured KB. KCharselect unicode block name</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>དབྱིན་ཡུལ་དང་གཞི་རྟེན་པའི་འདྲི་ཞིབ་ལན་པར(KB_QA)སླེབས་ཀྱི་འདྲི་ཚིག་འདིས་རང་འགུལ་གྱིས་ཐུབ་པའི་སྐད་འགན་སྤྲོད་ཡོད ང་ཚོས་ཀྱི་ལས་ཀ་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་མཐུན་སྣུམ་གྱི་གནད་དོན་དག་ཕྱོགས་ལ་མཐུན་དགོས་པ་ཡིན། ང་ཚོས་དུས་གཏམ་གླིང་གི་KB-QA་མ་ལག་ཆེན་པོ་ཞིག་འཆར་འདོད་པ་དེ་གིས་ཆ་རླུང་བའི་དྲི་ཚིག་ཅིག་སྒྲིག་འཛིན་གྱི་ཆོས་ཉིད་ཅི དེ་ནི་ཀློག་སྟངས་ལས་དབྱིབས་ཡོད་པའི་མཐུན་སྣེ་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་རྣམ་པ་ཞིག་ལ་སྤྱོད་པའི་སྔོན་སྒྲིག་དྲ་བ་དང་མཐུན་སྒྲིག Experiments show that our proposed system outperforms previous KB-QA systems on benchmark datasets, ComplexWebQuestions and WebQuestionsSP.</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_jv>Punika-akèh sing saben gambar ngganti Nang-Worksi iki, awake dhewe luwih-luwih cecaturan sing komplikasi sing njuk kesempatan informasi nyimpen nang sampek uga. Kita menehi ing nyumbal kb-qA sistem, Multique, sing iso nggambar sistem sing komplikasi layar kanggo kelas pangguna sing sampeyan seng sumelan dhéwé sistem sing sampeyan sampeyan kanggo kowé nggawe sistem sing sampeyan banget nggo kebutuhan MB sing apik. FindOK Name</abstract_jv>
      </paper>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Towards Reversal-Based Textual Data Augmentation for NLI Problems with Opposable Classes<fixed-case>NLI</fixed-case> Problems with Opposable Classes</title>
      <author><first>Alexey</first><last>Tarasov</last></author>
      <pages>11–19</pages>
      <abstract>Data augmentation methods are commonly used in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_vision">computer vision</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech">speech</a>. However, in domains dealing with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_(literary_theory)">textual data</a>, such techniques are not that common. Most of the existing methods rely on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rephrasing">rephrasing</a>, i.e. new sentences are generated by changing a source sentence, preserving its meaning. We argue that in tasks with opposable classes (such as Positive and Negative in sentiment analysis), it might be beneficial to also invert the source sentence, reversing its meaning, to generate examples of the opposing class. Methods that use somewhat similar intuition exist in the space of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adversarial_learning">adversarial learning</a>, but are not always applicable to text classification (in our experiments, some of them were even detrimental to the resulting classifier accuracy). We propose and evaluate two reversal-based methods on an NLI task of recognising a type of a simple logical expression from its description in plain-text form. After gathering a dataset on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MTurk">MTurk</a>, we show that a simple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuristic">heuristic</a> using a notion of negating the main verb has a potential not only on its own, but that it can also boost existing state-of-the-art rephrasing-based approaches.</abstract>
      <url hash="888880c6">2020.nli-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nli-1.2</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929795" />
      <bibkey>tarasov-2020-towards</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>