<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.sltu">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Joint Workshop on Spoken Language Technologies for Under-resourced languages (SLTU) and Collaboration and Computing for Under-Resourced Languages (CCURL)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Dorothee</first><last>Beermann</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Laurent</first><last>Besacier</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sakriani</first><last>Sakti</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Claudia</first><last>Soria</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-35-1</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="f2d4a780">2020.sltu-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sltu-2020-joint</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Open-Source High Quality Speech Datasets for Basque, Catalan and Galician<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>asque, <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>atalan and <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>alician</title>
      <author><first>Oddur</first><last>Kjartansson</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexander</first><last>Gutkin</last></author>
      <author><first>Alena</first><last>Butryna</last></author>
      <author><first>Isin</first><last>Demirsahin</last></author>
      <author><first>Clara</first><last>Rivera</last></author>
      <pages>21–27</pages>
      <abstract>This paper introduces new open speech datasets for three of the languages of Spain : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basque_language">Basque</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Catalan_language">Catalan</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galician_language">Galician</a>. Catalan is furthermore the official language of the Principality of Andorra. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> consist of high-quality multi-speaker recordings of the three languages along with the associated transcriptions. The resulting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpora</a> include over 33 hours of crowd-sourced recordings of 132 male and female native speakers. The recording scripts also include material for elicitation of global and local place names, personal and business names. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> are released under a permissive license and are available for free download for commercial, academic and personal use. The high-quality annotated speech datasets described in this paper can be used to, among other things, build <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_synthesis">text-to-speech systems</a>, serve as adaptation data in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">automatic speech recognition</a> and provide useful phonetic and phonological insights in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corpus_linguistics">corpus linguistics</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="7c050393">2020.sltu-1.3</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>kjartansson-etal-2020-open</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Morphological Disambiguation of South Smi with FSTs and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network">Neural Networks</a><fixed-case>S</fixed-case>outh <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>ámi with <fixed-case>FST</fixed-case>s and Neural Networks</title>
      <author><first>Mika</first><last>Hämäläinen</last></author>
      <author><first>Linda</first><last>Wiechetek</last></author>
      <pages>36–40</pages>
      <abstract>We present a method for conducting morphological disambiguation for South Smi, which is an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">endangered language</a>. Our method uses an FST-based morphological analyzer to produce an ambiguous set of morphological readings for each word in a sentence. These readings are disambiguated with a Bi-RNN model trained on the related North Smi UD Treebank and some synthetically generated South Smi data. The disambiguation is done on the level of morphological tags ignoring word forms and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lemma_(morphology)">lemmas</a> ; this makes it possible to use North Smi training data for South Smi without the need for a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bilingual_dictionary">bilingual dictionary</a> or aligned word embeddings. Our approach requires only minimal resources for South Smi, which makes it usable and applicable in the contexts of any other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">endangered language</a> as well.</abstract>
      <url hash="f80e78b8">2020.sltu-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>hamalainen-wiechetek-2020-morphological</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Neural Text-to-Speech Synthesis for an Under-Resourced Language in a Diglossic Environment : the Case of Gascon Occitan<fixed-case>G</fixed-case>ascon <fixed-case>O</fixed-case>ccitan</title>
      <author><first>Ander</first><last>Corral</last></author>
      <author><first>Igor</first><last>Leturia</last></author>
      <author><first>Aure</first><last>Séguier</last></author>
      <author><first>Michäel</first><last>Barret</last></author>
      <author><first>Benaset</first><last>Dazéas</last></author>
      <author><first>Philippe</first><last>Boula de Mareüil</last></author>
      <author><first>Nicolas</first><last>Quint</last></author>
      <pages>53–60</pages>
      <abstract>Occitan is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minority_language">minority language</a> spoken in Southern France, some Alpine Valleys of Italy, and the Val d’Aran in Spain, which only very recently started developing language and speech technologies. This paper describes the first project for designing a Text-to-Speech synthesis system for one of its main <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gascon_language">regional varieties</a>, namely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gascon_language">Gascon</a>. We used a state-of-the-art deep neural network approach, the Tacotron2-WaveGlow system. However, we faced two additional difficulties or challenges : on the one hand, we wanted to test if it was possible to obtain good quality results with fewer recording hours than is usually reported for such systems ; on the other hand, we needed to achieve a standard, non-Occitan pronunciation of French proper names, therefore we needed to record French words and test phoneme-based approaches. The evaluation carried out over the various developed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_development_process">approaches</a> shows promising results with near production-ready quality. It has also allowed us to detect the phenomena for which some flaws or fall of quality occur, pointing at the direction of future work to improve the quality of the actual system and for new systems for other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variety_(linguistics)">language varieties</a> and voices.</abstract>
      <url hash="51050726">2020.sltu-1.8</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>corral-etal-2020-neural</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Poio Text Prediction : Lessons on the Development and Sustainability of LTs for Endangered Languages<fixed-case>LT</fixed-case>s for Endangered Languages</title>
      <author><first>Gema</first><last>Zamora Fernández</last></author>
      <author><first>Vera</first><last>Ferreira</last></author>
      <author><first>Pedro</first><last>Manha</last></author>
      <pages>106–110</pages>
      <abstract>2019, the International Year of Indigenous Languages (IYIL), marked a crucial milestone for a diverse community united by a strong sense of urgency. In this presentation, we evaluate the impact of IYIL’s outcomes in the development of LTs for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">endangered languages</a>. We give a brief description of the field of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_documentation">Language Documentation</a>, whose experts have led the research and data collection efforts surrounding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">endangered languages</a> for the past 30 years. We introduce the work of the Interdisciplinary Centre for Social and Language Documentation and we look at Poio as an example of an LT developed specifically with speakers of endangered languages in mind. This example illustrates how the deeper systemic causes of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">language endangerment</a> are reflected in the development of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_proficiency">LTs</a>. Additionally, we share some of the strategic decisions that have led the development of this project. Finally, we advocate the importance of bridging the divide between research and activism, pushing for the inclusion of threatened languages in the world of LTs, and doing so in close collaboration with the speaker community.</abstract>
      <url hash="9a0d1bde">2020.sltu-1.14</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>zamora-fernandez-etal-2020-poio</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Scaling Language Data Import / Export with a Data Transformer Interface</title>
      <author><first>Nicholas</first><last>Buckeridge</last></author>
      <author><first>Ben</first><last>Foley</last></author>
      <pages>121–125</pages>
      <abstract>This paper focuses on the technical improvement of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elpis">Elpis</a>, a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_technology">language technology</a> which assists people in the process of transcription, particularly for low-resource language documentation situations. To provide better support for the diversity of file formats encountered by people working to document the world’s languages, a Data Transformer interface has been developed to abstract the complexities of designing individual data import scripts. This work took place as part of a larger project of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_quality">code quality improvement</a> and the publication of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template_processor">template code</a> that can be used for development of other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Programming_language">language technologies</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="007f0046">2020.sltu-1.16</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>buckeridge-foley-2020-scaling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Natural Language Processing Chains Inside a Cross-lingual Event-Centric Knowledge Pipeline for European Union Under-resourced Languages<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>uropean <fixed-case>U</fixed-case>nion Under-resourced Languages</title>
      <author><first>Diego</first><last>Alves</last></author>
      <author><first>Gaurish</first><last>Thakkar</last></author>
      <author><first>Marko</first><last>Tadić</last></author>
      <pages>153–158</pages>
      <abstract>This article presents the strategy for developing a platform containing Language Processing Chains for European Union languages, consisting of Tokenization to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">Parsing</a>, also including Named Entity recognition and with addition of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">Sentiment Analysis</a>. These chains are part of the first step of an event-centric knowledge processing pipeline whose aim is to process multilingual media information about major events that can cause an impact in Europe and the rest of the world. Due to the differences in terms of availability of language resources for each language, we have built this strategy in three steps, starting with processing chains for the well-resourced languages and finishing with the development of new modules for the under-resourced ones. In order to classify all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Languages_of_the_European_Union">European Union official languages</a> in terms of resources, we have analysed the size of annotated corpora as well as the existence of pre-trained models in mainstream Language Processing tools, and we have combined this information with the proposed classification published at META-NET whitepaper series.</abstract>
      <url hash="c953eb1b">2020.sltu-1.21</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>alves-etal-2020-natural</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>Acoustic-Phonetic Approach for ASR of Less Resourced Languages Using Monolingual and Cross-Lingual Information<fixed-case>ASR</fixed-case> of Less Resourced Languages Using Monolingual and Cross-Lingual Information</title>
      <author><first>Shweta</first><last>Bansal</last></author>
      <pages>167–171</pages>
      <abstract>The exploration of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_processing">speech processing</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endangered_language">endangered languages</a> has substantially increased in the past epoch of time. In this paper, we present the acoustic-phonetic approach for automatic speech recognition (ASR) using monolingual and cross-lingual information with application to under-resourced Indian languages, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Punjabi_language">Punjabi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nepali_language">Nepali</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a>. The challenging task while developing the ASR was the collection of the acoustic corpus for under-resourced languages. We have described here, in brief, the strategies used for designing the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> and also highlighted the issues pertaining while collecting data for these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">languages</a>. The bootstrap GMM-UBM based approach is used, which integrates pronunciation lexicon, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language model</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acoustic_phonetics">acoustic-phonetic model</a>. Mel Frequency Cepstral Coefficients were used for extracting the acoustic signal features for training in monolingual and cross-lingual settings. The experimental result shows the overall performance of ASR for cross-lingual and monolingual. The phone substitution plays a key role in the cross-lingual as well as monolingual recognition. The result obtained by cross-lingual recognition compared with other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline system</a> and it has been found that the performance of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">recognition system</a> is based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phoneme">phonemic units</a>. The recognition rate of cross-lingual generally declines as compared with the monolingual.</abstract>
      <url hash="7fa62cee">2020.sltu-1.23</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>bansal-2020-acoustic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="25">
      <title>A Sentiment Analysis Dataset for Code-Mixed Malayalam-English<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>alayalam-<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish</title>
      <author><first>Bharathi Raja</first><last>Chakravarthi</last></author>
      <author><first>Navya</first><last>Jose</last></author>
      <author><first>Shardul</first><last>Suryawanshi</last></author>
      <author><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Sherly</last></author>
      <author><first>John Philip</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <pages>177–184</pages>
      <abstract>There is an increasing demand for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> of text from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a> which are mostly code-mixed. Systems trained on monolingual data fail for code-mixed data due to the complexity of mixing at different levels of the text. However, very few resources are available for code-mixed data to create <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a> specific for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a>. Although much research in multilingual and cross-lingual sentiment analysis has used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semi-supervised_learning">semi-supervised or unsupervised methods</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supervised_learning">supervised methods</a> still performs better. Only a few datasets for popular languages such as English-Spanish, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language_in_India">English-Hindi</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Chinese">English-Chinese</a> are available. There are no resources available for Malayalam-English code-mixed data. This paper presents a new gold standard corpus for sentiment analysis of code-mixed text in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malayalam">Malayalam-English</a> annotated by voluntary annotators. This gold standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> obtained a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krippendorff’s_alpha">Krippendorff’s alpha</a> above 0.8 for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>. We use this new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> to provide the benchmark for sentiment analysis in Malayalam-English code-mixed texts.</abstract>
      <url hash="59bc1465">2020.sltu-1.25</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>chakravarthi-etal-2020-sentiment</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/bharathichezhiyan/MalayalamMixSentiment" additional="false">bharathichezhiyan/MalayalamMixSentiment</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/malayalammixsentiment">MalayalamMixSentiment</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Macsen : A Voice Assistant for Speakers of a Lesser Resourced Language<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>acsen: A Voice Assistant for Speakers of a Lesser Resourced Language</title>
      <author><first>Dewi</first><last>Jones</last></author>
      <pages>194–201</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports on the development of a voice assistant mobile app for speakers of a lesser resourced language   Welsh. An assistant with a smaller set of effective but useful skills is both desirable and urgent for the wider Welsh speaking community. Descriptions of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_app">app</a>’s skills, architecture, design decisions and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_interface">user interface</a> is provided before elaborating on the most recent research and activities in open source speech technology for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welsh_language">Welsh</a>. The paper reports on the progress to date on crowdsourcing Welsh speech data in Mozilla Common Voice and of its suitability for training Mozilla’s DeepSpeech speech recognition for a voice assistant application according to conventional and transfer learning methods. We demonstrate that with smaller datasets of speech data, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">transfer learning</a> and a domain specific language model, acceptable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">speech recognition</a> is achievable that facilitates, as confirmed by beta users, a practical and useful voice assistant for Welsh speakers. We hope that this work informs and serves as a model to researchers and developers in other lesser-resourced linguistic communities and helps bring into being voice assistant apps for their languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="21215a5f">2020.sltu-1.27</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>jones-2020-macsen</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/techiaith/docker-deepspeech-cy" additional="true">techiaith/docker-deepspeech-cy</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="29">
      <title>Gender Detection from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_voice">Human Voice</a> Using Tensor Analysis</title>
      <author><first>Prasanta</first><last>Roy</last></author>
      <author><first>Parabattina</first><last>Bhagath</last></author>
      <author><first>Pradip</first><last>Das</last></author>
      <pages>211–217</pages>
      <abstract>Speech-based communication is one of the most preferred modes of communication for humans. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_voice">human voice</a> contains several important information and clues that help in interpreting the voice message. The gender of the speaker can be accurately guessed by a person based on the received voice of a speaker. The knowledge of the speaker’s gender can be a great aid to design accurate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">speech recognition systems</a>. GMM based classifier is a popular choice used for gender detection. In this paper, we propose a Tensor-based approach for detecting the gender of a speaker and discuss its implementation details for low resourceful languages. Experiments were conducted using the TIMIT and SHRUTI dataset. An average gender detection accuracy of 91 % is recorded. Analysis of the results with the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> is presented in this paper.</abstract>
      <url hash="d708a748">2020.sltu-1.29</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>roy-etal-2020-gender</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="30">
      <title>Data-Driven Parametric Text Normalization : Rapidly Scaling Finite-State Transduction Verbalizers to New Languages</title>
      <author><first>Sandy</first><last>Ritchie</last></author>
      <author><first>Eoin</first><last>Mahon</last></author>
      <author><first>Kim</first><last>Heiligenstein</last></author>
      <author><first>Nikos</first><last>Bampounis</last></author>
      <author><first>Daan</first><last>van Esch</last></author>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Schallhart</last></author>
      <author><first>Jonas</first><last>Mortensen</last></author>
      <author><first>Benoit</first><last>Brard</last></author>
      <pages>218–225</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents a methodology for rapidly generating FST-based verbalizers for ASR and TTS systems by efficiently sourcing language-specific data. We describe a questionnaire which collects the necessary data to bootstrap the number grammar induction system and parameterize the verbalizer templates described in Ritchie et al. (2019), and a machine-readable data store which allows the data collected through the questionnaire to be supplemented by additional data from other sources. This system allows us to rapidly scale technologies such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autonomous_system_(Internet)">ASR</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text-based_user_interface">TTS</a> to more languages, including low-resource languages.</abstract>
      <url hash="2fb9504b">2020.sltu-1.30</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>ritchie-etal-2020-data</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="32">
      <title>Adapting a Welsh Terminology Tool to Develop a Cornish Dictionary<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>elsh Terminology Tool to Develop a <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ornish Dictionary</title>
      <author><first>Delyth</first><last>Prys</last></author>
      <pages>235–239</pages>
      <abstract>Cornish and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welsh_language">Welsh</a> are closely related <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celtic_languages">Celtic languages</a> and this paper provides a brief description of a recent project to publish an online bilingual English / Cornish dictionary, the Gerlyver Kernewek, based on similar work previously undertaken for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welsh_language">Welsh</a>. Both languages are endangered, Cornish critically so, but both can benefit from the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_technology">language technology</a>. Welsh has previous experience of using language technologies for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_revitalization">language revitalization</a>, and this is now being used to help the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cornish_language">Cornish language</a> create new tools and resources, including lexicographical ones, helping a dispersed team of language specialists and editors, many of them in a voluntary capacity, to work collaboratively online. Details are given of the Maes T dictionary writing and publication platform, originally developed for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welsh_language">Welsh</a>, and of some of the adaptations that had to be made to accommodate the specific needs of Cornish, including their use of Middle and Late varieties due to its development as a revived language.</abstract>
      <url hash="48eef228">2020.sltu-1.32</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>prys-2020-adapting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="40">
      <title>On the Exploration of English to Urdu Machine Translation<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish to <fixed-case>U</fixed-case>rdu Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Sadaf</first><last>Abdul Rauf</last></author>
      <author><first>Syeda</first><last>Abida</last></author>
      <author><first>Noor-e-</first><last>Hira</last></author>
      <author><first>Syeda</first><last>Zahra</last></author>
      <author><first>Dania</first><last>Parvez</last></author>
      <author><first>Javeria</first><last>Bashir</last></author>
      <author><first>Qurat-ul-ain</first><last>Majid</last></author>
      <pages>285–293</pages>
      <abstract>Machine Translation is the inevitable technology to reduce communication barriers in today’s world. It has made substantial progress in recent years and is being widely used in commercial as well as non-profit sectors. Such is only the case for European and other high resource languages. For English-Urdu language pair, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technology">technology</a> is in its infancy stage due to scarcity of resources. Present research is an important milestone in English-Urdu machine translation, as we present results for four major domains including Biomedical, Religious, Technological and General using Statistical and Neural Machine Translation. We performed series of experiments in attempts to optimize the performance of each <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> and also to study the impact of data sources on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a>. Finally, we established a comparison of the data sources and the effect of language model size on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_machine_translation">statistical machine translation</a> performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="d45e0926">2020.sltu-1.40</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>abdul-rauf-etal-2020-exploration</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="42">
      <title>Adapting Language Specific Components of Cross-Media Analysis Frameworks to Less-Resourced Languages : the Case of Amharic<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>mharic</title>
      <author><first>Yonas</first><last>Woldemariam</last></author>
      <author><first>Adam</first><last>Dahlgren</last></author>
      <pages>298–305</pages>
      <abstract>We present an ASR based pipeline for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amharic">Amharic</a> that orchestrates NLP components within a cross media analysis framework (CMAF). One of the major challenges that are inherently associated with CMAFs is effectively addressing multi-lingual issues. As a result, many languages remain under-resourced and fail to leverage out of available media analysis solutions. Although spoken natively by over 22 million people and there is an ever-increasing amount of Amharic multimedia content on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web">Web</a>, querying them with simple text search is difficult. Searching for, especially audio / video content with simple key words, is even hard as they exist in their raw form. In this study, we introduce a spoken and textual content processing workflow into a CMAF for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amharic">Amharic</a>. We design an ASR-named entity recognition (NER) pipeline that includes three main components : ASR, a transliterator and NER. We explore various acoustic modeling techniques and develop an OpenNLP-based NER extractor along with a transliterator that interfaces between ASR and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Near-infrared_spectroscopy">NER</a>. The designed ASR-NER pipeline for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amharic">Amharic</a> promotes the multi-lingual support of CMAFs. Also, the state-of-the art design principles and techniques employed in this study shed light for other less-resourced languages, particularly the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semitic_languages">Semitic ones</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="d9c253ee">2020.sltu-1.42</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>woldemariam-dahlgren-2020-adapting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="45">
      <title>Owksape-An Online Language Learning Platform for Lakota<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>akota</title>
      <author><first>Jan</first><last>Ullrich</last></author>
      <author><first>Elliot</first><last>Thornton</last></author>
      <author><first>Peter</first><last>Vieira</last></author>
      <author><first>Logan</first><last>Swango</last></author>
      <author><first>Marek</first><last>Kupiec</last></author>
      <pages>321–329</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents Owksape, an online language learning platform for the under-resourced language Lakota. The Lakota language (Laktiyapi) is a Siouan language native to the United States with fewer than 2000 fluent speakers. Owksape was developed by The Language Conservancy to support revitalization efforts, including reaching younger generations and providing a tool to complement traditional teaching methods. This project grew out of various multimedia resources in order to combine their most effective aspects into a single, self-paced learning tool. The first section of this paper discusses the motivation for and background of Owksape. Section two details the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_description">linguistic features</a> and language documentation principles that form the backbone of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computing_platform">platform</a>. Section three lays out the unique integration of cultural aspects of the Lakota people into the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphic_design">visual design</a> of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software">application</a>. Section four explains the pedagogical principles of Owksape. Application features and exercise types are then discussed in detail with visual examples, followed by an overview of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_design">software design</a>, as well as the effort required to develop the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computing_platform">platform</a>. Finally, a description of future features and considerations is presented.</abstract>
      <url hash="26a7b211">2020.sltu-1.45</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>ullrich-etal-2020-owoksape</bibkey>
    <title_ar>Owöksape - منصة تعلم اللغة عبر الإنترنت لاكوتا</title_ar>
      <title_es>Owöksape: una plataforma de aprendizaje de idiomas en línea para lakota</title_es>
      <title_pt>Owöksape - Uma plataforma de aprendizado de idiomas on-line para Lakota</title_pt>
      <title_ja>Owöksape -ラコタ州のオンライン言語学習プラットフォーム</title_ja>
      <title_zh>Owöksape - 拉科塔语在线语学平台</title_zh>
      <title_hi>Owöksape - Lakota के लिए एक ऑनलाइन भाषा सीखने मंच</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Owöksape - Ardán Foghlama Teanga ar Líne do Lakota</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Owoksape - ლაკჲრაName</title_ka>
      <title_el>Μια διαδικτυακή πλατφόρμα εκμάθησης γλωσσών για τη Λακότα</title_el>
      <title_hu>Owoksape - Online nyelvtanulási platform Lakota számára</title_hu>
      <title_it>Owoksape - Una piattaforma di apprendimento linguistico online per Lakota</title_it>
      <title_lt>Owoksape – Lakotos kalbų mokymosi internete platforma</title_lt>
      <title_kk>Owoksape - Лакота үшін онлайн тіл оқыту платформасы</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Оуксапе - Платформа за онлајн учење јазик за Лакота</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Owoksape - Platform Belajar Bahasa Online untuk Lakota</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ഒവോക്സ്പീ - ലാകോട്ടാവിനുള്ള ഓണ്‍ലൈന്‍ ഭാഷ പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്ന പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോം</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Owoksape - Pjattaforma Online għat-Tagħlim tal-Lingwi għal Lakota</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Owoksape - Лакота-ын онлайн хэл суралцах платформ</title_mn>
      <title_no>Owoksape – Ein online språk læringsplattform for Lakota</title_no>
      <title_pl>Owoksape – Online Platform Nauki Języków dla Lakoty</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Owoksape - O platformă online de învățare a limbilor străine pentru Lakota</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Owoksape - Online Language Learning Platform for Lakota</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_so>Owoksape - Platforma waxbarashada afka internetka ee Lakota</title_so>
      <title_sv>Owoksape - En plattform för språkinlärning online för Lakota</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>اوووکسپ - لاکوتا کے لئے ایک آنلاین زبان سکونت پٹروم</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Một chương trình giáo dục ngôn ngữ trực tuyến cho Lakota</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Owoksape - Lakota uchun Online tilni oʻrganish platformiName</title_uz>
      <title_hr>Owoksape - Online Language Learning Platform for Lakota</title_hr>
      <title_da>Owoksape - En online sproglæringsplatform for Lakota</title_da>
      <title_bg>Онлайн платформа за езиково обучение за Лакота</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Owoksape is een online platform voor het leren van talen voor Lakota.</title_nl>
      <title_id>Owoksape - Platform Belajar Bahasa Online untuk Lakota</title_id>
      <title_fa>اوووکساپ - یک نقشه آموزش زبان آنلاین برای لاکوتا</title_fa>
      <title_ko>Owoksape-라코타 온라인 언어 학습 플랫폼</title_ko>
      <title_de>Owoksape – Eine Online Sprachlernplattform für Lakota</title_de>
      <title_sw>Owoksape - Jukwaa la Kufundisha Lugha ya Mtandaoni kwa ajili ya Lakota</title_sw>
      <title_af>Owoksape - An Online Language Learning Platform for Lakota</title_af>
      <title_sq>Owoksape - Një platformë e mësimit të gjuhës në internet për Lakota</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Owoksape - An Online Language Learning Platform for Lakota</title_hy>
      <title_bn>ওওকসেপ - লাকোটার জন্য অনলাইন ভাষা শিক্ষা প্ল্যাটফর্ম</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Owoksape - Online Language Learning Platform for Lakota</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Owoksape - Una plataforma d'aprenentatge de llenguatges en línia per Lakota</title_ca>
      <title_tr>Owoksape - Lakota için Online Dil Öğrenme Platformu</title_tr>
      <title_et>Owoksape - Lakota veebipõhine keeleõppe platvorm</title_et>
      <title_fi>Owoksape - Online Language Learning Platform for Lakota</title_fi>
      <title_am>Owoksape - ለሎኮታ የቋንቋ ትምህርት ፕላንፈር</title_am>
      <title_az>Owoksape - Lakota 칲칞칲n Online Dil 칐yr톛nm톛 Platformu</title_az>
      <title_cs>Owoksape: Online platforma pro výuku jazyků pro Lakota</title_cs>
      <title_jv>Owaksape - online Language Learning Plaformat kanggo Lakota</title_jv>
      <title_he>Owoksape - Platform Online Language Learning for Lakota</title_he>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Owoksape - Spletna platforma za učenje jezikov za Lakoto</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Owoksape - Lakota ལ་ཡོད་པའི་སྐད་ཡིག་ཤེས་ཀྱི་གྲོང་ཁྱེར་ཞིག་གི་</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تقدم هذه الورقة Owöksape ، وهي منصة لتعلم اللغة عبر الإنترنت للغة لاكوتا ضعيفة الموارد. لغة لاكوتا (Lakȟötiyapi) هي لغة سيوان أصلية في الولايات المتحدة مع أقل من 2000 متحدث بطلاقة. تم تطوير Owöksape من قبل The Language Conservancy لدعم جهود التنشيط ، بما في ذلك الوصول إلى الأجيال الشابة وتوفير أداة لاستكمال طرق التدريس التقليدية. نشأ هذا المشروع من مصادر متعددة الوسائط من أجل دمج جوانبها الأكثر فاعلية في أداة تعليمية واحدة ذاتية الوتيرة. يناقش القسم الأول من هذه الورقة الدافع وراء Owöksape وخلفيته. يوضح القسم الثاني تفاصيل السمات اللغوية ومبادئ التوثيق اللغوي التي تشكل العمود الفقري للمنصة. يوضح القسم الثالث التكامل الفريد للجوانب الثقافية لشعب لاكوتا في التصميم المرئي للتطبيق. يشرح القسم الرابع المبادئ التربوية لـ Owöksape. ثم تتم مناقشة ميزات التطبيق وأنواع التمارين بالتفصيل مع أمثلة مرئية ، متبوعة بنظرة عامة على تصميم البرنامج ، فضلاً عن الجهد المطلوب لتطوير النظام الأساسي. أخيرًا ، يتم تقديم وصف للميزات والاعتبارات المستقبلية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo presenta Owöksape, una plataforma de aprendizaje de idiomas en línea para el idioma lakota, de escasos recursos. El idioma lakota (Lakötiyapi) es un idioma siouano nativo de los Estados Unidos con menos de 2000 hablantes fluidos. Owöksape fue desarrollado por The Language Conservancy para apoyar los esfuerzos de revitalización, incluyendo llegar a las generaciones más jóvenes y proporcionar una herramienta para complementar los métodos de enseñanza tradicionales. Este proyecto surgió de varios recursos multimedia para combinar sus aspectos más efectivos en una sola herramienta de aprendizaje autodidacta. La primera sección de este artículo analiza la motivación y los antecedentes de Owöksape. La segunda sección detalla las características lingüísticas y los principios de documentación lingüística que forman la columna vertebral de la plataforma. La tercera sección describe la integración única de los aspectos culturales del pueblo lakota en el diseño visual de la aplicación. La cuarta sección explica los principios pedagógicos de Owöksape. Las características de la aplicación y los tipos de ejercicio se discuten en detalle con ejemplos visuales, seguidos de una descripción general del diseño del software, así como del esfuerzo necesario para desarrollar la plataforma. Por último, se presenta una descripción de las características y consideraciones futuras.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo apresenta o Owöksape, uma plataforma online de aprendizado de idiomas para o idioma com poucos recursos Lakota. A língua Lakota (Lakȟötiyapi) é uma língua Siouan nativa dos Estados Unidos com menos de 2000 falantes fluentes. Owöksape foi desenvolvido pela The Language Conservancy para apoiar os esforços de revitalização, incluindo alcançar as gerações mais jovens e fornecer uma ferramenta para complementar os métodos tradicionais de ensino. Este projeto surgiu de vários recursos multimídia para combinar seus aspectos mais eficazes em uma única ferramenta de aprendizado individualizada. A primeira seção deste artigo discute a motivação e os antecedentes de Owöksape. A seção dois detalha os recursos linguísticos e os princípios de documentação da linguagem que formam a espinha dorsal da plataforma. A seção três apresenta a integração exclusiva de aspectos culturais do povo Lakota no design visual do aplicativo. A seção quatro explica os princípios pedagógicos de Owöksape. Os recursos do aplicativo e os tipos de exercícios são discutidos em detalhes com exemplos visuais, seguidos por uma visão geral do design do software, bem como do esforço necessário para desenvolver a plataforma. Por fim, é apresentada uma descrição dos recursos e considerações futuras.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>この論文では、資源不足の言語Lakotaのためのオンライン言語学習プラットフォームであるOwöksapeを紹介しています。 ラコタ族の言語（ラコタぞくのげんご）はアメリカ合衆国原産のスー族の言語で、流暢な話者は2000人に満たない。 Owöksapeは、若い世代にアプローチし、伝統的な教育方法を補完するツールを提供するなど、活性化の取り組みを支援するためにThe Language Conservancyによって開発されました。 このプロジェクトは、最も効果的な側面を単一の自己ペースの学習ツールに組み合わせるために、さまざまなマルチメディアリソースから成長しました。 本稿の最初のセクションでは、Owöksapeの動機と背景について述べる。 セクション2では、プラットフォームの根幹を形成する言語学的特徴と言語文書化の原則について詳しく説明します。 セクション3は、ラコタ族の文化的側面をアプリケーションの視覚的デザインに統合するユニークな方法を示しています。 第4節では、Owöksapeの教育原理について説明する。 次に、アプリケーションの機能とエクササイズタイプについて視覚的な例で詳細に説明し、その後にソフトウェア設計の概要とプラットフォームの開発に必要な努力について説明します。 最後に、将来の特徴と考慮事項の説明を提示する。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर Owöksape, कम संसाधन वाली भाषा Lakota के लिए एक ऑनलाइन भाषा सीखने के मंच प्रस्तुत करता है। Lakota भाषा (Lakötiyapi) 2000 से कम धाराप्रवाह वक्ताओं के साथ संयुक्त राज्य अमेरिका के लिए मूल निवासी एक Siouan भाषा है। Owöksape द्वारा विकसित किया गया था भाषा संरक्षण पुनरुद्धार के प्रयासों का समर्थन करने के लिए, युवा पीढ़ियों तक पहुंचने और पारंपरिक शिक्षण विधियों के पूरक के लिए एक उपकरण प्रदान करने सहित। यह परियोजना विभिन्न मल्टीमीडिया संसाधनों से बाहर हो गई ताकि उनके सबसे प्रभावी पहलुओं को एक एकल, आत्म-पुस्तक सीखने के उपकरण में संयोजित किया जा सके। इस पेपर का पहला खंड Owöksape के लिए प्रेरणा और पृष्ठभूमि पर चर्चा करता है। अनुभाग दो भाषाई विशेषताओं और भाषा प्रलेखन सिद्धांतों का विवरण देता है जो मंच की रीढ़ बनाते हैं। खंड तीन आवेदन के दृश्य डिजाइन में लकोटा लोगों के सांस्कृतिक पहलुओं के अद्वितीय एकीकरण को बताता है। धारा चार Owöksape के शैक्षणिक सिद्धांतों की व्याख्या करता है। एप्लिकेशन सुविधाओं और व्यायाम प्रकारों पर तब दृश्य उदाहरणों के साथ विस्तार से चर्चा की जाती है, इसके बाद सॉफ़्टवेयर डिज़ाइन का अवलोकन किया जाता है, साथ ही साथ प्लेटफ़ॉर्म को विकसित करने के लिए आवश्यक प्रयास भी किया जाता है। अंत में, भविष्य की विशेषताओं और विचारों का विवरण प्रस्तुत किया गया है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>本文引Owöksape,此一针贫乏语言Lakota在线语学平台也。 拉科塔语(Lakȟötiyapi)是一种苏安语,原产于美国,只有不到2000人流利地说。 Owöksape言护协会,赞振事业,包接年轻一代,补旧教学方法之具。 夫项目者,所以资多媒体也,所以合至效于一也,定进度之学也。 本文第一部议Owöksape机背景。 其二详言平台骨干之语,与语言文档法。 其三曰拉科塔人文应用程序独整合。 四曰Owöksape之教。 然后因可视化示例详论应用程序功能与习类,然后概述软件设计及发平台所须工作。 最后,说来世功能和注意事项。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Cuireann an páipéar seo i láthair Owöksape, ardán foghlama teanga ar líne don teanga Lakota gann ar acmhainní. Is teanga Siouan ó dhúchas na Stát Aontaithe í an teanga Lakota ( Lakȟötiyapi ) le níos lú ná 2000 cainteoir líofa. D’fhorbair The Language Conservancy Owöksape chun tacú le hiarrachtaí athbheochana, lena n-áirítear teagmháil a dhéanamh leis na glúnta níos óige agus uirlis a sholáthar chun cur leis na modhanna múinte traidisiúnta. D’fhás an tionscadal seo as acmhainní éagsúla ilmheán chun na gnéithe is éifeachtaí a chur le chéile in aon uirlis foghlama amháin féinluais. Pléann an chéad chuid den pháipéar seo spreagadh agus cúlra Owöksape. Sonraíonn cuid a dó na gnéithe teanga agus na prionsabail doiciméadaithe teanga atá mar chnámh droma an ardáin. Leagann cuid a trí amach comhtháthú uathúil gnéithe cultúrtha mhuintir Lakota i ndearadh amhairc an fheidhmchláir. Míníonn cuid a ceathair prionsabail oideolaíocha Owöksape. Ansin déantar gnéithe feidhmchláir agus cineálacha cleachtaidh a phlé go mion le samplaí amhairc, agus forbhreathnú ina dhiaidh sin ar dhearadh na mbogearraí, chomh maith leis an iarracht is gá chun an t-ardán a fhorbairt. Ar deireadh, cuirtear síos ar ghnéithe agus ar bhreithnithe na todhchaí.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a tanulmány bemutatja az Owoksape-t, egy online nyelvtanulási platformot az alacsony forrásokkal rendelkező Lakota nyelv számára. A lakota nyelv (Lakhotiyapi) az Egyesült Államokban anyanyelv, kevesebb mint 2000 folyékony beszélővel. Az Owoksape-t a The Language Conservancy fejlesztette ki, hogy támogassa a revitalizációs erőfeszítéseket, beleértve a fiatalabb generációk elérését és a hagyományos oktatási módszerek kiegészítésére szolgáló eszközt. Ez a projekt különböző multimédiás erőforrásokból fejlődött ki annak érdekében, hogy a leghatékonyabb aspektusaikat egyetlen, öntempójú tanulási eszközzé egyesítse. A tanulmány első része az Owoksape motivációját és hátterét tárgyalja. A második szakasz részletezi a platform gerincét képező nyelvi jellemzőket és nyelvi dokumentációs elveket. A harmadik szakasz bemutatja a lakota nép kulturális aspektusainak egyedülálló integrációját az alkalmazás vizuális tervezésébe. A negyedik rész elmagyarázza az Owoksape pedagógiai elveit. Az alkalmazási jellemzőket és a gyakorlattípusokat ezután vizuális példákkal részletesen megvitatjuk, majd áttekintést követ a szoftver tervezéséről, valamint a platform fejlesztéséhez szükséges erőfeszítésekről. Végül ismertetjük a jövőbeli jellemzőket és megfontolásokat.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία παρουσιάζει μια διαδικτυακή πλατφόρμα εκμάθησης γλωσσών για τη γλώσσα Λακότα που δεν διαθέτει πόρους. Η γλώσσα Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) είναι μια γλώσσα Σιού μητρική στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες με λιγότερους από 2000 άπταιτους ομιλητές. Το αναπτύχθηκε από τη Γλωσσική Συντήρηση για να υποστηρίξει προσπάθειες αναζωογόνησης, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της προσέγγισης των νεότερων γενεών και της παροχής ενός εργαλείου για τη συμπλήρωση των παραδοσιακών μεθόδων διδασκαλίας. Το έργο αυτό αναπτύχθηκε από διάφορους πόρους πολυμέσων προκειμένου να συνδυάσει τις πιο αποτελεσματικές πτυχές τους σε ένα μόνο εργαλείο μάθησης με αυτορυθμό. Το πρώτο τμήμα της παρούσας εργασίας συζητά τα κίνητρα και το υπόβαθρο του Owoksape. Η δεύτερη ενότητα περιγράφει τα γλωσσικά χαρακτηριστικά και τις αρχές γλωσσικής τεκμηρίωσης που αποτελούν τη ραχοκοκαλιά της πλατφόρμας. Το τρίτο τμήμα παρουσιάζει τη μοναδική ενσωμάτωση των πολιτιστικών πτυχών του λαού των Λακώτα στον οπτικό σχεδιασμό της εφαρμογής. Το τέταρτο τμήμα εξηγεί τις παιδαγωγικές αρχές του Owoksape. Στη συνέχεια, τα χαρακτηριστικά εφαρμογής και οι τύποι ασκήσεων συζητούνται λεπτομερώς με οπτικά παραδείγματα, ακολουθούμενη από μια επισκόπηση του σχεδιασμού του λογισμικού, καθώς και της προσπάθειας που απαιτείται για την ανάπτυξη της πλατφόρμας. Τέλος, παρουσιάζεται περιγραφή μελλοντικών χαρακτηριστικών και προβληματισμών.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ეს დოკუმენტი აჩვენებს Owoksape, ინტერნეული ენის სწავლების პლატატური ლაკოტატისთვის. ლაკოტიანი ენაა (ლაკოტიოოთ) არის შიუანი ენაა, რომელიც ამერიკეთებული შტატებში მცირე 2000 წლის სიტყვანტისგან. Owoksape იქნება ენის კონსერვანციის განვითარება, რომლებიც ახალგაზრდება მხარე წლისთვის და საკუთარ ხელსაწყოთა საკუთარი სწავლების მეტისების დამატებლად. ეს პროექტი განსხვავებული მლიტიმედია რესურსიდან გაზრდა, რომ მათი უფრო ეფექტიური აპექტები ერთი, თავიდან განსხვავებული სწავლების ხელსაწყოთან შემყვებელ ამ დოკუნტის პირველი ნაწილი განსაზღვრებს Owoksape-ის მოტივაციის და ფონდომის მოტივაციას. მეორე წევრი ინგუმისტიკური ფუნქციები და ენის დოკუმენტიკური პრინციპები, რომლებიც პლატატატის ძირითადი ფუნქცია. მესამე წევრი ლაკოტის ადამიანების კულტური აპექტების უნიკალური ინტერგურაცია პროგრამის ვიზუალური დიზაინში. მეოთხე წერტილი განახსენებს Owoksape-ის პედაგოგიური პრინციპები. პროგრამის ფუნქციები და გამოყენების ტიპები შემდეგ ვიზუალური მაგალითან განსაკუთრებულია, შემდეგ პროგრამის განსაკუთრება და პროგრამის განვითარებისთვის მუშაობა. საბოლოოდ, მომავალეთი განსაზღვრებების და შესახებების გამოყენება.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo presenta Owoksape, una piattaforma online per l'apprendimento delle lingue Lakota con scarse risorse. La lingua Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) è una lingua siouan nativa degli Stati Uniti con meno di 2000 parlanti fluenti. Owoksape è stato sviluppato da The Language Conservancy per sostenere gli sforzi di rivitalizzazione, tra cui raggiungere le giovani generazioni e fornire uno strumento per integrare i metodi di insegnamento tradizionali. Questo progetto è nato da varie risorse multimediali per combinare i loro aspetti più efficaci in un unico strumento di apprendimento autonomo. La prima sezione di questo articolo discute la motivazione e il background di Owoksape. La seconda sezione descrive le caratteristiche linguistiche e i principi di documentazione linguistica che costituiscono la spina dorsale della piattaforma. La sezione tre illustra l'integrazione unica degli aspetti culturali del popolo Lakota nel design visivo dell'applicazione. La sezione quattro spiega i principi pedagogici di Owoksape. Le caratteristiche dell'applicazione e i tipi di esercizio vengono poi discussi in dettaglio con esempi visivi, seguiti da una panoramica del design del software e dello sforzo necessario per sviluppare la piattaforma. Infine, viene presentata una descrizione delle caratteristiche e delle considerazioni future.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Овој весник го претставува Оуксапе, онлајн платформа за учење јазик за јазикот Лакота со недоволни ресурси. Јазикот Лакотијапи (Lakhotiyapi) е сиуански јазик од САД со помалку од 2000 тековни говорници. Оуксапе беше развиен од страна на Зачувувањето на јазикот за поддршка на напорите за ревитализација, вклучително и достигнување на помладите генерации и обезбедување алатка за комплиментирање на традиционалните методи на учење. Овој проект израсна од различни мултимедијални ресурси со цел да ги комбинира нивните најефикасни аспекти во една единствена алатка за самоуспешно учење. Првиот дел од овој весник дискутира за мотивацијата и позадината на Оуксапе. Другиот оддел ги детализира јазичните карактеристики и принципите на јазичката документација кои ја формираат грб коска на платформата. Section three lays out the unique integration of cultural aspects of the Lakota people into the visual design of the application.  Четвртиот оддел ги објаснува педагошките принципи на Оуксајп. Потоа се дискутираат детално за апликациските карактеристики и типовите на вежбање со визуелни примери, по кои следи преглед на софтверскиот дизајн, како и напорите потребни за развој на платформата. Конечно, се претставува опис на идните карактеристики и размислувања.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз Лакота тілінің онлайн тілді оқыту платформасын көрсетеді. Лакота тілі (Лакотипи) Америка тілінде 2000 жылдан аз тілді сиуан тілі. Овоксап тіл консервациясы қайта жалғастыру әрекеттерін қолдау үшін құрылды, жастағы әлемдерді жеткізу және әдімгі оқыту әдістерін қолдау үшін құралы береді. Бұл жоба өзінің ең эффективті аспектерін бір-бір, өзіңіздің оқыту құралына біріктіру үшін көптеген мультимедиа ресурстардан өсті. Бұл қағаздың бірінші бөлігі Owoksape- тың мотивациясын және аясын талқылады. Екінші бөлім платформасының қапшығын жасайтын лингвистикалық мүмкіндіктері мен тіл құжаттамасының принципі. Үшінші бөлім Лакота адамдарының мәдениеттерін көрінетін қолданбаның көрінетін дизайнына бірнеше біріктіру үшін анықтайды. Дөрінші бөлім Овоксап педагогиялық принципін түсіндіреді. Қолданбаның мүмкіндіктері мен жұмыс түрлері көрінетін мысалдар менен егжей- тегжейлі сөйлесіледі. Бағдарламаның құрылымын қарап, платформасын жасау үшін қажетті жұмыс істеу және қажет Соңында болашақ мүмкіндіктерді және түсініктердің сипаттамасы көрсетіледі.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente pristatoma „Owoksape“, internetinė kalbų mokymo platforma nepakankamai išteklių turinčiai Lakota kalbai. Lakotos kalba (Lakhotiyapi) yra Jungtinių Amerikos Valstijų giminė siovės kalba, kurioje kalbama mažiau kaip 2000 skysčių kalbėtojų. Savivaldybė „Owoksape“ plėtojo kalbų išsaugojimą siekiant remti atnaujinimo pastangas, įskaitant jaunesnių kartų pasiekimą ir tradicinių mokymo metodų papildymą. Šis projektas išaugo iš įvairių daugialypių žiniasklaidos išteklių, kad veiksmingiausi jų aspektai būtų sujungti į vieną savarankišką mokymosi priemonę. Pirmame šio dokumento skyriuje aptariama Owoksape motyvacija ir aplinkybė. Antrajame skirsnyje išsamiai aprašytos kalbos ypatybės ir kalbos dokumentų principai, kurie sudaro platformos pagrindą. Trečiame skirsnyje pateikiama unikali Lakotos žmonių kultūrinių aspektų integracija į vizualinį programos projektą. Ketvirtame skirsnyje paaiškinami Owoksape pedagoginiai principai. Tada išsamiai aptariamos programos savybės ir pratybų rūšys su vizualiais pavyzdžiais, po kurių pateikiama programinės įrangos projekto apžvalga ir pastangos, reikalingos plėtoti platform ą. Galiausiai pateikiamas būsimų požymių ir svarstymų aprašymas.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ ഒവോക്സ്പെയിനെ സമ്മാനിക്കുന്നു, ലാകോട്ടായുള്ള ഓണ്‍ലൈന്‍ ഭാഷ പഠിക്കുന്ന പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോമിനായ ലാക്കോട്ട ഭാഷ (ലാഖോട്ടിയപ്പി) അമേരിക്കയിലേക്കുള്ള സിയൂവാന്‍ ഭാഷയാണ്. 2000 ലോകത്തിലെ സ്പീക്ടറുകള്‍ കുറച്ചുകൂ ഒവോക്സെപ്പ് ഭാഷ സംരക്ഷിക്കുന്നത് പുനര്‍ത്ഥിപ്പിക്കാനാണ്. ചെറുപ്പമുള്ള തലമുറതലമുറകളിലേക്ക് എത്തുന്നതും പാഠമായ ഉപദേശ This project grew out of various multimedia resources in order to combine their most effective aspects into a single, self-paced learning tool.  ഈ പത്രത്തിന്റെ ആദ്യത്തെ ഭാഗമാണ് ഓവോക്സ്പെയിന്റെ പ്രഭാതത്തിന്റെയും പശ്ചാത്തലത്തിന്റെയും പ് പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോമിന്റെ ബാക്ക്ബോണ്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കുന്ന ഭാഷകങ്ങളുടെയും ഭാഷ പ്രമാണങ്ങളുടെയും വിശദീകരണങ്ങളുടെയും വിവരങ് പ്രയോഗത്തിന്റെ കാഴ്ചപ്രയോഗത്തിന്റെ കാഴ്ചകളിലേക്ക് ലാക്കോട്ട ആളുകളുടെ സംസ്കാര്യത്തിന്റെ ഒരുമിച്ചുകൂട് സെക്ഷന്‍ നാല് വിഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ ഓവോക്സ്പെയിന്‍റെ വിദ്യാഭ്യാസിക നിയമങ്ങള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു. പ്രയോഗത്തിന്റെ പ്രയോഗത്തിന്റെ ഗുണഗണങ്ങളും പരിശീലിക്കുന്ന രീതികളും കാണാവുന്ന ഉദാഹരണങ്ങളുമായി വിശദീകരിക്കപ്പെടുന്നു. പിന്നീട് സ അവസാനം, ഭാവിയുടെ ഗുണഗണങ്ങളുടെയും വിശദീകരണങ്ങളുടെയും വിവരണങ്ങള്‍ കാണിക്കുന്നു.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас Лакота хэл доорх хүчний онлайн хэл суралцах Платформ Овоксап-г харуулдаг. Лакота хэл (Лакотипи) бол АНУ-ын суурин хэл ба 2000-аас бага шингэн ярьдаг. Овоксапын Холбооны хамгаалалт нь дахин сэргээх хичээлийг дэмжихийн тулд хөгжүүлсэн. Залуу үеүүдэд хүрэх болон уламжлалт багш нарын аргыг нэмэгдүүлэх хэрэгсэл өгсөн. Энэ төсөл олон олон мэдээллийн хөрөнгө оруулсан бөгөөд өөрсдийн хамгийн үр дүнтэй асуудлыг ганц, өөртөө зогсоох суралцах хэрэгсэл болгон нийлүүлэх боломжтой болсон. Энэ цаасны анхны хэсэг нь Owoksape-ын урам зорилго болон түүний сэтгэл хөдлөлийг ярьдаг. Хоёр дахь хэлний харилцаа болон хэлний документацийн үндсэн зарчмыг бүтээж буй платформын хөндий хэлбэрүүдийг тодорхойлдог. Гурав хэсэг нь Лакота хүмүүсийн соёлын асуудлуудын нэг нэг нэгтгэлийг хэрэглээний үзүүлэлтийн дизайнд тайлбарладаг. Дөрвөн хэсэг нь Овоксапийн педагогик зарчмыг тайлбарладаг. Ингээд програм хангамж болон дасгал хөдөлгөөн төрлийн төрлүүд дүрслэгддэг. Програм хангамжийн дизайны тухай дүрслэгддэг. Платформ хөгжүүлэх шаардлагатай хичээл. Эцэст нь ирээдүйн төлөвлөгөө болон санаануудын тодорхойлолт гарч ирнэ.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret viser Owoksape, eit internett språk læringsplattform for det underressurserte språket Lakota. Lakotaspråket (Lakhotiyapi) er ein Siouansk språk i USA med mindre enn 2000 fluent taler. Owoksape er utvikla av Språk-konservansen for å støtte innsatslar for revitalisering, inkludert å nå ungre generasjonar og gi eit verktøy for å komplemetere tradisjonelle læringsmetodar. Dette prosjektet voksa ut av ulike multimediaressursar for å kombinere dei mest effektive aspektane i eit enkelt, selvpakke læringsverktøy. Den første delen av denne papiret diskuterer motivasjonen for og bakgrunnen av Owoksape. Seksjon to detaljar på språkdokumentasjonsprinsippene og språkdokumentasjonane som formar bakgrunnsbene på plattformet. Seksjon tre legg inn unikkelt integrering av kulturelle aspektar av Lakota-menneskene i det visuelle design av programmet. Seksjon fire forklarer pedagogiske prinsippene av Owoksape. Programfunksjonar og øvingstypar vert derfor diskutert i detaljar med visuelle eksemplar, etterfulgt av eit oversikt over programvareininga, og forsøket som krevst for å utvikla plattformet. Ein skildring av framtidige funksjonar og forståking vert vist til slutt.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>W artykule przedstawiono Owoksape, internetową platformę nauki języków dla niedostatecznie zasobów języka Lakota. Język Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) jest językiem syouańskim pochodzącym ze Stanów Zjednoczonych z mniej niż 2000 płynnych użytkowników. Owoksape został opracowany przez The Language Conservancy w celu wspierania działań rewitalizacyjnych, w tym dotarcia do młodszych pokoleń i dostarczania narzędzia uzupełniającego tradycyjne metody nauczania. Projekt ten powstał z różnych zasobów multimedialnych, aby połączyć ich najbardziej efektywne aspekty w jedno narzędzie uczenia się w samym tempie. W pierwszej części artykułu omówiono motywację i tło Owoksape. Sekcja druga opisuje cechy językowe i zasady dokumentacji językowej, które stanowią podstawę platformy. Sekcja trzecia przedstawia unikalną integrację kulturowych aspektów ludności Lakotów w projektowaniu wizualnym aplikacji. Sekcja czwarta wyjaśnia zasady pedagogiczne Owoksape. Funkcje aplikacji i rodzaje ćwiczeń są następnie szczegółowo omówione na przykładach wizualnych, a następnie przegląd projektu oprogramowania, a także wysiłku wymaganego do rozwoju platformy. Na koniec przedstawiono opis przyszłych cech i rozważań.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jippreżenta Owoksape, pjattaforma ta’ tagħlim tal-lingwi onlajn għall-lingwa Lakota b’riżorsi baxxi. Il-lingwa Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) hija lingwa Siwajana li hija oriġinali mill-Istati Uniti b’inqas minn 2000 kelliem fluwenti. Owoksape ġie żviluppat mill-Konservanza tal-Lingwi biex jappoġġja l-isforzi ta’ revitalizzazzjoni, inkluż l-ilħuq ta’ ġenerazzjonijiet iżgħar u l-forniment ta’ għodda biex jikkumplimenta metodi ta’ tagħlim tradizzjonali. Dan il-proġett kiber minn diversi riżorsi multimedjali sabiex jingħaqdu l-aspetti l-aktar effettivi tagħhom f’għodda unika ta’ tagħlim b’pass awtonomu. The first section of this paper discusses the motivation for and background of Owoksape.  It-tieni taqsima tiddettalja l-karatteristiċi lingwistiċi u l-prinċipji tad-dokumentazzjoni lingwistika li jiffurmaw is-sinsla tal-pjattaforma. It-tielet taqsima tistabbilixxi l-integrazzjoni unika tal-aspetti kulturali tal-poplu tal-Lakota fid-disinn viżwali tal-applikazzjoni. Section four explains the pedagogical principles of Owoksape.  Il-karatteristiċi tal-applikazzjoni u t-tipi ta’ eżerċizzju mbagħad jiġu diskussi fid-dettall b’eżempji viżivi, segwiti minn ħarsa ġenerali tad-disinn tas-softwer, kif ukoll l-isforz meħtieġ għall-iżvilupp tal-pjattaforma. Fl-a ħħar nett, qed tiġi ppreżentata deskrizzjoni tal-karatteristiċi u l-kunsiderazzjonijiet futuri.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>This paper presents Owoksape, an online language learning platform for the under-resourced language Lakota.  Bahasa Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) adalah bahasa Siouan yang asli di Amerika Syarikat dengan kurang dari 2000 pembicara. Owoksape dikembangkan oleh The Language Conservancy untuk menyokong usaha pemulihan, termasuk mencapai generasi muda dan menyediakan alat untuk menambah kaedah pengajaran tradisional. Projek ini tumbuh dari berbagai sumber multimedia untuk menggabungkan aspek paling efektif mereka ke dalam satu alat belajar yang bertindak sendiri. Bahagian pertama kertas ini membahas motivasi untuk dan latar belakang Owoksape. Section two details the linguistic features and language documentation principles that form the backbone of the platform.  Seksyen tiga mengadakan integrasi unik aspek budaya rakyat Lakota ke dalam desain visual aplikasi. Seksyen empat menjelaskan prinsip pedagogi Owoksape. Ciri-ciri aplikasi dan jenis latihan kemudian dibahas secara terperinci dengan contoh visual, diikuti oleh paparan ringkasan rancangan perisian, serta usaha yang diperlukan untuk mengembangkan platform. Akhirnya, penerangan ciri-ciri masa depan dan pertimbangan dipaparkan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare prezintă Owoksape, o platformă online de învățare a limbilor străine pentru limba Lakota cu resurse insuficiente. Limba Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) este o limbă siouan nativă în Statele Unite ale Americii, cu mai puțin de 2000 vorbitori fluenți. Owoksape a fost dezvoltat de The Language Conservancy pentru a sprijini eforturile de revitalizare, inclusiv pentru a ajunge la generațiile tinere și pentru a oferi un instrument care să completeze metodele tradiționale de predare. Acest proiect s-a dezvoltat din diferite resurse multimedia pentru a combina cele mai eficiente aspecte ale acestora într-un singur instrument de învățare auto-ritmat. Prima secțiune a acestei lucrări discută motivația și fundalul Owoksape. Secțiunea a doua detaliază caracteristicile lingvistice și principiile documentației lingvistice care formează coloana vertebrală a platformei. Secțiunea a treia stabilește integrarea unică a aspectelor culturale ale oamenilor Lakota în designul vizual al aplicației. Secţiunea patru explică principiile pedagogice ale Owoksape. Caracteristicile aplicației și tipurile de exerciții sunt apoi discutate în detaliu cu exemple vizuale, urmate de o imagine de ansamblu a designului software, precum și efortul necesar pentru dezvoltarea platformei. În cele din urmă, este prezentată o descriere a caracteristicilor și considerațiilor viitoare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir predstavlja Owoksape, internetsku platformu za učenje jezika Lakota pod resursima. Lakota jezik (Lakhotiyapi) je Siouan jezik koji se rodi u SAD-u sa manjim od 2000 tekućih govornika. Owoksape je razvila Konservacija jezika kako bi podržala napore za revitalizaciju, uključujući postizanje mladih generacija i pružanje alata za dodatne tradicionalne metode učenja. Ovaj projekat je rastao iz različitih multimedijskih resursa kako bi kombinirao svoje najefikasnije aspekte u jedno, samoporučeno učenje alata. Prvi dio ovog papira razgovara o motivaciji i pozadini Owoksapea. Drugi deo detalja o jezičkim karakteristikama i principima za dokumentaciju jezika koji formiraju leđa platforme. Treća sekcija predstavlja jedinstvenu integraciju kulturnih aspekta naroda Lakota u vizualni dizajn aplikacije. Sekcija 4 objašnjava pedagogičke principe Owoksape. Onda se detaljno raspravljaju o karakteristikama aplikacije i vrstama vježbe sa vizualnim primjerima, slijedeći pregled dizajna softvera, kao i napora potrebne za razvoj platforme. Konačno se predstavlja opis budućih karakteristika i razmišljanja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>මේ පත්තුව ඔවොක්සාප්, ඇන්ලයින් භාෂාව ඉගෙන ගන්න ප්‍ලේටෆ්ටෝම් එකක් ලැකෝටා භාෂාව සඳහා ප්‍රත ලැකෝටා භාෂාව (ලැකෝටියාපී) තමයි අමෙරිකාන් ජාතිකාවේ සියුවන් භාෂාවක්, 2000 වඩා වඩා ප්‍රශ්නයක් ති Owaksape විස්තර කරලා තියෙන්නේ භාෂාව සංවර්ධනයෙන් ආපහු ප්‍රශ්නයක් සහාය කරන්න, තරුණු ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් සමග මේ ව්‍යාපෘතිය විවිධ මල්ටමිඩියාව ප්‍රවෘත්තියෙන් විශේෂ වෙලා තියෙන්නේ ඔවුන්ගේ හොඳම ප්‍රශ්ණ ප්‍ මේ පැත්තේ පළමු පැත්තේ ඔවොක්සාප් ගේ පිටිපස්සේ ප්‍රතිකාරය සහ පිටිපස්සේ කතා කරනවා. විස්තර දෙකක් විස්තර දෙකක් භාෂාවික විශේෂය සහ භාෂාවික විස්තර ප්‍රධාන වලින් පසුපසුපස විශේෂ තුන්වෙනි ලැකෝටා මිනිස්සුන්ගේ සංස්කෘතිය සංවිධානය සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න පුළුවන් විතරය විශේෂ හතරයි ඔවොක්සාප් ගේ පෙඩාගෝජික ප්‍රධානය පැහැදිලි කරනවා. වැඩසටහන් වර්ගයක් සහ වැඩසටහන් වර්ගයක් පස්සේ විස්තර වර්ගයක් විස්තර විදිහට කතා කරනවා, පස්සේ සොෆ්ටවර් විදිහයේ ප්‍ර අන්තිමේදි, අනාගතයේ අවස්ථාවක් සහ අවස්ථාවක් තියෙනවා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Warqaddan waxaa lagu qoraa qorshaha waxbarashada afka internetka ee Lakota oo ku qoran luqada hoose-resourceed. Luqada Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) waa luqada Siouyan oo u dhashay Mareykanka, kuwaas oo ay ku hadlaan wax ka yar 2000 luqadood. Owoksape waxaa loo hormariyey Maamulka luqada si uu u caawiyo hawlaha dib u soo celinta, kuwaas oo ku jira gaadhid qarniyada dhallinyarada iyo hagitaan in lagu dhammeeyo qaababka cilmiga caadiga ah. Projeygan wuxuu ka soo baxay hanti kala duduwan oo kala duduwan si uu ugu wada ururiyo dhinacyadooda ugu saamayn oo uu u noqdo qalabka waxbarashada oo kaliya. Qaybta kowaad ee warqaddan ayaa ka sheekaynaya dhaqdhaqaalaha iyo gadaasha Owoksape. Qaybta laba waxay ku qoran yihiin xarumaha luuqadaha iyo qoraalka dukumentiyada luuqadaha oo u sameeya bakhtiga qorshaha. Qeybta saddexdu waxay ka dhigaan qaabka la qabsashada dhaqamada ee dadka Lakota ah oo ku qoran qorshaha muuqashada codsiga. qeybta afarta waxaa lagu caddeeyaa qaynuunnada cilmiga ah ee Owoksape. Sidoo kale waxaa loola hadlaa tusaale ahaan aragga, waxaana lagu soo bandhigayaa sawirada dhaqaalaha ee codsiga iyo noocyada jimicsiga oo loo baahan yahay in lagu horumariyo tababarka. Ugu dambaysta waxaa la muujiyaa tilmaamo ku saabsan aqoonta mustaqbalka iyo fiirsashada.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats presenterar Owoksape, en onlineplattform för språkinlärning för det underresurserade språket Lakota. Lakota språket (Lakhotiyapi) är ett sikuanskt språk infödd i USA med färre än 2000 flytande talare. Owoksape utvecklades av The Language Conservancy för att stödja återupplivande insatser, inklusive att nå yngre generationer och tillhandahålla ett verktyg för att komplettera traditionella undervisningsmetoder. Projektet växte fram ur olika multimedieresurser för att kombinera deras mest effektiva aspekter till ett enda verktyg för självgående lärande. Den första delen av denna uppsats diskuterar motivationen för och bakgrunden till Owoksape. I avsnitt två beskrivs de språkliga egenskaper och principer för språkdokumentation som utgör plattformens ryggrad. I avsnitt tre beskrivs den unika integrationen av Lakotafolkets kulturella aspekter i applikationens visuella design. Avsnitt fyra förklarar Owoksapes pedagogiska principer. Applikationsfunktioner och träningstyper diskuteras sedan i detalj med visuella exempel, följt av en översikt över mjukvarudesign samt den insats som krävs för att utveckla plattformen. Slutligen presenteras en beskrivning av framtida egenskaper och överväganden.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதம் Owoksape, ஒரு ஆன்லைன் மொழி கற்றுக்கொள்ளும் தளம் லாகோட்டாவுக்கு கொடுக்கிறது. லாகோட்டா மொழி (லாக்ஹோடியாபி) ஒரு சியூயன் மொழி அமெரிக்காவிற்கு உள்ளது 2000 க்கு மிகவும் குறைவான பேச்சாளர்கள். Owoksape was developed by The Language Conservancy to support revitalization efforts, including reaching younger generations and providing a tool to complement traditional teaching methods.  இந்த திட்டத்தில் பல்வேறு மாதிரி வளங்களிலிருந்து வளர்ந்து அவர்களின் மிகவும் பயனுள்ள விளைவுகளை ஒரு ஒற்றைச்செல்லும்  இந்த காகிதத்தின் முதல் பகுதி ஓவாக்ஸ்கேபின் ஊக்கத்தையும் பின்னணியையும் விவாதம் செய்கிறது. பிரிவு இரண்டு விவரங்கள் மொழி குணங்கள் மற்றும் மொழி ஆவணப் பொருள் பின்னணியை உருவாக்குகிறது. பிரிவு மூன்று பயன்பாட்டின் பார்வையான வடிவமைப்பில் லாகோடா மக்களின் தனிப்பட்ட கலாச்சார பாகங்களை ஒருங்கிணைக்கும பிரிவு நான்கு ஓவாக்ஸ்கேபின் விவரங்களை விளக்குகிறது. பயன்பாட்டின் குணங்கள் மற்றும் பயிற்சி வகைகள் பிறகு பார்வையான உதாரணங்களுடன் விளக்கப்படும், பின்னர் மென்பொருள் வடிவமைப்பின் மேலோட் இறுதியில், எதிர்காலத்தின் குணங்கள் மற்றும் கருத்துக்கள் ஒரு விவரம் காட்டப்படுகிறது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>یہ کاغذ اوووکساپ کو پیش کرتا ہے، ایک آنلاین زبان سکھانے والی پلٹورم لاکوتا کی زبان کے لئے۔ لاکوتای زبان (لاکوتاپی) ایک سیوئن زبان ہے جو ایالات متحدہ کی ملک میں ہے اور 2000 سے کم سیوئن زبان کرنے والے ہیں۔ اووووکساپ کو زبان کی محافظت کے ذریعہ تولید کی گئی تھی کہ دوبارہ زندہ کرنا کی کوشش کی مدد کرے، یہاں تک کہ جوان نسلوں کو پہنچ جائے اور سنتی سیکھانے کے طریقے کے مطابق ایک ابزار دیں۔ یہ پروژہ مختلف مولٹی میڈیا رسورسوں سے بڑھا گیا ہے تاکہ ان کے سب اثر اثر الفاظت کو ایک ہی، خود پختہ سیکھنے کے وسیلہ میں جمع کرے۔ اس کاغذ کی پہلی قسمت اوووکساپ کے لئے اور پچھلے کے لئے موثرت کا مشورہ کرتی ہے۔ دو قسمت کی تفصیل زبان کی ویژگی اور زبان دکھانے کی اصل جو پلٹورم کی پشت ہڈی بناتے ہیں۔ تین قسمت لاکوتا لوگوں کی فرهنگی الگوں کی مختلف تفریق کے ساتھ کاربرد کی تصویر طراحی میں رکھتا ہے. چوتر قسمت اوووکساپ کے پڈاگوژیک اصولوں کو واضح کرتا ہے۔ اس کے بعد سافٹوفر ڈیزائن کی اوربوری نظر کے ساتھ ویزیئل مثالوں کے ساتھ تفصیل کے ساتھ مشورہ کیا جاتا ہے اور پٹوٹوفور ڈیزائن کے لئے ضرورت کی تلاش بھی۔ بالآخر، مستقبل فرضیوں اور توقع کی ایک تعریف پیش کیے جاتے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này giới thiệu Owlsley, một nền tảng học ngôn ngữ trực tuyến dành cho các ngôn ngữ thiếu nguồn thức Lakota. Tiếng Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) là một ngôn ngữ Sioux thổ dân Hoa Kỳ với ít hơn 2000kg người nói thông thạo. Owoksap được phát triển bởi Hội Bảo vệ Ngôn ngữ để hỗ trợ nỗ lực phục hồi lại, bao gồm cả việc tìm đến các thế hệ trẻ hơn và là một công cụ hỗ trợ phương pháp giảng dạy truyền thống. Dự án này phát triển bằng các nguồn nhân lực đa dạng, nhằm kết hợp các khía cạnh hiệu quả nhất thành một công cụ học riêng. Phần đầu tiên của bài báo này bàn về động cơ và nền tảng của Owlsley. Phần thứ hai chi tiết về các yếu tố ngôn ngữ và các nguyên tắc tài liệu ngôn ngữ. Khu ba đề cập đến sự hoà nhập độc đáo của nhân dân Lakota vào thiết kế thị giác của chương trình đó Phần bốn giải thích nguyên tắc giáo dục của Owlsley. Các tính năng ứng dụng và các loại tập thể dục được thảo luận chi tiết với các ví dụ thị giác, sau đó là một bản tổng quát về thiết kế phần mềm, cũng như những nỗ lực cần thiết để phát triển nền tảng. Cuối cùng, sẽ được mô tả các tính chất và quan điểm tương lai.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Bu qogʻoz Owoksape o'rganish platformini o'rganishga ega beradi. Lakota tili (Lakhotiyapi) 2000 ta'mindan kam so'zlar borligi Siou tili. Name Bu loyihani bitta, o'zimni o'rganish asboblarga bitta, o'zimni o'rganish uchun har xil multimedia manbalardan chiqaradi. Ushbu qogʻozning birinchi qismlari Owoksapening orqa fon orqa foni harakat qiladi. @ info: whatsthis Boʻlim 3 davomida Lakota odamlarning uning aloqali birlashtirishni qo'llab beradi. Boʻlim to'rtta qismni Owoksapening o'quvdagi o'quvvat qoidalarini anglatadi. Name Oxirgi, kelajakdagi xususiyatlar va tasavvur haqida koʻrsatiladi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия представя онлайн платформа за езиково обучение на езика Лакота с недостатъчни ресурси. Лакотският език (Лакотиапи) е сиуански език, роден в Съединените щати с по-малко от 2000 свободно говорещи. Оуоксапе е разработен от Езикова консервация, за да подкрепи усилията за съживяване, включително достигане до по-младите поколения и предоставяне на инструмент за допълване на традиционните методи на преподаване. Този проект израства от различни мултимедийни ресурси, за да съчетае най-ефективните им аспекти в един инструмент за самообучение. Първият раздел на тази статия разглежда мотивацията и фона на Оуоксапе. Раздел две подробно описва езиковите особености и принципите на езиковата документация, които формират гръбнака на платформата. Раздел три излага уникалната интеграция на културните аспекти на народа Лакота във визуалния дизайн на приложението. Четвърти раздел обяснява педагогическите принципи на Оуоксапе. След това функциите на приложението и видовете упражнения се обсъждат подробно с визуални примери, последвани от преглед на софтуерния дизайн, както и усилията, необходими за разработването на платформата. Накрая е представено описание на бъдещите характеристики и съображения.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel presenteert Owoksape, een online taalleerplatform voor de onderontwikkelde taal Lakota. De Lakota taal (Lakhotiyapi) is een Siouan taal die afkomstig is uit de Verenigde Staten met minder dan 2000 vloeiende sprekers. Owoksape werd ontwikkeld door The Language Conservancy om revitalisatie inspanningen te ondersteunen, waaronder het bereiken van jongere generaties en het verstrekken van een hulpmiddel om traditionele onderwijsmethoden aan te vullen. Dit project is voortgekomen uit verschillende multimedia bronnen om hun meest effectieve aspecten te combineren in een enkele, op eigen tempo lerende tool. Het eerste deel van dit artikel bespreekt de motivatie voor en achtergrond van Owoksape. Sectie twee beschrijft de taalkundige kenmerken en taaldocumentatieprincipes die de ruggengraat van het platform vormen. Sectie drie beschrijft de unieke integratie van culturele aspecten van het Lakota volk in het visuele ontwerp van de applicatie. Sectie vier legt de pedagogische principes van Owoksape uit. Toepassingskenmerken en oefentypen worden vervolgens uitgebreid besproken met visuele voorbeelden, gevolgd door een overzicht van het softwareontwerp en de inspanning die nodig is om het platform te ontwikkelen. Tot slot wordt een beschrijving gegeven van toekomstige kenmerken en overwegingen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag stellt Owoksape vor, eine Online-Sprachlernplattform für die unterversorgte Sprache Lakota. Die Lakota-Sprache (Lakhotiyapi) ist eine Siouan-Sprache, die in den Vereinigten Staaten mit weniger als 2000-Sprechern Muttersprache ist. Owoksape wurde von The Language Conservancy entwickelt, um Wiederbelebungsmaßnahmen zu unterstützen, einschließlich der Ansprache jüngerer Generationen und der Bereitstellung eines Tools zur Ergänzung traditioneller Unterrichtsmethoden. Dieses Projekt ist aus verschiedenen multimedialen Ressourcen entstanden, um ihre effektivsten Aspekte in einem einzigen Lerntool zu vereinen. Der erste Teil dieses Artikels diskutiert die Motivation und den Hintergrund von Owoksape. Abschnitt zwei beschreibt die sprachlichen Merkmale und Prinzipien der Sprachdokumentation, die das Rückgrat der Plattform bilden. Der dritte Abschnitt beschreibt die einzigartige Integration kultureller Aspekte der Lakota in das visuelle Design der Anwendung. Abschnitt vier erläutert die pädagogischen Prinzipien von Owoksape. Anwendungsmerkmale und Übungstypen werden anschließend anhand von visuellen Beispielen ausführlich diskutiert, gefolgt von einem Überblick über das Softwaredesign sowie den Aufwand für die Entwicklung der Plattform. Abschließend wird eine Beschreibung zukünftiger Merkmale und Überlegungen vorgestellt.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel præsenterer Owoksape, en online sproglæringsplatform for det underressourceorienterede sprog Lakota. Lakota sproget (Lakhotiyapi) er et sikuansk sprog indfødt i USA med færre end 2000 flydende talende. Owoksape blev udviklet af The Language Conservancy for at støtte revitaliseringsindsatsen, herunder at nå frem til yngre generationer og tilbyde et værktøj til at supplere traditionelle undervisningsmetoder. Dette projekt voksede ud af forskellige multimedieressourcer for at kombinere deres mest effektive aspekter i et enkelt, tempofyldt læringsværktøj. Første afsnit af denne artikel diskuterer motivationen for og baggrunden for Owoksape. Afsnit to beskriver de sproglige træk og sprogdokumentationsprincipper, der udgør rygraden i platformen. Afsnit tre beskriver den unikke integration af kulturelle aspekter af Lakota-folket i det visuelle design af ansøgningen. Afsnit fire forklarer Owoksapes pædagogiske principper. Applikationsfunktioner og træningstyper diskuteres derefter detaljeret med visuelle eksempler, efterfulgt af et overblik over softwaredesignet samt den indsats, der kræves for at udvikle platformen. Endelig præsenteres en beskrivelse af fremtidige træk og overvejelser.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ آوووکساپ را نشان می دهد، یک نقشه آموزش زبان آنلاین برای زبان لاکوتا زیر منبع است. زبان لاکوتای (لاکوتایپی) زبان سیوئی است که در ایالات متحده متحده آمریکا واقع شده‌است. اوووکساپ توسط محافظت زبان برای پشتیبانی تلاش‌های زنده‌سازی توسعه داده شده است، شامل رسیدن به نسل‌های جوان و دادن یک ابزار برای تعداد روش‌های آموزش سنتی. این پروژه از منابع متعدد رسانه‌های مختلف بزرگ شد تا بهترین نقطه‌های آنها را به یک ابزار یادگیری با خودم متصل کند. اولین بخش این کاغذ در مورد انگیزه و پشتیبانی Owoksape صحبت می کند. بخش دوم جزئیات ویژه‌های زبان‌شناسی و اصول‌های مدارک زبان‌شناسی که استخوان پشتیبانی Platform را شکل می‌دهند. بخش سوم تفریق فرهنگی فرهنگی مردم لاکوتا را در طراحی دیده‌ی کاربرد قرار می‌دهد. بخش چهارم اصولات پداگوژیک اوووکساپ را توضیح می دهد. ویژگی‌های کاربرد و نوع تمرین‌ها در جزئیات با مثال‌های دیدگانی بحث می‌شوند، بعد از نظر نظر نظر طراحی نرم‌افزار و تلاش نیاز برای توسعه Platform. بالاخره، توضیح ویژه‌های آینده و توجه‌های آینده پیش‌فرض می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir predstavlja Owoksape, internetsku platformu učenja jezika za manje resursnog jezika Lakota. Lakota jezik (Lakhotiyapi) je Siouan jezik koji se rodi Sjedinjenim Državama s manjim od 2000 tekućih govornika. Owoksape je razvio Zaštita jezika kako bi podržala napore za revitalizaciju, uključujući postizanje mlađih generacija i pružanje alata za dodavanje tradicionalnih metoda učenja. Ovaj projekt je rastao iz različitih multimedijskih resursa kako bi kombinirao njihove najučinkovitije aspekte u jedinstveni, samoporučeni instrument učenja. Prvi dio ovog papira razgovara o motivaciji i pozadini Owoksape. Drugi dio detalja o jezičkim karakteristikama i načelima dokumentacije jezika koji formiraju podkoštanje platforme. Treći dio utvrđuje jedinstvenu integraciju kulturnih aspekta naroda Lakota u vizualni dizajn aplikacije. Odjel 4 objašnjava pedagogičke principe Owoksape. Potom se detaljno raspravljaju o karakteristikama i vrstama vježbe s vizualnim primjerima, slijedeći pregled dizajna softvera, kao i napora potrebne za razvoj platforme. Konačno se predstavlja opis budućih karakteristika i razmišljanja.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz Owoksapy, Lakota diliniň aşagyndaky dil öwrenmek platformyny görkezýär. Lakota dili (Lakhotiyapi) ABŞ-de 2000-nji ýyldan az çykan bir süýür dilidir. Owoksap täzeden durmuşy güýçlemek üçin dil konservasy tarapyndan döredildi. ýa ş döwletlere ýetýär we däpli öwrenme metodlaryny ewirmek üçin bir araç bereldi. Bu projet öz iň täsirli aspektlerini ýeke özi-özi bilen birleştirmek üçin birnäçe multimedianyň çeşmelerinden uly boldy. Bu gazetin ilkinji bölegi Owoksapyň motivasiýasyny we arkaýynda çykýar. 2-nji sany platformyň derjesi we dil dökümentleriniň esaslaryny bejer. Üçüncü bölüm Lakota adamlaryň kültürel aspektlerini uygulamanyň görsel taslamasyna üýtgedýär. Dört sany Owoksapyň pedagogiýaly prinsiplerini düşündirir. Programiň üýtgewleri we pratik hilleri soňra görsel mysal bilen detaylardan çykalýar. Soňra softwaryň dizaynynyň üstüne bir görnöş we platformyň gelişmesi üçin gerekli çabalary bar. Soňunda gelejekde üýtgewler we düşünjelerin waspy görkezildi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini memperkenalkan Owoksape, sebuah platform belajar bahasa online untuk bahasa yang kurang sumber daya Lakota. Bahasa Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) adalah bahasa Siouan yang asli dari Amerika Serikat dengan kurang dari 2000 pembicara fluent. Owoksape dikembangkan oleh The Language Conservancy untuk mendukung usaha revitalisasi, termasuk mencapai generasi muda dan menyediakan alat untuk mendalam metode pengajaran tradisional. Proyek ini tumbuh dari berbagai sumber daya multimedia untuk menggabungkan aspek yang paling efektif mereka menjadi alat belajar tunggal, langkah sendiri. Bagian pertama dari kertas ini mendiskusikan motivasi dan latar belakang Owoksape. Bagian dua rincian ciri-ciri bahasa dan prinsip dokumentasi bahasa yang membentuk tulang belakang platform. Bagian tiga menampilkan integrasi unik dari aspek budaya rakyat Lakota ke desain visual aplikasi. Bagian empat menjelaskan prinsip pedagogi Owoksape. Karakteristik aplikasi dan jenis latihan kemudian didiskusikan secara rinci dengan contoh visual, diikuti oleh overview desain perangkat lunak, serta usaha yang diperlukan untuk mengembangkan platform. Akhirnya, deskripsi ciri-ciri dan pertimbangan masa depan dipaparkan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sq>Ky artikull paraqet Owoksape, një platform ë e mësimit të gjuhës në internet për gjuhën Lakota me pak burime. The Lakota language (Lakhotiyapi) is a Siouan language native to the United States with fewer than 2000 fluent speakers.  Owoksape was developed by The Language Conservancy to support revitalization efforts, including reaching younger generations and providing a tool to complement traditional teaching methods.  Ky projekt u rrit nga burime të ndryshme multimediale me qëllim që të kombinojnë aspektet më të efektshëm të tyre në një mjet të vetme mësimi. Seksioni i parë i këtij artikulli diskuton motivimin dhe sfondin e Owoksape. Seksioni i dytë detalizon karakteristikat gjuhësore dhe parimet e dokumentacionit gjuhësor që formojnë shpinën e platform ës. Sekcioni tre përcakton integrimin unik të aspekteve kulturore të popullit të Lakota në dizajnin vizual të aplikimit. Seksioni katër shpjegon parimet pedagogjike të Owoksape. Application features and exercise types are then discussed in detail with visual examples, followed by an overview of the software design, as well as the effort required to develop the platform.  Finally, a description of future features and considerations is presented.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier stel Owoksape voor 'n online taal leer platforma vir die ondersteunde taal Lakota. Die Lakota taal (Lakhotiyapi) is 'n Sioue taal wat aan die Vereenigde State moet staan, met minder as 2000 fluent sprekkers. Owoksape is ontwikkeld deur die Taal Konservasie om revitaliseeringsversoekte te ondersteun, insluitend om jonger generasies te bereik en 'n hulpmiddel te verskaf om tradisionele onderwerking metodes te voldoen. Hierdie projek het uitgegroei van verskeie multimedia hulpbronne om hul mees effektief aspekte in 'n enkele, self-pakte leer hulpbronne te kombinerer. Die eerste artikel van hierdie papier bespreek die motivasie vir en agtergrond van Owoksape. Seksie twee besonderhede die lingvisse funksies en taal dokumentasie prinsipels wat die backbone van die platforme vorm. Seksie drie lê die unieke integrasie van kulturele aspekte van die Lakota mense in die visuele ontwerp van die toepassing uit. Seksie vier verduidelik die pedagogiese prinsipels van Owoksape. Aansoek funksies en oefening tipes word dan in detail gespreek met visuele voorbeelde, volg deur 'n oorskou van die sagteware ontwerp, en die versoek wat benodig is om die platforma te ontwikkel. Eindelik word 'n beskrywing van toekomstige funksies en aandagings voorgeskryf.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 자원이 부족한 언어인 라코타인을 위한 온라인 언어 학습 플랫폼인 오우크스페이를 소개한다.라코타어(Lakhotiyapi)는 미국에서 원산된 소주족 언어로 유창하게 말하는 사람이 2000명도 안 된다.Owoksape는 언어보호협회가 개발한 것으로 젊은 세대를 대상으로 하는 부흥 사업을 지원하고 전통적인 교수법을 보완하는 도구를 제공하기 위한 것이다.이 프로젝트는 각종 멀티미디어 자원에서 유래한 것으로 가장 효과적인 부분을 단일하고 스스로 진도를 정하는 학습 도구에 결합시키는 데 목적을 둔다.본문의 첫 부분에서 Owoksape의 동기와 배경을 토론하였다.제2절은 플랫폼의 기둥을 구성하는 언어 특징과 언어 문서 원칙을 상세하게 소개했다.세 번째 부분은 라코타인의 문화적 측면을 응용 프로그램의 시각적 디자인에 독특하게 통합시키는 것을 보여준다.4절은 Owoksape의 교학 원칙을 설명했다.그리고 가시화 예시를 통해 응용 프로그램 기능과 연습 유형을 상세하게 토론한 다음에 소프트웨어 디자인과 플랫폼 개발에 필요한 업무를 개괄한다.마지막으로 미래의 특징과 주의사항을 소개했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_hy>Այս հոդվածը ներկայացնում է Օուքսապին, լեզվի սովորելու առցանց հարթակը, որն ունի թերռեսուրսներ ունեցող լեզվի Լեյքոտայի համար: Լեյքոտայի լեզուն (Լեյքոտիապի) ԱՄՆ-ից բնակվող սիուական լեզու է, որն ունի ավելի քիչ քան 2000 հեշտ խոսնակներ: Օուքսափը ստեղծվել է Լեզու պահպանության կողմից, որպեսզի աջակցել վերականգնման ջանքերը, ներառյալ հասնել երիտասարդ սերունդներին և ապահովել միջոց ավանդական ուսուցման մեթոդների ավելացման համար: Այս նախագիծը բազմաթիվ մեդիայի ռեսուրսներից օգտագործվեց, որպեսզի միավորվի իրենց ամենաարդյունավետ ասպեկտները մի միակ, ինքնաարագ ուսուցման գործիքի: Այս աշխատանքի առաջին հատվածը քննարկում է Օուքսափի մոտիվացիայի և հետևի մասին: Section two details the linguistic features and language documentation principles that form the backbone of the platform.  Section three lays out the unique integration of cultural aspects of the Lakota people into the visual design of the application.  Չորրորդ հատվածը բացատրում է Օուքսափի pedagoգիական սկզբունքները: Այնուհետև ծրագրային հատկությունները և վարժությունների տեսակները մանրամասն քննարկվում են տեսողական օրինակների հետ, հետևում է ծրագրային ծրագրի դիզայնի վերաբերյալ, ինչպես նաև հարթակի զարգացման համար անհրաժեշտ ջանքերը: Finally, a description of future features and considerations is presented.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_sw>Makala hii inaonyesha Owoksape, jukwaa la kujifunza lugha za mtandaoni kwa lugha ya Lakota isiyo na rasmi. Lugha ya Lakota (Lakhotiyapi) ni lugha ya Kisiou anayeishi Marekani yenye wazungumzaji wachache zaidi ya milipuko 2000. Owoksape iliundwa na Utetezi wa Lugha ili kuunga mkono jitihada za upya, ikiwa ni pamoja na kufikia vizazi vijana na kutoa zana ya kuumiza njia za utamaduni. Mradi huu ulitokana na rasilimali mbalimbali za mitandao ili kuunganisha vipengele vyao vyenye ufanisi zaidi katika zana ya kujifunza pekee. The first section of this paper discusses the motivation for and background of Owoksape.  Sehemu mbili zinaelezea vipengele vya lugha na kanuni za nyaraka za lugha zinazotengeneza mgongo wa jukwaa hilo. Sehemu tatu inatengeneza ushirikiano wa kipekee wa masuala ya kitamaduni ya watu wa Lakota katika ubunifu wa maombi. Sehemu ya nne inaeleza kanuni za kitaaluma za Owoksape. Tamko za matumizi na aina za mazoezi baadae hujadiliwa kwa kina kwa mifano ya kuona, kufuatia mtazamo wa ubunifu wa programu, pamoja na juhudi zinazohitajika kuendeleza jukwaa hili. Mwisho, maelezo ya tabia za baadae na maoni yanaonyeshwa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকা অওকস্পেকে অনলাইন ভাষা শিক্ষা প্ল্যাটফর্ম উপস্থাপন করেছে লাকোটার জন্য। লাকোতা ভাষা (লাখোটিয়াপি) হচ্ছে যুক্তরাষ্ট্রের স্থানীয় সিউয়ান ভাষা, যার মধ্যে ২০০০ এর চেয়ে কম ফ্লুয়েন্ট ভাষাকার অওকসেপে ভাষা রক্ষণকে পুনরায় প্রচেষ্টার সমর্থন করার জন্য উন্নয়ন করেছে, যার মধ্যে তরুণ প্রজন্মের কাছে পৌঁছানো এবং ঐতিহ্যবাহী শিক্ষা  এই প্রকল্পটি বিভিন্ন মাল্টিমিডিয়া সম্পদ থেকে উৎপাদন করেছে যাতে তাদের সবচেয়ে কার্যকর প্রাক্ষাপগুলোকে একটি স্বয়ংক এই পত্রিকার প্রথম অংশ ওওওক্সপের উদ্দেশ্য এবং পটভূমির প্রচেষ্টা নিয়ে আলোচনা করেছে। Section two details the linguistic features and language documentation principles that form the backbone of the platform.  তিনটি বিভাগ ল্যাকোতার লাকোতাদের সাংস্কৃতিক বিষয়গুলোর একত্রিত করার বিষয়টি এই অ্যাপ্লিকেশনের দৃশ্যমান ডিজাইন বিভাগ চার ব্যাখ্যা করেছে ওওওকস্পের শিক্ষাগত নীতি। Application features and exercise types are then discussed in detail with visual examples, followed by an overview of the software design, as well as the effort required to develop the platform.  অবশেষে, ভবিষ্যতের বৈশিষ্ট্য এবং বিবেচনা সম্পর্কে বর্ণনা করা হয়েছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt Lakota dili altındakı dillərin online dil öyrənmə platformu Owoksape'i göstərir. Lakota dili (Lakhotiyapi) Birləşik Devletlərdə olan Siouan dilidir. Owoksape yenidən diriləcək çabalarını dəstəkləmək üçün dil konservancası tarafından tədbir edildi. Genç nəsillərə çatmaq və nəticəli öyrənmə metodlarını tamamlamaq üçün bir vasitə təmin edir. Bu proyekt müxtəlif multimedia kaynaqlarından böyükdü ki, onların ən efektiv aspektlərini tək, özü-tərəfli öyrənmə aracı ilə birləşdirmək üçün. Bu kağıdın ilk bölümü Owoksape'in motivasyonu və arxa plan barəsində mübahisə edir. İki ayrılıq platformunun arka sümüklərini olub dil təhsil və dil təhsil qanunları. Üçüncü bölüm Lakota insanların kültürlü aspektlərinin ünsiyyətini uygulamağının vizuali dizaynına qoyur. Dördüncü bölüm Owoksape'in pedagojik prinsiplərini açıqlayır. Sonra uyğulama özellikləri və təhsil növlərini görünür misalları ilə detaylı mübahisə edirlər. Sonra proqramın dizaynının üstünlüyü və platformu təhsil etmək üçün ehtiyacı olan çabalar. Sonunda gələcək fəaliyyətlərin və düşüncələrin təsbiqi göstərildi.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir predstavlja Owoksape, internetsku platformu učenja jezika za manje resursnog jezika Lakota. Lakota jezik (Lakhotiyapi) je Siouan jezik koji se rodi Sjedinjenim Državama sa manje od 2000 tekućih govornika. Owoksape je razvila Konservacija jezika za podršku napora za revitalizaciju, uključujući postizanje mlađih generacija i pružanje alata za dodavanje tradicionalnih metoda učenja. Ovaj projekt je rastao iz različitih multimedijskih resursa kako bi kombinirao svoje najefikasnije aspekte u jedno, samoporučeno učenje. Prvi dio ovog papira razgovara o motivaciji i pozadini Owoksape. Drugi dio detalja o jezičkim karakteristikama i principima za dokumentaciju jezika koji formiraju leđa platforme. Treća odjela utvrđuje jedinstvenu integraciju kulturnih aspekta naroda Lakota u vizualni dizajn aplikacije. Odjel 4 objašnjava pedagogičke principe Owoksape. Onda se detaljno raspravljaju o karakteristikama i vrstama vježbe s vizualnim primjerima, slijedeći pregled dizajna softvera, kao i napora potrebne za razvoj platforme. Konačno se predstavlja opis budućih karakteristika i razmatranja.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_am>ይህች ገጽ ለቋንቋ ቋንቋ መምህርት የኢንተርኔት ቋንቋ መምህርት ፕሮግራም የኦዎክስፓን ያቀርባል፡፡ ላቁታ ቋንቋ (Lakhotiyapi) ከ2000 የበለጠ የውሃ ቋንቋዎች የሚያንስ የአሜሪካ ቋንቋ ነው፡፡ ኦኦክስፔ የሕግ ትውልድ ትውልድ እንዲደርስ እና ለትምህርት ትምህርት ማድረግ ማቀናጃ እንዲሞላ የቋንቋ አገልግሎት ተደጋጅቷል፡፡ ይሄ ፕሮጀክት በተለየ ብዛት ሚዲያ ሀብት አካባቢ ጉዳዮቻቸውን በአንድ አንዲት፣ ለራሱ የተማረ መማር ዕቃ ለመቀላቀል ያቆመ፡፡ The first section of this paper discusses the motivation for and background of Owoksape.  የቋንቋው ግንኙነት እና የቋንቋ አካላት ሥርዓት መክፈቻ የፕላጦማር ጀርባ የሚያደርጉትን ጥረቶች ሁለት ግልጽዎች፡፡ በሦስት ክፍል ለሎኮታ ሰዎች የባሕላዊ ጉዳይ የግንኙነት ጉዳይ ወደ ፕሮግራሙን የራእይ አካባቢ እንዲያሳየው ነው፡፡ ክፍለ አራት የኦኦኦክስፓን የትምህርት መሠረት ይናገራል፡፡ የፕሮግራም ምርጫዎች እና የፕሮግራም ዓይነቶች በተጨማሪው በተለያዩ በተለያዩ ምሳሌዎች፣ በተጨማሪም የሶፍትዌር ጥናት ማየት እና ፕሮግራሙን ለመግኘት የሚያስፈልገውን ድጋፍ ይታወቃል፡፡ በመጨረሻው የኋለኛይቱ የአፍሪካ ምርጫዎች እና አስተያየት መግለጫ ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa esitellään Owoksape, verkkokielinen kieltenoppimisalusta vajavaiselle kielelle lakota. Lakotan kieli (Lakhotiyapi) on Yhdysvalloissa syntyperäinen Siouan kieli, jolla on alle 2000 sujuvaa puhujaa. The Language Conservancy kehitti Owoksapen tukemaan elvyttämistoimia, mukaan lukien nuorempien sukupolvien tavoittaminen ja perinteisten opetusmenetelmien täydentäminen. Hankkeessa hyödynnettiin erilaisia multimediaresursseja yhdistääkseen niiden tehokkaimmat puolet yhdeksi omatoimiseksi oppimisvälineeksi. Työn ensimmäisessä osassa käsitellään Owoksapen motivaatiota ja taustaa. Toisessa jaksossa esitellään foorumin selkärankana olevat kielelliset ominaisuudet ja kielidokumentointiperiaatteet. Kolmannessa osassa esitellään lakotalaisten kulttuuristen näkökohtien ainutlaatuinen integrointi sovelluksen visuaaliseen suunnitteluun. Osassa neljä kerrotaan Owoksapen pedagogisista periaatteista. Sovellusominaisuuksista ja harjoitustyypeistä keskustellaan yksityiskohtaisesti visuaalisten esimerkkien avulla, minkä jälkeen luodaan yleiskatsaus ohjelmistosuunnitteluun sekä alustan kehittämiseen tarvittavaan työhön. Lopuksi esitetään kuvaus tulevista ominaisuuksista ja huomioista.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest article presenta Owoksape, una plataforma d'aprenentatge de llenguatges en línia per a la llengua Lakota amb menys recursos. The Lakota language (Lakhotiyapi) is a Siouan language native to the United States with fewer than 2000 fluent speakers.  L'Owoksape va ser desenvolupat per The Language Conservance per sostenir els esforços de revitalització, incloent arribar a generacions joves i proporcionar una eina per complementar els mètodes tradicionals d'ensenyament. This project grew out of various multimedia resources in order to combine their most effective aspects into a single, self-paced learning tool.  La primera secció d'aquest paper discute la motivació i el fons d'Owoksape. La segona secció detalla les característiques lingüístices i principis de documentació lingüística que formen la columna vertebral de la plataforma. La tercera secció mostra l'integració única dels aspectes culturals de la població de Lakota en el disseny visual de l'aplicació. La quarta secció explica els principis pedagògics d'Owoksape. Les característiques de l'aplicació i els tipus d'exercici es discuten en detall amb exemples visuals, seguits d'una visió general del disseny del software, i l'esforç requerit per desenvolupar la plataforma. Finalment, es presenta una descripció de les característiques i consideracions futures.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek představuje Owoksape, online platformu pro výuku jazyků pro nedostatečně zdrojovaný jazyk Lakota. Lakota jazyk (Lakhotiyapi) je siouanský jazyk rodilý ze Spojených států s méně než 2000 plynnými mluvčími. Owoksape byl vyvinut The Language Conservancy na podporu revitalizačního úsilí, včetně oslovení mladších generací a poskytování nástroje pro doplnění tradičních metod výuky. Tento projekt vyrostl z různých multimediálních zdrojů s cílem spojit jejich nejefektivnější aspekty do jediného, samostatného učebního nástroje. První část tohoto článku pojednává o motivaci a pozadí Owoksape. Druhá část popisuje jazykové rysy a principy jazykové dokumentace, které tvoří páteř platformy. Třetí část popisuje unikátní integraci kulturních aspektů Lakotů do vizuálního designu aplikace. Čtvrtá část vysvětluje pedagogické principy Owoksape. Funkce aplikací a typy cvičení jsou následně podrobně diskutovány na vizuálních příkladech, následně přehled návrhu softwaru a úsilí potřebné k vývoji platformy. V závěru je uveden popis budoucích vlastností a úvah.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas töös tutvustatakse Owoksape'i, veebipõhist keeleõppeplatvormi alaressurssidega lakota keele jaoks. Lakota keel (Lakhotiyapi) on Ameerika Ühendriikide emakeel, kus kõneleb vähem kui 2000 vabalt. Owoksape töötas välja The Language Conservancy, et toetada elavdamisjõupingutusi, sealhulgas jõuda noorematele põlvkondadele ja pakkuda vahendit traditsiooniliste õpetamismeetodite täiendamiseks. See projekt kasvas välja mitmesugustest multimeediaressurssidest, et ühendada nende kõige tõhusamad aspektid üheks enesetempoliseks õppevahendiks. Käesoleva artikli esimeses osas käsitletakse Owoksape motivatsiooni ja tausta. Teises jaos kirjeldatakse platvormi selgroogu moodustavaid keelelisi omadusi ja keeledokumentatsiooni põhimõtteid. Kolmas jagu kirjeldab Lakota rahva kultuuriliste aspektide unikaalset integreerimist rakenduse visuaalsesse disaini. Neljas osa selgitab Owoksape pedagoogilisi põhimõtteid. Seejärel arutatakse üksikasjalikult rakenduse funktsioone ja harjutuste tüüpe visuaalsete näidetega, millele järgneb ülevaade tarkvara disainist ja platvormi arendamiseks vajalikest jõupingutustest. Lõpuks esitatakse tulevaste omaduste ja kaalutluste kirjeldus.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>Gambar iki bakal ning Owaksape, banget online kanggo kelas nang Lakota. Lakota lang Owaksape wis dipoleh Perancis Language Proyek iki lak akeh akeh liyane sing sampeyan Multimedia kanggo ngubah sing titimbane neng sistem sing apik, sampeyan sampeyan. Seksi perusahaan karo pepul iki ngrungkasi tarjamahan kanggo ndebok karo Owaksape Seksi durung ono langkung kelompok nggunaké kesempatan lan basa dokumen anyar kuwi nggawe bukal karo sistem. Seksi telu nggawe akeh unik neng sampek anyar tentang kanggo ngilangno Lakota wong liyane ing nguasar winih kanggo ngilangno aplikasi. section 4 Kapan aplikasi lan akeh nyong langgar sampeyan ngubah akeh nyong bisa mlebu kanggo ngerasakno ning bisala anyar, supoyo ngewehi nggawe ngubah ceringan perangkat-sistem, lan akeh nyong nggawe sistem sing takon nggawe sistem. Tulung, nggambaran pawaran karo hal-hal kanggo nggunakaké</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku je predstavljena Owoksape, spletna platforma za učenje jezikov za jezik Lakota s premalo virov. Lakota jezik (Lakhotiyapi) je jezik Siouan, ki izvira iz Združenih držav Amerike z manj kot 2000 tekočimi govorci. Owoksape je razvil The Language Conservancy za podporo revitalizacijskim prizadevanjem, vključno z doseganjem mlajših generacij in zagotavljanjem orodja za dopolnitev tradicionalnih metod poučevanja. Ta projekt je nastal iz različnih multimedijskih virov, da bi njihove najučinkovitejše vidike združil v eno samostojno orodje za učenje. Prvi del prispevka obravnava motivacijo in ozadje Owoksape. Drugi del podrobno opisuje jezikovne značilnosti in načela jezikovne dokumentacije, ki tvorijo hrbtenico platforme. Tretji del predstavlja edinstveno vključevanje kulturnih vidikov ljudi Lakote v vizualno oblikovanje aplikacije. Četrti del pojasnjuje pedagoška načela Owoksape. Značilnosti aplikacij in vrste vadb so nato podrobno obravnavane z vizualnimi primeri, sledi pregled zasnove programske opreme in naporov, potrebnih za razvoj platforme. Nazadnje je predstavljen opis prihodnjih značilnosti in premislekov.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Wannan karatun na gaurar da Owokspe, wata platform na sanar da harshen na ɗabi'a Lakota. Lughan Lakota (Lakhotyapti) yana da harshen Siouki wanda ke natinsa zuwa Marekani, da sauran mafiya ƙaranci daga 2000. An developed Owokspe by the Lugha tsare for a ƙarfafa aikin kurriga, ikin ya kai ƙarami sauri, kuma ya sami zance da ya cika hanyoyin ayuka na'ura. Wannan Projekt ya fita daga manyan multi-dabam, dõmin ya haɗa masu mafi masu amfani da su zuwa zanen kwamfyuta mai amfani da jiɓinta ta. Babban farkon takardan wannan na yi muhimmin da aka yi amfani da bakin Owokscape. Babu biyu ana bayyana kayan tsarin masu cikin linguistic da kayan takardar takardar harshen waɗanda ke tsare bakin bangon wannan platform. Seki uku na samun haɗi da akan tamadun da mutane na Lakota ke cikin shirin ayukan ayuka. Bayani huɗu yana bayyana kimada na Owokscape. Furofati na Shiryoyin Ayuka da za'a yi musu magana a bayan bayani da misãlai masu gani, wanda aka daba wani surowa wa zauren shiryoyin ayuka, da kuma aikin da za'a buɗe wannan platform. Ga ƙarshe, an zo da bayani ga wasu tayari na buƙata da kalmõmi.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་ཕན་འབྱུང་བའི་སྐད་རིགས་ལ་ཉེ་གནས་ཀྱི་སྐད་ཀྱི་ཤོག་བྱང་ཆ་ཁོ་ཝེ་པོ་ཞིག་ལ་སྟོན་པ་རེད། ཨ་རིའི་སྐད་ཀྱི་ལཀོ་ཊ་སིའི་སྐད་ཡིག་གཅིག་ནི་ཨ་རིའི་ཐོག་ལས་དུང་ཕྱུར་བའི་སྐད་རིགས་ཤིག་རེད། Owoksape ནི་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་ལྟ་རྒྱབ་སྐྱོར་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་རྒྱབ་སྐྱོར་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཆེད་དུ་ཡར་རྒྱས་གཏོང་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ཤེས་དང་ཆ་རྐྱེན་ཚུན ལས་འགུལ་འདིས་སྒྲ་བརྙན་ནང་ལས་ཆ་འཕྲིན་འགྱུར་བ་རྐྱེན་བྱུང་བ་རེད། དེ་ནི་ཁོང་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་གླེང་སྒྲུབ་ཀྱི་ཆེས་ཤུ ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ཆ་དང་པོ་དེ་ནི་Owoksape ཡི་རྒྱབ་ལྗོངས་ཀྱི་རྒུལ་སྐྱེན་དང་རྒྱབ་ལྗོངས་འདི་བཤད་ཡོད། སྐད་རིགས་ཀྱི་ཆ་ཁོངས་དང་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་ཡིག་ཆ་གི་རྩོམ་པ་གཉིས་དབྱེ་སྟངས་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་བཏོན་ཡོད། དབྱེ་ཚན་གསུམ་པ་དེ་ལ་ཀོ་ཁ་མི་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་རིག་སྲོལ་རྒྱུན་གྱི་ཆ་རྐྱེན་ཀྱི་ཁྱད་ཆོས་སྒྲིག་འཇུག་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། དབྱེ་ཚན་འདི་བཞིན་དེ་Owoksape-ཡི་སྒྲ་ཚིགས་ཤིག་གི་ཐབས་ལམ་དེ་འགྲེལ་བཤད་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ཉེར་སྤྱོད་ཆ་འཆར་དང་སྣུམ་གྱི་རིགས་དག་ཚང་མིན་ན་གསལ་བཤད་ནས་གསལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་དཔེར་ན། མཐའ་མར་མ་དེར། མ་འོངས་པའི་ཁྱད་ཆོས་དང་བསམ་བློ་གཏད་ཀྱི་འགྲེལ་བཤད་སྟོན་ཡོད།</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>העיתון הזה מציג את אווקסיפ, פלטפורמת לימוד שפות באינטרנט לשפה הלקוטה עם פחות משאבים. שפת ליקוטה (Lakhotiyapi) היא שפת סיואנית מקומית לארצות הברית Owoksape was developed by The Language Conservancy to support revitalization efforts, including reaching younger generations and providing a tool to complement traditional teaching methods.  הפרויקט הזה גדל מתוך משאבים מולטימדיה שונים כדי לשלב את היבטים הכי יעילים שלהם לתוך כלי לימוד אחד, במהירות עצמית. החלק הראשון של העיתון הזה מדבר על המוטיבציה ולרקע של אווקסיפ. המחלקה השנייה מפרט את תכונות השפה ועקרונות תיעוד השפה שמוצרים את עצמת הגב של הפלטפורמה. החלק השלישי מציג את האינטגרציה הייחודית של היבטים התרבותיים של אנשי ליקוטה לתכנית ויזואלית של התוכנית. Section four explains the pedagogical principles of Owoksape.  Application features and exercise types are then discussed in detail with visual examples, followed by an overview of the software design, as well as the effort required to develop the platform.  סוף סוף, תיאור של תכונות ותחשבות עתידים מוצג.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="51">
      <title>Speech Transcription Challenges for Resource Constrained Indigenous Language Cree<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ree</title>
      <author><first>Vishwa</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Gilles</first><last>Boulianne</last></author>
      <pages>362–367</pages>
      <abstract>Cree is one of the most spoken Indigenous languages in Canada. From a speech recognition perspective, it is a low-resource language, since very little data is available for either acoustic or language modeling. This has prevented development of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_technology">speech technology</a> that could help revitalize the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">language</a>. We describe our experiments with available Cree data to improve <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transcription_(biology)">automatic transcription</a> both in speaker- independent and dependent scenarios. While it was difficult to get low speaker-independent word error rates with only six speakers, we were able to get low word and phoneme error rates in the speaker-dependent scenario. We compare our phoneme recognition with two state-of-the-art open-source phoneme recognition toolkits, which use end-to-end training and sequence-to-sequence modeling. Our phoneme error rate (8.7 %) is significantly lower than that achieved by the best of these systems (15.1 %). With these systems and varying amounts of transcribed and text data, we show that pre-training on other languages is important for speaker-independent recognition, and even small amounts of additional text-only documents are useful. These results can guide practical language documentation work, when deciding how much transcribed and text data is needed to achieve useful phoneme accuracies.</abstract>
      <url hash="5d9bcbea">2020.sltu-1.51</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>gupta-boulianne-2020-speech</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>