<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.clssts">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the workshop on Cross-Language Search and Summarization of Text and Speech (CLSSTS2020)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Kathy</first><last>McKeown</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Douglas W.</first><last>Oard</last></editor>
      <editor><first /><last>Elizabeth</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Richard</first><last>Schwartz</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-55-9</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="27b49c1f">2020.clssts-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>clssts-2020-cross</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>SEARCHER : Shared Embedding Architecture for Effective Retrieval<fixed-case>SEARCHER</fixed-case>: Shared Embedding Architecture for Effective Retrieval</title>
      <author><first>Joel</first><last>Barry</last></author>
      <author><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Boschee</last></author>
      <author><first>Marjorie</first><last>Freedman</last></author>
      <author><first>Scott</first><last>Miller</last></author>
      <pages>22–25</pages>
      <abstract>We describe an approach to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-lingual_information_retrieval">cross lingual information retrieval</a> that does not rely on explicit translation of either document or query terms. Instead, both queries and documents are mapped into a shared embedding space where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">retrieval</a> is performed. We discuss potential advantages of the approach in handling <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polysemy">polysemy</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synonym_(taxonomy)">synonymy</a>. We present a method for training the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a>, and give details of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> implementation. We present experimental results for two cases : Somali-English and Bulgarian-English CLIR.</abstract>
      <url hash="daff9c04">2020.clssts-1.4</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>barry-etal-2020-searcher</bibkey>
    <title_pt>SEARCHER: Arquitetura de Incorporação Compartilhada para Recuperação Eficaz</title_pt>
      <title_ar>SEARCHER: هندسة التضمين المشتركة من أجل الاسترداد الفعال</title_ar>
      <title_es>BUSCADOR: Arquitectura de incrustación compartida para una recuperación eficaz</title_es>
      <title_zh>搜索器:共嵌体系结构</title_zh>
      <title_ja>検索ツール:効果的な検索のための共有埋め込みアーキテクチャ</title_ja>
      <title_hi>खोजकर्ता: प्रभावी पुनर्प्राप्ति के लिए साझा एम्बेडिंग आर्किटेक्चर</title_hi>
      <title_ga>SEARCHER: Ailtireacht Leabú Comhroinnte le hAghaidh Aisghabhála Éifeachtach</title_ga>
      <title_el>ΑΝΑΖΗΤΗΣΗΣ: Κοινή αρχιτεκτονική ενσωμάτωσης για αποτελεσματική ανάκτηση</title_el>
      <title_hu>Keresés: Megosztott beágyazási architektúra a hatékony visszaszerezés érdekében</title_hu>
      <title_ka>Constellation name (optional)</title_ka>
      <title_it>SEARCHER: architettura di embedding condivisa per un recupero efficace</title_it>
      <title_kk>САРКАТЫ: Эффективті алу үшін ортақтастырылған ендіру архитектурасы</title_kk>
      <title_mk>SEARCHER: Shared Embedding Architecture for Effective Retrieval</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Constellation name (optional)</title_ms>
      <title_ml>സെയാര്‍ച്ചര്‍: സാക്ഷ്യമായ വീണ്ടെടുക്കുന്നതിനായി പങ്കുചേര്‍ത്ത എംബെഡിങ്ങ് ആര്‍ക്ടിക്കറ്റ</title_ml>
      <title_mt>SEARCHER: arkitettura inkorporata kondiviża għall-kisba effettiva</title_mt>
      <title_mn>ШАБЛАГАН: Эффектив авах үед хуваалцагдаг бүтээгдэхүүний архитектур</title_mn>
      <title_no>Constellation name (optional)</title_no>
      <title_pl>SEARCHER: Wspólna architektura osadzania dla skutecznego odzyskiwania</title_pl>
      <title_ro>CĂUTARE: Arhitectură partajată de încorporare pentru recuperarea eficientă</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Оделена архитектура за ефективно получене</title_sr>
      <title_si>පරීක්ෂක: ප්‍රභාවිත පිළිගන්න සඳහා සම්බන්ධ සංවිධානය</title_si>
      <title_lt>Bendra įdiegta veiksmingo gavimo architektūra</title_lt>
      <title_so>SEARCHER: Shared Embedding Architecture for Effective Retrieval</title_so>
      <title_sv>SÖKER: Delad inbäddningsarkitektur för effektiv hämtning</title_sv>
      <title_ta>SEARCHER: விளைவான திரும்பப்பெறுவதற்கான பகிர்ந்த உட்பொதித் திட்டம்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>جشنگر: فعالی اٹھانے کے لئے شریک ایمبڈینگ آرکیٹر</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Tìm kiếm: Kiến trúc chung để lấy lại hiệu quả</title_vi>
      <title_uz>SEARCHER: Effektiv tiklash uchun boʻlishilgan embedded architecture</title_uz>
      <title_bg>ТАРЧЕР: Споделена архитектура за вграждане за ефективно извличане</title_bg>
      <title_hr>SEČARČE: Dijeljena arhitektura za uključenje učinkovitog primanja</title_hr>
      <title_da>Søger: Delt indlejringsarkitektur for effektiv hentning</title_da>
      <title_nl>SEARCHER: Gedeelde Embedding Architecture voor effectieve Retrieval</title_nl>
      <title_fa>ساختار داخلی برای بازیابی تاثیر</title_fa>
      <title_id>Pencari: Shared Embedding Architecture for Effective Retrieval</title_id>
      <title_ko>SEARCHER: 효과적인 검색을 위한 공유 내장 구조</title_ko>
      <title_de>SEARCHER: Gemeinsame Einbettungsarchitektur für effektives Abrufen</title_de>
      <title_sw>SEARCHER: Udhibiti wa makazi yanayoshirikishwa kwa ajili ya kurejeshwa kwa ufanisi</title_sw>
      <title_af>Constellation name (optional)</title_af>
      <title_tr>DELABOşy: Efektiv Mazmunlar üçin Bölünmek Arhitektura</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Arkitektura e përbashkët e përfshirjes për marrje efektive</title_sq>
      <title_am>ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_az>SEARCHOR: Efektiv almaq üçün paylaşılmış Bölünmə Arhitektura</title_az>
      <title_bn>সেয়ার্চার: কার্যকর পুনরুদ্ধারের জন্য বেডিং আর্কিচেক্ট শেয়ার করা হয়েছে</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Ավելի արդյունավետ վերադարձման համար ընդգրկված արխիկտուր</title_hy>
      <title_bs>Podijeljena arhitektura za učinkovito uzdržavanje</title_bs>
      <title_ca>ARCÍTEL: Arquitectura integrada compartida per a obtenir efectivament</title_ca>
      <title_cs>SEARCHER: Sdílená architektura vložení pro efektivní vyhledávání</title_cs>
      <title_et>SEARCHER: Jagatud manustamise arhitektuur tõhusaks taastamiseks</title_et>
      <title_fi>SEARCHER: Jaettu upotusarkkitehtuuri tehokkaaseen noutoon</title_fi>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_jv>architecture</title_jv>
      <title_he>מחפש: ארכיטקטורה משותפת להשיגה אפקטיבית</title_he>
      <title_sk>SEARCHER: Skupna arhitektura vdelave za učinkovito pridobivanje</title_sk>
      <title_bo>SEARCHER: Shared Embedding Architecture for Effective Retrieval</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نحن نصف نهجًا لاسترجاع المعلومات اللغوية المتقاطعة لا يعتمد على الترجمة الصريحة لأي من مصطلحات المستند أو الاستعلام. بدلاً من ذلك ، يتم تعيين كل من الاستعلامات والمستندات في مساحة تضمين مشتركة حيث يتم إجراء الاسترداد. نناقش المزايا المحتملة للنهج في التعامل مع تعدد المعاني والمرادفات. نقدم طريقة لتدريب النموذج ، ونعطي تفاصيل عن تنفيذ النموذج. نقدم نتائج تجريبية لحالتين: الصومالية-الإنجليزية والبلغارية-الإنجليزية CLIR.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Descrevemos uma abordagem para recuperação de informações em vários idiomas que não depende da tradução explícita de documentos ou termos de consulta. Em vez disso, as consultas e os documentos são mapeados em um espaço de incorporação compartilhado onde a recuperação é executada. Discutimos as vantagens potenciais da abordagem no tratamento de polissemia e sinonímia. Apresentamos um método para treinar o modelo e detalhamos a implementação do modelo. Apresentamos resultados experimentais para dois casos: CLIR somali-inglês e búlgaro-inglês.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Describimos un enfoque para la recuperación de información en varios idiomas que no se basa en la traducción explícita de los términos del documento o de la consulta. En cambio, tanto las consultas como los documentos se asignan a un espacio de incrustación compartido donde se realiza la recuperación. Discutimos las posibles ventajas del enfoque en el manejo de la polisemia y la sinonimia. Presentamos un método para entrenar el modelo y damos detalles de la implementación del modelo. Presentamos los resultados experimentales de dos casos: CLIR somalí-inglés y búlgaro-inglés.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>私たちは、文書またはクエリ用語のいずれかの明示的な翻訳に依存しない、言語間情報検索のアプローチを説明します。代わりに、クエリとドキュメントの両方が、取得が実行される共有埋め込みスペースにマッピングされます。多義性と同義語を扱う際のアプローチの潜在的な利点について考察します。モデルをトレーニングする方法を提示し、モデルの実装の詳細を説明します。ソマリ-英語とブルガリア-英語のCLIRの2つのケースの実験結果を提示します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>述跨语信息检索法,不依文档询显式译。 询与文档俱映行检者共嵌空中。 论其方多义性与同义词之善势。 吾为之教模之法,而与之细节。 二病例之实验:索马里语-英语、保加利亚语-英语CLIR。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम पार भाषाई जानकारी पुनर्प्राप्ति के लिए एक दृष्टिकोण का वर्णन करते हैं जो या तो दस्तावेज़ या क्वेरी शर्तों के स्पष्ट अनुवाद पर भरोसा नहीं करता है। इसके बजाय, क्वेरीज़ और दस्तावेज़ दोनों को एक साझा एम्बेडिंग स्थान में मैप किया जाता है जहाँ पुनर्प्राप्ति की जाती है। हम polysemy और पर्यायवाची से निपटने में दृष्टिकोण के संभावित लाभों पर चर्चा करते हैं। हम मॉडल को प्रशिक्षित करने के लिए एक विधि प्रस्तुत करते हैं, और मॉडल कार्यान्वयन का विवरण देते हैं। हम दो मामलों के लिए प्रयोगात्मक परिणाम प्रस्तुत करते हैं: सोमाली-अंग्रेजी और बल्गेरियाई-अंग्रेजी सीएलआईआर।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Déanaimid cur síos ar chur chuige maidir le haisghabháil faisnéise trasteangacha nach bhfuil ag brath ar aistriúchán follasach ar théarmaí doiciméad nó ceiste. Ina áit sin, déantar ceisteanna agus doiciméid a mhapáil isteach i spás leabaithe roinnte ina ndéantar iad a aisghabháil. Pléimid buntáistí féideartha an chur chuige maidir le láimhseáil polysemy agus comhchiall. Cuirimid modh i láthair chun an tsamhail a oiliúint, agus tugaimid sonraí ar fheidhmiú an mhúnla. Cuirimid torthaí turgnamhacha i láthair do dhá chás: Somáilis-Béarla agus Bulgáiris-Béarla CLIR.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Περιγράφουμε μια προσέγγιση για την ανάκτηση πληροφοριών που δεν βασίζεται στη ρητή μετάφραση είτε των όρων εγγράφου είτε ερωτήματος. Αντίθετα, τόσο τα ερωτήματα όσο και τα έγγραφα αντιστοιχίζονται σε έναν κοινόχρηστο χώρο ενσωμάτωσης όπου πραγματοποιείται ανάκτηση. Συζητούμε τα πιθανά πλεονεκτήματα της προσέγγισης στον χειρισμό της πολυσεμίας και της συνώνυμης. Παρουσιάζουμε μια μέθοδο για την εκπαίδευση του μοντέλου και δίνουμε λεπτομέρειες για την εφαρμογή του μοντέλου. Παρουσιάζουμε πειραματικά αποτελέσματα για δύο περιπτώσεις: Σομαλ-Αγγλικά και Βουλγαρ-Αγγλικά CLIR.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Olyan megközelítést írunk le, amely nem támaszkodik sem dokumentum, sem lekérdezés kifejezéseinek kifejezett fordítására. Ehelyett mind a lekérdezések, mind a dokumentumok lekérdezése egy megosztott beágyazási területbe kerül, ahol a visszakeresés végrehajtásra kerül. Beszéljük a megközelítés lehetséges előnyeit a poliszémia és a szinonimák kezelésében. Bemutatjuk a modell képzésének módszerét, és részletesen bemutatjuk a modell megvalósítását. Két kísérleti eredményt mutatunk be: szomáliai-angol és bolgár-angol CLIR.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ჩვენ განახსენებთ ენგუმენტის ინფორმაციის გაკვირთვის პროგრამა, რომელიც არ განახსენებულია კოკუმენტის ან კითხვის სიტყვების გაკვირთვის. მაშინ, ორივე კითხვები და დოკუმენტები იქნება საზოგადოებულ დამატებული სივრცეში, სადაც მიიღება მოქმედება. ჩვენ განსაკუთრებით პოლისემის და სინონიმის პოლისემის შესაძლებლობა. ჩვენ მოდელის შემწყვებას მეტი და მოდელის შემწყვებას დეტალები. ჩვენ ექსპერიმენტიური წარმოდგენება ორი შემთხვევაში: Somali-English და Bulgarian-English CLIR.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_it>Descriviamo un approccio al recupero di informazioni multilingue che non si basa sulla traduzione esplicita di termini di documento o query. Invece, sia le query che i documenti vengono mappati in uno spazio di incorporazione condiviso in cui viene eseguito il recupero. Discutiamo i potenziali vantaggi dell'approccio nella gestione della polisemia e della sinonimia. Presentiamo un metodo per formare il modello e diamo dettagli sull'implementazione del modello. Presentiamo i risultati sperimentali per due casi: somalo-inglese e bulgaro-inglese CLIR.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Біз тілді мәліметті алу арқылы құжат не сұраныс терминлердің түсінікті аудармасына тәуелді таңдаймыз. Осының орнына, сұраныс мен құжаттардың екеуі жалғастырылған ендіру орынға карталады. Біз полиземияны және синонимияны қамтамасыз ету үшін қолдануға мүмкіндік артықшылықтарды талқылаймыз. Біз үлгі оқыту әдісін келтіріп, үлгі іске асыру үшін егжей- тегжейін береміз. Екі жағдай туралы эксперименталдық нәтижелерін таңдаймыз: Сомали-ағылшын және Болгария-ағылшын CLIR.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Mes apibūdiname požiūrį į tarpkalbinę informacijos gavimą, kuris nesiremia aiškiu nei dokumentų, nei klausimo terminų vertimu. Vietoj to, tiek klausimai, tiek dokumentai yra mapuojami į bendrą įterpimo erdvę, kurioje atliekamas paieškas. Mes aptariame galimus požiūrio pranašumus, susijusius su polisemija ir sinonimija. Pateikiame modelio mokymo metodą ir išsamiai aprašome modelio įgyvendinimą. Pateikiame eksperimentinius rezultatus dviem atvejais: Somalio-anglų ir Bulgarijos-anglų CLIR.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Ние опишуваме пристап до крстојачното преземање на информации кои не се потпираат на експлицитно преведување на документите или термините на прашањето. Наместо тоа, и прашањата и документите се мапирани во заеднички вставен простор каде што се извршува преземањето. Разговараме за потенцијалните предности на пристапот во справувањето со полисимијата и синонимијата. Презентираме метод за обука на моделот и даваме детали за имплементацијата на моделот. Презентираме експериментални резултати за два случаи: Сомалско-англиски и бугарско-англиски КЛИР.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami menggambarkan pendekatan untuk mengambil maklumat bahasa salib yang tidak bergantung pada terjemahan eksplicit sama ada dokumen atau terma pertanyaan. Instead, both queries and documents are mapped into a shared embedding space where retrieval is performed.  Kami membincangkan keuntungan potensi pendekatan dalam mengendalikan polisemi dan sinonimi. Kami memperkenalkan kaedah untuk melatih model, dan memberikan perincian pelaksanaan model. Kami memperkenalkan hasil percubaan untuk dua kes: Somali-Inggeris dan Bulgarian-Inggeris CLIR.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഭാഷ വിവരങ്ങളുടെ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ വീണ്ടെടുക്കാനുള്ള ഒരു വഴിയെക്കുറിച്ച് ഞങ്ങള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു. അത് പ്രത്യക്ഷമായ ഒരു ര പകരം ചോദ്യങ്ങളും രേഖകളും പങ്കുചേര്‍ക്കുന്ന സ്ഥലത്തേക്ക് മാപ്പ് ചെയ്യപ്പെടുന്നു പോളിസിമിയെയും സിനോണിയെയും കൈകാര്യം ചെയ്യുന്നതില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ സാധ്യതകള്‍ക്കുള്ള ഉപകാരങ്ങള്‍ സംസാര മോഡലിനെ പരിശീലിപ്പിക്കാനുള്ള ഒരു രീതിയില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കൊണ്ടുവന്നിട്ടുണ്ട്, മോഡല്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പി രണ്ടു കേസുകള്‍ക്കുള്ള പരീക്ഷണ ഫലങ്ങള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചുകൊടുക്കുന്നു</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>We describe an approach to cross lingual information retrieval that does not rely on explicit translation of either document or query terms.  Minflok, iż-żewġ mistoqsijiet u d-dokumenti huma mmappjati fi spazju ta’ inkorporazzjoni kondiviż fejn isir l-irkupru. Aħna niddiskutu l-vantaġġi potenzjali tal-approċċ fl-immaniġġjar tal-polisimja u s-sinonimja. We present a method for training the model, and give details of the model implementation.  Aħna nippreżentaw riżultati sperimentali għal żewġ każijiet: Somali-Ingliż u Bulgari-Ingliż CLIR.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Vi beskriver ein tilnærming til å henta kryss språk- informasjon som ikkje kjem på eksplisitt omsetjing av anten dokument eller spørjingstemmer. I staden blir både spørjingar og dokument kopla inn i eit delt innbyggingsplass der henting vert utført. Vi diskuterer potensielle fordeler av tilnærminga i handling av polysemet og synonym. Vi presenterer ein metode for å lære modellen og gi detaljar om implementasjonen av modellen. Vi presenterer eksperimentelle resultat for to tilfeller: Somali-engelsk og bulgarsk-engelsk CLIR.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Descriem o abordare a extragerii informațiilor între limbi care nu se bazează pe traducerea explicită a termenilor documentului sau interogării. În schimb, atât interogările, cât și documentele sunt mapate într-un spațiu partajat de încorporare unde se efectuează recuperarea. Discutăm potențialele avantaje ale abordării în manipularea polisemiei și sinonimiei. Prezentăm o metodă de instruire a modelului și oferim detalii privind implementarea modelului. Prezentăm rezultate experimentale pentru două cazuri: somalez-englez și bulgar-englez CLIR.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_pl>Opisujemy podejście do pozyskiwania informacji wielojęzycznych, które nie opiera się na wyraźnym tłumaczeniu ani dokumentu, ani terminów zapytania. Zamiast tego zarówno zapytania, jak i dokumenty są mapowane do wspólnej przestrzeni osadzania, w której wykonywane jest pobieranie. Omówimy potencjalne zalety tego podejścia w obsłudze polisemii i synonii. Przedstawiamy metodę szkolenia modelu oraz podajemy szczegóły wdrożenia modelu. Przedstawiamy wyniki eksperymentalne dla dwóch przypadków: somalijsko-angielskiego i bułgarsko-angielskiego CLIR.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Бид хэлний мэдээллийг олох аргыг тайлбарлаж өгдөг. Энэ нь баримт эсвэл query томъёогоор тодорхойлж чадахгүй. Үүний оронд, квери болон баримтууд хоёуланг авч авах зай руу хуваалцагдаж байна. Бид полицемийн болон синонимийн тусламжтайгаар тохирох боломжтой давуу талаар ярьдаг. Бид загварыг суралцах, загварын үйлдвэрлэлийн талаар нарийвчлан өгдөг. Бид хоёр тохиолдолд туршилтын үр дүнг үзүүлнэ: Сомали-Англи, Болгари-Англи CLIR.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_si>අපි භාෂාත්මක තොරතුරු ප්‍රවේශනය කරන්න ප්‍රවේශනයක් විස්තර කරනවා ඒක නොවිශ්වාස කරන්නේ විස්තර විවේශනය කරනව වෙනස්, ප්‍රශ්න සහ ලිපින්ත දෙන්නම් සංවිධානයක් සම්බන්ධ කරලා තියෙන්නේ ප්‍රශ්න ස්ථානයකට. අපි පොලිසිමිය සහ සමානෝමිය විදියට ප්‍රයෝජනයක් කතා කරනවා. අපි මොඩල් ප්‍රධානය කරන්න විදිහක් පෙන්වන්න, මොඩල් ප්‍රධානය ගැන විස්තර දෙන්න. අපි පරීක්ෂණ ප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Waxaannu tilmaamaynaa qaab u baahan kara helitaanka macluumaadka luuqadaha oo aan ku xirnayn turjumidda cad ama qoraalka la xiriira. Instead, both queries and documents are mapped into a shared embedding space where retrieval is performed.  Waxaynu ka sheekeynaynaa faa'iidada suurtagalka ah ee dhaqdhaqaalaha kala qabashada polysemi iyo sinonimo. Waxaynu keennaa qaab ku tababarinta modellka, waxaana siinaynaa macluumaad ku saabsan sameynta modellka. Waxaannu keennaa arimaha imtixaanka labada xaaladood: Soomaali-Ingiriis iyo Bulgarian-Ingiriis CLIR.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>Opišemo pristup prikupljanju jezičkih informacija koji se ne oslanja na pojasno prevod ni dokumenta ni uslova pitanja. Umjesto toga, obje pitanja i dokumente su mapirane u zajednički integracijski prostor u kojem se izvodi prikupljanje. Razgovaramo o potencijalnim prednostima pristupa u rješavanju polizemije i sinonije. Predstavljamo metodu za obuku model a i dati detalje o implementaciji modela. Predstavljamo eksperimentalne rezultate za dva slučaja: Somali-engleski i bugarski-engleski CLIR.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Vi beskriver ett tillvägagångssätt för tvärspråkig informationssökning som inte bygger på uttrycklig översättning av varken dokument- eller frågetermer. Istället mappas både frågor och dokument till ett delat inbäddningsutrymme där hämtning utförs. Vi diskuterar potentiella fördelar med tillvägagångssättet vid hantering av polysemi och synonymer. Vi presenterar en metod för att utbilda modellen och ger detaljer om modellimplementeringen. Vi presenterar experimentella resultat för två fall: somalisk-engelska och bulgarisk-engelska CLIR.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>நாம் மொழியில் தகவல் மீட்டெடுப்பதற்கு ஒரு வழியை விவரிக்கிறோம். அது வெளிப்படையான மொழிமாற்று அல்லது கேள்வி மொழிகள பதிலாக, கேள்விகள் மற்றும் ஆவணங்கள் இருவரும் பகிர்ந்து கொண்டிருக்கும் இடைவெளியில் வரையப்படுகின்றன மற்றும்  நாங்கள் போலிசேமி மற்றும் ஒத்திசையை கையாளும் சாத்தியமான உபயோகங்களை விவாதம் செய்கிறோம். We present a method for training the model, and give details of the model implementation.  இரண்டு விஷயங்களுக்கு நாம் சோமாலி- ஆங்கிலம் மற்றும் புல்கேரிய- ஆங்கிலத்தின் CLIR.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم زبان کی معلومات حاصل کرنے کے لئے ایک طریقہ کا مفصل بیان کرتے ہیں جو نہ سند یا سوال کی اصل پر صریح ترجمہ کرتی ہے۔ اس عوض، دونوں سؤال اور دفتروں کو ایک شریک ایمبڈینگ جگہ میں نقشه بنا دیا جاتا ہے جہاں پھیرنے کا انجام ہوتا ہے. ہم اس طریقے کے امکان فائدہ کے بارے میں مشورہ کرتے ہیں کہ مشورہ اور مشورہ کے بارے میں۔ ہم مدل کی تعلیم کے لئے ایک طریقہ پیش کرتے ہیں اور مدل کی تعلیم کے معاملات کا تفصیل دیتے ہیں۔ ہم دو مواقع کے لئے آزمائش نتیجے پیش کرتے ہیں: سومالی-انگلیسی اور بلگاری-انگلیسی CLIR۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi mô tả một cách tiếp cận việc truy tìm thông tin ngôn ngữ mà không dựa trên một bản dịch rõ ràng của cả tài liệu lẫn các điều khoản truy vấn. Thay vào đó, cả các câu hỏi và tài liệu đều được lập thành một không gian chia sẻ nơi thực hiện việc lấy dữ liệu. Chúng ta thảo luận về lợi ích của cách tiếp cận trong cách điều khiển polysemy và đồng nghĩa. Chúng tôi cung cấp một phương pháp huấn luyện mô hình, và chi tiết về cách thực hiện mô hình. Chúng tôi đưa ra kết quả thử nghiệm cho hai trường hợp:</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Biz tilda maʼlumotni olish muvaffaqiyatlarini anglatamiz, bu hujjat yoki soʻrov soʻzlariga shaxsiy tarjima qilmaydi. @ info: whatsthis Biz polysemi va synonymini boshqarish uchun eng muhimlik foydalanuvchilarni javob beramiz. Biz modelni o'rganish uchun usulni hosil qilamiz va modelni bajarish haqida bajaramiz. Biz ikkita tilga tajriba natijalarini hozir qilamiz: Somaliya- Inglizcha va Bulgariy- Inglizcha CLIR.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Описваме подход за извличане на информация между езиците, който не разчита на изричен превод на нито документ, нито на термини за заявка. Вместо това, както заявките, така и документите се картографират в споделено пространство за вграждане, където се извършва извличане. Обсъждаме потенциалните предимства на подхода при работа с полисемия и синонимия. Представяме метод за обучение на модела, както и подробности за внедряването на модела. Представяме експериментални резултати за два случая: сомалийско-английски и българо-английски.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Mi opisujemo pristup prikupljanju jezičkih informacija koji se ne oslanja na pojasno prevod ni dokumenta ni uslova pitanja. Umjesto toga, obje ispitivanja i dokumente su mapirane u zajednički ugrađeni prostor u kojem se izvodi prikupljanje. Razgovaramo o potencijalnim prednostima pristupa u rješavanju polizemije i sinonije. Predstavljamo metodu za obuku model a i dati detalje o provedbi modela. Predstavljamo eksperimentalne rezultate za dva slučaja: Somali-engleski i bugarski-engleski CLIR.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Vi beskriver en tilgang til tværsproget informationssøgning, der ikke er afhængig af eksplicit oversættelse af hverken dokument- eller forespørgselsbetingelser. I stedet knyttes både forespørgsler og dokumenter til et delt indlejringsrum, hvor hentning udføres. Vi diskuterer potentielle fordele ved tilgangen til håndtering af polysemi og synonymer. Vi præsenterer en metode til træning af modellen, og giver detaljer om modellens implementering. Vi præsenterer eksperimentelle resultater for to tilfælde: somalisk-engelsk og bulgarsk-engelsk CLIR.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>We beschrijven een aanpak voor het ophalen van informatie in meerdere talen die niet afhankelijk is van expliciete vertaling van documenten of query termen. In plaats daarvan worden zowel query's als documenten toegewezen aan een gedeelde insluitruimte waar het ophalen wordt uitgevoerd. We bespreken mogelijke voordelen van de aanpak bij het hanteren van polysemie en synoniem. We presenteren een methode voor het trainen van het model, en geven details over de uitvoering van het model. We presenteren experimentele resultaten voor twee gevallen: Somalisch-Engels en Bulgaars-Engels CLIR.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Wir beschreiben einen Ansatz zur sprachübergreifenden Informationssuche, der nicht auf einer expliziten Übersetzung von Dokumenten oder Abfragebegriffen beruht. Stattdessen werden sowohl Abfragen als auch Dokumente einem gemeinsamen Einbettungsraum zugeordnet, in dem der Abruf durchgeführt wird. Wir diskutieren mögliche Vorteile des Ansatzes im Umgang mit Polysemie und Synonym. Wir stellen eine Methode zur Schulung des Modells vor und geben Details zur Modellimplementierung. Wir präsentieren experimentelle Ergebnisse für zwei Fälle: somalisch-englisch und bulgarisch-englisch CLIR.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Kami menggambarkan pendekatan untuk merebut informasi bahasa yang tidak bergantung pada terjemahan eksplicit dari sama ada dokumen atau istilah pertanyaan. Sebaliknya, kedua pertanyaan dan dokumen dipetakan ke ruang penyembedding berbagi di mana penulisan dilakukan. Kami mendiskusikan keuntungan potensial pendekatan dalam menangani polisemi dan sinonimi. Kami mempersembahkan metode untuk melatih model, dan memberikan rincian tentang implementasi model. Kami mempersembahkan hasil percobaan untuk dua kasus: Somali-Inggris dan Bulgaria-Inggris CLIR.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>ما یک روش برای خروج اطلاعات زبانی را توصیف می‌کنیم که بر ترجمه‌های خاصی از سند یا ترجمه‌های پرسیدن اعتماد ندارد. به جای این، هر دو سوال و سند به یک فضای مشترک در جایی که بازیابی انجام می‌شود نقشه‌بندی می‌شوند. ما مطابق منافع‌های پتانسیل از دسترسی در کنترل polysemy و synonymy صحبت می‌کنیم. ما روش آموزش مدل را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم و جزئیات عملکرد مدل را می‌دهیم. ما نتایج آزمایشی را برای دو پرونده نشان می دهیم: سومالی-انگلیسی و بلگاری-انگلیسی CLIR.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 문서나 검색어의 현식 번역에 의존하지 않는 다중 언어 정보 검색 방법을 묘사했다.반대로, 검색과 문서는 공유된 삽입 공간에 비치며, 이 공간에서 검색을 실행합니다.우리는 이런 방법이 다의와 동의어를 처리하는 데 있어 잠재적인 장점을 토론했다.우리는 훈련 모델의 방법을 제시했고 모델이 실현되는 세부 사항을 제시했다.우리는 소말리아 영어와 불가리아 영어 두 사례의 실험 결과를 제시했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Tunaelezea njia ya kupitia upatikanaji wa taarifa za lugha ambazo haitegemea tafsiri ya wazi ya kitabu au vipengele vya kuuliza. Badala yake, maswali na nyaraka zote zimezorodheshwa katika sehemu inayoshirikishwa ambapo kurejeshwa. We discuss potential advantages of the approach in handling polysemy and synonymy.  Tunaweza kuweka mbinu ya mafunzo mifano, na kutoa maelezo ya utekelezaji wa mifano. Tunatoa matokeo ya majaribio kwa kesi mbili: Kisomali-Kiingereza na Kiingereza CLIR.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>Ne përshkruajmë një qasje për marrjen e informacionit gjuhësor që nuk mbështetet në përkthimin eksplicit të as termave të dokumentit, as të pyetjes. Në vend të kësaj, të dy pyetjet dhe dokumentet janë hartuar në një hapësirë të përbashkët të përfshirjes ku kryehet marrja. Ne diskutojmë avantazhet e mundshme të qasjes në trajtimin e polizimit dhe sinonimisë. Ne paraqesim një metodë për trajnimin e modelit dhe japim detaje të zbatimit të modelit. Ne paraqesim rezultate eksperimentale për dy raste: Somali-Anglisht dhe Bullgar-Anglisht CLIR.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Biz dil maglumaty almak üçin bir gollany tassyýarys. Bu senediň ya da soragy terjime edilmedi. Bu ýerde, hem soraglar hem senedler bir paylaşdyrylýan ýere çykylýar. Biz polysemiýany we synonymyny ýüze çykmak üçin golaýynyň potensial bahallaryny gürrüň berýäris. Biz nusgany okuw etmek üçin bir yöntem görkezip, we nusganyň implementasy barada maglumatlary berip bereris. Biz iki durum üçin synanyşan netijeleri görkeýäris: Somali-Iňlisçe we Bulgarça-Iňlisçe CLIR.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Ons beskryf 'n toegang na kruis tale inligting ontvang wat nie op eksplisiese vertaling van óf dokument of navraag terme vertrou nie. In plaas, albei vrae en dokumente word gekap in 'n gedeelde inbêer spasie waar ontvanging uitgevoer word. Ons bespreek potensiele voordeel van die toegang in die handling van polisemie en sinoniem. Ons stel 'n metode om die model te oefen en besonderhede van die model implementering te gee. Ons stel eksperimentale resultate vir twee gevalle: Somali-Engels en Bulgarse-Engels CLIR.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք նկարագրում ենք լեզվային ինֆորմացիայի փոխադարձման մոտեցումը, որը չի հիմնված ոչ փաստաթղթի, ոչ էլ հարցման տերմինների բացատրական թարգմանման վրա: Փոխարենը, երկու հարցեր և փաստաթղթեր քարտեզագրված են ընդհանուր ներգրավման տարածքում, որտեղ վերադարձում է: Մենք քննարկում ենք պոլիզեմիայի և սինոնիմիայի վերաբերյալ մոտեցման պոտենցիալ առավելությունները: Մենք ներկայացնում ենք մոդելի ուսումնասիրության մեթոդ և ներկայացնում ենք մոդելի իրականացման մանրամասնությունները: Մենք ներկայացնում ենք փորձարկման արդյունքներ երկու դեպքում՝ Սոմալի-անգլերեն և բուլերեն-անգլերեն ԿԼԻՌ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_am>በቋንቋ ቋንቋ መረጃዎችን ለማስቀበል እናሳውቃለን፡፡ Instead, both queries and documents are mapped into a shared embedded space where retrieval is performed. በፖሊሳሚን እና ሲኒኖኒን ለመቆጣጠር የሚችሉትን የስልጣን ጥቅም እናሳውቃለን፡፡ ምሳሌውን ለማስተማር እናስገራለን የሞዴል ተርጓሚዎቹንም እናስጠጋለን፡፡ ለሁለት ጉዳዮች የሞከር ፍሬዎችን እናቀርባለን፤ ሶማሊ-እንግሊዘኛ እና ቡልጋሪኛ-እንግሊዘኛ CLIR።</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>Biz dil məlumatlarını almaq üçün tərzini təsdiqləyirik ki, belə bir məlumat və ya soruşma şəkillərinin açıq-aydın tərzinə təvəkkül edilməz. Əvəzində, hər ikisi sual və beləliklər alış yerinə paylaşdırılır. Biz çoxluğu və sinonimi müdafiə etmək üçün mümkün mənfəətlər barəsində mübahisə edirik. Biz modeli təhsil etmək üçün bir metodu göstəririk və modeli təhsil etmək barəsindəki detayları veririk. İki vəziyyət üçün eksperimentli sonuçlar göstəririk: Somali-İngilizce və Bulgarca-İngilizce CLIR.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা ভাষাভাষী তথ্য পুনরুদ্ধার পার করার একটি উপায় বর্ণনা করি যা কোন নথিপত্রের ব্যাপারে নির্ভর করে না অথবা অনুসন্ধানের শর্ তার পরিবর্তে প্রশ্ন ও নথিপত্র উভয় একটি শেয়ার করা বিভিন্ন স্থানে ম্যাপ করা হচ্ছে যেখানে পুনরুদ্ধার করা হচ্ছে। আমরা পলিসেমি এবং সিনোনিয়ামির মাধ্যমে এই পদ্ধতির সম্ভাব্য সুবিধা নিয়ে আলোচনা করি। আমরা মডেল প্রশিক্ষণের একটি পদ্ধতি উপস্থাপন করি এবং মডেল বাস্তবায়নের বিস্তারিত ব্যাখ্যা দিয়েছি। আমরা দুই মামলার পরীক্ষার ফলাফল উপস্থাপন করছি: সোমালিয়া-ইংরেজি এবং বুলগেরিয়ান-ইংরেজি সিলির।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>Descrivem un enfocament per a recuperar informació llengua que no es basa en traducció explícita ni de termes de documentació ni de consulta. En comptes d'això, tant les preguntes com els documents es mapeixen en un espai compartit d'incorporació on es fa la recuperació. Discutem sobre les avantatges potencials de l'enfocament en la gestió de la polissima i la sinonimia. Presentam un mètode d'entrenament del model i donem detalls sobre la implementació del model. Presentam resultats experimentals en dos casos: CLIR somali-anglès i búlgar-anglès.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Popisujeme přístup k vyhledávání informací v křížových jazycích, který nespoléhá na explicitním překladu dokumentů ani dotazových termínů. Místo toho jsou dotazy i dokumenty mapovány do sdíleného vkládacího prostoru, kde se provádí načtení. Diskutujeme potenciální výhody tohoto přístupu při manipulaci s polysémií a synonymií. Představujeme metodu pro trénink modelu a podrobnosti o implementaci modelu. Představujeme experimentální výsledky pro dva případy: somálsko-anglické a bulharsko-anglické CLIR.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Kirjeldame keeleülese teabe hankimise lähenemisviisi, mis ei põhine dokumendi ega päringuterminite selgesõnalisel tõlkimisel. Selle asemel kaardistatakse nii päringud kui ka dokumendid ühiskasse manustamisruumi, kus teostatakse otsinguid. Arutleme lähenemisviisi võimalikke eeliseid polüseemia ja sünonüümia käsitlemisel. Tutvustame mudeli koolitamise meetodit ja anname üksikasjad mudeli rakendamise kohta. Esitleme eksperimentaalseid tulemusi kahel juhul: somaali-inglise ja bulgaaria-inglise CLIR.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>Opišemo pristup prikupljanju jezičkih informacija koji se ne oslanja na pojasno prevod ni dokumenta ni uslova pitanja. Umjesto toga, obje ispitivanja i dokumente su mapirane u zajednički ugrađeni prostor gdje se izvodi prikupljanje. Razgovaramo o potencijalnim prednostima pristupa u rješavanju polizemije i sinonije. Predstavljamo metodu za obuku model a i dati detalje o implementaciji modela. Predstavljamo eksperimentalne rezultate za dva slučaja: Somali-engleski i bugarski-engleski CLIR.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_fi>Kuvaamme monikieliseen tiedonhakuun perustuvaa lähestymistapaa, joka ei perustu dokumentin tai kyselytermien nimenomaiseen kääntämiseen. Sen sijaan sekä kyselyt että asiakirjat yhdistetään jaettuun upotustilaan, jossa haku suoritetaan. Keskustelemme menetelmän mahdollisista eduista polysemian ja synonyymin käsittelyssä. Esittelemme mallin koulutusmenetelmän ja kerromme yksityiskohtaisesti mallin toteutuksesta. Esitämme kokeellisia tuloksia kahdesta tapauksesta: somali-englanti ja bulgaria-englanti CLIR.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Awakdhéwé nglarang kapan nganggo nggawe informasi langkung nggawe gerakan kuwi jenis cara-lisan sing paling nggambar tokkum uga ngono ujian terjamahan Tanggal Awak dhéwé éntuk perbudhakan kanggo nggawe polisemi lan senonnyomi. Tulung awak dhéwé éntuk sistem kanggo nggawe model lan ngono njaluk-njaluk ngewehku modèl Awak dhéwé éntukno pancening alaman kanggo kelas rambarang durung: Somali-Inggris lan CLIR Inggris barang.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Opisujemo pristop k medjezičnemu pridobivanju informacij, ki se ne opira na ekspliciten prevod dokumentov ali poizvedbenih izrazov. Namesto tega so poizvedbe in dokumenti preslikani v prostor za vdelavo v skupni rabi, kjer se izvede pridobivanje. Razpravljamo o potencialnih prednostih pristopa pri ravnanju s polikemijo in sinonimijo. Predstavljamo metodo za usposabljanje modela in podrobnosti o implementaciji modela. Predstavljamo poskusne rezultate za dva primera: somalsko-angleški in bolgarsko-angleški CLIR.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna bayyana wani hanyoyi wa ka samu motsari na information cikin harshen, wanda bai dõgara ga fassarar-bayani na takardar ko kuma don ka tambaye. Babu musamman, za'a rasa koyan tambayar da takardun aiki biyu zuwa wani filin da aka raba shi cikin filin da ake samu da shi. Munã jãyayya masu yiwuwa da amfani na hanyoyi a cikin kudai mulki da sunonini. Tuna gabatar da wata hanyor wa yin wa'azi ga misalin, kuma Muke bayyana misalin ayukan misalin. Tuna halatar da matsaran jarrabãwa biyu: Somaliya-Ingiriya da Bulgaria-Ingiriya CLIR.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>אנו מתארים גישה לחצות מידע שפוי שפוי שגיאה שלא תלוי בתרגום ברור של מסמכים או תנאים בקשה. במקום זה, שני השאלות ומסמכים מופיעים לתוך מרחב משותף של קיבלה שבו מבצעים השיגה. אנחנו מדברים על יתרונות פוטנציאליים של הגישה בטיפול בפוליסמיה וסינונימיה. אנחנו מציגים שיטה לאימון הדוגמנית, ולתת פרטים על ההפעלה של הדוגמנית. אנחנו מציגים תוצאות ניסויים לשני מקרים: סומאלי-אנגלי ובולגרי-אנגלי CLIR.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་དང་འཛམ་གླིང་བའི་བརྡ་འཕྲིན་དོན་ཀྱི་བཟོ་བཅོས་གཅིག་འགྲེལ་བཤད་བྱེད་ཀྱི་མིན འདི་ཚབ་དུ། དྲི་ཞིབ་དང་ཡིག་ཆ་གཉིས་ཀྱིས་ཉར་འཇུག་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ས་སྟོང་ཞིག་ཏུ་སྒྲིག་ཡོད་པ ང་ཚོས་འདྲི་ཚིག་གཟུགས་རིས་དང་མཐུན་རྣམས་ལ་སྐྱོང་ཐབས་ནང་གི་གོ་སྐབས་ཆེ་མཐོང་ཐུབ་པའི་སྐྱོན་འབྲེལ་ ང་ཚོས་མ་དབྱེ་བ་ལྟ་སློང་བྱེད་ཐབས་ལམ་ཞིག་བྱས་ནས་མིག་ཆའི་གསལ་བཤད་མང་ཙམ་སྟོན་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་ཕལ་ཆེར་བརྟན་པའི་གྲུབ་འབྲས་མང་པོ་ཞིག་འཆར་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད།སོ་མ་ལི་ཨིན་ཇིས་དང་བུ་ལ་གྷི་ར་ཡི</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Cross-lingual Information Retrieval with BERT<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Zhuolin</first><last>Jiang</last></author>
      <author><first>Amro</first><last>El-Jaroudi</last></author>
      <author><first>William</first><last>Hartmann</last></author>
      <author><first>Damianos</first><last>Karakos</last></author>
      <author><first>Lingjun</first><last>Zhao</last></author>
      <pages>26–31</pages>
      <abstract>Multiple neural language models have been developed recently, e.g., BERT and XLNet, and achieved impressive results in various NLP tasks including sentence classification, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Question_answering">question answering</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_ranking">document ranking</a>. In this paper, we explore the use of the popular bidirectional language model, BERT, to model and learn the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relevance_(information_retrieval)">relevance</a> between English queries and foreign-language documents in the task of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-lingual_information_retrieval">cross-lingual information retrieval</a>. A deep relevance matching model based on BERT is introduced and trained by finetuning a pretrained multilingual BERT model with weak supervision, using home-made CLIR training data derived from parallel corpora. Experimental results of the retrieval of Lithuanian documents against short English queries show that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> is effective and outperforms the competitive baseline approaches.</abstract>
      <url hash="632e3463">2020.clssts-1.5</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>jiang-etal-2020-cross</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>A Comparison of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unsupervised_learning">Unsupervised Methods</a> for Ad hoc Cross-Lingual Document Retrieval</title>
      <author><first>Elaine</first><last>Zosa</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Granroth-Wilding</last></author>
      <author><first>Lidia</first><last>Pivovarova</last></author>
      <pages>32–37</pages>
      <abstract>We address the problem of linking related documents across languages in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collection_(abstract_data_type)">multilingual collection</a>. We evaluate three diverse unsupervised methods to represent and compare documents : (1) multilingual topic model ; (2) cross-lingual document embeddings ; and (3) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wasserstein_distance">Wasserstein distance</a>. We test the performance of these methods in retrieving news articles in Swedish that are known to be related to a given Finnish article. The results show that ensembles of the methods outperform the stand-alone methods, suggesting that they capture complementary characteristics of the documents</abstract>
      <url hash="ccf36348">2020.clssts-1.6</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>zosa-etal-2020-comparison</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>