<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nlpcss">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-06">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on Natural Language Processing and Computational Social Science</booktitle>
      <editor><first>David</first><last>Bamman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Dirk</first><last>Hovy</last></editor>
      <editor><first>David</first><last>Jurgens</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Brendan</first><last>O'Connor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Svitlana</first><last>Volkova</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="f83c4f5a">2020.nlpcss-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp-css-2020-natural</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Swimming with the Tide? Positional Claim Detection across Political Text Types</title>
      <author><first>Nico</first><last>Blokker</last></author>
      <author><first>Erenay</first><last>Dayanik</last></author>
      <author><first>Gabriella</first><last>Lapesa</last></author>
      <author><first>Sebastian</first><last>Padó</last></author>
      <pages>24–34</pages>
      <abstract>Manifestos are official documents of political parties, providing a comprehensive topical overview of the electoral programs. Voters, however, seldom read them and often prefer other channels, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Article_(publishing)">newspaper articles</a>, to understand the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Party_platform">party positions</a> on various policy issues. The natural question to ask is how compatible these two formats (manifesto and newspaper reports) are in their representation of party positioning. We address this question with an approach that combines political science (manual annotation and analysis) and natural language processing (supervised claim identification) in a cross-text type setting : we train a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifier</a> on annotated newspaper data and test its performance on manifestos. Our findings show a) strong performance for supervised classification even across text types and b) a substantive overlap between the two formats in terms of party positioning, with differences regarding the salience of specific issues.</abstract>
      <url hash="c3816eb8">2020.nlpcss-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpcss-1.3</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940616" />
      <bibkey>blokker-etal-2020-swimming</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Identifying Worry in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a> : Beyond Emotion Analysis<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter: Beyond Emotion Analysis</title>
      <author><first>Reyha</first><last>Verma</last></author>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>von der Weth</last></author>
      <author><first>Jithin</first><last>Vachery</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohan</first><last>Kankanhalli</last></author>
      <pages>72–82</pages>
      <abstract>Identifying the worries of individuals and societies plays a crucial role in providing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_support">social support</a> and enhancing policy decision-making. Due to the popularity of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media platforms</a> such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a>, users share worries about personal issues (e.g., health, finances, relationships) and broader issues (e.g., changes in society, environmental concerns, terrorism) freely. In this paper, we explore and evaluate a wide range of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning models</a> to predict <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Worry">worry</a> on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a>. While this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> has been closely associated with emotion prediction, we argue and show that identifying worry needs to be addressed as a separate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> given the unique challenges associated with it. We conduct a user study to provide evidence that social media posts express two basic kinds of worry   normative and pathological   as stated in psychology literature. In addition, we show that existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_detection">emotion detection techniques</a> underperform, especially while capturing normative worry. Finally, we discuss the current limitations of our approach and propose future applications of the worry identification system.</abstract>
      <url hash="148e3b48">2020.nlpcss-1.9</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpcss-1.9</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940602" />
      <bibkey>verma-etal-2020-identifying</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Recalibrating classifiers for interpretable abusive content detection</title>
      <author><first>Bertie</first><last>Vidgen</last></author>
      <author><first>Scott</first><last>Hale</last></author>
      <author><first>Sam</first><last>Staton</last></author>
      <author><first>Tom</first><last>Melham</last></author>
      <author><first>Helen</first><last>Margetts</last></author>
      <author><first>Ohad</first><last>Kammar</last></author>
      <author><first>Marcin</first><last>Szymczak</last></author>
      <pages>132–138</pages>
      <abstract>We investigate the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">machine learning classifiers</a> for detecting online abuse in empirical research. We show that uncalibrated classifiers (i.e. where the ‘raw’ scores are used) align poorly with human evaluations. This limits their use for understanding the dynamics, patterns and prevalence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_abuse">online abuse</a>. We examine two widely used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifiers</a> (created by Perspective and Davidson et al.) on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">tweets</a> directed against candidates in the UK’s 2017 general election. A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_inference">Bayesian approach</a> is presented to recalibrate the raw scores from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifiers</a>, using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Probabilistic_programming">probabilistic programming</a> and newly <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotated data</a>. We argue that interpretability evaluation and recalibration is integral to the application of abusive content classifiers.</abstract>
      <url hash="d914fd9c">2020.nlpcss-1.14</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="4a119199">2020.nlpcss-1.14.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpcss-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>vidgen-etal-2020-recalibrating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>Mapping Local News Coverage : Precise location extraction in textual news content using fine-tuned BERT based language model<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> based language model</title>
      <author><first>Sarang</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Kumari</first><last>Nishu</last></author>
      <pages>155–162</pages>
      <abstract>Mapping local news coverage from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text-based_user_interface">textual content</a> is a challenging problem that requires extracting precise location mentions from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Article_(publishing)">news articles</a>. While traditional named entity taggers are able to extract geo-political entities and certain non geo-political entities, they can not recognize precise location mentions such as addresses, streets and intersections that are required to accurately map the news article. We fine-tune a BERT-based language model for achieving high level of granularity in location extraction. We incorporate the model into an end-to-end tool that further geocodes the extracted locations for the broader objective of mapping news coverage.</abstract>
      <url hash="f49f3623">2020.nlpcss-1.17</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpcss-1.17</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940613" />
      <bibkey>gupta-nishu-2020-mapping</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>Foreigner-directed speech is simpler than native-directed : Evidence from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a></title>
      <author><first>Aleksandrs</first><last>Berdicevskis</last></author>
      <pages>163–172</pages>
      <abstract>I test two hypotheses that play an important role in modern sociolinguistics and language evolution studies : first, that non-native production is simpler than native ; second, that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_production">production</a> addressed to non-native speakers is simpler than that addressed to natives. The second hypothesis is particularly important for theories about contact-induced simplification, since the accommodation to non-natives may explain how the simplification can spread from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adult_learner">adult learners</a> to the whole community. To test the hypotheses, I create a very large corpus of native and non-native written speech in four languages (English, French, Italian, Spanish), extracting data from an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_forum">internet forum</a> where native languages of the participants are known and the structure of the interactions can be inferred. The corpus data yield inconsistent evidence with respect to the first hypothesis, but largely support the second one, suggesting that foreigner-directed speech is indeed simpler than native-directed. Importantly, when testing the first hypothesis, I contrast production of different speakers, which can introduce confounds and is a likely reason for the inconsistencies. When testing the second hypothesis, the comparison is always within the production of the same speaker (but with different addressees), which makes it more reliable.</abstract>
      <url hash="d08974a6">2020.nlpcss-1.18</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpcss-1.18</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940614" />
      <bibkey>berdicevskis-2020-foreigner</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/aleksandrsberdicevskis/word-reference-corpus" additional="false">aleksandrsberdicevskis/word-reference-corpus</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Understanding Weekly COVID-19 Concerns through Dynamic Content-Specific LDA Topic Modeling<fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 Concerns through Dynamic Content-Specific <fixed-case>LDA</fixed-case> Topic Modeling</title>
      <author><first>Mohammadzaman</first><last>Zamani</last></author>
      <author><first>H. Andrew</first><last>Schwartz</last></author>
      <author><first>Johannes</first><last>Eichstaedt</last></author>
      <author><first>Sharath Chandra</first><last>Guntuku</last></author>
      <author><first>Adithya</first><last>Virinchipuram Ganesan</last></author>
      <author><first>Sean</first><last>Clouston</last></author>
      <author><first>Salvatore</first><last>Giorgi</last></author>
      <pages>193–198</pages>
      <abstract>The novelty and global scale of the COVID-19 pandemic has lead to rapid societal changes in a short span of time. As government policy and health measures shift, public perceptions and concerns also change, an evolution documented within discourse on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. We propose a dynamic content-specific LDA topic modeling technique that can help to identify different domains of COVID-specific discourse that can be used to track societal shifts in concerns or views. Our experiments show that these model-derived topics are more coherent than standard LDA topics, and also provide new features that are more helpful in prediction of COVID-19 related outcomes including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_mobility">social mobility</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unemployment">unemployment rate</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="0273ecef">2020.nlpcss-1.21</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpcss-1.21</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940607" />
      <bibkey>zamani-etal-2020-understanding</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/wwbp/weekly_covid_lda_topics" additional="false">wwbp/weekly_covid_lda_topics</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Emoji and Self-Identity in Twitter Bios<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>witter Bios</title>
      <author><first>Jinhang</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <author><first>Giorgos</first><last>Longinos</last></author>
      <author><first>Steven</first><last>Wilson</last></author>
      <author><first>Walid</first><last>Magdy</last></author>
      <pages>199–211</pages>
      <abstract>Emoji are widely used to express emotions and concepts on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>, and prior work has shown that users’ choice of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emoji</a> reflects the way that they wish to present themselves to the world. Emoji usage is typically studied in the context of posts made by users, and this view has provided important insights into phenomena such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotional expression</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-representation">self-representation</a>. In addition to making posts, however, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media platforms</a> like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter</a> allow for users to provide a short bio, which is an opportunity to briefly describe their account as a whole. In this work, we focus on the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emoji</a> in these bio statements. We explore the ways in which users include <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emoji</a> in these self-descriptions, finding different patterns than those observed around <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emoji</a> usage in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">tweets</a>. We examine the relationships between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emoji</a> used in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biography">bios</a> and the content of users’ tweets, showing that the topics and even the average sentiment of tweets varies for users with different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emoji</a> in their bios. Lastly, we confirm that homophily effects exist with respect to the types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji">emoji</a> that are included in bios of users and their followers.</abstract>
      <url hash="5f5de8a8">2020.nlpcss-1.22</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nlpcss-1.22</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38940622" />
      <bibkey>li-etal-2020-emoji</bibkey>
    <title_ar>الرموز التعبيرية والهوية الذاتية في Twitter Bios</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Emoji e auto-identidade na biografia do Twitter</title_pt>
      <title_es>Emoji y identidad propia en la biografía de Twitter</title_es>
      <title_ja>Twitterバイオの絵文字と自己同一性</title_ja>
      <title_zh>Twitter Bios中表情符号与自同</title_zh>
      <title_hi>चहचहाना Bios में इमोजी और आत्म पहचान</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Emoji agus Féinaitheantas i Twitter Bios</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Emoji és önazonosság a Twitter Bios-ben</title_hu>
      <title_el>Emoji και αυτοταυτότητα σε βιογραφικά του Twitter</title_el>
      <title_it>Emoji e auto-identità in Twitter Bios</title_it>
      <title_kk>Твиттердің Emoji және Өзіңіздің идентификациясы</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Emoji ir savitarpio tapatybė Twitter Bios</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Емоја и самоидентитет на Твитер Биос</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Emoji dan Identiti Sendiri dalam Bio Twitter</title_ms>
      <title_mn>Twitter Bios-д эмози болон Өөрийгөө мэдэх</title_mn>
      <title_ml>എമോജിയും സ്വയം തിരിച്ചറിയാനുള്ള ഐഡിറ്റി</title_ml>
      <title_no>Emoji og selvidentitet i Twitter-bios</title_no>
      <title_pl>Emoji i samootożsamość w Twitterze Bios</title_pl>
      <title_mt>Emoji u Awto-Identità fi Twitter Bios</title_mt>
      <title_ro>Emoji și auto-identitate în Twitter Bios</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Emoji i Self-Identitet u Twitter Biosu</title_sr>
      <title_so>Aqoonshaha iskaa ee Twitterka</title_so>
      <title_si>ට්විටර් බියෝස් වල EmosiName</title_si>
      <title_sv>Emoji och självidentitet i Twitter Bios</title_sv>
      <title_ta>Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>ٹویٹر بیوس میں ایموجی اور خود هویت</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Emoji and Self Nhận diện trên Twitter Bios.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Емоции и самоличност в Биоса на Туитър</title_bg>
      <title_da>Emoji og selv-identitet i Twitter Bios</title_da>
      <title_hr>Emoji i Self-Identitet u Twitter Bios-u</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Emoji en zelfidentiteit in Twitter Bios's</title_nl>
      <title_de>Emoji und Selbstidentität in Twitter Bios</title_de>
      <title_id>Emoji dan Identitas Sendiri dalam Twitter Bios</title_id>
      <title_fa>ایموجی و هویت خود در توئیتر بیوس</title_fa>
      <title_ko>트위터 바이오스의 이모티콘과 자기 정체성</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Emoji na kujitambulisha katika Bios za Twita</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Twitter Biolarda Emoji we Öz-kimlik</title_tr>
      <title_af>Emoji en Self-Identiteit in Twitter Bios</title_af>
      <title_am>ኢሜጂ እና የራሳቸው አዳራሽ በትዊተር ቢዮስ</title_am>
      <title_hy>Թվիթեր կենսաբանության էմոյի և ինքնություն</title_hy>
      <title_az>Twitter Bios'da Emoji və Öz-kimlik</title_az>
      <title_sq>Emoji dhe vetë-identiteti në Twitter Bios</title_sq>
      <title_bs>Emoji i Self-Identitet u Twitter Bios</title_bs>
      <title_bn>টুইটার বিওসে ইমোজি এবং স্বাধীনতা</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Emoji i auto-identitat a Twitter Bios</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Emoji a sebe-identita v Twitteru Bios</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Emoji ja itseidentiteetti Twitter Biosissa</title_fi>
      <title_et>Emojid ja eneseidentiteet Twitter Bios</title_et>
      <title_jv>emuji karo Self-ID nang Google BIS</title_jv>
      <title_ha>Phonon:: MMF:: EffectFactory</title_ha>
      <title_he>Emoji זהות עצמית בטוויטר ביוס</title_he>
      <title_sk>Emoji in samoidentiteta v Twitterju Bios</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Twitter Bios ནང་དུ་emooji and Self-Identity</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تُستخدم الرموز التعبيرية على نطاق واسع للتعبير عن المشاعر والمفاهيم على وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي ، وقد أظهر العمل السابق أن اختيار المستخدمين للرموز التعبيرية يعكس الطريقة التي يرغبون بها في تقديم أنفسهم للعالم. عادةً ما تتم دراسة استخدام الرموز التعبيرية في سياق المنشورات التي ينشرها المستخدمون ، وقد قدمت وجهة النظر هذه رؤى مهمة حول ظواهر مثل التعبير العاطفي وتمثيل الذات. بالإضافة إلى إنشاء المنشورات ، تسمح منصات الوسائط الاجتماعية مثل Twitter للمستخدمين بتقديم سيرة ذاتية قصيرة ، وهي فرصة لوصف حسابهم ككل بإيجاز. في هذا العمل ، نركز على استخدام الرموز التعبيرية في هذه البيانات الحيوية. نستكشف الطرق التي يستخدمها المستخدمون لتضمين الرموز التعبيرية في هذه الأوصاف الذاتية ، وإيجاد أنماط مختلفة عن تلك التي لوحظت حول استخدام الرموز التعبيرية في التغريدات. ندرس العلاقات بين الرموز التعبيرية المستخدمة في السير ومحتوى تغريدات المستخدمين ، ونظهر أن الموضوعات وحتى المشاعر المتوسطة للتغريدات تختلف بالنسبة للمستخدمين الذين لديهم رموز تعبيرية مختلفة في سيرهم الذاتية. أخيرًا ، نؤكد وجود تأثيرات مثلي الجنس فيما يتعلق بأنواع الرموز التعبيرية المضمنة في سير المستخدمين ومتابعيهم.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Los emoji se utilizan ampliamente para expresar emociones y conceptos en las redes sociales, y trabajos anteriores han demostrado que la elección de los emojis por parte de los usuarios refleja la forma en que desean presentarse al mundo. El uso de emojis normalmente se estudia en el contexto de las publicaciones realizadas por los usuarios, y esta visión ha proporcionado información importante sobre fenómenos como la expresión emocional y la autorrepresentación. Sin embargo, además de hacer publicaciones, las plataformas de redes sociales como Twitter permiten a los usuarios proporcionar una breve biografía, que es una oportunidad para describir brevemente su cuenta en su conjunto. En este trabajo, nos centramos en el uso de emojis en estas declaraciones biográficas. Exploramos las formas en que los usuarios incluyen emojis en estas autodescripciones, encontrando patrones diferentes a los observados en torno al uso de emojis en los tuits. Examinamos las relaciones entre los emojis utilizados en las biografías y el contenido de los tuits de los usuarios, mostrando que los temas e incluso el sentimiento promedio de los tuits varían para los usuarios con diferentes emojis en sus biografías. Por último, confirmamos que existen efectos de homofilia con respecto a los tipos de emoji que se incluyen en las biografías de los usuarios y sus seguidores.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Os emojis são amplamente usados para expressar emoções e conceitos nas mídias sociais, e trabalhos anteriores mostraram que a escolha dos emojis pelos usuários reflete a maneira como eles desejam se apresentar ao mundo. O uso de emojis geralmente é estudado no contexto de postagens feitas por usuários, e essa visão forneceu informações importantes sobre fenômenos como expressão emocional e autorrepresentação. Além de fazer postagens, no entanto, plataformas de mídia social como o Twitter permitem que os usuários forneçam uma pequena biografia, que é uma oportunidade de descrever brevemente sua conta como um todo. Neste trabalho, focamos no uso de emoji nessas declarações bio. Exploramos as maneiras pelas quais os usuários incluem emoji nessas autodescrições, encontrando padrões diferentes daqueles observados em torno do uso de emojis nos tweets. Examinamos as relações entre os emojis usados nas biografias e o conteúdo dos tweets dos usuários, mostrando que os tópicos e até mesmo o sentimento médio dos tweets variam para usuários com diferentes emojis em suas biografias. Por fim, confirmamos que existem efeitos de homofilia em relação aos tipos de emojis incluídos nas biografias dos usuários e seus seguidores.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>絵文字は、感情や概念をソーシャルメディアで表現するために広く使用されており、以前の研究では、ユーザーが絵文字を選択することは、自分自身が世界に提示したい方法を反映していることが示されています。 絵文字の使用は、一般的にユーザーが投稿する文脈で研究されており、この見解は、感情表現や自己表現などの現象について重要な洞察を提供してきました。 しかし、投稿に加えて、Twitterのようなソーシャルメディアプラットフォームは、ユーザーが短い経歴を提供することを可能にします。これは、アカウント全体を簡単に説明する機会です。 本作では、これらのバイオステートメントでの絵文字の使用に焦点を当てています。 ユーザーがこれらの自己説明に絵文字を含める方法を探り、ツイートの絵文字の使用で観察されたものとは異なるパターンを見つけます。 バイオで使用されている絵文字とユーザーのツイートの内容との関係を調べると、トピックやツイートの平均的な感情は、バイオで絵文字が異なるユーザーによって異なることがわかります。 最後に、ユーザーとそのフォロワーのバイオに含まれる絵文字の種類に関して、ホモフィルム効果が存在することを確認します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>表情符号博施于社交媒体,而先论之,用户表情符号之所见,而欲示于世。 表情符号用法常于用户帖背景下究之,为情致自我表现之要。 然帖子之外,Twitter等社交媒体台犹许用户短简历,此简言其帐户以为一体也。 于此之事,专注于物表情符号。 探用户自述含表情符号,得与推表情符号异式。 臣等考bios之表情符号与用户推文之情,明于BIOS用异表情符号之用户,推文之主题,至均情异也。 最后认为,于用户及关注者生物中包含的表情符号类,存同质化效应。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>इमोजी का व्यापक रूप से सोशल मीडिया पर भावनाओं और अवधारणाओं को व्यक्त करने के लिए उपयोग किया जाता है, और पूर्व कार्य से पता चला है कि इमोजी की उपयोगकर्ताओं की पसंद उस तरीके को दर्शाती है जो वे खुद को दुनिया के सामने पेश करना चाहते हैं। इमोजी उपयोग आमतौर पर उपयोगकर्ताओं द्वारा किए गए पोस्ट के संदर्भ में अध्ययन किया जाता है, और इस दृश्य ने भावनात्मक अभिव्यक्ति और आत्म-प्रतिनिधित्व जैसी घटनाओं में महत्वपूर्ण अंतर्दृष्टि प्रदान की है। पोस्ट बनाने के अलावा, हालांकि, ट्विटर जैसे सोशल मीडिया प्लेटफॉर्म उपयोगकर्ताओं को एक छोटा जैव प्रदान करने की अनुमति देते हैं, जो कि उनके खाते को पूरी तरह से संक्षेप में वर्णन करने का अवसर है। इस काम में, हम इन जैव बयानों में इमोजी के उपयोग पर ध्यान केंद्रित करते हैं। हम उन तरीकों का पता लगाते हैं जिनमें उपयोगकर्ता इन आत्म-विवरणों में इमोजी शामिल करते हैं, ट्वीट्स में इमोजी उपयोग के आसपास देखे गए लोगों की तुलना में अलग-अलग पैटर्न ढूंढते हैं। हम बायोस में उपयोग किए जाने वाले इमोजी और उपयोगकर्ताओं के ट्वीट्स की सामग्री के बीच संबंधों की जांच करते हैं, यह दिखाते हुए कि विषय और यहां तक कि ट्वीट्स की औसत भावना उनके बायोस में अलग-अलग इमोजी वाले उपयोगकर्ताओं के लिए भिन्न होती है। अंत में, हम पुष्टि करते हैं कि होमोफिली प्रभाव इमोजी के प्रकारों के संबंध में मौजूद हैं जो उपयोगकर्ताओं और उनके अनुयायियों के बायोस में शामिल हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Úsáidtear Emoji go forleathan chun mothúcháin agus coincheapa a chur in iúl ar na meáin shóisialta, agus léirigh obair roimhe seo go léiríonn rogha úsáideoirí emoji an bealach ar mian leo iad féin a chur i láthair an domhain. Go hiondúil déantar staidéar ar úsáid Emoji i gcomhthéacs postálacha a dhéanann úsáideoirí, agus tá léargais thábhachtacha tugtha ag an dearcadh seo ar fheiniméin mar léiriú mothúchánach agus féin-léiriú. Chomh maith le postálacha a dhéanamh, áfach, ligeann ardáin meán sóisialta cosúil le Twitter d'úsáideoirí beathaisnéis ghearr a sholáthar, rud a thugann deis cur síos gairid a dhéanamh ar a gcuntas ina iomláine. Sa obair seo, dírímid ar úsáid emoji sna bithráitis seo. Déanaimid iniúchadh ar na bealaí ina n-áiríonn úsáideoirí emoji sna féin-thuairiscí seo, ag aimsiú patrúin éagsúla seachas iad siúd a breathnaíodh maidir le húsáid emoji i dtvuíteanna. Scrúdaímid na caidrimh idir emoji a úsáidtear i bios agus ábhar tweets na n-úsáideoirí, rud a thaispeánann go n-athraíonn na topaicí agus fiú meon na tweets d'úsáideoirí le emoji éagsúla ina bios. Ar deireadh, dearbhaímid go bhfuil éifeachtaí homafilí ann maidir leis na cineálacha emoji atá san áireamh i mbithsanna úsáideoirí agus a lucht leanúna.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Τα χρησιμοποιούνται ευρέως για να εκφράσουν συναισθήματα και έννοιες στα μέσα κοινωνικής δικτύωσης και προηγούμενες εργασίες έχουν δείξει ότι η επιλογή των χρηστών αντανακλά τον τρόπο με τον οποίο επιθυμούν να παρουσιαστούν στον κόσμο. Η χρήση μελετάται συνήθως στο πλαίσιο των δημοσιεύσεων που κάνουν οι χρήστες, και αυτή η άποψη έχει παράσχει σημαντικές γνώσεις σε φαινόμενα όπως η συναισθηματική έκφραση και η αυτοαναπαράσταση. Εκτός από τη δημοσίευση, ωστόσο, πλατφόρμες κοινωνικής δικτύωσης όπως το Twitter επιτρέπουν στους χρήστες να παρέχουν ένα σύντομο βιογραφικό, το οποίο είναι μια ευκαιρία να περιγράψουν εν συντομία το λογαριασμό τους ως σύνολο. Σε αυτή την εργασία, εστιάζουμε στη χρήση των σε αυτές τις βιοδηλώσεις. Ερευνούμε τους τρόπους με τους οποίους οι χρήστες περιλαμβάνουν σε αυτές τις αυτοπεριγραφές, βρίσκοντας διαφορετικά μοτίβα από αυτά που παρατηρούνται γύρω από τη χρήση σε tweets. Εξετάζουμε τις σχέσεις μεταξύ των emoji που χρησιμοποιούνται στα βιογραφικά και του περιεχομένου των tweets των χρηστών, δείχνοντας ότι τα θέματα και ακόμη και το μέσο συναίσθημα των tweets ποικίλουν για τους χρήστες με διαφορετικά emoji στα βιογραφικά τους. Τέλος, επιβεβαιώνουμε ότι υπάρχουν ομοιοφιλικές επιδράσεις όσον αφορά τους τύπους που περιλαμβάνονται στα βιογραφικά των χρηστών και των οπαδών τους.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>ემოჯია ძალიან გამოყენებულია სოციალური მედიაში ემოციების და კონცეტების გამოსახულებლად, და წინ სამუშაო სამუშაო მუშაოში გამოიყენება, რომ მომხმარებელი ემოჯიას გამ Emoji გამოყენება ტიპოლურად მომხმარების კონტექსტში აკეთებულია, და ეს ხედვა გასანიშვნელოვანი ფენომენებში, როგორც ემოციონალური გამოსახულება და self-representation. მაგრამ სოციალური მედია პლატატურები, როგორც Twitter, მომხმარებელი უნდა მომხმარებელი ბიოდომის შესაძლებლობა, რომელიც შესაძლებელია საკუთარ დონტურის აღწერა. ამ სამუშაოში, ჩვენ ვფიქრობთ ემოჯიას გამოყენებაზე ამ ბიოგიური გამოსახულებაში. ჩვენ ვაკვირდებით როგორც მომხმარებელი ემოჯია ამ თავისწერების განსაკუთრებულებაში დავყენებთ, განსხვავებული მონაცემებით, ვიდრე ემოჯიას გამოყენებაში. ჩვენ ვხედავთ ვიოჯიში გამოიყენებული ელემები და გამოყენებელების რვიტების შემდგომარების შესახებ, რომელიც გამოყენებულია, რომ ტემები და კიდევ სინამდგომარების სინტემენტი განსხვავებულია მო საბოლოოდ, ჩვენ დარწმუნებით, რომ ჰომოფილიური ეფექტები არსებობს, რომლებიც მომხმარებელი და შემდეგების ბიოჯში ჩვენებულია.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Az emojikat széles körben használják az érzelmek és fogalmak kifejezésére a közösségi médiában, és a korábbi munkák azt mutatták, hogy a felhasználók emojik választása tükrözi azt, ahogyan szeretnék bemutatni magukat a világnak. Az emoji használatát jellemzően a felhasználók által készített bejegyzések kontextusában tanulmányozzák, és ez a nézet fontos betekintést nyújtott olyan jelenségekbe, mint az érzelmi kifejezés és az önreprezentáció. A bejegyzések készítése mellett azonban a közösségi média platformok, mint a Twitter, lehetővé teszik a felhasználók számára, hogy rövid életrajzot adjanak, ami lehetőséget nyújt arra, hogy röviden leírják fiókjukat egészében. Ebben a munkában az emoji használatára összpontosítunk ezekben a bio állításokban. Megvizsgáljuk, hogy a felhasználók milyen módon foglalják be az emoji-t ezekben az önleírásokban, és különböző mintákat találnak, mint amelyeket az emoji használat körül megfigyeltek a tweetekben. Megvizsgáljuk a bioszban használt emoji-k és a felhasználók tweetjeinek tartalma közötti kapcsolatokat, bemutatva, hogy a témák, sőt még a tweetek átlagos érzelme is eltérő a bioszban eltérő emoji-kkel rendelkező felhasználók esetében. Végezetül megerősítjük, hogy homofília hatások léteznek a felhasználók és követőik bioszámában szereplő emoji típusok tekintetében.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Le emoji sono ampiamente utilizzate per esprimere emozioni e concetti sui social media, e il lavoro precedente ha dimostrato che la scelta degli utenti delle emoji riflette il modo in cui desiderano presentarsi al mondo. L'uso delle emoji è tipicamente studiato nel contesto dei post realizzati dagli utenti, e questa visione ha fornito importanti approfondimenti su fenomeni come l'espressione emotiva e l'auto-rappresentazione. Oltre a creare post, tuttavia, piattaforme di social media come Twitter consentono agli utenti di fornire una breve biografia, che è un'opportunità per descrivere brevemente il loro account nel suo complesso. In questo lavoro, ci concentriamo sull'uso delle emoji in queste bio dichiarazioni. Esploriamo i modi in cui gli utenti includono le emoji in queste auto-descrizioni, trovando modelli diversi da quelli osservati intorno all'uso delle emoji nei tweet. Esaminiamo le relazioni tra le emoji utilizzate nel bios e il contenuto dei tweet degli utenti, mostrando che gli argomenti e persino il sentiment medio dei tweet variano per gli utenti con emoji diversi nel loro bios. Infine, confermiamo che esistono effetti omofili rispetto ai tipi di emoji inclusi nei bios degli utenti e dei loro follower.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Emoji plačiai naudojama išreikšti emocijas ir koncepcijas socialinėje žiniasklaidoje, o ankstesnis darbas parodė, kad naudotojų pasirinktas emoji atspindi būdą, kaip jie nori pristatyti save pasauliui. Emoji naudojimas paprastai tiriamas naudojančių pareigų kontekste ir šis požiūris suteikė svarbų supratimą apie tokius reiškinius kaip emocinė išraiška ir savirepresentacija. Tačiau, be pareigybių, tokios socialinės žiniasklaidos platformos kaip Twitter leidžia naudotojams teikti trumpą biografiją, kuri yra galimybė trumpai aprašyti visą jų sąskaitą. Šiame darbe daugiausia dėmesio skiriame emodžių naudojimui šiuose biopareiškimuose. Mes tiriame būdus, kaip naudotojai įtraukia emodžius į šiuos savaprašymus, ieškodami skirtingų modelių nei pastebėti apie emodžių naudojimą tweetuose. Mes išnagrinėjame santykius tarp biografijoje naudojamų emodžių ir naudotojų tweetų turinio, rodydami, kad tema ir net vidutinis tweetų jausmas skiriasi naudotojams su skirtingomis emodžiomis jų biografijoje. Galiausiai patvirtiname, kad homofilijos poveikis yra susijęs su emodžių rūšimis, įtrauktomis į naudotojų ir jų sekėjų biologiją.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Эмози әлемдік медиақтағы емоциялар мен концепцияларды көрсету үшін көп қолданылады, және алдыңғы жұмыс пайдаланушылардың эмози таңдауы әлемге көрсету керек жолын көрсетеді. Эмози қолдануы әдетте пайдаланушылар жасалған пошта контекстінде оқылған, және бұл көрініс эмоциялық өрнек мен өзіңіздің түсініктеріне маңызды түсініктер берді. Бірақ, Твиттер секілді социалдық медиа платформаларын жасау үшін пайдаланушылардың қысқа биология беру мүмкіндігі болады. Бұл - тіркелгіні толық түрде таңдау мүмкіндігі. Бұл жұмыс ішінде, биологиялық мәліметтердің қолдануына көздейміз. Біз қолданушылардың өзінің түсініктемелерінде эмоджияларды қалай көрсету үлгілерін табу үлгілерінде табу үлгілерін табу үлгілерінде іздейміз. Біз биологияларда және пайдаланушылардың tweets мазмұнында қолданылатын эмоджтердің қатынастарын тексереміз. Тақырыптарды және tweets орташа сезімі өзінің биологияларда әртүрлі эмоджтердің пайдаланушыларға айыр Соңында, пайдаланушылардың биологияларында және олардың қадағалаушыларында қосылған эмодж түрлеріне қатынау гомофиялық эффекттері бар дегенді тексереміз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Emoji digunakan secara luas untuk mengekspresikan emosi dan konsep pada media sosial, dan kerja sebelumnya telah menunjukkan bahawa pilihan emoji pengguna mencerminkan cara mereka ingin memperkenalkan diri kepada dunia. Penggunaan emoji biasanya dipelajari dalam konteks pos yang dibuat oleh pengguna, dan pandangan ini telah memberikan pandangan penting kepada fenomena seperti ungkapan emosional dan mewakili diri. Selain membuat pos, bagaimanapun, platform media sosial seperti Twitter membenarkan pengguna untuk menyediakan bio pendek, yang merupakan peluang untuk menjelaskan secara singkat akaun mereka sebagai keseluruhan. Dalam kerja ini, kita fokus pada penggunaan emoji dalam pernyataan bio ini. Kami mengeksplorasi cara pengguna menyertai emoji dalam deskripsi-diri ini, mencari corak yang berbeza dari corak yang dilihat disekitar penggunaan emoji dalam tweet. Kami memeriksa hubungan antara emoji yang digunakan dalam bio dan kandungan tweet pengguna, menunjukkan bahawa topik dan sentimen purata tweet berbeza bagi pengguna dengan emoji yang berbeza dalam bio mereka. Akhirnya, kami mengesahkan bahawa kesan homofili wujud terhadap jenis emoji yang termasuk dalam bio pengguna dan pengikut mereka.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>എമോജി സോഷ്യല്‍ മീഡിയില്‍ വികാരങ്ങളും ആശയങ്ങളും പ്രസ്താവിക്കാന്‍ വിശാലമായി ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു. മുമ്പ് ജോലി കാണിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു ഉപയോക എമോജി ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത് ഉപയോക്താക്കള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയ പോസ്റ്റുകളുടെ കൂട്ടത്തില്‍ സാധാരണമായി പഠിക്കുന്നു. ഈ കാഴ്ച പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട ക പോസ്റ്റുകള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കുന്നതിനു ശേഷം ടൂട്ടറിനെപ്പോലുള്ള സാമൂഹ്യ മാധ്യമങ്ങളുടെ പ്ലാറ്റ്ഫോമുകള്‍ ഉപയോക്താക്കള്‍ക്ക് ഒരു ചെ ഈ ജോലിയില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ ഇമോജിയെ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതിനെപ്പറ്റി ശ്രദ്ധിക്കുന്നു. ഈ സ്വയം വിശദീകരണങ്ങളില്‍ ഇമോജിയെ ഉപയോക്താക്കള്‍ ചേര്‍ക്കുന്ന വഴികള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ പരിശോധിക്കുന്നു. ഇമോജി ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നതിനെക ബൈയോസിയിലും ഉപയോക്താക്കളുടെ ടൂട്ടുകളിലും ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന ഇമോജിയുടെ ബന്ധങ്ങള്‍ നമ്മള്‍ പരിശോധിക്കുന്നു. പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട വിഷയങ്ങളും ടൂട്ടുകളു അവസാനം, ഞങ്ങള്‍ ഉറപ്പ് വരുത്തുന്നത് ഹോമോഫിയില്‍ പ്രഭാവങ്ങള്‍ ഉണ്ടെന്നാണ്. ഇമോജിയുടെ തരത്തില്‍ ഉള്‍പെടുന്ന ഇമോജിയുടെയ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mk>Емоџи се широко употребени за изразување на емоции и концепти на социјалните медиуми, а претходната работа покажа дека изборот на емоции на корисниците го одразува начинот на кој сакаат да се претстават на светот. Користењето на емоџи обично се проучува во контекст на постови направени од корисниците, и овој поглед обезбеди важни сфаќања за феномени како емоционално изразување и самопретставување. Но, покрај поставувањето на постови, платформите на социјалните медиуми како Твитер им овозможуваат на корисниците да обезбедат кратко био, што е можност за кратко да ја опишат нивната сметка како целина. Во оваа работа, се фокусираме на употребата на емоџи во овие биолошки изјави. Ги истражуваме начините на кои корисниците вклучуваат емоџи во овие самописи, откривајќи различни шеми од оние кои се набљудуваат околу употребата на емоџи на твитови. Ги испитуваме односите помеѓу емоџите кои се користат во биологијата и содржината на твитовите на корисниците, покажувајќи дека темите и дури и просечното чувство на твитовите се различни за корисниците со различни емоџи во нивните биологии. На крајот, потврдиме дека постојат хомофилни ефекти во однос на видовите на емоџи кои се вклучени во биологијата на корисниците и нивните следбеници.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mt>Emoji jintużaw b’mod wiesa’ biex jesprimu emozzjonijiet u kunċetti fuq il-midja soċjali, u xogħol preċedenti wera li l-għażla tal-utenti tal-emoji tirrifletti l-mod kif jixtiequ jippreżentaw ruħhom lid-dinja. L-użu ta’ Emoji huwa tipikament studjat fil-kuntest ta’ karigi magħmula mill-utenti, u din il-fehma pprovdiet għarfien importanti dwar fenomeni bħall-espressjoni emozzjonali u l-awto-rappreżentanza. Minbarra li jagħmlu postijiet, madankollu, pjattaformi tal-midja soċjali bħal Twitter jippermettu lill-utenti jipprovdu bijoloġija qasira, li hija opportunità biex jiddeskrivu fil-qosor il-kont tagħhom kollu kemm hu. F’dan ix-xogħol, niffokaw fuq l-użu ta’ emoji f’dawn id-dikjarazzjonijiet bijoloġiċi. Aħna nesploraw il-modi kif l-utenti jinkludu l-emoji f’dawn l-awtodiskrizzjonijiet, u nsibu mudelli differenti minn dawk osservati madwar l-użu tal-emoji fit-tweets. Aħna jeżaminaw ir-relazzjonijiet bejn l-emoji użati fil-bijoloġiji u l-kontenut tat-tweets tal-utenti, li juru li s-suġġetti u saħansitra s-sentiment medju tat-tweets ivarjaw għall-utenti b’emoji differenti fil-bijoloġiji tagħhom. Fl-aħħar nett, nikkonfermaw li jeżistu effetti omofiliċi fir-rigward tat-tipi ta’ emoji li huma inklużi fil-bijoloġiji tal-utenti u ta’ dawk li jsegwuhom.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Эмози нийгмийн мэдээллийн хэрэглэгчийн сонголтыг дэлхий дээр харуулахын тулд сэтгэл хөдлөл, ойлголт илэрхийлдэг. Эмози хэрэглээнд хэрэглэгчид хийсэн захирамжуудын тухай ихэвчлэн судалдаг. Энэ үзэл сэтгэл хөдлөл, өөрийгөө үзүүлэх мэт явдалд чухал ойлголт өгсөн. Гэхдээ Twitter шиг нийгмийн хэвлэлийн платформ нь хэрэглэгчид богино биологийг хангах боломж олгодог. Энэ нь тэдний тоонуудыг тодорхойлох боломж юм. Энэ ажил дээр бид эдгээр биологийн илтгэл дээр эмози хэрэглээнд анхаарлаа хандуулдаг. Бид хэрэглэгчид эдгээр өөрийгөө тайлбарлаж, эмоджийн хэрэглээнээс өөр хэлбэрийг олох арга замыг судалж байна. Бид биос болон хэрэглэгчдийн tweets-ээр хэрэглэгдсэн эможийн хоорондын харилцааны хоорондын харилцааныг шалгаж үздэг. Хэдий сэдэв болон дундаж tweets-ийн мэдрэмж нь биос дээр өөр эможийн хэрэглэгчид өөр өөр өөр өөр өөр өөр Эцэст нь бид хэрэглэгчид болон дагагчид биологийн биологид дүрслэгдсэн эможи төрлийн эффектүүд байдаг гэдгийг баталж байна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Emoji są szeroko stosowane do wyrażania emocji i koncepcji w mediach społecznościowych, a wcześniejsze prace pokazały, że wybór emoji użytkowników odzwierciedla sposób, w jaki chcą się prezentować światu. Użycie emoji jest zazwyczaj badane w kontekście postów publikowanych przez użytkowników, a ten widok dostarczył ważnych wglądów w zjawiska takie jak ekspresja emocjonalna i samoreprezentacja. Oprócz publikowania postów jednak platformy mediów społecznościowych, takie jak Twitter, pozwalają użytkownikom na podanie krótkiej biografii, która jest okazją krótko opisać swoje konto jako całość. W tej pracy skupiamy się na wykorzystaniu emoji w tych bio stwierdzeniach. Badamy sposoby, w jakie użytkownicy umieszczają emoji w tych samopisach, znajdując inne wzorce niż te obserwowane wokół używania emoji w tweetach. Badamy związki między emoji używanymi w bios a treścią tweetów użytkowników, pokazując, że tematy, a nawet średni sentyment tweetów różni się u użytkowników z różnymi emoji w ich bios. Wreszcie potwierdzamy, że efekty homofiliczne istnieją w odniesieniu do rodzajów emoji, które są zawarte w bios użytkowników i ich zwolenników.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_si>එමෝජියා සාමාජික මිඩියාවේ හැඟීම සහ අදහසක් ප්‍රවේශනය කරන්න භාවිත වෙනවා, ඒ වගේම කලින් වැඩේ ප්‍රවේශනය කරලා තියෙනවා ඒ වග එමෝජි භාවිතානය සාමාන්‍යයෙන්ම ප්‍රයෝජකයෙන් කරපු පොස්ට්ස් සංවේදනයේ අධ්‍යානය කරනවා, ඒ වගේම මේ ප්‍රයෝජනය ලැබුන ඒත් පොස්ටල් හදන්න සමාජික මාධ්‍යම ප්ලේටම් වගේ ට්විටර් වගේ සාමාජික මාධ්‍යම ප්‍ලේටම් වලින් පාවිච්චි බියෝ මේ වැඩේ අපි මේ බියෝජි ප්‍රතිචාරයේ emoji භාවිතා කරන්න බලන්න. අපි පාවිච්චි කරන්නේ මේ ස්වයංග විස්තරයෙන් emoji වලින් සම්බන්ධ වෙන්න ප්‍රයෝජනය, emoji වලින් පාවිච්චි වලින් ව අපි බියෝජි වල භාවිත කරපු emoji වල සම්බන්ධතාවක් පරීක්ෂා කරනවා, ප්‍රයෝජකයාගේ ට්විට් වලින් සමාන්‍ය විදිහට ප්‍රයෝජකයෙන් වෙනස්  අන්තිමේදී, අපි තහවුරු කරනවා මෙමෝජි වර්ගයක් ගැන සම්බන්ධයෙන් තියෙනවා කියලා.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_no>Emoji er breidd brukt for å uttrykke emosjoner og konseptar på sosiale medier, og førre arbeid har vist at brukaren har valet på emoji reflekterer måten dei ønskjer å visa seg til verden. Bruk av emoji er vanlegvis studiert i konteksten av postar lagt av brukarar, og denne visinga har tilgang viktige innsyningar i fenomenar som emosjonell uttrykk og selvrepresentasjon. I tillegg til å laga e-post, kan imidlertid sosiale mediaplattformar som Twitter tillata brukarar å gje kort biografikk, som er ein mulighet til å skildra kontoen sin kort heilt. I dette arbeidet fokuserer vi på bruk av emoji i disse biouttrykkene. Vi undersøker måtene brukarar inkluderer emoji i desse selvskriftene, og finn ulike mønsterer enn dei som er observert rundt bruk av emoji i tweets. Vi undersøker forbindelsane mellom emoji som brukar i biografikk og innhaldet i brukaren av tweeter, viser at emna og sjølv gjennomsnittlig følelse av tweeter varierer for brukarar med ulike emoji i biografikk sine. Etter slutt, vi bekrefter at homofiske effektar finst i henhold til typane emoji som er inkludert i biografikk av brukarar og følgjande sine.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Emoji-urile sunt utilizate pe scară largă pentru a exprima emoții și concepte pe rețelele de socializare, iar lucrările anterioare au arătat că alegerea emoji-urilor utilizatorilor reflectă modul în care doresc să se prezinte lumii. Utilizarea emoji-urilor este de obicei studiată în contextul postărilor făcute de utilizatori, iar această viziune a oferit perspective importante asupra fenomenelor cum ar fi expresia emoțională și auto-reprezentarea. Pe lângă a face postări, totuși, platformele de social media precum Twitter permit utilizatorilor să ofere o scurtă biografie, ceea ce reprezintă o oportunitate de a descrie pe scurt contul lor ca întreg. În această lucrare, ne concentrăm pe utilizarea emoji-urilor în aceste declarații bio. Explorăm modalitățile în care utilizatorii includ emoji-uri în aceste auto-descrieri, găsind modele diferite decât cele observate în jurul utilizării emoji-urilor în tweet-uri. Examinăm relațiile dintre emoji utilizate în bios și conținutul tweeturilor utilizatorilor, arătând că subiectele și chiar sentimentul mediu al tweeturilor variază pentru utilizatorii cu emoji diferite în bios. În cele din urmă, confirmăm că există efecte homofile în ceea ce privește tipurile de emoji care sunt incluse în bios-urile utilizatorilor și ale adepților acestora.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Emoji se široko koriste za izražavanje emocija i koncepta na društvenim medijima, a pre posla pokazuje da izbor emoji korisnika odražava način na koji žele da se predstave svijetu. Koristenje emoji se obično proučava u kontekstu postova koje su napravljene korisnicima, a ovaj pogled je pružio važne uvide u fenomene kao što su emocionalni izraz i samoopredstavljanje. Međutim, dodatno postima, društveni medijski platformi poput Twitter omogućavaju korisnicima da pruže kratku biologiju, što je prilika kratko opisati svoj račun kao cjelokupan. U ovom poslu, fokusiramo se na upotrebu emoji u ovim bioizjavama. Istražujemo način na koji korisnici uključuju emoji u tih samopopisivanja, pronalaženje različitih obrazaca od onih koji su posmatrali oko korištenja emoji u tweetima. Pregledavamo odnose između emoji korištenih u biologiji i sadržaja tweta korisnika, pokazujući da teme i prosječni osjećaj tweta razlikuju korisnicima sa različitim emojima u njihovim biologijama. Na kraju, potvrđujemo da homofijski efekti postoje u odnosu na vrste emoji koji su uključeni u biografije korisnika i njihovih slijeditelja.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>எமோஜி பெரிய உணர்வுகளையும் கருத்துக்களையும் வெளிப்படுத்த பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது, முன்னால் வேலை காண்பிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது எமோஜி தேர்வு அவர எமோஜி பயன்பாடு பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது பயனர் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட அஞ்சல்களின் மூலத்தில் படிக்கப்படுகிறது, இந்த காட்சி உணர்வு கூற்று மற்றும் தன்னியக் எனினும் பதிவுகளை உருவாக்குவதற்குக் கூட, Twitter போன்ற சமூக ஊடகங்கள் தளங்கள் பயனர்கள் சிறிய உயிரியல் வழங்க அனுமதிக்க அனுமதிக்கிறது, அது சிறிதாக இந்த வேலையில், நாம் இந்த உயிரியல் கூற்றுகளில் உணர்ச்சியை பயன்படுத்தி கவனம் செலுத்துகிறோம். We explore the ways in which users include emoji in these self-descriptions, finding different patterns than those observed around emoji usage in tweets.  நாம் உயிரோடுகளில் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட emoji மற்றும் பயனரின் tweetiகளின் உள்ளடக்கத்திற்கும் இடையே தொடர்புகளை பரிசோதிக்கிறோம். தலைப்புகள் மற்றும் அவர்கள் உயிர்கள கடைசியாக, நாம் நிரூபிக்கிறோம் பாதிப்பு விளைவுகள் இருக்கிறது என்று மற்றும் பயனர்கள் மற்றும் அவர்கள் பின்பற்றுபவர்கள் இமோ</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_so>Emoji waxaa si badan loogu isticmaalaa fikrada iyo fikrada ku saabsan shabakada bulshada, shaqada horena waxaa tusay in doorashada isticmaalayaasha emoji ay ka muuqato qaabka ay doonayaan inay isu soo bandhigaan dunida. Sida caadiga ah isticmaalka Emoji waxaa lagu bartaa warqadaha ay isticmaalayaasha, aragtidaasuna wuxuu ka dhigay aragti muhiim ah oo ka mid ah fikrada emotional iyo iskuulka. Si kastaba ha ahaatee, koorasyo sameynta qoraalka shabakada bulshada ee sida Twitterka ayaa isticmaalayaasha u ruqsan kara inuu siiyo bio gaaban, taas oo fursado si fudud ugu sawiro akauntooda oo dhan. Shaqodaas waxan, waxaynu ku kalsoonaynaa isticmaalka emoji ee warqaddan biobiyada ah. Waxaynu baaraynaa jidadka ay isticmaalayaashaas ku jiraan emoji, kaas oo aan helayno noocyo kala duduwan oo ay ka heleen isticmaalka emoji ee tweetka. Waxaan baaritaannaa xiriirka emoji ee ku isticmaalaya dabiicadda iyo waxyaabaha ku jira tweetka isticmaalayaasha, waxaynu tusnaynaa in arimaha iyo xittaa xisaabta ugu badnaanta tweetka ay u kala duwan yihiin isticmaalayaasha emoji kala duduwan. ugu dambeyso waxaynu xaqiijinnaa in saamaynta homofayga ah ay jiraan noocyada emoji ee ku jira bio-tijaabiyada isticmaalayaasha iyo raacayaashooda.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Emoji används ofta för att uttrycka känslor och begrepp på sociala medier, och tidigare arbete har visat att användares val av emoji återspeglar hur de vill presentera sig för världen. Emojianvändning studeras vanligtvis i samband med inlägg gjorda av användare, och denna syn har gett viktiga insikter i fenomen som känslomässigt uttryck och självrepresentation. Förutom att göra inlägg, tillåter sociala medier plattformar som Twitter användare att tillhandahålla en kort bio, vilket är en möjlighet att kort beskriva sitt konto som helhet. I detta arbete fokuserar vi på användningen av emoji i dessa bio uttalanden. Vi undersöker hur användare inkluderar emoji i dessa självbeskrivningar och hittar olika mönster än de som observeras kring emoji användning i tweets. Vi undersöker relationerna mellan emoji som används i bios och innehållet i användares tweets, vilket visar att ämnena och även den genomsnittliga känslan i tweets varierar för användare med olika emoji i deras bios. Slutligen bekräftar vi att homofila effekter finns med avseende på de typer av emoji som ingår i bios av användare och deras följare.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>ایموجی کو سوسیل میڈیا کے ذریعے احساسات اور نظریں بیان کرنے کے لئے وسیع طور پر استعمال کیا جاتا ہے، اور پہلے کام نے دکھایا ہے کہ اپنا کارساز ایموجی کا انتخاب کس طرح دکھاتا ہے جس طرح وہ دنیا میں حاضر کرنا چاہتے ہیں۔ ایموجی کا استعمال معمولاً کارساز کے بنائے ہوئے پوسٹوں میں پڑھا جاتا ہے، اور اس نظر نے اہم بصیرت کو ایسے موجودات میں پیش کیا ہے جیسے احساساتی اثر اور خود نمایش. اگرچہ پوسٹ بنانے کے علاوہ، ٹویٹر جیسی سوسیل میڈیا پٹرومٹ کاروں کو چھوٹی بیویو کے لئے اجازت دیتے ہیں، جو ان کے حساب کو تھوڑی سی دفعہ دفع کرنے کی فرصت ہے۔ اس کام میں ہم emoji کے استعمال پر تمرکز کر رہے ہیں۔ ہم ان طریقوں کو دیکھتے ہیں جن طریقوں میں استعمال کرنے والے emoji کے ساتھ ان کی خود واضح توجیت میں ملتے ہیں، اور ان سے مختلف طریقوں کو دیکھتے ہیں جو emoji کے گرد موجود ہیں۔ ہم اِموجی کے درمیان ان رابطہ تحقیق کرتے ہیں جو اِموجی کے ساتھ استعمال کئے جاتے ہیں اور اُن کے ٹویٹوں کی منصوبت کے ساتھ، دکھاتے ہیں کہ ٹویٹوں کے متوسط احساسات بھی اُن کے بیوی میں مختلف emoji کے ساتھ متفاوت ہیں۔ بالآخر، ہم تصدیق کرتے ہیں کہ موجود اثرات موجود ہیں جن میں موجود موجود موجود موجود ہیں جو استعمال کرنے والوں اور ان کے تابعداروں میں شامل ہوئے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Emoji shamol media hissiyotlari va g'oyalarni ko'rsatish uchun juda ko'p foydalanadi va avval ishni ko'rsatadi, foydalanuvchilar emoji xususiyatlarini dunyo bo'ylashni qanday qilishini ko'rsatadi. Name In addition to making posts, however, social media platforms like Twitter allow for users to provide a short bio, which is an opportunity to briefly describe their account as a whole.  Bu ishda, biz bu bioviy hodisadagi emoji ishlatishga foydalanamiz. Biz foydalanuvchilar foydalanuvchilarga emoji o'z taʼriflarida o'rganamiz, Twitterda emoji foydalanuvchidan boshqa shakllarni topamiz. Biz bioviy va foydalanuvchilar Twitterdan foydalanuvchilar tarkibida ishlatilgan munosabatlarni ko'rib chiqaramiz. Bu haqida mavzu va o'sha Twitterdan foydalanuvchilar bilan boshqa emoji bo'lgan foydalanuvchiga o'zgarishdir. Keyingi biz foydalanuvchilar va foydalanuvchilar biosidagi foydalanuvchilarga qo'llangan emoji turlari haqida ishonch qilamiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Emoji đã được phổ biến để bộc lộ cảm xúc và khái niệm về các phương tiện truyền thông xã hội, và những công việc trước đó đã cho thấy sự lựa chọn biểu tượng của người dùng phản ánh cách họ muốn tự giới thiệu. Cách sử dụng Emoji được nghiên cứu trong hoàn cảnh của những người dùng, và quan điểm này đã cung cấp những nhận thức quan trọng về những hiện tượng như biểu hiện cảm xúc và tự đại. Bên cạnh việc đăng bài, các nền truyền thông xã hội như Twitter cho phép người dùng cung cấp một tiểu sử ngắn, cơ hội để mô tả ngắn gọn to àn bộ tài khoản của họ. Trong công việc này, chúng ta tập trung vào việc dùng biểu tượng đa dạng trong bản sinh học. Chúng tôi tìm hiểu cách dùng biểu tượng trong những mô tả tự động này, tìm ra những mô hình khác với cách sử dụng biểu tượng biểu tượng trên Twitter. Chúng tôi kiểm tra các mối quan hệ giữa các biểu tượng dùng trong sinh học và nội dung của các dòng tweet, cho thấy các chủ đề và thậm chí tỉ lệ cảm nhận của tweet khác nhau trong các bản sinh học. Cuối cùng, chúng tôi xác nhận sự đồng tính có tác dụng đối với những loại biểu tượng có tính đồng tính đồng tính bao gồm trong sinh học của người dùng và người theo họ.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Емодите са широко използвани за изразяване на емоции и концепции в социалните медии, а предишни изследвания показват, че изборът на емоджи от потребителите отразява начина, по който те искат да се представят на света. Използването на емоджи обикновено се изучава в контекста на публикациите, направени от потребителите, и това виждане дава важни прозрения за явления като емоционално изразяване и самопредставяне. В допълнение към публикуването на публикации обаче, платформите за социални медии като Туитър позволяват на потребителите да предоставят кратка биография, което е възможност накратко да опишат профила си като цяло. В тази работа се фокусираме върху използването на емоджи в тези биоизявления. Ние изследваме начините, по които потребителите включват емоджи в тези самоописания, намирайки различни модели от тези, наблюдавани около използването на емоджи в туитове. Разглеждаме взаимоотношенията между емоджи използвани в биосите и съдържанието на туитовете на потребителите, показвайки, че темите и дори средните настроения на туитовете варират за потребители с различни емоджи в биосите си. И накрая, потвърждаваме, че хомофиличните ефекти съществуват по отношение на видовете емоджи, които са включени в биографията на потребителите и техните последователи.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Emoji se široko koriste kako bi izrazili emocije i koncept na društvenim medijima, a prije posla pokazalo je da izbor emoji korisnika odražava način na koji žele predstaviti se svijetu. Korištenje emoji obično se proučava u kontekstu postova koje su napravljene korisnicima, a ovaj pogled je pružio važne uvide u fenomene poput emocionalnog izraza i samoozastupanja. Međutim, osim postupaka, društveni medijski platformi poput Twitter omogućavaju korisnicima pružiti kratku biografiju, što je prilika kratko opisati svoj račun kao cjelokupan. U ovom poslu, fokusiramo se na upotrebu emoji u ovim bioizjavama. Istražujemo načine na koji korisnici uključuju emoji u tih samopisa, pronalaženje različitih obrazaca od onih koji su posmatrali oko korištenja emoji u tweetima. Istražujemo odnose između emoji korištenih u biologiji i sadržaja tweta korisnika, pokazujući da se teme i čak prosječna osjećaj tweta razlikuju za korisnike s različitim emojima u njihovim biologijama. Na kraju, potvrđujemo da homofijski učinci postoje u odnosu na vrste emoji koji su uključeni u biografije korisnika i njihove sljedbenike.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Emoji bruges i vid udstrækning til at udtrykke følelser og begreber på sociale medier, og tidligere arbejde har vist, at brugernes valg af emoji afspejler den måde, de ønsker at præsentere sig for verden. Emoji brug studeres typisk i forbindelse med indlæg lavet af brugere, og dette synspunkt har givet vigtig indsigt i fænomener som følelsesmæssig udtryk og selvrepræsentation. Ud over at lave indlæg giver sociale medieplatforme som Twitter dog brugerne mulighed for at levere en kort biografi, hvilket er en mulighed for kort beskrivelse af deres konto som helhed. I dette arbejde fokuserer vi på brugen af emoji i disse bio-udsagn. Vi undersøger, hvordan brugerne inkluderer emoji i disse selvbeskrivelser, og finder forskellige mønstre end dem, der observeres omkring emoji brug i tweets. Vi undersøger forholdet mellem emoji brugt i bios og indholdet af brugernes tweets, og viser, at emnerne og selv den gennemsnitlige følelse af tweets varierer for brugere med forskellige emoji i deres bios. Endelig bekræfter vi, at homofile effekter eksisterer med hensyn til de typer emoji, der er inkluderet i bios af brugere og deres tilhængere.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Emoji worden veel gebruikt om emoties en concepten uit te drukken op sociale media, en eerder werk heeft aangetoond dat de keuze van gebruikers voor emoji weerspiegelt de manier waarop ze zichzelf willen presenteren aan de wereld. Emoji-gebruik wordt meestal bestudeerd in de context van berichten van gebruikers, en deze kijk heeft belangrijke inzichten gegeven in verschijnselen zoals emotionele expressie en zelfrepresentatie. Naast het plaatsen van berichten, bieden sociale media platforms zoals Twitter gebruikers echter de mogelijkheid om een korte bio te verstrekken, wat een gelegenheid is om hun account als geheel kort te beschrijven. In dit werk richten we ons op het gebruik van emoji in deze bio statements. We onderzoeken de manieren waarop gebruikers emoji opnemen in deze zelfbeschrijvingen, waarbij we andere patronen vinden dan die waargenomen rond emoji-gebruik in tweets. We onderzoeken de relaties tussen emoji gebruikt in bios en de inhoud van tweets van gebruikers, waaruit blijkt dat de onderwerpen en zelfs het gemiddelde sentiment van tweets variëren voor gebruikers met verschillende emoji in hun bios. Tot slot bevestigen we dat homofiele effecten bestaan met betrekking tot de soorten emoji die zijn opgenomen in bios van gebruikers en hun volgers.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Emoji werden häufig verwendet, um Emotionen und Konzepte in sozialen Medien auszudrücken, und frühere Arbeiten haben gezeigt, dass die Wahl der Emoji-Nutzer die Art und Weise widerspiegelt, wie sie sich der Welt präsentieren möchten. Emoji-Nutzung wird typischerweise im Kontext von Beiträgen von Nutzern untersucht, und diese Ansicht hat wichtige Einblicke in Phänomene wie emotionalen Ausdruck und Selbstdarstellung geliefert. Neben der Veröffentlichung von Beiträgen ermöglichen Social-Media-Plattformen wie Twitter es Nutzern jedoch, eine kurze Biografie bereitzustellen, die eine Möglichkeit ist, ihr Konto als Ganzes kurz zu beschreiben. In dieser Arbeit konzentrieren wir uns auf die Verwendung von Emoji in diesen Bio-Aussagen. Wir erforschen, wie Nutzer Emoji in diese Selbstbeschreibungen einbeziehen und finden dabei andere Muster als jene, die bei der Emoji-Nutzung in Tweets beobachtet werden. Wir untersuchen die Zusammenhänge zwischen Emoji, die in Bios verwendet werden, und dem Inhalt der Tweets der Nutzer und zeigen, dass die Themen und sogar die durchschnittliche Stimmung von Tweets für Benutzer mit unterschiedlichen Emoji in ihrem Bios variieren. Schließlich bestätigen wir, dass homophile Effekte in Bezug auf die Arten von Emoji existieren, die in den Bios der Benutzer und ihrer Follower enthalten sind.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Emoji sering digunakan untuk mengekspresikan emosi dan konsep di media sosial, dan pekerjaan sebelumnya menunjukkan bahwa pilihan emoji pengguna merefleksikan cara mereka ingin memperkenalkan diri kepada dunia. Penggunaan Emoji biasanya dipelajari dalam konteks pos yang dibuat oleh pengguna, dan pandangan ini telah memberikan pandangan penting pada fenomena seperti ekspresi emosional dan represensi diri. Selain membuat pos, bagaimanapun, platform media sosial seperti Twitter memungkinkan pengguna untuk menyediakan bio pendek, yang merupakan kesempatan untuk menjelaskan secara singkat rekening mereka sebagai keseluruhan. Dalam pekerjaan ini, kita fokus pada penggunaan emoji dalam pernyataan bio ini. Kami mengeksplorasi cara dimana pengguna memasukkan emoji dalam deskripsi-diri ini, menemukan pola yang berbeda dari pola yang dilihat di sekitar penggunaan emoji dalam tweet. Kami memeriksa hubungan antara emoji yang digunakan dalam bio dan isi tweet pengguna, menunjukkan bahwa topik dan bahkan sentimen rata-rata tweet berbeda bagi pengguna dengan emoji yang berbeda dalam bio mereka. Akhirnya, kita mengkonfirmasi bahwa efek homofili ada mengenai jenis emoji yang termasuk dalam bio pengguna dan pengikut mereka.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>이모티콘은 소셜미디어에서 감정과 개념을 표현하는 데 널리 사용되고 있다. 이전의 연구에 따르면 사용자들이 이모티콘에 대한 선택은 그들이 세계에 자신의 방식을 보여주고 싶어 하는 것을 반영했다.이모티콘의 사용은 일반적으로 사용자가 글을 올린 배경에서 연구한 것으로 이 관점은 감정 표현과 자기 표징 등 현상에 중요한 견해를 제공했다.그러나 글을 올리는 것 외에 트위터 등 소셜미디어 플랫폼에서는 사용자가 자신의 계정 전체를 간략하게 설명할 수 있는 간단한 이력서를 제공할 수 있다.이 작업에서, 우리는 이 생물 진술에서 이모티콘의 사용에 주목한다.우리는 사용자가 이러한 자기묘사에서 이모티콘을 사용하는 방식을 탐색하고 추문에서 관찰한 이모티콘과 다른 모델을 사용하는 것을 발견했다.우리는bios에서 사용하는 이모티콘과 사용자의 추문 내용 간의 관계를 연구한 결과bios에서 서로 다른 이모티콘을 사용하는 사용자에 대해 추문의 주제, 심지어 평균 정서가 다르다는 것을 알 수 있다.마지막으로 사용자와 그 추종자의bios에 포함된 이모티콘 유형에 대해 동질효과가 있음을 확인했습니다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>اموژی به وسیله برای تعریف احساسات و مفهوم در رسانه‌های اجتماعی استفاده می‌شود، و کارهای قبل نشان داده است که انتخاب اموژی کاربران راهی را که می‌خواهند به دنیا نشان دهند. استفاده از ایموزی معمولاً در محیط پوست‌های کاربر ساخته شده مطالعه می‌شود، و این دید، مشاهده‌های مهم را به عنوان اتفاقات احساساتی و نمایش خودش داده است. البته به علاوه بر ساختن پست‌ها، Platform‌های رسانه‌های اجتماعی مانند توئیتر اجازه می‌دهند که کاربران یک بیولوژی کوتاه را تهیه کنند، که فرصتی است که به کوتاه حساب‌هایشان را در کل توصیف کند. در این کار، ما روی استفاده از ایموجی در این گزارش های بیولوژی تمرکز می کنیم. ما روش‌هایی که استفاده‌ها در این توضیح‌های خودش شامل emoji هستند را تحقیق می‌کنیم، که الگوهای متفاوتی از آن‌ها که اطراف استفاده از emoji در تویت‌ها مشاهده شده‌اند پیدا می‌کنیم. ما رابطه‌های بین ایموجی که در بیوژی و محتوای توئیت کاربر استفاده می‌شود را تحقیق می‌کنیم، نشان می‌دهیم که موضوع و حتی احساس متوسط توئیت برای کاربران با ایموجی متفاوت در بیوژی‌هایشان تفاوت می‌کنند. بالاخره، ما تایید می کنیم که اثرات همجنسفی در مورد نوع ایموجی وجود دارد که در بیولوژی کاربران و پیروانشان شامل شده اند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Emoji anatumiwa sana kuonyesha hisia na mawazo kwenye mitandao ya kijamii, na kazi ya kabla imeonyesha kuwa uchaguzi wa watumiaji wa emoji unaonyesha jinsi wanavyotaka kujiwekea duniani. Utumiaji wa Emoji kwa kawaida unasomwa katika muktadha wa makala zilizotengenezwa na watumiaji, na mtazamo huu umetoa mitazamo muhimu katika hali kama vile hisia na kujikiliza. Zaidi ya kutengeneza makala, hata hivyo, majukwaa ya mitandao ya kijamii kama Twita yanaruhusu watumiaji kutoa bio fupi, ambayo ni fursa ya kuelezea akaunti yao kama ujumla. Katika kazi hii, tunalenga kutumia emoji katika matamko haya ya bio. Tunapunguza njia ambazo watumiaji wanajumuisha emoji katika maelezo haya wenyewe, kwa kutafuta mitindo tofauti kuliko zile zilizotazama kuhusu matumizi ya emoji katika twita. Tunatachunguza uhusiano kati ya emoji uliotumika katika bio na maudhui ya twiti za watumiaji, tukionesha kuwa mada na hata hisia za wastani wa twita zinatofauti kwa watumiaji wenye emoji tofauti katika bio zao. Mwisho, tunathibitisha kuwa madhara ya ushoga yanakuwepo kwa kuheshimu aina ya emoji ambayo inajumuisha kwenye bio za watumiaji na wafuatiliaji wao.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Emoji word heeltemal gebruik om emosies en konsepte op sosiale media te uitdruk, en voorheen werk het vertoon dat gebruikers se keuse van emoji reflekteer die manier wat hulle wil hê om hulleself aan die wêreld te voorsien. Emoji gebruik is tipik in die konteks van pos wat deur gebruikers gemaak is, ondersoek, en hierdie aansig het belangrike inligtings verskaf in fenomene soos emosiele uitdrukking en self-verteenwoording. In addition to making posts, however, social media platforms like Twitter allow for users to provide a short bio, which is an opportunity to briefly describe their account as a whole. In hierdie werk, ons fokus op die gebruik van emoji in hierdie bioverklaring. Ons ondersoek die maniere waarmee gebruikers emoji in hierdie self-beskrywings insluit, vind verskillende patrone as die wat rondom emoji gebruik in tweets aangesien is. Ons ondersoek die verwantings tussen emoji wat in bios gebruik word en die inhoud van gebruikers se tweets, wat vertoon dat die onderwerpe en selfs die gemiddelde sentiment van tweets verander vir gebruikers met verskillende emoji in hulle bios. Las, ons bevestig dat homofiële effekte bestaan met respek na die tipes emoji wat in bios van gebruikers en hulle volgenders ingesluit word.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Emojiler sosial medýädäki duýgular we düşünjeleri görkezmek üçin köplenç ulanýarlar, we öňki işiň emojileriň saýlamaklarynyň dünýäde özlerini görkezmek isleýän ýolyny düşündirýärler. Emoji ulanmalary adatça ullanýar ullanyşylar tarapyndan ýazylan poýatlaryň kontekstinde, we bu görüntü duýumsal ifade we özüni represije ýaly möhüm paýatlara üýtgedýär. Ýöne, Twitter ýaly sosyal medialar platformalary üýtgetmek üçin gysga bir biologiýa saýlamak üçin rugsat berýär. Bu ýerde esaplaryny gysga bir şekilde tanyşdyrmak mümkinçiligidir. Bu işde emoji ulanmaklaryna üns berýäris. Ullançylaryň bu özi tassymlarda emoji ýaly nusgalary tapylyp, emoji ýanyň töwereklerinde üýtgeýän nusgalaryndan farklı nusgalary tapylýarys. Biz emoji bilen ulanylan tweets içerisindeki baglaýyşlaryň we olaryň tweets içerisindeki baglaýyşlaryň barlygyny barlaýarys. Meýdanlaryň we hatda tweets içerisindeki ortalama duýgularyň hem olaryň biologiýasynda farklı emoji bilen üýtgeýändigini görkez. Iň soňunda, ullançylaryň we dalgalaryň biologiýasynda dahil edilen emoji türleri barada homofiýaly täsirler bar diýip tassyklanýarys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>ኢሜጂ ማኅበራዊ ሚዲያ ላይ አዳማዊ እና አሳቤዎችን ለመናገር በተስፋት ይደረጋል፤ አስቀድሞም ሥራ የኢሜጂ የተመረጠውን የኢሜጂ ምርጫ ወደ ዓለም ለመቆየት የሚወዱትን መንገድ ይመልሳል፡፡ ኢሜጂ በተጠቃሚ ተጠቃሚዎች በተደረገው ጽሑፎች ውስጥ በተማርከዋል፡፡ ምንም እንኳን የጦማሪያው ማኅበራዊ አውታር ሚዲያ መድረኮች እንደ ትዊተር ተጠቃሚዎች አካባቢ ቢዮ እንዲሰጥ ይፈቅዳሉ፤ ይህም አካባቢቸውን በሙሉ እንዲያሳያል ፈቃድ ነው፡፡ In this work, we focus on the use of emoji in these bio statements.  ኢሜጂን በተጠቃሚው ኢሜጂን በሚያሳድጉበት መንገዶች እናደርጋለን፡፡ የኢሜጂ እና የኢትዮጵያውያን ትዊት ውስጥ የሚጠቀሙትን ግንኙነት እናደርጋለን፡፡ በመጨረሻውም፣ በተጠቃሚዎች እና በሚከተሉት የኢሜጂ ዓይነቶች ላይ የተደረገ የሞፊ ፍሬ እንዲኖር እናረጋግጣለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Emoji përdoret gjerësisht për të shprehur emocione dhe koncepte në mediat shoqërore dhe puna e mëparshme ka treguar se zgjedhja e emoxhit e përdoruesve pasqyron mënyrën se si duan të paraqesin veten në botë. Përdorimi i Emoji zakonisht studiohet në kontekstin e postimeve të bërë nga përdoruesit dhe ky pikëpamje ka dhënë kuptime të rëndësishme në fenomene të tilla si shprehja emocionale dhe vetë-përfaqësimi. Përveç bërjes së postimeve, megjithatë, platformet e medias sociale si Twitter lejojnë përdoruesit të ofrojnë një bio të shkurtër, e cila është një mundësi për të përshkruar shkurtër llogarinë e tyre si të tërë. Në këtë punë, ne përqëndrohemi në përdorimin e emoxhit në këto deklarata biologjike. Ne eksplorojmë mënyrat në të cilat përdoruesit përfshijnë emoji në këto vetëpërshkrime, duke gjetur modele të ndryshme sesa ato të vëzhguara rreth përdorimit të emoji në tweet. Ne shqyrtojmë marrëdhëniet midis emoxhit të përdorur në biografi dhe përmbajtjen e tweeteve të përdoruesve, duke treguar se temat dhe madje ndjenja mesatare e tweeteve ndryshojnë për përdoruesit me emoxhi të ndryshme në biografitë e tyre. Më në fund, ne konfirmojmë se efektet homofilike ekzistojnë lidhur me llojet e emoxhit që janë përfshirë në biografitë e përdoruesve dhe pasuesve të tyre.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_hy>Էմոջան տարածաբար օգտագործվում է զգացմունքների և գաղափարների արտահայտությանը սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցների վրա, և նախորդ աշխատանքը ցույց է տալիս, որ օգտագործողների ընտրությունը էմոջան արտացոլում է այն ձևը, թե ինչպես են նրանք ցանկանում ներկայ Էմոջայի օգտագործումը սովորաբար ուսումնասիրում է օգտագործողների ստեղծված աշխատանքների կոնտեքստում, և այս տեսանկյունից կարևոր ընկալումներ են տրամադրվել այնպիսի երևույթների, ինչպիսիք են զգայական արտահայտությունը և ինքնաներկայ Բացի տեղադրություններից, այնուամենայնիվ, Թվիթերի նման սոցիալական լրատվամիջոցները թույլ են տալիս օգտագործողներին կարճ կենսաբանություն տրամադրել, որը հնարավորություն է կարճ ներկայացնել իրենց հաշիվը որպես ամբողջ: Այս աշխատանքում մենք կենտրոնանում ենք էմոջի օգտագործման վրա այս կենսաբանական հայտարարություններում: Մենք ուսումնասիրում ենք, թե ինչպես են օգտագործողները ներառում էմոջիները այս ինքնանկարագրությունների մեջ, որոնք տարբեր կաղապարներ են գտնում, քան այն կաղապարները, որոնք դիտարկվում են էմոջիների օգտագործման շուրջ թվիթերում: Մենք ուսումնասիրում ենք կենսաբանության մեջ օգտագործվող էմոջիների և օգտագործողների թվիթերի պարունակության հարաբերությունները, ցույց տալով, որ թեմաները և նույնիսկ թվիթերի միջին զգացմունքները տարբերվում են նրանց կենսաբանության մեջ տարբեր էմոջիների օգտագործողների համար: Վերջապես, մենք հաստատում ենք, որ հոմոֆիլիայի էֆեկտները գոյություն ունեն այն էմոֆիլիաների տեսակների նկատմամբ, որոնք ներառված են օգտագործողների և նրանց հետևողների կենսաբանության մեջ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Emoji sosyal medya üzərində emoji və fikirləri ifadə etmək üçün genişliyi istifadə edilir, və əvvəlki işdə istifadəçilərinin emoji seçimləri dünyaya göstərmək istədikləri kimi ifadə edir. Emoji istifadəsi istifadəçilər tarafından yapılmış məlumatların məlumatlarında təhsil edilir, və bu görünüş emosiyal ifadə və özünü göstərmək kimi möhkəm fikirləri göstərdi. Lakin, Twitter kimi sosyal media platformları yaratmaq üçün istifadəçilərin qısa bir bioloji təyin etməsinə imkan verir. Bu, onların hesabını tamamlamaq üçün qısa bir fırsatdır. Bu işdə, emoji istifadəsində bu biyoloji ifadələrində odaqlanırıq. Biz istifadəçilərin emoji ilə bu təfsirlərdə istifadəçilər barəsində keşf edirik, emoji istifadəçilərinin Twittlərdə gördüklərindən farklı modelləri tapıb keşf edirik. Biz emoji və istifadəçilərin twetlərin içərisində istifadə edilən məsələlərin arasındakı ilişkilerini incidirik, məsələlərin və hətta twetlərin ortalama hissləri öz biolarında müxtəlif emoji ilə istifadəçilər üçün dəyişiklikdir. Sonunda, istifadəçilərin və tabeçilərinin biologiyalarına daxil edilən emoji türləri haqqında homofiyli etkisi var olduğunu təsdiq edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Emoji se široko koriste za izražavanje emocija i koncepta na društvenim medijima, a prije posla pokazuje da izbor emoji korisnika odražava način na koji žele da se predstave svijetu. Korištenje emoji se obično proučava u kontekstu postova koje su napravljene korisnicima, a ovaj pogled je pružio važne uvide u fenomene poput emocionalnog izraza i samoozastupanja. Međutim, dodatno pravljenju postova, društvenih medijskih platformi poput Twitter omogućavaju korisnicima da pruže kratku biologiju, što je prilika kratko opisati svoj račun kao cjelokupan. U ovom poslu, fokusiramo se na upotrebu emoji u ovim bioizjavama. Istražujemo načine na koji korisnici uključuju emoji u tih samopopisivanja, pronalaženje različitih obrazaca od onih koji su posmatrali oko korištenja emoji u tweetima. Provjeravamo odnose između emoji koji se koristi u biologiji i sadržaj tweta korisnika, pokazujući da se teme i čak prosječan osjećaj tweta razlikuju za korisnike s različitim emojima u njihovim biologijama. Na kraju, potvrđujemo da homofijski efekti postoje u odnosu na vrste emoji koji su uključeni u biografije korisnika i njihovih sljedbenika.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Els emoji s'utilitzen ampliament per expressar emocions i conceptes als mitjans socials, i el treball anterior ha demostrat que l'elecció d'emoji dels usuaris reflecteix la manera en què volen presentar-se al món. L'ús d'Emoji és normalment estudiat en el context de les publicacions fetes pels usuaris, i aquesta visió ha proporcionat importants insights en fenomens com l'expressió emocional i l'autorepresentació. A més de fer posts, però, plataformes de mitjans socials com Twitter permeten als usuaris proporcionar una breu biografia, que és una oportunitat de descriure breument el seu compte en seu conjunt. En aquest treball ens centrem en l'ús d'emoji en aquestes declaracions biològiques. Explorem com els usuaris inclouen emoji en aquestes autodescripcions, trobant patrons diferents d'aquells observats al voltant de l'ús d'emoji en tweets. We examine the relationships between emoji used in bios and the content of users' tweets, showing that the topics and even the average sentiment of tweets varies for users with different emoji in their bios.  Finalment, confirmem que existeixen efectes homofilis en relació amb els tipus d'emoji que estan inclosos en bios dels usuaris i els seus seguidors.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bn>এমোজি সামাজিক প্রচার মাধ্যমে আবেগ এবং ধারণা প্রকাশ করার জন্য ব্যাপক ব্যবহার করা হয়েছে এবং এর আগে কাজ প্রদর্শন করেছে যে ব্যবহারকারীরা ইমোজির বেছে নিয়ে ইমোজি ব্যবহার সাধারণত ব্যবহার করা ব্যবহারকারীদের পোস্ট তৈরি করা পোস্টের প্রেক্ষাপটে পড়া হয় এবং এই দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি আবেগের প্রকাশ এবং নিজের প্রত In addition to making posts, however, social media platforms like Twitter allow for users to provide a short bio, which is an opportunity to briefly describe their account as a whole.  এই কাজে আমরা এই বায়োর বিবৃতিতে ইমোজির ব্যবহারের উপর মনোযোগ দিচ্ছি। আমরা যেভাবে ব্যবহারকারীরা ইমোজির মধ্যে রয়েছে সেগুলো নিজেদের বর্ণনায়, টুইটারে ইমোজি ব্যবহারের চারপাশে দেখা যাচ্ছে তাদ আমরা বায়োজিতে ব্যবহার করা এবং ব্যবহারকারীদের টুইটের বিষয়বস্তুর মধ্যে ইমোজির সম্পর্ক পরীক্ষা করি, যেখানে দেখা যাচ্ছে যে বিষয় এবং এমনকি তাদের বায়োজিতে ব শেষে, আমরা নিশ্চিত করি যে সমকামীতার প্রভাব রয়েছে ইমোজির ধরনের সম্মানের প্রতি যারা ব্যবহারকারী এবং তাদের অনুসারীদের বায়োজিত</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_cs>Emoji jsou široce používány k vyjádření emocí a konceptů na sociálních médiích a předchozí práce ukázaly, že volba emoji uživatelů odráží způsob, jakým se chtějí prezentovat světu. Použití emoji je obvykle studováno v kontextu příspěvků uživatelů, a tento pohled poskytl důležité pohledy na jevy, jako je emocionální vyjádření a sebeprezervace. Kromě příspěvků však platformy sociálních médií, jako je Twitter, umožňují uživatelům poskytnout krátkou biografii, což je příležitost stručně popsat svůj účet jako celek. V této práci se zaměřujeme na použití emoji v těchto bio prohlášeních. Prozkoumáme způsoby, jakými uživatelé zahrnují emoji do těchto sebepisů, a najdeme odlišné vzorce, než ty, které jsou pozorovány kolem používání emoji ve tweetech. Zkoumáme vztahy mezi emoji používanými v bios a obsahem tweetů uživatelů a ukazujeme, že témata a dokonce i průměrný sentiment tweetů se liší u uživatelů s různými emoji v bios. Nakonec potvrzujeme, že homofilní účinky existují s ohledem na typy emoji, které jsou zahrnuty v bios uživatelů a jejich následovníků.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Emojisid kasutatakse laialdaselt emotsioonide ja kontseptsioonide väljendamiseks sotsiaalmeedias ning varasemad tööd on näidanud, et kasutajate valik emojid peegeldab seda, kuidas nad soovivad end maailmale esitleda. Emojide kasutamist uuritakse tavaliselt kasutajate postituste kontekstis ning see vaade on andnud olulise ülevaate sellistest nähtustest nagu emotsionaalne väljendus ja eneseväljendus. Lisaks postituste tegemisele võimaldavad sotsiaalmeedia platvormid nagu Twitter kasutajatel esitada lühikese bioloogia, mis annab võimaluse kirjeldada lühidalt oma kontot tervikuna. Selles töös keskendume emojide kasutamisele nendes bio avaldustes. Uurime viise, kuidas kasutajad lisavad emojid nendesse enesekirjeldustesse, leides erinevaid mustreid kui need, mida täheldatakse emojide kasutamise kohta säutsides. Uurime seoseid bioses kasutatavate emojide ja kasutajate säutsude sisu vahel, näidates, et teemad ja isegi keskmine säutsude tunded erinevad erinevate emojidega kasutajate bioses. Lõpuks kinnitame, et homofiilia mõju on olemas seoses emojide tüüpidega, mis sisalduvad kasutajate ja nende järgijate bioses.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Emojia käytetään laajasti tunteiden ja käsitteiden ilmaisemiseen sosiaalisessa mediassa, ja aiemmat tutkimukset ovat osoittaneet, että käyttäjien valinta emojien kuvastaa tapaa, jolla he haluavat esitellä itsensä maailmalle. Emojien käyttöä tutkitaan tyypillisesti käyttäjien tekemien viestien kontekstissa, ja tämä näkemys on antanut tärkeitä oivalluksia ilmiöistä, kuten tunneilmaisusta ja itseedustuksesta. Viestien tekemisen lisäksi Twitterin kaltaiset sosiaalisen median alustat antavat käyttäjille mahdollisuuden esittää lyhyt biografia, joka on mahdollisuus kuvailla lyhyesti tiliään kokonaisuutena. Tässä työssä keskitytään emojien käyttöön näissä bio lauseissa. Tutkimme tapoja, joilla käyttäjät sisällyttävät emojit näihin itsekuvauksiin, löytäen erilaisia kuvioita kuin ne, joita havaitaan emojien käytöstä tweeteissä. Tutkimme biosissa käytettyjen emojien ja käyttäjien twiittien sisällön välisiä suhteita, osoittaen, että aiheet ja jopa twiittien keskimääräinen mielipide vaihtelevat käyttäjillä, joilla on eri emojit biossaan. Lopuksi vahvistamme, että homofiilisiä vaikutuksia on olemassa käyttäjien ja heidän seuraajiensa biosiin sisältyvien emojien suhteen.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>Emoji se pogosto uporabljajo za izražanje čustev in konceptov na družbenih omrežjih, predhodna dela pa je pokazala, da uporabnikova izbira emojijev odraža način, kako se želijo predstaviti svetu. Uporaba emojev se običajno proučuje v kontekstu objav uporabnikov in ta pogled je omogočil pomemben vpogled v pojave, kot sta čustveno izražanje in samoreprezentacija. Poleg objave pa platforme družbenih medijev, kot je Twitter, uporabnikom omogočajo, da zagotovijo kratek biografij, kar je priložnost, da na kratko opišejo svoj račun kot celoto. V tem delu se osredotočamo na uporabo emojijev v teh bio izjavah. Raziskujemo načine, na katere uporabniki vključujejo emojije v te samoopise, pri čemer najdemo različne vzorce, kot jih opazujemo pri uporabi emojijev v tweetih. Preučujemo odnose med emojiji uporabljenimi v biosih in vsebino uporabnikovih tweetov, pri čemer pokažemo, da se teme in celo povprečni občutek tweetov razlikujejo za uporabnike z različnimi emojiji v biosih. Na koncu potrjujemo, da homofilijski učinki obstajajo v zvezi z vrstami emojijev, ki so vključeni v bio uporabnikov in njihovih sledilcev.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Emoji ana yi amfani da yawa ga su bayyana hisia da mawaƙo a kan mitandaki masu jamii, kuma aiki na gabani ya nuna cewa zaɓaɓen masu amfani da amfani da mutane, za'a nuna hanyar da suke so zuwa ga duniya. Emoji usage is typically studied in the context of posts made by users, and this view has provided important insights into phenomena such as emotional expression and self-representation.  Ga ku sami makala, amma, platforms na mitandai da jamii kamar Twitter za'a yarda da mãsu amfani da su ga su bãyar da wani abu kaɗan, wannan na da fursa ya bayyana akansa kodi ɗaya. Ina cikin wannan aikin, tuna makini a kan amfani da foji a cikin waɗannan matangazo. Munã jarraba hanyõyi da mãsu amfani da shi ke haɗa foji cikin wannan misãlai na kangara, kuma munã sami wasu misãlai ko da aka taɓa wa amfani da foji a cikin Twitter. Ko jarraba mazaɓa tsakanin Emji da ke amfani da cikin birai da wanda ke cikin mawadãtan watumin masu amfani da, sunã nũna cẽwa madaidaita da kuma ko kuma haske saurin Twitter yana sãɓã wa masu amfani da mutane masu da mutane daban-dabam na'anar foji. Lallai, Munã gaskata cewa akwai mai amfani da musamman da wasu irin mutane na Emji waɗanda ke cikin zabiya masu amfani da mataimaka.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>האמוג'י משתמשים באופן רחב כדי להביע רגשות ומחשבות על התקשורת החברתית, ועבודה קודמת הראה שבחירת האמוג'י של המשתמשים משקפת את הדרך שבה הם רוצים להציג את עצמם לעולם. השימוש באמוג'י בדרך כלל לומד בקשר לתפקידים שנעשו ע"י משתמשים, והנוף הזה סיפק תובנות חשובות לתופעות כמו הביטוי רגשי והייצוג עצמי. בנוסף לייצור תפקידים, למרות זאת, פלטפורמות התקשורת החברתית כמו טוויטר מאפשרות למשתמשים לספק ביו קצר, וזה הזדמנות לתאר בקצר את חשבונם כולו. בעבודה הזאת, אנחנו מתמקדים בשימוש של אמוג'י בהצהרות ביולוגיות האלה. אנו חוקרים את הדרכים שבהן משתמשים מכילים אמוג'י בתיאורים עצמיים האלה, למצוא דפוסים שונים מאלה שמוצפים סביב השימוש של אמוג'י בטוויטים. אנו בודקים את מערכות היחסים בין האמוג'י שנמשכות ביולוגיות לתוכן הטוויטים של המשתמשים, מראים שהנושאים ואפילו הרגשה הממוצעת של הטוויטים שונות עבור המשתמשים עם האמוג'י שונים בביוגים שלהם. בסופו של דבר, אנו מאשרים שהתופעות הומופיליות קיימות בנוגע לסוגי האמוג'י שנכללים בביולוגיה של משתמשים ומעקביהם.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Emaji kang hal kudu ampuhi kanggo ngomongke luwih perasaane lan nggunakake neng media sotiki, lan uwis mesthi nang aréwé kuwi tindakan nggawe ngubah maun karo awak dhéwé mengkakan karo awak dhéwé nggawe ngubah awak dhéwé. Ngawe empati Emaji dipun digawe ing kontèks pawaran oleh nggambar aturan karo pawaran, lan nggarangé iki bakal nyimpen kuwi basa sing dikarepaké akèh seneng aparané karo pawaran omongaké lan kedaulatan sampeyan. Nanging tambah nggawe mripat, dadi, sistem media sotiki lagi Google dumadhi kanggo tutanan ping mbutuhak biyo, sing apik kanggo ngubah kapan kanggo ngubah kontu sak sabanjuré. Nang barêng-barêng iki, kéné iso disebarke ning epoje uwis nggambar obaraning biyo kuwi. Awak dhéwé éntukno ngerasai gambaran ning sampeyan empji nang pisan-sampeyan iki, nggawe nyimpen maneh sing kalah apik karo koyok nggambar ampuhi emuji nang tuwit. Awak dhéwé éntuk perusahaan karo emuji iki gambar lan nganggo kuwi nggawe bitutuhé, nik nggambar kuwi téma karo hal sampek éntuk dhéwé Laha luwih, awak dhéwé ngerasai bener pancene éntuk karo nganggo sistem omoji sing katêpakan karo bijo pengguna-pengguna lan barang pancen.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་གནས་ཚུལ་དང་། སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་དྲ་ཐོག་ཏུ་སྒེར་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་སྟོན་ན་ཡོད། སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་ལག་ལེན་འཐབ་པ་དེ་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་གནས་སྟངས་ལ་ཕན་ཞིབ་འཇུག་ཡོད། ཡིན་ནའང་། སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་མཁན་གྱི་གླེང་སྟེགས་འདི་ལག་ལེན་པ་ཚོས་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་འཛམ་གླིང་གསར་པ་ཞིག་དང་། ལས་ཀ་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོས་རང་བཞིན་པའི་སྐོར་བརྗོད་འདི་ནང་གི་emoji སྤྱད་ནས་བློ་གཏོང་ཐུབ། ང་ཚོས་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་རང་འགུལ་གསལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་emoji་དག་གི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་འཚོལ་ཞིབ་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་འཛམ་གླིང་དང་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་དྲ་ཐོག་གི་ནང་དུ་སྤྱོད་པའི་emoji་དང་བརྗོད་ཀྱི་འབྲེལ་བ་གཉིས་ཀྱི་འབྲེལ་བ་དག་ལ་བརྟག མཐའ་མར་མ་དེ། འུ་ཅག་གིས་སྤྱོད་མཁན་ཉེན་བྱ་ཚིག་དང་ཁོང་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་ཡོད་པའི་emoji རིགས་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་ཡོད་པ་ནི་</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>