<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.inlg">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-11-29">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Natural Language Generation</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Brian</first><last>Davis</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yvette</first><last>Graham</last></editor>
      <editor><first>John</first><last>Kelleher</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yaji</first><last>Sripada</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Dublin, Ireland</address>
      <month>December</month>
      <year>2020</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="c03367d5">2020.inlg-1.0</url>
      <revision id="1" href="2020.inlg-1.0v1" hash="0cd95e3d" />
      <revision id="2" href="2020.inlg-1.0v2" hash="c03367d5" date="2021-04-26">Added missing sponsor and made changes to the organizational committee.</revision>
      <bibkey>inlg-2020-international</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="8">
      <title>Assessing Discourse Relations in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_generation">Language Generation</a> from GPT-2<fixed-case>GPT</fixed-case>-2</title>
      <author><first>Wei-Jen</first><last>Ko</last></author>
      <author><first>Junyi Jessy</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <pages>52–59</pages>
      <abstract>Recent advances in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> have been attributed to the emergence of large-scale pre-trained language models. GPT-2, in particular, is suited for generation tasks given its left-to-right language modeling objective, yet the linguistic quality of its generated text has largely remain unexplored. Our work takes a step in understanding GPT-2’s outputs in terms of discourse coherence. We perform a comprehensive study on the validity of explicit discourse relations in GPT-2’s outputs under both organic generation and fine-tuned scenarios. Results show GPT-2 does not always generate text containing valid discourse relations ; nevertheless, its text is more aligned with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expectation_(epistemic)">human expectation</a> in the fine-tuned scenario. We propose a decoupled strategy to mitigate these problems and highlight the importance of explicitly modeling discourse information.</abstract>
      <url hash="de60e57f">2020.inlg-1.8</url>
      <bibkey>ko-li-2020-assessing</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>The CACAPO Dataset : A Multilingual, Multi-Domain Dataset for Neural Pipeline and End-to-End Data-to-Text Generation<fixed-case>CACAPO</fixed-case> Dataset: A Multilingual, Multi-Domain Dataset for Neural Pipeline and End-to-End Data-to-Text Generation</title>
      <author><first>Chris</first><last>van der Lee</last></author>
      <author><first>Chris</first><last>Emmery</last></author>
      <author><first>Sander</first><last>Wubben</last></author>
      <author><first>Emiel</first><last>Krahmer</last></author>
      <pages>68–79</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the CACAPO dataset, built for training both neural pipeline and end-to-end data-to-text language generation systems. The dataset is multilingual (Dutch and English), and contains almost 10,000 sentences from human-written news texts in the sports, weather, stocks, and incidents domain, together with aligned attribute-value paired data. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> is unique in that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variation_(linguistics)">linguistic variation</a> and indirect ways of expressing data in these texts reflect the challenges of real world NLG tasks.</abstract>
      <url hash="6218b1e2">2020.inlg-1.10</url>
      <attachment type="Supplementary_Attachment" hash="e55d25a7">2020.inlg-1.10.Supplementary_Attachment.pdf</attachment>
      <bibkey>van-der-lee-etal-2020-cacapo</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/rotowire">RotoWire</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/webnlg">WebNLG</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>DaMata : A Robot-Journalist Covering the Brazilian Amazon Deforestation<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>a<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>ata: A Robot-Journalist Covering the <fixed-case>B</fixed-case>razilian <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>mazon Deforestation</title>
      <author><first>André Luiz</first><last>Rosa Teixeira</last></author>
      <author><first>João</first><last>Campos</last></author>
      <author><first>Rossana</first><last>Cunha</last></author>
      <author><first>Thiago</first><last>Castro Ferreira</last></author>
      <author><first>Adriana</first><last>Pagano</last></author>
      <author><first>Fabio</first><last>Cozman</last></author>
      <pages>103–106</pages>
      <abstract>This demo paper introduces DaMata, a robot-journalist covering <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deforestation">deforestation</a> in the Brazilian Amazon. The robot-journalist is based on a pipeline architecture of Natural Language Generation, which yields multilingual daily and monthly reports based on the public data provided by DETER, a real-time deforestation satellite monitor developed and maintained by the Brazilian National Institute for Space Research (INPE). DaMata automatically generates reports in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brazilian_Portuguese">Brazilian Portuguese</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> and publishes them on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter">Twitter platform</a>. Corpus and code are publicly available.</abstract>
      <url hash="2aee9bfe">2020.inlg-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>rosa-teixeira-etal-2020-damata</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/botsdobem/demo_inpe_covid" additional="false">botsdobem/demo_inpe_covid</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>PARENTing via Model-Agnostic Reinforcement Learning to Correct Pathological Behaviors in Data-to-Text Generation<fixed-case>PARENT</fixed-case>ing via Model-Agnostic Reinforcement Learning to Correct Pathological Behaviors in Data-to-Text Generation</title>
      <author><first>Clement</first><last>Rebuffel</last></author>
      <author><first>Laure</first><last>Soulier</last></author>
      <author><first>Geoffrey</first><last>Scoutheeten</last></author>
      <author><first>Patrick</first><last>Gallinari</last></author>
      <pages>120–130</pages>
      <abstract>In language generation models conditioned by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structured_data">structured data</a>, the classical training via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maximum_likelihood_estimation">maximum likelihood</a> almost always leads models to pick up on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Divergence_(statistics)">dataset divergence</a> (i.e., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallucination">hallucinations</a> or omissions), and to incorporate them erroneously in their own generations at inference. In this work, we build on top of previous Reinforcement Learning based approaches and show that a model-agnostic framework relying on the recently introduced PARENT metric is efficient at reducing both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallucination">hallucinations</a> and omissions. Evaluations on the widely used WikiBIO and WebNLG benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_framework">framework</a> compared to state-of-the-art models.</abstract>
      <url hash="5dfd3607">2020.inlg-1.18</url>
      <bibkey>rebuffel-etal-2020-parenting</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/KaijuML/PARENTing-rl" additional="false">KaijuML/PARENTing-rl</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wikibio">WikiBio</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Chart-to-Text : Generating Natural Language Descriptions for Charts by Adapting the Transformer Model</title>
      <author><first>Jason</first><last>Obeid</last></author>
      <author><first>Enamul</first><last>Hoque</last></author>
      <pages>138–147</pages>
      <abstract>Information visualizations such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bar_chart">bar charts</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line_chart">line charts</a> are very popular for exploring data and communicating insights. Interpreting and making sense of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visualization_(graphics)">visualizations</a> can be challenging for some people, such as those who are visually impaired or have low visualization literacy. In this work, we introduce a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> and present a neural model for automatically generating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-language_understanding">natural language summaries</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chart">charts</a>. The generated summaries provide an interpretation of the chart and convey the key insights found within that chart. Our neural model is developed by extending the state-of-the-art <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> for the data-to-text generation task, which utilizes a transformer-based encoder-decoder architecture. We found that our approach outperforms the base model on a content selection metric by a wide margin (55.42 % vs. 8.49 %) and generates more informative, concise, and coherent summaries.</abstract>
      <url hash="b06fec26">2020.inlg-1.20</url>
      <bibkey>obeid-hoque-2020-chart</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/JasonObeid/Chart2Text" additional="false">JasonObeid/Chart2Text</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/chart2text">Chart2Text</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>رسم بياني إلى نص: إنشاء أوصاف لغة طبيعية للمخططات عن طريق تكييف نموذج المحولات</title_ar>
      <title_es>Gráfico a texto: Generación de descripciones en lenguaje natural para gráficos mediante la adaptación del modelo Transformer</title_es>
      <title_pt>Chart-to-Text: Gerando Descrições de Linguagem Natural para Gráficos Adaptando o Modelo Transformer</title_pt>
      <title_ja>グラフからテキストへ：トランスフォーマーモデルを適応させることにより、グラフの自然言語説明を生成する</title_ja>
      <title_zh>图表至文本:因转换器模形为图自然语言</title_zh>
      <title_hi>चार्ट-टू-टेक्स्ट: ट्रांसफॉर्मर मॉडल को अनुकूलित करके चार्ट के लिए प्राकृतिक भाषा विवरण जनरेट करना</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Cairt go Téacs: Cur síos ar Theanga Nádúrtha a Ghiniúint do Chairteacha tríd an Múnla Trasfhoirmeora a Oiriúnú</title_ga>
      <title_el>Γράφημα-σε-κείμενο: Δημιουργία περιγραφών φυσικής γλώσσας για γραφήματα με προσαρμογή του μοντέλου μετασχηματιστή</title_el>
      <title_hu>Diagramról szövegre: Természetes nyelvleírások generálása diagramokhoz a transzformátor modelljének adaptálásával</title_hu>
      <title_ka>ტექსტის დირაფიკატის შესახებ: დირაფიკატის ნაირადი ენის აღწერების შექმნა</title_ka>
      <title_it>Grafico a testo: generazione di descrizioni del linguaggio naturale per i grafici adattando il modello del trasformatore</title_it>
      <title_kk>Диаграмма- мен мәтін: Диаграммалардың табиғи тілдерді түрлендіру үлгісін өзгерту</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Ženklas į tekstą: Gamtinės kalbos apibūdinimų kūrimas Ženklams pritaikant transformatoriaus modelį</title_lt>
      <title_mk>График во текст: Генерирање на описи на природен јазик за графики со адаптирање на моделот на трансформирање</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Huraian-ke-Teks: Menjana Huraian Bahasa Biasa untuk Huraian dengan menyesuaikan Model Penukar</title_ms>
      <title_ml>KChart- to- Text: Transformer Model Adapting</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Iċ-Ċart għat-Test: Il-Ġenerazzjoni ta’ Deskrizzjonijiet tal-Lingwa Naturali għall-Ċerti bl-Adattament tal-Mudell tat-Trasferiment</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Диаграмм-ээс-текст: Диаграмтын байгалийн хэл тайлбарлалт бүтээж Төрвөлдөгч Загварын загварыг загварчлан</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Wykres-do-tekst: generowanie opisów języka naturalnego dla wykresów poprzez dostosowanie modelu transformatora</title_pl>
      <title_no>Grafikk til tekst: Lagar naturspråkkskildringar for grafikk ved å tilpassa transformeringsmodellen</title_no>
      <title_ro>Diagramă în text: generarea descrierilor limbajului natural pentru diagrame prin adaptarea modelului transformatorului</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Chart- to- text: Generiranje prirodnih jezika opisa za grafike prilagođenjem modela transformera</title_sr>
      <title_sv>Diagram till text: Generera beskrivningar av naturligt språk för diagram genom att anpassa transformatormodellen</title_sv>
      <title_so>Chart-to-text: Generating Descriptions of Language Nature for Characters by Adapting the Model Transfer</title_so>
      <title_si>චාර්ට් වෙනුවෙන් පාළුව: ස්වභාවික භාෂාව විස්තර කරන්නේ චාර්ට් වලින් විස්තර</title_si>
      <title_ta>வரைபடத்திலிருந்து உரை: மாற்றும் மாதிரியை ஏற்றுமதி செய்து இயல்பான மொழி வரைவடிவமைப்புகளை உருவாக்குகிறது</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Chart- to- text: Natural Language Descriptions for Charts by Adapting the Transformer Model</title_ur>
      <title_uz>KChart- to- matn: Transfer Model</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Bản đồ Văn bản: Tạo ra các mô tả ngôn ngữ tự nhiên cho các bản đồ bằng cách sửa đổi mô hình biến hình</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Диаграма в текст: генериране на естествени езикови описания за диаграми чрез адаптиране на модела на трансформатора</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Grafiek-naar-tekst: Het genereren van beschrijvingen in natuurlijke taal voor grafieken door het transformatormodel aan te passen</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Grafik do teksta: Generiranje prirodnog jezika opisa za grafike prilagođenjem modela transformacije</title_hr>
      <title_da>Diagram til tekst: Generere beskrivelser af naturligt sprog for diagrammer ved at tilpasse transformatormodellen</title_da>
      <title_id>Chart-to-Text: Menjana Deskripsi Bahasa Alami untuk Chart dengan menyesuaikan Model Transformer</title_id>
      <title_de>Diagramm-zu-Text: Generieren natürlicher Sprachbeschreibungen für Diagramme durch Anpassung des Transformatormodells</title_de>
      <title_ko>그래프에서 텍스트로: Transformer 모델을 조정하여 그래프에 자연 언어 설명을 생성합니다</title_ko>
      <title_fa>نمودار به متن: توصیف زبان طبیعی برای نمودارها با تغییر مدل تغییردهنده</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Resim we Metin Saýlaw</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Mjumbe-hadi-maandishi: Kutengeneza maelezo ya lugha ya asili kwa ajili ya ramani kwa Kupitisha Modeli ya Tafsiri</title_sw>
      <title_sq>Chart-to-Text: Generating Natural Language Descriptions for Charts by Adapting the Transformer Model</title_sq>
      <title_af>Kaart- na- Teks: Genereer Natuurlike Taal Beskrywings vir Kaart deur aanpassing van die Transformer Model</title_af>
      <title_hy>Տեքստի քարտեզ: Գեներացնում է բնական լեզվի նկարագրություններ քարտեզների համար՝ հարմարեցնելով փոխակերպող մոդելը</title_hy>
      <title_bn>চিত্র- থেকে টেক্সট: ট্রান্সফ্রান্সফার্নার মোডেল পাঠানোর মাধ্যমে প্রাকৃতিক ভাষা বিবরণ তৈরি করা হচ্ছ</title_bn>
      <title_am>የፊደል ቅርጽ ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_bs>Grafik na tekst: Generiranje prirodnog jezika opisa za grafike prilagođenjem modela transformacije</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Gràfic a text: generar descripcions de llenguatge natural per a gràfics adaptant el model de transformador</title_ca>
      <title_az>Chart-to-Text: Diagramlar 칲칞칲n t톛bi톛tli dil T톛rc칲ml톛yici Modelini Adland캼ran</title_az>
      <title_cs>Graf-to-Text: Generování popisů přirozeného jazyka pro grafy přizpůsobením modelu transformátoru</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Kaavio tekstiksi: Luonnollisten kielikuvausten luominen kaavioille muuntajamallin mukauttamisella</title_fi>
      <title_et>Diagramm tekstiks: diagrammide loomulike keelekirjelduste genereerimine teisendusmudeli kohandamise abil</title_et>
      <title_he>גרט לטקסט: יצירת תיאור שפת טבעית עבור גרטים על ידי שינוי מודל המעבר</title_he>
      <title_jv>structural navigation</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Grafikon v besedilo: Ustvarjanje opisov naravnega jezika za grafikone s prilagajanjem modela transformatorja</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Chart-to-Text: Generating Natural Language Descriptions for Charts by Adapting the Transformer Model</title_bo>
      <title_ha>KChart- to- Text: Creating KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <abstract_ar>تحظى تصورات المعلومات مثل المخططات الشريطية والمخططات الخطية بشعبية كبيرة لاستكشاف البيانات وتوصيل الرؤى. قد يكون تفسير مثل هذه التصورات وفهمها أمرًا صعبًا بالنسبة لبعض الأشخاص ، مثل أولئك الذين يعانون من إعاقة بصرية أو لديهم معرفة القراءة والكتابة المرئية منخفضة. في هذا العمل ، نقدم مجموعة بيانات جديدة ونقدم نموذجًا عصبيًا لإنشاء ملخصات لغة طبيعية للمخططات تلقائيًا. توفر الملخصات التي تم إنشاؤها تفسيرًا للمخطط وتنقل الأفكار الرئيسية الموجودة في هذا المخطط. تم تطوير نموذجنا العصبي من خلال توسيع النموذج الحديث لمهمة إنشاء البيانات إلى النص ، والتي تستخدم بنية مفكك تشفير تعتمد على المحولات. وجدنا أن نهجنا يتفوق في الأداء على النموذج الأساسي على مقياس اختيار المحتوى بهامش عريض (55.42٪ مقابل 8.49٪) ويولد ملخصات أكثر إفادة وموجزة ومتماسكة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Las visualizaciones de información, como los gráficos de barras y los gráficos de líneas, son muy populares para explorar datos y comunicar información valiosa. Interpretar y dar sentido a estas visualizaciones puede ser un desafío para algunas personas, como las que tienen una discapacidad visual o tienen un bajo nivel de alfabetización visual. En este trabajo, presentamos un nuevo conjunto de datos y presentamos un modelo neuronal para generar automáticamente resúmenes en lenguaje natural para gráficos. Los resúmenes generados proporcionan una interpretación del gráfico y transmiten las ideas clave que se encuentran en ese gráfico. Nuestro modelo neuronal se desarrolla ampliando el modelo de vanguardia para la tarea de generación de datos a texto, que utiliza una arquitectura de codificador-decodificador basada en transformadores. Descubrimos que nuestro enfoque supera al modelo base en una métrica de selección de contenido por un amplio margen (55,42% frente al 8,49%) y genera resúmenes más informativos, concisos y coherentes.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>As visualizações de informações, como gráficos de barras e gráficos de linhas, são muito populares para explorar dados e comunicar insights. Interpretar e dar sentido a tais visualizações pode ser um desafio para algumas pessoas, como aquelas com deficiência visual ou com baixa alfabetização em visualização. Neste trabalho, apresentamos um novo conjunto de dados e apresentamos um modelo neural para gerar automaticamente resumos em linguagem natural para gráficos. Os resumos gerados fornecem uma interpretação do gráfico e transmitem os principais insights encontrados nesse gráfico. Nosso modelo neural é desenvolvido estendendo o modelo de última geração para a tarefa de geração de dados para texto, que utiliza uma arquitetura de codificador-decodificador baseada em transformador. Descobrimos que nossa abordagem supera o modelo básico em uma métrica de seleção de conteúdo por uma ampla margem (55,42% vs. 8,49%) e gera resumos mais informativos, concisos e coerentes.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>棒グラフや折れ線グラフなどの情報可視化は、データの探索や洞察の伝達に非常に人気があります。そのような視覚化の解釈と理解は、視覚障害者や視覚化リテラシーが低い人々など、一部の人々にとって困難な場合があります。この研究では、新しいデータセットを紹介し、グラフの自然言語サマリーを自動生成するためのニューラルモデルを提示します。生成された要約は、チャートの解釈を提供し、そのチャート内で見つかった主要な洞察を伝えます。当社のニューラルモデルは、変圧器ベースのエンコーダデコーダアーキテクチャを利用したデータツーテキスト生成タスクの最先端モデルを拡張することで開発されています。当社のアプローチは、コンテンツ選択指標のベースモデルを大幅に上回り（ 55.42 ％対8.49 ％ ）、より情報量が多く、簡潔で一貫性のある要約を生成することがわかりました。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>条形图与折线图等信息可视化探索传见甚受欢迎。 其于人也,解释之类可视化或有挑战性,视损可视化养下者也。 引入一新数集,立一神经模形,以成图自然语言摘要。 生成之摘要,资图表之说,传其要会。 吾神经者,所以广数而先事者也,因转换器之编码器 - 解码器架构也。 吾见其法指标大于本(55.42%于8.49%),而信息益丰,简洁连贯之摘要。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>बार चार्ट और लाइन चार्ट जैसे सूचना विज़ुअलाइज़ेशन डेटा की खोज और अंतर्दृष्टि संचार करने के लिए बहुत लोकप्रिय हैं। इस तरह के विज़ुअलाइज़ेशन की व्याख्या करना और समझना कुछ लोगों के लिए चुनौतीपूर्ण हो सकता है, जैसे कि वे जो नेत्रहीन हैं या कम विज़ुअलाइज़ेशन साक्षरता रखते हैं। इस काम में, हम एक नया डेटासेट पेश करते हैं और चार्ट के लिए प्राकृतिक भाषा सारांश स्वचालित रूप से उत्पन्न करने के लिए एक तंत्रिका मॉडल पेश करते हैं। जेनरेट किए गए सारांश चार्ट की एक व्याख्या प्रदान करते हैं और उस चार्ट के भीतर पाए जाने वाले प्रमुख अंतर्दृष्टि को व्यक्त करते हैं। हमारा तंत्रिका मॉडल डेटा-टू-टेक्स्ट जनरेशन कार्य के लिए अत्याधुनिक मॉडल का विस्तार करके विकसित किया गया है, जो एक ट्रांसफॉर्मर-आधारित एन्कोडर-डिकोडर आर्किटेक्चर का उपयोग करता है। हमने पाया कि हमारा दृष्टिकोण एक व्यापक मार्जिन (55.42% बनाम 8.49%) द्वारा सामग्री चयन मीट्रिक पर आधार मॉडल को मात देता है और अधिक जानकारीपूर्ण, संक्षिप्त और सुसंगत सारांश उत्पन्न करता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Bíonn an-tóir ar léirshamhlú faisnéise ar nós barrachairteacha agus línechairteacha chun sonraí a iniúchadh agus chun léargais a chur in iúl. D’fhéadfadh sé a bheith dúshlánach do roinnt daoine léirmhíniú agus ciall a bhaint as léirshamhlú den sórt sin, mar iad siúd a bhfuil lagú amhairc orthu nó a bhfuil litearthacht íseal amharcléirithe acu. San obair seo, tugaimid tacar sonraí nua isteach agus cuirimid i láthair samhail néarúil chun achoimrí teanga nádúrtha a ghiniúint go huathoibríoch do na cairteacha. Soláthraíonn na hachoimrí ginte léirmhíniú ar an gcairt agus cuireann siad in iúl na príomhléargais a fhaightear sa chairt sin. Forbraítear ár múnla néarúil tríd an tsamhail úrscothach a leathnú don tasc giniúna sonraí-go-téacs, a úsáideann ailtireacht ionchódóra-díchódóra atá bunaithe ar chlaochladán. Fuaireamar amach go sáraíonn ár gcur chuige an bonn-mhúnla ar mhéadracht roghnú ábhair le corrlach leathan (55.42% vs. 8.49%) agus gineann sé achoimrí níos faisnéiseach, gonta agus níos soiléire.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ინფორმაციის ვიზუალიზაციები, როგორც ბარის ფარატი და ხაზის ფარატი, ძალიან პოლუბურია მონაცემების და კომუნიკაციის შესახებისთვის. ასეთი ვიზუალიზაციების შესაძლებლობა შეიძლება იყოს გასაკეთებელი ადამიანებისთვის, როგორც ვიზუალიზაციურად დააკეთებული ადამიანებისთვის, ან ცოტა ვიზუალიზაციის სიტ ამ სამუშაოში, ჩვენ ახალი მონაცემების კონფიგურაციას ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენ ჩვენებთ და ჩვენ ჩვენებთ ნეიროლური მოდელს ჩვენ ჩვენებთ ჩვენ შექმნილი საზოგადოებები ჩატვირთვას ჩატვირთვას ჩატვირთვას და ჩატვირთვას ჩატვირთვა ჩატვირთვა ამ შატში. ჩვენი ნეიროლური მოდელი განვითარებულია, რომელიც მონაცემებით ტექსტის განვითარებისთვის მოდელს განზომილებით, რომელიც ტრანფორმებით გადატანგებული კოდერს-ევკოდერს აქტიქტი ჩვენ მივიღეთ, რომ ჩვენი მიღება უფრო გავაკეთება ბაზი მოდელის მონიშნულების მონიშნულების მეტრიკის გარეშე (55.42% vs. 8.49%) და უფრო ინფორმაციური, კონსტიური და კონსტენტიური გარეშე.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Az információs megjelenítések, például a sávdiagramok és a vonaldiagramok nagyon népszerűek az adatok feltárásához és az információk kommunikálásához. Az ilyen vizualizációk értelmezése és értelmezése kihívást jelenthet egyes emberek számára, például azok számára, akik látássérültek vagy alacsony vizualizációs műveltséggel rendelkeznek. Ebben a munkában bemutatunk egy új adatkészletet és bemutatunk egy neurális modellt a diagramok természetes nyelvi összefoglalóinak automatikus generálására. A létrehozott összefoglalók értelmezik a diagramot, és közvetítik a diagramban található kulcsfontosságú betekintéseket. Neurális modellünket az adat-szöveg generálási feladat korszerű modelljének kiterjesztésével fejlesztjük ki, amely transzformátor alapú kódoló-dekóder architektúrát használ. Megállapítottuk, hogy megközelítésünk széles margóval (55,42% vs. 8,49%) felülmúlja az alapmodellt egy tartalom kiválasztására vonatkozóan, és információsabb, tömörebb és koherens összefoglalókat generál.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Οι οπτικοποιήσεις πληροφοριών, όπως γραφήματα ράβδων και γραφήματα γραμμών, είναι πολύ δημοφιλείς για την εξερεύνηση δεδομένων και την επικοινωνία πληροφοριών. Η διερμηνεία και η κατανόηση τέτοιων οπτικοποιήσεων μπορεί να είναι πρόκληση για ορισμένους ανθρώπους, όπως εκείνους που έχουν προβλήματα όρασης ή έχουν χαμηλό γραμματισμό οπτικοποίησης. Σε αυτή την εργασία, εισάγουμε ένα νέο σύνολο δεδομένων και παρουσιάζουμε ένα νευρωνικό μοντέλο για την αυτόματη δημιουργία σύνοψης φυσικής γλώσσας για γραφήματα. Οι περιλήψεις που δημιουργούνται παρέχουν μια ερμηνεία του διαγράμματος και μεταφέρουν τις βασικές πληροφορίες που βρέθηκαν μέσα σε αυτό το γράφημα. Το νευρωνικό μας μοντέλο αναπτύσσεται επεκτείνοντας το μοντέλο τελευταίας τεχνολογίας για την εργασία δημιουργίας δεδομένων σε κείμενο, το οποίο χρησιμοποιεί μια αρχιτεκτονική κωδικοποιητή-αποκωδικοποιητή βασισμένη σε μετασχηματιστή. Διαπιστώσαμε ότι η προσέγγισή μας ξεπερνά το μοντέλο βάσης σε μια μετρική επιλογή περιεχομένου κατά ένα ευρύ περιθώριο (55.42% έναντι 8.49%) και παράγει πιο ενημερωτικές, συνοπτικές και συνεκτικές περιλήψεις.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_kk>Бар диаграммалар мен сызық диаграммалар секілді мәліметті визуализациялау деректерді зерттеу және байланысты көрсету үшін өте маңызды. Бұл визуализацияларды түсіндіру және түсіндіру кейбір адамдар үшін көпшілік көмектеседі, мысалы, визуализациялардың көмектесілігі немесе артық түсіндіру мүмкін. Бұл жұмыс ішінде, жаңа деректер жинағын келтіріп, диаграммалар үшін табиғи тілдерді автоматты түрде құру үшін невралдық моделін келтіреміз. Жасалған тұжырымдамалар диаграммасының түсініктемесін келтіріп, оның ішінде табылған кілттердің түсініктемесін береді. Біздің невралдық моделіміз деректер мен мәтін құру тапсырмасының күй- жай моделін кеңейту арқылы құрылады. Бұл түрлендіруші негізінде кодер- декодер архитектурасын қолданады. Біз тәсіліміздің мазмұнды таңдау метрикалық метрикалық негізгі үлгісін көбірек шегімен (55,42% vs. 8,49%) жасайды және көбірек мәлімет, тәсілдік және тәсілдік тәсіліктерді жа</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Informaciniai vizualizavimai, pavyzdžiui, juostų grafikai ir linijų grafikai, yra labai populiarūs duomenų žvalgymui ir informacijos perdavimui. Tokių vizualizacijų aiškinimas ir prasmė gali būti sunku kai kuriems žmonėms, pavyzdžiui, tiems, kuriems yra regėjimo sutrikimas arba kurie yra mažai vaizduojami raštu. Šiame darbe pristatome naują duomenų rinkinį ir pristatome nervinį model į, skirtą automatiškai kurti gamtinių kalbų santraukas grafikams. The generated summaries provide an interpretation of the chart and convey the key insights found within that chart.  Mūsų nervinis model is plėtojamas išplečiant naujausią model į, skirtą duomenų ir tekstų generavimo užduotims, kuria naudojama transformatoriumi pagrįsta kodavimo dekoderio architektūra. Nustatėme, kad mūsų požiūris yra didesnis už bazinį turinio atrankos metrinį model į plačiu maržu (55,42 proc., palyginti su 8,49 proc.) ir sukuria išsamesnes, glaudesnes ir nuoseklesnes santraukas.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>Le visualizzazioni di informazioni come grafici a barre e grafici a righe sono molto popolari per esplorare i dati e comunicare informazioni. Interpretare e dare un senso a tali visualizzazioni può essere difficile per alcune persone, come quelle che sono ipovedenti o hanno scarsa capacità di visualizzazione. In questo lavoro introduciamo un nuovo dataset e presentiamo un modello neurale per generare automaticamente riassunti di linguaggio naturale per i grafici. I riassunti generati forniscono un'interpretazione del grafico e trasmettono le informazioni chiave trovate all'interno di tale grafico. Il nostro modello neurale è sviluppato estendendo il modello all'avanguardia per il compito di generazione dati-testo, che utilizza un'architettura encoder-decoder basata su trasformatori. Abbiamo scoperto che il nostro approccio supera il modello base su una metrica di selezione dei contenuti di un ampio margine (55,42% vs. 8,49%) e genera riassunti più informativi, concisi e coerenti.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Информациските визуализации како што се барови и линии карти се многу популарни за истражување на податоци и комуникација на информации. Интерпретањето и размислувањето за ваквите визуализации може да биде предизвик за некои луѓе, како што се оние кои се визуелно оштетени или имаат ниска визуализациска литература. Во оваа работа, ние воведуваме нови податоци и претставуваме нервен модел за автоматски генерирање на природни јазички резултати за графиките. Генеративните резултати обезбедуваат интерпретација на графиката и ги пренесуваат клучните информации пронајдени во таа графика. Нашиот нервен модел е развиен со проширување на најновиот модел за задачата на генерација на податоци до текст, која користи архитектура на кодер-декодер базирана на трансформатори. Најдовме дека нашиот пристап го надминува базичкиот модел на метричката селекција на содржината за широка маргина (55,42 отсто против 8,49 отсто) и генерира поинформативни, кратки и кохерентни резултати.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Visualisasi maklumat seperti kad bar dan kad baris sangat populer untuk mengeksplorasi data dan berkomunikasi pandangan. Penjelasan dan memahami visualisasi tersebut boleh menjadi tantangan bagi beberapa orang, seperti orang-orang yang cacat visual atau mempunyai kecerdasan visualisasi rendah. In this work, we introduce a new dataset and present a neural model for automatically generating natural language summaries for charts.  Ringkasan yang dijana menyediakan interpretasi bagi kad dan menyampaikan pandangan kunci yang ditemui dalam kad itu. Model saraf kami dikembangkan dengan memperluas model-state-of-the-art untuk tugas generasi data-ke-teks, yang menggunakan arkitektur pengekod-dekoder berdasarkan pengubah. Kami mendapati bahawa pendekatan kita melebihi model asas pada metrik pemilihan kandungan dengan margin lebar (55.42% vs. 8.49%) dan menghasilkan ringkasan yang lebih maklumat, singkat, dan konsisten.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Il-viżwalizzazzjonijiet tal-informazzjoni bħal bar charts u line charts huma popolari ħafna għall-esplorazzjoni tad-dejta u l-komunikazzjoni tal-fehmiet. L-interpretazzjoni u s-sens ta’ viżwalizzazzjonijiet bħal dawn jistgħu jkunu ta’ sfida għal xi nies, bħal dawk li għandhom indeboliment viżwali jew li għandhom litteriżmu baxx ta’ viżwalizzazzjoni. F’dan ix-xogħol, a ħna nintroduċu sett ta’ dejta ġdid u nippreżentaw mudell newrali biex jiġġeneraw awtomatikament sommarji tal-lingwa naturali għall-mapep. Is-sommarji ġġenerati jipprovdu interpretazzjoni tal-grafika u jgħaddu l-fehmiet ewlenin li jinsabu f’dik il-grafika. Il-mudell newrali tagħna huwa żviluppat billi jestendi l-mudell l-aktar avvanzat għall-kompitu ta’ ġenerazzjoni tad-dejta għat-test, li juża arkitettura ta’ kodifikatur-dekoder ibbażata fuq it-trasformatur. Instabna li l-approċċ tagħna jaqbeż il-mudell bażiku fuq metrika tal-għa żla tal-kontenut b'marġini wiesa' (55.42% kontra 8.49%) u jiġġenera sommarji aktar informativi, konċiżi u koerenti.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>വിവരങ്ങളുടെ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ബാര്‍ ചാര്‍ട്ടും വരി ചിത്രങ്ങളും പരിശോധിക്കുന്നതിനും വിവരങ്ങള്‍ പരിശോധിക്കുന്നതിനും വളരെ പ്ര ഇത്തരം കാഴ്ചപ്പെടുത്തുന്നതിന്റെയും മനസ്സിലാക്കുന്നതും ചില ആളുകള്‍ക്ക് വേണ്ടി ചോദ്യം ചെയ്യാന്‍ സാധിക്കുന്നതും കാണുന്ന ഈ ജോലിയില്‍, നമ്മള്‍ ഒരു പുതിയ ഡാറ്റാസസെറ്റിനെ പരിചയപ്പെടുത്തുകയും ചിത്രങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷയുടെ ചുരുക്കം സൃ സൃഷ്ടിക്കപ്പെട്ട വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ചാര്‍ട്ടിന്‍റെ വിശദീകരണം നല്‍കുന്നു എന്നിട്ട് ആ ചാര്‍ട്ടില്‍ കണ്ടെത്തിയ ക നമ്മുടെ ന്യൂറല്‍ മോഡല്‍ നിര്‍മ്മിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്നു. ഡേറ്റാ ടെക്സ്റ്റ് തലമുറതലമുറയ്ക്കുള്ള രീതിയിലെ മോഡല്‍ വികസിപ്പിക്ക ഞങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടെത്തിയിരുന്നു നമ്മുടെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തിന്‍റെ മോഡലിന്‍റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ നിന്നും പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നത് (55.42% vs 8. 49%) വിശാലമായ വിവ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Бар чарт, шугам чарт мэт мэдээллийн үзүүлэлт нь мэдээллийг судалж, харилцаа холбогдохын тулд их алдартай. Ийм дүрслэлүүдийг ойлгох болон ойлгох нь зарим хүмүүст төвөгтэй болж чадна. Яг харагдаж, харагдаж буй хүмүүст төвөгтэй байдаг. Энэ ажлын хувьд бид шинэ өгөгдлийн санг танилцуулж, диаграмм дээр байгалийн хэл дээр автоматжуулах мэдрэлийн загвар өгдөг. Бүтээгдэхүүний жинхэнэ дүрслэл нь диаграммын тухай ярьж, тэр диаграммын дотор олсон чухал ойлголтыг илтгэдэг. Бидний мэдрэлийн загвар нь өгөгдлийн хувьд текст бүтээлтийн ажлын байр суурь загварыг нэмэгдүүлснээр хөгжүүлж байна. Энэ нь шилжүүлэгч дээр суурилсан коддогч-декодер архитектурыг ашигладаг. Бид ойлголт нь тодорхойлолт сонголтын метрикийн суурь загварыг нэмэгдүүлдэг (55.42% vs. 8.49%) болон илүү мэдээллийн, тодорхойлолт, хоорондоо нийлүүлдэг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Visualiseringar av informasjon, som listediagrammar og linjestykk, er veldig populært for å utforska data og kommunikasjonar. Omsetjing og gjennomsetjing av slike visualiseringar kan vera vanskeleg for nokre menneske, slik som dei som er synleg utvikla eller har låg visualisering. I dette arbeidet introduserer vi eit ny dataset og presenterer ein neuralmodell for automatisk laga naturspråk samandrag for diagrammar. Den genererte samandrag gjev eit tolking av diagrammet og flyttar nøkkelinnsiktene funne i diagrammet. Dette neuralmodellet er utvikla ved å utvide tilstanden av kunstmodellen for oppgåva for data- til- tekst, som brukar ein transformeringsbasert kodkoder- dekoderarkitektur. Vi fann at tilnærminga vårt utfører basemodellen på eit innhaldsutvalet metrisk med eit brett margin (55,42% mot 8,49%) og lager meir informativt, konkisert og koherent samandrag.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Wizualizacje informacyjne, takie jak wykresy słupkowe i wykresy liniowe, są bardzo popularne do eksplorowania danych i przekazywania informacji. Tłumaczenie i uzyskanie sensu takich wizualizacji może stanowić wyzwanie dla niektórych osób, takich jak osób z upośledzeniem wzroku lub niską umiejętnością wizualizacji. W niniejszej pracy wprowadzamy nowy zestaw danych oraz przedstawiamy model neuronowy umożliwiający automatyczne generowanie podsumowań języka naturalnego dla wykresów. Generowane streszczenia zapewniają interpretację wykresu i przekazują kluczowe spostrzeżenia znalezione w tym wykresie. Nasz model neuronowy został opracowany poprzez rozszerzenie najnowocześniejszego modelu do zadania generowania danych do tekstu, który wykorzystuje architekturę kodera-dekodera opartą na transformatorze. Stwierdziliśmy, że nasze podejście przewyższa model bazowy dotyczący wyboru treści o duży margines (55,42% vs. 8,49%) i generuje bardziej informacyjne, zwięzłe i spójne podsumowania.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Vizualizările informațiilor, cum ar fi diagramele cu bare și diagramele linii, sunt foarte populare pentru explorarea datelor și comunicarea informațiilor. Interpretarea și interpretarea unor astfel de vizualizări poate fi o provocare pentru unii oameni, cum ar fi cei care au deficiențe de vedere sau au o alfabetizare scăzută în vizualizare. În această lucrare, introducem un nou set de date și prezentăm un model neural pentru generarea automată a rezumatelor limbajului natural pentru diagrame. Rezumatele generate oferă o interpretare a graficului și transmit informațiile cheie găsite în acel grafic. Modelul nostru neural este dezvoltat prin extinderea modelului de ultimă generare a datelor-text, care utilizează o arhitectură codificator-decodor bazată pe transformator. Am constatat că abordarea noastră depășește modelul de bază pe o metrică de selecție a conținutului cu o marjă largă (55,42% față de 8,49%) și generează rezumate mai informative, concise și coerente.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>දත්ත සහ සම්බන්ධ පරීක්ෂණය සඳහා බාර් චාර්ට්ස් සහ ලායින් චාර්ට්ස් වගේ තොරතුරු දර්ශනය සඳහා ගොඩක්  අනිවාර්යාත්මක කරන්න සහ අදහස් කරන්න පුළුවන් මිනිස්සු වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙන්න පුළුවන්, හරියට ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙ මේ වැඩේ අපි අළුත් දත්ත සෙට් එකක් පෙන්වන්න සහ චාර්ට්ස් වලට ස්වයංක්‍රිය භාෂාවක් සාමාන්‍ය විදියට ස් නිර්මාණය කරලා තියෙන සංශ්‍ය සංශ්‍ය සංවේදනයක් චාර්ට් එකේ අභිවේදනයක් සඳහා ඒ චාර්ට් එකේ හ අපේ න්‍යූරාල් මොඩේල් විස්තර කරලා තියෙන්නේ දත්ත සිද්ධ විස්තර ක්‍රියාව සඳහා ස්ථිතිය-සිද්ධ විස්තරය සඳහා ස්ථිතිය-ක අපිට හොයාගත්තා අපේ ප්‍රවේශනය ප්‍රවේශනයක් ප්‍රවේශනය කරන්න පුළුවන් සාමාන්‍ය විකල්පයක් තෝරාගන්න (55.42% vs. 8.49%) වලින් පරීක්ෂණයක් ව</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Wixii macluumaad lagu arko sida jardiinada barta iyo bandhigyadu waa kuwa aad u populan si ay u baaraandegaan macluumaadka iyo waxyaabaha la xiriira. Turjumidda iyo fikrada aragtida waxaa laga yaabaa in dad qaar ka mid ah caqabad, tusaale ahaan kuwa aragga laxaad la’aanta ama ay leeyihiin aqoon yar. Markaas waxan, waxaynu soo bandhignaa sawir cusub oo macluumaad ah, waxaana soo bandhignaa model neuro ah oo si automatic ah u sameynaya summarin luuqada asalka ah. Jardiinooyinka la soo saaray waxay fidiyaan turjumaadda kaarka, waxayna u sheegtaa aragtida furan ee laga helay kaarka gudaheeda. Tusaalkayaga neurada ah waxaa la horumariyey sida loo sii fidiyo qaabka xaaladda-farshaxanta, kaas oo isticmaalaya dhismaha sawir-sawir-u-qorid-ka-beddelista. Waxaynu helnay in dhaqdhaqaalkayagu uu ka muujiyo qaabka aasaasiga ah oo ku qoran baaritaanka waxyaabaha la doorto (55.42% vs. 8.49%) oo uu sameeyo macluumaad dheeraad ah, xaajooyin iyo xilli.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Informationsvisualiseringar som stapeldiagram och linjediagram är mycket populära för att utforska data och kommunicera insikter. Att tolka och förstå sådana visualiseringar kan vara utmanande för vissa människor, till exempel de som är synskadade eller har låg visualiseringskompetens. I detta arbete introducerar vi en ny datauppsättning och presenterar en neural modell för att automatiskt generera naturliga språksammanfattningar för diagram. De genererade sammanfattningarna ger en tolkning av diagrammet och förmedlar de viktigaste insikterna i diagrammet. Vår neurala modell utvecklas genom att utöka den senaste modellen för data-till-text generation uppgift, som använder en transformatorbaserad encoder-dekoder arkitektur. Vi fann att vårt tillvägagångssätt överträffar basmodellen på ett innehållsval med en bred marginal (55,42% jämfört med 8,49%) och genererar mer informativa, koncisa och sammanhängande sammanfattningar.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Informativne vizualizacije poput tablica i linijskih grafika su veoma popularne za istraživanje podataka i komunikaciju. Razumevanje i razmišljanje o takvim vizualizacijama može biti izazovno za neke ljude, kao što su oni koji su vizualno oštećeni ili imaju nisku vizualizaciju. U ovom poslu predstavljamo novi set podataka i predstavljamo neuralni model za automatsku stvaranje sažetaka prirodnog jezika za grafike. Generirani sažetci pružaju interpretaciju grafika i prenose ključne uvide koje su pronađene u tom grafiku. Naš neuralni model se razvija proširenjem stanja umetničkog model a za zadatak generacije podataka na tekst, koji koristi arhitekturu kodera na transformaciji. Pronašli smo da naš pristup iznosi bazni model na metriku selekcije sadržaja širom marginom (55,42% protiv 8,49%) i stvara informativnije, konkretnije i sasluženije sažetke.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ur>جیسے بار چارٹ اور لین چارٹ بہت محبوب ہیں ڈیٹا کا تحقیق اور بصیرت کا ارتباط کرنے کے لئے۔ اس طرح کی تصویزی کا تفصیل اور سمجھ کرنا بعض لوگوں کے لئے مشکل ہے، جیسے وہ لوگ جن کو نظر انداز ہو یا کم تصویزی کا ذریعہ ہے۔ ہم نے اس کام میں ایک نئی ڈاٹ سٹ کو معلوم کریں اور چارٹوں کے لئے طبیعی زبان کے سامنے آزاد کرنے کے لئے نئورل موڈل کو پیش کریں۔ پیدا کئے گئے سارے چارٹ کی تعبیر دیتے ہیں اور اس چارٹ کے اندر پائی ہوئی کلید معلومات کو پہنچاتے ہیں. ہمارا نئورل موڈل ڈیٹ پر ٹیکسٹ نسل کے کام کے لئے استعمال کرنے کے ذریعہ استعمال کیا گیا ہے جو ایک ٹیکسٹر-بنیادی اکڈر-ڈیکوڈر معماری کے مطابق استعمال کرتا ہے. ہم نے دیکھا کہ ہماری تقریبا ایک منزل منزل کے منزل کے منزل کے ذریعہ ایک وسیع منزل (55.42% vs. 8.49%) پر بنسٹ موڈل کو عمدہ کر رہا ہے اور اس سے زیادہ معلومات، معلومات اور مشکل ترکیب پیدا کرتا ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>தகவல் பார்வைகள் மற்றும் வரி வரி வரைபடங்கள் போன்ற தகவல் பார்வைகள் தகவல் மற்றும் தொடர்பு கூறும் குறிப்புகளை தேடுவதற்க இத்தகைய பார்வைகளை மொழிபெயர்ப்பு மற்றும் உணர்வு சில மக்களுக்கு சவாலாக இருக்கலாம், பார்வையில் குறைந்தவர்கள் அல்லது பார்வையில இந்த வேலையில், நாம் ஒரு புதிய தகவல் அமைப்பை குறிப்பிட்டு வரைபடங்களுக்கு தானாகவே இயல்பான மொழி சுருக்கங்களை உருவாக்கு The generated summaries provide an interpretation of the chart and convey the key insights found within that chart.  தகவல்- உரை உருவாக்கும் பணிக்கான நிலையின் மாதிரி மாதிரி உருவாக்கப்பட்டது, இது மாற்றும் அடிப்படையிலான குறியீட்டு குறியீட்டு அமைப்பை பயன்படு நாங்கள் கண்டுபிடித்துக் கொண்டோம் என்றால் நமது அடிப்படை மாதிரியை வெளியேற்றும் பொருள் தேர்ந்தெடுப்பு மெட்ரிக்கையில் செயல்படுத்துகிறது ஒரு</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Name Ko'rinishni o'rganish va o'rganish bir necha odamlar uchun qanday qilishi mumkin, xuddi ko'rinishni ko'rinishni o'rganish yoki ko'rinishi haqida yaratish mumkin. Bu ishda, biz yangi maʼlumotlar tarkibini aniqlash va avtomatik raqamli tilning muhitirlari yaratish uchun neyrol modelini koʻrsatish. @ info: whatsthis Bizning neyrolik modelimiz taʼlumotlar matn yaratish vazifasi holatini ajratish mumkin. Bu vazifani o'zgartirish asosida kodkoder- dekoder architektidan foydalanadi. We found that our approach outperforms the base model on a content selection metric by a wide margin (55.42% vs. 8.49%) and generates more informative, concise, and coherent summaries.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Các hình ảnh thông tin như các bảng thanh và các biểu đồ đường nét rất phổ biến để tìm hiểu thông tin và giao tiếp. Việc giải thích và hiểu rõ những hình ảnh như vậy có thể gây khó khăn cho một số người, như những người bị mù suy giảm hoặc có khả năng hiểu rõ hình ảnh thấp. Trong công trình này, chúng tôi giới thiệu một bộ dữ liệu mới và một mô hình thần kinh để tự động tạo ra các bản đồ ngôn ngữ tự nhiên. Những bản tóm tắt tạo ra cung cấp một cách giải thích của biểu đồ và truyền đạt những nhận thức chủ chốt tìm thấy trong biểu đồ đó. Hệ thống thần kinh của chúng tôi được phát triển bằng cách mở rộng hệ thống truyền dữ liệu sang văn bản, sử dụng cấu trúc mã hóa dựa vào máy biến. Chúng tôi phát hiện ra cách tiếp cận của chúng tôi hoàn thiện mô hình căn cứ dựa trên một thước đo nội dung bằng một khối lớn (5004=.=) và tạo ra các bản tóm tắt thêm thông tin, ngắn gọn và liên quan.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_hr>Visualizacije informacija poput tablica i linijskih grafika su vrlo popularne za istraživanje podataka i komunikaciju. Razumijevanje i osjećanje takvih vizualizacija može biti izazovno za neke ljude, poput one koji su vizualno oštećeni ili niske vizualizacije. U ovom poslu predstavljamo novi set podataka i predstavljamo neuralni model za automatski proizvedenje sažetaka prirodnog jezika za grafike. Generirani sažetci pružaju interpretaciju grafika i prenose ključne uvjete pronađene u tom grafiku. Naš neuronski model se razvija proširenjem model a umjetnosti za zadatak generacije podataka na tekst, koji koristi arhitekturu kodera-dekodera na transformaciji. Pronašli smo da naš pristup nadmašuje bazni model na selekciji sadržaja metrika širom marginom (55,42% protiv 8,49%) i stvara informativnije, konkretnije i sasluženije sažetke.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Informationsvisualiseringer som stregdiagrammer og linjediagrammer er meget populære til at udforske data og formidle indsigt. At fortolke og give mening til sådanne visualiseringer kan være udfordrende for nogle mennesker, f.eks. dem, der er synshæmmede eller har lav visualiseringsfærdighed. I dette arbejde introducerer vi et nyt datasæt og præsenterer en neural model til automatisk generering af natursprog resuméer til diagrammer. De genererede resuméer giver en fortolkning af diagrammet og formidler de vigtigste indsigter, der findes i diagrammet. Vores neurale model er udviklet ved at udvide den state-of-the-art model for data-to-tekst generation opgave, som bruger en transformer-baseret encoder-dekoder arkitektur. Vi fandt ud af, at vores tilgang overgår basismodellen på en metric for indholdsvalg med en bred margin (55,42% mod 8,49%) og genererer mere informative, kortfattede og sammenhængende resuméer.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Informatie visualisaties zoals staafdiagrammen en lijndiagrammen zijn erg populair voor het verkennen van gegevens en het communiceren van inzichten. Het interpreteren en begrijpen van dergelijke visualisaties kan een uitdaging zijn voor sommige mensen, zoals mensen met een visuele beperking of een lage visualisatie geletterdheid. In dit werk introduceren we een nieuwe dataset en presenteren we een neuraal model voor het automatisch genereren van natuurlijke taalsamenvattingen voor grafieken. De gegenereerde samenvattingen geven een interpretatie van de grafiek en brengen de belangrijkste inzichten uit die grafiek. Ons neurale model wordt ontwikkeld door het state-of-the-art model uit te breiden voor de data-to-text generatie taak, dat gebruikmaakt van een transformator gebaseerde encoder-decoder architectuur. We ontdekten dat onze aanpak het basismodel op een inhoudselectiemetriek met een grote marge overtreft (55,42% vs. 8,49%) en meer informatieve, beknopte en coherente samenvattingen genereert.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Визуализациите на информация като бардиаграми и линейни диаграми са много популярни за проучване на данни и комуникация на прозрения. Тълкуването и осмислянето на такива визуализации може да бъде предизвикателство за някои хора, като например тези, които са със зрително увреждане или имат ниска визуална грамотност. В тази работа въвеждаме нов набор от данни и представяме невронен модел за автоматично генериране на резюмета от естествени езици за диаграми. Генерираните резюмета предоставят интерпретация на диаграмата и предават ключовите прозрения, намерени в тази диаграма. Нашият невронен модел е разработен чрез разширяване на най-съвременния модел за задачата за генериране на данни към текст, който използва базирана на трансформатор кодер-декодер архитектура. Установихме, че нашият подход превъзхожда базовия модел на метричен подбор на съдържание с широк марж (55.42% при 8.49%) и генерира по-информативни, кратки и съгласувани резюмета.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_de>Informationsvisualisierungen wie Balkendiagramme und Liniendiagramme sind sehr beliebt, um Daten zu erkunden und Erkenntnisse zu vermitteln. Das Dolmetschen und Verstehen solcher Visualisierungen kann für manche Menschen eine Herausforderung darstellen, beispielsweise für Menschen mit Sehbehinderung oder geringer Visualisierungskompetenz. In dieser Arbeit stellen wir einen neuen Datensatz vor und stellen ein neuronales Modell zur automatischen Generierung natürlicher Sprachzusammenfassungen für Diagramme vor. Die generierten Zusammenfassungen liefern eine Interpretation des Diagramms und vermitteln die wichtigsten Erkenntnisse, die in diesem Diagramm gefunden werden. Unser neuronales Modell wird durch Erweiterung des State-of-the-Art Modells für die Daten-zu-Text-Generierungsaufgabe entwickelt, das eine transformatorbasierte Encoder-Decoder-Architektur nutzt. Wir fanden heraus, dass unser Ansatz das Basismodell für eine Inhaltsauswahlmetrik um einen großen Spielraum übertrifft (55,42% vs. 8,49%) und informativere, prägnantere und kohärentere Zusammenfassungen generiert.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Visualisasi informasi seperti bar chart dan line chart sangat populer untuk mengeksplorasi data dan komunikasi penglihatan. Interpretasi dan memahami visualisasi tersebut dapat menantang bagi beberapa orang, seperti orang-orang yang mengalami cacat visual atau memiliki kebijaksanaan visualisasi rendah. Dalam pekerjaan ini, kami memperkenalkan set data baru dan memperkenalkan model saraf untuk secara otomatis menghasilkan ringkasan bahasa alam untuk grafik. Ringkasan yang dihasilkan memberikan interpretasi dari grafik dan menyampaikan pandangan kunci yang ditemukan dalam grafik itu. Model saraf kita dikembangkan dengan memperluas model state-of-the-art untuk tugas generasi data-ke-teks, yang menggunakan arsitektur pengekode-dekoder berdasarkan transformer. Kami menemukan bahwa pendekatan kita melebihi model dasar pada metrik seleksi konten dengan margin lebar (55,42% vs. 8,49%) dan menghasilkan ringkasan yang lebih informatif, singkat, dan konsisten.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Kuonyesha taarifa kama vile chart za baro na chart za mstari ni maarufu sana kwa kutafuta taarifa na maoni ya mawasiliano. Kutafsiri na kutambua maono kama haya yanaweza kuwa na changamoto kwa baadhi ya watu, kama wale ambao wameathirika kwa kuona au wana ufahamu mdogo wa kuona. Katika kazi hii, tunaonyesha seti mpya ya taarifa na kuweka mtindo wa neura kwa ajili ya kutengeneza muhtasari wa lugha za asili kwa ajili ya charts. Makala yaliyozaliwa yanatoa tafsiri ya ramani hiyo na kutoa maoni muhimu yaliyopatikana ndani ya ramani hiyo. Mradi wetu wa kiserikali umeundwa kwa kuongeza muundo wa hali ya sanaa kwa ajili ya kazi za kizazi cha taarifa hadi ujumbe wa ujumbe, ambazo hutumia ujenzi wa kodi-decode inayohusiana na mabadiliko. Tumegundua kuwa hatua yetu inafanya mifano ya msingi kwenye mitindo ya uchaguzi wa maudhui kwa kiasi kikubwa (55.42% vs. 8.49%) na inatengeneza muhtasari wa habari, mahususi na muhtasari wa pamoja.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>تصویرات اطلاعات مثل نقشه‌های بار و نقشه‌های خط بسیار مشهور برای تحقیق داده‌ها و ارتباط با مشاهده‌ها هستند. تعبیر و احساس این تصویر ها برای بعضی از مردم، مثل کسانی که به نظر آسیب دیده‌اید یا نوشته‌ی تصویر کمی دارند، می‌توانند سخت بگیرند. در این کار، ما یک مجموعه داده‌های جدید را معرفی می‌کنیم و یک مدل عصبی را برای تولید کردن مجموعه‌های زبان طبیعی برای نقشه‌ها نشان می‌دهیم. جمع‌آوری‌ها تولید شده‌اند یک تعبیر از نمودار را می‌دهند و مشاهده‌های کلید در آن نمودار را می‌دهند. مدل عصبی ما توسعه می‌شود با افزایش مدل وضعیت هنری برای کار تولید داده‌ها به متن، که از یک معماری که بر اساس تغییر دهنده‌ها بنیاد می‌آید، استفاده می‌کند. ما فهمیدیم که دستور ما مدل بنیادی را بر یک منطقه انتخاب محتویات متریک با یک منطقه وسیع (55.42% vs. 8.49%) انجام می دهد و جمع‌آوری اطلاعات بیشتری، دقیق و هماهنگی می‌کند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>정보의 시각화(예를 들어 스트라이프맵과 접선도)는 데이터를 탐색하고 견해를 교류하는 데 매우 유행한다.일부 사람들에게 이런 시각화를 해석하고 이해하는 것은 도전일 수 있다. 예를 들어 시력이 손상되거나 시각화 소양이 낮은 사람들이다.이 작업에서 우리는 새로운 데이터 집합을 도입하고 도표의 자연 언어 요약을 자동으로 생성하는 신경 모델을 제시했다.생성된 요약은 도표에 대한 해석을 제공하고 이 도표에서 발견된 관건적인 견해를 전달한다.우리의 신경 모델은 데이터를 확장하여 텍스트 생성 임무를 수행하는 최신 모델을 통해 개발된 것으로 이 모델은 변압기 기반의 인코더-디코더 구조를 사용한다.우리는 내용 선택 지표에 있어서 우리의 방법이 기본 모델보다 훨씬 낫다(55.42% 대 8.49%)를 발견했고 더 많은 정보, 간결함과 일관된 요약을 생성했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_tr>Çap çizgileri we hatlary ýaly maglumat görkezilişmeleri, maglumatlary gözlemek we geýinişlemek üçin örän meşhur. Böyle görselleri düşünmek we düşünmek käbir adamlar üçin kynçylyk edip biler, görsel hasaplanýan ýa-da düşük görselleştirme edebiýaty ýaly. Bu işde, täze bir dataseti tanyşdirip, täze diller üçin baýram dillerini öz-özüne bejermek üçin bir nural nusgasyny çykarýarys. üretilen toplamlar grafikiň bir terjimesini temin edip, we şol grafikiň içinde tapylan aç noktalary görkez. Biziň neiral nusgasymyz data-a-tekst döredişi işi üçin stat-of-the-art nusgasyny uzatmak bilen geliştirildi. Bu nusgasymyz sisteminde koder-dekoder arhitektegi ullanýar. Biziň ýaryşymyz daňry bir mahal saýlawyň metriklerinde üýtgeşik gabdalyk (55.42% vs. 8.49%) üstünde esasy nusgasyny çykýar we daňry informatiýa, konkes we coherent sammlary döredir.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Informasie visualiserings soos balk kaarte en lyn kaarte is baie populaar vir ondersoek van data en kommunikasie inligtings. Interpreting en maak sens van sodanige visualiserings kan vir sommige mense uitgelyk wees, soos die wat visualiseer invloei is of het lae visualisering literateit. In hierdie werk, introduseer ons 'n nuwe datastel en voorsien 'n neurale model vir outomaties genereer natuurlike taal opsommings vir kaarte. Die genereerde opsommings verskaf 'n uitlegging van die kaart en bring die sleutel inligtings wat binne daardie kaart gevind is. Ons neurale model is ontwikkeld deur die state-of-the-art model te verleng vir die data-to-text generation taak, wat gebruik 'n transformer-gebaseerde enkoder-dekoder-arkitektuur. Ons het gevind dat ons toegang uitvoer die basis model op 'n inhoud keuse metrie deur 'n wyde marjin (55.42% teen 8.49%) en genereer meer inligtige, samekoms en samekoms.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Vizualizimet e informacionit të tilla si kartat e linjave dhe kartat e linjave janë shumë të popullarizuara për eksplorimin e të dhënave dhe komunikimin e kuptimeve. Interpretimi dhe kuptimi i vizualizimeve të tilla mund të jetë sfidues për disa njerëz, të tillë si ata që janë të dëmtuar vizualisht apo kanë shkrim vizualizues të ulët. In this work, we introduce a new dataset and present a neural model for automatically generating natural language summaries for charts.  Përmbledhjet e gjeneruara ofrojnë një interpretim të grafikut dhe transmetojnë pamjet kryesore të gjetura brenda atij grafiku. Modeli ynë neural është zhvilluar duke zgjeruar modelin më të lartë për detyrën e gjenerimit të të dhënave në tekst, i cili përdor një arkitekturë koduesi-dekoderi bazuar në transformues. Ne zbuluam se qasja jonë e tejkalon modelin bazë në një metrikë zgjedhjeje të përmbajtjes me një margin të gjerë (55.42% krahasuar me 8.49%) dhe gjeneron përmbledhje më informative, të shkurtra dhe koherente.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>ዳታ እና ማቀናጃ ማቀናቀል እና የመስመር ማህበረሰብ እንደምትመስል የሀብት ማህበረሰብ እጅግ የበለጠ ነው፡፡ እንደዚህ ባለ ራእይ መተርጓሜ እና ማሳየት ለአንዳንዶች፣ ያይነቱ ደካማ ወይም የራእይ ሐሳብ ያላቸው ሰዎች ማዋጋት ይችላል፡፡ በዚህ ሥራ አዲስ የዳታ ሰርተቶችን እናሳውቃለን እና ለባሕላዊ ቋንቋ ጉዳዮች ለካርተሮች ማሳየያ የደብዳቤ ሞዴል እናቀርባለን፡፡ የተፈጠረው አረንጓዴዎች የካርታ ትርጉም ይሰጣቸዋል፡፡ የናውሬው ሞዴል ለዳታ-ወደ-ጽሑፍ ትውልድ ስራ መዘርጋት የሀብት-የ-አርእስት ሞዴል መዘርጋት ነው፡፡ አካሄዳችን በመምረጥ ማተሚያ ላይ የሚደረገውን መሠረት (55.42 በመቶ ወደ8.49 በመቶ) እና የተመረጠውን፣ ቁጥጥር እና የተጨማሪውን አዋጅ እንዲያሳየው አግኝተናል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Տեղեկատվական վիզուալիզացիաները, ինչպիսիք են խողովակները և գծերի գծերը, շատ հայտնի են տվյալների ուսումնասիրելու և տեղեկատվության ընկալումների համար: Այսպիսի վիզուալիզացիաների մեկնաբանությունը և իմաստավորումը կարող է դժվար լինել որոշ մարդկանց համար, ինչպիսիք են օրինակ նրանք, ովքեր վիզուալիզացիայի խնդիրներ ունեն կամ ովքեր ունեն ցածր վիզուալիզացիայի գրականություն: In this work, we introduce a new dataset and present a neural model for automatically generating natural language summaries for charts.  Գործված համառոտագրությունները տալիս են աղյուսակի մեկնաբանությունը և հաղորդում են այդ աղյուսակի մեջ գտնվող գլխավոր ընկալումները: Մեր նյարդային մոդելը զարգացվում է ընդլայնելով տվյալների ստեղծման վերջին մոդելը տեքստի առաջադրանքի համար, որը օգտագործում է վերափոխողի հիմնված կոդեր-կոդեր ճարտարապետություն: Մենք հայտնաբերեցինք, որ մեր մոտեցումը գերազանցում է հիմնական մոդելը պարունակության ընտրության մետրիկայի վրա լայն տարբերակով (55.42 տոկոս, համեմատած 8.49 տոկոսին), և ստեղծում է ավելի տեղեկատվական, կարճ և համապատասխան համառոտագրություններ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bar çizgələri və çizgi çizgələri kimi məlumatları keşfetmək və əlaqələri ilə əlaqə etmək üçün çox məşhurdur. Bütün bu vizualizasyonların anlaşılması və anlaşılması bəzisi insanlar üçün çətin olar, bəzisi şəkildə zəif olanlar və ya düşük vizualizasyon yazılımları olan insanlar kimi. Bu işdə, yeni verilən qurğunu tanıyırıq və çiftlər üçün təbiətli dil toplamlarını avtomatik olaraq yaratmaq üçün nöral modeli göstəririk. Yapılmış toplamlar diagramin yorumlayıcını təmin edir və bu diagramda bulunan anahtar anlayışları təmin edir. Bizim nöral modelimiz, data-to-text nəzəriyyəti işinin durumu-sanat modelini genişləndirək, transformer-tabanlı koder-dekoder arhitektarını istifadə edir. Yaxınlığımız məlumat seçimlərinin metriklərindən çox geniş qədər (55,42% vs. 8,49%) üssü modelini üstün edir və daha informativ, concise və coherent toplamlar yaradır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>তথ্যের দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি যেমন বার চার্ট এবং লাইন চ্যার্ট অনেক জনপ্রিয়। এই ধরনের দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি সম্পর্কে ব্যাখ্যা এবং বুঝতে পারে কিছু মানুষের জন্য চ্যালেঞ্জ হতে পারে, যেমন যারা দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি হারিয়ে এই কাজে আমরা একটি নতুন ডাটাসেট পরিচয় করিয়ে দেই এবং স্বয়ংক্রিয়ভাবে প্রাকৃতিক ভাষার সারিম তৈরি করার জন্য একটি নিউরেল মডেল উপস তৈরি করা সংক্ষেপ এই চার্টের ব্যাখ্যা প্রদান করে এবং এই চ্যার্টের ভেতরে পাওয়া গেছে কী দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি প্রদান কর ডাটা থেকে টেক্সট প্রজন্মের কাজের জন্য আমাদের নিউরেল মডেল উন্নয়ন করা হয়েছে, যা পরিবর্তনের ভিত্তিক কোডার-ডেকোডার কাঠামো ব্যবহার করে। আমরা আবিষ্কার করেছি যে আমাদের প্রতিযোগিতা বিশাল মার্গিনের মাধ্যমে একটি বিষয়বস্তু নির্বাচিত মেট্রিকে বেশী প্রকাশ করে এবং আরো তথ্য, কনসিস এবং সংক্রান্ত</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Informativne vizualizacije poput tablica i linijskih grafika su veoma popularne za istraživanje podataka i komunikaciju uvida. Razumijevanje i osjećanje takvih vizualizacija može biti izazovno za neke ljude, kao što su oni koji su vizualno oštećeni ili imaju nisku vizualizaciju. U ovom poslu predstavljamo novi set podataka i predstavljamo neuralni model za automatski stvaranje sažetaka prirodnog jezika za grafike. Generirani sažetci pružaju interpretaciju grafika i prenose ključne uvide pronađene u tom grafiku. Naš neuronski model se razvija proširenjem model a stanja umjetnosti za zadatak generacije podataka na tekst, koji koristi arhitekturu kodera na transformaciji. Pronašli smo da naš pristup iznosi bazni model na metriku selekcije sadržaja širom marginom (55,42% protiv 8,49%) i stvara informativnije, konkretnije i sasluženije sažetke.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Visualitzacions d'informació com gràfics de barres i gràfics de línies són molt populars per explorar les dades i comunicar les informacions. Interpretar i tenir sentit d'aquestes visualitzacions pot ser un repte per a algunes persones, com per exemple aquelles que tenen deficiències visuals o tenen baixa alfabetització visual. En aquest treball, introduïm un nou conjunt de dades i presentem un model neural per generar automàticament resums de llenguatges naturals per a les gràfics. Els resums generats proporcionen una interpretació del gràfic i transmiten les idees clau trobadas dins aquest gràfic. El nostre model neural s'està desenvolupant estendre el model d'última generació de dades a text, que utilitza una arquitectura de codificador basada en transformadors. Vam descobrir que el nostre enfocament supera el model de base en una mètrica de selecció de continguts d'un gran marge (55,42% vs 8,49%) i genera resumes més informatius, concis i coherents.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Informační vizualizace, jako jsou pruhové grafy a čárové grafy, jsou velmi oblíbené pro zkoumání dat a komunikaci přehledů. Tlumočení a dávání smyslu těchto vizualizací může být pro některé lidi náročné, například ty, kteří jsou zrakově postiženi nebo mají nízkou vizualizační gramotnost. V této práci představujeme novou datovou sadu a představujeme neuronový model pro automatické generování souhrnů přirozeného jazyka pro grafy. Generované souhrny poskytují interpretaci grafu a sdělují klíčové poznatky nalezené v tomto grafu. Náš neuronový model je vyvinut rozšířením nejmodernějšího modelu pro úlohu generování dat na text, který využívá transformátorovou architekturu kodéru a dekodéru. Zjistili jsme, že náš přístup předčí základní model na metrice výběru obsahu o široké rozpětí (55,42% vs. 8,49%) a generuje informativnější, stručnější a soudržnější shrnutí.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Teabe visualiseerimised, näiteks tribdiagrammid ja joonediagrammid, on väga populaarsed andmete uurimiseks ja ülevaate edastamiseks. Selliste visualiseerimiste tõlgendamine ja mõistmine võib olla keeruline mõnedele inimestele, näiteks neile, kes on nägemispuudega või kellel on madal visualiseerimisalastus. Käesolevas töös tutvustame uut andmekogumit ja tutvustame neuromudelit graafikutele looduskeele kokkuvõtete automaatseks genereerimiseks. Koostatud kokkuvõtted annavad diagrammi tõlgenduse ja annavad selles diagrammis leitud peamised ülevaated. Meie närvimudel on välja töötatud, laiendades andmete genereerimise ülesandeks kaasaegset mudelit, mis kasutab trafopõhist kodeerija-dekooderi arhitektuuri. Leidsime, et meie lähenemisviis on sisuvaliku mõõdiku baasmudelist suurem (55,42% vs 8,49%) ning loob informatiivsemad, lühikesemad ja sidusamad kokkuvõtted.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tietojen visualisoinnit, kuten palkkikaaviot ja viivakaaviot, ovat erittäin suosittuja tietojen tutkimiseen ja tietojen välittämiseen. Tällaisten visualisointien tulkinta ja järkeistäminen voi olla haastavaa joillekin ihmisille, kuten niille, jotka ovat näkövammaisia tai joilla on heikko visualisointi lukutaito. Tässä työssä esitellään uusi aineisto ja esitetään neuromalli luonnollisen kielen yhteenvetojen automaattiseen tuottamiseen kaavioille. Luodut yhteenvedot antavat tulkinnan kaaviosta ja välittävät kaaviosta löydetyt keskeiset näkemykset. Neuromallimme on kehitetty laajentamalla datasta tekstiin -luontitehtävään uusinta mallia, jossa hyödynnetään muuntajapohjaista kooderi-dekooderiarkkitehtuuria. Havaitsimme, että lähestymistapamme on sisällönvalintamittarin perusmallia parempi (55,42% vs. 8,49%) ja tuottaa informatiivisempia, tiiviimpiä ja johdonmukaisempia yhteenvetoja.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>Vizualizacije informacij, kot so vrsticni grafikoni in črtni grafikoni, so zelo priljubljene za raziskovanje podatkov in komuniciranje vpogledov. Tolmačenje in smiselno razumevanje takšnih vizualizacij je lahko za nekatere ljudi izziv, na primer tiste, ki so slabovidni ali imajo nizko vizualno pismenost. V tem delu predstavljamo nov nabor podatkov in predstavljamo nevronski model za samodejno generiranje povzetkov naravnega jezika za grafikone. Ustvarjeni povzetki zagotavljajo interpretacijo grafikona in predstavljajo ključne vpoglede, ki jih najdemo v grafikonu. Naš nevronski model je razvit z razširitvijo najsodobnejšega modela za nalogo generiranja podatkov v besedilo, ki uporablja transformatorsko arhitekturo kodirnika-dekodirnika. Ugotovili smo, da naš pristop presega osnovni model pri meritvi izbire vsebine za široko maržo (55,42% v primerjavi z 8,49%) in ustvarja bolj informativne, jedrnate in skladne povzetke.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>ויזואליזציות מידע כמו רשימות ברדים ורשימות קווים מאוד פופולריות לחקור נתונים ולהתקשר לתבנות. ההתרשמות וההגיונית של חיזויים כאלה יכולות להיות מאתגרים עבור כמה אנשים, כמו אלה שיש להם פגיעות חיזויים או שיש להם ספרות חיזויים נמוכה. בעבודה הזו, אנחנו מציגים קבוצת נתונים חדשה ומציג מודל עצבי לייצור אוטומטי סדרות שפה טבעית לתרשים. הסרטים הנוצרים מספקים פירוש של התרשים ולהעביר את ההבנות המפתחות שנמצאו בתוך התרשים הזה. המודל העצבי שלנו פותח על ידי הרחיבה של המודל המאודם למשימת הדור של נתונים לטקסט, אשר משתמש בארכיטקטורת קודד-קידור מבוססת על מעבר. מצאנו שהגישה שלנו מעלית את הדוגמנית הבסיסית על מטריקת הבחירה של תוכן על ידי שווה רחבה (55.42% vs. 8.49%) ומוצרת סדרות מידעיות, קצרות וקשורות יותר.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Kunna zane-zane kamar bangon charter da jerin na jerin, sun zama mafiya popular dõmin su nẽmi gane da za'a haɗi da gannai. Ana fassarar da gareshi da za'a iya zama mai ƙaranci ga wasu mutane, kamar waɗanda aka raunanta ga gannai ko kuwa sunã da littafin ƙaranci. Daga wannan aikin, muna haɗa wani sabo na danne na yanzu, kuma muna sami wata motsi na neura dõmin a ƙiƙiro ƙararin harshen farat ɗaya wa zaɓe kurs ga KChart. QFontDatabase An buɗe shirin neural da ke shimfiɗa halin-sanar wa aikin data-to-text, wanda ke yi amfani da wani layin da aka bada-bane kode-coder. Mun gane cewa hanyoyinmu yana samar da misalin basasa a kan zaɓen wani metriki mai ƙunci (55.42% vers 8.49%) kuma yana samun ƙarami masu da labarai, ko da ƙarami.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Visual Informasi sing dibutuhke gambar diagram karo linen diagram sing populer kanggo kebah data karo komunikasi Jejaring Nang barêng-barêng iki, kéné mulai nggawe dataset anyar lan gawe ngubah model nêr kuwi nggawe tarjamahan kanggo nggawe resmi adalah kanggo nggawe tarjamahan. Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define" means "Define Njuk model sing wis digawe oleh nggawe barang nggawe state-of-the-Art model nggo data-to-text Generation task, kuwi nggawe barang transformer-basa koder-decoder architecture. Awak dhéwé ngerti nggawe dadi nggawe modèl kuwi nggawe dadi, dadi iki dadi, nik awak dhéwé kesempatan (75.34% karo 8.49 %) lan nganggep sistem informasi, sampeyan karo coherent sampeyan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>འཆར་བཤེར་དང་བྲལ་རིས་མང་ཆེ་བའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ལ་སྟོན་པར་ཆས། དབྱིན་བཟོ་བྱེད་དང་ལྟ་བུའི་རྣམ་པ་ཞིག་འདི་དག་པར་ཐད་ཀར་ཆེན་ཡིན། འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་བྱ་ཚིག་ནང་དུ་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག་ཆ་གསར་བ་ཞིག་སྟོན་པ་དང་རང་འགུལ་གྱིས་མིའི་རྣམ་གྲངས་སྒྲིག་ཆས་ གསར་བསྐྲུན་ཡོད་པའི་བཅུད་སྡུད་དེ་གི་རིས་བཀོད་རིས་ལ་གསལ་བཤད་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད་དོན་མིན་འདུག Our neural model is developed by extending the state-of-the-art model for the data-to-text generation task, which utilizes a transformer-based encoder-decoder architecture. We found that our approach outperforms the base model on a content selection metric by a wide margin (55.42% vs. 8.49%) and generates more informative, concise, and coherent summaries.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Disentangling the Properties of Human Evaluation Methods : A Classification System to Support Comparability, Meta-Evaluation and Reproducibility Testing</title>
      <author><first>Anya</first><last>Belz</last></author>
      <author><first>Simon</first><last>Mille</last></author>
      <author><first>David M.</first><last>Howcroft</last></author>
      <pages>183–194</pages>
      <abstract>Current standards for designing and reporting human evaluations in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> mean it is generally unclear which evaluations are comparable and can be expected to yield similar results when applied to the same system outputs. This has serious implications for reproducibility testing and meta-evaluation, in particular given that human evaluation is considered the gold standard against which the trustworthiness of automatic metrics is gauged. % and merging others, as well as deciding which evaluations should be able to reproduce each other’s results. Using examples from NLG, we propose a classification system for evaluations based on disentangling (i) what is being evaluated (which aspect of quality), and (ii) how it is evaluated in specific (a) evaluation modes and (b) experimental designs. We show that this approach provides a basis for determining <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparability">comparability</a>, hence for comparison of evaluations across papers, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meta-analysis">meta-evaluation experiments</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reproducibility">reproducibility testing</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="08a92927">2020.inlg-1.24</url>
      <revision id="1" href="2020.inlg-1.24v1" hash="b11eeb47" />
      <revision id="2" href="2020.inlg-1.24v2" hash="08a92927" date="2021-04-16">Extended the Acknowledgments section.</revision>
      <bibkey>belz-etal-2020-disentangling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>Listener’s Social Identity Matters in Personalised Response Generation</title>
      <author><first>Guanyi</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <author><first>Yinhe</first><last>Zheng</last></author>
      <author><first>Yupei</first><last>Du</last></author>
      <pages>205–215</pages>
      <abstract>Personalised response generation enables generating human-like responses by means of assigning the generator a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Identity_(social_science)">social identity</a>. However, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pragmatics">pragmatics theory</a> suggests that human beings adjust the way of speaking based on not only who they are but also whom they are talking to. In other words, when modelling personalised dialogues, it might be favourable if we also take the listener’s social identity into consideration. To validate this idea, we use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender">gender</a> as a typical example of a social variable to investigate how the listener’s identity influences the language used in Chinese dialogues on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media">social media</a>. Also, we build <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electric_generator">personalised generators</a>. The experiment results demonstrate that the listener’s identity indeed matters in the language use of responses and that the response generator can capture such differences in language use. More interestingly, by additionally modelling the listener’s identity, the personalised response generator performs better in its own identity.</abstract>
      <url hash="fd4cd4ad">2020.inlg-1.26</url>
      <bibkey>chen-etal-2020-listeners</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="35">
      <title>Schema-Guided Natural Language Generation</title>
      <author><first>Yuheng</first><last>Du</last></author>
      <author><first>Shereen</first><last>Oraby</last></author>
      <author><first>Vittorio</first><last>Perera</last></author>
      <author><first>Minmin</first><last>Shen</last></author>
      <author><first>Anjali</first><last>Narayan-Chen</last></author>
      <author><first>Tagyoung</first><last>Chung</last></author>
      <author><first>Anushree</first><last>Venkatesh</last></author>
      <author><first>Dilek</first><last>Hakkani-Tur</last></author>
      <pages>283–295</pages>
      <abstract>Neural network based approaches to data-to-text natural language generation (NLG) have gained popularity in recent years, with the goal of generating a natural language prompt that accurately realizes an input meaning representation. To facilitate the training of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network">neural network models</a>, researchers created large datasets of paired utterances and their meaning representations. However, the creation of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">datasets</a> is an arduous task and they mostly consist of simple meaning representations composed of slot and value tokens to be realized. These representations do not include any contextual information that an NLG system can use when trying to generalize, such as domain information and descriptions of slots and values. In this paper, we present the novel task of Schema-Guided Natural Language Generation (SG-NLG). Here, the goal is still to generate a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-language_understanding">natural language prompt</a>, but in SG-NLG, the input MRs are paired with rich schemata providing contextual information. To generate a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> for SG-NLG we re-purpose an existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> for another task : dialog state tracking, which includes a large and rich schema spanning multiple different attributes, including information about the domain, user intent, and slot descriptions. We train different state-of-the-art <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> for neural natural language generation on this dataset and show that in many cases, including rich schema information allows our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> to produce higher quality outputs both in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a> and diversity. We also conduct experiments comparing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> performance on seen versus unseen domains, and present a human evaluation demonstrating high ratings for overall output quality.</abstract>
      <url hash="ab06674d">2020.inlg-1.35</url>
      <bibkey>du-etal-2020-schema</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/alexa/schema-guided-nlg" additional="false">alexa/schema-guided-nlg</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/sg-nlg">SG-NLG</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="37">
      <title>Neural NLG for Methodius : From RST Meaning Representations to Texts<fixed-case>NLG</fixed-case> for Methodius: From <fixed-case>RST</fixed-case> Meaning Representations to Texts</title>
      <author><first>Symon</first><last>Stevens-Guille</last></author>
      <author><first>Aleksandre</first><last>Maskharashvili</last></author>
      <author><first>Amy</first><last>Isard</last></author>
      <author><first>Xintong</first><last>Li</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>White</last></author>
      <pages>306–315</pages>
      <abstract>While classic NLG systems typically made use of hierarchically structured content plans that included <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse_analysis">discourse relations</a> as central components, more recent neural approaches have mostly mapped simple, flat inputs to texts without representing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse_analysis">discourse relations</a> explicitly. In this paper, we investigate whether it is beneficial to include <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse_analysis">discourse relations</a> in the input to neural data-to-text generators for texts where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse_analysis">discourse relations</a> play an important role. To do so, we reimplement the sentence planning and realization components of a classic NLG system, Methodius, using LSTM sequence-to-sequence (seq2seq) models. We find that although seq2seq models can learn to generate fluent and grammatical texts remarkably well with sufficiently representative Methodius training data, they can not learn to correctly express Methodius’s similarity and contrast comparisons unless the corresponding RST relations are included in the inputs. Additionally, we experiment with using self-training and reverse model reranking to better handle train / test data mismatches, and find that while these methods help reduce content errors, it remains essential to include discourse relations in the input to obtain optimal performance.</abstract>
      <url hash="59008881">2020.inlg-1.37</url>
      <attachment type="Supplementary_Attachment" hash="3a84b37b">2020.inlg-1.37.Supplementary_Attachment.pdf</attachment>
      <bibkey>stevens-guille-etal-2020-neural</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/methodius-project/neural-methodius" additional="false">methodius-project/neural-methodius</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/webnlg">WebNLG</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="38">
      <title>From Before to After : Generating Natural Language Instructions from Image Pairs in a Simple Visual Domain</title>
      <author><first>Robin</first><last>Rojowiec</last></author>
      <author><first>Jana</first><last>Götze</last></author>
      <author><first>Philipp</first><last>Sadler</last></author>
      <author><first>Henrik</first><last>Voigt</last></author>
      <author><first>Sina</first><last>Zarrieß</last></author>
      <author><first>David</first><last>Schlangen</last></author>
      <pages>316–326</pages>
      <abstract>While certain types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Instruction_set_architecture">instructions</a> can be com-pactly expressed via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_image">images</a>, there are situations where one might want to verbalise them, for example when directing someone. We investigate the task of Instruction Generation from Before / After Image Pairs which is to derive from images an instruction for effecting the implied change. For this, we make use of prior work on instruction following in a visual environment. We take an existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>, the BLOCKS data collected by Bisk et al. (2016) and investigate whether it is suitable for training an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Instruction_set_architecture">instruction generator</a> as well. We find that it is, and investigate several simple baselines, taking these from the related task of image captioning. Through a series of experiments that simplify the task (by making <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_image_processing">image processing</a> easier or completely side-stepping it ; and by creating template-based targeted instructions), we investigate areas for improvement. We find that captioning models get some way towards solving the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(computing)">task</a>, but have some difficulty with it, and future improvements must lie in the way the change is detected in the instruction.</abstract>
      <url hash="e0f2a2a8">2020.inlg-1.38</url>
      <attachment type="Supplementary_Attachment" hash="02f65016">2020.inlg-1.38.Supplementary_Attachment.pdf</attachment>
      <revision id="1" href="2020.inlg-1.38v1" hash="0d842728" />
      <revision id="2" href="2020.inlg-1.38v2" hash="e0f2a2a8" date="2021-01-01">References to appendix were corrected as they were broken (e.g. pages 318, 319 "...Appendix ??" changed to "...Appendix [A,B,...]")</revision>
      <bibkey>rojowiec-etal-2020-generating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="42">
      <title>Rapformer : Conditional Rap Lyrics Generation with Denoising Autoencoders</title>
      <author><first>Nikola I.</first><last>Nikolov</last></author>
      <author><first>Eric</first><last>Malmi</last></author>
      <author><first>Curtis</first><last>Northcutt</last></author>
      <author><first>Loreto</first><last>Parisi</last></author>
      <pages>360–373</pages>
      <abstract>The ability to combine <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Symbol">symbols</a> to generate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">language</a> is a defining characteristic of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_intelligence">human intelligence</a>, particularly in the context of artistic story-telling through lyrics. We develop a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_method">method</a> for synthesizing a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rapping">rap verse</a> based on the content of any text (e.g., a news article), or for augmenting pre-existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rapping">rap lyrics</a>. Our method, called Rapformer, is based on training a Transformer-based denoising autoencoder to reconstruct rap lyrics from content words extracted from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyrics">lyrics</a>, trying to preserve the essential meaning, while matching the target style. Rapformer features a novel BERT-based paraphrasing scheme for rhyme enhancement which increases the average rhyme density of output lyrics by 10 %. Experimental results on three diverse input domains show that Rapformer is capable of generating technically fluent verses that offer a good trade-off between content preservation and style transfer. Furthermore, a Turing-test-like experiment reveals that Rapformer fools human lyrics experts 25 % of the time.</abstract>
      <url hash="966d1de8">2020.inlg-1.42</url>
      <attachment type="Supplementary_Attachment" hash="315249f7">2020.inlg-1.42.Supplementary_Attachment.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>nikolov-etal-2020-rapformer</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="46">
      <title>Policy-Driven Neural Response Generation for Knowledge-Grounded Dialog Systems</title>
      <author><first>Behnam</first><last>Hedayatnia</last></author>
      <author><first>Karthik</first><last>Gopalakrishnan</last></author>
      <author><first>Seokhwan</first><last>Kim</last></author>
      <author id="yang-liu-icsi"><first>Yang</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Mihail</first><last>Eric</last></author>
      <author><first>Dilek</first><last>Hakkani-Tur</last></author>
      <pages>412–421</pages>
      <abstract>Open-domain dialog systems aim to generate relevant, informative and engaging responses. In this paper, we propose using a dialog policy to plan the content and style of target, open domain responses in the form of an action plan, which includes knowledge sentences related to the dialog context, targeted dialog acts, topic information, etc. For <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training</a>, the attributes within the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Action_plan">action plan</a> are obtained by automatically annotating the publicly released Topical-Chat dataset. We condition neural response generators on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Action_plan">action plan</a> which is then realized as target utterances at the turn and sentence levels. We also investigate different dialog policy models to predict an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Action_plan">action plan</a> given the dialog context. Through automated and human evaluation, we measure the appropriateness of the generated responses and check if the generation models indeed learn to realize the given <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Action_plan">action plans</a>. We demonstrate that a basic dialog policy that operates at the sentence level generates better responses in comparison to turn level generation as well as baseline models with no <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Action_plan">action plan</a>. Additionally the basic dialog policy has the added benefit of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Controllability">controllability</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="009b2e1d">2020.inlg-1.46</url>
      <bibkey>hedayatnia-etal-2020-policy</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>