<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.sigdial">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-07-09">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 21th Annual Meeting of the Special Interest Group on Discourse and Dialogue</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Olivier</first><last>Pietquin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Smaranda</first><last>Muresan</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Vivian</first><last>Chen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Casey</first><last>Kennington</last></editor>
      <editor><first>David</first><last>Vandyke</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nina</first><last>Dethlefs</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Koji</first><last>Inoue</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Erik</first><last>Ekstedt</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Stefan</first><last>Ultes</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>1st virtual meeting</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <url hash="0fec3bb3">2020.sigdial-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="37c3ed2c">2020.sigdial-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sigdial-2020-special</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Semantic Guidance of Dialogue Generation with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">Reinforcement Learning</a></title>
      <author><first>Cheng-Hsun</first><last>Hsueh</last></author>
      <author><first>Wei-Yun</first><last>Ma</last></author>
      <pages>1–9</pages>
      <abstract>Neural encoder-decoder models have shown promising performance for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human–computer_interaction">human-computer dialogue systems</a> over the past few years. However, due to the maximum-likelihood objective for the decoder, the generated responses are often universal and safe to the point that they lack meaningful information and are no longer relevant to the post. To address this, in this paper, we propose semantic guidance using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">reinforcement learning</a> to ensure that the generated responses indeed include the given or predicted semantics and that these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">semantics</a> do not appear repeatedly in the response. Synsets, which comprise sets of manually defined synonyms, are used as the form of assigned semantics. For a given / assigned / predicted synset, only one of its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synonym">synonyms</a> should appear in the generated response ; this constitutes a simple but effective semantic-control mechanism. We conduct both quantitative and qualitative evaluations, which show that the generated responses are not only higher-quality but also reflect the assigned semantic controls.</abstract>
      <url hash="b4dfdde2">2020.sigdial-1.1</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=nNvH4co2qr0" />
      <bibkey>hsueh-ma-2020-semantic</bibkey>
    <title_ar>التوجيه الدلالي لجيل الحوار مع التعلم المعزز</title_ar>
      <title_es>Guía semántica de la generación de diálogos con aprendizaje por refuerzo</title_es>
      <title_pt>Orientação Semântica de Geração de Diálogo com Aprendizagem por Reforço</title_pt>
      <title_zh>基于强化之学,语生语义导</title_zh>
      <title_ja>強化学習による対話生成の意味論的ガイダンス</title_ja>
      <title_hi>सुदृढीकरण सीखने के साथ संवाद पीढ़ी का शब्दार्थ मार्गदर्शन</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Treoir Shéimeantach ar Ghiniúint Idirphlé le Foghlaim Neartaithe</title_ga>
      <title_ka>დიალოგის შექმნა სწავლების სემონტიკური მოწყვეტი</title_ka>
      <title_el>Σημαντική καθοδήγηση της δημιουργίας διαλόγου με τη μάθηση ενίσχυσης</title_el>
      <title_hu>A párbeszéd generálásának szemantikus iránymutatása a tanulás megerősítésével</title_hu>
      <title_lt>Semantinės dialogo su mokymosi stiprinimu kūrimo gairės</title_lt>
      <title_it>Orientamento semantico della generazione del dialogo con il rafforzamento dell'apprendimento</title_it>
      <title_kk>Құрастыру оқытуы арқылы диалогты құру семантикалық бағыттауы</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Семантична насока за генерација на дијалог со зајакнување на учењето</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Pemanduan Semantik bagi Jenerasi Dialog dengan Pembelajaran Pengesahan</title_ms>
      <title_ml>വീണ്ടും പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനൊപ്പം ഡയലോഗ് ജനാനത്തിന്റെ സെമാന്റിക് വഴികാട്ടി</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Gwida Semantika tal-Ġenerazzjoni ta’ Djalogu mat-Tagħlim ta’ Tisħiħ</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Сэтгэл хөдөлгөөн суралцах Диалог төрөлхтний Semantic Guidance of Dialogue Generation with reinforcement Learning</title_mn>
      <title_no>Semantisk hjelpelinje for dialoggenerering med forstørringar</title_no>
      <title_pl>Semantyczne wskazówki generowania dialogu z uczeniem się wzmacniającym</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Semantički uputstvo generacije dijaloga sa učenjem pojačanja</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Orientarea semantică a generarii dialogului cu învățarea consolidată</title_ro>
      <title_so>Hagaha hagitaanka dialog generation with Reinforcement Learning</title_so>
      <title_sv>Semantisk vägledning för dialogskapande med förstärkt lärande</title_sv>
      <title_si>සෙමැන්ටික් සංවාදය සංවාදය නිර්මාණය සඳහා ප්‍රශ්ණත්වය ඉගෙනගන්න</title_si>
      <title_ta>மீண்டும் கல்விப்புடன் உரையாடல் உருவாக்கத்தின் செமான்டிக் வழிகாட்டி</title_ta>
      <title_ur>سیمنٹی راہ دکھانے کے ساتھ ڈالیلوگ پیدا کرنے کی</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Hướng dẫn truyền trực tiếp cho Thế hệ giao tiếp</title_vi>
      <title_nl>Semantische begeleiding van het genereren van dialoog met versterking leren</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Semantička uputstva generacije dijaloga s učenjem pojačanja</title_hr>
      <title_bg>Семантично ръководство за създаване на диалог с подсилващо обучение</title_bg>
      <title_de>Semantische Begleitung der Dialoggenerierung mit Reinforcement Learning</title_de>
      <title_da>Semantisk vejledning i dialoggenerering med forstærket læring</title_da>
      <title_ko>대화 생성에 대한 의미 지도를 강화하다</title_ko>
      <title_id>Semantic Guidance of Dialogue Generation with Reinforcement Learning</title_id>
      <title_fa>هدایت نصیحتی نسل دیalog با یادگیری افزایش</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Uongozi wa Uzalishaji wa Dialogu kwa Kufundisha Maendeleo</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Küçlemek öwrenmek bilen Semantik Görniş Opşenler Dialog Düzenlemesi</title_tr>
      <title_af>Semantiese gids van dialoog genereering met versterking leer</title_af>
      <title_am>የመስኮት ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_hy>Խաղախոսության ստեղծման սեմանտիկ ուղղությունները ուժեղացման ուսումնասիրության հետ</title_hy>
      <title_bn>পুনরায় শিক্ষা দিয়ে ডায়ালগ জেনারেশনের সেম্যান্টিক গাইডেন্ট</title_bn>
      <title_az>Y칲kselm톛 칬yr톛nm톛si il톛 Dialog n톛z톛riyy톛ti Semantik hiday톛t</title_az>
      <title_sq>Udhëzimi Semantik i Gjenerimit të Dialogut me Mësimin e Përforcimit</title_sq>
      <title_cs>Sémantické vedení generování dialogu s posilovacím učením</title_cs>
      <title_ca>Orientació Semàtica de la generació de diàleg amb l'aprenentatge de reforç</title_ca>
      <title_bs>Semantička uputstva generacije dijaloga sa učenjem pojačanja</title_bs>
      <title_fi>Vuoropuhelun luomisen semanttinen ohjaus tehostetun oppimisen avulla</title_fi>
      <title_et>Dialoogi loomise semantiline juhendamine tugevdava õppega</title_et>
      <title_jv>semanti guideance of Dialog Generation with Regforcement Learning</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Semantno usmerjanje ustvarjanja dialoga z okrepitvijo učenja</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_bo>Semantic Guidance of Dialogue Generation with Reinforcement Learning</title_bo>
      <title_he>מדריך סמנטי ליצירת דיאלוג עם לימוד גיבוי</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>أظهرت نماذج وحدات فك التشفير والتشفير العصبية أداءً واعدًا لأنظمة الحوار بين الإنسان والحاسوب على مدى السنوات القليلة الماضية. ومع ذلك ، نظرًا لهدف الاحتمال الأقصى لوحدة فك التشفير ، غالبًا ما تكون الاستجابات المتولدة عالمية وآمنة لدرجة أنها تفتقر إلى معلومات مفيدة ولم تعد ذات صلة بالمنشور. لمعالجة هذا ، في هذه الورقة ، نقترح التوجيه الدلالي باستخدام التعلم المعزز للتأكد من أن الاستجابات المتولدة تتضمن بالفعل دلالات معينة أو متوقعة وأن هذه الدلالات لا تظهر بشكل متكرر في الاستجابة. تُستخدم Synsets ، التي تتألف من مجموعات من المرادفات المحددة يدويًا ، كشكل من الدلالات المعينة. بالنسبة لمزامنة معينة / مخصصة / متوقعة ، يجب أن يظهر واحد فقط من مرادفاتها في الاستجابة المولدة ؛ هذا يشكل آلية تحكم دلالية بسيطة ولكنها فعالة. نجري تقييمات كمية ونوعية على حد سواء ، والتي تظهر أن الاستجابات المتولدة ليست عالية الجودة فحسب ، بل تعكس أيضًا الضوابط الدلالية المحددة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Los modelos de codificador-decodificador neuronal han demostrado un rendimiento prometedor para los sistemas de diálogo humano-ordenador en los últimos años. Sin embargo, debido al objetivo de máxima verosimilitud para el decodificador, las respuestas generadas son a menudo universales y seguras hasta el punto de que carecen de información significativa y ya no son relevantes para la publicación. Para abordar esto, en este artículo, proponemos una guía semántica utilizando el aprendizaje por refuerzo para garantizar que las respuestas generadas incluyan realmente la semántica dada o predicha y que esta semántica no aparezca repetidamente en la respuesta. Los synsets, que comprenden conjuntos de sinónimos definidos manualmente, se utilizan como forma de semántica asignada. Para un synset dado/asignado/predicho, solo uno de sus sinónimos debe aparecer en la respuesta generada; esto constituye un mecanismo de control semántico simple pero efectivo. Llevamos a cabo evaluaciones cuantitativas y cualitativas, que muestran que las respuestas generadas no solo son de mayor calidad, sino que también reflejan los controles semánticos asignados.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Modelos de codificador-decodificador neural têm mostrado desempenho promissor para sistemas de diálogo humano-computador nos últimos anos. No entanto, devido ao objetivo de máxima verossimilhança para o decodificador, as respostas geradas são muitas vezes universais e seguras a ponto de carecerem de informações significativas e não serem mais relevantes para o post. Para resolver isso, neste artigo, propomos orientação semântica usando aprendizado por reforço para garantir que as respostas geradas realmente incluam a semântica dada ou prevista e que essas semânticas não apareçam repetidamente na resposta. Synsets, que compreendem conjuntos de sinônimos definidos manualmente, são usados como a forma de semântica atribuída. Para um synset dado/atribuído/previsto, apenas um de seus sinônimos deve aparecer na resposta gerada; isso constitui um mecanismo de controle semântico simples, mas eficaz. Realizamos avaliações quantitativas e qualitativas, que mostram que as respostas geradas não são apenas de alta qualidade, mas também refletem os controles semânticos atribuídos.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>ニューラルエンコーダーデコーダーモデルは、過去数年間に人間とコンピュータの対話システムの有望なパフォーマンスを示してきました。 しかしながら、デコーダの最大尤度の目的のために、生成された応答は、意味のある情報を欠いており、もはやポストに関連性がないという点で、普遍的で安全であることが多い。 これに対処するために、本稿では、生成された応答が実際に与えられたまたは予測された意味論を含み、これらの意味論が応答に繰り返し現れないようにするために、強化学習を使用した意味論的ガイダンスを提案する。 手動で定義された同義語のセットで構成されるシンセットは、割り当てられたセマンティクスの形式として使用されます。 所与の/割り当てられた/予測されたシンセットの場合、生成された応答にはその同義語の1つのみが表示されるはずです。これは、単純ですが効果的な意味制御メカニズムを構成します。 私たちは定量的評価と定性的評価の両方を行い、生成された応答がより高品質であるだけでなく、割り当てられた意味制御を反映していることを示します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>तंत्रिका एन्कोडर-डिकोडर मॉडल ने पिछले कुछ वर्षों में मानव-कंप्यूटर संवाद प्रणालियों के लिए आशाजनक प्रदर्शन दिखाया है। हालांकि, डिकोडर के लिए अधिकतम संभावना उद्देश्य के कारण, उत्पन्न प्रतिक्रियाएं अक्सर सार्वभौमिक और इस बिंदु पर सुरक्षित होती हैं कि उनके पास सार्थक जानकारी की कमी होती है और अब पोस्ट के लिए प्रासंगिक नहीं हैं। इसे संबोधित करने के लिए, इस पेपर में, हम यह सुनिश्चित करने के लिए सुदृढीकरण सीखने का उपयोग करके शब्दार्थ मार्गदर्शन का प्रस्ताव करते हैं कि उत्पन्न प्रतिक्रियाओं में वास्तव में दिए गए या भविष्यवाणी किए गए शब्दार्थ शामिल हैं और ये शब्दार्थ प्रतिक्रिया में बार-बार दिखाई नहीं देते हैं। Synsets, जिसमें मैन्युअल रूप से परिभाषित पर्यायवाची के सेट शामिल हैं, का उपयोग असाइन किए गए शब्दार्थ के रूप में किया जाता है। किसी दिए गए /असाइन किए गए / अनुमानित synset के लिए, इसके समानार्थक शब्दों में से केवल एक उत्पन्न प्रतिक्रिया में दिखाई देना चाहिए; यह एक सरल लेकिन प्रभावी शब्दार्थ-नियंत्रण तंत्र का गठन करता है। हम मात्रात्मक और गुणात्मक मूल्यांकन दोनों का संचालन करते हैं, जो दिखाते हैं कि उत्पन्न प्रतिक्रियाएं न केवल उच्च-गुणवत्ता वाली होती हैं, बल्कि असाइन किए गए शब्दार्थ नियंत्रणों को भी प्रतिबिंबित करती हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>在昔数年,神经编码器-解码器形于人机对话统。 然解码器之大似然,生应常安,至其乏义而不关帖也。 所以然者,吾发强学之语义,以保生成之应,实有给定占之语义,而语义不重复于应也。 Synset 手动义之同义词集,以为语义文。 分配给定//之同义词集,生成之应,唯其一同义词。 此简而有效者语义制也。 量定性评估,此生应不独高,而犹分制语义也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Thaispeáin samhlacha ionchódóra-díchódóra néaracha feidhmíocht iontach do chórais idirphlé idir an duine agus an ríomhaire le blianta beaga anuas. Mar sin féin, mar gheall ar chuspóir uasta na dóchúlachta don díchódóir, is minic go mbíonn na freagraí a ghintear uilíoch agus sábháilte go dtí go mbíonn easpa faisnéise brí acu agus nach mbaineann siad a thuilleadh leis an bpost. Chun dul i ngleic leis seo, sa pháipéar seo, molaimid treoir shéimeantach a úsáideann foghlaim athneartaithe chun a chinntiú go n-áiríonn na freagraí a ghintear go deimhin an tséimeantaic tugtha nó tuartha agus nach bhfeictear an tséimeantaic seo arís agus arís eile sa fhreagra. Úsáidtear sinsets, a chuimsíonn tacair de chomhchiallacha a shainítear de láimh, mar shéimeantaic sannta. Maidir le sinset tugtha/sannta/tuartha, níor cheart go mbeadh ach ceann amháin dá chomhchiallaigh le feiceáil sa fhreagra ginte; is meicníocht shimplí ach éifeachtach rialaithe shéimeantach é seo. Déanaimid meastóireachtaí cainníochtúla agus cáilíochtúla, a thaispeánann go bhfuil na freagraí a ghintear ní hamháin ar chaighdeán níos airde ach go léiríonn siad na rialuithe shéimeantacha sannta freisin.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ნეიროლური კოდირების რეკოდერების მოდელები შემდეგ ბოლო წლის შემდეგ ადამიანის კომპუტერის დიალოგის სისტემებისთვის გავაკეთება. მაგრამ მაქსიმალური შესაძლებელობის მიზეზი დეკოდერებისთვის, შექმნა პასუხი უნდა უნიველური და დარწმუნელია, რომ ისინი არ აქვს მნიშვნელოვანი ინფორმაცია და უკვე პოსტატისთ ამის შესახებ, ამ დომენტიში, ჩვენ ვაკეთებთ სმენტიკური მოწყვეტილება, რომელიც გამოიყენება სწავლის სწავლის შესაძლებლობად, რომ დავიწყებული რეაქციები ნამდვილად დავყენება ან დავიწყება სმენტიკები და სინქესტები, რომელიც ხელხილად განსაზღვრებული სინონიმების კონფიგურაცია, გამოყენებულია როგორც განსაზღვრებული სიმანტიკის ფორმა. მონიშნული/მონიშნული/დაწყვეტილი სინქესტისთვის, მხოლოდ მისი სინონიმების ერთი უნდა ჩვენება შექმნა პასუხში; ეს არის მხოლოდ, მაგრამ ეფექტიური სიმენტიკონტროლური მექანსი. ჩვენ ვაკეთებთ კოლუტატიური და კოლუტატიური განსაზღვრებები, რომელიც გამოჩვენება, რომ შექმნილი განსაზღვრებები არა მხოლოდ უფრო მეტი კოლუტატიური, მაგრამ განსაზღვ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Τα μοντέλα νευρωνικών κωδικοποιητών-αποκωδικοποιητών έχουν δείξει ελπιδοφόρες επιδόσεις για συστήματα διαλόγου ανθρώπου-υπολογιστή τα τελευταία χρόνια. Ωστόσο, λόγω του στόχου μέγιστης πιθανότητας για τον αποκωδικοποιητή, οι παραγόμενες απαντήσεις είναι συχνά καθολικές και ασφαλείς σε σημείο που δεν έχουν ουσιαστικές πληροφορίες και δεν είναι πλέον σχετικές με τη δημοσίευση. Για να αντιμετωπιστεί αυτό, στην παρούσα εργασία, προτείνουμε σημασιολογική καθοδήγηση χρησιμοποιώντας ενισχυτική μάθηση για να διασφαλίσουμε ότι οι παραγόμενες απαντήσεις όντως περιλαμβάνουν τη δεδομένη ή προβλεπόμενη σημασιολογία και ότι αυτές οι σημασιολογικές δεν εμφανίζονται επανειλημμένα στην απάντηση. Συνσύνολα, τα οποία αποτελούνται από σύνολα χειροκίνητα καθορισμένων συνώνυμων, χρησιμοποιούνται ως μορφή εκχωρημένης σημασιολογίας. Για ένα δεδομένο/εκχωρημένο/προβλεπόμενο σύνδρομο, μόνο ένα από τα συνώνυμά του θα πρέπει να εμφανίζεται στην παραγόμενη απάντηση. αυτό αποτελεί έναν απλό αλλά αποτελεσματικό σημασιολογικό μηχανισμό ελέγχου. Πραγματοποιούμε τόσο ποσοτικές όσο και ποιοτικές αξιολογήσεις, οι οποίες δείχνουν ότι οι παραγόμενες απαντήσεις δεν είναι μόνο υψηλότερης ποιότητας αλλά αντικατοπτρίζουν και τους καθορισμένους σημασιολογικούς ελέγχους.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az elmúlt néhány évben ígéretes teljesítményt mutattak az ember-számítógép párbeszédrendszerek számára. A dekódoló maximális valószínűségű célkitűzése miatt azonban a generált válaszok gyakran univerzálisak és biztonságosak annyira, hogy hiányoznak értelmes információk, és már nem relevánsak a bejegyzés szempontjából. Ennek megoldására ebben a tanulmányban szemantikai útmutatást javasolunk erősítési tanulással annak biztosítására, hogy a generált válaszok valóban tartalmazzák az adott vagy előrejelzett szemantikát, és hogy ezek a szemantikák ne jelenjenek meg többször a válaszban. A kézzel definiált szinonimák halmazát tartalmazó szinkronkészleteket a hozzárendelt szemantika formájaként használják. Egy adott/hozzárendelt/előrejelzett szinonimák esetében a generált válaszban csak az egyik szinonimája jelenik meg; Ez egy egyszerű, de hatékony szemantikai ellenőrzési mechanizmus. Mennyiségi és minőségi értékeléseket is végzünk, amelyek azt mutatják, hogy a generált válaszok nemcsak magasabb minőségűek, hanem a hozzárendelt szemantikai kontrollokat is tükrözik.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_mk>Neural encoder-decoder models have shown promising performance for human-computer dialogue systems over the past few years.  Сепак, поради целта со максимална веројатност за декодерот, генерираните одговори честопати се универзални и безбедни до точката дека тие немаат значајни информации и повеќе не се релевантни за постот. За да го решиме ова, во овој документ, предложуваме семантично упатување користејќи зајакнување учење за да се осигури дека генерираните одговори навистина вклучуваат дадена или предвидена семантичност и дека оваа семантичност не се појавува повторно во одговорот. Синсети, кои сочинуваат набори рачно дефинирани синоними, се користат како форма на призначена семантика. За даден/призначен/предвиден синсет, во генерираниот одговор треба да се појави само еден од неговите синоними; ова претставува едноставен но ефикасен механизам за семантична контрола. Правиме квантитивни и квалитетни проценки, кои покажуваат дека генерираните одговори не се само повисоки квалитети, туку и одразуваат на призначените семантични контроли.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Per pastaruosius kelerius metus žmogaus ir kompiuterių dialogo sistemų pažadus parodė neurologinio kodavimo kodavimo modeliai. Tačiau dėl didžiausios tikimybės tikslo dekoderiui gauti atsakymai dažnai yra universal ūs ir saugūs, nes trūksta reikšmingos informacijos ir nebeaktualūs pareigūnui. Siekiant išspręsti šį klausimą šiame dokumente siūlome semantines gaires, naudojant stiprinamąjį mokymąsi, kad būtų užtikrinta, jog sukauptas atsakas iš tikrųjų apimtų nurodytą arba prognozuojamą semantiką ir kad ši semantika neatsirastų pakartotinai atsakyme. Sintetiniai rinkiniai, sudaryti iš rankiniu būdu apibrėžtų sinonimų rinkinių, naudojami kaip priskirtos semantikos forma. Atsakyme turėtų būti nurodytas tik vienas iš jo sinonimų tam tikram (priskirtam) ir (arba) prognozuojamam sinonimui; tai yra paprastas, bet veiksmingas semantinės kontrolės mechanizmas. Atliekame tiek kiekybinius, tiek kokybinius vertinimus, kurie rodo, kad sukaupti atsakai yra ne tik kokybiškesni, bet ir atspindi paskirtą semantinę kontrolę.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>I modelli encoder-decoder neurali hanno mostrato prestazioni promettenti per i sistemi di dialogo uomo-computer negli ultimi anni. Tuttavia, a causa dell'obiettivo di massima probabilità per il decoder, le risposte generate sono spesso universali e sicure al punto che mancano di informazioni significative e non sono più rilevanti per il post. Per affrontare questo problema, in questo articolo, proponiamo una guida semantica utilizzando l'apprendimento di rinforzo per garantire che le risposte generate includano effettivamente la semantica data o prevista e che questa semantica non appaia ripetutamente nella risposta. I sintassi, che comprendono insiemi di sinonimi definiti manualmente, sono utilizzati come forma di semantica assegnata. Per un dato/assegnato/previsto synset, solo uno dei suoi sinonimi dovrebbe apparire nella risposta generata; questo costituisce un meccanismo di controllo semantico semplice ma efficace. Conduciamo valutazioni sia quantitative che qualitative, che dimostrano che le risposte generate non sono solo di qualità superiore, ma riflettono anche i controlli semantici assegnati.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Невралдық кодер- декодер үлгілері өткен бірнеше жылда адамдар- компьютер диалог жүйелерінде әсер ететін әрекеттерді көрсетті. Бірақ декодердің максималдық мүмкіндігінің мақсаттылығының себебі, жасалған жауаптар көбінде әлемдік және қауіпсіздік мәліметі жоқ және оқытуға қатынасыз болмайды. Бұл қағазға қатынау үшін, біз сентикалық мәліметтерді қолдану үшін жасалған жауап берілген немесе бұл сентикалық мәліметтер қайталап жауап берілмейді. Қолмен анықталған синонимдердің баптаулары қолданылатын синонимдердің түрі ретінде қолданылады. Келтірілген/тағайындалған/тағайындалған қадамдастыру үшін оның синонимдерінің бірі жауап берілген жауаптарында көрсетіледі. Бұл қарапайым, бірақ эффективті семантикалық контрол механизмі. Біз санативтік және квалификациялық оқиғаларды жасаймыз. Бұл құрылған жауаптарды тек жоғары сапасы емес, сондай-ақ бөлінген семантикалық контроллерді көрсетеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Model pengekod-dekoder saraf telah menunjukkan prestasi yang berjanji untuk sistem dialog manusia-komputer selama beberapa tahun terakhir. Namun, kerana objektif kemungkinan maksimum untuk penyahkod, balasan yang dijana sering universal dan selamat sehingga mereka kekurangan maklumat yang bermakna dan tidak lagi relevan untuk pos. Untuk mengatasi ini, dalam kertas ini, kami cadangkan panduan semantik menggunakan pembelajaran kuasa untuk memastikan bahawa balasan yang dijana benar-benar termasuk semantik yang diberikan atau dijangka dan bahawa semantik ini tidak muncul berulang kali dalam balasan. Sinset, yang mengandungi set sinonim ditakrif secara manual, digunakan sebagai bentuk semantik yang ditentukan. Untuk set sinfon yang diberi/ditugaskan/dijangka, hanya satu sinonymnya patut muncul dalam balasan yang dijana; ia membentuk mekanisme kawalan semantik yang mudah tetapi efektif. Kami melakukan penilaian kuantitatif dan kualitatif, yang menunjukkan bahawa respon yang dijana tidak hanya kualiti yang lebih tinggi tetapi juga mencerminkan kawalan semantik yang diberikan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Il-mudelli tad-dekodifikatur newrali wrew prestazzjoni promettenti għas-sistemi ta’ djalogu bejn il-bniedem u l-kompjuter matul dawn l-aħħar snin. However, due to the maximum-likelihood objective for the decoder, the generated responses are often universal and safe to the point that they lack meaningful information and are no longer relevant to the post.  Biex nindirizzaw dan, f'dan id-dokument, nipproponu gwida semantika bl-użu tat-tagħlim ta' rinfurzar biex niżguraw li r-risposti ġġenerati tabilħaqq jinkludu s-semantika mogħtija jew imbassra u li dawn is-semantiċi ma jidhrux ripetutament fir-rispons. Sinsetti, li jinkludu settijiet ta’ sinonimi definiti manwalment, jintużaw bħala l-forma ta’ semantika assenjata. Għal sinsett mogħti/assenjat/imbassar, wieħed biss mis-sinonimi tiegħu għandu jidher fir-rispons iġġenerat; dan jikkostitwixxi mekkaniżmu sempliċi iżda effettiv ta’ kontroll semantiku. Aħna nagħmlu kemm evalwazzjonijiet kwantitattivi kif ukoll kwalitattivi, li juru li r-reazzjonijiet iġġenerati mhumiex biss ta’ kwalità ogħla iżda jirriflettu wkoll il-kontrolli semantiċi assenjati.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>Neural encoder-decoder models have shown promising performance for human-computer dialogue systems over the past few years.  എന്നാലും, ഡെകോഡെറിന്റെ ഏറ്റവും സാധ്യതയുള്ള ലക്ഷ്യം കാരണം, ജനിപ്പിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഉത്തരങ്ങള്‍ സാധാരണമായും സുരക്ഷിതമായും പ്രധാനപ്പെട്ട വിവരങ്ങള ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ ഇതിനെ വിശദീകരിക്കാന്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ സെമാന്റിക് വഴികാട്ടിയാണ് പ്രാര്‍ത്ഥിക്കുന്നത്, കൂടുതല്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ പഠിപ്പിക്കുന്നത് ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത്, ഉ കൈയ്യില്‍ നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കപ്പെട്ട സിനോണിമുകളുടെ സജ്ജീകരണങ്ങള്‍ ചേര്‍ക്കുന്ന സിനിസ്റ്റുകള്‍, നിര്‍ബന്ധിതമ കൊടുക്കപ്പെട്ട/നിശ്ചയിക്കപ്പെട്ട സിനിസ്റ്റെറ്റിനു് മാത്രമേ അതിന്റെ സിനോണിമുകളില്‍ ഒരു പ്രത്യേകം പ ഇത് എളുപ്പമുള്ള പക്ഷെ സെമാന്റിക് നിയന്ത്രിക്കുന്ന മെക്കയാണ്. നമ്മള്‍ രണ്ടുപേര്‍ക്കും വിലാസവും പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. ഉയര്‍ത്തപ്പെട്ട പ്രതികരണങ്ങള്‍ ഉയര്‍ത്തിയിരിക്കുന്നത് മാത്രമല്ല,</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Сүүлийн хэдэн жилийн турш хүн-компьютерийн диалог системийн амлалтай үйл ажиллагааг харуулсан. Гэвч шийдвэрлэгчийн магадлалын зорилготой учраас үүсгэсэн хариулт ихэвчлэн нийтлэл болон аюулгүй байдаг. Тэдний тодорхой мэдээлэл байхгүй болон цахилгаан дээр хамааралтай байхгүй. Үүнийг хэлэхэд, энэ цаасан дээр бид суралцах сургалтыг нэмэгдүүлэх болон тодорхойлж өгсөн эсвэл тодорхойлж байгаа семантик болон эдгээр семантик нь хариултаар дахин харагдахгүй гэдгийг баталж байна. Хоосон тодорхойлогдсон синонимуудын хэлбэрүүд нь холбоотой синонимуудын хэлбэрээр хэрэглэгддэг. Дараагдсан/тайлбарласан/тайлбарласан синонимуудын нэг зөвхөн үүсгэсэн хариултанд харагдах хэрэгтэй. Энэ нь энгийн, гэхдээ үр дүнтэй semantic-control механизм юм. Бид хэмжээст болон квалифицийн оюун шалгалт хийдэг. Энэ нь үүсгэсэн хариулт нь зөвхөн өндөр чанартай биш, мөн зарцуулагдсан семантийн удирдлагааг харуулдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>W ciągu ostatnich kilku lat modele koderów-dekoderów neuronowych okazały się obiecujące wydajności dla systemów dialogu człowiek-komputer. Jednak ze względu na cel maksymalnego prawdopodobieństwa dekodera generowane odpowiedzi są często uniwersalne i bezpieczne do tego stopnia, że brakuje im znaczących informacji i nie są już istotne dla danego postu. Aby temu rozwiązać, w niniejszym artykule proponujemy wskazówki semantyczne wykorzystujące uczenie się wzmacniające, aby zapewnić, że generowane odpowiedzi rzeczywiście obejmują daną lub przewidywaną semantykę i że semantyka ta nie pojawia się wielokrotnie w odpowiedzi. Zestawy synonimów, które składają się z zestawów ręcznie zdefiniowanych synonimów, są używane jako forma przypisanej semantyki. Dla danego/przypisanego/przewidywanego zestawu synonimów w generowanej odpowiedzi powinien pojawić się tylko jeden z jego synonimów; stanowi to prosty, ale skuteczny mechanizm kontroli semantycznej. Przeprowadzamy zarówno oceny ilościowe, jak i jakościowe, które pokazują, że generowane odpowiedzi są nie tylko wyższej jakości, ale również odzwierciedlają przypisane kontrole semantyczne.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Nøyrale koderingsmodeller har vist forventande utvikling for menneskelige datamaskiner i løpet av siste par år. Men på grunn av den maksimale sannsynlighetskobjekten for dekoderen er dei genererte svara ofte universelle og trygge til punktet at dei manglar meningsinformasjon og er ikkje lenger relevant for post. For å handsama dette, i denne papiret foreslår vi semantiske hjelpelinjer ved å bruka styrke læring for å sikre at dei genererte svara faktisk inkluderer den gjevne eller foreslåde semantikka og at desse semantikkane ikkje dukkar opp repet i svaret. @ info: whatsthis For ein gitt/tildelt/foregått synkronisering, bør berre eitt av sine synonym visast i den genererte svaret. Dette er ein enkel, men effektiv semantikkontrollmekanisme. Vi gjer både kvantitative og kvalitative evaluering, som viser at dei genererte svara er ikkje berre høgare kvalitet, men også reflekterer dei tildelte semantiske kontrollene.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Modelele encoder-decoder neurale au demonstrat performanțe promițătoare pentru sistemele de dialog om-computer în ultimii ani. Cu toate acestea, datorită obiectivului de probabilitate maximă pentru decodor, răspunsurile generate sunt adesea universale și sigure până la punctul în care lipsesc informații semnificative și nu mai sunt relevante pentru post. Pentru a aborda acest lucru, în această lucrare, propunem orientări semantice folosind învățarea de consolidare pentru a ne asigura că răspunsurile generate includ într-adevăr semantica dată sau prevăzută și că aceste semantice nu apar în mod repetat în răspuns. Sintetiile, care cuprind seturi de sinonime definite manual, sunt folosite ca forma semanticii atribuite. Pentru un sinonim dat/atribuit/previzionat, numai unul dintre sinonimele sale ar trebui să apară în răspunsul generat; aceasta constituie un mecanism simplu, dar eficient de control semantic. Realizăm evaluări atât cantitative, cât și calitative, care arată că răspunsurile generate nu sunt doar de calitate superioară, ci reflectă și controalele semantice atribuite.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Tusaalooyinka koordirada ee Neural-decoder waxay tuseen sameynta ballan u leh nidaamka dialogka ee computer-computer ee ugu dambeeyey dhawr sano. Si kastaba ha ahaatee, sababtoo ah waxyaabaha ugu macquul ah ee codsiga, jawaabaha la soo bixiyey waa caalami iyo ammaan, marka ay u baahan yihiin macluumaad faa’iido ah oo ayan mar dambe la xiriirin boostada. Si aan warqaddan uga sheekeyno, waxaan u soo jeedaynaa hagitaanka semantiga ah oo ku isticmaalaya barashada kordhinta si aan u xaqiiqsan in jawaabaha dhashay ay ku jiraan sida runta ah waxay ku jiraan semantika la siiyay ama la sii sheegay, oo aan dib u soo noqonaynin jawaabta. Isticmaalka ku qoran sawirada qof lagu qoray waxaa loo isticmaalaa sida foomka semantika la qaybiyey. Maxaa yeelay, hees la siiyay/la qaybiyey oo la sii sheegay waa in mid ka mid ah dhammaantiis uu ka muuqdo jawaabta la generay; taasi waxay noqotaa mekani fudud laakiin tayo leh Waxaynu sameynaa qiimeynta qiyaastii iyo qiimeynta, taas oo caddaynaya in jawaabaha dhalay aysan ahayn mid aad u sareeya, laakiin sidoo kale waxaynu ka fiirsanaynaa maamulka qeybta.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>Neuralni modeli dekodera pokazali su obećavajuću izvedbu za ljudski kompjuterski dijalog u proteklih nekoliko godina. Međutim, zbog cilja maksimalne verovatnosti za dekoder, generirane odgovore su često univerzalne i bezbedne do tačke da im nedostaje značajne informacije i više nisu relevantne na poštu. Da bi se ovo riješili, u ovom papiru predlažemo semantičke upute koristeći učenje pojačanja kako bi se osigurali da stvarno proizvedeni odgovori uključuju određene ili predviđene semantike i da se ovi semantici ne pojavljuju ponovno na odgovoru. Sinkronizacija, koja sadrži setove ručno definiranih sinonima, koriste se kao oblik određenih semantika. Za određenu/određenu/predviđenu sinonimu treba pojaviti samo jedan od njegovih sinonima u proizvedenom odgovoru; To je jednostavan, ali efikasan semantički kontrolni mehanizam. Mi vodimo kvantitativne i kvalitativne procjene, koje pokazuju da su proizvedene odgovore ne samo veće kvalitete, nego i odražavaju određene semantičke kontrole.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අවුරුදු කීපයක් පස්සේ මිනිස්සු කම්පියුටර් සංවාද පද්ධතියට ප්‍රශ්නයක් පෙන්වනවා. නමුත්, ඩිකෝඩර් වෙනුවෙන් විශේෂතාවක් අභ්‍යාගයක් නිසා, ප්‍රතිචාර ප්‍රතිචාරයක් සාමාන්‍ය සහ ආරක්ෂිතයි, ඔවුන්ට අවශ මේක විශ්වාස කරන්න, මේ පැත්තට, අපි සෙමාන්ටික් මධ්‍යස්ථානය ප්‍රවේශනය කරන්න පුළුවන් විදිහට උපදේශනය කරන්න පුළුවන් විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියා සම්බන්ධතාවක්, සම්බන්ධතාවක් සම්බන්ධතාවක් සම්බන්ධතාවක් සම්බන්ධතාවක් තියෙන්නේ, සම්බන්ධතාව දැනගත්ත/සැකසුම/සැකසුම් වෙනුවෙන්, ඒකේ සැකසුම් එකක් විතරයි නිර්මාණය කරපු ප්‍රතික්‍රියාවට පෙන් මේක සාමාන්‍ය නමුත් ප්‍රශ්නයක් නිර්මාණය කරන්නේ. අපි ප්‍රමාණය සහ ප්‍රමාණය විශ්වාස කරනවා, ඒකෙන් පෙන්වන්නේ නිර්මාණය කරපු ප්‍රතිචාරයක් විතරයි වඩා විශේෂ විශේෂ ව</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Neural encoder-dekoder modeller har visat lovande prestanda för människa-dator dialogsystem under de senaste åren. På grund av målet med maximal sannolikhet för avkodaren är de genererade svaren emellertid ofta universella och säkra till den grad att de saknar meningsfull information och inte längre är relevanta för posten. För att ta itu med detta föreslår vi i denna uppsats semantisk vägledning med hjälp av förstärkt lärande för att säkerställa att de genererade svaren verkligen inkluderar den givna eller förutspådda semantiken och att denna semantik inte visas upprepade gånger i svaret. Synuppsättningar, som består av uppsättningar av manuellt definierade synonymer, används som form av tilldelad semantik. För en given/tilldelad/förutspådd synuppsättning bör endast en av dess synonymer visas i det genererade svaret. Detta utgör en enkel men effektiv semantisk kontrollmekanism. Vi genomför både kvantitativa och kvalitativa utvärderingar som visar att de genererade svaren inte bara är av högre kvalitet utan också återspeglar de tilldelade semantiska kontrollerna.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>கடந்த சில வருடங்களில் மனித கணினி உரையாடல் அமைப்புகளுக்கு வாக்களிக்கப்பட்ட செயல்பாட்டை காட்டுகிறது. ஆனால், குறியீட்டிற்கான அதிகபட்ச ச சாத்தியமான பொருளால், உருவாக்கப்பட்ட பதில் இந்த காகிதத்தில், நாம் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள விடைகள் உண்மையில் கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது அல்லது எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்துவதற்கா ஒத்திசைவுகள், கைமுறையாக வரையறுக்கப்பட்ட ஒத்திசைவுகளை ஒப்பிடுக For a given/assigned/predicted synset, only one of its synonyms should appear in the generated response;  இது ஒரு எளிய ஆனால் செயல்படுத்தும் பாதுகாப்பு கட்டுப்பாட்டு முறைமையை உருவாக்குகிறது. நாம் இரண்டு அளவிற்கும் குறிப்பிட்ட மதிப்புகளையும் செயல்படுத்துகிறோம். உருவாக்கப்பட்ட பதில்கள் உயர்தரவு மட்டும் அல்ல, ஆனால் வழங</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>نیورال اکڈر-ڈیکوڈر موڈل نے اگلے چند سال میں انسان-کمپیوٹر کے ڈالیوسٹم کے لئے وعدہ دینے والی عمل دکھائی ہے. لیکن، ڈیکوڈر کے مطابق سب سے زیادہ احتمال کا موضوع کے سبب، پیدا کئے ہوئے جواب اکثر وغیر معنی معلومات کے لائق ہیں اور پوسٹ کے معاملہ نہیں ہیں. اس کے لئے ہم اس کاغذ میں سیمنٹی ہدایت کی پیشنهاد کرتے ہیں تاکہ اس کے ساتھ مضبوط تعلیم کے مطابق مضبوط کریں کہ پیدا کئے ہوئے پاسخ ضرور دیئے ہوئے یا پیش کئے ہوئے سیمنٹیکوں میں شامل ہوتے ہیں اور یہ سیمانٹیکوں کا جواب دوبارہ نہیں آتا۔ Synsets, which consists of sets of manually defined synonyms, are used as the form of assigned semantics. ایک مقررہ/مقررہ/پیش بینی سینسٹ کے لئے، اس کے سائنومین میں سے ایک ہی پیدا ہونے والی جواب میں ظاہر ہونا چاہیے، یہ ایک ساده لیکن اثرات سیمنٹی کنٹرول مکانیزی ہے۔ ہم گنتی اور کفایت کی ارزش کرتے ہیں جو دکھاتے ہیں کہ پیدا کئے ہوئے جواب نہیں صرف بلند کیفیت ہیں بلکہ اسی طرح مقرر کئے ہوئے سیمانتی کنٹرول کو دکھاتے ہیں</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Lekin, kodlash uchun eng eng eng eng eng muhimi maqsadi sababda, generated javoblar ko'p umumiy va xavfsiz holatda, ularda muhim maʼlumot yoʻq va keyin pochta bilan bog'liq emas. Bu qogʻozdagi xabarga qarish uchun biz "semantik" talabasini foydalanish uchun qo'llanmalarni qo'shish imkoniyatini foydalanishimiz va yaratilgan javoblarni aslida qo'llashga ishonch hosil qilamiz. Bu semantika qayta javob bermaydi. @ info: whatsthis Koʻrsatilgan/koʻrsatilgan синтаксис учун, teng bir synonymetrning yetarli javob boʻyicha koʻrsatilishi kerak; bu oddiy, lekin ishlaydigan semantik boshqaruv mekaniga ega. Biz ko'pchilik va kvalitative qiymatlarini bajaramiz. Bu natijalar javoblari faqat eng yuqori sifatida emas, balki qaytadan qo'llangan semantik boshqaruvchilarini tasavvur qilamiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Mẫu mã hóa thần kinh đã cho thấy hiệu quả hứa hẹn với hệ thống đối thoại máy tính con người trong vài năm qua. Tuy nhiên, vì mục tiêu có khả năng cao nhất cho bộ giải mã, các phản ứng đã tạo ra thường là phổ biến và an to àn đến mức họ thiếu thông tin có ý nghĩa và không còn liên quan đến bài viết. Để giải quyết vấn đề này, trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi đề nghị hướng dẫn ngữ pháp sử dụng việc củng cố học để đảm bảo rằng các phản ứng đã tạo ra cũng gồm ngữ pháp hay được dự đoán và rằng những ngữ pháp này không xuất hiện liên tục trong phản ứng. Những từ điển, gồm các bộ đồng nghĩa được xác định bằng tay, được sử dụng như một dạng ngữ pháp được phân công. Đối với một cú đồng hồ đã gán/tiên đoán, chỉ một trong những từ đồng nghĩa nó xuất hiện trong phản ứng đã tạo ra. Đây là một cơ chế điều khiển đơn giản nhưng hiệu quả. Chúng tôi tiến hành đánh giá về chất lượng và chất lượng, cho thấy các phản ứng đó không chỉ là chất lượng cao, mà còn phản ánh các kiểm soát theo ngữ pháp.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Моделите на невронен кодер-декодер показаха обещаваща производителност за диалоговите системи човек-компютър през последните няколко години. Въпреки това, поради целта за максимална вероятност за декодера, генерираните отговори често са универсални и безопасни до степен, че липсва смислена информация и вече не са релевантни за поста. За да се справим с това, в настоящата статия предлагаме семантични насоки, използващи усилвателно обучение, за да се гарантира, че генерираните отговори наистина включват дадената или прогнозираната семантика и че тези семантики не се появяват многократно в отговора. Синтезите, които включват набор от ръчно дефинирани синоними, се използват като форма на зададена семантика. За даден/зададен/прогнозен синдром в генерирания отговор трябва да се появи само един от неговите синоними; това представлява прост, но ефективен семантично-контролен механизъм. Провеждаме както количествени, така и качествени оценки, които показват, че генерираните отговори са не само по-качествени, но и отразяват зададените семантични контроли.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Modeli neuronskog kodera-dekodera pokazali su obećavajuću učinku za ljudski kompjuterski dijalog u proteklih nekoliko godina. Međutim, zbog cilja maksimalne vjerojatnosti za dekoder, proizvedeni odgovori su često univerzalni i sigurni u to čki da im nedostaje značajne informacije i više nisu relevantne na postaju. Da bi to riješili, u ovom papiru predlažemo semantičke upute koristeći učenje pojačanja kako bi se osigurali da stvarno proizvedeni odgovori uključuju određene ili predviđene semantike i da se ovi semantici ne pojavljuju ponovno na odgovoru. Sinkronizacije, uključujući setove ručno definiranih sinonima, koriste se kao oblik određenih semantika. Za određeni/određeni/predviđeni sinonim samo jedan od njegovih sinonima treba pojaviti u proizvedenom odgovoru; to predstavlja jednostavan, ali efikasan semantički mehanizam kontrole. Mi vodimo kvantitativne i kvalitativne procjene, koje pokazuju da su proizvedeni odgovori ne samo veći kvalitet, već i odražavaju određene semantičke kontrole.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Neuronale Encoder-Decoder-Modelle haben in den letzten Jahren vielversprechende Leistungen für Mensch-Computer-Dialogsysteme gezeigt. Aufgrund des maximalen Wahrscheinlichkeitsziels für den Decoder sind die generierten Antworten jedoch häufig universell und sicher bis zu dem Punkt, dass ihnen aussagekräftige Informationen fehlen und für den Beitrag nicht mehr relevant sind. Um dies anzugehen, schlagen wir in diesem Beitrag semantische Guidance durch Verstärkungslernen vor, um sicherzustellen, dass die generierten Antworten tatsächlich die gegebene oder vorhergesagte Semantik enthalten und dass diese Semantik nicht wiederholt in der Antwort vorkommt. Synsets, die Sätze von manuell definierten Synonymen umfassen, werden als Form der zugewiesenen Semantik verwendet. Für ein gegebenes/zugewiesenes/vorhergesagtes Synset sollte nur eines seiner Synonyme in der generierten Antwort erscheinen; Dies stellt einen einfachen, aber effektiven semantischen Kontrollmechanismus dar. Wir führen sowohl quantitative als auch qualitative Auswertungen durch, die zeigen, dass die generierten Antworten nicht nur qualitativ hochwertig sind, sondern auch die zugewiesenen semantischen Kontrollen widerspiegeln.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Model pengkode-dekoder saraf telah menunjukkan prestasi yang berjanji untuk sistem dialog manusia-komputer selama beberapa tahun terakhir. Namun, karena tujuan maksimal kemungkinan untuk dekoder, respon yang dihasilkan sering universal dan aman sampai titik bahwa mereka kekurangan informasi yang berarti dan tidak lagi relevan untuk pos. Untuk mengatasi hal ini, dalam kertas ini, kami mengusulkan petunjuk semantis menggunakan pembelajaran pemerintahan untuk memastikan bahwa respon yang dihasilkan benar-benar termasuk semantis yang diberikan atau diprediksi dan bahwa semantis ini tidak muncul berulang kali dalam respon. Sinset, yang mengandung set sinonym yang didefinisikan secara manual, digunakan sebagai bentuk semantik yang ditentukan. Untuk sinset yang diberi/ditugaskan/diprediksi, hanya salah satu sinonymnya harus muncul dalam respon yang dibuat; this constitutes a simple but effective semantic-control mechanism.  Kami melakukan evaluasi kuantitatif dan kualitatif, yang menunjukkan bahwa respon yang dihasilkan tidak hanya kualitas yang lebih tinggi tetapi juga merefleksikan kontrol semantis yang diberikan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>지난 몇 년 동안 신경 인코더-디코더 모형은 인간 대화 시스템에서 좋은 성능을 보였다.그러나 디코더의 가장 큰 유사 목표 때문에 생성된 응답은 보편성과 안전성을 가지기 때문에 의미 있는 정보가 부족하여 게시물과 관련이 없다.이 문제를 해결하기 위해 본고에서 우리는 학습을 강화하는 의미 지도를 사용하여 생성된 응답이 주어지거나 예측된 의미를 포함하고 이런 의미가 응답에 중복되지 않도록 확보했다.문법집은 수동으로 정의된 동의어집으로 구성되어 지정된 의미의 형식으로 쓰인다.주어진/지정/예측된 문법집에 대해 생성된 응답에는 동의어 중 하나만 나타나야 한다.이것은 간단하지만 효과적인 의미 제어 메커니즘을 구성했다.우리는 정량과 정성 평가를 실시했는데 이것은 생성된 응답이 질이 높을 뿐만 아니라 지정된 의미 제어도 반영한 것을 나타낸다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_nl>Neuronale encoder-decoder modellen hebben de afgelopen jaren veelbelovende prestaties getoond voor mens-computer dialoogsystemen. Vanwege de maximale waarschijnlijkheidsdoelstelling voor de decoder zijn de gegenereerde reacties echter vaak universeel en veilig tot het punt dat ze betekenisvolle informatie missen en niet langer relevant zijn voor de post. Om dit aan te pakken, stellen we semantische begeleiding voor met behulp van versterking learning om ervoor te zorgen dat de gegenereerde antwoorden inderdaad de gegeven of voorspelde semantiek bevatten en dat deze semantiek niet herhaaldelijk in de respons voorkomt. Synsets, die sets van handmatig gedefinieerde synoniemen bevatten, worden gebruikt als de vorm van toegewezen semantiek. Voor een gegeven/toegewezen/voorspelde synset mag slechts één van zijn synoniemen in de gegenereerde respons verschijnen; Dit is een eenvoudig maar effectief semantisch controlemechanisme. We voeren zowel kwantitatieve als kwalitatieve evaluaties uit, waaruit blijkt dat de gegenereerde reacties niet alleen kwalitatief hoogstaand zijn, maar ook de toegewezen semantische controles weerspiegelen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_fa>مدل‌های رمزبندی‌کننده‌های عصبی در چند سال گذشته برای سیستم‌های محاورۀ محاورۀ انسان و کامپیوتر اجرا کردند. با این حال، به دلیل هدف بزرگترین احتمال برای دکور، پاسخ‌های پیدا شده اغلب جهانی و امن هستند تا نقطه‌ای که آنها اطلاعات معنی را کم می‌کنند و دیگر به نقطه ارتباطی ندارند. برای حل این کار، در این کاغذ، ما پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که با استفاده از یادگیری تأثیر استفاده کنیم تا مطمئن شویم که پاسخ‌های تولید شده‌ها واقعاً همراه‌های semantics داده یا پیش‌بینی شده‌اند و این semantics هربار در پاسخ ظاهر نمی‌شوند. سینکست‌ساز، که شامل مجموعه‌های سینونیم‌های دستی تعریف شده است، به عنوان شکل سیمانتیک‌های مقرر شده استفاده می‌شوند. برای یک تنظیم مقرر شده/مقرر شده/پیش‌بینی، تنها یکی از تنظیم‌های آن در پاسخ تولید باید ظاهر شود. این یک مکانیسم کنترل semantic ساده اما موثر است. ما هر دو ارزیابی مقداری و کیفیت را انجام می دهیم، که نشان می دهد که پاسخ های تولید فقط کیفیت بالاتر نیست، بلکه همچنین کنترل های طبیعی مقرر شده را نشان می دهیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_da>Neurale encoder-dekoder modeller har vist lovende ydeevne for menneske-computer dialogsystemer i de seneste par år. På grund af dekoderens maksimale sandsynlighedsmål er de genererede svar dog ofte universelle og sikre, så de mangler meningsfulde oplysninger og ikke længere er relevante for indlægget. For at løse dette foreslår vi i denne artikel semantisk vejledning ved hjælp af forstærket læring for at sikre, at de genererede svar faktisk inkluderer den givne eller forudsigede semantik, og at denne semantik ikke optræder gentagne gange i svaret. Synsæt, som omfatter sæt af manuelt definerede synonymer, bruges som form for tildelt semantik. For et givet/tildelt/forventet synsæt bør kun ét af dets synonymer vises i det genererede svar. Dette udgør en enkel, men effektiv semantisk kontrolmekanisme. Vi foretager både kvantitative og kvalitative evalueringer, som viser, at de genererede svar ikke kun er af højere kvalitet, men også afspejler de tildelte semantiske kontroller.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_sw>Mfano wa kodi ya uraia umeonyesha ufanisi wa kuahidini kwa mfumo wa mazungumzo ya kompyuta ya binadamu kwa miaka michache iliyopita. Hata hivyo, kwa sababu ya malengo yenye uwezekano mkubwa kwa kupunguza kiwango hiki, majibu yaliyozaliwa mara nyingi ni ya ulimwengu na salama kwa kusema kwamba hawana taarifa yenye maana na hawana uhusiano tena na makala hiyo. Ili kukabiliana na hili, katika gazeti hili, tunapendekeza uongozi wa kimapenzi kwa kutumia kujifunza kuboresha ili kuhakikisha kwamba majibu yaliyozaliwa kwa hakika yanajumuisha mifano inayopewa au kutabiriwa na kwamba mifumo hii hayataonekana mara kwa mara kwenye majibu. Mitengo, ambayo inajumuisha seti za synonyesha zinazoelezea mikononi, inatumika kama aina ya semantiki zilizowekwa. For a given/assigned/predicted synset, only one of its synonyms should appear in the generated response;  hii inaleta mfumo rahisi lakini wenye ufanisi wa kudhibiti ngono. Tunafanya tathmini za kiasi na kipimo, ambazo zinaonyesha kuwa majibu yaliyozaliwa siyo tu yenye kiwango kikubwa bali pia zinaonyesha udhibiti wa sekunde zilizotolewa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Nöral ködleme modelleri son birnäçe ýyl içinde insan-kompýuter dialoglary üçin söz etýän täsirini görkezilýär. Ýöne, dekoder üçin iň maksimal mümkinçilik maksady sebäbi üretilen jogaplar köplenç uniwersal we amanlyk bilen meňzeş maglumatlaryň ýok bolmagynyň we netijesine degişli däldir. Bu kagyzda çykmak üçin semantik gidişi öngörüp, üretilen jogaplaryň hakykatdanam berilen ýa-da öngörülenen semantikleriň gaýtalanmagyny we bu semantikleriň jogapynda gaýtalanmagyny üçin ulanmagy teklip edýäris. Ellene taniş synonymlaryň düzümlerini, beýleki semantikler ýaly ullanylar. Berilen Bu basit fakat semantik kontrol mekanizmasıdır. Biz hem sanat, hem kaliwatli deňleşik çözümleri çykarýarys. Bu ýagdaýda döredilen jogaplar diňe ýokary kaliwatly däldir, hem beýleki semantik kontrollerini garaşýarys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Modelet e kodifikuesit neuronal kanë treguar performancë premtuese për sistemet e dialogut njerëzor-kompjuter gjatë viteve të fundit. However, due to the maximum-likelihood objective for the decoder, the generated responses are often universal and safe to the point that they lack meaningful information and are no longer relevant to the post.  To address this, in this paper, we propose semantic guidance using reinforcement learning to ensure that the generated responses indeed include the given or predicted semantics and that these semantics do not appear repeatedly in the response.  Synsets, which comprise sets of manually defined synonyms, are used as the form of assigned semantics.  For a given/assigned/predicted synset, only one of its synonyms should appear in the generated response;  this constitutes a simple but effective semantic-control mechanism.  Ne kryejmë si vlerësime kuantitative ashtu edhe kualitative, të cilat tregojnë se përgjigjet e gjeneruara nuk janë vetëm cilësi më e lartë por reflektojnë gjithashtu kontrollin semantik të caktuar.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>ባለፉት ጥቂት ዓመታት ውስጥ የሰው-ኮምፒውተር አካባቢ ጥያቄ የሆኑትን አካባቢ አካባቢ-አካባቢ ምረጡ አሳየዋል፡፡ ምንም እንኳን፣ በክፍለ ክፍተት የሚቻለው አቃውሞ በመስጠት፣ የፍጥረት መልስ ብዙ ጊዜ ዓለምባዊ እና ደኅና ናቸው፡፡ ይህንን ገጽ ለመቀበል፣ የፍጥረት መልስ በተሰጠው ወይም በተቀጠቀጠው የተሰጡትን ወይም በተመለከተው የተሰጡትን ስምናን እንዲያረጋግጥ እና ይህ ተሳካሪዎቹ በጥያቄ እንዳይታሰቡ እናስፈልጋለን፡፡ Synthesizes, which comprise manually defined synonyms, are used as assigned semantics. የተሰጠ/የተቀጠቀጠ/የተቀጠቀጠ ሲንሰሌት፣ አንድ ከሲኒኖቹ ብቻ በተፈጠረ መልስ ሊታይ ይችላል፤ this constitutes a simple but effective semantic-control mechanism.  የፍጥረት መልስ ከፍተኛ ብልሃት ብቻ አይደለም ነገር ግን የተለየውን የስሜት ግንኙነት ደግሞ ያሳያል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Neural encoder-decoder models have shown promising performance for human-computer dialogue systems over the past few years.  Այնուամենայնիվ, դեկոդերի մեծագույն հավանականության օբյեկտիվի պատճառով, ստեղծված պատասխանները հաճախ համընդհանուր են և ապահով, մինչև որ դրանք բացակայում են իմաստալից տեղեկատվություն և այլևս չեն կարևոր տեղադրության համար: To address this, in this paper, we propose semantic guidance using reinforcement learning to ensure that the generated responses indeed include the given or predicted semantics and that these semantics do not appear repeatedly in the response.  Synsets, which comprise sets of manually defined synonyms, are used as the form of assigned semantics.  For a given/assigned/predicted synset, only one of its synonyms should appear in the generated response;  սա պարզ, բայց արդյունավետ սեմանտիկ կառավարման մեխանիզմ է: We conduct both quantitative and qualitative evaluations, which show that the generated responses are not only higher-quality but also reflect the assigned semantic controls.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Nöral koder-dekoder modelləri son neçə il ərzində insan-kompjuter dialogu sistemlərinə vəd verici performans göstərdilər. Lakin, dekoderin maksimum mümkün olaraq məqsədilə, ürəkləndirilmiş cavab çox üniversal və təhlükəsizlik olaraq məlumatı yoxdur və postaya artıq əlaqəsizlər deyildir. Bunu çəkmək üçün, bu kağızda semantik hidayəti təklif edirik ki, ürəkləndirilmiş cavabların həqiqətən verilmiş və ya tədbir edilmiş semantik və bu semantik reaksiyada birdəfə görünməyəcəyini təsdiqləyirik. Əl təyin edilmiş sinonimlərin qurğuları olan sinonimlərin qurğuları, müəyyən edilmiş semantik formu olaraq istifadə edilir. Verilmiş/təyin edilmiş/təmin edilmiş sinonimdən yalnız bir sinonim yaratdığı cavab içində görünmək lazımdır; Bu çox asanlıdır, amma etkili semantik kontrol mehanizmidir. Biz kvantitatlı və qiymətli değerlendirmələri işlədirik ki, ürəkləndirilmiş cavabların yalnız yüksək kaliteli deyil, ancaq müəyyən edilmiş semantik kontrollərini də göstərir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>গত কয়েক বছর ধরে মানব-কম্পিউটার ডায়ালগ সিস্টেমের জন্য প্রতিশ্রুতি প্রদর্শন করা হয়েছে। তবে ডিকোডারের জন্য সর্বোচ্চ সম্ভাব্য উদ্দেশ্যের কারণে তৈরি করা প্রতিক্রিয়া প্রায়শ বিশ্ববিদ্যালয় এবং নিরাপদ যেখানে তাদের কাছে অর্থহীন এই প্রবন্ধে আমরা সেমেন্টিক পরিচালনা করার প্রস্তাব দিচ্ছি যে সৃষ্টির প্রতিক্রিয়া নিশ্চিত করার জন্য বাড়ানো শিক্ষা ব্যবহার করে সেমান্টিক পরিচালনা করা যায় সিনেটগুলো যেগুলো হাতে নির্ধারিত সিনোনিম সম্পূর্ণ সিনোনিমের সেট, নির্ধারিত সেম্যান্টিকের ফর্ম প্রদত্ত প্রতিক্রিয়ার মধ্যে একটি প্রদত্ত/দায়িত্ব/ভবিষ্যদ্বাণী সিনেটের জন্য, তার সিনোনিমের মধ্যে কেবল এটি একটি সাধারণ কিন্তু কার্যকর সেমেন্টিক নিয়ন্ত্রণের মাধ্যম। আমরা উভয়েই পরিমাণ এবং পরিমাণ মূল্যের ব্যবস্থা করি, যা দেখাচ্ছে যে সৃষ্ট প্রতিক্রিয়া শুধুমাত্র উচ্চমান নয়, কিন্তু তারা দায়িত্ব</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Neuralni modeli dekodera pokazali su obećavajuću izvedbu za ljudski kompjuterski dijalog u proteklih nekoliko godina. Međutim, zbog cilja maksimalne vjerojatnosti za dekoder, proizvedeni odgovori su često univerzalni i sigurni u to čki da im nedostaje značajne informacije i više nisu relevantne na postaju. Da bi to riješili, u ovom papiru predlažemo semantičke upute koristeći učenje pojačanja kako bi se osigurali da stvarno proizvedeni odgovori uključuju određene ili predviđene semantike i da se ovi semantici ne pojavljuju ponovno na odgovoru. Sinkronizacije, koje sadrže setove ručno definiranih sinonima, koriste se kao oblik određenih semantika. Za određenu/određenu/predviđenu sinonimu treba pojaviti samo jedan od njegovih sinonima u proizvedenom odgovoru; To je jednostavan, ali efikasan semantički kontrolni mehanizam. Mi vodimo kvantitativne i kvalitativne procjene, koje pokazuju da su proizvedeni odgovori ne samo veći kvalitet, već i odražavaju određene semantičke kontrole.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Els models neurocodificadors han demostrat un desempeny prometedor per als sistemes de diàleg humà-ordinador en els últims anys. Però, degut a l'objectiu de la màxima probabilitat del decodificador, les respostes generades sovint són universals i segures fins que no tenen informació significativa i ja no són pertinents per al post. Per abordar això, en aquest paper proposem orientació semàntica utilitzant l'aprenentatge de reforç per assegurar que les respostes generades inclouen realment la semàntica dada o predida i que aquesta semàntica no apareixi repetidament en la resposta. Els sinsets, que componen conjunts de sinònims definits manualment, s'utilitzen com a forma de semàntica assenyada. Per a un conjunt dado/assenyat/predit, només un dels seus sinonims hauria d'aparèixer en la resposta generada; això és un mecanisme senzill però efectiu de control semàntic. We conduct both quantitative and qualitative evaluations, which show that the generated responses are not only higher-quality but also reflect the assigned semantic controls.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Modely neurálních kodérů a dekodérů prokázaly v posledních letech slibný výkon pro dialogové systémy člověk-počítač. Vzhledem k cíli s maximální pravděpodobností dekodéru jsou generované odpovědi však často univerzální a bezpečné do té míry, že postrádají smysluplné informace a již nejsou relevantní pro daný příspěvek. Abychom to řešili, v tomto článku navrhujeme sémantické pokyny pomocí zesíleného učení, abychom zajistili, že generované odpovědi skutečně obsahují danou nebo předpokládanou sémantiku a že se tato sémantika neobjevuje opakovaně v odpovědi. Synsety, které tvoří množiny ručně definovaných synonymů, se používají jako forma přiřazené sémantiky. U daného/přiřazeného/předpokládaného synsetu by se v generované odpovědi mělo objevit pouze jedno z jeho synonymů; představuje jednoduchý, ale efektivní sémantický kontrolní mechanismus. Provádíme kvantitativní i kvalitativní hodnocení, která ukazují, že generované odpovědi jsou nejen kvalitnější, ale také odrážejí přidělené sémantické kontroly.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_af>Neurale enkoder- dekoder modele het beloftende prestasie vir mens- rekenaar dialoog stelsels in die verlede paar jaar vertoon. Maar, vanweë die maksimum-waarskynlik doel vir die dekoder, is die genereerde antwoordes dikwels universele en veilig tot die punt dat hulle betekenlike inligting ontbreek en nie meer relevant is aan die pos nie. Om dit te adres, in hierdie papier, voorstel ons semantiese gids met die gebruik van versterking leer om te verseker dat die genereerde antwoordes sekerlik die gegewe of voorskoude semantieke inkluit en dat hierdie semantieke nie herhaal in die antwoord verskyn nie. Sinkronisasies, wat bevat stelle van hand gedefinieerde sinonies, word gebruik as die vorm van toegestelde semantieke. Vir 'n gegewe/toegewys/voorskou sinkronisasie moet slegs een van sy sinonime in die gegenereerde antwoord verskyn; Dit is 'n eenvoudige maar effektief semantiese-beheer mekanisme. Ons doen beide kvantitatiewe en kwaliteit evaluasies, wat wys dat die genereerde reaksies nie net hoër-kwaliteit is nie, maar ook reflekteer die aangestelde semantiese kontroles.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_et>Närvikodeerija-dekooderi mudelid on viimastel aastatel näidanud inimese-arvuti dialoogisüsteemide jaoks paljulubavat jõudlust. Dekooderi maksimaalse tõenäosuse eesmärgi tõttu on loodud vastused sageli universaalsed ja ohutud, kuni neil puudub sisuline teave ega ole enam ametikoha jaoks asjakohased. Selle lahendamiseks pakume käesolevas dokumendis välja semantilised juhised tugevdamisõppe abil, et tagada, et genereeritud vastused sisaldavad tõepoolest antud või prognoositud semantikat ja et need semantika ei ilmu vastuses korduvalt. Määratud semantika vormina kasutatakse käsitsi määratletud sünonüümide hulka kuuluvaid sünonüüme. Antud/määratud/prognoositud sünkronismi puhul peaks genereeritud vastuses olema ainult üks selle sünonüümidest; see kujutab endast lihtsat, kuid tõhusat semantilise kontrolli mehhanismi. Teostame nii kvantitatiivseid kui ka kvalitatiivseid hinnanguid, mis näitavad, et genereeritud vastused ei ole mitte ainult kvaliteetsemad, vaid peegeldavad ka määratud semantilisi kontrolle.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Neurokooderi-dekooderimallit ovat osoittaneet lupaavaa suorituskykyä ihmisen ja tietokoneen dialogijärjestelmille viime vuosina. Koska dekooderin todennäköisyystavoite on mahdollisimman suuri, saadut vastaukset ovat usein yleismaailmallisia ja turvallisia siinä määrin, että niistä puuttuu merkityksellistä tietoa eivätkä ole enää merkityksellisiä toimen kannalta. Tämän vuoksi ehdotamme tässä artikkelissa semanttista ohjausta vahvistamalla oppimista varmistaaksemme, että luodut vastaukset todella sisältävät annetun tai ennustetun semantiikan ja että nämä semantiikka ei näy toistuvasti vastauksessa. Synteettiset, jotka koostuvat manuaalisesti määriteltyjen synonyymien joukoista, käytetään määritetyn semantiikan muotona. Tietylle/määritetylle/ennustetulle synonyymille vain yksi synonyymi tulisi näkyä luodussa vastauksessa; Tämä on yksinkertainen mutta tehokas semanttinen ohjausmekanismi. Teemme sekä kvantitatiivisia että kvalitatiivisia arviointeja, jotka osoittavat, että saadut vastaukset eivät ole ainoastaan laadukkaampia, vaan heijastavat myös annettuja semanttisia kontrolleja.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>Modeli živčnih kodirnikov-dekoderjev so v zadnjih nekaj letih pokazali obetavno zmogljivost za dialogne sisteme med človekom in računalnikom. Vendar pa so zaradi cilja največje verjetnosti za dekoder ustvarjeni odzivi pogosto univerzalni in varni do točke, da nimajo smiselnih informacij in niso več pomembni za delovno mesto. Za obravnavo tega v tem prispevku predlagamo semantično usmerjanje z uporabo ojačitvenega učenja, da bi zagotovili, da ustvarjeni odzivi dejansko vključujejo dano ali predvideno semantiko in da se ti semantiki ne pojavljajo večkrat v odzivu. Sinfoni, ki sestavljajo nabore ročno določenih sinonimov, se uporabljajo kot oblika dodeljene semantike. Za dano/dodeljeno/predvideno sinonim se mora v ustvarjenem odzivu pojaviti samo eden od njegovih sinonimov; to je preprost, vendar učinkovit semantični nadzorni mehanizem. Izvajamo kvantitativne in kvalitativne ocene, ki kažejo, da generirani odzivi niso le kakovostnejši, temveč odražajo tudi dodeljene semantične kontrole.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>@ info: whatsthis A lokacin da aka yiwo amfani da wajen kodi, juwãsi da aka ƙãga, za'a iya amfani da su a cikin jumla'a ko da kuma ba su da amfani da jumla ba. To, in karanta wannan, cikin wannan takarda, Munã buɗa shiryarwa na semanti da za mu yi amfani da ƙaranci da learning dõmin ka tabbatar da cewa masu jayayar da aka ƙãga, lalle ne su suna cikin ana ba da ko da ake yi wa jinkiri, kuma ba za mu sami wannan semantiki ba da sauri ba. @ info: whatsthis Ji da wani shirin/da aka ƙayyade/wanda aka ƙayyade, sai wani daga sunoninsa ya fito a cikin jibar da aka ƙãga; this constitutes a simple but effective semantic-control mechanism.  Munã aiki da rabon ƙaddara da gwantive, wanda ke nũna cewa majiɓintan da aka ƙãga, ba su zama masu sarki ba kawai kuma amma suna ƙayyade domin tarakin da aka raba.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>model de 'decoder' politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Ngawe Perintah iki ning acara, ning kelas iki, kita supoyo semanti nggawe ngubah tindakan tentang kanggo ngerasai winih dhéwé kuwi mau sing apik dhéwé uga ngerasai semanti sing apik dhéwé lan alam sing apik dhéwé. Sample rate Sample rate Punika dipunangé sistem sing paling semanti-kuwi nguasakno. Awak dhéwé éntuk kaliterasi lan akeh cara-teka, lan akeh iso nggawe barang langgar tarjamahan sing apik dhéwé kuwi nggawe kaliterasi luwih apik dhéwé, ngono nggawe nguasai kontrol sematik nggawe</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>ནུས་མེད་ཀྱི་སྒེར་གྱི་རྩིས་འཁོར་གྱི་མ་དབྱེ་བ་དག་གིས་མིའི་གྲངས་སྤྱོད་ཆས་མངོན་གསལ་འཆར་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ཡིན་ནའང་། གསལ་བཤེར་གྱི་དམིགས་ཡུལ་ཆེ་ཤོས་ཀྱི་རྒྱུ་མཚན་ནི། གསར་བསྐྲུན་ཡོད་པའི་ལན་གསལ་ཚུ་ཡང་ཆེན་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་དང་བདེ་སྐྱོང་བ་ཡིན་པས་ཁོང་ཚ འདི་ལྟ་བུ་བཤད་ན། ཤོག་བུ་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོས་རྒྱུན་ལྡན་གྱི་འགོ་བཙུགས་སྟངས་ལ་སྔོན་བསྐྱེད་པའི་སྐད་འགན་སྤྲོད་རྒྱུ་དང་། སྔོན་སྒྲིག་བྱ་ཚིག་ལ་ལག་ཐོག་དམིགས་འཛུགས་ཀྱི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་ཚོ་ཡི་གྲངས་སྒྲིག་ཚུ། བྱིན་ཡོད་པ་དང་དམིགས་འཛུགས་ཀྱི་སྔོན་སྒྲིག དེ་ནི་སླ་བོ་ཞིག་དག་ལག་ལེན་ཐབས་ལམ་ཞིག་ལས་སླ་བོ་ཞིག་རེད། ང་ཚོས་གྲངས་འབོར</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>דוגמני קודד-קידור נוירואלים הראו ביצועים מבטיחים למערכות דיאלוג בני אדם-מחשב במהלך השנים האחרונות. בכל אופן, בגלל המטרה של הסיכוי המקסימלי עבור הפיתוח, התגובות המיוצרות הן לעתים קרובות אוניברסליות ובטוחות עד הנקודה שהם חסרים מידע משמעותי ולא יותר רלוונטיים לתפקיד. כדי להתמודד עם זה, בעיתון הזה, אנו מציעים כיוון סמנטי באמצעות לימוד גיבוי כדי להבטיח שהתגובות המיוצרות באמת כוללות את הסמנטיקה הנתונה או צפויה ולא שהסמנטיקה הזאת מופיעה שוב ושוב בתגובה. Synsets, which comprise sets of manually defined synonyms, are used as the form of assigned semantics.  For a given/assigned/predicted synset, only one of its synonyms should appear in the generated response;  this constitutes a simple but effective semantic-control mechanism.  אנו מבצעים גם ערכות כיוותיות וגם איכותיות, אשר מראות שהתגובות המיוצרות לא רק איכות גבוהה יותר, אלא גם משקפים את השליטה הסמנטית המסוגרת.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>TripPy : A Triple Copy Strategy for Value Independent Neural Dialog State Tracking<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>rip<fixed-case>P</fixed-case>y: A Triple Copy Strategy for Value Independent Neural Dialog State Tracking</title>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Heck</last></author>
      <author><first>Carel</first><last>van Niekerk</last></author>
      <author><first>Nurul</first><last>Lubis</last></author>
      <author><first>Christian</first><last>Geishauser</last></author>
      <author><first>Hsien-Chin</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Marco</first><last>Moresi</last></author>
      <author><first>Milica</first><last>Gasic</last></author>
      <pages>35–44</pages>
      <abstract>Task-oriented dialog systems rely on dialog state tracking (DST) to monitor the user’s goal during the course of an interaction. Multi-domain and open-vocabulary settings complicate the task considerably and demand scalable solutions. In this paper we present a new approach to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discrete_cosine_transform">DST</a> which makes use of various copy mechanisms to fill slots with values. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> has no need to maintain a list of candidate values. Instead, all values are extracted from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context_(computing)">dialog context</a> on-the-fly. A slot is filled by one of three copy mechanisms : (1) Span prediction may extract values directly from the user input ; (2) a value may be copied from a system inform memory that keeps track of the system’s inform operations (3) a value may be copied over from a different slot that is already contained in the dialog state to resolve coreferences within and across domains. Our approach combines the advantages of span-based slot filling methods with memory methods to avoid the use of value picklists altogether. We argue that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy">strategy</a> simplifies the DST task while at the same time achieving state of the art performance on various popular evaluation sets including Multiwoz 2.1, where we achieve a joint goal accuracy beyond 55 %.</abstract>
      <url hash="39b9202b">2020.sigdial-1.4</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=qWLnp4tPbPM" />
      <bibkey>heck-etal-2020-trippy</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/multiwoz">MultiWOZ</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>MC-Saar-Instruct : a Platform for Minecraft Instruction Giving Agents<fixed-case>MC</fixed-case>-Saar-Instruct: a Platform for <fixed-case>M</fixed-case>inecraft Instruction Giving Agents</title>
      <author><first>Arne</first><last>Köhn</last></author>
      <author><first>Julia</first><last>Wichlacz</last></author>
      <author><first>Christine</first><last>Schäfer</last></author>
      <author><first>Álvaro</first><last>Torralba</last></author>
      <author><first>Joerg</first><last>Hoffmann</last></author>
      <author><first>Alexander</first><last>Koller</last></author>
      <pages>53–56</pages>
      <abstract>We present a comprehensive platform to run <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human–computer_interaction">human-computer experiments</a> where an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intelligent_agent">agent</a> instructs a human in Minecraft, a 3D blocksworld environment. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computing_platform">platform</a> enables comparisons between different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intelligent_agent">agents</a> by matching users to agents. It performs extensive logging and takes care of all boilerplate, allowing to easily incorporate new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intelligent_agent">agents</a> to evaluate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intelligent_agent">them</a>. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Environment_(systems)">environment</a> is prepared to evaluate any kind of instruction giving system, recording the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interaction">interaction</a> and all actions of the user. We provide example <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Architect">architects</a>, a Wizard-of-Oz architect and set-up scripts to automatically download, build and start the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computing_platform">platform</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="649a092c">2020.sigdial-1.7</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=ipGAj_qLXz4" />
      <bibkey>kohn-etal-2020-mc</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Identifying Collaborative Conversations using Latent Discourse Behaviors</title>
      <author><first>Ayush</first><last>Jain</last></author>
      <author><first>Maria Leonor</first><last>Pacheco</last></author>
      <author><first>Steven</first><last>Lancette</last></author>
      <author><first>Mahak</first><last>Goindani</last></author>
      <author><first>Dan</first><last>Goldwasser</last></author>
      <pages>74–78</pages>
      <abstract>In this work, we study collaborative online conversations. Such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversation">conversations</a> are rich in content, constructive and motivated by a shared goal. Automatically identifying such conversations requires modeling complex discourse behaviors, which characterize the flow of information, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentimentality">sentiment</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Community_structure">community structure</a> within discussions. To help capture these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior">behaviors</a>, we define a hybrid relational model in which relevant discourse behaviors are formulated as discrete latent variables and scored using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_network">neural networks</a>. These <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variable_(mathematics)">variables</a> provide the information needed for predicting the overall collaborative characterization of the entire conversational thread. We show that adding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inductive_bias">inductive bias</a> in the form of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latent_variable">latent variables</a> results in performance improvement, while providing a natural way to explain the decision.</abstract>
      <url hash="99f84b81">2020.sigdial-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>jain-etal-2020-identifying</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Learning and Reasoning for Robot Dialog and Navigation Tasks</title>
      <author><first>Keting</first><last>Lu</last></author>
      <author><first>Shiqi</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Peter</first><last>Stone</last></author>
      <author><first>Xiaoping</first><last>Chen</last></author>
      <pages>107–117</pages>
      <abstract>Reinforcement learning and probabilistic reasoning algorithms aim at learning from interaction experiences and reasoning with probabilistic contextual knowledge respectively. In this research, we develop <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithms</a> for robot task completions, while looking into the complementary strengths of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning">reinforcement learning</a> and probabilistic reasoning techniques. The robots learn from trial-and-error experiences to augment their declarative knowledge base, and the augmented knowledge can be used for speeding up the learning process in potentially different tasks. We have implemented and evaluated the developed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithms</a> using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_robot">mobile robots</a> conducting dialog and navigation tasks. From the results, we see that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robot">robot</a>’s performance can be improved by both reasoning with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge">human knowledge</a> and learning from task-completion experience. More interestingly, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robot">robot</a> was able to learn from navigation tasks to improve its dialog strategies.</abstract>
      <url hash="f3873d64">2020.sigdial-1.14</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=KS4LPkdFyBU" />
      <revision id="1" href="2020.sigdial-1.14v1" hash="681a0ae1" />
      <revision id="2" href="2020.sigdial-1.14v2" hash="f3873d64" date="2020-09-08">A sponsor was removed from the Acknowledgments section.</revision>
      <bibkey>lu-etal-2020-learning</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>An Attentive Listening System with Android ERICA : Comparison of Autonomous and WOZ Interactions<fixed-case>ERICA</fixed-case>: Comparison of Autonomous and <fixed-case>WOZ</fixed-case> Interactions</title>
      <author><first>Koji</first><last>Inoue</last></author>
      <author><first>Divesh</first><last>Lala</last></author>
      <author><first>Kenta</first><last>Yamamoto</last></author>
      <author><first>Shizuka</first><last>Nakamura</last></author>
      <author><first>Katsuya</first><last>Takanashi</last></author>
      <author><first>Tatsuya</first><last>Kawahara</last></author>
      <pages>118–127</pages>
      <abstract>We describe an attentive listening system for the autonomous android robot ERICA. The proposed system generates several types of listener responses : backchannels, repeats, elaborating questions, assessments, generic sentimental responses, and generic responses. In this paper, we report a subjective experiment with 20 elderly people. First, we evaluated each system utterance excluding backchannels and generic responses, in an offline manner. It was found that most of the system utterances were linguistically appropriate, and they elicited positive reactions from the subjects. Furthermore, 58.2 % of the responses were acknowledged as being appropriate listener responses. We also compared the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> with a WOZ system where a human operator was operating the robot. From the subjective evaluation, the proposed system achieved comparable scores in basic skills of attentive listening such as encouragement to talk, focused on the talk, and actively listening. It was also found that there is still a gap between the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> and the WOZ for more sophisticated skills such as dialogue understanding, showing interest, and empathy towards the user.</abstract>
      <url hash="7bcad570">2020.sigdial-1.15</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=Ds4LiqSh_EA" />
      <bibkey>inoue-etal-2020-attentive</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>Discovering Knowledge Graph Schema from Short Natural Language Text via Dialog</title>
      <author><first>Subhasis</first><last>Ghosh</last></author>
      <author><first>Arpita</first><last>Kundu</last></author>
      <author><first>Aniket</first><last>Pramanick</last></author>
      <author><first>Indrajit</first><last>Bhattacharya</last></author>
      <pages>136–146</pages>
      <abstract>We study the problem of schema discovery for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_graph">knowledge graphs</a>. We propose a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solution">solution</a> where an agent engages in multi-turn dialog with an expert for this purpose. Each mini-dialog focuses on a short natural language statement, and looks to elicit the expert’s desired schema-based interpretation of that statement, taking into account possible augmentations to the schema. The overall schema evolves by performing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue">dialog</a> over a collection of such statements. We take into account the probability that the expert does not respond to a query, and model this probability as a function of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_complexity_theory">complexity</a> of the query. For such mini-dialogs with response uncertainty, we propose a dialog strategy that looks to elicit the schema over as short a dialog as possible. By combining the notion of uncertainty sampling from active learning with generalized binary search, the strategy asks the query with the highest expected reduction of entropy. We show that this significantly reduces dialog complexity while engaging the expert in meaningful dialog.</abstract>
      <url hash="ab21813f">2020.sigdial-1.18</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=OD_c-tim8JI" />
      <bibkey>ghosh-etal-2020-discovering</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>User Impressions of Questions to Acquire Lexical Knowledge</title>
      <author><first>Kazunori</first><last>Komatani</last></author>
      <author><first>Mikio</first><last>Nakano</last></author>
      <pages>147–156</pages>
      <abstract>For the acquisition of knowledge through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue">dialogues</a>, it is crucial for systems to ask questions that do not diminish the user’s willingness to talk, i.e., that do not degrade the user’s impression. This paper reports the results of our analysis on how user impression changes depending on the types of questions to acquire lexical knowledge, that is, explicit and implicit questions, and the correctness of the content of the questions. We also analyzed how sequences of the same type of questions affect <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_experience">user impression</a>. User impression scores were collected from 104 participants recruited via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crowdsourcing">crowdsourcing</a> and then <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_analysis">regression analysis</a> was conducted. The results demonstrate that implicit questions give a good impression when their content is correct, but a bad impression otherwise. We also found that consecutive explicit questions are more annoying than implicit ones when the content of the questions is correct. Our findings reveal helpful insights for creating a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy">strategy</a> to avoid user impression deterioration during <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_acquisition">knowledge acquisition</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="b4a55b09">2020.sigdial-1.19</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=-i9XnHcoIRc" />
      <bibkey>komatani-nakano-2020-user</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Simulating Turn-Taking in Conversations with Delayed Transmission</title>
      <author><first>Thilo</first><last>Michael</last></author>
      <author><first>Sebastian</first><last>Möller</last></author>
      <pages>157–161</pages>
      <abstract>Conversations over the telephone require timely turn-taking cues that signal the participants when to speak and when to listen. When a two-way transmission delay is introduced into such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversation">conversations</a>, the immediate feedback is delayed, and the interactivity of the conversation is impaired. With <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delayed_speech">delayed speech</a> on each side of the transmission, different conversation realities emerge on both ends, which alters the way the participants interact with each other. Simulating conversations can give insights on turn-taking and spoken interactions between humans but can also used for analyzing and even predicting human behavior in conversations. In this paper, we simulate two types of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversation">conversations</a> with distinct levels of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactivity">interactivity</a>. We then introduce three levels of two-way transmission delay between the agents and compare the resulting interaction-patterns with human-to-human dialog from an empirical study. We show how the turn-taking mechanisms modeled for conversations without delay perform in scenarios with delay and identify to which extend the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulation">simulation</a> is able to model the delayed turn-taking observed in human conversation.</abstract>
      <url hash="816d6543">2020.sigdial-1.20</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=9jerzgGw0pY" />
      <bibkey>michael-moller-2020-simulating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Is this Dialogue Coherent? Learning from Dialogue Acts and Entities</title>
      <author><first>Alessandra</first><last>Cervone</last></author>
      <author><first>Giuseppe</first><last>Riccardi</last></author>
      <pages>162–174</pages>
      <abstract>In this work, we investigate the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coherence_(linguistics)">human perception of coherence</a> in open-domain dialogues. In particular, we address the problem of annotating and modeling the coherence of next-turn candidates while considering the entire history of the dialogue. First, we create the Switchboard Coherence (SWBD-Coh) corpus, a dataset of human-human spoken dialogues annotated with turn coherence ratings, where next-turn candidate utterances ratings are provided considering the full dialogue context. Our statistical analysis of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a> indicates how turn coherence perception is affected by patterns of distribution of entities previously introduced and the Dialogue Acts used. Second, we experiment with different architectures to model entities, Dialogue Acts and their combination and evaluate their performance in predicting human coherence ratings on SWBD-Coh. We find that models combining both DA and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entity–relationship_model">entity information</a> yield the best performances both for response selection and turn coherence rating.</abstract>
      <url hash="d62102f6">2020.sigdial-1.21</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=IIcHVI9Kc0Y" />
      <bibkey>cervone-riccardi-2020-dialogue</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/alecervi/switchboard-coherence-corpus" additional="true">alecervi/switchboard-coherence-corpus</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>Contextualized Emotion Recognition in Conversation as Sequence Tagging</title>
      <author><first>Yan</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Jiayu</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Jun</first><last>Ma</last></author>
      <author><first>Shaojun</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Jing</first><last>Xiao</last></author>
      <pages>186–195</pages>
      <abstract>Emotion recognition in conversation (ERC) is an important topic for developing empathetic machines in a variety of areas including social opinion mining, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Health_care">health-care</a> and so on. In this paper, we propose a method to model ERC task as sequence tagging where a Conditional Random Field (CRF) layer is leveraged to learn the emotional consistency in the conversation. We employ LSTM-based encoders that capture self and inter-speaker dependency of interlocutors to generate contextualized utterance representations which are fed into the CRF layer. For capturing long-range global context, we use a multi-layer Transformer encoder to enhance the LSTM-based encoder. Experiments show that our method benefits from modeling the emotional consistency and outperforms the current state-of-the-art methods on multiple emotion classification datasets.</abstract>
      <url hash="6416ca30">2020.sigdial-1.23</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=1PH6JXbc3EI" />
      <bibkey>wang-etal-2020-contextualized</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/dailydialog">DailyDialog</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/iemocap">IEMOCAP</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/meld">MELD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="31">
      <title>Agent-Based Dynamic Collaboration Support in a Smart Office Space</title>
      <author><first>Yansen</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>R. Charles</first><last>Murray</last></author>
      <author><first>Haogang</first><last>Bao</last></author>
      <author><first>Carolyn</first><last>Rose</last></author>
      <pages>257–260</pages>
      <abstract>For the past 15 years, in computer-supported collaborative learning applications, conversational agents have been used to structure group interactions in online chat-based environments. A series of experimental studies has provided an empirical foundation for the design of chat-based conversational agents that significantly improve learning over no-support control conditions and static-support control conditions. In this demo, we expand upon this foundation, bringing conversational agents to structure group interaction into physical spaces, with the specific goal of facilitating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collaboration">collaboration</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning">learning</a> in workplace scenarios.</abstract>
      <url hash="8d12f903">2020.sigdial-1.31</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=3uC3ZJSL2Xc" />
      <bibkey>wang-etal-2020-agent</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="34">
      <title>A Sequence-to-sequence Approach for Numerical Slot-filling Dialog Systems</title>
      <author><first>Hongjie</first><last>Shi</last></author>
      <pages>272–277</pages>
      <abstract>Dialog systems capable of filling slots with numerical values have wide applicability to many task-oriented applications. In this paper, we perform a particular case study on the number_of_guests slot-filling in hotel reservation domain, and propose two methods to improve current dialog system model on 1. numerical reasoning performance by training the model to predict arithmetic expressions, and 2. multi-turn question generation by introducing additional context slots. Furthermore, because the proposed methods are all based on an end-to-end trainable sequence-to-sequence (seq2seq) neural model, it is possible to achieve further performance improvement on increasing dialog logs in the future.</abstract>
      <url hash="e62fb03c">2020.sigdial-1.34</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=p8cvYEjct5g" />
      <bibkey>shi-2020-sequence</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="38">
      <title>Similarity Scoring for Dialogue Behaviour Comparison</title>
      <author><first>Stefan</first><last>Ultes</last></author>
      <author><first>Wolfgang</first><last>Maier</last></author>
      <pages>311–322</pages>
      <abstract>The differences in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision-making">decision making</a> between behavioural models of voice interfaces are hard to capture using existing measures for the absolute performance of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a>. For instance, two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> may have a similar task success rate, but very different ways of getting there. In this paper, we propose a general <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methodology</a> to compute the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Similarity_measure">similarity</a> of two dialogue behaviour models and investigate different ways of computing scores on both the semantic and the textual level. Complementing absolute measures of performance, we test our scores on three different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a> and show the practical usability of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Measurement">measures</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="84acdb32">2020.sigdial-1.38</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=zs0yOpHWBf8" />
      <bibkey>ultes-maier-2020-similarity</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="39">
      <title>Collection and Analysis of Dialogues Provided by Two Speakers Acting as One</title>
      <author><first>Tsunehiro</first><last>Arimoto</last></author>
      <author><first>Ryuichiro</first><last>Higashinaka</last></author>
      <author><first>Kou</first><last>Tanaka</last></author>
      <author><first>Takahito</first><last>Kawanishi</last></author>
      <author><first>Hiroaki</first><last>Sugiyama</last></author>
      <author><first>Hiroshi</first><last>Sawada</last></author>
      <author><first>Hiroshi</first><last>Ishiguro</last></author>
      <pages>323–328</pages>
      <abstract>We are studying a cooperation style where multiple speakers can provide both advanced dialogue services and operator education. We focus on a style in which two operators interact with a user by pretending to be a single operator. For two operators to effectively act as one, each must adjust his / her conversational content and timing to the other. In the process, we expect each operator to experience the conversational content of his / her partner as if it were his / her own, creating efficient and effective learning of the other’s skill. We analyzed this educational effect and examined whether dialogue services can be successfully provided by collecting travel guidance dialogue data from operators who give travel information to users. In this paper, we report our preliminary results on dialogue content and user satisfaction of operators and users.</abstract>
      <url hash="18cb50ab">2020.sigdial-1.39</url>
      <video href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=hFIHx-PqzDE" />
      <bibkey>arimoto-etal-2020-collection</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>