<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.nuse">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2020-06-21">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the First Joint Workshop on Narrative Understanding, Storylines, and Events</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Claire</first><last>Bonial</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Tommaso</first><last>Caselli</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Snigdha</first><last>Chaturvedi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Clark</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ruihong</first><last>Huang</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mohit</first><last>Iyyer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alejandro</first><last>Jaimes</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Heng</first><last>Ji</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Lara J.</first><last>Martin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ben</first><last>Miller</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Teruko</first><last>Mitamura</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nanyun</first><last>Peng</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Joel</first><last>Tetreault</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>July</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <url hash="9075bb72">2020.nuse-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="16e67b2a">2020.nuse-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nuse-2020-joint</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Improving the Identification of the Discourse Function of News Article Paragraphs</title>
      <author><first>Deya</first><last>Banisakher</last></author>
      <author><first>W. Victor</first><last>Yarlott</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammed</first><last>Aldawsari</last></author>
      <author><first>Naphtali</first><last>Rishe</last></author>
      <author><first>Mark</first><last>Finlayson</last></author>
      <pages>17–25</pages>
      <abstract>Identifying the discourse structure of documents is an important task in understanding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writing">written text</a>. Building on prior work, we demonstrate an improved approach to automatically identifying the discourse function of paragraphs in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Article_(publishing)">news articles</a>. We start with the hierarchical theory of news discourse developed by van Dijk (1988) which proposes how paragraphs function within <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Article_(publishing)">news articles</a>. This discourse information is a level intermediate between phrase- or sentence-sized discourse segments and document genre, characterizing how individual paragraphs convey information about the events in the storyline of the article. Specifically, the theory categorizes the relationships between narrated events and (1) the overall storyline (such as Main Events, Background, or Consequences) as well as (2) commentary (such as Verbal Reactions and Evaluations). We trained and tested a linear chain conditional random field (CRF) with new features to model van Dijk’s labels and compared it against several machine learning models presented in previous work. Our model significantly outperformed all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baselines</a> and prior approaches, achieving an average of 0.71 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-number">F1 score</a> which represents a 31.5 % improvement over the previously best-performing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Support_vector_machine">support vector machine model</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="f4f0aef0">2020.nuse-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nuse-1.3</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929742" />
      <bibkey>banisakher-etal-2020-improving</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Extensively Matching for Few-shot Learning Event Detection</title>
      <author><first>Viet Dac</first><last>Lai</last></author>
      <author><first>Thien Huu</first><last>Nguyen</last></author>
      <author><first>Franck</first><last>Dernoncourt</last></author>
      <pages>38–45</pages>
      <abstract>Current event detection models under supervised learning settings fail to transfer to new event types. Few-shot learning has not been explored in event detection even though it allows a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> to perform well with high <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generalization">generalization</a> on new event types. In this work, we formulate event detection as a few-shot learning problem to enable to extend event detection to new event types. We propose two novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loss_factor">loss factors</a> that matching examples in the support set to provide more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training signals</a> to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a>. Moreover, these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Training,_validation,_and_test_sets">training signals</a> can be applied in many metric-based few-shot learning models. Our extensive experiments on the ACE-2005 dataset (under a few-shot learning setting) show that the proposed method can improve the performance of few-shot learning.</abstract>
      <url hash="adf9c622">2020.nuse-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nuse-1.5</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929744" />
      <bibkey>lai-etal-2020-extensively</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Annotating and quantifying narrative time disruptions in modernist and hypertext fiction</title>
      <author><first>Edward</first><last>Kearns</last></author>
      <pages>72–77</pages>
      <abstract>This paper outlines work in progress on a new method of annotating and quantitatively discussing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Narrative">narrative techniques</a> related to time in fiction. Specifically those techniques are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analepsis">analepsis</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prolepsis">prolepsis</a>, narrative level changes, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stream_of_consciousness">stream-of-consciousness</a> and free-indirect-discourse narration. By counting the frequency and extent of the usage of these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_narrative_techniques">techniques</a>, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Narrative">narrative characteristics</a> of different works from different time periods and genres can be compared. This project uses <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Literary_modernism">modernist fiction</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_fiction">hypertext fiction</a> as its case studies.</abstract>
      <url hash="54dba309">2020.nuse-1.9</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nuse-1.9</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929748" />
      <bibkey>kearns-2020-annotating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Exploring aspects of similarity between spoken personal narratives by disentangling them into narrative clause types</title>
      <author><first>Belen</first><last>Saldias</last></author>
      <author><first>Deb</first><last>Roy</last></author>
      <pages>78–86</pages>
      <abstract>Sharing personal narratives is a fundamental aspect of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_behavior">human social behavior</a> as it helps share our life experiences. We can tell stories and rely on our background to understand their context, similarities, and differences. A substantial effort has been made towards developing storytelling machines or inferring characters’ features. However, we do n’t usually find <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> that compare narratives. This task is remarkably challenging for machines since they, as sometimes we do, lack an understanding of what similarity means. To address this challenge, we first introduce a corpus of real-world spoken personal narratives comprising 10,296 narrative clauses from 594 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Videotape">video transcripts</a>. Second, we ask non-narrative experts to annotate those clauses under Labov’s sociolinguistic model of personal narratives (i.e., action, orientation, and evaluation clause types) and train a classifier that reaches 84.7 % F-score for the highest-agreed clauses. Finally, we match stories and explore whether people implicitly rely on Labov’s framework to compare narratives. We show that actions followed by the narrator’s evaluation of these are the aspects non-experts consider the most. Our approach is intended to help inform <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">machine learning methods</a> aimed at studying or representing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_narrative">personal narratives</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="64dc1ef4">2020.nuse-1.10</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nuse-1.10</doi>
      <video href="https://slideslive.com/38939705" />
      <bibkey>saldias-roy-2020-exploring</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/social-machines/acl-nuse-personal-narratives" additional="false">social-machines/acl-nuse-personal-narratives</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/rtn">RTN</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>استكشاف جوانب التشابه بين الروايات الشخصية المنطوقة من خلال فصلها في أنواع الجمل السردية</title_ar>
      <title_es>Explorar aspectos de similitud entre las narrativas personales habladas al desentrañarlas en tipos de cláusulas narrativas</title_es>
      <title_pt>Explorando aspectos de semelhança entre narrativas pessoais faladas, separando-as em tipos de orações narrativas</title_pt>
      <title_ja>話されている個人的な物語の類似性の側面を、物語の条項タイプに分離することによって探求する</title_ja>
      <title_zh>因口语人述离为叙述性子句类以求其相似性</title_zh>
      <title_hi>बोले गए व्यक्तिगत आख्यानों के बीच समानता के पहलुओं की खोज करते हुए उन्हें कथा खंड प्रकारों में विभाजित करके</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Iniúchadh ar ghnéithe cosúlachta idir scéalta pearsanta labhartha trí iad a dhícheangal i gcineálacha clásail insinte</title_ga>
      <title_ka>სხვადასხვა ასპექტების განსხვავება განსხვავებული პირადასხვა სიტყვების შორის გამოყენება, რომელიც ისინი განსხვავებული სიტყვების ტიპში</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A beszélt személyes narratívák hasonlóságának aspektusainak feltárása narratív záradéktípusokba való bontásával</title_hu>
      <title_el>Εξερεύνηση πτυχών ομοιότητας μεταξύ προφορικών προσωπικών αφηγήσεων μέσω της αποσύνδεσης τους σε τύπους αφηγηματικών ρητρών</title_el>
      <title_it>Esplorare aspetti di somiglianza tra narrazioni personali parlate districandole in tipi di clausole narrative</title_it>
      <title_kk>Оларды түсінікті түсініктер түрлеріне айналысып</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Истражување на аспектите на сличноста помеѓу говорените лични раскажувања со нивното развлекување во типови на раскажувачки клаузули</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Išnagrinėti asmeninių kalbų panašumo aspektus, išskiriant juos į narracinių sąlygų tipus</title_lt>
      <title_ml>സംസാരിക്കപ്പെട്ട വ്യക്തിപരമായ കഥകള്‍ക്കിടയിലുള്ള ഒരേപോലെയുള്ള ഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ വിശദീകരിക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Хүмүүсийн зохиолуудын хоорондын адилхан хэсгийг судалж өгүүлж</title_mn>
      <title_ms>Exploring aspects of similarity between spoken personal narratives by disentangling them into narrative clause types</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Exploring aspects of similarity between spoken personal narratives by disentangling them into narrative clause types</title_mt>
      <title_pl>Badanie aspektów podobieństwa mówionych narracji osobistych poprzez rozłączenie ich na typy klauzul narracyjnych</title_pl>
      <title_no>Utforskar aspektar av likheten mellom tale personlege narrativ ved å forstørra dei i taletypar</title_no>
      <title_ro>Explorarea aspectelor similarității dintre narațiunile personale vorbite prin dezlegarea lor în tipuri de clauze narative</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Istražujući aspekte sličnosti između govornih ličnih priča, odbacujući ih u vrste priče.</title_sr>
      <title_ta>பேசும் தனிப்பட்ட வரலாறுகளுக்கிடையில் ஒத்திசைப்பாடு</title_ta>
      <title_sv>Utforska aspekter av likhet mellan talade personliga berättelser genom att koppla upp dem i narrativa satser typer</title_sv>
      <title_si>කතා කරපු පෞද්ගලික කතාවක් අතර සමාන වර්ගයක් විශ්වාස කරනවා එයාලව කතාවක් වර්ගයක් වලට අතරින්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Ka baaraandegista dhinacyada siman ee sheekooyinka shakhsiyadda la hadlay si ay u baaraandegiso noocyada qoraalka ah</title_so>
      <title_ur>بات کی شخصی کہانیاں کے درمیان برابری کے منحصروں کو تحقیق کر رہا ہے کہ ان کو داستان کلاس کے طریقوں میں ناپھیر دیتے ہیں</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Talab qilingan shaxsiy tarixilar orasidagi bir xil qismlarni o'zgartirish</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Khám phá các khía cạnh của sự giống nhau giữa những lời kể cá nhân bằng cách chia chúng thành các kiểu mô tả.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Изследване на аспектите на сходството между говорените лични разкази чрез разгръщане им в типове разказни клаузи</title_bg>
      <title_da>Udforske aspekter af lighed mellem talte personlige fortællinger ved at adskille dem i narrative sætningstyper</title_da>
      <title_hr>Istražujući aspekte sličnosti između govorenih ličnih priča, odbacujući ih u vrste priče.</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Het verkennen van aspecten van gelijkenis tussen gesproken persoonlijke verhalen door ze te ontkoppelen in narratieve clausuletypen</title_nl>
      <title_de>Untersuchung von Aspekten der Ähnlichkeit zwischen gesprochenen persönlichen Narrativen, indem sie in narrative Satztypen entkoppelt werden</title_de>
      <title_ko>구어 개인 서사를 서사 종구 유형으로 나누어 구어 개인 서사 간의 유사성을 탐색하다</title_ko>
      <title_id>Menjelaskan aspek persamaan antara cerita pribadi yang dibicarakan dengan melepaskan mereka ke jenis klausul cerita</title_id>
      <title_fa>توسط توسعه‌های مشابهی بین داستانهای شخصی صحبت می‌کند با توسعه‌شان به نوع داستانهای</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Kuelezea vipengele vya usawa kati ya simulizi za binafsi zinazozungumzwa kwa kuwanyamazisha kuwa aina ya ukweli wa habari</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Gürilen kişisel hekaýatlar arasyndaky meňzeşliklerini taryha çevirerek</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Shqyrtimi i aspekteve të ngjashmërisë midis tregimeve personale të folura duke i shpërndarë ato në lloje klauzule treguese</title_sq>
      <title_am>በተናገሩት የግል ታሪክ ታሪክ እና ታሪክ ክፍሎች በመግለጽ</title_am>
      <title_hy>Խոսվող անձնական պատմությունների նմանության ասպեկտների ուսումնասիրելը՝ դրանք բաժանելով պատմությունների բառերի տեսակների մեջ,</title_hy>
      <title_bn>কথা বলা ব্যক্তিগত গল্পের মধ্যে একই ধরনের বিষয়গুলো ব্যাখ্যা করে তাদের কাহিনীতে বিস্তারিত ব্যাপারে বিস্তারি</title_bn>
      <title_az>Onları hekayətli klauzul növlərinə ayırmaq üçün danışan kişisel hekayələr arasındakı bənzərin səviyyələrini söyləyir</title_az>
      <title_bs>Istražujući aspekte sličnosti između govorenih ličnih priča, odbacujući ih u vrste priče.</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Explorar aspectes de la similitud entre narratives personals parlades desmantellant-los en tipus de clàusules narratives</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Zkoumání aspektů podobnosti mluvených osobních vyprávění jejich rozdělením do typů narativních vět</title_cs>
      <title_et>Räägitud isiklike narratiivide sarnasuse aspektide uurimine, lahutades need narratiivseteks klauslitüüpideks</title_et>
      <title_fi>Tutkitaan puhuttujen henkilökohtaisten kertomusten samankaltaisuutta erottamalla ne narratiivisiksi lausetyypeiksi</title_fi>
      <title_af>Ondersoek aspekte van gelykheid tussen gespreek persoonlike narraties deur hulle te verwyder in narratiewe klause tipes</title_af>
      <title_jv>Jejaring</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Raziskovanje vidikov podobnosti govorjenih osebnih pripovedi z razpletenjem v pripovedne klavzule</title_sk>
      <title_ha>Explore aspects of misãli between histories of Personal Person by spelling them as types of description</title_ha>
      <title_he>לחקור את היבטים של דמיון בין סיפורים אישיים מדברים על ידי לפרוק אותם לסוגים של פסקים סיפורים</title_he>
      <title_bo>གནད་དོན་མི་སྒེར་གྱི་གནད་དོན་རྐྱེན་ཚོའི་ཆོས་ཉིད་གང་འདྲ་བྱེད་བཞིན་པའི་ཆོས་ཉིད་དེ་</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تعد مشاركة الروايات الشخصية جانبًا أساسيًا من السلوك الاجتماعي البشري لأنها تساعد في مشاركة تجارب حياتنا. يمكننا سرد القصص والاعتماد على خلفيتنا لفهم سياقها وأوجه التشابه والاختلاف. تم بذل جهد كبير نحو تطوير آلات سرد القصص أو استنتاج سمات الشخصيات. ومع ذلك ، لا نجد عادة نماذج تقارن السرد. تمثل هذه المهمة تحديًا ملحوظًا للآلات لأنها ، كما نفعل أحيانًا ، تفتقر إلى فهم معنى التشابه. لمواجهة هذا التحدي ، قدمنا أولاً مجموعة من الروايات الشخصية المنطوقة في العالم الواقعي تتألف من 10296 بندًا روائيًا من 594 نسخة فيديو. ثانيًا ، نطلب من الخبراء غير السرديين وضع تعليقات توضيحية على تلك البنود في إطار نموذج لابوف اللغوي الاجتماعي للسرد الشخصي (أي أنواع الإجراءات والتوجيه والتقييم) وتدريب المصنف الذي يصل إلى 84.7٪ درجة F لأعلى البنود المتفق عليها. أخيرًا ، نطابق القصص ونستكشف ما إذا كان الناس يعتمدون ضمنيًا على إطار عمل لابوف لمقارنة الروايات. نظهر أن الإجراءات التي يتبعها تقييم الراوي لهذه هي الجوانب التي يعتبرها غير الخبراء أكثر من غيرها. يهدف نهجنا إلى المساعدة في إعلام طرق التعلم الآلي التي تهدف إلى دراسة السرد الشخصي أو تمثيله.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Compartir narrativas personales es un aspecto fundamental del comportamiento social humano, ya que ayuda a compartir nuestras experiencias de vida. Podemos contar historias y confiar en nuestros antecedentes para entender su contexto, similitudes y diferencias. Se ha hecho un esfuerzo sustancial para desarrollar máquinas narrativas o inferir las características de los personajes. Sin embargo, no solemos encontrar modelos que comparen narrativas. Esta tarea es notablemente desafiante para las máquinas, ya que, como a veces lo hacemos nosotros, carecen de una comprensión de lo que significa similitud. Para abordar este desafío, primero presentamos un corpus de narrativas personales habladas del mundo real que comprende 10 296 cláusulas narrativas de 594 transcripciones de video. En segundo lugar, pedimos a los expertos no narrativos que anoten esas cláusulas bajo el modelo sociolingüístico de Labov de narrativas personales (es decir, tipos de cláusulas de acción, orientación y evaluación) y entrenen un clasificador que alcance el 84,7% de puntuación F para las cláusulas más acordadas. Finalmente, comparamos historias y exploramos si las personas confían implícitamente en el marco de Labov para comparar narrativas. Demostramos que las acciones seguidas por la evaluación del narrador de estos son los aspectos que más consideran los no expertos. Nuestro enfoque tiene como objetivo ayudar a informar los métodos de aprendizaje automático destinados a estudiar o representar narrativas personales.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Compartilhar narrativas pessoais é um aspecto fundamental do comportamento social humano, pois ajuda a compartilhar nossas experiências de vida. Podemos contar histórias e contar com nossa experiência para entender seu contexto, semelhanças e diferenças. Um esforço substancial foi feito para desenvolver máquinas de contar histórias ou inferir características dos personagens. No entanto, não costumamos encontrar modelos que comparem narrativas. Essa tarefa é extremamente desafiadora para as máquinas, pois elas, como às vezes fazemos, não compreendem o que significa similaridade. Para enfrentar esse desafio, primeiro apresentamos um corpus de narrativas pessoais faladas do mundo real, compreendendo 10.296 orações narrativas de 594 transcrições de vídeo. Em segundo lugar, pedimos a especialistas não narrativos para anotar essas cláusulas sob o modelo sociolinguístico de Labov de narrativas pessoais (ou seja, tipos de cláusulas de ação, orientação e avaliação) e treinar um classificador que atinja 84,7% F-score para as cláusulas mais bem aceitas. Finalmente, combinamos histórias e exploramos se as pessoas confiam implicitamente na estrutura de Labov para comparar narrativas. Mostramos que as ações seguidas pela avaliação do narrador são os aspectos que os não especialistas mais consideram. Nossa abordagem visa ajudar a informar métodos de aprendizado de máquina destinados a estudar ou representar narrativas pessoais.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>個人的な物語を共有することは、私たちの人生経験を共有するのに役立つため、人間の社会的行動の基本的な側面です。 私たちはストーリーを語ることができ、その背景を頼りにそれらの背景、類似点、違いを理解することができます。 ストーリーテリングマシンの開発やキャラクターの特徴の推測には大きな努力が払われています。 しかし、私たちは通常、物語を比較するモデルを見つけることはありません。 この作業は機械にとって非常に困難です。私たちが時々行うように、機械は類似性が何を意味するのかを理解していないからです。 この課題に対処するために、まずは594のビデオトランスクリプトから10,296の物語条項を含む、現実世界で話されている個人的な物語のコーパスを紹介します。 第二に、私たちは、非叙述的な専門家に、個人の叙述（すなわち、行動、方向、および評価条項の種類）のラボフの社会言語学的モデルの下でこれらの条項に注釈を付け、最も合意された条項で84.7 ％のFスコアに達する分類子を訓練するよう求めます。 最後に、ストーリーを一致させ、人々が物語を比較するために暗黙のうちにラボフの枠組みに依存しているかどうかを探ります。 私たちは、ナレーターによるこれらの評価に続く行動が、非専門家が最も考慮する側面であることを示しています。 私たちのアプローチは、個人的な物語を研究または表現することを目的とした機械学習方法に情報を提供することを目的としています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>分人者,人之大经也,以其有助于分享也。 吾可讲故事也,因吾背景以知其背景,相似而异也。 开讲故事之机器,推角色之力也。 但我们常常不会较叙事的模样。 其于机器甚有挑战性,以其时若我,无相似性义也。 为此挑战,先入一世界口语人叙事语料库,其中594视频脚本10,296叙条款。 其次,请非叙事专家据Labov人叙世间语言学模(即动,向与评估子句类)注此子句,并为子句教习一至84.7%F分之器。 最后,我们匹配故事并探索人们隐含地靠Labov的框架来较叙事。 吾言之,叙述者于此者,是非之家虑最多也。 吾道之旨在研究、示人述者机器学以信息。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>व्यक्तिगत कथाओं को साझा करना मानव सामाजिक व्यवहार का एक मौलिक पहलू है क्योंकि यह हमारे जीवन के अनुभवों को साझा करने में मदद करता है। हम कहानियां बता सकते हैं और उनके संदर्भ, समानताओं और मतभेदों को समझने के लिए हमारी पृष्ठभूमि पर भरोसा कर सकते हैं। कहानी कहने की मशीनों को विकसित करने या पात्रों की विशेषताओं का अनुमान लगाने की दिशा में एक महत्वपूर्ण प्रयास किया गया है। हालांकि, हम आमतौर पर ऐसे मॉडल नहीं पाते हैं जो कथाओं की तुलना करते हैं। यह कार्य मशीनों के लिए उल्लेखनीय रूप से चुनौतीपूर्ण है क्योंकि वे, जैसा कि कभी-कभी हम करते हैं, समानता का क्या मतलब है, इसकी समझ की कमी है। इस चुनौती को संबोधित करने के लिए, हम पहले वास्तविक दुनिया के बोले जाने वाले व्यक्तिगत आख्यानों का एक कॉर्पस पेश करते हैं जिसमें 594 वीडियो टेपों से 10,296 कथा खंड शामिल हैं। दूसरा, हम गैर-कथा विशेषज्ञों से व्यक्तिगत कथाओं (यानी, कार्रवाई, अभिविन्यास और मूल्यांकन खंड प्रकार) के लाबोव के समाजशास्त्रीय मॉडल के तहत उन खंडों को एनोटेट करने के लिए कहते हैं और एक क्लासिफायर को प्रशिक्षित करते हैं जो उच्चतम-सहमत खंडों के लिए 84.7% एफ-स्कोर तक पहुंचता है। अंत में, हम कहानियों से मेल खाते हैं और यह पता लगाते हैं कि क्या लोग कथाओं की तुलना करने के लिए लाबोव के ढांचे पर स्पष्ट रूप से भरोसा करते हैं। हम दिखाते हैं कि इन के कथाकार के मूल्यांकन के बाद की गई कार्रवाइयां उन पहलुओं पर विचार करती हैं जिन पर गैर-विशेषज्ञ सबसे अधिक विचार करते हैं। हमारा दृष्टिकोण व्यक्तिगत कथाओं का अध्ययन या प्रतिनिधित्व करने के उद्देश्य से मशीन सीखने के तरीकों को सूचित करने में मदद करने का इरादा है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Is gné bhunúsach d’iompar sóisialta an duine é scéalta pearsanta a roinnt mar go gcabhraíonn sé lenár dtaithí saoil a roinnt. Is féidir linn scéalta a insint agus brath ar ár gcúlra chun a gcomhthéacs, cosúlachtaí agus difríochtaí a thuiscint. Tá iarracht shubstaintiúil déanta chun meaisíní scéalaíochta a fhorbairt nó gnéithe carachtair a bhaint amach. Mar sin féin, de ghnáth ní aimsímid samhlacha a dhéanann comparáid idir scéalta. Tá an tasc seo thar a bheith dúshlánach do mheaisíní mar go bhfuil easpa tuisceana acu, mar a dhéanaimid uaireanta, ar cad is brí le cosúlacht. Chun aghaidh a thabhairt ar an dúshlán seo, tugaimid isteach ar dtús corpas de scéalta pearsanta labhartha fíor-dhomhanda ina bhfuil 10,296 clásal insinte as 594 tras-scríbhinní físeáin. Ar an dara dul síos, iarraimid ar shaineolaithe neamhinscne na clásail sin a anótáil faoi mhúnla sochtheangeolaíoch Labov de insintí pearsanta (i.e. cineálacha clásail gníomhaíochta, treoshuímh agus meastóireachta) agus oiliúint a chur ar aicmitheora a shroichfidh 84.7% an scór-F do na clásail is airde comhaontaithe. Ar deireadh, déanaimid scéalta a mheaitseáil agus fiosrú an bhfuil daoine ag brath go hintuigthe ar chreat Labov chun scéalta a chur i gcomparáid. Léirímid gurb iad na gníomhaíochtaí a leanann meastóireacht an scéalaí orthu seo na gnéithe is mó a mheasann neamhshaineolaithe. Tá sé mar aidhm ag ár gcur chuige cabhrú le heolas a chur ar mhodhanna meaisínfhoghlama atá dírithe ar staidéar a dhéanamh ar scéalta pearsanta nó iad a léiriú.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η ανταλλαγή προσωπικών αφηγήσεων είναι μια θεμελιώδης πτυχή της ανθρώπινης κοινωνικής συμπεριφοράς καθώς βοηθά να μοιραστούμε τις εμπειρίες της ζωής μας. Μπορούμε να πούμε ιστορίες και να βασιστούμε στο παρελθόν μας για να κατανοήσουμε το πλαίσιο, τις ομοιότητες και τις διαφορές τους. Έχει καταβληθεί ουσιαστική προσπάθεια για την ανάπτυξη μηχανών αφήγησης ιστοριών ή την εξαγωγή χαρακτηριστικών χαρακτήρων. Ωστόσο, συνήθως δεν βρίσκουμε μοντέλα που συγκρίνουν αφηγήσεις. Αυτό το έργο είναι εξαιρετικά δύσκολο για τις μηχανές, δεδομένου ότι, όπως μερικές φορές κάνουμε εμείς, δεν καταλαβαίνουν τι σημαίνει ομοιότητα. Για να αντιμετωπιστεί αυτή η πρόκληση, εισάγουμε πρώτα ένα σώμα πραγματικών ομιλούμενων προσωπικών αφηγήσεων που περιλαμβάνουν 10,296 αφηγηματικές ρήτρες από 594 βίντεο μεταγραφές. Δεύτερον, ζητούμε από μη αφηγηματικούς εμπειρογνώμονες να σχολιάσουν αυτές τις ρήτρες σύμφωνα με το κοινωνικογλωσσικό μοντέλο προσωπικών αφηγήσεων του Λάμποφ (δηλ. τύποι ρήτρες δράσης, προσανατολισμού και αξιολόγησης) και να εκπαιδεύσουν έναν ταξινομητή που φθάνει σε 84,7% βαθμολογία για τις υψηλότερες συμφωνημένες ρήτρες. Τέλος, ταιριάζουμε ιστορίες και εξερευνούμε αν οι άνθρωποι βασίζονται σιωπηρά στο πλαίσιο του Λάμποφ για να συγκρίνουν αφηγήσεις. Δείχνουμε ότι οι ενέργειες που ακολουθούνται από την αξιολόγηση από τον αφηγητή αυτών είναι οι πτυχές που οι μη ειδικοί θεωρούν περισσότερο. Η προσέγγισή μας έχει ως στόχο να βοηθήσει στην ενημέρωση μεθόδων μηχανικής μάθησης που στοχεύουν στη μελέτη ή την αναπαράσταση προσωπικών αφηγήσεων.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>A személyes narratívák megosztása az emberi társadalmi viselkedés alapvető aspektusa, mivel segít megosztani élettapasztalatainkat. Mesélhetünk történeteket, és támaszkodhatunk a hátterünkre, hogy megértsük kontextusukat, hasonlóságokat és különbségeket. Jelentős erőfeszítéseket tettek a történetmesélő gépek fejlesztésére vagy a karakterek jellemzőinek következtetésére. Általában azonban nem találunk olyan modelleket, amelyek összehasonlítják a narratívákat. Ez a feladat rendkívül kihívást jelent a gépek számára, mivel ők, mint néha mi, nem értik, mit jelent a hasonlóság. Ennek a kihívásnak a megoldására először a valós világban beszélt személyes elbeszélésekből álló korpuszt mutatjuk be, amely 594 videóátiratból 10 296 elbeszélő záradékot tartalmaz. Másodszor, megkérjük a nem elbeszélő szakértőket, hogy jegyezzék meg ezeket a záradékokat Labov szociolinglisztikai modellje szerint a személyes elbeszélések (tehát akció, orientáció és értékelési záradék típusai), és képezzenek egy olyan osztályozót, amely eléri a 84,7%-os F pontszámot a legmagasabb elfogadott záradékok esetében. Végül összehasonlítjuk a történeteket, és megvizsgáljuk, hogy az emberek implicit módon támaszkodnak-e Labov keretrendszerére a narratívák összehasonlításához. Megmutatjuk, hogy az elbeszélő értékelése által követett cselekvések azok a szempontok, amelyeket a nem szakértők figyelembe vesznek a legjobban. Megközelítésünk célja, hogy segítsen a gépi tanulási módszerek tájékoztatásában, amelyek célja a személyes narratívák tanulmányozása vagy ábrázolása.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ადამიანის სოციალური ქცევის ფუნდამეტური აპექტირება, როგორც ჩვენი ცხოვრების გამოცდილების გაყოფა. ჩვენ შეგვიძლია ისტორიების შესახებ და ჩვენი ფონქონის შესახებ გავიგოთ ისინი კონტექსტური, სხვადასხვების და განსხვავებების შესახებ. მნიშვნელოვანი წარმოდგენა ისტორიების მაქანების განვითარებაში ან სიმბოლოების ფუნქციების განვითარებაში. მაგრამ, ჩვენ უბრალოდ არ ვიძებთ მოდელები, რომლებიც ისტორიების შემდგენება. ეს სამუშაო მაქსინტებისთვის შესაძლებელია, რადგან ისინი, როგორც კიდევ ჩვენ ვაკეთებთ, არსებობს სხვადასხვა რას ნიშნავს. ამ გამოცდილების გარეშე, ჩვენ პირველად ვიყენებთ რეალურად მსოფლიოს პირადი განსახულების კორპუსს, რომლებიც 594 ვიდეო ტრანსკრიპტების 10 296 განსახულების კლასები. მეორე, ჩვენ მოთხოვრობთ არატატიური ექსპერტები, რომ ლაბოგის სოციოლოლინგურისტიური მოდელის შესახებ ამ კლასების შესახებ (მაგალითად, მოქმედება, ორიენტირება და განსაზღვრებული კლასოზების ტიპები) და გაგრძელოთ კლასფიზერი, რომელი საბოლოოდ, ჩვენ ისტორიების შესაბამისი და განსხვავებთ თუ ადამიანები იმპლიციტურად ლაბოგის ფრამეტრის შესაბამისი სიტყვები. ჩვენ ჩვენ აჩვენებთ, რომ მოქმედება, რომლებიც ახალგაზრუქტორის განსაზღვრებას შემდეგ, არის არსებული ექსპერტები, რომლებიც ყველაზე უფრო ახალგაზრ ჩვენი პროგრამის მიზეზი იყენება, რომ ინფორმაცია მაქსინური სწავლების მეტოვების მიზეზი სწავლად ან გამოსახულებლად პირადგილური ისტორიები.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_kk>Жеке оқиғаларды ортақтастыру - адамдардың әлеуметтік тәртіптерімізді ортақтастыру үшін негізгі аспекті. Біз оқиғаларды түсіндіре аламыз және аясымызды түсіндіре аламыз. Журнал тізімдеу машиналарын не таңбалардың мүмкіндіктерін жасау үшін көп жұмыс істеді. Бірақ әдетте, оқиғаларды салыстыратын үлгілер табылмаймыз. Бұл тапсырма машиналар үшін кәдімгі қызықтық, өйткені кейбірде біз бұл ұқсастығының түсініктемесіз. Бұл мәселеге қатынау үшін, біріншіден 594 видео транскрипттерден 10 296 жазулық жазулардың корпусын таныстық. Екіншіден, біз бұл классификацияларды Лабовдың социологиялық түсініктер үшін (яғни әрекет, бағыттау және оқу классификацияларының түрлері) түсініп, ең жоғары классификациялық классификациялық түрлеріне 84,7% F- score жеткізеді. Соңында, біз оқиғаларға сәйкес келеді және адамдар Лабовдің қоршауына салыстыру үшін түсініктерді салыстыру үшін қолданып тұрып көрдік. Біз түсініктердің оқиғасынан келесі әрекеттердің көпшілігі емес експерттердің ең көпшілігі деп ойлайтынын көрсетедік. Біздің қасиетіміз жеке оқиғаларды оқыту не көрсету үшін машинаны оқыту әдістерін көмектесетін.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_it>Condividere narrazioni personali è un aspetto fondamentale del comportamento sociale umano in quanto aiuta a condividere le nostre esperienze di vita. Possiamo raccontare storie e contare sul nostro background per comprenderne il contesto, le somiglianze e le differenze. Uno sforzo sostanziale è stato fatto per sviluppare macchine di narrazione o per dedurre le caratteristiche dei personaggi. Tuttavia, di solito non troviamo modelli che confrontano le narrazioni. Questo compito è estremamente impegnativo per le macchine, poiché esse, come a volte facciamo noi, non hanno una comprensione di cosa significhi somiglianza. Per affrontare questa sfida, introduciamo per prima cosa un corpus di narrazioni personali parlate nel mondo reale comprendente 10.296 clausole narrative da 594 trascrizioni video. In secondo luogo, chiediamo agli esperti non narrativi di annotare queste clausole secondo il modello sociolinguistico di Labov di narrazioni personali (cioè, azioni, orientamento e tipi di clausole di valutazione) e formare un classificatore che raggiunge l'84,7% F-score per le clausole concordate più alte. Infine, confrontiamo le storie ed esploriamo se le persone si affidano implicitamente al framework di Labov per confrontare le narrazioni. Mostriamo che le azioni seguite dalla valutazione del narratore di questi sono gli aspetti che i non esperti considerano di più. Il nostro approccio ha lo scopo di aiutare a informare i metodi di apprendimento automatico volti a studiare o rappresentare narrazioni personali.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ms>Berkongsi cerita peribadi adalah aspek dasar perilaku sosial manusia kerana ia membantu berkongsi pengalaman hidup kita. Kita boleh ceritakan cerita dan bergantung pada latar belakang kita untuk memahami konteks, persamaan dan perbezaan mereka. Name Namun, kita biasanya tidak mencari model yang membandingkan cerita. Tugas ini sangat menantang bagi mesin kerana mereka, seperti yang kadang-kadang kita lakukan, kurang memahami apa makna persamaan. Untuk mengatasi cabaran ini, kita pertama-tama memperkenalkan korpus cerita peribadi yang bercakap di dunia nyata yang mengandungi 10,296 klausul cerita dari 594 transkrip video. Kedua, kami meminta ahli tidak-cerita untuk anotasi klawsul-klawsul tersebut di bawah model sosiolingvistik Labov cerita peribadi (iaitu tindakan, orientasi, dan jenis klawsul penilaian) dan melatih kelas yang mencapai skor-F 84.7% untuk klawsul yang setuju tertinggi. Akhirnya, kita sepadan cerita dan mengeksplorasi sama ada orang secara implicit bergantung pada kerangka Labov untuk membandingkan cerita. Kami menunjukkan bahawa tindakan diikuti oleh penilaian pencerita tentang ini adalah aspek yang tidak-pakar mempertimbangkan paling. Pendekatan kami adalah bertujuan untuk membantu maklumkan kaedah pembelajaran mesin yang bertujuan untuk mempelajari atau mewakili cerita peribadi.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_lt>Sharing personal narratives is a fundamental aspect of human social behavior as it helps share our life experiences.  Galime pasakoti istorijas ir pasikliauti savo fonu, kad suprastume jų kontekstą, panašumą ir skirtumus. Buvo dedamos didelės pastangos kurti storytelling mašinas arba daryti išvadas apie charakteristikas. Vis dėlto paprastai neradome modelių, kurie palygina pasakojimus. Ši užduotis mašinoms labai sunki, nes jos, kaip ir kartais mes, nesupranta, ką reiškia panašumas. Siekdami išspręsti šį iššūkį, pirmiausia įvedame tikrojo pasaulio kalbėtų asmeninių narratyvų korpusą, apimantį 10 296 narratyvų straipsnius iš 594 vaizdo transkripcijų. Antra, prašome nepranešusių ekspertų anotuoti ši a s i šlygas pagal Labov socialinės kalbos model į asmeninių narratyvų (t. y. veiksmų, orientacijos ir vertinimo išlygų tipus) ir parengti klasifikatorių, kuris pasiekia 84,7 % F tašką aukščiausių sutartų išlygų atžvilgiu. Galiausiai, mes suderiname istorijas ir tiriame, ar žmonės netiesiogiai pasikliauja Labovo sistema, kad palygintume istorijas. Mes rodome, kad veiksmai, po kurių pranešėjas vertina šiuos aspektus, yra aspektai, kuriuos labiausiai svarsto ne ekspertai. Mūsų požiūriu siekiama padėti informuoti mašininio mokymosi metodus, kuriais siekiama studijuoti ar atstovauti asmeniniams pasakojimams.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mt>Il-kondiviżjoni ta’ narrattivi personali hija aspett fundamentali tal-imġiba soċjali tal-bniedem peress li tgħin fil-kondiviżjoni tal-esperjenzi tal-ħajja tagħna. Aħna nistgħu ngħidu storji u nistrieħu fuq l-isfond tagħna biex nifhmu l-kuntest, ix-similaritajiet, u d-differenzi tagħhom. Sar sforz sostanzjali lejn l-iżvilupp ta’ magni tat-storytelling jew l-inferiment tal-karatteristiċi. Madankollu, normalment ma ssibx mudelli li jqabblu n-narrattivi. Dan il-kompitu huwa notevolment ta’ sfida għall-magni peress li, kif xi drabi nagħmlu, ma jifhmux x’tfisser similarità. Biex nindirizzaw din l-isfida, l-ewwel a ħna nintroduċu korpus ta’ narrattivi personali mitkellma fid-dinja reali li jinkludu 10 296 klawżola narrattiva minn 594 video transcripts. It-tieni nett, nistaqsu lill-esperti mhux narrattivi biex janataw dawk il-klawżoli taħt il-mudell soċjolangwistiku tan-narrattivi personal i ta’ Labov (jiġifieri, it-tipi ta’ azzjoni, orjentazzjoni, u klawżoli ta’ evalwazzjoni) u nħarrġu klassifikatur li jilħaq il-punteġġ F ta’ 84,7 % għall-klawżoli l-aktar miftiehma. Fl-aħħar nett, aħna nqabblu l-istejjer u nesploraw jekk in-nies jistriegħux impliċitament fuq il-qafas ta' Labov biex iqabblu n-narrattivi. We show that actions followed by the narrator's evaluation of these are the aspects non-experts consider the most.  Our approach is intended to help inform machine learning methods aimed at studying or representing personal narratives.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mk>Соделувањето лични приказни е фундаментален аспект на човечкото социјално однесување бидејќи помага да ги споделиме нашите животни искуства. Можеме да раскажуваме приказни и да се потпираме на нашата позадина за да го разбереме нивниот контекст, сличностите и разликите. Направени се значителни напори за развој на машини за раскажување приказни или конференција на карактеристиките на ликовите. Сепак, обично не најдеме модели кои ги споредуваат приказните. Оваа задача е неверојатно предизвикувачка за машините бидејќи тие, како што понекогаш ние, немаат разбирање што значи сличноста. За да го решиме овој предизвик, прво воведуваме корпус на лични приказни на реалниот свет кои вклучуваат 10.296 приказни од 594 видео транскрипти. Второ, ние побараме од нераскажувачките експерти да ги анотираат тие клаузули во социјалингвистичкиот модел на Лабов за лични раскажувања (т.е. типови на акција, ориентација и оценка) и да обучат класификатор кој достигнува 84,7 отсто ф-оценка за највисоко договорени клаузули. Конечно, ги споредуваме приказните и истражуваме дали луѓето имплицитно се потпираат на рамките на Лабов за да ги споредат приказните. Ние покажуваме дека акциите следени од оценката на раскажувачот за овие се аспектите кои не експертите ги сметаат за најголеми. Нашиот пристап има за цел да помогне во информирањето на методите на машинско учење кои имаат за цел учење или претставување на личните приказни.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ml>വ്യക്തിപരമായ കഥകള്‍ പങ്കുചേര്‍ക്കുന്നത് മനുഷ്യരുടെ സാമൂഹ്യസ്ഥിതിയുടെ അടിസ്ഥാനമാണ്. അത് നമ്മുടെ ജീവിതം അന നമുക്ക് കഥകള്‍ പറയാനും പശ്ചാത്തലത്തില്‍ ആശ്രയിക്കാനും അവയുടെ സംസ്ഥാനത്തിലും സമമായതും വ്യത്യാസങ്ങളും മനസ്സ കഥ പറയുന്ന യന്ത്രങ്ങള്‍ മുന്‍പിടിക്കുന്നതിനോ അക്ഷരങ്ങളുടെ പ്രശ്നങ്ങളെ അപകടിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനോ വേണ്ടി ഒരു വലിയ ശ്രമ എന്നാലും, കഥകളെ തുല്യമാക്കുന്ന മോഡലുകള്‍ നമുക്ക് സാധാരണ കണ്ടെത്തുന്നില്ല. ഈ ജോലി യന്ത്രങ്ങള്‍ക്ക് വേണ്ടി വിലപാടാണ്. ചിലപ്പോള്‍ നമ്മള്‍ ചെയ്യുന്നത് പോലെ ഒരുപാട് എന്താണ് ഉദ്ദേശിക്കുന്നത ഈ വെല്ലുവെക്കുവാന്‍, നമ്മള്‍ ആദ്യം ഒരു യഥാര്‍ത്ഥ ലോകത്തില്‍ സംസാരിക്കുന്ന വ്യക്തിപരമായ കഥകളെ പരിചയപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു. അത് 594 വീഡി രണ്ടാമത്, വിവരങ്ങളില്ലാത്ത വിശേഷികളോട് ഞങ്ങള്‍ ആവശ്യപ്പെടുന്നത് ലേവിവിന്‍റെ സോഷ്യലിഗ്ലാനിസ്റ്റിക്ക് മോഡലിന്‍റെ കീഴില്‍ വ്യക്തിപ്പെടുത്തുവാന്‍ വേണ്ടി (ഉദാഹരണമായ പ്രവര്‍ത്ത അവസാനം, നമ്മള്‍ കഥകളോടൊപ്പം ചേര്‍ന്ന് പരിശോധിക്കുന്നു, ആളുകള്‍ ലേവിന്റെ ഫ്രെയിമ്പില്‍ ആശ്രയിക്കുന്നുണ്ട വിവരങ്ങളുടെ പിന്നാലെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നുവെന്ന് ഞങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചു തരുന്നു. ഇതിലെ വി വ്യക്തിപരമായ കഥകള്‍ പഠിക്കുകയോ പ്രതിനിധിക്കുകയോ ചെയ്യുന്ന യന്ത്രം പഠിക്കുന്ന രീതികള്‍ അറിയിക്കാന</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Deling av personlege narrativ er ein grunnleggjande aspekt av menneskelige sosiale oppførsel som han hjelper å dele livet våre erfaringar. Vi kan fortelle historiane og rely på bakgrunnen vårt for å forstå konteksten, likningar og forskjeller sine. Det er gjort ein stort forsøk mot å utvikla storytellingsmaskiner eller å få opp karakterfunksjonar. Men vi finn ikkje vanlegvis modeller som samanliknar narrativ. Denne oppgåva er veldig vanskeleg for maskiner sidan dei, som noen ganger me gjer, manglar forståelse av kva liknande betyr. For å handtera denne utfordringen, introdusere vi først ein korpus av verkeleg snakkete personlege narrativ som inneheld 10.296 narrativ klausar frå 594 video-transkript. For det andre, spør vi ikkje-narrativ ekspertar å merke på dei klausene under Labov sin sosiallingsmedleg av personlege narrativ (t.d. handlingar, orientering og evalueringsklausetypar) og trene ein klassifiserer som når 84,7 % F-poeng for de høgste samordne klausene. Etter slutt, vi passar med historiar og utforsker om folk implisitt brukar på Labov rammeverket for å sammenligne historiar. Vi viser at handlingane følgjande av narratorens evaluering av desse er aspektane som ikkje er ekspertane syner dei meste. Tilnærminga vårt er for å hjelpa å informera maskinelæringsmetodar med mål på å studera eller representera personlege narrativ.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Dzielenie się osobistymi narracjami jest podstawowym aspektem ludzkich zachowań społecznych, ponieważ pomaga dzielić się doświadczeniami życiowymi. Możemy opowiadać historie i polegać na naszym pochodzeniu, aby zrozumieć ich kontekst, podobieństwa i różnice. Podjęto znaczne wysiłki w celu opracowania maszyn do opowiadania historii lub wnioskowania cech postaci. Zazwyczaj jednak nie znajdujemy modeli porównujących narracje. To zadanie jest niezwykle trudne dla maszyn, ponieważ nie wiedzą, co oznacza podobieństwo. Aby sprostać temu wyzwaniu, wprowadzamy najpierw korpus rzeczywistych narracji osobistych zawierających 10,296 klauzule narracyjne z transkrypcji wideo 594. Po drugie, prosimy ekspertów nienarracyjnych o adnotację tych klauzul w ramach socjolingwistycznego modelu narracji osobistych Labova (tj. typów klauzul działania, orientacji i oceny) i przeszkolenie klasyfikatora osiągającego 84,7% F-punktu dla najwyższych uzgodnionych klauzul. Wreszcie, dopasowujemy historie i badamy, czy ludzie bezpośrednio polegają na ramach Labova do porównywania narracji. Pokazujemy, że działania, po których następuje ocena ich przez narratora, są aspektami, które nie-eksperci uważają najbardziej. Nasze podejście ma na celu pomóc w informowaniu metod uczenia maszynowego ukierunkowanych na studiowanie lub reprezentowanie narracji osobistych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Хүн төрөлхтний түүхийг хуваалцах нь хүний нийгмийн үйл явцын үндсэн асуудал юм. Энэ нь бидний амьдралын туршлагыг хуваалцах тулд тусалдаг. Бид түүхийг ярьж, өөрчлөлтийг ойлгохын тулд өөрсдийгөө өөрсдийгөө өөрчлөх боломжтой. Хүмүүсийн түүх ярианы машинуудыг боловсруулахын тулд маш их хичээл хийгдсэн. Гэхдээ бид түүхийг харьцуулдаг загваруудыг ихэвчлэн олохгүй. Энэ үйл ажиллагаа машинуудын тулд гайхалтай төвөгтэй. Яагаад гэвэл заримдаа бидний хийж байгаа шиг адилхан гэдгийг ойлгохгүй. Энэ сорилтыг удирдахын тулд бид анх жинхэнэ ертөнцийн ярилцаж буй хувийн зохиолуудын корпус дээр 594 бичлэгийн хувьцааны 10,296 түүх хувьцааны тухай танилцуулдаг. Хоёрдугаар, бид Лабовын социологичдын зохиолын загварын доор тэдгээр загваруудыг анзаарах мэргэжлийн мэргэжлийн хүмүүсээс (яг л үйл ажиллагаа, ориентаци, үнэлгээ, дүгнэлтийн хэлбэрээр) хүртэл хамгийн өндөр зөвшөөрөгдсөн загваруудын тулд 84. Эцэст нь бид түүхийг тоглож, хүмүүс түүхийг харьцуулахын тулд Лабовын хэлбэрээр хамаарч байгааг судалж байна. Бид зохиолчдын оюутнуудын дараах үйл явдлыг харуулж байна. Эдгээрийн оюутнууд биш мэргэжилтнүүд хамгийн их боддог зүйлс. Бидний арга зам нь хувийн зохиолуудыг судлах эсвэл илэрхийлдэг машин суралцах арга замыг мэдээллээр тусалдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sr>Dijeljenje ličnih priča je osnovni aspekt ljudskog društvenog ponašanja jer pomaže da podeli naše životno iskustvo. Možemo ispričati priče i oslanjati se na našu pozadinu da razumemo njihov kontekst, sličnosti i razlike. Veliki napor je napravljen u razvoju uređaja za priču ili privlačenje karaktera. Međutim, obično ne nađemo modele koji uspoređuju priče. Ovaj zadatak je izuzetno izazovan za mašine jer oni, kao ponekad radimo, nedostaju razumevanje šta znači sličnost. Za rješavanje ovog izazova, prvo predstavljamo korpus rečenih ličnih priča sa 10.296 prièanih klauzula iz 594 video transkripta. Drugo, tražimo nekoraktivne stručnjake da annotiraju te klauzule pod sociolingustičkim modelom ličnih priča Labova (tj. akcije, orijentacije i procjene klauzula) i treniraju klasifikatora koji dostiže 84,7% F-rezultata za najviše dogovorene klauzule. Konačno, odgovaramo pričama i istražujemo da li se ljudi implicitno oslanjaju na Labovov okvir da usporede priče. Pokazujemo da su akcije koje prate procjena narratora ovih aspekta koje ne smatraju stručnjacima najviše. Naš pristup je nameravan da pomognemo da obavijestimo metode učenja mašina usmjerene na učenje ili predstavljanje ličnih priča.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>පෞද්ගලික කතාවක් සමාගන්න එක මිනිස්සු සාමාජික ව්‍යාපෘතියේ මූලික ප්‍රදේශයක් විතරයි ඒක අපේ ජී අපිට කතාවක් කියන්න පුළුවන් අපේ පිටිපස්සේ විශ්වාස කරන්න ඔවුන්ගේ සංවේදනය, වගේම වෙනස් තේරුම්  කතාවක් සංවේදනය කරන්න යන්ත්‍රය නැත්තම් අකුරුවන්ගේ විශේෂතාවක් විස්තර කරනවා. ඒත් අපිට සාමාන්‍යයෙන්ම කතාවක් සමාන්‍යය කරන්න ප්‍රමාණයක් හොයාගන්නේ නෑ. මේ වැඩේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් තමයි යන්ත්‍රය සඳහා ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙන්නේ, ඒ වගේම, සමහර වෙලාවට අපි කරනවා වගේම, සමහර වෙලාව මේ අභ්‍යානය විදිහට, අපි මුලින්ම ඇත්ත ලෝකයේ කතා කරපු පෞද්ගලික කතාවක් වලින් පුළුවන් වීඩියෝව 594 විදියෝ වාර්ත දෙවෙනි විදියටම, අපි නොකතාවික විශේෂයෙන්ට අහන්නේ ලැබෝව්ගේ සාමාජික භාෂාවික මොඩේලයේ පුළුවන් කතාවක් වලින් ඒ වගේම ලැබෝව්ගේ සාමාජික භාෂාවික විද අන්තිමේදි, අපි කතාවල් එක්ක සම්බන්ධ කරනවා සහ කතාවල් සම්බන්ධ කරනවා කියලා පරීක්ෂා කරනවා කියලා. අපි පෙන්වන්නේ ක්‍රියාවල් පස්සේ කතාකරුවගේ විශ්වාස කරනවා කියලා අපේ ප්‍රවේශනය තියෙන්නේ මැෂින් ඉගෙන ගන්න විදියට උදව් කරන්න.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ro>Împărtășirea narațiunilor personale este un aspect fundamental al comportamentului social uman, deoarece ajută la împărtășirea experiențelor noastre de viață. Putem spune povești și ne putem baza pe fundalul nostru pentru a înțelege contextul, similitudinile și diferențele lor. S-a făcut un efort substanțial pentru a dezvolta mașini de povestire sau pentru a deduce caracteristicile personajelor. Cu toate acestea, de obicei nu găsim modele care să compare narațiuni. Această sarcină este remarcabil de provocatoare pentru mașini, deoarece acestea, așa cum uneori facem noi, nu înțeleg ce înseamnă similaritatea. Pentru a aborda această provocare, introducem mai întâi un corpus de narațiuni personale vorbite în lumea reală cuprinzând 10.296 de clauze narative din 594 de transcrieri video. În al doilea rând, solicităm experților non-naraționali să adnoteze aceste clauze în cadrul modelului sociolingvistic al narațiunilor personale (adică tipurile de clauze de acțiune, orientare și evaluare) și să instruiască un clasificator care ajunge la 84,7% F-scor pentru cele mai mari clauze convenite. În cele din urmă, potrivim poveștile și explorăm dacă oamenii se bazează implicit pe cadrul lui Labov pentru a compara narațiunile. Arătăm că acțiunile urmate de evaluarea naratorului asupra acestora sunt aspectele pe care nu le consideră experții cel mai mult. Abordarea noastră este menită să ajute la informarea metodelor de învățare automată care vizează studierea sau reprezentarea narațiunilor personale.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Sharciga sheekooyinka shakhsiga ah waa dhinac muhiim ah oo dabeecada bulshada ee biniaadamka ah, sababtoo ah waxay caawinaysaa sharciga aragtideena nolosha. Waxaannu sheegi karnaa sheekooyinka, waxaynu ku kalsoonaan karnaa bakhtigayaga si aan u garanayno xaalkooda, isku mid ah iyo kala duwanaanshaha. Jahaado badan waxaa loo sameeyay in loo horumariyo qalabka sheekadaha ama in loo dhibo qalcadaha. Si kastaba ha ahaatee, ma helno tusaalooyin isbarbardhiga sheekooyinka. Shaqadan aad buu u qallafsan yahay mashiinadaha, sababtoo ah marka qaarkood sida aan sameyno, ma baahna garasho u eg macnahooda. Marka ugu horeysa waxaynu soo bandhignaa warqado shakhsiyeed ah oo la hadlay oo ka mid ah 10,296 warqado sheekeysan oo ka qoran 594 fiidiyowga. Second, we ask non-narrative experts to annotate those clauses under Labov's sociolinguistic model of personal narratives (i.e., action, orientation, and evaluation clause types) and train a classifier that reaches 84.7% F-score for the highest-agreed clauses.  Ugu dambaysta, waxaynu la xiriirnaa sheekooyinka iyo baaraynaa in dadka si dhab ah ugu talo saaran yihiin qorshaha shaqada si ay u barbaraan sheekooyinka. Waxaynu muujinnaa in waxyaabaha lagu soo daba galay qiimeynta qiimeynta qiimeynta taariikhda waa arrimaha aan khabiir aheyn ay ugu badan ka fikiraan. Dhaqdhaqaalkayaga waxaa loogu talogalay in lagu ogeysiiyo qaababka waxbarashada mashiinka oo loogu talagalay waxbarashada ama ka mid ah sheekooyinka shakhsiyadda.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Att dela personliga berättelser är en grundläggande aspekt av mänskligt socialt beteende eftersom det hjälper till att dela våra livserfarenheter. Vi kan berätta historier och förlita oss på vår bakgrund för att förstå deras sammanhang, likheter och skillnader. En betydande ansträngning har gjorts för att utveckla berättande maskiner eller härleda karaktärernas egenskaper. Men vi brukar inte hitta modeller som jämför berättelser. Denna uppgift är anmärkningsvärt utmanande för maskiner eftersom de, som ibland gör vi, saknar förståelse för vad likhet innebär. För att möta denna utmaning introducerar vi först en korpus av verkliga talade personliga berättelser bestående av 10 296 narrativa klausuler från 594 videoskript. För det andra ber vi icke-narrativa experter att kommentera dessa klausuler under Labovs sociolingvistiska modell av personliga berättelser (dvs handling, orientering och utvärdering klausuler typer) och utbilda en klassificerare som når 84,7% F-poäng för de högst överenskomna klausulerna. Slutligen matchar vi berättelser och undersöker om människor underförstått förlitar sig på Labovs ramverk för att jämföra berättelser. Vi visar att åtgärder som följs av berättarens utvärdering av dessa är de aspekter som icke-experter anser mest. Vårt tillvägagångssätt är avsett att hjälpa till att informera maskininlärningsmetoder som syftar till att studera eller representera personliga berättelser.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>தனிப்பட்ட கதைகளை பகிர்ந்து கொள்வது மனித சமூக செயல்பாடுகளின் முக்கியமான பகுதி நாம் கதைகளை சொல்ல முடியும் பின்னணியை நம்ப முடியும் அவர்களுடைய சூழ்நிலையையும், ஒத்திசையையும் வ கதை சொல்லும் இயந்திரங்களை உருவாக்குவதற்கு அல்லது எழுத்துகளின் குணங்களை பாதிக்கும் முயற்சி செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது. ஆனால், நாம் வழக்கமாக கதைகளை ஒப்பிடும் மாதிரிகளை கண்டுபிடிக்கவில்லை. இந்த செயல் இயந்திரங்களுக்கு மிகவும் சவால் இருக்கிறது ஏனெனில் சில நேரங்களில் நாம் செய்யும் போது, ஒத்தும் என்ன என்ற இந்த சவால்களை முதலில் நாம் முதலில் ஒரு உண்மையான உலகத்தில் பேசும் தனிப்பட்ட கதைகளை குறிப்பிடுகிறோம் 594 வீடியோ எழுத்துக்களில் இரு இரண்டாவது, நாம் அறிவிப்பாளர்களை கேட்கிறோம் லேவின் சமூகத்தான மாதிரிகளின் கீழ் அந்த விளக்கங்களை அறிவிப்பதற்கு (அதாவது, செயல், சார்ந்து, நீங்கள் மற்றும் மதிப்பு வகுப்புகள் வகுப்பாடுகள் வகு Finally, we match stories and explore whether people implicitly rely on Labov's framework to compare narratives.  நாம் காண்பிக்கிறோம் கதையின் மதிப்பு பின்பற்றும் செயல்கள் இந்த விஷயங்களின் மதிப்பு பின்பற்றும் என்பதை நாம்  எங்கள் செயல்பாடு சொல்லும் இயந்திரத்தை கற்றுக்கொள்ள முறைகளை அறிவிக்க உதவும் என்று தெரியும்.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>شخصی کہانیاں شریک کرنا انسان کی اجتماعی رفتار کی بنیادی حصہ ہے جس طرح یہ ہماری زندگی کے تجربے کا شریک کرنے کی مدد کرتا ہے. ہم کہانیاں بیان کر سکتے ہیں اور اپنے پیچھے پر بھروسہ کر سکتے ہیں کہ ان کے متعلق، برابری اور اختلاف سمجھ سکتے ہیں. ایک بڑی تلاش کی گئی ہے کہانیاں سنانے کے ماشین یا شخصیٹوں کی فرصت کے لئے۔ ہمیں معمولاً کہانیاں مقایسہ کرنے والی موڈل نہیں پاتے۔ یہ کام ماشین کے لئے بہت اچھا مشکل ہے اس وجہ سے کہ وہ بعض موجود ہیں جیسے ہم کیا کرتے ہیں، برابری کا معنی نہیں سمجھتے۔ اس چالوں کے بارے میں ہم پہلی بار ایک حقیقی دنیا میں صحبت کی شخصی حکایتوں کو معرفی کرتے ہیں جو 594 ویڈیو ٹرنسکرپٹوں سے 10,296 داستان کلاس ہیں۔ دوسرا، ہم نے غیر داستان پڑھنے والوں سے درخواست کیا ہے کہ لابوف کے سوسیولیولینگ موڈل کے ذریعے ان کلیزوں کو اظہار کریں (یعنی اقدام, منظور اور ارزیابی کلیزوں کی طرح) اور ایک کلیزور کو ترین کریں جو 84.7% F-اسکور تک پہنچتا ہے سب سے بالاترین موافق کلیزوں کے لئے۔ آخر میں ہم کہانیاں مطابق کرتے ہیں اور دیکھتے ہیں کہ آیا لوگوں نے لابوف کے فرم پر اپنا اعتماد رکھا ہے کہ کہانیاں مقایسہ کرنے کے لئے۔ ہم دکھاتے ہیں کہ ان کی تعلیمات کے پیچھے ان کی تعلیمات کے سب سے زیادہ بصیرت غیر علماء ہیں ہمارا طریقہ یہ ہے کہ مشین یادہانی طریقے کی اطلاعات کرنے کی مدد کریں جو شخصی داستان کی تعلیم یا تعلیم کرنے کی هدف رکھتے ہیں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Shaxsiy hikoyalarni qayta qilish inson jamiyat xudding asosiy dhinaclari, chunki u hayotimizning tajribalarimizni qayta oladi. We can tell stories and rely on our background to understand their context, similarities, and differences.  Name Lekin, biz odatda qismlarni o'xshash modellarni topmaymiz. Bu vazifa juda qiziqarli mashinalar uchun murakkab qiladi, chunki ba'zida biz bajaramiz, biz bir xil narsa nima narsa tushunishni tushunmaymiz. Bu muammolarni boshqarish uchun biz birinchi marta gapiradigan shaxsiy hikoyalarning qismlarini boshqaramiz. 594 Video skriptlardan 10,296 qismi klassiyatlari bor. Ikkinchi so'zda, biz Labovning shaxsiy tarixi modelidagi o'xshash haqida o'xshash taʼminlovchilar so'rayapmiz va maktab soʻzlariga 84.7% F scorning yuqori darajasini o'rganish mumkin. Oxirgi, biz hikoyalarni o'xshash va o'rganamiz, odamlar Labov ijodkorini o'xshasha ishlayapti va hikoyalarni kamaytirish mumkin. Biz hikoyalarning qiymatlarining qiymatiga qo'shilgan amallarni ko'rsatganimizni ko'rsatdik bu haqida ma'lumotlar ko'p narsa o'ylamaydi. Bizning usuli mashina o'rganish yoki shaxsiy hikoyalarni tahrirlash uchun o'rganish usullarini yordam berish uchun.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Chia sẻ những câu chuyện cá nhân là một khía cạnh cơ bản của hành vi xã hội con người vì nó giúp chia sẻ kinh nghiệm cuộc sống. Chúng ta có thể kể chuyện và dựa vào nền tảng để hiểu được ngữ cảnh, điểm tương đồng và khác biệt của họ. Đã có một nỗ lực rất lớn để phát triển các cỗ máy kể chuyện hoặc tạo ra các nhân vật. Tuy nhiên, chúng t ôi không thường tìm những người mẫu so sánh truyện kể. Nhiệm vụ này là một thử thách đáng kể đối với máy móc vì họ, như đôi khi chúng ta làm, thiếu nhận thức về nét giống nhau. Để giải quyết thử thách này, trước tiên chúng ta sẽ giới thiệu một tập thể các lời kể cá nhân được nói trên thế giới thực gồm có 10,296 các đoạn văn bản của 594. Thứ hai, chúng tôi yêu cầu các chuyên gia không thuật to án ghi chú những đi ều khoản đó dưới kiểu cách xã hội của Labov về các câu chuyện cá nhân (như là các kiểu hoạt động, hướng dẫn và các phân tích) và huấn luyện một chuyên gia đạt được 84.7=-điểm F cho các hợp đồng cao nhất. Cuối cùng, chúng ta kết hợp các câu chuyện và tìm hiểu xem liệu người ta có dựa vào khung hình của Labov để so s ánh truyện. Chúng tôi cho thấy những hành động sau đó là đánh giá của người kể chuyện về những thứ này là quan trọng nhất. Mục đích của chúng tôi là trợ giúp thông báo các phương pháp học máy móc nhằm mục đích học tập hay đại diện cho các đời tư.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Споделянето на лични разкази е фундаментален аспект на човешкото социално поведение, тъй като помага за споделянето на нашия житейски опит. Можем да разказваме истории и да разчитаме на нашия опит, за да разберем техния контекст, прилики и различия. Положени са значителни усилия за разработване на машини за разказване на истории или извличане на характеристиките на героите. Обикновено обаче не намираме модели, които сравняват разказите. Тази задача е изключително предизвикателна за машините, тъй като те, както понякога правим ние, нямат разбиране какво означава сходство. За да се справим с това предизвикателство, първо въвеждаме корпус от говорени в реалния свят лични разкази, съдържащи 10 296 разказни клаузи от 594 видео транскрипта. Второ, молим експертите, които не са разказващи, да анотират тези клаузи по социолингвистичния модел на Лабов за лични разкази (т.е. типове клаузи за действие, ориентация и оценка) и да обучават класификатор, който достига 84,7% за най-високо договорените клаузи. И накрая, сравняваме истории и изследваме дали хората имплицитно разчитат на рамката на Лабов, за да сравняват разказите. Показваме, че действията, последвани от оценката на разказвача на тези, са аспектите, които не експертите считат най-много. Нашият подход има за цел да помогне за информиране на методите за машинно обучение, насочени към изучаване или представяне на лични разкази.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>At dele personlige fortællinger er et grundlæggende aspekt af menneskelig social adfærd, da det hjælper med at dele vores livsoplevelser. Vi kan fortælle historier og stole på vores baggrund for at forstå deres kontekst, ligheder og forskelle. Der er gjort en betydelig indsats for at udvikle fortællingsmaskiner eller udlede karakterernes træk. Men vi finder normalt ikke modeller, der sammenligner fortællinger. Denne opgave er bemærkelsesværdig for maskiner, da de, som nogle gange gør vi, mangler forståelse af, hvad lighed betyder. For at løse denne udfordring introducerer vi først et korpus af talede personlige fortællinger i den virkelige verden bestående af 10.296 narrative klausuler fra 594 videoudskrifter. For det andet beder vi ikke-narrative eksperter om at kommentere disse klausuler under Labovs sociolingvistiske model af personlige fortællinger (dvs. handling, orientering og evaluering klausuler typer) og træne en klassifikation, der når 84,7% F-score for de højeste aftalte klausuler. Endelig matcher vi historier og undersøger, om folk implicit stoler på Labovs rammer til at sammenligne fortællinger. Vi viser, at handlinger efterfulgt af fortællerens evaluering af disse er de aspekter, ikke-eksperter overvejer mest. Vores tilgang er beregnet til at hjælpe med at informere maskinlæringsmetoder, der tager sigte på at studere eller repræsentere personlige fortællinger.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Het delen van persoonlijke verhalen is een fundamenteel aspect van menselijk sociaal gedrag omdat het helpt onze levenservaringen te delen. We kunnen verhalen vertellen en vertrouwen op onze achtergrond om hun context, overeenkomsten en verschillen te begrijpen. Er is een aanzienlijke inspanning gedaan om storytelling machines te ontwikkelen of de kenmerken van personages uit te voeren. Meestal vinden we echter geen modellen die verhalen vergelijken. Deze taak is opmerkelijk uitdagend voor machines omdat zij, zoals soms wij doen, geen begrip hebben van wat gelijkenis betekent. Om deze uitdaging aan te pakken, introduceren we eerst een corpus van real-world gesproken persoonlijke verhalen bestaande uit 10,296 narratieve clausules uit 594 video transcripts. Ten tweede vragen we niet-narratieve experts om deze clausules te annoteren onder Labov's sociolinguïstische model van persoonlijke verhalen (d.w.z. actie-, oriëntatie- en evaluatieclausules) en een classificator te trainen die 84,7% F-score bereikt voor de hoogst overeengekomen clausules. Tot slot matchen we verhalen en onderzoeken we of mensen impliciet vertrouwen op Labov's raamwerk om verhalen te vergelijken. We laten zien dat acties gevolgd door de evaluatie van deze door de verteller zijn de aspecten die niet-experts het meest overwegen. Onze aanpak is bedoeld om machine learning methodes te helpen informeren die gericht zijn op het bestuderen of weergeven van persoonlijke verhalen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Dijeljenje ličnih priča je osnovni aspekt ljudskog društvenog ponašanja jer pomaže dijeliti naše životno iskustvo. Možemo pričati priče i oslanjati se na našu pozadinu da razumijemo njihov kontekst, sličnosti i razlike. U razvoju uređaja za priču ili privlačenje karaktera napravljena je značajna napora. Međutim, obično ne nađemo modele koji uspoređuju priče. Ovaj zadatak je izuzetno izazovan za strojeve jer oni, kao ponekad radimo, nedostaju razumijevanje sličnosti. Za rješavanje ovog izazova, prvo predstavljamo korpus osobnih priče o stvarnom svijetu koja uključuje 10.296 priče klauzula iz 594 video transkripta. Drugo, tražimo stručnjaka bez priče da navode te klauzule pod sociolingustičkim modelom osobnih priče Labov a (tj. akcije, orijentacije i procjene klasifikacije) i treniraju klasifikatora koji dostiže 84,7% F-rezultata za najviše dogovorene klauzule. Konačno, odgovaramo pričama i istražujemo da li se ljudi implicitno oslanjaju na Labovov okvir za usporedbu priče. Pokazujemo da su postupke nakon procjene narratora ovih aspekta koje ne smatraju stručnjacima najviše. Naš pristup je namijenjen da pomognemo obavijestiti metode učenja strojeva usmjerene na učenje ili predstavljanje ličnih priča.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Persönliche Erzählungen zu teilen ist ein grundlegender Aspekt menschlichen sozialen Verhaltens, da es hilft, unsere Lebenserfahrungen zu teilen. Wir können Geschichten erzählen und uns auf unseren Hintergrund verlassen, um deren Kontext, Gemeinsamkeiten und Unterschiede zu verstehen. Es wurden erhebliche Anstrengungen unternommen, um Storytelling-Maschinen zu entwickeln oder die Merkmale der Charaktere abzuleiten. Allerdings finden wir normalerweise keine Modelle, die Narrative vergleichen. Diese Aufgabe ist für Maschinen bemerkenswert herausfordernd, da ihnen, wie manchmal auch uns, das Verständnis dafür fehlt, was Ähnlichkeit bedeutet. Um diese Herausforderung anzugehen, stellen wir zunächst einen Korpus realer gesprochener persönlicher Erzählungen vor, der 10,296-Erzählsätze aus 594-Videotranskripten umfasst. Zweitens bitten wir nicht-narrative Experten, diese Klauseln unter Labows soziolinguistischem Modell persönlicher Narrative (d.h. Aktions-, Orientierungs- und Bewertungsklausentypen) zu kommentieren und einen Klassifikator zu trainieren, der 84,7% F-Score für die am höchsten vereinbarten Sätze erreicht. Schließlich werden Geschichten abgeglichen und untersucht, ob sich Menschen implizit auf Labows Rahmen verlassen, um Narrative zu vergleichen. Wir zeigen, dass Handlungen, die auf die Bewertung durch den Erzähler folgen, die Aspekte sind, die Nicht-Experten am meisten berücksichtigen. Unser Ansatz soll helfen, Methoden des maschinellen Lernens zu informieren, die darauf abzielen, persönliche Narrative zu studieren oder darzustellen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Berbagi cerita pribadi adalah aspek dasar perilaku sosial manusia karena membantu berbagi pengalaman hidup kita. Kita bisa menceritakan cerita dan bergantung pada latar belakang kita untuk memahami konteks, persamaan, dan perbedaan mereka. Sebuah usaha besar telah dibuat untuk mengembangkan mesin cerita atau menyimpulkan karakter 'karakter. Namun, kita biasanya tidak menemukan model yang membandingkan cerita. Tugas ini sangat menantang bagi mesin karena mereka, seperti yang kadang-kadang kita lakukan, tidak mengerti apa artinya persamaan. Untuk mengatasi tantangan ini, kita pertama kali memperkenalkan sebuah korpus cerita pribadi yang dibicarakan di dunia nyata yang terdiri dari 10.296 klausul cerita dari 594 transkrip video. Kedua, kami meminta para ahli non-narratif untuk anotasi klausul-klausul tersebut di bawah model sosiolingvistik Labov cerita pribadi (i.e., tindakan, orientasi, dan tipe klausul evaluasi) dan melatih seorang klasifikator yang mencapai 84,7% F-skor untuk klausul yang setuju tertinggi. Akhirnya, kita cocok cerita dan mengeksplorasi apakah orang secara implicit bergantung pada cadangan Labov untuk membandingkan cerita. Kami menunjukkan bahwa tindakan diikuti oleh evaluasi narrator ini adalah aspek yang tidak ahli mempertimbangkan paling. pendekatan kami berniat untuk membantu informasi metode belajar mesin yang bertujuan untuk mempelajari atau mewakili cerita pribadi.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>Sharing personal narratives is a fundamental aspect of human social behavior as it helps share our lives experiences. ما می‌توانیم داستان‌ها را بگوییم و بر زمینه‌ی خود اعتماد کنیم تا موضوع، شبیه‌هایشان و تفاوتهایشان را درک کنیم. تلاش زیادی برای توسعه ماشین‌های داستان‌گذاری یا ویژگی‌های شخصیت‌ها انجام شده است. ولی ما معمولا مدل‌هایی را پیدا نمی‌کنیم که داستان‌ها را مقایسه می‌کنند. این وظیفه برای ماشینها بسیار مشکل است از زمانی که آنها، همانطور که بعضی وقتها انجام می دهیم، درک کردن شبیه به چه معنی ندارند. برای حل این چالش، ما اول یک جسد از داستانهای شخصی که در دنیا واقعی صحبت می‌کنند را معرفی می‌کنیم که شامل 10.296 کلاس داستانی از نوشته‌های ویدئو 594 است. دوم، ما از متخصص غیر داستان خواستیم که این قطعه‌ها را تحت مدل سوسیولینگ‌شناسی لابوف از داستان‌های شخصی (یعنی اقدام، رهبری و ارزیابی) نشان دهند و یک قطعه‌شناسی را آموزش دهند که به 84.7 درصد F-score برای قطعه‌های بالاترین موافق می‌شود. بالاخره، ما داستان‌ها را هماهنگ می‌کنیم و تحقیق می‌کنیم که آیا مردم به صورت معمولی بر چهارچوب لابوف اعتماد دارند تا داستان‌ها را مقایسه کنند. ما نشان می دهیم که اقدامات دنبال ارزیابی داستان این‌ها نقطه‌های غیر متخصص‌ها بیشترین مورد نظر می‌گیرند. دستور ما برای اطلاعات روش یادگیری ماشین هدف یادگیری یا نمایش داستان شخصی است.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Kushirikisha simulizi binafsi ni mtazamo wa msingi wa tabia za kijamii za binadamu kwa sababu inasaidia kushirikisha uzoefu wetu wa maisha. Tunaweza kuelezea hadithi na kutegemea nyuma yetu kuelewa mazingira yao, sawa na tofauti. Jitihada kubwa imetengenezwa kuendeleza mashine ya simulizi au kutengeneza tabia za wahusika. Hata hivyo, mara nyingi hatupati mifano inayolinganisha hadithi. Kazi hii ni changamoto kubwa kwa mashine kwa sababu, kama wakati mwingine tunavyofanya, hatuna uelewa wa maana yanayofanana. Ili kukabiliana na changamoto hii, kwanza tunaanzisha makampuni ya simulizi za binafsi zinazozungumzwa na maelezo 10,296 kutoka kwenye makala za video 594. Pili, tunawaomba wataalam wasioelezea taarifa hizo kwa kutumia mifano ya kijamii ya simulizi za watu binafsi (yaani hatua, orientation, na uchunguzi wa vifaa vya uchunguzi) na kuwafundisha wataalam anayefikia vipindi vya asilimia 84.7 kwa ajili ya vipengele vya juu vya makubaliano. Finally, we match stories and explore whether people implicitly rely on Labov's framework to compare narratives.  Tunaonyesha kwamba vitendo vinavyofuatiwa na tathmini ya simulizi hizi ni mambo ambazo wasio wataalam wanafikiri zaidi. Hatua yetu ni lengo la kusaidia kutoa taarifa za njia za kujifunza mashine zinazolenga kusoma au kuwakilisha simulizi binafsi.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_ko>개인 이야기를 공유하는 것은 인류 사회 행위의 기본적인 부분이다. 왜냐하면 우리의 생활 경험을 공유하는 데 도움이 되기 때문이다.우리는 이야기를 할 수 있고, 그들의 배경, 유사점, 차이를 우리의 배경에 의존해서 이해할 수 있다.이야기를 하는 기계를 개발하거나 캐릭터의 특징을 추측하기 위해 많은 노력을 기울였다.그러나 우리는 보통 서사를 비교하는 모델을 찾지 못한다.이 임무는 기계에 있어서 매우 도전적이다. 왜냐하면 그들은 우리가 때때로 하는 것처럼 유사성이 무엇을 의미하는지에 대한 이해가 부족하기 때문이다.이 도전에 대응하기 위해 우리는 먼저 진실한 세계의 구어 개인 서사 어료 라이브러리를 소개한다. 594개의 영상 기록 중의 10296개의 서사 종문을 포함한다.그 다음으로 우리는 비서사 전문가가 라보프의 개인 서사의 사회언어학 모델(즉, 동작, 취향과 평가 종문 유형)에 따라 이 종문에 대한 주석을 하고 분류기를 훈련시켜 가장 일치 동의하는 종문의 F점수가 84.7%에 달하도록 요구한다.마지막으로 우리는 이야기와 일치하고 사람들이 라포프의 틀에 은근히 의존해서 서사를 비교하는지 탐색한다.우리는 서술자가 이런 문제에 대한 평가 이후의 행동은 비전문가들이 가장 주목하는 부분이라고 밝혔다.우리의 방법은 개인의 서사를 연구하거나 표현하기 위한 기계 학습 방법에 대한 정보를 제공하는 데 목적을 두고 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_tr>Şahsy hekaýatlary paylaşmak adamlaryň sosyal hereketleriniň esasy aspektidir, onuň biziň durmuşymyzyň tecrübesimizi paylaşmagyna kömek edip ýöreýär. Biz hekaýalary aýdyp bileris we arkaýymyza öz kontekstlerini, meňzeşliklerini we üýtgeşiklerini düşünmek üçin bilip bileris. Geçmiş çykarma makinelerini geliştirmek ýada karakterlerniň özelliklerini çykarmak üçin örän wajyp boldy. Adatça, hekaýatlary ýalñyşlyk eden nusgalary tapmaýarys. Bu zady maşynlaryň üçin gaty kynçylykly.sebäbi käwagt edip bilýän ýaly meňzeşlik näme diýjek bolýandygyny düşünmek ýok. Bu kynçylyky çözmek üçin ilkinji gezek 594 wideo çykyşyndan 10,296 hekaýat düzgünlerini çykar. Ikinjisi, biz bu klawutlary Labowyň sosyal dil çykyşlaryň (meselâ, hereket, orjentasy we çykyş klasifikalaryň) astyndaky klawutlary ýazyklamak isleýäris we bu klasifikaty üçin 84.7% F sany derejesi bar. Soňunda, biz hekaýalary eşleýäris we adamlar Labowyň çerçevesine pikir etýändigini gözləýäris. Biz bu taryhçylaryň deňlemeginiň yzyndaky hereketleriň uzmançylyklaryň iň köp pikir edýän aspektleri diýip görkeýäris. Biziň golamyz maşynlary öwrenmek yöntemlerini öwrenmek ýa-da şahsy hekaýatlary temsil etmek üçin kömek etmek üçin maksat edildi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Die deel van persoonlike narraties is 'n fundamentale aspekt van menslike sosiale gedrag, omdat dit hulp ons lewe erfarings deel. Ons kan stories vertel en op ons agtergrond vertel om hul konteks, gelykenisse en verskillinge te verstaan. 'n Groot versoek is gemaak tot die ontwikkeling van storytelling masjiene of die inligting van karakters se funksies. Maar ons vind nie gewoonlik modele wat vergelyk narraties nie. Hierdie taak is betekeurig aanvaardig vir masjiene sedert hulle, soos soms ons doen, het 'n verstanding van wat gelykheid beteken. Om hierdie uitdrukking te raak, introduseer ons eerste 'n korpus van reël-wêreld gespreek persoonlike narratiewe met 10,296 narratiewe klauses van 594 video transkripte. Tweede, ons vra nie-narratiewe eksperte om dié klauses onder Labov s e sosiallingwisiese model van persoonlike narraties (i.e. aksie, oriëntasie, en evalueringsklause tipes) te annoteer en 'n klassifiseerder wat 84.7% F- telling bereik vir die hoogste ooreenkomste klauses. Eindelik, on s ooreenstem stories en ondersoek of mense implisiteit op Labov se raamwerk vertrou om narraties te vergelyk. Ons wys dat aksies gevolg deur die narrator se evaluasie van hierdie is die aspekte wat nie-eksperte oorskou is nie. Ons toegang is bedoel om masjien leer metodes te informeer wat bedoel is om persoonlike narraties te studeer of te verteenwoordig.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Tregimi i tregimeve personale është një aspekt themelor i sjelljes sociale njerëzore pasi ndihmon të ndajmë përvojat tona të jetës. Ne mund të tregojmë histori dhe të mbështetemi në sfondin tonë për të kuptuar kontekstin e tyre, ngjashmëritë dhe dallimet. Një përpjekje thelbësore është bërë për zhvillimin e makinave treguese tregimesh apo përfundimin e karaktereve. Megjithatë, ne zakonisht nuk gjejmë modele që krahasojnë tregimet. Kjo detyrë është shumë e vështirë për makinat pasi ato, siç bëjmë ndonjëherë ne, nuk kuptojnë se çfarë do të thotë ngjashmëria. Për të trajtuar këtë sfidë, ne së pari prezantojmë një korpus tregimesh personale të folura në botën reale që përfshijnë 10,296 klauzula treguese nga 594 video transkripte. Së dyti, ne i kërkojmë ekspertëve jo-tregues të anotojnë këto klauzula në kuadrin e modelit sociolingvistik të tregimeve personale të Labov (pra, veprimi, orientimi dhe tipi i klauzuleve të vlerësimit) dhe të trajnojnë një klasifikues që arrin 84.7% pikë F për klauzulet më të rënda dakord. Më në fund, ne përputhemi me historitë dhe eksplorojmë nëse njerëzit mbështeten implicitisht në kuadrin e Labov për të krahasuar tregimet. Ne tregojmë se veprimet e ndjekur nga vlerësimi i treguesit për këto janë aspektet që jo-ekspertët konsiderojnë më shumë. Përqasja jonë synon të ndihmojë në informimin e metodave të mësimit të makinave që synojnë studimin apo përfaqësimin e tregimeve personale.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>የግዛት ታሪክ ማጋራት የሰው ማኅበራዊ ሁኔታ መሠረት ነው፤ የሕይወትን እድል ፈቃድ ማጋራት ይረዳል፡፡ ታሪኮችን እናስታውቃለን በመሬታችንም ላይ እናምናለን፣ ሥርዓታቸውን እናስተውል ዘንድ እናስፈልጋለን፡፡ የታሪክ ዜና መሳሪያዎች ወይም የፊደል ቅርጽ ማደላቀል ተደረገ፡፡ ነገር ግን በዜና የሚተካክሉ ምሳሌዎችን አያገኘንም፡፡ ይህ ስራ ለመሳሪያዎች የሚያስቃወም ነው፤ አንዳንድ ጊዜ እናደርጋለን እንደምናስተካከል ምን እንደሆነ ማስተዋል አያስፈልግም፡፡ ይህንን ጥያቄ ለመቀበል በመጀመሪያ የቅርብ ዓለም የተናገረውን የብሔራዊ ዝርዝርቶች 10,296 ታሪክ ክፍሎች ከ594 ቪዲዮ ጽሑፎች እናሳውቃለን፡፡ በሁለተኛው፣ ከሎቪ ማኅበራዊ ቋንቋዊ ምሳሌ በታች ያሉትን ክፍተቶችን እናሳውቃለን፡፡ በመጨረሻውም፣ ሰዎች ተሪኮችን ለማስተካከል በLabov ፍሬም ላይ እንዲታመኑ እናሳውቃለን፡፡ የእነዚህ ተርጓሚዎች ማስታወቂያው የተከተለውን ተግባሮች ብዙውን የሚያስተውሉ ናቸው ብለን እናሳያቸዋለን፡፡ የሥርዓታችን ጉዳይ የህዝብ ታሪክ ለማስተማር ወይም ለማስተካከል የመኪን ትምህርት ማድረጉን ለማሳወቅ ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Անձնական պատմությունների կիսվելը մարդկային սոցիալական վարքագիծի հիմնական ասպեկտ է, քանի որ այն օգնում է կիսվել մեր կյանքի փորձով: We can tell stories and rely on our background to understand their context, similarities, and differences.  Մեծ ջանքեր են արվել պատմություններ պատմելու մեքենաների զարգացման կամ հերոսների հատկանիշների հետևանքի համար: Այնուամենայնիվ, մենք սովորաբար չենք գտնում մոդելներ, որոնք համեմատում են պատմությունները: Այս խնդիրը մեքենաների համար շատ դժվար է, որովհետև նրանք, ինչպես երբեմն մենք, չեն հասկանում, թե ինչ է նման նշանակում: Այս մարտահրավերի լուծման համար մենք առաջին անգամ ներկայացնում ենք իրական աշխարհում խոսվող անձնական պատմություններ, որոնք բաղկացած են 10,29 պատմությունների բառերից, որոնք բաղկացած են 554 տեսագրություններից: Երկրորդ, մենք խնդրում ենք ոչ պատմվածքային մասնագետներին նշել Լաբովի անձնական պատմվածքների սոցիոլեզվաբանական մոդելի այդ բառերը (այսինքն, գործողություն, ուղղություն և գնահատման բառերի տեսակներ) և ուսուցանել դասակարգչին, որը հասնում է 84.7 տոկոսի F-գնահատականի ամենաբարձր համաձայն բառերի Վերջապես, մենք համապատասխանում ենք պատմություններին և ուսումնասիրում, արդյոք մարդիկ միանգամայն հույս են տալիս Լաբուի կառուցվածքի վրա, որպեսզի համեմատենք պատմությունները: Մենք ցույց ենք տալիս, որ այն գործողությունները, որոնց հետևում է պատմողի գնահատումը սրանց մասին, այն ասպեկտներն են, որոնք ոչ մասնագետները ամենաշատն են համարում: Մեր մոտեցումը նպատակն է օգնել մեքենային ուսումնասիրության մեթոդներ տեղեկացնել, որոնք նպատակով են ուսումնասիրել կամ ներկայացնել անձնական պատմություններ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Kişisel hekayələri paylaşmaq insan sosyal davranışının əsas hissəsi, həyatımızın təcrübələrini paylaşmasına kömək edir. Biz hekayələri danışa bilərik və onların məsələlərini, məsələlərini və fərqlərini anlamaq üçün arxa planımıza təvəkkül edərik. Hikayə danışma makinelərini və karakterlərin özelliklərini inkişaf etmək üçün çox böyük çabalar edildi. Ancaq, biz genellikle hekayələri salmaq üçün modelləri tapmırıq. Bu iş maşınlar üçün çox çətin olandır, çünki, bəzi vaxtlarda onların bənzərinin nə anlama gələcəyini bilmədikləri kimi. Bu çətinlikdən çəkinmək üçün ilk dəfə biz 594 video transkriptdən 10.296 hekayət klauzulu olan gerçek dünyada danışan kişisel hekayələrin korpusu tanıyırıq. İkincisi, biz Labov'un sosyal dilindəki kişisel hekayələrin model i altında bu klauzulu bildirmələrini istəyirik və ən yüksək müzakirə olunan klauzulu üçün 84,7% F-score təhsil edəni təhsil edirik. Sonunda, biz hekayələrə uyuşuruq və insanların hekayələrini salmaq üçün Labov'un çerçivesinə təvəkkül edir. Biz göstəririk ki, bu hekayətlərin değerlendirməsinin ardınca gələn əməllərin ən çox xəbərdar olmayan aspektləridir. Bizim yaxınlığımız maşın öyrənmə metodlarını öyrənmək və ya kişisel hekayələri təsdiqləmək üçün yardım etmək məqsədildir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>ব্যক্তিগত গল্প শেয়ার করা হচ্ছে মানুষের সামাজিক আচরণের মৌলিক প্রতিক্রিয়া, কারণ এটা আমাদের জীবনের অভিজ্ঞতা শেয়া আমরা গল্প বলতে পারি এবং আমাদের পটভূমিতে নির্ভর করতে পারি তাদের প্রেক্ষাপট, সমতা এবং পার্থক্য বুঝতে। গল্পের গল্প প্রকাশিত মেশিন বা অক্ষরের বৈশিষ্ট্য উন্নয়নের জন্য একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ প্রচেষ্টা করা হয়েছে। তবে আমরা সাধারণত গল্পের তুলনায় মডেল খুঁজে পাই না। মেশিনের জন্য এই কাজ চমৎকার চ্যালেঞ্জ হচ্ছে যেহেতু মাঝে মাঝে মাঝে মাঝে মাঝে আমরা কি করি তা বুঝতে পারি না। এই চ্যালেঞ্জের কথা বলার জন্য আমরা প্রথমে ব্যক্তিগত ব্যক্তিগত গল্পের একটি কোর্পাস উপস্থাপন করেছি যার মধ্যে ৫৯৪ ভিডিও ট্রান্সপ্রিপ্ট থে দ্বিতীয়, আমরা বিশেষজ্ঞদের জিজ্ঞাসা করছি যে ল্যাবেভের সামাজিক ভাষায় ব্যক্তিগত গল্পের মোডেলের অধীনে এই ধরনের বিষয়গুলোকে ঘোষণা করার জন্য (যেমন কাজ, দিকে নির্দেশ এবং মূল্যায়নের ধরন)  শেষ পর্যন্ত আমরা গল্পের সাথে মিলি এবং খুঁজে বের করি ল্যাবেভের কাঠামোর উপর নির্ভর করি কিনা তার গল্পের তুলনায়। We show that actions followed by the narrator's evaluation of these are the aspects non-experts consider the most.  আমাদের প্রতিযোগিতার উদ্দেশ্য হচ্ছে মেশিনের শিক্ষা পদ্ধতি জানানোর যার লক্ষ্য হচ্ছে ব্যক্তিগত গল্প পড়া অথবা প</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>Compartir narratives personals és un aspecte fonamental del comportament social humà perquè ajuda a compartir les nostres experiències de vida. Podem explicar històries i confiar en el nostre passat per entendre el seu context, similituds i diferències. S'ha fet un esforç substancial per desenvolupar màquines de narració o inferir les característiques dels caràcters. However, we don't usually find models that compare narratives.  Aquesta tasca és increïblement difícil per a les màquines, perquè, com a vegades fem, no entenen el que significa la similitud. Per abordar aquest repte, vam introduir primer un cos de narratives personals parlades en el món real que compten 10.296 clàusules narratives de 594 vídeo transcripts. Segon, demanem als experts no narrativs que anotin aquestes clàusules sota el model sociolingüístic de la Labov de narrative s personals (i.e., tipus d'acció, orientació i clàusules d'evaluació) i que entrenen un classificador que arribi a l'84,7% de puntuació F per a les clàusules més acordades. Finalment, ens ajustam a les històries i explorem si la gent confia implícitament en el marc de Labov per comparar narratives. Mostrem que les accions seguides de l'evaluació dels narradors s ón els aspectes que els no experts consideren més. El nostre enfocament està destinat a ajudar a informar mètodes d'aprenentatge màquinari destinats a estudiar o representar narratives personals.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>Dijeljenje ličnih priča je osnovni aspekt ljudskog socijalnog ponašanja jer pomaže dijeliti naše iskustvo života. Možemo ispričati priče i oslanjati se na našu pozadinu da razumijemo njihov kontekst, sličnosti i razlike. Veliki napor je napravljen u razvoju strojeva za priču ili privlačenje karaktera. Međutim, obično ne nađemo modele koji uspoređuju priče. Ovaj zadatak je izuzetno izazovan za strojeve, jer oni, kao ponekad radimo, nedostaju razumijevanje sličnosti. Za rješavanje ovog izazova, prvo predstavljamo korpus stvarnog svijeta govorenih ličnih priča, uključujući 10.296 priče klauzula iz 594 video transkripta. Drugo, tražimo nekoraktivne stručnjake da annotiraju te klauzule pod Labovskim sociolingustičkim modelom ličnih priča (tj. akcija, orijentacija i klasifikacija za procjenu) i treniraju klasifikatora koji dostigne 84,7% F-rezultata za najviše dogovorene klauzule. Konačno, odgovaramo pričama i istražujemo da li se ljudi implicitno oslanjaju na Labovov okvir za usporedbu priče. Pokazujemo da su akcije koje prate procjena narratora ovih aspekta koje ne smatraju stručnjacima najviše. Naš pristup je namijenjen da pomognemo da obavijestimo metode učenja mašina usmjerene na učenje ili predstavljanje ličnih priča.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Isiklike jutustuste jagamine on inimeste sotsiaalse käitumise põhiaspekt, kuna see aitab jagada meie elukogemusi. Me saame rääkida lugusid ja toetuda oma taustale, et mõista nende konteksti, sarnasusi ja erinevusi. Märkimisväärseid jõupingutusi on tehtud jutustamise masinate arendamiseks või tegelaste omaduste järeldamiseks. Siiski ei leia me tavaliselt mudeleid, mis võrdlevad narratiive. See ülesanne on masinate jaoks märkimisväärselt keeruline, sest neil, nagu mõnikord meiegi, puudub arusaam sarnasusest. Selle väljakutse lahendamiseks tutvustame esmalt korpust reaalses maailmas räägitavatest isiklikest narratiividest, mis sisaldab 10 296 narratiivset klauslit 594 videotranskriptsioonist. Teiseks palume mitteknarratiivsetel ekspertidel märkida need klauslid Labovi sotsiolingvistilise isikliku narratiivi mudeli (st tegevus-, orientatsioon- ja hindamisklauslite tüübid) alusel ning koolitada klassifitseerijat, mis jõuab 84,7% F-skoorini kõrgeimate kokkulepitud klauslite puhul. Lõpuks sobitame lugusid ja uurime, kas inimesed loodavad kaudselt Labovi raamistikule narratiivide võrdlemisel. Näitame, et tegevused, millele järgneb jutustaja hinnang neile, on aspektid, mida mitteaksperdid peavad kõige rohkem. Meie lähenemisviis on mõeldud aitama teavitada masinõppe meetodeid, mis on suunatud isiklike narratiivide uurimisele või esindamisele.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_cs>Sdílení osobních příběhů je základním aspektem lidského sociálního chování, protože pomáhá sdílet naše životní zkušenosti. Můžeme vyprávět příběhy a spoléhat na naše zázemí, abychom porozuměli jejich kontextu, podobnostem a rozdílům. Bylo vynaloženo značné úsilí na vývoj strojů pro vyprávění příběhů nebo odvození rysů postav. Obvykle však nenajdeme modely, které by srovnávaly příběhy. Tento úkol je pro stroje pozoruhodně náročný, protože jim, jako někdy děláme my, chybí pochopení toho, co znamená podobnost. Pro řešení této výzvy nejprve představujeme korpus mluvených osobních vyprávění v reálném světě obsahující 10,296 narativní věty z 594 video transkriptů. Za druhé žádáme non-narativní odborníky, aby tyto věty anotovali v Labově sociolingvistickém modelu osobních vyprávění (tj. akční, orientační a hodnotící klauzule) a trénovali klasifikátor, který dosahuje 84,7% F skóre pro nejvyšší dohodnuté klauzule. Na závěr porovnáváme příběhy a zkoumáme, zda lidé implicitně spoléhají na Labovův rámec při srovnávání příběhů. Ukazujeme, že akce následující vypravěčovým hodnocením těchto aspektů jsou aspekty, které nespecialisté považují za nejvíce. Náš přístup má za cíl pomoci informovat metody strojového učení zaměřené na studium nebo reprezentování osobních vyprávění.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Henkilökohtaisten kertomusten jakaminen on olennainen osa ihmisen sosiaalista käyttäytymistä, sillä se auttaa jakamaan elämänkokemuksiamme. Voimme kertoa tarinoita ja luottaa taustaamme ymmärtääksemme niiden kontekstia, yhtäläisyyksiä ja eroja. Tarinankertoja ja hahmojen ominaisuuksia on pyritty kehittämään merkittävästi. Emme kuitenkaan yleensä löydä malleja, jotka vertailevat kertomuksia. Tämä tehtävä on erittäin haastava koneille, koska ne, kuten joskus teemme, eivät ymmärrä, mitä samankaltaisuus tarkoittaa. Haasteeseen vastaamiseksi esittelemme ensin korpusen, joka sisältää 10 296 narratiivista lausetta 594 videotranskriptiosta. Toiseksi pyydämme ei-narratiivisia asiantuntijoita tekemään huomautuksia näihin lauseisiin Labovin sosiokielisessä henkilökohtaisen kerronnan mallissa (eli toiminta-, orientaatio- ja arviointilauseketyypit) ja kouluttamaan luokittelijaa, joka saavuttaa 84,7% F-pisteen korkeimmilla sovituilla lauseilla. Lopuksi vertailemme tarinoita ja selvitämme, tukeutuvatko ihmiset implisiittisesti Labovin viitekehykseen kertomusten vertailussa. Osoitamme, että toimet, joita seuraa kertojan arvio näistä, ovat asioita, joita ei-asiantuntijat pitävät eniten. Lähestymistapamme tarkoituksena on auttaa ohjaamaan koneoppimismenetelmiä, jotka on tarkoitettu henkilökohtaisten kertomusten tutkimiseen tai esittämiseen.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_sk>Delitev osebnih pripovedi je temeljni vidik človeškega družbenega vedenja, saj pomaga deliti naše življenjske izkušnje. Pripovedujemo lahko zgodbe in se zanašamo na svoje ozadje, da razumemo njihov kontekst, podobnosti in razlike. Pomembno si je bilo prizadevati za razvoj strojev za pripovedovanje zgodb ali sklepanje značilnosti likov. Vendar običajno ne najdemo modelov, ki bi primerjali pripovedi. Ta naloga je izjemno zahtevna za stroje, saj tako kot včasih mi ne razumemo, kaj pomeni podobnost. Za reševanje tega izziva najprej predstavimo korpus resnično govorjenih osebnih pripovedi, ki vsebuje 10.296 pripovednih klavzul iz 594 video transkripcij. Drugič, prosimo strokovnjake, ki niso pripovedne, da navedejo te klavzule pod Labovim sociolingvističnim modelom osebnih pripovedi (tj. vrste akcijskih, orientacijskih in evalvacijskih klavzul) in usposobijo klasifikatorja, ki doseže 84,7% F-score za najvišje dogovorjene klavzule. Na koncu primerjamo zgodbe in raziskujemo, ali se ljudje implicitno zanašajo na Labov okvir za primerjavo zgodb. Pokazujemo, da so dejanja, ki jim sledi pripovedovalčeva ocena teh vidikov, ki jih ne upoštevajo strokovnjaki. Naš pristop je namenjen informacijam o metodah strojnega učenja, namenjenih preučevanju ali predstavljanju osebnih pripovedi.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Sharing hadiyadai na kansi ni'ima ne daga aikin jamii mutane kamar yadda yana taimakon su shara masu'anar rãyukanmu. Kana iya gaya hadiyado kuma munã dõgara a kan bangonmu dõmin mu fahimta mazauninsu, da misãlinsu da sãɓãni. An sami aikin muhimmi zuwa ta buɗe kayan faɗin manyan ayuka ko kuma an buga wasu tayari. A lokacin da ba mu iya sãmun misãlai da ke sammenliki lãbãrayen. Wannan aikin yana mai shano ga mashinaikin, dõmin, kamar da za mu aikata, bã mu fahimta da abin da ke daidai. To address this challenge, we first introduce a corpus of real-world spoken personal narratives comprising 10,296 narrative clauses from 594 video transcripts.  Dukkan na, Munã tambayi masu ƙidãya masu cikin ma'anar wannan musamman a ƙarami cikin mazaɓan aikin Lab (misali, hanyoyi, da nau'i-nau'in rubutu da kakwai) kuma mu sanar da mai fasalkafi wanda ya isa matsayin 84.7% F-score wa makusanta da aka sani. Haƙĩƙa, Munã yi daidai da hadiyado kuma munã sami ko mutane yana dõgara a kan firam na Lab ko da misalin lãbãri. Tuna nũna cewa aikin da aka bi qiimamin waɗannan masu kambu ne waɗanda bã masu fitarwa ba su ƙaddara mafi yawa. Mataimakinmu na yi nufin in gaya wa zanan sanar da mashinaki don a yi amfani da karatun ko kuma a wakilisha hadiyadan bayani.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_jv>Nambah aturan persilangan sing paling budhakan dumadhi sak nguasai perusahaan anyar tentang tanggal Awak dhéwé iso nglanggar aturan lan ijol-ijolan winih dhéwé kanggo ngerasakno kontèké, seneng kabèh lan mungkar-mungkar. deep politenessoffpolite, "), and when there is a change ("assertive Mbok iki dadi akeh barang-barang nggo kelas karo milih sedhaya, dadi kapan karo awak dhéwé, kuwi mau ngerti apa sing dikarepaké. Mbok nganggo urêm iki, dhéwé ngerasakno perusahaan karo perusahaan anyar-perusahaan sing basa gambar 10.tasklist Pawis kabèh, awak dhéwé éntukno karo perusahaan sing gak nglanggar petani sing berarti winih dhéwé (SMS). Eremut, kita mbukak dadi nan ngerasara karo akeh wong liyane sak luwih dumaten Labow's rampungan kanggo nggawe tarjamahan. Awak dhéwé éntuk aksi sing berarti kanggo nggawe gerakan karo perusahaan sing gak bênêr nik angka sing luwih apik dhéwé. Awakdhéwé wis ngerasakno ngéwangi kanggo ngerasakno ngerwih maning ingkang nggambar obah-obahan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>לחלוק סיפורים אישיים הוא היבט בסיסי של התנהגות חברתית אנושית, כיוון שזה עוזר לחלוק את חוויות חיינו. אנחנו יכולים לספר סיפורים ולסמוך על הרקע שלנו כדי להבין את הקשר שלהם, הדמות שלהם, והשונים. מאמץ משמעותי נעשה בפיתוח מכונות סיפור סיפורים או להוציא תכונות של דמויות. בכל אופן, אנחנו בדרך כלל לא מוצאים דוגמנים שישוואים סיפורים. המשימה הזאת מאתגרת באופן יוצא דופן למכונות, מכיוון שהם, כפי שאנחנו עושים לפעמים, חסרים להבין מה התשובה. כדי להתמודד עם האתגר הזה, אנחנו קודם מכירים קורפוס של סיפורים אישיים מדברים בעולם האמיתי שמכילים 10,296 פסקים סיפורים מ-594 תוצאות וידאו. שנית, אנו מבקשים ממומחים לא-סיפורים לציין את הציוקים האלה תחת המודל הסוציולינגוסטי של לאב של סיפורים אישיים (כלומר, פעולה, כיוון, וטיפוס הערכה) ולאימון מסווג שמגיע ל-84.7% נקודת F עבור הציוקים המסכמים ביותר. סוף סוף, אנחנו מתאימים לסיפורים ולחקור אם אנשים סומכים באופן מילוי על המסגרת של לאב כדי להשוות סיפורים. אנו מראים שהפעולות שלאחר הן הערכה של הסיפור של אלה הם היבטים שאינם מומחים שוקלים ביותר. Our approach is intended to help inform machine learning methods aimed at studying or representing personal narratives.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>མི་དང་མི་སྒེར་གྱི་གནད་དོན་འདྲ་བརྗོད་ནི་མིའི་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་འབྲེལ་བ་དང་མཉམ་དུ་འཇུག་པའི་ཆེན་པོ་ཞིག་རེད། ང་ཚོས་སྒྲུང་ཚོར་བཤད་དང་། རྒྱབ་ལྗོངས་ལ་ཡོད་པར་ཁོ་ཚོའི་ཁྲོད་དང་། འདྲ་བ་དང་ཁྱད་པར་རྟོགས་ཐུབ། storytelling machines or inferring characters' features have been developed towards developing a substantial effort. ཡིན་ནའང་ང་ཚོས་སྒྲུང་གཏོང་བྱེད་པའི་མིག་ཆས་རྣམས་མེད་པར། བྱ་འགུལ་འདི་ལ་འཛོམས་ཁང་ཆེན་པོ་ཞིག་ཡིན་པས། མཚམས་རེར་ང་ཚོས་གནས་ཚུལ་མཉམ་དུ་མཐུན་འགྱུར་བའི་གོ་སྐབས་ལ། གདོང་ལེན་འདི་ལ་བཟོ་བཅོས་ནི་ང་ཚོས་ཐོག་དང་པོ་དེ་རྣམས་འཛམ་གླིང་མོངས་དང་མི་སྤྲོད་པའི་མིང་རྣམས་ཀྱི་གཏམ་གླེང་སྒྲོམ་ནང་གི་མ གཉིས་པ། ང་ཚོས་ཀྱིས་གནད་དོན་དག་གི་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་སྡུད་མིན་པའི་ཁྱད་ཆོས་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་བློ་གཏོང་བ་དང་། མཐའ་མར་ང་ཚོས་སྒྲུང་དང་མཉམ་དུ་མཐུན་པ་དང་བསམ་དགོས་མིན་ཡང་ལྟ་བུའི་གཞུང་ཐོག་ནས་སྔོན་སྒྲིག་གཏོང་། ང་ཚོས་བྱ་འགུལ་གྱི་རྗེས་སུ་འབོར་བ་ཡིན་པའི་དཔོན་རིགས་ཀྱི་དཔོན་རྐྱེན་མེད་པའི་གྲངས་ཀ་དེ་གང་ཟག་ཡིན་ན། ང་ཚོའི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་འདིས་མ་ལག་གི་སློབ་ནུས་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་སྟོན་པར་རོགས་རམ་གནང་བ་ཡིན་པ་དང་། མི་སྒེར་གྱི་གཏོང་</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>On-The-Fly Information Retrieval Augmentation for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">Language Models</a></title>
      <author><first>Hai</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>David</first><last>McAllester</last></author>
      <pages>114–119</pages>
      <abstract>Here we experiment with the use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">information retrieval</a> as an augmentation for pre-trained language models. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">text corpus</a> used in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">information retrieval</a> can be viewed as form of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Episodic_memory">episodic memory</a> which grows over time. By augmenting GPT 2.0 with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval">information retrieval</a> we achieve a zero shot 15 % relative reduction in perplexity on Gigaword corpus without any re-training. We also validate our IR augmentation on an event co-reference task.</abstract>
      <url hash="fd6b3f36">2020.nuse-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2020.nuse-1.14</doi>
      <video href="http://slideslive.com/38929754" />
      <bibkey>wang-mcallester-2020-fly</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ecb">ECB+</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>