<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2020.ldl">
  <volume id="1">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 7th Workshop on Linked Data in Linguistics (LDL-2020)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Maxim</first><last>Ionov</last></editor>
      <editor><first>John P.</first><last>McCrae</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Christian</first><last>Chiarcos</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Thierry</first><last>Declerck</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Julia</first><last>Bosque-Gil</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jorge</first><last>Gracia</last></editor>
      <publisher>European Language Resources Association</publisher>
      <address>Marseille, France</address>
      <month>May</month>
      <year>2020</year>
      <isbn>979-10-95546-36-8</isbn>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="f15e978d">2020.ldl-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>ldl-2020-linked</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Transforming the Cologne Digital Sanskrit Dictionaries into OntoLex-Lemon<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>anskrit Dictionaries into <fixed-case>O</fixed-case>nto<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>ex-Lemon</title>
      <author><first>Francisco</first><last>Mondaca</last></author>
      <author><first>Felix</first><last>Rau</last></author>
      <pages>11–14</pages>
      <abstract>The Cologne Digital Sanskrit Dictionaries (CDSD) is a large collection of complex digitized Sanskrit dictionaries, consisting of over thirty-five works, and is the most prominent collection of Sanskrit dictionaries worldwide. In this paper we evaluate two methods for transforming the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conformational_isomerism">CDSD</a> into Ontolex-Lemon based on a modelling exercise. The first method that we evaluate consists of applying <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RDFa">RDFa</a> to the existent TEI-P5 files. The second method consists of transforming the TEI-encoded dictionaries into new files containing RDF triples modelled in OntoLex-Lemon. As a result of the modelling exercise we choose the second method : to transform TEI-encoded lexical data into Ontolex-Lemon by creating new files containing exclusively RDF triples.</abstract>
      <url hash="7bb4408c">2020.ldl-1.2</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>mondaca-rau-2020-transforming</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Challenges of Word Sense Alignment : Portuguese Language Resources<fixed-case>P</fixed-case>ortuguese Language Resources</title>
      <author><first>Ana</first><last>Salgado</last></author>
      <author><first>Sina</first><last>Ahmadi</last></author>
      <author><first>Alberto</first><last>Simões</last></author>
      <author><first>John Philip</first><last>McCrae</last></author>
      <author><first>Rute</first><last>Costa</last></author>
      <pages>45–51</pages>
      <abstract>This paper reports on an ongoing task of monolingual word sense alignment in which a comparative study between the Portuguese Academy of Sciences Dictionary and the Dicionrio Aberto is carried out in the context of the ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) project. Word sense alignment involves searching for matching senses within dictionary entries of different lexical resources and linking them, which poses significant challenges. The lexicographic criteria are not always entirely consistent within individual dictionaries and even less so across different projects where different options may have been assumed in terms of structure and especially wording techniques of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gloss_(annotation)">lexicographic glosses</a>. This hinders the task of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sensory_nervous_system">matching senses</a>. We aim to present our annotation workflow in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portuguese_language">Portuguese</a> using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web">Semantic Web technologies</a>. The results obtained are useful for the discussion within the community.</abstract>
      <url hash="71ecc019">2020.ldl-1.7</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>salgado-etal-2020-challenges</bibkey>
    <title_ar>تحديات محاذاة Word Sense: موارد اللغة البرتغالية</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Desafios do Alinhamento do Sentido das Palavras: Recursos da Língua Portuguesa</title_pt>
      <title_es>Retos de la alineación del sentido de las palabras: recursos del idioma</title_es>
      <title_ja>ワードセンスアライメントの課題：ポルトガル語リソース</title_ja>
      <title_hi>शब्द भावना संरेखण की चुनौतियां: पुर्तगाली भाषा संसाधन</title_hi>
      <title_zh>词义对齐挑战:葡萄牙语资源</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Dúshláin Ailínithe Focal: Acmhainní Teanga Portaingéile</title_ga>
      <title_ka>სიტყვების შეცდომის შეცდომა: პორტეგური ენის რესურსი</title_ka>
      <title_hu>A Word Sense igazításának kihívásai: Portugál nyelvi források</title_hu>
      <title_el>Προκλήσεις της ευθυγράμμισης της αίσθησης λέξεων: Πόροι πορτογαλικής γλώσσας</title_el>
      <title_lt>Sąvokų jautrumo suderinimo iššūkiai: Portugalijos kalbos ištekliai</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Предизвики на израмнување на чувството на зборовите: Португалски јазички ресурси</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Challenges of Word Sense Alignment: Sumber Bahasa Portugis</title_ms>
      <title_mt>Sfidi ta’ Allinjament tas-Sens tal-Kliem: Riżorsi tal-Lingwa Portugiża</title_mt>
      <title_it>Sfide dell'allineamento del senso delle parole: risorse linguistiche portoghesi</title_it>
      <title_mn>Үүний мэдрэмжлэх хэлбэрүүдийн шалгалт: Португалийн хэл нөөц</title_mn>
      <title_no>Utfordringar for ordførselsjustering: Portuguese Language Resources</title_no>
      <title_kk>Сөзді сезім туралы түрлендіру шақырулары: Португалия тіл ресурстары</title_kk>
      <title_ml>വാക്കിന്റെ സെന്‍സിന്റെ സങ്കേതം: പോര്‍ട്ടുഗീഷ് ഭാഷ വിഭവങ്ങള്‍</title_ml>
      <title_pl>Wyzwania związane z dostosowaniem zmysłu słowa: zasoby języka portugalskiego</title_pl>
      <title_si>පොර්ටුගුලි භාෂාව සම්පූර්ණය සම්පූර්ණය</title_si>
      <title_ro>Provocările alinierii sensului Word: Resurse lingvistice portugheze</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Izazovi prikazivanja reči: Portugalski jezički resursi</title_sr>
      <title_so>Challenges of Word Sense Alignment: Resources of Burtuqiis</title_so>
      <title_sv>Utmaningar med Word Sense Alignment: Portugisiska språkresurser</title_sv>
      <title_ur>Word Sense Alignment کی چالج: Portuguese Language Resources</title_ur>
      <title_ta>வார்த்தை உணர்வு ஒழுங்குபடுத்தல் சவால்கள்:</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Lời thách đấu về Từ trường ngữ học: Tham vọng ngôn ngữ Bồ Đào Nha</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Предизвикателства за подравняване на чувството на думи: португалски езикови ресурси</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Izazovi prikazivanja riječi: Portugalski jezički resursi</title_hr>
      <title_da>Udfordringer ved Word Sense Alignment: Portugisisk sprogressourcer</title_da>
      <title_nl>Uitdagingen van Word Sense Alignment: Portugese Taalbronnen</title_nl>
      <title_de>Herausforderungen bei der Ausrichtung von Word Sense: Portugiesische Sprachressourcen</title_de>
      <title_fa>تحقیقات تنظیمات کلمه: منابع زبان پورتوژیک</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Challenges of Word Sense Alignment: Portuguese Language Resources</title_sw>
      <title_ko>포르투갈어 자원</title_ko>
      <title_af>Opdragte van Woord Sense Oplyn: Portugees Taal Hulpbronne</title_af>
      <title_am>undo-type</title_am>
      <title_tr>Sözler Senediň Çözümleri: Portugalça Diller</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Challenges of Word Sense Alignment: Portuguese Language Resources</title_sq>
      <title_az>S칬zl칲k S칬zl칲y칲n칲n 칞톛tinlikl톛ri: Portugalca Dili M톛lumat캼</title_az>
      <title_hy>Բառերի զգացմունքի հավասարման մարտահրավերները. պորտուգալերեն լեզվի ռեսուրսներ</title_hy>
      <title_id>tantangan penyesuaian Sens Perkataan: Sumber Bahasa Portugis</title_id>
      <title_bs>Izazovi prikazivanja riječi: Portugalski jezički resursi</title_bs>
      <title_bn>শব্দের সেন্সের সামান্য চ্যালেঞ্জ: পর্তুগীজ ভাষা সম্পদ</title_bn>
      <title_fi>Word Sense -linjauksen haasteet: portugalin kielen resurssit</title_fi>
      <title_cs>Výzvy při zarovnávání smyslu slova: portugalské jazykové zdroje</title_cs>
      <title_et>Sõnatunne ühtlustamise väljakutsed: portugali keele ressursid</title_et>
      <title_ca>Els reptes de l'allinjament del sentit de les paraules: recursos portuguesos</title_ca>
      <title_jv>Spanish</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ item Text character set</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Izzivi usklajevanja besednega smisla: portugalski jezik Viri</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Challenges of Word Sense Alignment: Portuguese Language Resources</title_bo>
      <title_he>אתגרים של התאמה של חוש מילים: משאבי שפה פורטוגזית</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>تقدم هذه الورقة تقريرا عن مهمة مستمرة لمحاذاة معنى الكلمة بلغة واحدة يتم فيها إجراء دراسة مقارنة بين قاموس الأكاديمية البرتغالية للعلوم و Dicionärio Aberto في سياق مشروع ELEXIS (البنية التحتية المعجمية الأوروبية). تتضمن محاذاة معنى الكلمات البحث عن حواس مطابقة ضمن إدخالات القاموس لمصادر معجمية مختلفة وربطها ، مما يشكل تحديات كبيرة. لا تكون معايير المعجم دائمًا متسقة تمامًا داخل القواميس الفردية وحتى أقل من ذلك عبر المشاريع المختلفة حيث قد يتم افتراض خيارات مختلفة من حيث الهيكل وخاصة تقنيات الصياغة للمعاجم المعجمية. هذا يعيق مهمة مطابقة الحواس. نهدف إلى تقديم سير عمل التعليقات التوضيحية باللغة البرتغالية باستخدام تقنيات الويب الدلالية. النتائج التي تم الحصول عليها مفيدة للمناقشة داخل المجتمع.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo informa sobre una tarea en curso de alineación del sentido de las palabras monolingües en la que se lleva a cabo un estudio comparativo entre el Diccionario de la Academia Portuguesa de Ciencias y el Dicionärio Aberto en el contexto del proyecto ELEXIS (Infraestructura Lexicográfica Europea). La alineación del sentido de las palabras implica buscar sentidos coincidentes dentro de las entradas del diccionario de diferentes recursos léxicos y vincularlos, lo que plantea desafíos importantes. Los criterios lexicográficos no siempre son totalmente consistentes dentro de los diccionarios individuales y menos aún en los diferentes proyectos en los que pueden haberse asumido diferentes opciones en términos de estructura y, especialmente, técnicas de redacción de glosas lexicográficas. Esto dificulta la tarea de hacer coincidir los sentidos. Nuestro objetivo es presentar nuestro flujo de trabajo de anotaciones en portugués utilizando las tecnologías de la Web Semántica. Los resultados obtenidos son útiles para la discusión dentro de la comunidad.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo relata uma tarefa em curso de alinhamento monolingue de sentido de palavras em que é realizado um estudo comparativo entre o Dicionário da Academia Portuguesa de Ciências e o Dicionärio Aberto no âmbito do projeto ELEXIS (Infraestrutura Lexicográfica Europeia). O alinhamento do sentido da palavra envolve a busca de sentidos correspondentes nas entradas do dicionário de diferentes recursos lexicais e ligá-los, o que apresenta desafios significativos. Os critérios lexicográficos nem sempre são totalmente consistentes dentro de dicionários individuais e muito menos em diferentes projetos onde diferentes opções podem ter sido assumidas em termos de estrutura e principalmente técnicas de redação de glosas lexicográficas. Isso dificulta a tarefa de combinar os sentidos. Nosso objetivo é apresentar nosso workflow de anotações em português utilizando as tecnologias da Web Semântica. Os resultados obtidos são úteis para a discussão dentro da comunidade.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では、ポルトガル科学アカデミー辞典とDicionärio Abertoとの比較研究がELEXIS （ヨーロッパ語彙インフラストラクチャ）プロジェクトの文脈で行われている、単語センスアライメントの進行中のタスクについて報告する。語感の整列には、さまざまな語彙リソースの辞書エントリ内で一致する感覚を検索し、それらをリンクすることが含まれ、大きな課題をもたらします。辞書基準は、個々の辞書内で常に完全に一貫しているわけではなく、さまざまなプロジェクトでは、構造、特に辞書の言葉遣いのテクニックに関して異なるオプションが想定されている可能性があります。これは、感覚を一致させる作業を妨げます。私たちは、セマンティックWebテクノロジーを使用して、ポルトガル語でアノテーションワークフローを提示することを目指しています。得られた結果は、コミュニティ内のディスカッションに役立ちます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>यह पेपर मोनोलिंगुअल शब्द भावना संरेखण के चल रहे कार्य पर रिपोर्ट करता है जिसमें पुर्तगाली एकेडमी ऑफ साइंसेज डिक्शनरी और डायसियो एबर्टो के बीच एक तुलनात्मक अध्ययन ELEXIS (यूरोपीय लेक्सिकोग्राफिक इंफ्रास्ट्रक्चर) परियोजना के संदर्भ में किया जाता है। वर्ड सेंस संरेखण में विभिन्न लेक्सिकल संसाधनों की शब्दकोश प्रविष्टियों के भीतर मिलान इंद्रियों की खोज करना और उन्हें जोड़ना शामिल है, जो महत्वपूर्ण चुनौतियां पैदा करता है। लेक्सिकोग्राफिक मानदंड हमेशा व्यक्तिगत शब्दकोशों के भीतर पूरी तरह से सुसंगत नहीं होते हैं और विभिन्न परियोजनाओं में भी कम होते हैं जहां संरचना के संदर्भ में अलग-अलग विकल्पों को माना जा सकता है और विशेष रूप से लेक्सिकोग्राफिक ग्लोस की शब्दावली तकनीकों को माना जा सकता है। इससे इंद्रियों के मिलान के कार्य में बाधा आती है। हम सिमेंटिक वेब प्रौद्योगिकियों का उपयोग करके पुर्तगाली में हमारे एनोटेशन वर्कफ़्लो को प्रस्तुत करने का लक्ष्य रखते हैं। प्राप्त परिणाम समुदाय के भीतर चर्चा के लिए उपयोगी हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>本文奏单语义齐务,其在ELEXIS(欧洲词典基础设施)项目背景下葡萄牙语科学院词典与Dicionärio Aberto之间较之。 词义异于齐词汇资源之字典,搜匹配之词义而链接之,大挑战也。 词典纂格于词典,非一也;更是如此于目者,非一也;结构者,词汇表之辞巧也。 此格匹配感官之任也。 吾道用语义网术葡萄牙语展我注事流程。 得之于社区内议甚有用。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Tuairiscíonn an páipéar seo ar thasc leanúnach ailíniú aonteangach chiall na bhfocal ina ndéantar staidéar comparáideach idir Foclóir Acadamh Eolaíochtaí na Portaingéile agus an Dicionärio Aberto i gcomhthéacs an tionscadail ELEXIS (Bonneagar Foclóireachta Eorpach). Is éard atá i gceist le ailíniú chiall na bhfocal ná cuardach a dhéanamh ar na céadfaí a mheaitseáil laistigh d’iontrálacha foclóir d’acmhainní foclóireachta éagsúla agus iad a nascadh, rud a chruthaíonn dúshláin shuntasacha. Ní bhíonn na critéir fhoclóra go hiomlán comhsheasmhach i gcónaí laistigh d’fhoclóirí aonair agus ní bhíonn siad chomh comhsheasmhach fós thar thionscadail éagsúla ina bhféadfaí glacadh le roghanna éagsúla i dtéarmaí struchtúir agus go háirithe teicníochtaí foclaíocht gluaiseanna foclóireachta. Cuireann sé seo bac ar an tasc a bhaineann le meaitseáil na céadfaí. Tá sé mar aidhm againn ár sreabhadh oibre nótaí a chur i láthair sa Phortaingéilis ag baint úsáide as teicneolaíochtaí an Ghréasáin Shéimeantaigh. Tá na torthaí a fhaightear úsáideach don phlé laistigh den phobal.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>A tanulmány az egynyelvű szóérzékek összehangolásának folyamatban lévő feladatáról számol be, amelyben a Portugál Tudományos Akadémia Szótár és a Dicionärio Aberto összehasonlító tanulmányát végzik az ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) projekt keretében. A szóérzékek igazítása magában foglalja a különböző lexikai erőforrások szótárbejegyzéseinek megfelelő érzékek keresését és összekapcsolását, ami jelentős kihívásokat jelent. A lexikográfiai kritériumok nem mindig teljesen egységesek az egyes szótárakban, sőt még kevésbé a különböző projektekben, ahol a szerkezet és különösen a lexikográfiai szószedek szövegezési technikája tekintetében eltérő lehetőségeket feltételezhettek. Ez akadályozza az érzékek összehangolásának feladatát. Célunk, hogy a szemantikus webes technológiák használatával portugál nyelven bemutassuk jegyzetelési munkafolyamatunkat. Az elért eredmények hasznosak a közösségen belüli beszélgetéshez.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დოკუმენტის შესახებ მონოლიგური სიტყვების სიტყვების შესახებ, რომელიც პორტეგური მეცნიერების აკადემიის სიტყვების შესახებ და დიციონიარიო აბერტო პროექტის კონტექსტურაში გავაკეთება. სიტყვების სიტყვების შესაბამისათვის შესაბამისათვის სიტყვების შესაბამისათვის განსხვავებული ლექსიკალური რესურსების შესაბამისათვის და შესაბამისათვის, რომელსაც მნი ლექქსიკოგრაფიკური კრიტერიტები არ ყოველთვის განსხვავებული პროექტურების შესახებ სტრუქტურის და განსაკუთრებით ლექსიკოგრაფიკური დლოსების ტექნოგიების განსხვავებული პროექტურების შესახე ეს შეუძლებელია შესაბამისი სენსის დავალება. ჩვენ მინდომით ჩვენი ანტორაციის სამუშაო პორტეგური სამუშაო ტექნოლოგიების გამოყენება. მიღებული წარმოდგენები საჭიროა საზოგადოება საზოგადოებაში.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η παρούσα εργασία αναφέρεται σε ένα συνεχιζόμενο έργο ευθυγράμμισης της μονογλωσσικής έννοιας λέξεων στο οποίο πραγματοποιείται συγκριτική μελέτη μεταξύ του Λεξικό της Πορτογαλικής Ακαδημίας Επιστημών και του Ντιcionärio Αμπέρτο στο πλαίσιο του έργου ELEXIS (Ευρωπαϊκή Λεξικό Υποδομή). Η ευθυγράμμιση των αισθήσεων λέξεων περιλαμβάνει την αναζήτηση για τις αντίστοιχες αισθήσεις μέσα σε καταχωρήσεις λεξικών διαφορετικών λεξικών πόρων και τη σύνδεση τους, γεγονός που θέτει σημαντικές προκλήσεις. Τα λεξικογραφικά κριτήρια δεν είναι πάντα απόλυτα συνεπή στα επιμέρους λεξικά και ακόμη λιγότερο σε διάφορα έργα όπου μπορεί να έχουν ληφθεί διαφορετικές επιλογές όσον αφορά τη δομή και ειδικά τις τεχνικές διατύπωσης των λεξικογραφικών γλωσσών. Αυτό εμποδίζει το έργο της αντιστοίχισης των αισθήσεων. Στόχος μας είναι να παρουσιάσουμε τη ροή εργασίας σχολιασμού στα πορτογαλικά χρησιμοποιώντας τις τεχνολογίες Σημαντικού Ιστού. Τα αποτελέσματα που λαμβάνονται είναι χρήσιμα για τη συζήτηση εντός της κοινότητας.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo riporta un compito in corso di allineamento monolingue del senso delle parole in cui viene condotto uno studio comparativo tra il Dizionario dell'Accademia portoghese delle scienze e il Dicionärio Aberto nell'ambito del progetto ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure). L'allineamento dei sensi delle parole implica la ricerca di corrispondenti sensi all'interno di voci di dizionario di diverse risorse lessicali e il loro collegamento, che pone sfide significative. I criteri lessicografici non sono sempre del tutto coerenti all'interno dei singoli dizionari e ancor meno nei diversi progetti in cui sono state assunte diverse opzioni in termini di struttura e soprattutto tecniche di formulazione dei glossi lessicografici. Questo ostacola il compito di abbinare i sensi. Il nostro obiettivo è presentare il nostro flusso di lavoro di annotazione in portoghese utilizzando le tecnologie Semantic Web. I risultati ottenuti sono utili per la discussione all'interno della comunità.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente pateikiama ataskaita apie nuolatinę užduotį suderinti vienkalbį žodžių supratimą, kurioje Portugalijos mokslo akademijos ir Dicion ärio Aberto lyginamasis tyrimas atliekamas įgyvendinant ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) projektą. Sąvokų jausmų suderinimas apima skirtingų leksinių išteklių žodyno įrašuose paiešką ir jų susiejimą, o tai kelia didelių iššūkių. Leksikolografiniai kriterijai ne visada yra visiškai nuoseklūs atskiruose žodynuose ir net mažiau skirtinguose projektuose, kuriuose galėjo būti numatytos skirtingos galimybės struktūros ir ypač tekstinių šviesos būdų atžvilgiu. Tai trukdo suderinti jutimus. Mes siekiame pristatyti savo anotacijos darbo srautą portugalų kalba naudojant Semantinio tinklo technologijas. Gauti rezultatai yra naudingi diskusijoms bendruomenėje.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағаз бірнеше тілік сөздердің сезімдік түрлендіру тапсырмасының туралы хабарлады. ЕлексIS (Еуропалық лексографиялық инфраструктура) жобасының және диционарио Аберто арасындағы салыстырмалы зерттеу жұмыс істейді. Сөздердің сезімінің түрлі лексикалық ресурстардың жазуында сәйкес сезімдерді іздеу және оларды сілтемелеу және оның маңызды мәселелерін көрсетеді. Лексикографикалық критериялар әрқашан жеке сөздік сөздіктерінде тәуелді емес және әртүрлі жобалар бойынша әртүрлі параметрлер құрылғы мен әсіресе лекскографикалық глоссерлердің сөздік технологиялары үшін қа Бұл сәйкесті сезімдердің тапсырмасын бұғаттайды. Біз белгілеу жұмысын Португалияға Semantic Web технологияларды қолдану мақсатымыз. Тапсырылған нәтижелер көмектесу үшін пайдалы.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Овој документ известува за тековната задача на монојазичното прилагодување на чувството на зборовите во која се спроведува споредлива студија помеѓу португалската академија на науките речник и речникот Аберто во контекст на проектот ЕЛЕКСИС (Европска лексикографска инфраструктура). Распоредувањето на чувството на зборовите вклучува барање на соодветни чувства во речните записи на различни лексикални ресурси и поврзување на нив, што претставува значителни предизвици. Лексикографските критериуми не се секогаш целосно конзидентни во индивидуалните речници и дури и помалку во различните проекти каде што може да се претпоставуваат различни опции во поглед на структурата и особено техниките на изразување на лексикографските светла. Ова ја попречува задачата да се совпаѓаат сетилата. Ние имаме за цел да го претставиме нашиот тек на анотации на португалски користејќи ги семантичките веб технологии. Добиените резултати се корисни за дискусијата во заедницата.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kertas ini melaporkan tugas yang sedang berlangsung untuk penyesuaian perkataan monobahasa di mana kajian perbandingan antara Akademi Sains Portugis dan Dicion ärio Aberto dilakukan dalam konteks projek ELEXIS (Infrastruktur Lexicographic Eropah). Jajaran perasaan perkataan melibatkan mencari perasaan yang sepadan dalam masukan kamus sumber leksikal berbeza dan menghubungkannya, yang menghasilkan cabaran yang signifikan. Kriteria leksikografik tidak sentiasa sepenuhnya konsisten dalam kamus individu dan walaupun kurang begitu di seluruh projek yang berbeza di mana pilihan berbeza mungkin telah dianggap dalam terma struktur dan khususnya teknik perkataan cahaya leksikografik. Ini menghalangi tugas sens yang sepadan. Kami bertujuan untuk memperkenalkan aliran kerja anotasi kami dalam bahasa Portugis menggunakan teknologi Web Semantic. Hasil yang diperoleh berguna untuk diskusi di dalam komuniti.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പേപ്പറിന്റെ റിപ്പോര്‍ട്ട് ചെയ്യുന്നുണ്ട്. ഇതില്‍ പോര്‍ട്ടുഗീസ് ശാസ്ത്രത്തിന്റെ അക്കാഡിമി ഓഫ് നിഘണ്ടിയുടെയും ഡിസിയോണാറിയ അബെര്‍ട്ടോ (യൂറോപ്യന്‍ ലെക്സിക്സോഗ് വാക്കുകളുടെ വിവിധ വിഭവങ്ങളുടെ നിയന്ത്രത്തിലുള്ള നിഘണ്ടികങ്ങളില്‍ പൊരുതുന്ന ശേഖരങ്ങള്‍ അന്വേഷിക്കുന്നതിന് വേറെയൊര ലെക്സിക്സിക്കോഗ്രാഫിക വിധികള്‍ എപ്പോഴും സ്വകാര്യത്തില്‍ പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായിരിക്കുന്നില്ല. അതുകൊണ്ട് വ്യത്യസ്ത പ്രോജക്റ്റുകളില്‍ വ്യത്യസ്ത ഉപാധികള ഇത് സമ്മതിക്കുന്ന വിഷയങ്ങളുടെ ജോലിയെ തടഞ്ഞിരിക്കുന്നു. സെമാന്റിക് വെബ് ടെക്നോളജിക്കുകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ച് പോര്‍ട്ടൂഗീഷില്‍ ഞങ്ങളുടെ വിചാരപ്രവർത്തികമായ ജോലി സമൂഹത്തിനുള്ള സംസാരത്തിനുള്ള വിവരണത്തിനുള്ള ഫലങ്ങള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаас нь Португалийн Академийн Шинжлэх ухааны Академийн Дикционарио Аберто болон Европын Лексикографик Инфраструктурын төслийн тухай харьцуулсан нэг хэлний хэлний тухай ажилладаг. Өөр хэлбэрийн мэдрэмжтэй холбоотой байдал нь өөр хэлбэрийн боловсрол доторх мэдрэмжүүдийг хайж, тэднийг холбоотой. Энэ нь маш чухал сорилтуудыг бий болгодог. Лексикографик шаардлагатай шаардлагатай зүйл нь үргэлж хэн нэгэн үгүйлтийн үгүйлтийн дотор бүрэн байдаг. Ялангуяа өөр сонголтууд бүтэц болон ялангуяа Лексикографик үгүйлтийн техникуудыг тодорхойлох боломжтой. Энэ нь мэдрэмжтэй холбогдох үйлдэлийг зогсоож байна. Бид анзаарлын ажлын урсгалыг Португалид Semantic Web технологийг ашиглаж үзүүлэхэд зориулсан. Үүний үр дүнд нийгмийн ярилцлаганд ашигтай.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mt>Dan id-dokument jirrapporta dwar kompitu kontinwu ta’ allinjament monolingwistiku tas-sens tal-kelma li fih jitwettaq studju komparattiv bejn id-Dikjarnarju tal-Akkademja Portugiża tax-Xjenzi u d-Dikjarnarju Aberto fil-kuntest tal-proġett ELEXIS (Infrastruttura Lessikografika Ewropea). L-allinjament tas-sens tal-kliem jinvolvi t-tfittxija għal sensi ta’ tqabbil fi ħdan l-entrati tad-dikjaratorji ta’ riżorsi lexiċi differenti u r-rabta tagħhom, li toħloq sfidi sinifikanti. The lexicographic criteria are not always entirely consistent within individual dictionaries and even less so across different projects where different options may have been assumed in terms of structure and especially wording techniques of lexicographic glosses.  Dan ifixkel il-kompitu ta’ sensi ta’ tqabbil. Għandna l-għan li nippreżentaw il-fluss tax-xogħol tagħna tal-annotazzjoni bil-Portugiż bl-użu tat-teknoloġiji Semantiċi tal-Web. Ir-riżultati miksuba huma utli għad-diskussjoni fi ħdan il-komunità.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Denne papiret rapporterer om eit gjeldande oppgåve av monospråk-innstillingar for ordfølelsing, der eit sammenlignbare studie mellom Portugisiske akademiet av vitenskapelige ordbok og Dicion ärio Aberto vert utført i konteksten av prosjektet ELEXIS (europeisk leksikografisk infrastruktur). Justering av ordfølelsen inneheld å søkja etter tilsvarande senter i ordbokoppføringar med ulike leksiske ressursar og lenkje dei, som fører til signifikante utfordringar. Lekskografiske kriteriene er ikkje alltid samsvarende i individuelle ordbokstavar og til og med mindre så gjennom ulike prosjektar der ulike val kan vera anta i uttrykk av struktur og spesielt ordteknikk av lexicographic glosser. Dette hindrar oppgåva til tilsvarande senter. Vi mål å visa våre notasjonsverktøyflug i portugisisk ved hjelp av semiantiske nettteknologi. Resultatet som er oppteken er nyttig for diskusjonen i samfunnet.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Această lucrare prezintă o sarcină în curs de desfășurare a alinierii sensului cuvântului monolingv în cadrul căreia se realizează un studiu comparativ între Dicționarul Academiei Portugheze de Științe și Dicționarul Aberto în contextul proiectului ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure). Alinierea simțurilor cuvintelor implică căutarea simțurilor potrivite în cadrul intrărilor dicționare ale diferitelor resurse lexicale și conectarea lor, ceea ce reprezintă provocări semnificative. Criteriile lexicografice nu sunt întotdeauna în întregime coerente în cadrul dicționarelor individuale și cu atât mai puțin în cadrul diferitelor proiecte în care s-ar putea presupune opțiuni diferite în ceea ce privește structura și, în special, tehnicile de formulare a gloselor lexicografice. Acest lucru împiedică sarcina potrivirii simțurilor. Scopul nostru este să prezentăm fluxul nostru de adnotare în limba portugheză folosind tehnologiile Semantic Web. Rezultatele obținute sunt utile pentru discuțiile din cadrul comunității.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Warqadan warqaddan ku qoran shaqo ku socota isbedelka hadalka sinaanta ee munaasabada ah, kaas oo lagu sameeyaa waxbarasho isbarbardhig ah oo u dhexeeya iskuulka cilmiga Burtuqiis iyo Dicion ärio Aberto waxaa lagu sameeyaa qoraalka ELEXIS (ELEXIS Infrastructure Yurub). Isku-bedelka hadalka waxaa ka mid ah raadinta fikrada isku mid ah oo ku jirta macluumaadka kala duduwan ee luqada iyo xiriirka, taasoo ah dhibaatooyin muhiim ah. Xirfaha leksikarafka mar walba ma wada mid aha kaliya ee kaliyadaha gaarka ah gudahooda, xitaa wax ka yar waxyaabaha laga helo in laga sameeyo doorashooyin kala duduwan oo la xiriira dhismaha iyo dhaqdhaqaalaha kaleba qoraalaha leksikografiska. Tani waxay ka hor jeedisaa shaqada la isku daro. We aim to present our annotation workflow in Portuguese using the Semantic Web technologies.  Dhacdooyinka la helay waxey faa’iido u leeyihiin hadalka bulshada gudahooda.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Denna uppsats redogör för en pågående uppgift med enspråkig ordanpassning där en jämförande studie mellan Portuguese Academy of Sciences Dictionary och Dicionärio Aberto genomförs inom ramen för projektet ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure). Ordsinnesjustering innebär att söka efter matchande sinnen i ordboksposter av olika lexikala resurser och länka dem, vilket innebär betydande utmaningar. De lexikografiska kriterierna är inte alltid helt konsekventa inom enskilda ordböcker och ännu mindre inom olika projekt där olika alternativ kan ha antagits när det gäller struktur och särskilt ordningstekniker för lexikografiska ordlistor. Detta hindrar uppgiften att matcha sinnena. Vi strävar efter att presentera vårt arbetsflöde för anteckningar på portugisiska med hjälp av Semantic Web teknologier. De resultat som erhållits är användbara för diskussionen inom gemenskapen.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj papir izvještava o trenutnom zadatku usklađenja jednojezičkih reči o smislu osećanja, u kojem se u kontekstu projekta ELEXIS (Evropska leksiografska infrastruktura) provede komparativna studija između Portugalske akademije naučnih knjiga i Dicion ärio Aberto. Uspoređenje riječi uključuje potragu za odgovarajućim čulima unutar ulaska rečnika različitih leksičkih resursa i povezanje ih, što predstavlja značajne izazove. Leksikografički kriteriji nisu uvek potpuno konsistentni unutar individualnih rečnika i još manje u različitim projektima u kojima se mogu preduzeti različite opcije u smislu strukture i posebno rečenja tehnika leksikografskih glosa. To ometa zadatak odgovarajućih čula. Namjeravamo da predstavimo naš tok radnog notera na portugalskom jeziku koristeći semantičke mrežne tehnologije. Dobili su rezultati korisni za raspravu u zajednici.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł przedstawia bieżące zadanie jednojęzycznego dostosowania sensu słowa, w ramach którego prowadzone jest badanie porównawcze między Słownikiem Portugalskiej Akademii Nauk a Dicionärio Aberto w kontekście projektu ELEXIS (Europejska Infrastruktura Lexikograficzna). Wyrównanie zmysłów słowa polega na wyszukiwaniu pasujących zmysłów w wpisach słownikowych różnych zasobów leksykalnych i ich łączeniu, co stanowi istotne wyzwania. Kryteria leksykograficzne nie zawsze są całkowicie spójne w poszczególnych słownikach, a tym mniej w różnych projektach, w których można założyć różne opcje pod względem struktury, a zwłaszcza techniki sformułowania słowników leksykograficznych. Utrudnia to zadanie dopasowania zmysłów. Naszym celem jest przedstawienie naszego workflow adnotacji w języku portugalskim z wykorzystaniem technologii Semantic Web. Uzyskane wyniki są przydatne do dyskusji wewnątrz społeczności.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ur>This paper reports on an ongoing task of monolingual word sense alignment in which a comparative study is carried out between the Portuguese Academy of Sciences Dictionary and the Dicion ärio Aberto in the context of the ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) project. کلمات سمجھ کی تعمیر میں مختلف لکسیکل رسورسوں کے اندر مطابق سنسوں کے لئے تلاش کرنا ہے اور ان کی تعمیر کرنا ہے، جو اہم چالوں کو بناتا ہے. لکسیکوگرافیک مقدار ہمیشہ تک تک تک تک لکسیکوگرافیک لکھنے کے اندر مطابق مطابق نہیں ہیں اور بہت کم تک مختلف پروژیکوں کے اندر جہاں مختلف اختیاروں کو ساختار اور مخصوصا لکسیکوگرافیک گلوس کے مطابق سمجھ لیا گیا ہے یہ سمجھنے کے کام سے روکتا ہے ہم نے اپنے اپنا انٹوریسی ویب ٹیکنالوجی کے مطابق پورٹوگل میں اپنا انٹوریسی کارفول پیش کرنا چاہا ہے. جو نتیجے حاصل کئے گئے ہیں اس کامیونی میں بحث کے لئے فائدہ اٹھائے جاتے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த தாள் அறிக்கையில் நடப்பும் ஒரு ஒழுங்குபடுத்தப்பட்ட செயல் பற்றிய அறிக்கைகளை அறிகிறது. அதில் போர்த்துகிச் கலிவியல் கலைஞர் அகராதி மற்றும் டிசியோனாரி அப்பார்டோ (ஐரோப்பிய லெ வார்த்தை ஒழுங்குபடுத்தல் பொருத்தும் உணர்வுகளை அகராதி உள்ளீடுகளில் தேடும் மற்றும் அதை இணைக்கும், அது மிக பெரிய சவால்கள் ஆக லெக்சிகிராபிக் குறிப்புகள் எப்போதும் தனியார் அகராதிகளுக்குள் முழுமையாக பொருத்தமாக இல்லை மற்றும் குறைவாகவும் இருக்கும் வேறு திட்டங்களில் வேறு வ இது பொருந்தும் உணர்வுகளின் செயலை தடுக்கிறது. நாங்கள் போர்த்துகீசிஷில் எங்கள் அறிவிப்பு வேலை இயக்கத்தை காண்பிக்க வேண்டும் செமாண்டிக் வலை தொழில பெற்ற முடிவுகள் சமூகத்தின் உள்ள விவாதத்திற்கு பயனுள்ளது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_si>This paperreport on an ongoing job of one language word sensation Aliment in where a comparison study is underlined with the Portuge College of science dictator and the Diccionério Abbertto is done in the Contexts of the ELex IS (EUROPEAN Lexicographic Infrastructure) process. වචන අදහස් සම්බන්ධය සම්බන්ධයෙන් වෙනස් ලෙක්සිකල් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සම්බන්ධයෙන් සඳ ලෙක්සිකෝග්‍රාෆික් සිද්ධාවක් හැමවෙලේම ප්‍රතිකෘත භාෂාවක් වලට සම්පූර්ණයෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් නෙවෙයි. වෙ මේක ප්‍රතික්‍රියා කරන්න ප්‍රතික්‍රියාවක්. අපි අදහස් කරනවා අපේ පොර්ටුගුලිස් වල පොර්ටුගුලිස් වලට සෙමැන්ටික් වෙබ් තාක්ෂණාව භාවිත කරන්න ගත්ත ප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රවාදය සමාජයේ කතාවට ප්‍රයෝජනයි.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_uz>This paper reports on an ongoing task of monolingual word sense alignment in which a comparative study between the Portuguese Academy of Sciences Dictionary and the Dicionärio Aberto is carried out in the context of the ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) project.  Name Leksekografik kriterilari har doim bir xil lugʻatlarga butunlay bir necha bo'lmaydi va ammo har xil loyihalar boshqa loyihada boshqa parametrlar tuzilishi mumkin va maxsus, leksikografik glosslarining qismlarini o'ylab boʻlishi mumkin. Name Biz Portugalcha taqdimot ishlarimizni semantik veb teknologiya yordamida hozir qilishni istaysizmi. @ info: status</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Tờ giấy này báo cáo về một nhiệm vụ liên tục sắp xếp các từ ngữ, mà trong đó có một nghiên cứu so sánh giữa Học viện Khoa học Bồ Đào Nha và DictionC228; rio Abernathy được thực hiện trong hoàn cảnh dự án mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng mạng Lexicon (Sơ đồ ngôn ngữ Châu Âu). Theo nghĩa chữ là tìm kiếm các giác quan khớp trong các mục từ điển của các nguồn từ vựng khác nhau và kết nối chúng, mà là một thử thách quan trọng. Từ điển không phải lúc nào cũng hoàn toàn phù hợp trong các từ điển cá nhân và thậm chí hơn thế trong các dự án khác nhau nơi có thể có các lựa chọn khác nhau về cấu trúc và đặc biệt các kỹ thuật văn bản của từ điển. Điều này cản trở việc kết hợp các giác quan. Mục tiêu của chúng tôi là giới thiệu dòng chảy ghi chú tại Bồ Đào Nha bằng công nghệ mạng Semantic. Những kết quả này rất có ích cho cuộc thảo luận trong cộng đồng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel beskriver en igangværende opgave med ensproget ordsansjustering, hvor en sammenlignende undersøgelse mellem det portugisiske akademi for videnskab ordbog og Dictionario Aberto gennemføres i forbindelse med projektet ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure). Ordsanselig justering indebærer at søge efter matchende sanser i ordbogsposter af forskellige leksikalske ressourcer og sammenkæde dem, hvilket udgør betydelige udfordringer. De leksikografiske kriterier er ikke altid fuldstændig konsekvente inden for de enkelte ordbøger og endnu mindre på tværs af forskellige projekter, hvor der kan være antaget forskellige muligheder med hensyn til struktur og især ordningsteknikker i leksikografiske glosser. Dette hindrer opgaven med at matche sanser. Vi har til formål at præsentere vores arbejdsgang for annotering på portugisisk ved hjælp af Semantic Web teknologier. De opnåede resultater er nyttige for diskussionen i fællesskabet.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Beitrag berichtet über eine laufende Aufgabe der monolingualen Wortsinnausrichtung, bei der im Rahmen des ELEXIS-Projekts (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) eine vergleichende Studie zwischen dem Wörterbuch der Portugiesischen Akademie der Wissenschaften und dem Dicionario Aberto durchgeführt wird. Wortsinnausrichtung beinhaltet die Suche nach passenden Sinnen innerhalb von Wörterbucheinträgen verschiedener lexikalischer Ressourcen und deren Verknüpfung, was erhebliche Herausforderungen darstellt. Die lexikographischen Kriterien sind in einzelnen Wörterbüchern nicht immer vollständig konsistent und noch weniger projektübergreifend, bei denen unterschiedliche Optionen hinsichtlich Struktur und insbesondere Formulierungstechniken von lexikographischen Glossen angenommen wurden. Dies behindert die Aufgabe, die Sinne aufeinander abzustimmen. Unser Ziel ist es, unseren Annotations-Workflow auf Portugiesisch unter Verwendung der Semantic Web Technologien zu präsentieren. Die erzielten Ergebnisse sind nützlich für die Diskussion innerhalb der Community.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel gaat over een lopende taak van eentalige woordzinnelijkheidsafstemming waarbij een vergelijkende studie wordt uitgevoerd tussen het woordenboek van de Portugese Academie van Wetenschappen en het Dicionario Aberto in het kader van het ELEXIS-project (European Lexicographic Infrastructure). Woordzintuiguitlijning omvat het zoeken naar overeenkomende zintuigen in woordenboek items van verschillende lexicale bronnen en het koppelen ervan, wat aanzienlijke uitdagingen met zich meebrengt. De lexicografische criteria zijn niet altijd volledig consistent binnen individuele woordenboeken en nog minder in verschillende projecten waar verschillende opties zijn aangenomen op het gebied van structuur en met name formuleringstechnieken van lexicografische glossen. Dit belemmert de taak om zintuigen te matchen. We willen onze annotatie workflow in het Portugees presenteren met behulp van de Semantic Web technologieën. De verkregen resultaten zijn nuttig voor de discussie binnen de community.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Kertas ini melaporkan tugas yang sedang berlangsung dalam penyesuaian sensor kata-kata monobahasa di mana sebuah studi perbandingan antara Akademi Sains Portugis dan Dicionario Aberto dilakukan dalam konteks proyek ELEXIS (Infrastruktur Lexikografi Eropa). Penyesuaian perasaan kata melibatkan mencari sens yang cocok dalam masukan kamus sumber daya leksik yang berbeda dan menghubungkannya, yang menimbulkan tantangan yang signifikan. Kriteri lexikografi tidak selalu sepenuhnya konsisten dalam kata-kata individu dan bahkan kurang begitu di proyek yang berbeda di mana pilihan berbeda mungkin diasumsikan dalam terma struktur dan khususnya teknik pembicaraan cahaya lexikografi. This hinders the task of matching senses.  Kami bertujuan untuk memperlihatkan aliran kerja anotasi kami dalam bahasa Portugis menggunakan teknologi Semantik Web. Hasilnya berguna untuk diskusi di dalam komunitas.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 현재 진행 중인 단어의 의미 정렬 임무를 보고하는데 이 임무는 ELEXIS(유럽 사전 인프라) 프로젝트의 배경에서 포르투갈 과학원 사전과Diciario Aberto를 비교 연구했다.단어의 의미 정렬은 서로 다른 어휘 자원의 사전 항목에서 일치하는 단어를 검색하고 연결하는 데 큰 도전을 가져왔다.사전 편찬 기준은 개별 사전에서 항상 완전히 일치하는 것은 아니다. 서로 다른 항목에서 더욱 그렇다. 이런 항목에서 사전 편찬의 구조, 특히 사전 편찬의 언어 기교에 있어 서로 다른 선택이 있을 수 있다.이것은 감각이 일치하는 임무를 방해한다.우리의 목표는 포르투갈어로 우리의 주석 작업 절차를 보여주는 의미망 기술을 사용하는 것이다.얻은 결과는 지역 사회 내의 토론에 매우 유용하다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_bg>Настоящата статия представя текуща задача за едноезично подравняване на значението на думата, при която се извършва сравнително проучване между речника на Португалската академия на науките и Dicionario Aberto в контекста на проекта ЕЛЕКСИС (Европейска лексикографска инфраструктура). Подравняването на словните сетива включва търсене на съвпадащи сетива в речниците записи на различни лексикални ресурси и свързването им, което поставя значителни предизвикателства. Лексикографските критерии не винаги са напълно съгласувани в рамките на отделните речници и още по-малко в различните проекти, в които могат да се приемат различни варианти по отношение на структурата и особено техниките за формулиране на лексикографските гласове. Това затруднява задачата за съвпадане на сетивата. Целта ни е да представим нашия работен процес на анотация на португалски език, използвайки Семантичната уеб технология. Получените резултати са полезни за дискусията в общността.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj papir izvještava o trenutnom zadatku usklađenja osjećaja jednojezičkih riječi u kojem se u kontekstu projekta ELEXIS (Europske leksiografske infrastrukture) provede usporedno ispitivanje između Portugalske akademije znanstvenih riječi i Dicionario Aberto. Poravnanje osjećaja riječi uključuje potragu za odgovarajućim čulima unutar ulaganja rečnika različitih leksičkih resursa i povezivanje ih, što predstavlja značajne izazove. Leksikografički kriteriji nisu uvijek potpuno konsistentni u pojedinačnim riječima, a čak i manje u raznim projektima u kojima se mogu preduzeti različite opcije u smislu strukture i posebno formuliranih tehnika leksikografskih glosa. To sprječava zadatak odgovarajućih čula. Namjeravamo predstaviti svoj tok rada annotacije na portugalskom jeziku koristeći semantičke web tehnologije. Dobili su rezultati korisni za raspravu u zajednici.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_sw>Kanisa hili linaripoti kuhusu jukumu linaloendelea la kukusanyika kwa maneno ya kiutamaduni ambapo utafiti unaofanana kati ya Chuo cha Sayansi cha Kireno na Dictionary Aberto kinaendeshwa katika muktadha wa mradi wa ELEXIS (Mfumo wa Ufumo wa Kilexico wa Ulaya). Uwekezaji wa maneno unahusisha kutafuta hisia zinazofanana ndani ya madikuni ya rasilimali tofauti za lexico na kuwaunganisha, ambayo ina changamoto kubwa. Vigezo vya lexico havina kamili kabisa ndani ya madikteta binafsi na hata kidogo zaidi katika miradi mbalimbali ambapo chaguo tofauti zinaweza kuchukuliwa kwa ajili ya muundo na hususani teknolojia za vibonzo vya lexico. This hinders the task of matching senses.  Tuna lengo la kuwasilisha safari zetu za kazi za kusisimua nchini Kireno kwa kutumia teknolojia ya mtandao wa Semantic. Matokeo yaliyopatikana yanasaidia mijadala ndani ya jamii.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyz hemişe ýerleşýän söz duýdury hasaplanjak meýdançasynda Portugalça Bilim Akademiýasy we Dicionario Aberto bilen ELEXIS (Ewrope Lexicographic Infrastructure) taslamasynda çykylýar. Sözler duýdury çyzyglamak üçin sözlük girişinde eşleýän duýgular üçin gözleýän sözlük girişinde we olary baglaýyşyp bilen wajyp kynçylyklary bar. Leksikografik kriteriýasy her zaman birnäçe sözlerniň içinde hemişe bir ýagdaýda däldir, hatda farklı projekleriň strukturda we özellikle leksikografik glossalaryň sözleşme teknikleri üýtgedilip bilýär. Bu duýgularyň täze zadyny engelleýär. Semantik web teknolojilerini ulanarak duýgulanmalaryň aklymyzy portugalça görkezmäge niýet edýäris. Alzan netijeler toplumyň içinde gürrüň üçin faydaly.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_fa>این کاغذ گزارش می‌دهد که در آن یک مطالعه مقایسه بین آکادمی دانشمندان پورتوژیک و Dicionario Aberto در کنترل پروژه ELEXIS (آفرینش لکسیکوگرافی اروپایی) انجام می‌شود. تنظیم حس کلمه شامل جستجوی حس‌های متفاوت در داخل دستورالژی از منابع زبانی متفاوت و ارتباط آنها است که چالش‌های مهم را می‌گذارد. شرایط لکسیکوگرافیک همیشه در کلمه‌های شخصی و حتی کمتر از پروژه‌های متفاوتی نیستند که ممکن است گزینه‌های متفاوتی به عنوان ساختار و مخصوصا تکنیک‌های کلمه‌های لکسیکوگرافیک پذیرفته شود. این کار حس‌های هماهنگی را باز می‌دارد. ما هدف می‌گیریم با استفاده از تکنولوژی‌های وب سیمانتیک، جریان کارهای نوشته‌های ما را در پورتوژیک نشان دهیم. نتیجه‌هایی که به دست آورده‌اند برای بحث در جامعه مفید هستند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie papier rapporteer op 'n voortdurende taak van monolinglike woord sins belyning waarin 'n vergelykbare studie tussen die Portugese Akademie van Wetenskaplike Woordeboek en die Dicionario Aberto uitgevoer word in die konteks van die ELEXIS (Europeese Lexicographic Infrastructure) projek. Woordsins belangriking involves searching for matching senses within dictionary entries of different lexical resources and linking them, which poses significant challenges. Die leksikografiese kriterie is nie altyd heeltemal in individuele woordeboekvorms en selfs minder so oor verskillende projekte waar verskillende opsies dalk mag aangeneem word ingevolge struktuur en spesiaal woordeteknike van leksikografiese glosse. Hierdie hinder die taak van ooreenstemmende senses. Ons doen doel om ons annotasie werksvloei in Portugees te voorsien deur die Semantiese Web teknologies te gebruik. Die ontvangde resultate is nuttig vir die diskusie binne die gemeenskap.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>ይህ የፕሮግራም ጉዳይ በፖርቱጋሊስ የሳይንስ ቃላት አካዳሚ እና ዲያኖሪያ አበባሮው መካከል በELEXIS (አውሮፓውያን ሊክሲኮግራክ Infrastructure) ፕሮጀክት ውስጥ የሚተካክል ትምህርት ነው፡፡ የንግግር አስተያየት ማሰናከል በተለያዩ የሊክሲካዊ ሀብት ውስጥ ያሉትን አስተያየትን ለመፈለግ እና ማጠቃለያቸውን በመጠየቅ ትልቅ ጥቃቄ ያቆማል፡፡ ሌክሲካፍ ክፍተቶችን ሁልጊዜ በአንድ ብሔራዊ መዝገብ ውስጥ አይተካከሉም፣ ይልቁንም በተለያዩ ፕሮጀክቶች ውስጥ ልዩ ምርጫዎች በተለየ ሥርዓት እና በተለየ ለሌክክሲኮፖርቲካ ጉልማሶች እና በተለየ ቃላት የንግግር ቴክክኖጂ ይደረጋሉ፡፡ ይህም የሚተያያየው ስራዎችን የሚከለክል ነው፡፡ በፖርቱጋሊስ የስሜንቲክ የዌብ ቴክኖሎጂ የተጠቃሚ ስራዎችን ለመቀበል እናስፈልጋለን፡፡ የተገኘው ውጤቶች በሕዝብ ውስጥ ውይይት ይጠቅማል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Այս հոդվածը ներկայացնում է մեկլեզու բառի զգացմունքի հարմարեցման ընթացքում ընդունվող խնդիրը, որտեղ պորտուգալիական գիտության ակադեմիայի և Աբերտո բառարանի միջև կատարվող համեմատական ուսումնասիրությունը կատարվում է ELExIS (Եվրոպական լեքսիկոգրաֆիկ ինֆրաֆրակտուրա) նա Բառերի զգացմունքների հավասարակշռությունը ներառում է բառարանի տարբեր լեքսիկական ռեսուրսների բառարանում համապատասխանվող զգացմունքների որոնումը և դրանց կապելը, ինչը մեծ մարտահրավեր է առաջացնում: Լեքսիկոգրաֆիկ կանոնները ոչ միշտ ամբողջովին համապատասխանում են անհատական բառարաններում, և նույնիսկ ավելի քիչ տարբեր նախագծերում, որտեղ տարբեր տարբեր տարբերակներ կարող են ենթադրվել կառուցվածքի և հատկապես լեքսիկոգրաֆիկ լուսավորումների տեխնիկա This hinders the task of matching senses.  Մենք նպատակում ենք ներկայացնել մեր annoտացիոն աշխատանքի հոսքը պորտուգալերենում օգտագործելով սեմանտիկ վեբ տեխնոլոգիաները: The results obtained are useful for the discussion within the community.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj papir izvještava o trenutnom zadatku usklađivanja osjećaja jednojezičkih riječi u kojem se u kontekstu projekta ELEXIS (Evropska leksiografska infrastruktura) provede usporedno ispitivanje između portugalske akademije naučnih knjiga i Dicionario Aberto. Poravnanje osjećaja riječi uključuje potragu za odgovarajućim čulima unutar ulaganja rečnika različitih leksičkih resursa i povezivanje ih, što predstavlja značajne izazove. Leksikografički kriteriji nisu uvijek potpuno konsistentni unutar individualnih riječi, a čak i manje u raznim projektima u kojima se mogu preduzeti različite opcije u smislu strukture i posebno formuliranih tehnika leksikografskih glosa. To sprječava zadatak odgovarajućih čula. Namjeravamo predstaviti svoj tok rada annotacije na portugalskom jeziku koristeći semantičke web tehnologije. Dobili su rezultati korisni za raspravu u zajednici.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_az>Bu kağıt, elmi təhsil və Dicionario Aberto təhsil ilə ELEXIS (Avropa Lexicographic Infrastructure) proqramının dəyişiklik təhsil edildiyi təhsil təhsil edilməsi barəsində tələb edir. Sözlük məlumatı tərəfindən müxtəlif sözlük kaynaqlarının içində və onları bağlayıb, böyük çətinliklərə bənzəyir. Leksikografik kriterilər həmişə individual sözlər içində uyğun deyildir, hətta daha az da, fərqli seçimlər strukturda və özlərinə də lexikografik glosslərinin sözləri ilə müəyyən edilmiş, müxtəlif seçimlərin tərzlərində müəyyən edilmiş olaraq. Bu, eşitmə hisslərinin işini engel edir. Semantik Web tehnologiyalarını istifadə etmək istəyirik. Qazanmış sonuçlar toplum içindəki müzakirə üçün faydalıdır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>This paper reports on an ongoing task of monolingual word sense alignment in which a comparative study between the Portuguese Academy of Sciences Dictionary and the Dicionario Aberto is carried out in the context of the ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) project.  Word sense alignment involves searching for matching senses within dictionary entries of different lexical resources and linking them, which poses significant challenges.  The lexicographic criteria are not always entirely consistent within individual dictionaries and even less so across different projects where different options may have been assumed in terms of structure and especially wording techniques of lexicographic glosses.  This hinders the task of matching senses.  Tenim l'objectiu de presentar el nostre flux de treball d'anotació en portuguès utilitzant les tecnologies de la Web Semàtica. Els resultats obtenits són útils per a la discussió dins la comunitat.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek pojednává o probíhajícím úkolu sladění jednojjazyčného slovního smyslu, v němž je v rámci projektu ELEXIS (European Lexikographic Infrastructure) provedena srovnávací studie mezi slovníkem Portugalské akademie věd a Dicionario Aberto. Zarovnání slovních smyslů zahrnuje vyhledávání odpovídajících smyslů v rámci slovníkových položek různých lexikálních zdrojů a jejich propojení, což představuje významné výzvy. Lexikografická kritéria nejsou vždy zcela konzistentní v rámci jednotlivých slovníků, a to ještě méně napříč různými projekty, kde mohly být předpokládány různé možnosti z hlediska struktury a zejména textových technik lexikografických glosářů. To brání úkolu sladit smysly. Naším cílem je prezentovat náš anotací workflow v portugalštině pomocí sémantických webových technologií. Získané výsledky jsou užitečné pro diskusi v rámci komunity.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas dokumendis käsitletakse käimasolevat ühekeelse sõnade tähenduse ühtlustamise ülesannet, milles viiakse läbi võrdlev uuring Portugali Teaduste Akadeemia Sõnaraamatu ja Dicionario Aberto vahel projekti ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) kontekstis. Sõnatunde joondamine hõlmab erinevate leksikaalsete ressursside sõnastikukannete vahel sobivate meelte otsimist ja nende sidumist, mis tekitab märkimisväärseid väljakutseid. Leksikograafilised kriteeriumid ei ole alati üksikutes sõnaraamatutes täielikult kooskõlas ja veelgi vähem erinevate projektide puhul, kus võib eeldada erinevaid võimalusi leksikograafiliste sõnaraamatute struktuuri ja eriti sõnastusmeetodite osas. See takistab meelte ühitamist. Meie eesmärk on tutvustada oma kommenteerimistööd portugali keeles semantilise veebi tehnoloogiate abil. Saadud tulemused on kasulikud aruteluks kogukonnas.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tämä artikkeli käsittelee meneillään olevaa monikielisen sanamerkityksen yhdenmukaistamisen tehtävää, jossa Portugalin tiedeakatemian sanakirjan ja Dicionario Aberto vertaileva tutkimus tehdään ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) -hankkeen yhteydessä. Sanaaistien tasaaminen edellyttää eri sanastoaineistojen sanakirjojen yhteensopivien aistien etsimistä ja niiden linkittämistä, mikä asettaa merkittäviä haasteita. Leksikografiset kriteerit eivät aina ole täysin yhdenmukaisia yksittäisissä sanakirjoissa ja vielä vähemmän eri projekteissa, joissa on voitu olettaa, että sanaston rakenne ja erityisesti sanamuoto ovat erilaisia. Tämä vaikeuttaa aistien yhdistämistä. Pyrimme esittelemään merkintöjen työnkulkuamme portugaliksi Semanttisen Web-teknologian avulla. Saadut tulokset ovat hyödyllisiä yhteisön sisäisessä keskustelussa.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bn>এই পত্রিকাটি প্রতিবেদন করছে যেখানে পোর্টুগীজ বিজ্ঞানের অ্যাকাডেমি অফ ফ ফিশনারিশনারি এবং ডিকিশনারিয়া আবার্টো ইউরোপিয়ান লেক্সিকোগ্রাফিক ইনফ্রাক্টার্মিক প্রকল্পের প বিভিন্ন লেক্সিক্সিয়াল সম্পদের ভিত্তিতে অনুসন্ধানের মধ্যে শব্দের মানসিকতা অনুসন্ধান এবং সেগুলোর সাথে যুক্ত করার বিষয়টি  লেক্সিকোগ্রাফিক ক্রীয় মূল্য সবসময় ব্যক্তিগত সংবাদপত্রের মধ্যে একত্র নয় এবং এমনকি বিভিন্ন প্রকল্পের মধ্যে কম যেখানে বিভিন্ন প্রকল্পের মাধ্যমে বিভিন্ন কাঠ এটা মিলিয়ে যাওয়ার কাজ বাধা দেয়। আমরা পর্তুগীজে আমাদের বিস্তারিত কার্যক্রম প্রবাহ উপস্থাপন করার উদ্দেশ্যে সেম্যান্টিক ওয়েব প্রযুক্তি ব্যবহ সম্প্রদায়ের মধ্যে আলোচনার জন্য প্রাপ্ত ফলাফল প্রয়োজন।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_sq>This paper reports on an ongoing task of monolingual word sense alignment in which a comparative study between the Portuguese Academy of Sciences Dictionary and the Dicionario Aberto is carried out in the context of the ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) project.  Word sense alignment involves searching for matching senses within dictionary entries of different lexical resources and linking them, which poses significant challenges.  The lexicographic criteria are not always entirely consistent within individual dictionaries and even less so across different projects where different options may have been assumed in terms of structure and especially wording techniques of lexicographic glosses.  This hinders the task of matching senses.  Ne synojmë të paraqesim rrjedhjen tonë të punës së anotacionit në portugal duke përdorur teknologjitë Semantike Web. The results obtained are useful for the discussion within the community.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_jv>Perintah iki dadi nggawe barang urip kuwi nggawe pawaran uninglanggar sampeyan urip kuwi nggawe gerarangkar karo sekondirno portugo akade dhe Sayensi Ditionari Uber AllProgressBar Leksikograf sing dipileksi kuwi mesthi akeh saben nêmên diketeksi sing nguasai nêmên lagi pangutêm kanggo sampeyan akeh operasi sing dipileksi sampeyan nêmên karo sistem sampeyan karo teknik sing paling leksikograf Ngomongke kuwi nggawe Perintah sing dumadhakan Sene Awak dhéwé kepengin kanggo ngerasakno kanggo nggawe barang-barang ning portugik iki gambar semanti web teknêji. Pametuné awak dhéwé butilèh kanggo nggawe komunitas.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Wannan littãfi yana da wani aikin mai tafiya a matsayin mantawa na monoli-harshen, inda wani littãfi mai sammenliki a tsakanin Academy of the Sanin Fashion Portugal da the Dicionary Abertao is performed in context of the ELEXIS (ELEXIS) Projekt na Leksograpic InFracture. Juyin faɗi na faɗi na amfani da kwamfyuta a ƙidãya wa saniya masu daidaita cikin matabbatan da ke cikin masu tsari masu nau'i na leksisi kuma yana haɗi da su, da kuma yana ƙara masu kanana mai girma. QFontDatabase Wannan yana hana aikin da ke daidaita. Tuna aimar mu gabatar da aikin da aka sanar da shi a Kirangiz, da amfani da Technical na Semantic Web. Mataimakin da aka sãmi shi yana da amfani ga jayayya a cikin jamii.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Ta prispevek poroča o tekoči nalogi enojezičnega usklajevanja besednih pomenov, v kateri se v okviru projekta ELEXIS (European Lexicographic Infrastructure) izvaja primerjalna študija slovarja portugalske akademije znanosti in Dicionario Aberto. Usklajevanje besednih čutov vključuje iskanje ujemajočih čutov znotraj slovarskih vnosov različnih leksikalnih virov in njihovo povezovanje, kar predstavlja velike izzive. Leksikografska merila niso vedno popolnoma usklajena znotraj posameznih slovarjev, še manj pa v različnih projektih, kjer so lahko predvidevale različne možnosti glede strukture in zlasti besedilnih tehnik leksikografskih glosov. To ovira nalogo usklajevanja čutil. Naš cilj je predstaviti potek dela označevanja v portugalščini z uporabo semantičnih spletnih tehnologij. Dobljeni rezultati so koristni za razpravo znotraj skupnosti.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>העבודה הזו דווחת על משימה ממשיכה של התאמה של מילים מונושפות שבה מחקר משווה בין המילון של האקדמיה הפורטוגזית למדעים והדיקונריו אברטו נעשה בתוך הקשר של פרויקט ELEXIS (Infrastructure Lexicographic Europe). התאמת תחושת מילים כוללת חיפוש אחר תחושות מתאימות בתוך מכתבי מילון של משאבים לקסיים שונים וקשורים אותם, מה שמוציא אתגרים משמעותיים. הקריטריונים הלקסיקוגרפיים לא תמיד תואמים לחלוטין בתוך מילונים בודדים ואפילו פחות בתוך פרוייקטים שונים זה מפריע למשימה של חושים מתאימים. אנחנו מתכוונים להציג את זרימת העבודה שלנו בפורטוגזית באמצעות טכנולוגיות האינטרנט הסמנטיות. התוצאות שנקבלו הן שימושיות לדיון בתוך הקהילה.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>འོག་གི་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་སྔོན་སྒྲིག་གི་དོན་ལ་ངོས་འཛིན་པའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག་གཟུགས་དང་། འདི་ནང་དུ་པོར་ཊུ་གླིང་སྒྲོམ་དང་Dicionario Aberto་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་ཡོངས་བསྒྲགས་ཅན་གྱི་ Word sense alignment involves searching for matching senses within dictionary entries of different lexical resources and linking them, which poses significant challenges. lexicographic criteria are not always consistent with individual dictionaries.Even so different projects where different options are assumed in terms of structure and especially wording techniques of lexicographic glosses. འདིས་མཐུན་རུང་བའི་བསམ་བློ་གཏོང་ལ་ལས་འགུལ་འདོད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་རྒྱ་ནག་གི་དྲ་རྒྱ་སྟངས་སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་རྩོལ་འབྲེལ་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་དུ་སྟོན་དགོས་པ་ཡིན། གྲངས་འབོར་བ་ཡོད་པའི་གྲངས་འབོར་ཚོགས་སྤྱི་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་གྲོས་འཆར་བྱ་སྤྱོད་རྒྱུ་དེ་རེད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Lexemes in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikidata">Wikidata</a> : 2020 status<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ikidata: 2020 status</title>
      <author><first>Finn</first><last>Nielsen</last></author>
      <pages>82–86</pages>
      <abstract>Wikidata now records data about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexeme">lexemes</a>, senses and lexical forms and exposes them as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linguistic_Linked_Open_Data">Linguistic Linked Open Data</a>. Since <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexeme">lexemes</a> in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikidata">Wikidata</a> was first established in 2018, this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a> has grown considerable in size. Links between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexeme">lexemes</a> in different languages can be made, e.g., through a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphological_derivation">derivation property</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_sense">senses</a>. We present some descriptive statistics about the lexemes of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikidata">Wikidata</a>, focusing on the multilingual aspects and show that there are still relatively few multilingual links.</abstract>
      <url hash="0d0fdd66">2020.ldl-1.12</url>
      <language>eng</language>
      <bibkey>nielsen-2020-lexemes</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>