<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.starsem">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of *SEM 2021: The Tenth Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Lun-Wei</first><last>Ku</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Vivi</first><last>Nastase</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ivan</first><last>Vulić</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="b7c2739b">2021.starsem-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="2ecd08a5">2021.starsem-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sem-2021-sem</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Can Transformer Language Models Predict Psychometric Properties?</title>
      <author><first>Antonio</first><last>Laverghetta Jr.</last></author>
      <author><first>Animesh</first><last>Nighojkar</last></author>
      <author><first>Jamshidbek</first><last>Mirzakhalov</last></author>
      <author><first>John</first><last>Licato</last></author>
      <pages>12–25</pages>
      <abstract>Transformer-based language models (LMs) continue to advance state-of-the-art performance on NLP benchmark tasks, including tasks designed to mimic human-inspired commonsense competencies. To better understand the degree to which LMs can be said to have certain linguistic reasoning skills, researchers are beginning to adapt the tools and concepts of the field of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychometrics">psychometrics</a>. But to what extent can the benefits flow in the other direction? I.e., can <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Longitudinal_study">LMs</a> be of use in predicting what the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychometrics">psychometric properties</a> of test items will be when those items are given to human participants? We gather responses from numerous human participants and LMs (transformer- and non-transformer-based) on a broad diagnostic test of linguistic competencies. We then use the responses to calculate standard psychometric properties of the items in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medical_test">diagnostic test</a>, using the human responses and the LM responses separately. We then determine how well these two sets of predictions match. We find cases in which transformer-based LMs predict psychometric properties consistently well in certain categories but consistently poorly in others, thus providing new insights into fundamental similarities and differences between human and LM reasoning.</abstract>
      <url hash="c9268154">2021.starsem-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>laverghetta-jr-etal-2021-transformer</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/Advancing-Machine-Human-Reasoning-Lab/transformer-psychometrics" additional="false">Advancing-Machine-Human-Reasoning-Lab/transformer-psychometrics</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/anli">ANLI</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/chaosnli">ChaosNLI</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/glue">GLUE</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/snli">SNLI</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/taxinli">TaxiNLI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>A Study on Using Semantic Word Associations to Predict the Success of a Novel</title>
      <author><first>Syeda</first><last>Jannatus Saba</last></author>
      <author><first>Biddut Sarker</first><last>Bijoy</last></author>
      <author><first>Henry</first><last>Gorelick</last></author>
      <author><first>Sabir</first><last>Ismail</last></author>
      <author><first>Md Saiful</first><last>Islam</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammad Ruhul</first><last>Amin</last></author>
      <pages>38–51</pages>
      <abstract>Many new books get published every year, and only a fraction of them become popular among the readers. So the prediction of a book success can be a very useful parameter for publishers to make a reliable decision. This article presents the study of semantic word associations using the word embedding of book content for a set of Roget’s thesaurus concepts for book success prediction. In this work, we discuss the method to represent a book as a spectrum of concepts based on the association score between its content embedding and a global embedding (i.e. fastText) for a set of semantically linked word clusters. We show that the semantic word associations outperform the previous methods for book success prediction. In addition, we present that semantic word associations also provide better results than using features like the frequency of word groups in Roget’s thesaurus, LIWC (a popular tool for linguistic inquiry and word count), NRC (word association emotion lexicon), and part of speech (PoS). Our study reports that concept associations based on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roget’s_Thesaurus">Roget’s Thesaurus</a> using word embedding of individual novel resulted in the state-of-the-art performance of 0.89 average weighted F1-score for book success prediction. Finally, we present a set of dominant themes that contribute towards the popularity of a book for a specific genre.</abstract>
      <url hash="c3d53777">2021.starsem-1.4</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="4dd3ad88">2021.starsem-1.4.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>jannatus-saba-etal-2021-study</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>ParsFEVER : a Dataset for Farsi Fact Extraction and Verification<fixed-case>P</fixed-case>ars<fixed-case>FEVER</fixed-case>: a Dataset for <fixed-case>F</fixed-case>arsi Fact Extraction and Verification</title>
      <author><first>Majid</first><last>Zarharan</last></author>
      <author><first>Mahsa</first><last>Ghaderan</last></author>
      <author><first>Amin</first><last>Pourdabiri</last></author>
      <author><first>Zahra</first><last>Sayedi</last></author>
      <author><first>Behrouz</first><last>Minaei-Bidgoli</last></author>
      <author><first>Sauleh</first><last>Eetemadi</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammad Taher</first><last>Pilehvar</last></author>
      <pages>99–104</pages>
      <abstract>Training and evaluation of automatic fact extraction and verification techniques require large amounts of annotated data which might not be available for low-resource languages. This paper presents ParsFEVER : the first publicly available Farsi dataset for fact extraction and verification. We adopt the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_grammar">construction procedure</a> of the standard English dataset for the task, i.e., <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fever">FEVER</a>, and improve it for the case of low-resource languages. Specifically, claims are extracted from sentences that are carefully selected to be more informative. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> comprises nearly 23 K manually-annotated claims. Over 65 % of the claims in ParsFEVER are many-hop (require evidence from multiple sources), making the dataset a challenging benchmark (only 13 % of the claims in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FEVER">FEVER</a> are many-hop). Also, despite having a smaller training set (around one-ninth of that in Fever), a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> trained on ParsFEVER attains similar downstream performance, indicating the quality of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>. We release the dataset and the annotation guidelines at https://github.com/Zarharan/ParsFEVER.</abstract>
      <url hash="8f67e828">2021.starsem-1.9</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="da2a6bcd">2021.starsem-1.9.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.9</doi>
      <bibkey>zarharan-etal-2021-parsfever</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/zarharan/parsfever" additional="false">zarharan/parsfever</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/fever">FEVER</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hover">HoVer</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/liar">LIAR</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>BiQuAD : Towards <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quality_assurance">QA</a> based on deeper text understanding<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>i<fixed-case>Q</fixed-case>u<fixed-case>AD</fixed-case>: Towards <fixed-case>QA</fixed-case> based on deeper text understanding</title>
      <author><first>Frank</first><last>Grimm</last></author>
      <author><first>Philipp</first><last>Cimiano</last></author>
      <pages>105–115</pages>
      <abstract>Recent question answering and machine reading benchmarks frequently reduce the task to one of pinpointing spans within a certain text passage that answers the given question. Typically, these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> are not required to actually understand the text on a deeper level that allows for more complex reasoning on the information contained. We introduce a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> called BiQuAD that requires deeper comprehension in order to answer questions in both extractive and deductive fashion. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> consist of 4,190 closed-domain texts and a total of 99,149 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Question_answering">question-answer pairs</a>. The texts are synthetically generated soccer match reports that verbalize the main events of each match. All texts are accompanied by a structured Datalog program that represents a (logical) model of its information. We show that state-of-the-art QA models do not perform well on the challenging long form contexts and reasoning requirements posed by the dataset. In particular, transformer based state-of-the-art models achieve F1-scores of only 39.0. We demonstrate how these synthetic datasets align structured knowledge with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural text</a> and aid model introspection when approaching complex text understanding.</abstract>
      <url hash="1cb2ee65">2021.starsem-1.10</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.10</doi>
      <bibkey>grimm-cimiano-2021-biquad</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/drop">DROP</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/medhop">MedHop</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/newsqa">NewsQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/openbookqa">OpenBookQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/qasc">QASC</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/race">RACE</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/triviaqa">TriviaQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wikihop">WikiHop</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Evaluating Universal Dependency Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analysis<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ependency Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure via <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>omp<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hain Analysis</title>
      <author><first>Sagar</first><last>Indurkhya</last></author>
      <author><first>Beracah</first><last>Yankama</last></author>
      <author><first>Robert C.</first><last>Berwick</last></author>
      <pages>116–128</pages>
      <abstract>Accurate recovery of predicate-argument structure from a Universal Dependency (UD) parse is central to downstream tasks such as extraction of semantic roles or event representations. This study introduces compchains, a categorization of the hierarchy of predicate dependency relations present within a UD parse. Accuracy of compchain classification serves as a proxy for measuring accurate recovery of predicate-argument structure from sentences with embedding. We analyzed the distribution of compchains in three UD English treebanks, EWT, GUM and LinES, revealing that these treebanks are sparse with respect to sentences with predicate-argument structure that includes predicate-argument embedding. We evaluated the CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (dependency parsing) models as compchain classifiers for the EWT, GUMS and LinES UD treebanks. Our results indicate that these three baseline models exhibit poorer performance on sentences with predicate-argument structure with more than one level of embedding ; we used compchains to characterize the errors made by these parsers and present examples of erroneous parses produced by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a> that were identified using compchains. We also analyzed the distribution of compchains in 58 non-English UD treebanks and then used compchains to evaluate the CoNLL’18 Shared Task baseline model for each of these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebanks</a>. Our analysis shows that performance with respect to compchain classification is only weakly correlated with the official evaluation metrics (LAS, MLAS and BLEX). We identify gaps in the distribution of compchains in several of the UD treebanks, thus providing a roadmap for how these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treebank">treebanks</a> may be supplemented.</abstract>
      <url hash="a48eab5f">2021.starsem-1.11</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.11</doi>
      <bibkey>indurkhya-etal-2021-evaluating</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>تقييم الاسترداد المحلل اللغوي العالمي لبنية الحجة الأصلية عبر تحليل CompChain</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Avaliando a recuperação do analisador de dependência universal da estrutura do argumento predicado por meio da análise CompChain</title_pt>
      <title_es>Evaluación de la recuperación del analizador de dependencias universal de la estructura de argumentos de predicado mediante el análisis de Comp</title_es>
      <title_zh>因 CompChain 析评估谓词参数结构通用赖解析器复</title_zh>
      <title_ja>CompChain Analysisを介した述語引数構造の普遍的な依存関係の解析回復の評価</title_ja>
      <title_hi>यूनिवर्सल निर्भरता पार्सर CompChain विश्लेषण के माध्यम से विधेय तर्क संरचना की वसूली का मूल्यांकन</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Meastóireacht a dhéanamh ar Parsálaí Spleáchais Uilíoch Aisghabháil Struchtúr Argóintí Réamhthuartha trí Anailís CompChain</title_ga>
      <title_hu>Az univerzális függőség-elemző értékelése Predicate argumentum struktúra helyreállítása CompChain Analysis segítségével</title_hu>
      <title_el>Αξιολόγηση της καθολικής ανάλυσης εξάρτησης ανάκτηση της προκαθορισμένης δομής επιχειρημάτων μέσω ανάλυσης σύνθετης αλυσίδας</title_el>
      <title_it>Valutazione Universal Dependency Parser Recupero della struttura dell'argomento Predicate tramite CompChain Analysis</title_it>
      <title_ka>უნივერსალური დამხოლობულობის პერიზერის განახლება პრედიკომენტის სტრუქტურის განახლება CompChain ანალიზაციით</title_ka>
      <title_kk>CompChain Analysis арқылы әлемдік тәуелсіздік талдағыш аргументтің құрылымын қайталау</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Universalaus priklausomybės analizatoriaus išankstinės argumentų struktūros atkūrimo vertinimas atliekant kompleksinės grandinės analizę</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Оценувањето на универзалниот анализиран апаратор за зависност на предикатната аргументна структура преку комплајн анализа</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Mengevaluasi Penyuarat Dependensi Universal Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analysis</title_ms>
      <title_ml>പ്രിഡിക്കേറ്റ് ആര്‍ഗുമെന്റ് സ്ട്രാക്ട്രൂക്ട്രൂക്ടിക്കേറ്റ് സംവീകരിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള പ്രധാനപ്പെട്</title_ml>
      <title_mn>CompChain Analysis аргаар дэлхийн хамааралтай хамааралтай Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure</title_mn>
      <title_no>Evaluerer universell avhengighetstolkar gjenoppretting av predikate argumentstruktur via CompChain Analysis</title_no>
      <title_mt>Evaluating Universal Dependency Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analysis</title_mt>
      <title_sr>Оценивање универсалне зависимости родителе вратења предицитне аргументских структуре путем анализа компцејна анализа</title_sr>
      <title_si>CompChain විශ්ලේෂණය විධානයෙන් විශේෂයෙන් විශ්වාසයෙන් ජාතික විශේෂ විශ්ලේෂණය සඳහා ප්‍රධාන</title_si>
      <title_so>Qiimeynta baaritaanka baaritaanka ka baaraandegista sharciga ee jaamacadda via CompChain Analysis</title_so>
      <title_pl>Ocena uniwersalnego parsera zależności Odzyskiwanie predykowanej struktury argumentów za pomocą analizy CompChain</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Evaluarea parserului universal de dependenţă recuperarea structurii argumentelor predicate prin analiza CompChain</title_ro>
      <title_ta>Evaluating Universal Dependency Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analysis</title_ta>
      <title_ur>CompChain Analysis (CompChain Analysis) کے ذریعے ارومین اعتباری پارسر کی ارزش کرنا</title_ur>
      <title_sv>Utvärdering av Universal Dependency Parser Återvinning av Predicate Argumentstruktur via CompChain Analysis</title_sv>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Đánh giá sự phụ thuộc chung cực kỳ Phục hồi cấu trúc biện hộ sẵn sàng thông qua Kết cấu phân tích</title_vi>
      <title_hr>Procjenjivanje univerzalne zavisnosti roditelja povratka strukture predrasude Argumenta putem analize CompChain</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Evaluatie van Universal Dependency Parser Recovery van Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analysis</title_nl>
      <title_bg>Оценка на възстановяването на структурата на аргументите чрез анализ на компактната верига</title_bg>
      <title_de>Bewertung der Universal Dependency Parser Wiederherstellung prädikierter Argumentstruktur mittels CompChain Analysis</title_de>
      <title_id>Mengevaluasi Pemproses Dependensi Universal Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analysis</title_id>
      <title_ko>CompChain 분석을 통해 술어 매개 변수 구조를 평가하는 유니버설 의존 해상도 복구</title_ko>
      <title_fa>ارزیابی پزشکی اعتمادی جهانی از ساختار ارزیابی پیش‌بینی از طریق تحلیل CompChain</title_fa>
      <title_da>Evaluering af Universal Dependency Parser Gendannelse af Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analyse</title_da>
      <title_af>Assebliseer Universele Afhanklikheid Ontvaring van Predikteer Argumentstruktuur deur CompChain Analysis</title_af>
      <title_sq>Duke vlerësuar ripërtëritjen e analizuesit universal të varësisë të strukturës së argumentit të parashikuar nëpërmjet analizës së CompChain</title_sq>
      <title_am>ዶሴ `%s'ን ማስፈጠር አልተቻለም፦ %s</title_am>
      <title_sw>Kupima Mradi wa Uhuru wa Uamuzi wa Uamuzi wa Uamuzi wa Uamuzi ulimwenguni kupitia Uchambuzi wa Uchambuzi</title_sw>
      <title_az>CompChain Analizi vasitəsilə Universal Dependency Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure</title_az>
      <title_bs>Procjenjivanje univerzalne zavisnosti roditelja povratka strukture predikata argumenta preko analize CompChain</title_bs>
      <title_tr>Uniwersal Baýumlyk Aýratynyň Taýýarlanmasy Öňe Baglanyş Argument struktury Çarpmasy Aralygy Görkezilýär</title_tr>
      <title_ca>Evaluation Universal Dependence Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analysis</title_ca>
      <title_et>Hinnatakse universaalset sõltuvuse parserit Predicate Argumenti struktuuri taastamine CompChain analüüsi abil</title_et>
      <title_hy>Համաշխարհային կախվածության վերարտադրողի վերականգնումը նախատեսված բանավեճի կառուցվածքի միջոցով</title_hy>
      <title_fi>Universal Dependency Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure by CompChain Analysis</title_fi>
      <title_bn>কম্পিচেইন বিশ্লেষণের মাধ্যমে বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ের মাধ্যমে বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ের মূল্যায়ন করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_cs>Vyhodnocení Universal Dependency Parser Recovery predikátní struktury argumentů pomocí CompChain analýzy</title_cs>
      <title_jv>Language</title_jv>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Vrednotenje univerzalnega razčlenjevalnika odvisnosti Obnovitev strukture predhodnih argumentov z analizo kompaktnih verig</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Evaluating Universal Dependency Parser Recovery of Predicate Argument Structure via CompChain Analysis</title_bo>
      <title_he>הערכה של מחקר תלויות יוניברסלי של מבנה התווכחות מתוכנן באמצעות ניתוח Compchain</title_he>
      <abstract_ar>يعد الاسترداد الدقيق لهيكل الوسيطة الأصلية من تحليل التبعية العالمية (UD) أمرًا أساسيًا للمهام النهائية مثل استخراج الأدوار الدلالية أو تمثيلات الأحداث. تقدم هذه الدراسة compchains ، وهو تصنيف للتسلسل الهرمي لعلاقات التبعية الأصلية الموجودة داخل تحليل UD. تعمل دقة تصنيف compchain كبديل لقياس الاسترداد الدقيق لهيكل الحجة الأصلية من الجمل مع التضمين. قمنا بتحليل توزيع السلاسل في ثلاثة بنوك شجرية إنجليزية UD ، EWT ، GUM و LinES ، وكشفنا أن بنوك الأشجار هذه متفرقة فيما يتعلق بالجمل ذات بنية الحجة الأصلية التي تتضمن تضمين الحجج الأصلية. قمنا بتقييم نماذج خط الأساس UDPipe (v1.2) للمهام المشتركة CoNLL 2018 كمصنفات compchain لبنوك الشجرة EWT و GUMS و LinES UD. تشير نتائجنا إلى أن هذه النماذج الأساسية الثلاثة تظهر أداءً ضعيفًا في الجمل ذات بنية الحجة الأصلية مع أكثر من مستوى واحد من التضمين ؛ استخدمنا compchains لتوصيف الأخطاء التي قام بها هؤلاء المحللين وتقديم أمثلة للتحليلات الخاطئة التي تم إنتاجها بواسطة المحلل اللغوي والتي تم تحديدها باستخدام compchains. قمنا أيضًا بتحليل توزيع المجموعات في 58 بنكًا شجريًا غير إنجليزي UD ثم استخدمنا compchains لتقييم نموذج خط الأساس للمهمة المشتركة CoNLL'18 لكل من هذه البنوك الشجرية. يوضح تحليلنا أن الأداء فيما يتعلق بتصنيف compchain يرتبط ارتباطًا ضعيفًا فقط بـ
مقاييس التقييم الرسمية (LAS و MLAS و BLEX). نحدد الفجوات في توزيع السلاسل في العديد من ضفاف الأشجار UD ، وبالتالي نقدم خارطة طريق لكيفية تكملة بنوك الأشجار هذه. نختتم بمناقشة كيفية توفير الكتيبات لمنظور جديد حول تباين بيانات التدريب لمحللي UD ، فضلاً عن دقة تحليلات UD الناتجة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>La recuperación precisa de la estructura de predicado-argumento de un análisis de Dependencia Universal (UD) es fundamental para las tareas posteriores, como la extracción de roles semánticos o representaciones de eventos. Este estudio presenta compchains, una categorización de la jerarquía de las relaciones de dependencia de predicados presentes dentro de un análisis UD. La precisión de la clasificación de compchain sirve como un indicador para medir la recuperación precisa de la estructura del argumento predicado de las oraciones con incrustación. Analizamos la distribución de compchains en tres bancos de árboles en inglés UD, EWT, GUM y LINes, revelando que estos bancos de árboles son escasos con respecto a oraciones con estructura de predicado-argumento que incluye incrustación de predicado-argumento. Evaluamos los modelos de línea base (análisis de dependencias) de la tarea compartida UDPipe (v1.2) de CoNll 2018 como clasificadores compchain para los bancos de árboles EWT, GUMS y LIneS UD. Nuestros resultados indican que estos tres modelos de referencia muestran un rendimiento más pobre en oraciones con estructura de predicado-argumento con más de un nivel de incrustación; utilizamos compchains para caracterizar los errores cometidos por estos analizadores y presentamos ejemplos de análisis erróneos producidos por el analizador que eran identificado mediante compchains. También analizamos la distribución de compchains en 58 bancos de árboles de UD no ingleses y luego utilizamos compchains para evaluar el modelo de línea base de tareas compartidas de Conll'18 para cada uno de estos bancos de árboles. Nuestro análisis muestra que el rendimiento con respecto a la clasificación de la compchain solo está débilmente correlacionado con la
métricas de evaluación oficiales (LAS, MLAS y BLEX). Identificamos brechas en la distribución de compchains en varios de los bancos de árboles de la UD, proporcionando así una hoja de ruta sobre cómo se pueden complementar estos bancos de árboles. Concluimos discutiendo cómo las compchains proporcionan una nueva perspectiva sobre la escasez de datos de entrenamiento para los analizadores UD, así como la precisión de los análisis UD resultantes.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>A recuperação precisa da estrutura predicado-argumento de uma análise de Dependência Universal (UD) é fundamental para tarefas de downstream, como extração de funções semânticas ou representações de eventos. Este estudo apresenta compchains, uma categorização da hierarquia de relações de dependência de predicado presentes em uma análise UD. A precisão da classificação do compchain serve como um proxy para medir a recuperação precisa da estrutura predicado-argumento de sentenças com incorporação. Analisamos a distribuição de compchains em três treebanks da UD English, EWT, GUM e Lines, revelando que esses treebanks são esparsos em relação a sentenças com estrutura predicado-argumento que inclui embutimento predicado-argumento. Avaliamos os modelos de linha de base (análise de dependência) do CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) como classificadores de cadeia de compilação para os treebanks EWT, GUMS e LinES UD. Nossos resultados indicam que esses três modelos de linha de base apresentam desempenho inferior em sentenças com estrutura predicado-argumento com mais de um nível de incorporação; usamos compchains para caracterizar os erros cometidos por esses analisadores e apresentamos exemplos de análises errôneas produzidas pelo analisador que foram identificadas usando compchains. Também analisamos a distribuição de compchains em 58 treebanks UD não ingleses e, em seguida, usamos compchains para avaliar o modelo de linha de base CoNLL'18 Shared Task para cada um desses treebanks. Nossa análise mostra que o desempenho em relação à classificação da cadeia de compchain é apenas fracamente correlacionado com a
métricas oficiais de avaliação (LAS, MLAS e BLEX). Identificamos lacunas na distribuição de compchains em vários bancos de árvores UD, fornecendo assim um roteiro de como esses bancos de árvores podem ser suplementados. Concluímos discutindo como compchains fornecem uma nova perspectiva sobre a escassez de dados de treinamento para analisadores UD, bem como a precisão das análises UD resultantes.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>ユニバーサル依存性（ UD ）パースからの述語引数構造の正確な回復は、セマンティックロールまたはイベント表現の抽出などのダウンストリームタスクの中心です。 この研究では、UD構文解析内に存在する述語依存関係の階層の分類であるコンピューティングチェーンを紹介します。 コンプチェイン分類の精度は、埋め込みを伴う文から述語-引数構造の正確な回復を測定するためのプロキシとして機能します。 我々は、UD英語のツリーバンク、EWT、GUM、LinESの3つのツリーバンクにおけるコンプチェインの分布を分析し、これらのツリーバンクは、述語論証埋め込みを含む述語論証構造を持つ文に関してまばらであることを明らかにした。 CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2)ベースライン（依存性解析）モデルを、EWT、GUMS、LinES UDツリーバンクのコンプチェーン分類子として評価しました。 私たちの結果は、これらの3つのベースラインモデルは、複数のレベルの埋め込みを持つ述語論証構造を持つ文章では、より悪いパフォーマンスを示していることを示しています。私たちは、これらの構文解析器によって行われたエラーを特徴付けるためにコンプチェインを使用し、コンプチェインを使用して識別された構文解析器によって生成された誤った構文解析の例を提示しました。 また、58の非英語UDツリーバンクにおけるコンプチェインの分布を分析し、その後、これらのツリーバンクのCoNLL '18共有タスクのベースラインモデルを評価するためにコンプチェインを使用しました。 当社の分析によると、コンプチェインの分類に関するパフォーマンスは、
公式の評価指標（ LAS、MLAおよびBLEX ）。私たちは、いくつかのUDツリーバンクにおけるコンプチェーンの配分のギャップを特定し、これらのツリーバンクがどのように補完されるかのロードマップを提供します。最後に、コンプチェインがUDパーサーのトレーニングデータの希少性と、結果として生じるUDパーサーの精度について、どのように新しい視点を提供するかについて説明します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>自通用倚 (UD) 解析中准复谓词-参数结构为下流之任(如取语义角色事示)心。 本论复合,此 UD 解析之所谓词恃层次结构之类也。 复合之类准确性可为摄,以度嵌句之确复谓词参数结构。 析三UD英语树库(EWT,GUM与LinES)中复合之分布,揭此树库相对有谓词参数结构之句(谓词参数嵌)疏也。 估 CoNLL 2018 共事 UDPipe (v1.2) 基线(赖解析)模形,以为 EWT、GUMS 、 LinES UD 树库复合之器。 吾之的结果表明,此三基线者,多嵌级之谓词 - 参数结构,差也; 以复合链来表此解析器所犯之过,而给解析器生用复合之解析示例。 论58非英语UD树库中复合之分,然后以复合链来评树库之CoNLL18共其任基线。 吾之分析表明,于复合之类也
官方评估指标(LAS、MLAS 和 BLEX)。 定数UD树库中复合之差,以补此树库之路线图。 最后,将议复合为 UD 解析器练数疏性及生成 UD 解析准确性供新视角。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Is cuid lárnach de thascanna iartheachtacha é struchtúr na hargóintí réamhaithrise a ghnóthú go cruinn ó pharsáil Spleáchais Uilíoch (UD) mar asbhaint róil shéimeantacha nó léirithe imeachtaí. Tugann an staidéar seo isteach compchains, catagóiriú ar an ordlathas de chaidrimh spleáchais tuar i láthair laistigh de pharsáil UD. Feidhmíonn cruinneas an aicmithe compchain mar sheachvótálaí chun aisghabháil cruinn a dhéanamh ar struchtúr argóinte preideacáide ó abairtí le neadú. Rinneamar anailís ar dháileadh na gcomhshlabhra i dtrí chrann crann Béarla de chuid na Ríochta Aontaithe, EWT, GUM agus Línte, ag tabhairt le fios go bhfuil na bainc chrainn seo gann maidir le habairtí a bhfuil struchtúr argóinte réamh-mheastacháin acu a chuimsíonn neadú réamh-argóint. Rinneamar measúnú ar mhúnlaí bonnlíne (parsáil spleáchais) Tasc Comhroinnte CoNLL 2018 UDPipe (v1.2) mar aicmitheoirí compchain do bhainc chrainn EWT, GUMS agus LineS UD. Léiríonn ár dtorthaí go léiríonn na trí mhúnla bonnlíne seo feidhmíocht níos measa ar phianbhreitheanna le struchtúr argóinte réamh-mheastacháin le níos mó ná leibhéal amháin neadaithe; d’úsáideamar compchain chun na hearráidí a rinne na parsálaithe seo a thréithriú agus samplaí a chur i láthair de pharsálacha earráideacha a tháirg an parsálaí a aithníodh ag baint úsáide as compchains. Rinneamar anailís freisin ar dháileadh compchain i 58 banc crann UD neamh-Bhéarla agus ansin d'úsáideamar compchain chun múnla bonnlíne Tasc Comhroinnte CoNLL'18 a mheas do gach ceann de na bainc crann seo. Léiríonn ár n-anailís nach bhfuil comhghaolú lag idir an fheidhmíocht maidir le haicmiú compchain agus an
méadracht mheastóireachta oifigiúil (LAS, MLAS agus BLEX). Aithnímid bearnaí i ndáileadh na gcomhshlabhraí i roinnt de na bainc chrainn UD, rud a sholáthraímid treochlár don chaoi ar féidir na bainc chrainn seo a fhorlíonadh. Críochnóimid trí phlé a dhéanamh ar an gcaoi a dtugann compchains peirspictíocht nua ar ghanntanas na sonraí oiliúna do pharsálaithe UD, chomh maith le cruinneas na bparsanna UD a thagann as.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hi>यूनिवर्सल डिपेंडेंसी (UD) पार्स से विधेय-तर्क संरचना की सटीक वसूली डाउनस्ट्रीम कार्यों के लिए केंद्रीय है जैसे कि शब्दार्थ भूमिकाओं या घटना प्रतिनिधित्व का निष्कर्षण। यह अध्ययन कॉम्पचेन का परिचय देता है, जो एक यूडी पार्स के भीतर मौजूद विधेय निर्भरता संबंधों के पदानुक्रम का वर्गीकरण है। Compchain वर्गीकरण की सटीकता एम्बेडिंग के साथ वाक्यों से विधेय-तर्क संरचना की सटीक वसूली को मापने के लिए एक प्रॉक्सी के रूप में कार्य करती है। हमने तीन UD अंग्रेजी ट्रीबैंक, EWT, GUM और LinES में compchains के वितरण का विश्लेषण किया, यह खुलासा करते हुए कि ये treebanks विधेय-तर्क संरचना के साथ वाक्यों के संबंध में विरल हैं जिसमें विधेय-तर्क एम्बेडिंग शामिल है। हमने CoNLL 2018 साझा कार्य UDPipe (v1.2) बेसलाइन (निर्भरता पार्सिंग) मॉडल का मूल्यांकन EWT, GUMS और LinES UD treebanks के लिए compchain क्लासिफायरके रूप में किया। हमारे परिणामों से संकेत मिलता है कि ये तीन बेसलाइन मॉडल एम्बेडिंग के एक से अधिक स्तर के साथ विधेय-तर्क संरचना के साथ वाक्यों पर खराब प्रदर्शन प्रदर्शित करते हैं; हम इन पार्सर द्वारा की गई त्रुटियों को चिह्नित करने के लिए compchains का उपयोग किया और पार्सर है कि compchains का उपयोग कर की पहचान की गई थी द्वारा उत्पादित गलत पार्स के उदाहरण प्रस्तुत करते हैं. हमने 58 गैर-अंग्रेजी यूडी ट्रीबैंक में कॉम्पचेन के वितरण का भी विश्लेषण किया और फिर इन ट्रीबैंक्स में से प्रत्येक के लिए CoNLL'18 साझा कार्य बेसलाइन मॉडल का मूल्यांकन करने के लिए compchains का उपयोग किया। हमारे विश्लेषण से पता चलता है कि compchain वर्गीकरण के संबंध में प्रदर्शन केवल कमजोर रूप से सहसंबद्ध है
आधिकारिक मूल्यांकन मैट्रिक्स (LAS, MLAS और BLEX)। हम यूडी ट्रीबैंक के कई हिस्सों में कॉम्पचेन के वितरण में अंतराल की पहचान करते हैं, इस प्रकार इन ट्रीबैंकों को पूरक करने के तरीके के लिए एक रोडमैप प्रदान करते हैं। हम इस बात पर चर्चा करके निष्कर्ष निकालते हैं कि कॉम्पचेन यूडी पार्सर्स के लिए प्रशिक्षण डेटा की स्पार्सिटी पर एक नया परिप्रेक्ष्य कैसे प्रदान करते हैं, साथ ही परिणामस्वरूप यूडी पार्स की सटीकता भी।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ka>სამყარო დამხოლობა (UD) პარასტიდან წარმოადგენებული არგუმენტიური სტრუქტურის წარმოადგენება ცენტრუალურია, როგორც სემონტიური პროლის ან მოვლენების გამოსახულებების გამოყენ ეს სწავლად კომპოფეციები, სუდის პასუზაციაში არსებულია სუდიატური დაკავშირებების თერაქტიკის კატეგორიზაცია. კომპოფეციის კლასიფიკაციის წარმატება იყო პროქსი, როგორც წარმატებითი არგუმენტის სტრუქტურაციის წარმატებით გადასვლა. ჩვენ ანალიზიციეთ სამი UD ინგლისური ტრებონში, EWT, GUM და LinES-ში, რომელიც გამოჩვენებულია, რომ ეს ტრებონები არსებობენ წარმოდგენების შესახებ წარმოდგენების სტრუქტურაციას, რომელიც პრედიკატიკურ ჩვენ CoNLL 2018-ის გაყოფილი საქმე UDPipe (v1.2) მუშაობის მოდელების შესახებ, როგორც EWT, GUMS და LinES UD კლასიფიკაციებისთვის კომპოფენტის კლასიფიკაციები. ჩვენი წარმოდგენები გვაჩვენებს, რომ ეს სამი მხარეს მოდელები გამოიყენებს უფრო ცოტა გამოყენება წარმოდგენებით, რომლებიც წარმოდგენებული არგუმენტის სტრუქტ ჩვენ გამოყენეთ კომპოფეციები, რომლებიც ამ პარასერების შეცდომის შეცდომების განსაკუთრებისთვის და შეცდომა პარასერების მაგალითები, რომლებიც კომპოფეციების გამოყ ჩვენ ასევე გავაანალიზეთ კომპოფეციის გაყოფილი 58 არ ანგლისური UD საბოლოში და შემდეგ გამოყენეთ კომპოფეციები, რომლებიც CoNLL'18 გაყოფილი საბოლოო მოდელს ყველა საბოლოო საბოლოო ჩვენი ანალიზია, რომ კომპოფეციის კლასიფიკაციის შესახებ მხოლოდ ცოტა კომპოფეციის შესახებ
უფრო მეტრიკალური განსაზღვრება (LAS, MLAS და BLEX). ჩვენ განვიცნობით კომპოფეციების გაყოფილების რამდენიმე UD კომპოფეციების განმავლობაში, როგორც ეს კომპოფეციები შეიძლება დამატება. ჩვენ გავაკეთებთ, როგორ კომპოფეციები ახალი პერსტიფიკაციის შესახებ UD პარასერებისთვის მონაცემების შესახებ, და შემდეგ UD პარასერების მართლა.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_kk>Жалпы Тәуелсіздік (UD) талдауынан алдын- ала аргументтің құрылымының тәртібі қалпына келтіру - семантикалық рольдерді не оқиғаларды таңдау сияқты тапсырмалардың ортасында төмендету тапсы Бұл зерттеу UD талдауындағы тәуелсіздік қатынастарының иерархиясының жинақтауын, композицияларды көрсетеді. Комплекциялау классификациясының дұрыс қалпындығын ендіру үшін прокси ретінде анықтайды. Біз үш UD ағылшын тіркесімдерінде композицияларды, EWT, GUM және LinES тіркесімдерінде тарату үшін анализ етіп, бұл жол тіркесімдері алдын- ала аргументті ендіру үшін сұлбалармен қатынасыз келеді. Біз CoNLL 2018 ортақтастырылған тапсырма UDPipe (v1.2) негізгі жол (тәуелдік талдау) үлгілерін EWT, GUMS және LinES UD бағыттарының композициялық классификаторлары ретінде анықтадық. Біздің нәтижелеріміз бұл үш негізгі үлгі үлгілер бірнеше деңгейінде аргументтің құрылымы бар сөздерге аргументтік құрылымыз керек болады дегенді көрсетеді. Біз осы талдаушылардың қателерін таңдау үшін композицияларды қолдандық және композициялармен анықталған талдаушылардың қате талдау мысалдарын таңдадық. Сонымен қатар, 58 ағылшын тілінде UD бақылау үшін композициялардың үлестірімін анализ және содан кейін CoNLL'18 ортақ тапсырмалар негізгі үлгісін бақылау үшін композицияларды қолдандық. Біздің анализиямыз композициялық классификациясына қатысты жылдамдығы тек бақытты қатысты
ресми оқу метрикалары (LAS, MLAS және BLEX). Біз композициялардың үлестірімінің бірнеше UD құрылғыларындағы кеңістіктерді анықтаймыз, сондықтан бұл құрылғылардың қалай қосылуы мүмкін екенін жол картасын көрсетеді. Біз UD талдаушыларының бақылау мәліметтерінің жаңа перспективін қалай бақылау керектігін және UD талдаушыларының дұрыстығын талдап тұрып тұрамыз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_el>Η ακριβής ανάκτηση της δομής προκαθορισμένων ορίων από μια ανάλυση καθολικής εξάρτησης (είναι κεντρική σε μεταγενέστερες εργασίες, όπως η εξαγωγή σημασιολογικών ρόλων ή αναπαραστάσεων συμβάντων. Η παρούσα μελέτη εισάγει σύνθετες αλυσίδες, μια κατηγοριοποίηση της ιεραρχίας των σχέσεων υπαρκτών εξαρτήσεων που υπάρχουν μέσα σε μια ανάλυση UD. Η ακρίβεια της ταξινόμησης συναλυσίδας χρησιμεύει ως αντιπρόσωπος για τη μέτρηση της ακριβούς ανάκτησης της δομής των υπαρκτών-ορίων από προτάσεις με ενσωμάτωση. Αναλύσαμε την κατανομή των σύνθετων αλυσίδων σε τρεις αγγλικές βάσεις δέντρων, EWT, GUM και LinES, αποκαλύπτοντας ότι αυτές οι βάσεις δέντρων είναι αραιές σε σχέση με προτάσεις με δομή υπαρκτού-ορίσματος που περιλαμβάνει ενσωμάτωση υπαρκτού-ορίσματος. Αξιολογήσαμε τα μοντέλα βάσης βάσης (ανάλυση εξαρτήσεων) ως ταξινομητές σύνθετης αλυσίδας για τις τράπεζες δέντρων EWT, GUMS και LinES UD. Τα αποτελέσματά μας δείχνουν ότι αυτά τα τρία βασικά μοντέλα παρουσιάζουν χειρότερη απόδοση σε προτάσεις με δομή υπαρκτού-επιχειρήματος με περισσότερα από ένα επίπεδα ενσωμάτωσης. Χρησιμοποιήσαμε συνθέσεις για να χαρακτηρίσουμε τα λάθη που έγιναν από αυτούς τους αναλυτές και να παρουσιάσουμε παραδείγματα λανθασμένων αναλύσεων που παράγονται από τον αναλυτή που εντοπίστηκαν χρησιμοποιώντας συνθέσεις. Αναλύσαμε επίσης την κατανομή των σύνθετων αλυσίδων σε 58 μη αγγλικές δένδρες και στη συνέχεια χρησιμοποιήσαμε σύνθετες αλυσίδες για να αξιολογήσουμε το μοντέλο βάσης κοινής εργασίας για κάθε μία από αυτές τις δένδρες. Η ανάλυσή μας δείχνει ότι η απόδοση όσον αφορά την ταξινόμηση της αλυσίδας συσχετίζεται ελάχιστα με την
επίσημες μετρήσεις αξιολόγησης (LAS, MLAS και BLEX). Εντοπίζουμε κενά στην κατανομή των συμπληρωμάτων σε αρκετές από τις δενδρόχθες, παρέχοντας έτσι έναν οδικό χάρτη για τον τρόπο με τον οποίο μπορούν να συμπληρωθούν αυτές οι δενδρόχθες. Ολοκληρώνοντας συζητώντας πώς οι συνθέσεις παρέχουν μια νέα προοπτική για τη σπανιότητα των δεδομένων κατάρτισης για τους αναλυτές καθώς και την ακρίβεια των αναλύσεων που προκύπτουν.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Il recupero accurato della struttura predicato-argomento da un'analisi UD (Universal Dependency) è centrale per attività a valle come l'estrazione di ruoli semantici o rappresentazioni di eventi. Questo studio introduce compchains, una categorizzazione della gerarchia delle relazioni di dipendenza predicate presenti all'interno di un parse UD. L'accuratezza della classificazione compchain serve da proxy per misurare il recupero accurato della struttura predicato-argomento da frasi con incorporazione. Abbiamo analizzato la distribuzione delle compchains in tre treebanks inglesi UD, EWT, GUM e LinES, rivelando che questi treebanks sono scarsi rispetto alle frasi con struttura predicato-argomento che include l'embedding predicato-argomento. Abbiamo valutato i modelli di base (analisi delle dipendenze) di CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) come classificatori compchain per i treebank EWT, GUMS e LinES UD. I nostri risultati indicano che questi tre modelli di base mostrano prestazioni più scarse su frasi con struttura predicato-argomento con più di un livello di incorporazione; Abbiamo usato compchains per caratterizzare gli errori commessi da questi parser e presentare esempi di pars erronei prodotti dal parser che sono stati identificati utilizzando compchains. Abbiamo anche analizzato la distribuzione di compchains in 58 treebank UD non inglesi e poi usato compchains per valutare il modello di base CoNLL'18 Shared Task di ciascuno di questi treebank. La nostra analisi mostra che la performance rispetto alla classificazione compchain è solo debolmente correlata con la
metriche ufficiali di valutazione (LAS, MLAS e BLEX). Identifichiamo le lacune nella distribuzione delle catene compchain in diversi dei banchi degli alberi UD, fornendo così una roadmap per come questi ultimi possono essere completati. Concludiamo discutendo come le compchains forniscono una nuova prospettiva sulla scarsità dei dati di addestramento per i parser UD, così come l'accuratezza dei pars UD risultanti.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_hu>A predikát-argumentum struktúra pontos helyreállítása az univerzális függőség (UD) elemezésből központi szerepet játszik az olyan downstream feladatokban, mint a szemantikai szerepek vagy eseményreprezentációk kivonása. Ez a tanulmány bemutatja a compchains-okat, a predikátus függőségi kapcsolatok hierarchiájának kategorizálását egy UD elemzésben. A compchain osztályozás pontossága proxyként szolgál a predikátus-argumentum struktúra pontos helyreállításának mérésére beágyazással. Elemeztük a kompchainok eloszlását három UD angol fákban, EWT-ben, GUM-ben és LinES-ben, feltárva, hogy ezek a fákban ritkák a predikát-argumentum struktúrájú mondatok tekintetében, amelyek magukban foglalják a predikát-argumentum beágyazást. A CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) alapértelmezési modelleket (függőség elemzése) az EWT, a GUMS és a LinES UD fák kompchain osztályozójaként értékeltük. Eredményeink azt mutatják, hogy ez a három alapvető modell rosszabb teljesítményt mutat olyan mondatokon, amelyek predikát-argumentum struktúrájú, több mint egy szintű beágyazással rendelkeznek; Kompchains segítségével jellemeztük az említett elemzők hibáit és bemutattuk a kompchains segítségével azonosított hibás elemzéseket. Ezenkívül elemeztük a kompchainok eloszlását 58 nem angol UD fákban, majd kompchainokat használtunk a CoNLL'18 Shared Task alapvető modelljének értékelésére mindegyik fákban. Elemzésünk azt mutatja, hogy a kompchain osztályozás teljesítménye csak gyengén korrelálódik a
hivatalos értékelési mutatók (LAS, MLAS és BLEX). Azonosítjuk a kompchains elosztásában rejlő hiányosságokat több UD-fázisban, így útitervet készítünk arra vonatkozóan, hogyan lehet kiegészíteni ezeket a fázisokat. Végezetül megvitatjuk, hogy a kompchains hogyan nyújt új perspektívát az UD elemzők képzési adatainak ritkaságáról, valamint az eredményekből eredő UD elemzések pontosságáról.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ms>Pemulihan tepat struktur argumen-predikat dari huraian Dependensi Universal (UD) adalah pusat ke tugas bawah seperti ekstraksi peranan semantik atau perwakilan peristiwa. kajian ini memperkenalkan compchains, kategorisasi hierarki hubungan dependensi predikat yang ada dalam huraian UD. Ketepatan klasifikasi compchain berkhidmat sebagai proksi untuk mengukur pemulihan tepat struktur argumen-predicate dari kalimat dengan penyembedding. Kami menganalisis distribusi kompchains dalam tiga batang pokok UD Inggeris, EWT, GUM dan LinES, mengungkapkan bahawa batang pokok ini jarang berkaitan dengan kalimat dengan struktur predicate-argumen yang termasuk penyambungan predicate-argumen. Kami menilai model dasar UDPipe Tugas Berkongsi CoNLL 2018 (v1.2) (penghuraian dependensi) sebagai klasifikasi kompchain untuk pangkalan pokok UD EWT, GUMS dan LinES. Keputusan kami menunjukkan bahawa tiga model asas ini menunjukkan prestasi yang lebih buruk pada kalimat dengan struktur argumen-predikat dengan lebih dari satu tahap penyambungan; kami menggunakan compchains untuk mengurai ralat yang dibuat oleh maklumat maklumat ini dan memperlihatkan contoh-contoh maklumat yang salah yang dibuat oleh maklumat maklumat yang dikenalpasti menggunakan compchains. Kami juga menganalisis distribusi kompchains dalam 58 batang pokok UD bukan Inggeris dan kemudian menggunakan batang untuk menilai model dasar Tugas Berkongsi CoNLL'18 untuk setiap batang pokok ini. Analisis kami menunjukkan bahawa prestasi terhadap klasifikasi compchain hanya berkorrelasi lemah dengan
metrik penilaian rasmi (LAS, MLAS dan BLEX). Kami mengenalpasti kekurangan dalam pengedaran komprantai di beberapa batang pokok UD, sehingga menyediakan peta laluan untuk bagaimana batang pokok ini boleh ditambah. Kami menyimpulkan dengan membincangkan bagaimana compchains menyediakan perspektif baru tentang kecepatan data latihan untuk penghurai UD, serta ketepatan hurai UD yang berasal.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Accurate recovery of predicate-argument structure from a Universal Dependency (UD) parse is central to downstream tasks such as extraction of semantic roles or event representations.  Dan l-istudju jintroduċi kompchains, kategorizzazzjoni tal-ġerarkija tar-relazzjonijiet ta’ dipendenza predikata preżenti fi ħdan analiżi UD. L-akkuratezza tal-klassifikazzjoni compchain isservi bħala proxy għall-kejl tal-irkupru preċiż tal-istruttura predikata-argument minn sentenzi bl-inkorporazzjoni. Aħna analizzaw id-distribuzzjoni tal-kompchains fi tliet banek tas-siġar Ingliżi UD, EWT, GUM u LinES, u żvelajna li dawn il-banek tas-siġar huma ftit fir-rigward ta’ sentenzi bi struttura ta’ argument predikat li tinkludi inkorporazzjoni ta’ argument predikat. Ivvalutajna l-mudelli tal-linja bażi tal-UDPipe (v1.2) ta’ Kompitu Kondiviż CoNLL 2018 (dependency parsing) bħala klassifikaturi kompchain għall-banek tas-siġar EWT, GUMS u LinES UD. Ir-riżultati tagħna jindikaw li dawn it-tliet mudelli ta’ linja bażi juru prestazzjoni aktar fqira fuq sentenzi bi struttura ta’ argument predikat b’aktar minn livell wieħed ta’ inkorporazzjoni; użajna compchains biex jikkaratterizzaw l-iżbalji magħmula minn dawn il-parsers u ppreżentajna eżempji ta’ parsers żbaljati prodotti mill-parser li ġew identifikati bl-użu ta’ compchains. Analiżijna wkoll id-distribuzzjoni ta’ compchains f’58 bank tas-siġar UD mhux Ingliż u mbagħad użajna compchains biex jevalwaw il-mudell ta’ linja bażi ta’ ħidma kondiviża CoNLL’18 għal kull wieħed minn dawn il-bank tas-siġar. L-analiżi tagħna turi li l-prestazzjoni fir-rigward tal-klassifikazzjoni compchain hija biss b’mod dgħajjef korrelata mal-
metriċi uffiċjali ta’ evalwazzjoni (LAS, MLAS u BLEX). Aħna nidentifikaw nuqqasijiet fid-distribuzzjoni tal-kompchains f’bosta mill-banek tas-siġar tal-UD, u b’hekk nipprovdu pjan direzzjonali dwar kif dawn il-banek tas-siġar jistgħu jiġu ssupplimentati. Aħna nikkonkludu billi niddiskutu kif il-kumpchains jipprovdu perspettiva ġdida dwar l-iskarsezza tad-dejta tat-taħriġ għall-analizzaturi UD, kif ukoll il-preċiżjoni tal-analiżijiet UD li jirriżultaw.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_lt>Tikslis išankstinių argument ų struktūros atkūrimas iš universaliosios priklausomybės (UD) analizės yra pagrindinis ir tolesnių užduočių, pavyzdžiui, semantinių vaidmenų gavimas arba renginių atstovavimas. Šiame tyrime įdiegtos sąsajos, pagal kurias klasifikuojami išankstiniai priklausomybės santykiai UD analizėje. Komplaketinės grandinės klasifikacijos tikslumas naudojamas kaip nuoroda tiksliam išgavimui iš įterptų sakinių matuoti. We analyzed the distribution of compchains in three UD English treebanks, EWT, GUM and LinES, revealing that these treebanks are sparse with respect to sentences with predicate-argument structure that includes predicate-argument embedding.  Įvertinome CoNLL 2018 m. bendros užduoties UDPipe (v1.2) bazinius modelius (priklausomybės analizavimas), kaip EWT, GUMS ir LinES UD medžių sąrankų kompleksų klasifikatorius. Mūsų rezultatai rodo, kad šiuose trijuose pagrindiniuose modeliuose prastesnis rezultatas vertinant sakinius, turinčius sudėtingą argument ų struktūrą ir turinčius daugiau kaip vieną įterpimo lygį; we used compchains to characterize the errors made by these parsers and present examples of erroneous parses produced by the parser that were identified using compchains.  Taip pat analizavome kompgrandinių pasiskirstymą 58 ne anglų UD medžių dėžutėse ir tada panaudojome kompgrandines įvertinti CoNLL'18 bendros užduoties bazinį model į kiekvienam iš šių medžių dėžučių. Mūsų analizė rodo, kad sąsajos klasifikavimo rezultatai yra tik silpnai koreliuojami su
oficialūs vertinimo rodikliai (LAS, MLAS ir BLEX). We identify gaps in the distribution of compchains in several of the UD treebanks, thus providing a roadmap for how these treebanks may be supplemented.  Baigdami diskutuojame apie tai, kaip kompchains suteikia naują perspektyvą dėl UD analizatorių mokymo duomenų nedaug, taip pat dėl gautų UD analizatorių tikslumo.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mn>Универсалд хамааралтай (UD) хуваалцааны алдартай аргументын бүтцийн шууд сэргээгдэх нь семантик дүр зураг эсвэл үйл явдлын төлөвлөлтийг гаргах төвөгтэй ажил юм. Энэ судалгаа UD хуваалцааны дотор байгаа хамааралтай хамааралтай харилцааны хэлбэрүүдийг бүрдүүлдэг. Compchain хуваалтын тодорхойлолт нь тодорхой аргументын бүтцийг өгүүлбэрээс тодорхойлохын тулд прокси болно. Бид гурван UD Англи хэлний дагуул, EWT, GUM болон LinES-д компцейнүүдийн хуваарилалтыг шинжилгээ хийсэн. Эдгээр дагуулын дагуул нь алдартай аргументын бүтцийг харуулж байгааг харуулсан. Бид 2018 оны CoNLL-ын хуваалтын Task UDPipe (v1.2) суурь шугам (dependency parsing) загварыг EWT, GUMS болон LinES UD загварын компцейны хуваалтын хуваалтын хуваалтын хуваалтын хэлбэрүүдийг үнэлгээд үзсэн. Бидний үр дүн нь эдгээр гурван суурь шугам загварууд нэгээс их хэмжээтэй аргументын бүтэц дээр илүү ядуу үйл ажиллагааг харуулж байна. Эдгээр ажиллагчид хийсэн алдаа нарийвчлахын тулд компцейнүүдийг ашиглаж, компцейнүүдийг ашиглан гаргасан алдаа алдаа ажиллах жишээ гаргасан. Бид мөн 58 Англи хэсгийг биш UD загварын хуваалцааны хуваалцааныг судалж, дараа нь CoNLL'18 хуваалцан ажлын суурь загварыг эдгээр загварын бүрт үнэлэх зорилго ашигласан. Бидний шинжилгээнд хэмжээний хэлбэртэй харьцуулах үйл ажиллагаа зөвхөн бага зэрэг холбоотой гэдгийг харуулж байна.
албан ёсны дүгнэлт метрик (LAS, MLAS, BLEX). Бид хэд хэдэн UD дагуулын зайн хуваарилалтын ялгааг тодорхойлдог. Иймээс эдгээр дагуулын зам газрын зураг хэрхэн нэмэгдүүлж болох вэ? Мөн бид UD ажиллаачидын сургалтын өгөгдлийг хэрхэн шинэ харагдах талаар ярилцсан юм. Мөн үр дүнтэй UD ажиллаачидын тодорхойлолт.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_mk>Точното обновување на структурата на предикативните аргументи од анализата на универзалната зависност (УД) е централно до понатамошни задачи, како што е извлекувањето семантични улоги или претставувањето на настаните. This study introduces compchains, a categorization of the hierarchy of predicate dependency relations present within a UD parse.  Точноста на класификацијата compchain служи како прокси за мерење на прецизното обновување на структурата predicate-argument од речениците со вградување. Ја анализиравме дистрибуцијата на комплајнови во три англиски дрвја на УД, ЕВТ, ГУМ и ЛИНЕС, откривајќи дека овие дрвја се мали во однос на речениците со структура на predicate-argument која вклучува вградување predicate-argument. Ги проценивме моделите на CoNLL 2018 поделена задача UDPipe (v1.2) во основа (анализирање зависност) како комплајн класификатори за EWT, GUMS и LinES UD дрвја. Нашите резултати укажуваат на тоа дека овие три основни модели покажуваат полоши резултати на речениците со структура на предикативни аргументи со повеќе од едно ниво на вградување; Користевме комплајни за да ги карактеризираме грешките направени од овие анализатори и да ги претставиме примерите на грешни анализатори произведени од анализаторот кои беа идентификувани користејќи комплајни. Ние, исто така, ја анализиравме дистрибуцијата на комплајнови во 58 неанглиски UD дрвја банки и потоа користевме комплајнови за да го процениме основниот модел на CoNLL'18 Shared Task за секоја од овие дрвја банки. Our analysis shows that performance with respect to compchain classification is only weakly correlated with the
официјални метрики за проценка (ЛАС, МЛАС и БЛЕКС). Ние ги идентификуваме празнините во дистрибуцијата на комплајнови во неколку од дрвјата на УД, со што ќе обезбедиме патоказ за тоа како овие дрвја може да бидат дополнителни. We conclude by discussing how compchains provide a new perspective on the sparsity of training data for UD parsers, as well as the accuracy of the resulting UD parses.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ro>Recuperarea exactă a structurii argumentelor predicate dintr-o analiză de dependență universală (UD) este centrală pentru activitățile din aval, cum ar fi extragerea rolurilor semantice sau reprezentările evenimentelor. Acest studiu introduce compchains, o categorizare a ierarhiei relațiilor de dependență predicate prezente într-un parse UD. Precizia clasificării compchain servește ca un proxy pentru măsurarea recuperării precise a structurii predicat-argument din propoziții cu încorporare. Am analizat distribuția compchain-urilor în trei braebanks UD engleză, EWT, GUM și LinES, dezvăluind că aceste braebanks sunt rare în ceea ce privește propozițiile cu structură predicat-argument care include încorporarea predicat-argument. Am evaluat modelele CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) de referință (analizarea dependenței) ca clasificatoare compchain pentru treebanks EWT, GUMS și LinES UD. Rezultatele noastre indică faptul că aceste trei modele de bază prezintă performanțe mai slabe pe propoziții cu structură predicat-argument cu mai mult de un nivel de încorporare; Am folosit compchains pentru a caracteriza erorile făcute de acești parsers și prezenta exemple de parsers eronate produse de parser care au fost identificate folosind compchains. De asemenea, am analizat distribuția compchain-urilor în 58 de treebanks UD non-engleză și apoi am folosit compchains pentru a evalua modelul de bază CoNLL'18 Shared Task pentru fiecare dintre aceste treebanks. Analiza noastră arată că performanța în ceea ce privește clasificarea compchain este doar slab corelată cu
măsurători oficiale de evaluare (LAS, MLAS și BLEX). Identificăm lacunele în distribuția lanțurilor complantate în mai multe dintre brațele UD, oferind astfel o foaie de parcurs pentru modul în care aceste brațe pot fi completate. Încheiem discutând modul în care compchain-urile oferă o nouă perspectivă asupra spartității datelor de instruire pentru analizoarele UD, precum și asupra acurateții analizărilor UD rezultate.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_ml>ഒരു യുഡി പാര്‍സില്‍ നിന്നും പ്രധാനപ്പെടുത്തുന്ന ആര്‍ഗ്യുമെന്‍റിയുടെ ഘട്ടത്തില്‍ നിന്നും പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായി വീണ്ടെടുക്കുന്നത് സെമാന്റിക ഈ പഠനത്തില്‍ യുഡി പാര്‍സിന്‍റെ ഉള്ളിലുള്ള ആശ്രയ ബന്ധങ്ങളുടെ ഹിയേരാര്‍ച്ചിയുടെ വിഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ ചങ്ങലകളെ പരിചയപ് വാക്കുകളില്‍ നിന്നും വാക്കുകളില്‍ നിന്നും പൂര്‍ണ്ണമായി വീണ്ടും നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കുന്നതിനായി സജ്ജീകരിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള ക്രോക മൂന്നു ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് ട്രീബാങ്കുകളിലും ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് ട്രീബാങ്കുകളിലും കോമ്പ്ഷന്‍ വിതരണം ചെയ്യുന്നതിനെ ഞങ്ങള്‍ അന്വേഷിച്ചു. പ്രഖ്യാപിക്കുന്ന വാക്കുകളില്‍ ഈ ട്ര ഞങ്ങള്‍ കോണ്‍എല്‍ 2018 പങ്കുചേര്‍ത്ത ടാസ്ക് യുഡിപിപ്പി (v1. 2) ബെസ്റ്റലൈന്‍ (ആശ്രയിക്കുന്ന പാര്‍സി) മോഡലുകള്‍ യൂട്ടിയുടെയും ഗ്യുമിസും ലൈനെസ് യുഡി ട്രീബ നമ്മുടെ ഫലങ്ങള്‍ വ്യക്തമാക്കുന്നു ഈ മൂന്നു ബെസ്ലൈന്‍ മോഡലുകള്‍ വാക്കുകളില്‍ ഏറ്റവും കുറഞ്ഞ പ്രദര്‍ശനം കാണിക്കുന്നു. ഒരു നിലയി ഈ പാര്‍സറുകള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കിയ തെറ്റുകളെ ക്രമീകരിക്കാന്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ സങ്കീര്‍ണ്ണചങ്ങലകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിച്ചു കൊണ്ടിരുന്നു. സങ്കീര്‍ണ് ഞങ്ങള്‍ 58 ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് അല്ലാത്ത ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് യുഡി ട്രീബാങ്കുകളില്‍ സങ്കീര്‍ണ്ണമായി വിതരണം ചെയ്യുന്നതും അന്വേഷിച്ചു. പിന്നീട് നമ്മള്‍ ഈ ട്രീബാങ് നമ്മുടെ അന്വേഷണം കാണിക്കുന്നത് കൊണ്ട് സങ്കീര്‍ണ്ണമായ വ്യവസ്ഥയുടെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനത്തിന് മാത്രമേ ദുര്‍ബ
official evaluation metrics (LAS, MLAS and BLEX).  യുഡി ട്രീബാങ്കുകളില്‍ കുറച്ച് കണക്കുകള്‍ വിതരണം ചെയ്യുന്നതില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ വ്യത്യാസങ്ങള്‍ തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നു. അതുകൊണ്ട് ഈ ത്രീബാ യുഡി പാര്‍സറുകള്‍ക്കുള്ള പരിശീലനത്തിന്റെ സ്പെരിസ്റ്റിയില്‍ പുതിയ കാഴ്ചപ്പെടുത്തുന്നതിനെക്കുറിച്ചും യുഡി പാര്‍സുകളുട</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_pl>Dokładne odzyskiwanie struktury argumentów predykatów z parsy uniwersalnej zależności (UD) ma kluczowe znaczenie dla dalszych zadań, takich jak ekstrakcja ról semantycznych lub reprezentacji zdarzeń. W pracy wprowadzono kompchainy, kategoryzację hierarchii relacji zależności predykatów obecnych w parsie UD. Dokładność klasyfikacji compchain służy jako zastępca do pomiaru dokładnego odzyskania struktury predykatów-argumentów ze zdań z osadzeniem. Analizowaliśmy rozkład kompańców w trzech angielskich bankach UD, EWT, GUM i LinES, ujawniając, że te banki drzew są rzadkie w odniesieniu do zdań o strukturze predykat-argument, która zawiera osadzanie predykat-argument. Oceniliśmy modele bazowe (parsowanie zależności) CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) jako klasyfikatory kompchain dla banków drzew EWT, GUMS i LinES UD. Nasze wyniki wskazują, że te trzy modele bazowe wykazują słabsze wydajności w zdaniach o strukturze predykatów-argumentów z więcej niż jednym poziomem osadzenia; Użyliśmy komponentów do scharakteryzowania błędów popełnionych przez te parsery i przedstawiliśmy przykłady błędnych parserów wytworzonych przez parser, które zostały zidentyfikowane za pomocą komponentów. Analizowaliśmy również rozkład kompchainów w 58 nieangielskich drzewach UD, a następnie użyliśmy kompchainów do oceny modelu bazowego CoNLL'18 Shared Task dla każdego z tych drzew. Nasza analiza pokazuje, że wydajność w zakresie klasyfikacji kompchain jest tylko słabo skorelowana z
oficjalne wskaźniki oceny (LAS, MLAS i BLEX). Identyfikujemy luki w rozkładzie kompańcuchów w kilku drzewach UD, dostarczając tym samym mapę drogową dla tego, jak te drzewa mogą być uzupełniane. Na zakończenie omówimy, w jaki sposób kompchainy zapewniają nową perspektywę na słabość danych treningowych dla parserów UD, a także dokładność wynikowych parser UD.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Akkurat gjenoppretting av predikativ argument-strukturen frå ein universell avhengighet (UD) er sentralt til nedtrekking av oppgåver som ekstrahering av semantiske rolar eller hendingssrepresentasjonar. Denne studien introduserer kompleksjonar, ein kategorisering av hierarkien av forandrande avhengighetsrelasjonar som finst i eit UD-tolking. Nøyaktighet for kompleksjonsklassifikasjon er ein mellomtenar for å måla nøyaktig gjenoppretting av predikat- argument- struktur frå setningar med innbygging. Vi analysere distribusjonen av kompleksjonar i tre UD-engelske treebanktar, EWT, GUM og LinES, som viser at desse treebankta er sparke med respekt til setningar med predikat-argument-struktur som inneheld predikat-argumentinnbygging. Vi evaluerte CoNLL 2018 delte oppgåva UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (avhengighetstolking) som komplekseringar for EWT, GUMS og LinES UD- treebanksane. Resultatet våre tyder på at desse tre baselinjemodelene viser dårlegare utføringar på setningar med predikat argument-struktur med fleire enn eitt innbyggingsnivå. vi brukte kompleksjonar for å karakterisera feilen gjeven av desse analyserane og gjeldande eksemplar av feil tolkingar produsert av tolkaren som vart identifisert med kompleksjonar. Vi analysere også distribusjonen av kompleksjonar i 58 treebanktar som ikkje er engelsk UD, og så brukte kompleksjonar for å evaluera baselinjesmodellen for CoNLL'18 delt oppgåver for kvar av desse treebankta. Analysen vårt viser at utviklinga med høve til kompleksjonsklassifikasjon er berre svakt korrelatert med den
offisielle evalueringsmetrikar (LAS, MLAS og BLEX). Vi identifiserer mellomrom i distribusjonen av kompleksjonar i fleire av UD- treebankene, slik at det gjev ei veikart for korleis desse treebankene kan leggjast til. Vi avsluttar med å diskutera korleis kompleksjonar gjev ei ny perspektiv på sparsiteten av opplæringsdata for UD-tolkarar, og nøyaktigheten av resultatet UD-tolkarar.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_sr>Upravo oporavak predikatne strukture argument a iz analize univerzalne zavisnosti (UD) je centralno za smanjenje zadataka poput izvlačenja semantičkih uloga ili predstavljanja događaja. Ova studija predstavlja komplansiranje, kategorizaciju hijerarhije predikatnih odnosa zavisnosti koje su prisutne unutar UD analize. Točnost klasifikacije kompchaina služi kao proksi za mjerenje tačnog oporavka strukture predikata argument a iz rečenica sa integracijom. Analizirali smo distribuciju kompchaina na tri UD engleske trgovine, EWT, GUM i LinES, otkrivajući da su te trgovine rezervne u vezi rečenica sa predikatnem strukturom argumenta koja uključuje predikatne integracije argumenta. Procjenjivali smo modele podijeljenog zadatka UDPipe (v1.2) za početnu liniju (analizanje ovisnosti) CoNLL 2018 kao klasifikatore kompchaina za EWT, GUMS i LinES UD trgovine. Naši rezultati ukazuju na to da ove tri osnovne modela pokazuju siromašniju izvršnost rečenica sa predikatnim strukturom argumenta sa više od jedne nivoe ugrađenja; Koristili smo komplansiranje kako bi karakterizirali greške koje su napravili ovi parseri i predstavili primjere grešnih parsera proizvođenih od strane analizatora koji su identifikovani koristeći komplansiranje. Takođe smo analizirali distribuciju kompchaina na 58 ne-engleskim UD treebancima i onda smo koristili kompchaine za procjenu model podjele zadataka CoNLL'18 za svaku od ovih treebancija. Naša analiza pokazuje da je izvedba u pogledu klasifikacije komplekcija slaba povezana sa
zvanična procjena metrika (LAS, MLAS i BLEX). Identificiramo praznine u distribuciji komplansa u nekoliko UD-ovih trgovačkih granica, tako pružajući putnu mapu kako bi se ovi treebani mogli dodati. Zaključili smo razgovoreći o tome kako komplanci pružaju novu perspektivu o isključivosti podataka obuke za UD parsere, kao i preciznosti rezultatnih UD analiza.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ta>பொது சார்ந்த சார்பு (UD) பகுதியிலிருந்து முன்னிருப்பு தருமதிப்பு உருவமைப்பை சரியாக மீட்டெடுப்பது பெரிய இடைவெளிப்பட்ட பணிகளை போன்று  இந்த ஆராய்ச்சியின் முன்னிருப்பு சார்ந்த சார்பு தொடர்புகளை குறிப்பிடுகிறது, முன்னிருப்பு சார்பு தொடர்புகளி வாக்கியங்களில் இருந்து முன்னிருந்து வாக்கியங்களின் சரியான மீட்டு சரியான முன்னிருப்பு வாக்கியம் அமைப்பை அளவிடுவதற்கு கூ மூன்று UD ஆங்கிலத்தின் Treebanks, EWT, GUM மற்றும் LinES-ல் இந்த மூன்று முன்னிருப்பு தருமதிப்பு கட்டமைப்பில் வாக்கியங்கள் சேர்க்கப்பட்டது என்பதை அறிவித்தோம். We evaluated the CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (dependency parsing) models as compchain classifiers for the EWT, GUMS and LinES UD treebanks.  நம்முடைய முடிவு இந்த பார்சர்கள் செய்யப்பட்ட பிழைகளை எழுதுவதற்காகவும் தற்போது பிழையான பார்ச்சர் உருவாக்கிய பிழைகளின் உதாரணங்களையும் க நாங்கள் 58 ஆங்கிலம் இல்லாத UD ட்ரீபாங்க்களில் கூட்டிய கட்டுப்பாட்டை விரிவாக்கத்தை ஆய்வு செய்தோம் மற்றும் ஒவ்வொரு treebanks க்கும் கோன்எல் ' நம்முடைய ஆய்வு காண்பிக்கிறது சங்கிலி வகைப்படுத்தல் பற்றிய செயல்பாடு மட்டும் பலவீனமாக இணைந்து கொண்ட
Official evaluation methods (LAS, MLAS and BLEX). நாம் குறிப்புகளை விரிவாக்குதலில் குறிப்புகளை கண்டுபிடிக்கிறோம். இந்த முனைகள் எவ்வாறு சேர்க்க முடியும். நாம் முடிவு செய்து விளக்கம் எவ்வாறு புதிய கூட்டும் பார்வைகளை கொடுக்கும் பொழுது தெரியும் முடிவு, UD பார்ச்சர்களுக்கு பய</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_si>සාමාන්‍ය විශේෂතාව (UD) පරීක්ෂණයෙන් ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක සංස්ථානය සඳහා ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක සංස්ථාන මේ පරීක්ෂණය සම්බන්ධ විශ්වාස කරනවා, UD පරීක්ෂණයෙන් ඉන්න තියෙන ප්‍රධානය සම්බන්ධ සම්බන්ධතාවක් වල Name අපි UD ඉංග්‍රීසි ට්‍රෙබැන්ක් තුන්දෙනුවෙන්, EWT, GUM හා Lines වලින් කම්පන්ස් විතරය විශ්ලේෂණය කරලා තියෙනවා, ප්‍රකාශ කරනවා මේ ට්‍රෙබැන්ක් වලින අපි CoNLL 2018 සාමාන්‍ය වැඩක් UDPipe (v1.2) ප්‍රමාණය (සාමාන්‍ය විශ්ලේෂණය) මොඩේල් වල EWT, GUMS සහ Lines UD ට්‍රෙබැන්ක්ස් වලට compchain classifiers විශේෂකයි. අපේ ප්‍රතිචාරය පෙන්වන්නේ මේ මූලික මොඩේල් තුන්දෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රතිචාරයක් පෙන්වන්නේ ප්‍රතිචාරයක් වගේ ප්‍රති අපි compchains භාවිතා කරනවා මේ පරිස්සර් වලින් කරපු වැරදි වලින් සැකසුම් වලින් පරිස්සර් වලින් පරිස්සර් වලින් පරිස්සර් වල අපි ඉංග්‍රීසි නොන් ඉංග්‍රීසි UD ට්‍රෙබෑන්ක් 58 දී කම්පචේන්ස් විතරය විශ්ලේෂණය කළා, ඊට පස්සේ CoNLL'18 කොටස් බේස් ලේන් මොඩේල්  අපේ විශ්ලේෂණය පෙන්වන්නවා කියලා කොම්ප්චේන්ස් විශේෂණය ගැන ප්‍රමාණය පෙන්වන්න පුළුවන්
ප්‍රධානික විශ්ලේෂණ මෙට්‍රික්ස් (LAS, MLAS සහ BLex). අපි UD ට්‍රීබෑන්ක් වලින් කොම්පචේන්ස් වලින් විතරයෙන් ප්‍රතිකාරයක් පරීක්ෂණය කරනවා, ඉතින් මේ ට්‍රීබෑන්ක් වලින් ප්‍ අපි සම්පූර්ණය කරනවා කොහොමද අලුත් පරීක්ෂණයක් දෙන්නේ කොහොමද UD පරීක්ෂකයන්ට ප්‍රධාන දත්ත ගැන අවස්ථාවක් ගැන, සහ UD පරීක</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Sida loo soo celiyo dhismo ku saabsan baarlamaanka ku saabsan qiimo-ku-xirfadeed (UD) waa u dhexe meelaha hoose laga sameeyo, sida ka soo bixinta qayb-qayb ama waxyaabaha dhacda. Waxbarashadan waxaa lagu soo bandhigaa silsilado, kooxo ku qoran hierarchy xiriir xiriir ku xiran ah oo ku jira baarlamaanka UD. Xirfada fasaxa shahaadada waxaa loo adeegaa jardiino si aad u qiyaasto cusboonaysiinta dhismaha rasmiga ah ee ku qoran qoraalka. Anagaa baaraynay qaybinta silsiladaha afka Ingiriiska, EWT, GUM iyo LinES, waxaynu muujinnay in looga baahan yahay dhibaatooyin ku saabsan qoraal muran ah oo ku qoran howlo-ku-qoran. We evaluated the CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (dependency parsing) models as compchain classifiers for the EWT, GUMS and LinES UD treebanks.  Abaalkayaga waxaa loola jeedaa in saddexdan tusaale ee aasaasiga ah ay muujiyaan tababar ka liita oo ay ku qoran yihiin dhismo ka mid ah oo ka badan hal heer. waxaynu isticmaalnay silsilado aan ku saxeyno qaladyada baarlamahaas ay sameeyeen iyo tusaalooyin baaritaanka qaladka ah oo ay soo saareen Parser oo lagu aqoonsaday isticmaalka compsilado. Waxaannu kaloo analyeennay qaybinta compsilado ee 58-ka-Ingiriis-ka-Ingiriis-ka-Ingiriis-taariikhda, kadibna waxaynu u isticmaalnay silsilado lagu qiimeeyo modelka aasaaska shaqada ee CoNLL-18 ee loo sharciyey qoraalkaas oo dhan. Analyskayagu wuxuu muujiyaa in muuqashada fasalka koobsiga
qeyminta rasmi ah (LAS, MLAS iyo BLEX). Sidaa darteed waxaynu baran nahay sidoo kale dariiqadahan lagu dari karo. Waxaynu ku dhamaystirnay baarlamaha UD iyo saxda baarlamaha UD ee uu soo jeedo sidoo kale sidoo kale baarlamaha UD-ka.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Exakt återställning av predikat-argumentstruktur från en UD-tolkning (Universal Dependency) är central för nedströmsuppgifter som extraktion av semantiska roller eller händelserepresentationer. Denna studie introducerar compchains, en kategorisering av hierarkin av predikatberoenderelationer som finns i en UD-parse. Noggrannheten i compchain klassificering fungerar som en proxy för att mäta exakt återställning av predikat-argumentstruktur från meningar med inbäddning. Vi analyserade fördelningen av kompchains i tre UD engelska trädbanker, EWT, GUM och LinES, vilket avslöjade att dessa trädbanker är glesa med avseende på meningar med predikat-argument struktur som inkluderar predikat-argument inbäddning. Vi utvärderade CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baslinje (beroendetolkning) modellerna som compchain klassificerare för EWT, GUMS och LinES UD trädbanker. Våra resultat indikerar att dessa tre basmodeller uppvisar sämre prestanda på meningar med predikat-argumentstruktur med mer än en nivå av inbäddning; Vi använde kompchains för att karakterisera fel som gjorts av dessa parsers och presentera exempel på felaktiga tolkningar producerade av parsern som identifierades med kompchains. Vi analyserade även fördelningen av compchains i 58 icke-engelska UD-trädbanker och använde sedan compchains för att utvärdera CoNLL'18 Shared Task baslinjemodell för var och en av dessa trädbanker. Vår analys visar att prestationen med avseende på compchain klassificering endast är svagt korrelerad med
officiella utvärderingsmetoder (LAS, MLAS och BLEX). Vi identifierar luckor i distributionen av kompkedjor i flera av UD-trädbackarna och ger därmed en färdplan för hur dessa trädbackar kan kompletteras. Vi avslutar med att diskutera hur kompchains ger ett nytt perspektiv på sparheten i utbildningsdata för UD-tolkare, samt noggrannheten i de resulterande UD-tolkarna.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>یونیورل ڈیفاندنستی (UD) پارس سے پیشڈیکٹ-آرگومیٹ کی ساختار کی دقیق بازیابی ہے اس طرح کہ سیمنٹی رول یا حادثہ نمایش کا اٹھانا ہے۔ This study introduces compchains, a category of predicate dependency relations present in a UD parse. کمپچین کلاسپیٹ کی دقیق مطابق باتوں کے ساتھ مطابق مطابق آرمونٹ ساختار کی مطابق مطابق پیروکسی کے طور پر ہے. ہم نے تین UD انگلیسی تریبانک، EWT, GUM اور LinES میں کمپچینٹوں کی تقسیم کی تحقیق کی ہے، جو ظاہر کر رہے ہیں کہ یہ تریبانک ان باتوں کے معاملہ میں پیشڈیکٹ-ارجمند ساختار کے ساتھ چھوڑ دیے جاتے ہیں جو پیشڈیکٹ-ارجمند میں شامل ہوتے ہیں. ہم نے CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (dependency parsing) موڈل کو EWT, GUMS اور LinES UD Treebanks کے لئے کمپچینٹ کلاسیر کے طور پر ارزش کیا۔ ہمارے نتیجے نشان دیتے ہیں کہ یہ تین بنیاس لین موڈل ایک سطح سے زیادہ زیادہ مضبوط باتوں پر کمزور فعالیت دکھاتے ہیں۔ ہم نے کمپٹینز کو ان پارچر کے ذریعے خطا کی تعریف کرنے کے لئے استعمال کیا تھا اور پارچر کے ذریعے پیدا کئے ہوئے غلطی پارچز کی مثالیں پیش کئے گئے ہیں جو کمپٹینز کے ذریعے پہچان کئے گئے تھے۔ ہم نے 58 غیر انگلیسی UD تریبانک میں کمپچینڈ کے تقسیم کا تحلیل کیا اور پھر کمپچینڈ استعمال کیا کہ CoNLL'18 شریک ٹاکس بنیس لین مدل کو ان تریبانک کے لئے مطابق کریں. ہماری تحلیل دکھاتی ہے کہ کامپینچین کلاسیفوں کے معاملہ میں عمل صرف کمزور تعلق ہے
رسمی evaluation metrics (LAS, MLAS اور BLEX). ہم نے کئی UD تریبانک میں کمپٹینک کے تقسیم میں فاصلہ پہچان لیا ہے، اسی طرح یہ تریبانک کس طرح اضافہ کیے جاتے ہیں، ایک راڈ نقشه کے ساتھ۔ ہم نے مشورہ کیا ہے کہ کمپچینڈ کس طرح نیا نظر دیتے ہیں UD پارس کے لئے تربیت ڈیٹ کی کمپچینڈ کے بارے میں اور نتیجہ UD پارس کے دقیق۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Bu ta'qituvni UD парламентда мавжуд боғлиқлик алоқаларини кўрсатади. Name Biz uchta ingliz tilida komponentlarning tarjimalarini o'zgartirish, EWT, GUM va LinES bilan tarjima qildik. Bu uchta suhbatlarni predpredicate argumentlar tuzilishini qo'shish mumkin. Biz 2018 bilan birlashtirilgan Vazifa UDPip (v1.2) bazasi modellarini EWT, GUMS va LinES UD treebanklari uchun kompyutsen klassiflari sifatida qiymatdik. Our results indicate that these three baseline models exhibit poorer performance on sentences with predicate-argument structure with more than one level of embedding;  Biz bu parserlarning xatolarini ko'rsatishga foydalanamiz va komputer bilan aniqlangan parslarning notoʻgʻri misollarini ko'rsatuvchimiz. Biz 5-8 ingliz tilida komponentlarning tarjima qilishni nazar qildik va keyin buning har bir treeborning CoNLL'18 bilan bogʻlangan vazifa asosiy modelini qiymatga ishlatdik. Analytikizni ko'rsatishimiz mumkin, bunday bir bir necha darajada
official evaluation metriclari (LAS, MLAS va BLEX). Biz komponentlarni bir nechta UD treeborning bir necha bogʻlarda ajratishni aniqlamiz, shunday qilib bu suhbatlarni qanday qo'shilishi mumkin. Biz kompyuterlar qanday foydalanishini va UD parserlarining tajribasining qismlarini va natijasida UD parserlarining imkoniyati haqida yangi ko'rinishini talab qilamiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Sự phục hồi chính xác cấu trúc khó khăn từ một phân tích sự phụ thuộc chung (UD) là trung tâm của các công việc theo cấp dưới như việc khai thác các vai trò theo ngữ nghĩa hoặc các biểu hiện sự kiện. This study introduced compchais, a classification of the priate dependence relationship present in a UD parre. Sự chính xác của việc phân loại compchain phục vụ như một ủy nhiệm cho việc đo lường phục hồi chính xác cấu trúc biện pháp chuẩn từ câu với sự nhúng. Chúng tôi phân tích sự phân phối hợp trong ba ba ba xâu bóng của Anh UD, EWT, GUM và Linus, tiết lộ rằng các xâu bóng này rất ít so với các câu với cấu trúc khó khăn-cãi mà bao gồm sự nhúng tạm thời. Chúng tôi đánh giá cơ sở tập tin hoạt động kép (v1.2) cơ sở cơ bản phân tích phụ thuộc) như những phân loại máy tính tổng hợp cho EWT, GUMS và Linney UD treebacks. Những kết quả của chúng tôi cho thấy ba mô hình cơ bản này có hiệu suất kém hơn về các câu với cấu trúc khó khăn với hơn một cấp độ tác nghiệp; Chúng tôi dùng các máy tính để phân tích lỗi của các phân viên này và trình bày các ví dụ của các phân viên lỗi được tạo ra bởi người phân tích được xác định bằng máy trộn. Chúng tôi cũng phân tích sự phân phối hợp trong 58 ngoài tiếng Anh ba lô UD và sau đó sử dụng các compxích để đánh giá mô hình nền tập tin (CONLL'18). Theo phân tích của chúng tôi, khả năng đạt được với mức độ phân hạng tổng hợp chỉ có liên quan nhẹ với...
Hệ thống đo đánh giá chính thức (LAS, MLAS và LEX). Chúng tôi xác định khoảng trống trong việc phân phối các công trình trong nhiều máy phát sóng UD, cung cấp bản đồ cho cách mà các chế độ phát sóng này có thể được bổ sung. Chúng tôi kết thúc bằng cách bàn bạc làm thế nào để tạo ra một viễn cảnh mới về khoảng trống của dữ liệu đào tạo cho các cha xứ UD, cũng như độ chính xác của các phân tách nó.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Точното възстановяване на структурата на предикат-аргумент от анализ на универсална зависимост (UD) е от основно значение за задачи надолу по веригата, като извличане на семантични роли или представяне на събития. Това изследване въвежда компхеинги, категоризация на йерархията на зависимостта на предикатите, присъстващи в анализа на UD. Точността на класификацията на компхейн служи като прокси за измерване на точното възстановяване на структурата на предикат-аргумент от изречения с вграждане. Анализирахме разпределението на компаньонките в три английски триленки, разкривайки, че тези триленки са оскъдни по отношение на изречения със структура на предикат-аргумент, която включва вграждане на предикат-аргумент. Оценихме базовите модели (анализ на зависимостта) за споделена задача на CoNLL 2018 като класификационни вериги за дървесните ленти. Нашите резултати показват, че тези три базови модела показват по-лошо представяне на изречения с предикатно-аргументна структура с повече от едно ниво на вграждане; Използвахме компверижни вериги, за да характеризираме грешките, направени от тези анализатори и да представим примери за грешни анализи, произведени от анализатора, които са идентифицирани с помощта на компверижни вериги. Анализирахме и разпределението на компаньонките в 58 неанглийски триленки и след това използвахме компаньонките, за да оценим базовия модел за споделена задача на CoNLL'18 за всеки от тези триленки. Нашият анализ показва, че ефективността по отношение на класификацията на компаньонките е слабо корелирана с
официални показатели за оценка (LAS, MLAS и BLEX). Идентифицираме пропуски в разпределението на веригите в няколко от дървесните ленти, като по този начин предоставяме пътна карта за това как тези ленти могат да бъдат допълнени. В заключение обсъждаме как компхеингите осигуряват нова перспектива за оскъдността на тренировъчните данни за анализаторите, както и точността на получените анализатори.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Nauwkeurig herstel van predicaat-argumentstructuur uit een UD parse (Universal Dependency) is centraal bij downstreamtaken zoals het extraheren van semantische rollen of gebeurtenisrepresentaties. Deze studie introduceert compchains, een categorisering van de hiërarchie van predicaat afhankelijkheidsrelaties die aanwezig zijn binnen een UD parse. Nauwkeurigheid van compchain classificatie dient als een proxy voor het meten van nauwkeurig herstel van predicaat-argument structuur uit zinnen met embedding. We analyseerden de verdeling van compchains in drie UD Engelse boombanken, EWT, GUM en LinES, waaruit bleek dat deze boombanken schaars zijn ten opzichte van zinnen met een predicaat-argumentstructuur die predicaat-argument embedding omvat. We hebben de CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (afhankelijkheidsparsing) modellen geëvalueerd als compchain classificatoren voor de EWT, GUMS en LinES UD boombanken. Onze resultaten geven aan dat deze drie basismodellen slechtere prestaties vertonen op zinnen met predicaat-argument structuur met meer dan één niveau van inbedding; We gebruikten compchains om de fouten van deze parsers te karakteriseren en voorbeelden te presenteren van foutieve parsers geproduceerd door de parser die geïdentificeerd werden met behulp van compchains. We hebben ook de verdeling van compchains geanalyseerd in 58-niet-Engelse UD boombanken en vervolgens compchains gebruikt om het CoNLL'18 Shared Task baseline model voor elk van deze boombanken te evalueren. Uit onze analyse blijkt dat de prestaties met betrekking tot compchain classificatie slechts zwak gecorreleerd zijn met de
officiële evaluatiestatistieken (LAS, MLAS en BLEX). We identificeren lacunes in de verdeling van compchains in verschillende UD boombanken, waardoor we een routekaart bieden voor hoe deze boombanken kunnen worden aangevuld. We sluiten af door te bespreken hoe compchains een nieuw perspectief bieden op de schaarse trainingsdata voor UD parsers, evenals de nauwkeurigheid van de resulterende UD parses.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Nøjagtig gendannelse af prædikat-argumentstruktur fra en Universal Dependency (UD) parse er centralt for downstream opgaver som ekstraktion af semantiske roller eller hændelsesrepræsentationer. Denne undersøgelse introducerer compchains, en kategorisering af hierarkiet af prædikateafhængighedsrelationer til stede i en UD parse. Nøjagtigheden af compchain klassificering tjener som en proxy til måling af nøjagtig genopretning af prædikat-argumentstruktur fra sætninger med indlejring. Vi analyserede fordelingen af kompchains i tre UD engelske treebanks, EWT, GUM og LinES, og afslørede, at disse treebanks er sparsomme i forhold til sætninger med prædikat-argument struktur, der inkluderer prædikat-argument indlejring. Vi evaluerede CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline-modellerne (afhængighedsparsing) som compchain klassifikationer for EWT, GUMS og LinES UD-træbanker. Vores resultater indikerer, at disse tre basismodeller udviser dårligere ydeevne på sætninger med prædikat-argumentstruktur med mere end ét niveau af indlejring; Vi brugte compchains til at karakterisere fejlene lavet af disse parsere og præsentere eksempler på fejlagtige parser produceret af parseren, der blev identificeret ved hjælp af compchains. Vi analyserede også fordelingen af compchains i 58 ikke-engelske UD treebanks og brugte derefter compchains til at evaluere CoNLL'18 Shared Task baseline model for hver af disse treebanks. Vores analyse viser, at præstation med hensyn til compchain klassificering kun er svagt korreleret med
officielle evalueringsmålinger (LAS, MLAS og BLEX). Vi identificerer huller i fordelingen af kompchains i flere af UD-træbankerne og giver dermed en køreplan for, hvordan disse træbanker kan suppleres. Vi afslutter med at diskutere, hvordan kompchains giver et nyt perspektiv på sparsommeligheden af træningsdata for UD-fortolkere, samt nøjagtigheden af de resulterende UD-fortolkninger.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Pemulihan yang tepat dari struktur argumen-predikat dari analisis Dependensi Universal (UD) adalah pusat untuk tugas turun seperti ekstraksi peran semantis atau rappresentasi peristiwa. Studi ini memperkenalkan compchains, kategorisasi hierarki hubungan dependensi predikat yang ada dalam analisis UD. Accuracy of compchain classification serves as a proxy for measuring accurate recovery of predicate-argument structure from sentences with embedding.  Kami menganalisis distribusi kompchains dalam tiga batang pohon UD Inggris, EWT, GUM dan LinES, mengungkap bahwa batang pohon ini jarang berkaitan dengan kalimat dengan struktur predicate-argumen yang termasuk penyambungan predicate-argumen. Kami mengevaluasi model UDPipe (v1.2) dasar tugas berbagi CoNLL 2018 (dependency parsing) sebagai klasifikasi kompchain untuk batang pohon EWT, GUMS dan LinES UD. Hasil kami menunjukkan bahwa tiga model dasar ini menunjukkan prestasi yang lebih buruk pada kalimat dengan struktur predikat-argumen dengan lebih dari satu tingkat penerbangan; kami menggunakan compchains untuk mengkaraterisasikan kesalahan yang dibuat oleh parser ini dan mempersembahkan contoh dari parser yang salah yang dibuat oleh parser yang diidentifikasi menggunakan compchains. Kami juga menganalisis distribusi compchains di 58 batang pohon UD bukan Inggris dan kemudian menggunakan compchains untuk mengevaluasi model dasar CoNLL'18 Shared Task untuk setiap batang pohon ini. Analisi kami menunjukkan bahwa prestasi terhadap klasifikasi compchain hanya terkait dengan kelemahan
metrik evaluasi resmi (LAS, MLAS dan BLEX). We identify gaps in the distribution of compchains in several of the UD treebanks, thus providing a roadmap for how these treebanks may be supplemented.  Kami menyimpulkan dengan mendiskusikan bagaimana compchains menyediakan perspektif baru tentang kecepatan data pelatihan untuk pemeriksa UD, serta akurasi pemeriksaan UD hasilnya.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_de>Die genaue Wiederherstellung der Prädikat-Argument-Struktur aus einer Universal Dependency (UD)-Parse ist von zentraler Bedeutung für nachgelagerte Aufgaben wie die Extraktion semantischer Rollen oder Ereignisrepräsentationen. Diese Studie stellt Compchains vor, eine Kategorisierung der Hierarchie von Prädikatabhängigkeitsbeziehungen, die innerhalb einer UD Parse vorhanden sind. Die Genauigkeit der Compchain-Klassifizierung dient als Proxy für die genaue Wiederherstellung der Prädikat-Argument-Struktur aus Sätzen mit Einbettung. Wir analysierten die Verteilung von Compchains in drei UD-englischen Baumbänken, EWT, GUM und LinES, und zeigten, dass diese Baumbänke spärlich sind in Bezug auf Sätze mit Prädikat-Argument Struktur, die Prädikat-Argument Einbettung beinhaltet. Wir haben die CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) Baseline (Dependency Parsing) Modelle als Compchain Klassifikatoren für die EWT, GUMS und LinES UD Baumbänke evaluiert. Unsere Ergebnisse deuten darauf hin, dass diese drei Basismodelle schlechtere Leistungen bei Sätzen mit Prädikat-Argument-Struktur mit mehr als einer Ebene der Einbettung aufweisen; Wir haben Compchains verwendet, um die Fehler dieser Parser zu charakterisieren und Beispiele für fehlerhafte Parses zu präsentieren, die vom Parser erzeugt wurden und die mithilfe von Compchains identifiziert wurden. Wir analysierten auch die Verteilung von Compchains in 58-nicht-englischen UD-Baumbänken und nutzten dann Compchains, um das CoNLL'18 Shared Task Basismodell für jede dieser Baumbänke zu evaluieren. Unsere Analyse zeigt, dass die Performance hinsichtlich der Compchain-Klassifizierung nur schwach mit der
offizielle Bewertungsmetriken (LAS, MLAS und BLEX). Wir identifizieren Lücken in der Verteilung von Compchains in mehreren UD-Baumbänken und liefern so eine Roadmap, wie diese Baumbänke ergänzt werden können. Abschließend diskutieren wir, wie Compchains eine neue Perspektive auf die Sparsamkeit von Trainingsdaten für UD-Parser sowie die Genauigkeit der resultierenden UD-Parses bieten.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_tr>Uniwersal Dependensiýa (UD) tarapyndan öň-öňkiň argüm strukturynyň ýeňlemesini takyklaşdyrmak semantik roller ýa-da çykyş täzeliklerini a çmak üçin merkezdir. Bu araşdyrma UD analyzasynda bolan öňki baglanylyk nişanlarynyň ýerarhiýasyny tanyşdyrýar. Syýallar arasyndaky gabdalyk sözleriň arasynda dogry bir arşiw bejermek üçin bir vekil döredir. Biz üç UD Iňlisiň baglançylary, EWT, GUM we LinES içinde süzmekler paýlaşypdyk, bu süzmekler öň-öňünden argüment daşarylýan sözleriň üçin boýun gaýşartypdyr. CoNLL 2018-nji ýylda Paýlaşylyş Taýgyny UDPipe (v1.2). Biziň netijelerimiz bu üç esasy nusgalaryň sözleriň öňki-argüm strukturasy bilen bir derejeden köp daşyrylygy bilen ýok täsirini tanaýarlar; Bu parsörler tarafından eden hatalary karakterize etmek üçin zıncıları kullandık. Şunlar şeklinde ayırt edilen yanlış parsallar örnekleri çözdük. Biz hem 58-nji iňlisçe UD süýşiklerinde süýşiklikler paýlaşypdyk we soňra CoNLL'18 Beýleki Görevler Baseline nusgasyny çykmak üçin süýşiklikleri ulandyk. Biziň analýusymyz çykyş klasifikasyyla baglanyşygy bilen diňe azajyk şekilde däldir.
resmi deňlenme metrikleri (LAS, MLAS we BLEX). UD çyzgymlaryň birnäçe sany çyzgymlaryň paýlaşmagynda gaplary tanyýarys, şonuň üçin bu çyzgymlaryň nädip täze edip biljekleri üçin ýoluň haritasyny berip barýarys. UD parsileri üçin üýtgetmek üçin hasaplamalaryň nähili täze perspektivini nähili süýtgetmelidigini we netijeli UD parsallaryň dogrylygyny taryşarak çykyp çykyp çykyp çykyp başladyk.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sw>Kurudishwa kwa miundombinu ya mahojiano yanayotangulia kutoka bunge la Dunia la Kutegemea (UD) ni katikati ya kazi za chini ya mto kama vile kutengeneza jukumu la kimapenzi au uwakilishi wa matukio. This study introduces compchains, a categorization of the hierarchy of predicate dependency relations present within a UD parse.  Ukurahisi wa usambazaji wa mfumo unahudumia kama proksi kwa kupima upya sahihi wa muundo wa hoja uliopita kutoka kwenye hukumu zinazoingizwa. Tulichambua usambazaji wa viungo vitatu vya Uingereza vya Uingereza, EWT, GUM na LinES, kwa kuonyesha kuwa vifaa hivi vya mitatu vinavyopungua kuhusiana na sentensi yenye muundo wa hoja maalum ambao unajumuisha mjadala unaoendelea. Tulifuatilia mtindo wa msingi wa UDPipe wa CoNLL 2018 (v1.2) kama wataalamu wa uchimbaji wa kompyuta wa EWT, GUMS na LinES UD. Matokeo yetu yanaonyesha kuwa mifano hii mitatu ya msingi inaonyesha ufanisi wa hali mbaya zaidi kwenye sentensi zenye muundo wa hoja na zaidi ya kiwango kimoja cha kuingia; tulitumia viungo vya kompyuta kuhusiana na makosa yaliyofanywa na wabunge hawa na mifano ya mabango yaliyotokea yaliyotengenezwa na Parser yaliyotambuliwa kwa kutumia mfumo wa kompyuta. Pia tulichambua usambazaji wa mfumo wa kompyuta katika viwanja vya Uingereza 58 wasio na UD vya Uingereza na baadae tulitumia viungo vya kompyuta ili kutathmini modeli ya msingi wa kazi ya CoNLL ya 18 kwa kila mmoja wa viwanja hivi. Uchambuzi wetu unaonyesha kwamba utendaji wa utangazaji wa vikosi ni dhaifu tu unaohusishwa na
mbinu rasmi za uchunguzi (LAS, MLAS na BLEX). Tunajua gaidi katika usambazaji wa viungo vya kompyuta katika baadhi ya viwanja vya UD, kwa hiyo tunatoa barabara kwa namna vigezo hivi vinavyoweza kuunganishwa. Tuhitimisha kwa kujadili jinsi viungo vya kompyuta vinavyotoa mtazamo mpya juu ya kuongezeka kwa taarifa za mafunzo kwa mabunge wa UDD, pamoja na uhalisia wa bunge la UDD.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_fa>بازیابی دقیقا از ساختار ارجمند پیشدیک از یک تجزیه بستگی جهانی (UD) مرکزی به کار های پایین‌ترین مانند استخراج از نقش‌های semantic یا نمایش‌های رویداد است. این مطالعه، مجموعه‌ها را معرفی می‌کند، یک مجموعه‌ای از مجموعه‌ی رابطه‌های بستگی پیشینیان در یک تجزیه UD وجود دارد. دقیقات گروه‌بندی مجموعه به عنوان پروکسی برای اندازه‌گیری بازیابی دقیقا از ساختار ارجمندی پیش‌فرض از جمله‌های مجموعه‌ای که دارند وارد می‌شوند خدمت می‌کند. ما توزیع مجموعه‌های مجموعه‌ها را در سه تخته‌های انگلیسی UD، EWT, GUM و LinES تحلیل کردیم، که نشان می‌دهند که این تخته‌های درخت‌ها در مورد جمله‌ها با ساختار مجموعه‌های پیش‌دبینی که شامل جمله‌های پیش‌دبینی‌های مجموعه‌ای است،  ما مدل‌های پایه‌خط (پارش بستگی) مشترک کار CoNLL ۲۰۱۸ را به عنوان مجموعه‌کننده‌های مجموعه‌بندی برای تختهای EWT, GUMS و LinES UD ارزیابی کردیم. نتیجه‌های ما نشان می‌دهند که این سه مدل‌های پایه‌خط ضعیف‌تر از جمله‌ها با ساختار ارائه‌های مختلف با بیشتر از یک سطح وارد شدن را نشان می‌دهند. ما از مجموعه‌زنجیرها استفاده کردیم تا اشتباهی که توسط این مجموعه‌کننده‌ها انجام داده‌اند را تشخیص دهیم و مثال‌هایی از تجزیه‌های اشتباهی که توسط مجموعه‌کننده‌ها توسط مجموعه‌زنجیرها شناسایی شده ما همچنین تقسیم مجموعه‌ها را در ۱۸ تخته‌های UD غیر انگلیسی تحلیل کردیم و سپس از مجموعه‌های مجموعه برای ارزیابی مدل پایین خط‌خط مشترک کوNLL ۱۸ برای هر یک از این تخته‌ها استفاده کردیم. تحلیل ما نشان می دهد که عملکرد با ارتباط برقراری مجموعه فقط ضعیف ارتباط با
متریک ارزیابی رسمی (LAS, MLAS and BLEX). ما فاصله‌هایی را در تقسیم مجموعه‌ها در چندین از مجموعه‌های UD شناسایی می‌کنیم، بنابراین نقشه جاده‌ای برای اینکه چگونه این مجموعه‌ها ممکن است اضافه شود. ما با توجه به بحث کردن چگونه کمپین‌زنجیرها یک نگاه جدید در مورد کمپیوتری داده‌های آموزش برای متخصص‌کنندگان UD، و دقیق تحلیل‌های UD نتیجه را می‌دهیم.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_hr>Upravo je oporavak predikatne strukture argument a iz razmatranja univerzalne zavisnosti (UD) centralno za smanjenje zadataka poput izvlačenja semantičkih uloga ili predstavljanja događaja. U ovom ispitivanju predstavljaju komplansiranje, kategorizaciju hijerarhije predikatnih odnosa ovisnosti koje su predstavljene u razmatranju UD-a. Točnost klasifikacije kompchaina služi kao proizvođa č za mjerenje točnog oporavka strukture predikata argument a iz rečenica sa uključenjem. Analizirali smo distribuciju kompchainsa u tri UD engleske trgovine, EWT, GUM i LinES, otkrivajući da su te trgovine rezervne u odnosu na rečenice sa predikatnem strukturom argumenta koja uključuje predikatne integracije argumenta. Procjenili smo početne modele zajedničkog zadatka UDPipe (v1.2) CoNLL 2018 kao klasifikatore kompchaina za EWT, GUMS i LinES UD trgovine. Naši rezultati ukazuju na to da ove tri početne modela pokazuju siromašniju učinku na rečenicama sa predikatnim strukturom argumenta s više od jedne razine ugrađenja; Koristili smo compchains kako bi karakterizirali greške koje su napravili ovi parseri i predstavili primjere grešnih parsova proizvođenih od strane analizatora koji su identificirani koristeći kompchains. Također smo analizirali distribuciju kompchainsa u 58 ne-engleskim UD treebancima i onda smo koristili kompchains za procjenu početnog modela podjele zadataka CoNLL'18 za svaku od ovih treebancija. Naša analiza pokazuje da je učinkovito povezano sa klasifikacijom kompchaina samo slabo povezano s
zvanična procjena metrika (LAS, MLAS i BLEX). Identificiramo praznine u distribuciji kompchainsa u nekoliko UD treebancija, tako pružajući putnu mapu kako bi se ovi treebanci mogli dodati. Zaključili smo razgovaranjem o tome kako komplanci pružaju novu perspektivu o isključivosti podataka obuke za UD analizatore, kao i preciznosti rezultatnih UD analiza.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_af>Akkuraat herstelling van predikaat-argument struktuur van 'n Universele Afhanklikheid (UD) verwerking is sentrale na onderstreem opdragte soos uitpakking van semantiese role of gebeurtenis voorstellings. Hierdie studie introduseer kompleksies, 'n kategorisasie van die hierarkie van vooraflikte afhanklikheidverhoudings wat binne 'n UD verwerking is. Nagtigheid van kompleksie klasifikasie bediener as 'n volmag vir die gemeet van presies herstelling van predikaat- argument struktuur van setinge met inbêring. Ons het die verspreiding van kompchains in drie UD Engelske treebanks, EWT, GUM en Lines analiseer, wat hierdie treebanks vertel het dat hierdie treebanks spanseer is met betrekking na setinge met predikaat-argument struktuur wat predikaat-argument ingesluit word. Ons het die CoNLL 2018 Gedeelde Opdrag UDPipe (v1.2) basisline (afhanklikheid verwerking) modele as kompchain klassifiseerders vir die EWT, GUMS en Lynes UD treebanks evalueer. Ons resultate wys dat hierdie drie basisline modele verminder uitwerking op setinge met predikaat-argument struktuur met meer as een vlak van inbêding; ons resultate wys dat hierdie drie basisline modele verminder is ons het kompchains gebruik om die foute wat deur hierdie verwerkers gemaak is te karakteriseer en voorneemde voorbeelde van foute verwerking wat deur die ontleerder geïdentifiseer is deur kompchains. Ons het ook die verspreiding van kompchains in 58 non- English UD treebanks analiseer en dan gebruik kompchains om die CoNLL' 18 Gedeelde taak baselyn model vir elke van hierdie treebanks te evalueer. Ons analisie wys dat die prestasie met respek na kompleksie klasifikasie slegs swak verbind is met die
offisiele evalueringsmetries (LAS, MLAS en BLEX). Ons identifiseer spasies in die verspreiding van kompchains in verskeie van die UD treebanks, sodat verskaf 'n pad kaart vir hoe hierdie treebanks kan bygevoeg word. Ons sluit deur te bespreek hoe kompchains 'n nuwe perspektief verskaf op die sparsiteit van onderwerking data vir UD verwerkers, en die presisie van die resulteerde UD verwerking.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_am>በዩንቨርስቲ ግንኙነት (ዩዲ) ፓርቲ ላይ የሚቆጠሩ አካባቢ ግንኙነት አካባቢ አካባቢ (UD) አካባቢ አካባቢ እንደምታወጣ የሴሜንቲክ ክፍል ወይም የሁኔታ ክፍሎች ማውጣት ማዕከል ነው፡፡ ይህ ትምህርት በዩዲ ፓርቲ ውስጥ ያሉትን የአፍሪካዊ ግንኙነት አካባቢ ግንኙነትን ያሳያል፡፡ ምርጫዎች በሦስት ኢንግሊዝኛ ግንኙነት፣ ኢዩተቲ፣ ጉዩም እና ሊኔስ የተካፈሉትን ሰንሰለቶች አካባቢ እና አፈላጊዎችን አስተያየን፡፡ የኮንጆል 2018 ስራውን UDPipe (v1.2) መደገፊያውን (የታሰረ ፓርቲ) ሞዴላዎችን ለEWT፣ GUMS እና LinES UD treebanks እንደተካፈሉ አካውንተናል፡፡ ፍሬዎቻችን እነዚህ ሦስት የደረጃ መተላለፊያዎች በአንድ ደረጃዎች ላይ የበለጠ የውይይት ግንኙነትን የሚያሳዩ ናቸው፡፡ እነዚህን ፓርስር የተደረጉትን ስህተት እና በሙሉ ሰንሰለት የተገኘውን የስሕተት ፓርቲዎች ምሳሌዎችን ለመግለጽ ተጠቃሚ ነበር፡፡ በ58 ያልኢንልዝላዊ ዩዲ ደራቦች ውስጥ የሰንሰለቱን አካባቢ እና በዚያን ጊዜም ለሁሉም የኮንLL 18 የተካፈሉት የስራ መሠረት ሞዴል ለማስተካከል ተጠቃሚ ሰንሰሮችን አሰራንተናል፡፡ ትምህርታችን የሰንሰለት ክፍል ማድረግ ብቻ ደካማ ነው፡፡
የሥልጣን ማውጣት ማተሚያዎች (LAS, MLAS እና BLEX) በአሁኑ የዩድ አውታር እስራዊ ግንኙነትን በማካፈል ውጤቶች እናውቃለን፡፡ የዩዲ ፓርላር ዳታዎችን በጥቅምነት እና የዩዲ ፓርራርስ እና የዩዲ ፓርላማ ውስጥነት እንዴት አዲስ ስርዓት እንዳደረገ እናሳውቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Rikthimi i saktë i strukturës predikate-argument nga një analizë e Varësisë Universale (UD) është qendrore në detyra poshtë të tilla si nxjerrja e rolit semantik apo përfaqësimet e ngjarjeve. Ky studim fut ndërlidhje, një kategorizim të hierarkisë së marrëdhënieve të varësisë të predikuara të pranishme brenda një analize UD. E saktësia e klasifikimit compchain shërben si një proxy për matjen e ripërtëritjes së saktë të strukturës predicate-argument nga fjalët me përfshirje. Ne analizuam shpërndarjen e kompçinat në tre baza druri angleze UD, EWT, GUM dhe LinES, duke zbuluar se këto baza druri janë të pakta lidhur me fjalët me strukturën predicate-argument që përfshin përfshirjen predicate-argument. Kemi vlerësuar modelet bazë (analiza e varësisë) të CoNLL 2018 të UDPipe Task Shared (v1.2) si klasifikues compchain për bazat e drurit EWT, GUMS dhe LinES UD. Rezultatet tona tregojnë se këto tre modele bazë tregojnë performancë më të dobët në fjalët me strukturë predikate-argumenti me më shumë se një nivel të përfshirjes; ne përdorëm kompçinat për të karakterizuar gabimet e bërë nga këta analizues dhe për të paraqitur shembuj të analizave të gabuara të prodhuara nga analizuesi që u identifikuan duke përdorur kompçinat. Ne analizuam gjithashtu shpërndarjen e kompçinat në 58 baza druri jo-angleze UD dhe pastaj përdorëm kompçinat për të vlerësuar model in bazë të CoNLL'18 Task Shared për secilin nga këto baza druri. Our analysis shows that performance with respect to compchain classification is only weakly correlated with the
metrika zyrtare e vlerësimit (LAS, MLAS dhe BLEX). Ne identifikojmë boshllëqet në shpërndarjen e ndërtesave në disa nga bazat e drurit të UD, duke ofruar kështu një hartë rrugës për mënyrën se si këto baza druri mund të shtohen. Ne përfundojmë duke diskutuar se si compchains ofrojnë një perspektivë të re mbi pakësinë e të dhënave të trajnimit për analizuesit UD si dhe saktësinë e analizave të UD që rezultojnë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_az>Universel bağımlılıq (UD) ayırmasından öndək-arqümet quruluşunun yenilənməsi, semantik rollərin və olaraq göstərilmələrinin çıxarılması kimi mərkəzdir. Bu təhsil, UD analizi içində bulunan müxtəlif bağımlılıqların hierarhiyasının kategoriyasını göstərir. Kompcin klasifikasiyasının ədaləti, sözlərlə birlikdə dəyişiklik arqüd quruluşunu ölçürmək üçün proksi olar. Biz üç UD İngilizci çubuqlarda, EWT, GUM və LinES kompozicilərin dağıtılışını analiz etdik, bu çubuqların predikat-argument yapısıyla olan cümlələrə bağlı olduğunu göstərdik. Biz CoNLL 2018 paylaşılmış Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (dependency parsing) modellərini EWT, GUMS və LinES UD treebankları üçün kompchain klasifikatorları kimi değerlendirdik. Sonuçlarımız belə göstərir ki, bu üç sinyal modellərin bir səviyyədən daha çox səviyyədə olan cümlələr barəsində daha zəif performans göstərir; Biz bu ayırıcılar tarafından etdikləri hataları tanımlamaq üçün compchain və compchain vasitəsilə tanımlanan ayırış ayırıcıların məsəllərini istifadə etdik. Biz də 58 İngilizə olmayan UD treebanklarında compchains dağıtılışını analiz etdik və sonra CoNLL'18 paylaşılmış Task baseline modelini hər çubuğun üçün kompchains kullandıq. Bizim analizimiz göstərir ki, compchain klasifikasiyası haqqında performans ancaq zəif bir şəkildə
resmi değerlendirmə metrikləri (LAS, MLAS və BLEX). Bizim UD tərəflərinin çoxlu tərəflərində kompozisyonların dağıtılmasında boşluqları tanıyırıq, buna görə də bu tərəflərin necə uyğunlaşdırılması üçün yol haritası təyin edirik. Və UD analizacıları üçün təhsil məlumatlarının çoxluğu və sonuçlarının UD analizacıların doğruluğu barəsində, kompchains necə yeni bir perspektivə təhsil edir?</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ের নির্ভরশীল (ইউডি) পার্স থেকে পূর্ববর্তী যুক্তির কাঠামো পুনরুদ্ধারের সঠিক পুনরুদ্ধার করা হচ্ছে, যেমন সেমেন্টিক ভূম এই গবেষণাটি ইউডি পার্জের মধ্যে উপস্থিত নির্ভরশীল সম্পর্কের একটি বিভাগের শ্রেণীবিভাগ উপস্থাপন করেছে। কমফেইন ক্লাস্ফিকেশনের গুরুত্বপূর্ণ প্রক্সি হিসেবে সার্ভার ব্যবহার করা হয়েছে যার ফলে বাক্য থেকে নির্ধারিত যুক্তিক্ত আর্ আমরা তিনটি ইউডি ইংরেজি ট্রিব্যাংক, ইউটি, জিউএম এবং লিনেসের মধ্যে কম্পিশেন বিতরণ বিশ্লেষণ করেছি, যেখানে আমরা প্রকাশ করেছি যে এই ত্রীব্যাংকেরা পূর্বাহিত যুক্তির কাঠা আমরা কএনএল ২০১৮ শেয়ার করা কাজ উডিপিপি (ভি১. ২) বেসাইন (নির্ভরশীল পার্সিং) মডেলের মূল্য মূল্যায়ন করেছি ইউডিউটি, জিউএমস এবং লিনেস ইউডি ট্রিব্যাংকের জন্য ক আমাদের ফলাফল নির্দেশ করা হয়েছে যে এই তিনটি বেস্লাইন মডেল প্রদর্শন করা হয়েছে বিশেষ করে যুক্তি প্রতিষ্ঠানের মাধ্যমে যুক্তি প্রতিষ্ঠ আমরা এই পার্সারের দ্বারা ত্রুটিকে চিহ্নিত করার জন্য কম্পিশেন ব্যবহার করেছিলাম এবং বর্তমানে পার্স তৈরি করা ভুল পার্সের উদাহ We also analyzed the distribution of compchains in 58 non-English UD treebanks and then used compchains to evaluate the CoNLL'18 Shared Task baseline model for each of these treebanks.  আমাদের বিশ্লেষণ দেখাচ্ছে যে কমচেইনের শ্রেণীতে প্রকাশ করা শুধুমাত্র দুর্বল সংশ্লিষ্ট
অফিসিয়াল মুল্যায়ন মেট্রিক (লাস, ম্যালেস এবং বিলেক্স)। আমরা বেশ কয়েকটি ইউডি ট্রিব্যাংকে কম্পিশেন বিতরণের মধ্যে বিভেদ চিহ্নিত করি, যার ফলে রাস্তা প্রদান করা হয় কিভাবে এই ত্রিব্যাংকের সাথে  আমরা শেষ করেছি যে কিভাবে কম্পিশেন নতুন দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি দিয়ে ইউডি পার্সারের জন্য প্রশিক্ষণের তথ্যের স্প্রাইজের ব্যাপারে আর ফলাফলের ই</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_ca>La recuperació exacta de l'estructura predicat-argument d'una analisi de Dependencia Universal (UD) és central a tasques avall, com l'extracció de rols semàntics o representacions d'eventos. Aquest estudi introdueix compchains, una categorització de la jerarquia de les relacions predicates de dependencia presents dins un examen UD. La precisió de la classificació compchain serveix de proxy per mesurar la recuperació exacta de l'estructura predicat-argument a partir de frases amb incorporació. Vam analitzar la distribució de compchains en tres bancs d'arbres anglesos UD, EWT, GUM i LinES, revelant que aquestes bancs d'arbres són escases en relació a frases amb estructura predicate-argument que inclou incorporació predicate-argument. We evaluated the CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (dependency parsing) models as compchain classifiers for the EWT, GUMS and LinES UD treebanks.  Els nostres resultats indican que aquests tres models de base mostran un rendiment més dolent en frases amb estructura de predicat-argument amb més d'un nivell d'integració; vam utilitzar compchains per caracteritzar els errors fets per aquests analitzadors i vam presentar exemples d'errors d'analitzadors produïts per l'analitzador que van ser identificats fent servir compchains. També vam analitzar la distribució de compchains en 58 bancs d'arbres UD no anglesos i vam utilitzar compchains per avaluar el model de base CoNLL'18 Shared Task per cada una d'aquestes bancs d'arbres. La nostra anàlisi mostra que el rendiment en relació a la classificació compchain només està debidament correlacionat amb
mètriques oficials d'evaluació (LAS, MLAS i BLEX). We identify gaps in the distribution of compchains in several of the UD treebanks, thus providing a roadmap for how these treebanks may be supplemented.  Concluïm discutind com compchains proporcionen una nova perspectiva sobre la escassetat de dades d'entrenament dels analitzadors UD, i sobre la precisió dels analitzadors UD resultants.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_ko>통용 의존(UD) 해석에서 술어 파라미터 구조를 정확하게 회복하는 것은 하류 임무(예를 들어 의미 역할 추출이나 이벤트 표시)의 핵심이다.이 연구는compchains를 도입했는데 이것은 UD 해석에서 술어 의존 관계 차원의 분류이다.compchain 분류의 정확성은 술어 논원 구조가 문장에 삽입되어 정확하게 회복되는 지표로 삼을 수 있다.우리는 세 종류의 UD 영어 트리 라이브러리, EWT, GUM과 Lines 중의 복합 체인의 분포를 분석한 결과 이런 트리 라이브러리는 술어 파라미터가 삽입된 술어 파라미터 구조를 포함하는 문장에 대해 희소하다는 것을 발견했다.우리는 CoNLL 2018 공유 작업 UDPipe(v1.2) 기선(의존항 해석) 모델을 평가하여 EWT, GUM, UD 트리 라이브러리 줄의compchain 분류기로 삼았다.우리의 연구 결과에 의하면 이 세 가지 기선 모델은 1개 이상의 삽입 수준의 술어인 논원 구조를 가진 문장에서 비교적 나쁜 성능을 나타낸다.우리는 compchains를 사용하여 이 해석기에서 발생하는 오류를 설명하고,compchains를 사용하여 식별하는 해석기에서 발생하는 오류 해석의 예시를 제시합니다.우리는 58개의 비영어 UD 트리 라이브러리에 있는compchains의 분포를 분석한 다음에compchains를 사용하여 각 트리 라이브러리의CoNLL'18 공유 임무 기선 모델을 평가했다.우리의 분석에 의하면compchain 분류의 성능과
공식 평가 지표(LAS, MLAS 및 BLEX).우리는 여러 개의 UD수상은행 중compchains분포의 차이를 확정하여 이러한 수상은행을 어떻게 보충하는지에 대해 노선도를 제공하였다.마지막으로, 우리는compchains가 UD해석기에 어떻게 데이터의 희소성을 훈련하는 새로운 시각을 제공하고, 이로 인해 발생하는 UD해석의 정확성을 토론할 것이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_hy>Համաշխարհային կախվածության (UD) վերլուծությունից ստացված ճշգրիտ վերականգնումը կենտրոնական է դեպի ներքևի գործողությունները, ինչպիսիք են սեմանտիկ դերերի կամ իրադարձությունների ներկայացումների վերացումը: Այս ուսումնասիրությունը ներկայացնում է համաշխարհային շղթաներ, խմբավորում UD-ի վերլուծության մեջ գոյություն ունեցող բարդ կախվածության հարաբերությունների հիերարխիան: Կոմպլանտային դասակարգման ճշգրտությունը ծառայում է որպես պրոքսի, որպեսզի չափվի ճշգրիտ վերականգնումը նախադասություններից ներգրավման հետ: Մենք վերլուծեցինք կառուցվածքների տարածումը երեք անգլերենի անգլերենի ծառերի տախտակներում, Էութ, ԳուՄ և Լինեսում, բացահայտելով, որ այս ծառերի տախտակները քիչ են վերաբերյալ նախադասությունների հետ, որոնք ներառում են նախադասություններ և բանավեճեր: Մենք գնահատեցինք CONSL 2018-ի ընդհանուր հանձնարարությունների UDPipe (v1.2) հիմնական (կախվածության վերլուծում) մոդելները որպես համաշխարհային դասակարգեր, որոնք օգտագործվում են ԵՈւ-ի, ԳՈՄՍ-ի և Լինեսի UD-ի ծառերի վրա: Our results indicate that these three baseline models exhibit poorer performance on sentences with predicate-argument structure with more than one level of embedding;  we used compchains to characterize the errors made by these parsers and present examples of erroneous parses produced by the parser that were identified using compchains.  Մենք նաև վերլուծեցինք համաշխարհային շղթաների բաշխման 58 ոչ անգլերեն UD ծառերի տախտակներում և հետո օգտագործեցինք համաշխարհային շղթաներ, որպեսզի գնահատենք այս ծառերի տախտակներից յուրաքանչյուր մեկի կոնֆլենսի 18-ի ընդհանուր գործող Մեր վերլուծությունը ցույց է տալիս, որ կառուցվածքային դասակարգման արդյունքները միայն թույլ են կապված
պաշտոնական գնահատման չափումները (LAS, MLAS և Blax). Մենք բացահայտում ենք բազմաթիվ ԱՄՆ-ի ծառերի բաշխման բաժանման բացառումները, այնպես որ առաջարկում ենք ճանապարհ, թե ինչպես են ծառերի բաշխման բաղադրիչները լրացվում: Մենք եզրակացնում ենք քննարկելով, թե ինչպես են կոմպշինտները նոր տեսանկյունից UD-ի վերլուծումների ուսումնասիրության տվյալների հազվադեպությունը, ինչպես նաև արդյունքում ստացված UD-ի վերլուծումների ճշգրտությունը:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_et>Preikaadi-argumendi struktuuri täpne taastamine universaalse sõltuvuse (UD) parsimisest on keskse tähtsusega järgnevates ülesannetes, näiteks semantiliste rollide või sündmuste esituste ekstraheerimisel. Käesolev uuring tutvustab kompchaineid, mis on UD parsis esinevate predikaatide sõltuvussuhete hierarhia kategoriseerimine. Komplikaatide klassifitseerimise täpsus on vahend eelkaadi-argumendi struktuuri täpse taastumise mõõtmiseks lausetest koos manustamisega. Analüüsisime kompchainide jaotust kolmes UD inglise keele puupangas EWT, GUM ja LinES, näidates, et need puupangad on hõredad seoses lausetega predikaadi-argumendi struktuuriga, mis sisaldab predikaadi-argumendi manustamist. Hindasime CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baasmudeleid (sõltuvuse parsimine) EWT, GUMS ja LinES UD puupankade kompahelate klassifitseerijatena. Meie tulemused näitavad, et need kolm baasmudelit näitavad halvemat jõudlust lausete puhul, millel on predikaadi-argumendi struktuur, millel on rohkem kui üks manustamistase; kasutasime kompchaineid, et kirjeldada nende parserite tehtud vigu ja esitada näiteid parseri tehtud vigadest, mis tuvastati kompchainide abil. Analüüsisime ka kompahelate jaotumist 58 mitte-inglise UD puupangas ja seejärel kasutasime kompahelaid, et hinnata CoNLL'18 Shared Task baasmudelit iga puupanga jaoks. Meie analüüs näitab, et komplektide klassifitseerimise tulemuslikkus on ainult nõrgalt korrelatsioonis
ametlikud hindamismeetodid (LAS, MLAS ja BLEX). Me tuvastame lüngad komplektide jaotuses mitmes UD puupunktis, pakkudes seega tegevuskava, kuidas neid puupunkte täiendada. Lõpetuseks arutleme, kuidas komplektid pakuvad uut perspektiivi UD parserite treeningandmete vähesusele ning tulemusena saadud UD parsimiste täpsusele.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>predikaatti-argumenttirakenteen tarkka palautuminen UD (Universal Dependency) -jäsentämisestä on keskeistä jatkovaiheen tehtävissä, kuten semanttisten roolien tai tapahtumaesitysten poimimisessa. Tämä tutkimus esittelee kompchaineja, jotka ovat UD-jäsennyksessä esiintyvien predikaattien riippuvuussuhteiden hierarkian kategorisointia. Komponenttiketjun luokittelun tarkkuus toimii proxynä predikaatti-argumenttirakenteen tarkan palautumisen mittaamiseen lauseista upotuksella. Analysoimme kompchainien jakautumista kolmessa UD English treebankissa, EWT, GUM ja LinES, ja paljastimme, että nämä puupankit ovat harvoja suhteessa lauseisiin, joissa predikaatti-argumentti rakenne sisältää predikaatti-argumentti upotuksen. Arvioimme CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) -perusmallin (riippuvuuden parsaus) kompchain luokittelijoina EWT-, GUMS- ja LinES UD -puupankeille. Tuloksemme osoittavat, että näillä kolmella perusmallilla on huonompi suorituskyky lauseilla, joissa predikaatti-argumenttirakenne on useampi kuin yksi upotustaso. Käytimme kompchaineja karakterisoimaan näiden jäsentäjien tekemiä virheitä ja esittämään esimerkkejä jäsentäjien tuottamista virheellisistä jäsentäjistä, jotka tunnistettiin kompchaineilla. Analysoimme myös kompchainien jakautumista 58:ssa ei-englantilaisessa UD-puupankissa ja käytimme kompchaineja arvioimaan CoNLL'18 Shared Task -perusmallia kullekin näistä puupankeista. Analyysimme osoittaa, että compchain-luokituksen suorituskyky korreloi vain heikosti
viralliset arviointimittarit (LAS, MLAS ja BLEX). Havaitsemme puutteita komplekttiketjujen jakautumisessa useissa UD-puupankeissa, ja näin tarjoamme tiekartan siitä, miten näitä puita voidaan täydentää. Päätämme puheenvuoron keskustelemalla siitä, miten kompchainit tarjoavat uuden näkökulman UD-jäsentäjien harjoitustietojen niukkuuteen sekä tuloksena olevien UD-jäsentäjien tarkkuuteen.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bs>Upravo je oporavak predikatne strukture argument a iz analize univerzalne zavisnosti (UD) centralno za smanjenje zadataka poput izvlačenja semantičkih uloga ili predstavljanja događaja. Ova studija predstavlja komplansiranje, kategoriju hijerarhije predikatnih odnosa ovisnosti koje su prisutne u analizu UD-a. Točnost klasifikacije kompchaina služi kao proksi za mjerenje tačnog oporavka strukture predikata argument a iz rečenica sa integracijom. Analizirali smo distribuciju kompchainsa na tri UD engleske trgovine, EWT, GUM i LinES, otkrivajući da su te trgovine rezervne u odnosu na rečenice sa predikatnem strukturom argumenta koja uključuje predikatne integracije argumenta. Procjenili smo modele podijeljenog zadatka UDPipe (v1.2) za početnu liniju (analizanje ovisnosti) CoNLL 2018 kao klasifikatore kompchaina za EWT, GUMS i LinES UD trgovine. Naši rezultati ukazuju na to da ove tri osnovne modela pokazuju siromašniju predstavu na rečenicama sa predikatnim strukturom argumenta sa više od jedne nivoe ugrađenja; Koristili smo komplansiranje kako bi karakterizirali greške koje su napravili ovi parseri i predstavili primjere grešnih parsera proizvođenih od strane analizatora koji su identifikovani koristeći komplansiranje. Također smo analizirali distribuciju kompchaina u 58 ne-engleskim UD treebancima i onda smo koristili kompchaine kako bi procijenili model podijeljenog zadatka CoNLL'18 za svaku od ovih treebancija. Naša analiza pokazuje da je izvedba u pogledu klasifikacije kompchaina slaba povezana sa
zvanična procjena metrika (LAS, MLAS i BLEX). Identificiramo praznine u distribuciji kompchainsa u nekoliko UD-ovih trgovačkih granica, tako pružajući putnu mapu kako bi se ovi treebani mogli dodati. Zaključili smo razgovaranjem o tome kako komplanci pružaju novu perspektivu o isključivosti podataka obuke za UD analizatore, kao i preciznosti rezultatnih UD analiza.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Přesné obnovení struktury predikátů-argumentů z parsy univerzální závislosti (UD) je klíčové pro následné úlohy, jako je extrakce sémantických rolí nebo reprezentace událostí. Tato studie představuje kompchainy, kategorizaci hierarchie predikátových závislostních vztahů přítomných v UD parse. Přesnost klasifikace compchain slouží jako proxy pro měření přesného obnovení struktury predikátů-argumentů z vět s vložením. Analyzovali jsme distribuci kompchain ve třech UD anglických stromových bankách, EWT, GUM a LinES, a odhalili, že tyto stromové banky jsou řídké vzhledem k větám se strukturou predikátů, která zahrnuje vložení predikátů do argumentů. Vyhodnotili jsme základní modely CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) jako klasifikátory kompchain pro stromové banky EWT, GUMS a LinES UD. Naše výsledky ukazují, že tyto tři základní modely vykazují špatnější výkon u vět se strukturou predikátů argumentů s více než jednou úrovní vložení; K charakterizaci chyb těchto parserů jsme použili komponenty a prezentovali příklady chybných parserů vytvořených parserem, které byly identifikovány pomocí komponentů. Rovněž jsme analyzovali distribuci kompchainů v 58 neanglických UD stromových bázích a pak použili kompchainy k vyhodnocení základního modelu CoNLL'18 Shared Task pro každou z těchto stromových bází. Naše analýza ukazuje, že výkonnost s ohledem na klasifikaci kompchain je pouze slabě korelována s
oficiální hodnotící metriky (LAS, MLAS a BLEX). Identifikujeme mezery v distribuci kompchainů v několika UD stromových břehů, čímž poskytujeme plán pro doplnění těchto stromových břehů. Na závěr diskutujeme, jak kompchainy poskytují nový pohled na řídkost tréninkových dat pro UD parsery, stejně jako na přesnost výsledných UD parser.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_jv>Print checkbox Genjer-Genjer Strikethrough Awak dhéwé éngleksi perusahaan tanggal winih karo perusahaan tanggal urip Uit dumateng, IWT, GIM lan Lines, menehi kowe ngupakan karo perusahaan karo perusahaan karo perusahaan sing dadi tanggal nggalakno karo perusahaan dumateng-atik dhéwé Awak dhéwé éntuk nggawe CoNLL 2008 shared task udPipe (V1.2) bazline (diphendisentasi aléntasi) model karo kompstring dipolesane nggo eWT, GIMP karo Lines udd traebangs Rejalaké awak dhéwé ngerti barang-barang telu model sing bisa ngomong gawe barang kelas barang kanggo kelas barang sampek karo perusahaan-argument sing wis luwih apik sing katya sampek sing luwih dumadhi; string" in "context_BAR_stringLink Awak dhéwé éntuk cara-cara kotak nggawe sapa tanggal ndherek wih-wih lan nganggo cara-cara kotak nggawe lan nambah wih-wih apik dhéwé nggawe model CoNLL'18 Tarjamahan sing wis berarti barêng-barêng kuwi cara-barêng iki. Ndeleksyon awak dhéwé ngomong nik nggawe kesempatan kanggo kelas terakhir dhéwé kuwi duluran ngono</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>התאוששות מדויקת של מבנה טיעון מוגדר ממחקר תלויות יוניברסליות (UD) היא מרכזית למשימות מתחתונות כמו החלץ של תפקידים סמנטיים או מייצג אירועים. This study introduces compchains, a categorization of the hierarchy of predicate dependency relations present within a UD parse.  Accuracy of compchain classification serves as a proxy for measuring accurate recovery of predicate-argument structure from sentences with embedding.  We analyzed the distribution of compchains in three UD English treebanks, EWT, GUM and LinES, revealing that these treebanks are sparse with respect to sentences with predicate-argument structure that includes predicate-argument embedding.  We evaluated the CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (dependency parsing) models as compchain classifiers for the EWT, GUMS and LinES UD treebanks.  התוצאות שלנו מצביעות ששלושת הדוגמנים הבסיסיים האלה מראים ביצועים גרועים יותר על משפטים עם מבנה טיעון מוקדם השתמשנו בשרשרות כדי לתייצב את השגיאות שנעשו על ידי המעבדים האלה ולהציג דוגמאות של מעבדות שגויות שנוצרו על ידי המעבד שנזהו באמצעות השרשרות. We also analyzed the distribution of compchains in 58 non-English UD treebanks and then used compchains to evaluate the CoNLL'18 Shared Task baseline model for each of these treebanks.  הניתוח שלנו מראה שהביצועים בנוגע להקליזציה של compchain רק קשורים חלשים עם</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Salon da shirin hagu na ɗabi'a daga parse na Universal Deƙaitacce (UD) na tsakiya zuwa taskõkin ƙarami kamar fitarwa na aikin semantic ko shiryoyin ayuka. Wannan littafin na ƙunsa da nauyi, wani category of the hierrchy of predefined dependanci wanda ke cikin wata parse na UD. Tilas na tsarin classifori na cikin shaƙƙi ya yi amfani da shi kamar wata proksi dõmin a ƙayyade kure na tsari mai daidaita na bakin-rubutu na-ɗabi'a daga cire da aka shigar da. Ba mu yi anayya da rabon sarƙoƙi uku na Ingiriya ta UD, EWT, GUM da LinES, kuma mun yi bayani da cewa waɗannan turbuɗe su yi sauri a cikin salon da ke ƙunsa da bakin rubutu wanda ke shiga Mun ƙaddara misãlai na CoNLL 2018 mai Shared Takar UD (v1.2) da suka zama samun samun samun sarƙoƙi wa EWT, GUM da LinES UD Treebanks. MatamayinMu na nũna cewa waɗannan misalin basalin mita uku sun nuna mafiya kwanza a kan sonar da bakin rubutun da ke ƙara daraja guda; we used compchains to characterize the errors made by these parsers and present examples of erroneous parses produced by the parser that were identified using compchains.  Mu yi anayyar da rabon sarƙoƙi a 58 na-Ingiriya na UD-Treebanks kuma muka yi amfani da sarƙoƙi dõmin an evaluce misalin babban aikin CoNLL'18 wanda aka Shara wa dukkan wannan Treebanks. AnayyayinMu yana nũna cewa aikin da aka yi wa fassarar sarƙoƙi kawai yana mai rauni da</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Natančno obnovitev strukture predikatov-argumentov iz razčlenitve univerzalne odvisnosti (UD) je osrednjega pomena za nadaljnja opravila, kot je ekstrakcija semantičnih vlog ali predstavitev dogodkov. Ta študija uvaja kompchaine, kategorizacijo hierarhije predikatnih odvisnosti, prisotnih v razčlenitvi UD. Natančnost klasifikacije kompaktnih verig služi kot približek za merjenje natančnega obnovitve strukture predikatov-argumentov iz stavkov z vdelavo. Analizirali smo porazdelitev kompaktov v treh UD angleških treebanks, EWT, GUM in LinES, pri čemer smo razkrili, da so te dreebanke redke glede stavkov s strukturo predikat-argument, ki vključuje vdelavo predikat-argument. Ocenili smo osnovne modele CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) kot klasifikatorje kompozicijskih verig za drevesne zbirke EWT, GUMS in LinES UD. Naši rezultati kažejo, da so ti trije osnovni modeli slabši pri stavkih s strukturo predikatov-argumentov z več kot eno stopnjo vdelave; Za opredelitev napak, ki jih naredijo ti razčlenjevalniki, smo uporabili kompaktne verige in predstavili primere napačnih razčlenjevalnikov, ki jih je naredil razčlenjevalnik, ki so bile identificirane z uporabo kompaktnih verig. Analizirali smo tudi porazdelitev kompletnih verig v 58 ne-angleških UD treebanks in nato uporabili kompletne verige za oceno osnovnega modela CoNLL'18 Shared Task za vsako od teh treebanks. Naša analiza kaže, da je uspešnost pri klasifikaciji kompletnih verig le šibko korelacija z</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>Accurate recovery of predicate-argument structure from a Universal Dependency (UD) parse is central to downstream tasks such as extraction of semantic roles or event representations. UD་ལྟ་ཞིབ་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་ཡོད་པའི་སྒྲིག་རིམ་གྱི་དབྱེ་རིམ་གྱི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་དང་ཐོག་རིམ། Accuracy of compchain classification serves as a proxy for measuring accurate recovery of predicate-argument structure from sentences with embedding. We analyzed the distribution of compchains in three UD English treebanks, EWT, GUM and LinES, revealing that these treebanks are sparse with respect to sentences with predicate-argument structure that includes predicate-argument embedding. We evaluated the CoNLL 2018 Shared Task UDPipe (v1.2) baseline (dependency parsing) models as compchain classifiers for the EWT, GUMS and LinES UD treebanks. Our results indicate that these three baseline models exhibit poorer performance on sentences with predicate-argument structure with more than one level of embedding; and we used compchains to characterize the errors made by these parsers and present examples of erroneous parses produced by the parser that were identified using compchains. ང་ཚོས་དབྱིན་ཡིག་ཆ་མིན་པའི་བརྗོད་ཆེན་ཀྱི་བགོ་སྟངས་ཀྱང་58 རེད་ཅིག་གི་ནང་དུ་ཞིབ་དཔྱད་བྱས་ནས་བསྡུས་རི་(compchains)རྩིས་པ་འདི་རེ་རེར་བཞིན ང་ཚོའི་དབྱེ་ཞིབ་ཡིན་ན་མཛོད་ཁང་གི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་དང་མཐུན་རྐྱེན་འདྲེན་བྱེད་པའི་གོ་སྐབས་</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Disentangling Online Chats with DAG-structured LSTMs<fixed-case>DAG</fixed-case>-structured <fixed-case>LSTM</fixed-case>s</title>
      <author><first>Duccio</first><last>Pappadopulo</last></author>
      <author><first>Lisa</first><last>Bauer</last></author>
      <author><first>Marco</first><last>Farina</last></author>
      <author><first>Ozan</first><last>İrsoy</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohit</first><last>Bansal</last></author>
      <pages>152–159</pages>
      <abstract>Many modern <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Message-oriented_middleware">messaging systems</a> allow fast and synchronous textual communication among many users. The resulting sequence of messages hides a more complicated structure in which independent sub-conversations are interwoven with one another. This poses a challenge for any task aiming to understand the content of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chat_log">chat logs</a> or gather information from them. The ability to disentangle these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversation">conversations</a> is then tantamount to the success of many downstream <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">tasks</a> such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_summarization">summarization</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Question_answering">question answering</a>. Structured information accompanying the text such as user turn, user mentions, timestamps, is used as a cue by the participants themselves who need to follow the conversation and has been shown to be important for disentanglement. DAG-LSTMs, a generalization of Tree-LSTMs that can handle directed acyclic dependencies, are a natural way to incorporate such information and its non-sequential nature. In this paper, we apply DAG-LSTMs to the conversation disentanglement task. We perform our experiments on the Ubuntu IRC dataset. We show that the novel model we propose achieves state of the art status on the task of recovering reply-to relations and it is competitive on other disentanglement metrics.</abstract>
      <url hash="fb1be83f">2021.starsem-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>pappadopulo-etal-2021-disentangling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Toward Diverse Precondition Generation</title>
      <author><first>Heeyoung</first><last>Kwon</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathanael</first><last>Chambers</last></author>
      <author><first>Niranjan</first><last>Balasubramanian</last></author>
      <pages>160–172</pages>
      <abstract>A typical goal for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-language_understanding">language understanding</a> is to logically connect the events of a discourse, but often connective events are not described due to their commonsense nature. In order to address this deficit, we focus here on generating precondition events. Precondition generation can be framed as a sequence-to-sequence problem : given a target event, generate a possible precondition. However, in most real-world scenarios, an event can have several preconditions, which is not always suitable for standard seq2seq frameworks. We propose DiP, the Diverse Precondition generation system that can generate unique and diverse preconditions. DiP consists of three stages of the generative process   an event sampler, a candidate generator, and a post-processor. The event sampler provides control codes (precondition triggers) which the candidate generator uses to focus its generation. Post-processing further improves the results through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranking">re-ranking</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Filter_(software)">filtering</a>. Unlike other conditional generation systems, DiP automatically generates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Control_code">control codes</a> without training on diverse examples. Analysis reveals that DiP improves the diversity of preconditions significantly compared to a beam search baseline. Also, manual evaluation shows that DiP generates more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precursor_(chemistry)">preconditions</a> than a strong nucleus sampling baseline.</abstract>
      <url hash="0afad549">2021.starsem-1.15</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.15</doi>
      <bibkey>kwon-etal-2021-toward</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="19">
      <title>Incorporating EDS Graph for AMR Parsing<fixed-case>EDS</fixed-case> Graph for <fixed-case>AMR</fixed-case> Parsing</title>
      <author><first>Ziyi</first><last>Shou</last></author>
      <author><first>Fangzhen</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <pages>202–211</pages>
      <abstract>AMR (Abstract Meaning Representation) and EDS (Elementary Dependency Structures) are two popular meaning representations in NLP / NLU. AMR is more abstract and conceptual, while EDS is more low level, closer to the lexical structures of the given sentences. It is thus not surprising that EDS parsing is easier than AMR parsing. In this work, we consider using information from EDS parsing to help improve the performance of AMR parsing. We adopt a transition-based parser and propose to add EDS graphs as additional semantic features using a graph encoder composed of LSTM layer and GCN layer. Our experimental results show that the additional information from EDS parsing indeed gives a boost to the performance of the base AMR parser used in our experiments.</abstract>
      <url hash="92dfd058">2021.starsem-1.19</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.19</doi>
      <bibkey>shou-lin-2021-incorporating</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/penn-treebank">Penn Treebank</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="21">
      <title>Neural Metaphor Detection with Visibility Embeddings</title>
      <author><first>Gitit</first><last>Kehat</last></author>
      <author><first>James</first><last>Pustejovsky</last></author>
      <pages>222–228</pages>
      <abstract>We present new results for the problem of sequence metaphor labeling, using the recently developed Visibility Embeddings. We show that concatenating such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embedding">embeddings</a> to the input of a BiLSTM obtains consistent and significant improvements at almost no cost, and we present further improved results when visibility embeddings are combined with BERT.</abstract>
      <url hash="90afa474">2021.starsem-1.21</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.21</doi>
      <bibkey>kehat-pustejovsky-2021-neural</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/visual-genome">Visual Genome</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="22">
      <title>Inducing Language-Agnostic Multilingual Representations</title>
      <author><first>Wei</first><last>Zhao</last></author>
      <author><first>Steffen</first><last>Eger</last></author>
      <author><first>Johannes</first><last>Bjerva</last></author>
      <author><first>Isabelle</first><last>Augenstein</last></author>
      <pages>229–240</pages>
      <abstract>Cross-lingual representations have the potential to make NLP techniques available to the vast majority of languages in the world. However, they currently require large pretraining corpora or access to typologically similar languages. In this work, we address these obstacles by removing language identity signals from multilingual embeddings. We examine three approaches for this : (i) re-aligning the vector spaces of target languages (all together) to a pivot source language ; (ii) removing language-specific means and variances, which yields better discriminativeness of embeddings as a by-product ; and (iii) increasing input similarity across languages by removing morphological contractions and sentence reordering. We evaluate on XNLI and reference-free MT evaluation across 19 typologically diverse languages. Our findings expose the limitations of these approachesunlike <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_normalization">vector normalization</a>, vector space re-alignment and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_normalization">text normalization</a> do not achieve consistent gains across encoders and languages. Due to the approaches’ additive effects, their combination decreases the cross-lingual transfer gap by 8.9 points (m-BERT) and 18.2 points (XLM-R) on average across all tasks and languages, however.</abstract>
      <url hash="b003b43c">2021.starsem-1.22</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="4468620b">2021.starsem-1.22.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.pdf</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.22</doi>
      <bibkey>zhao-etal-2021-inducing</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/AIPHES/Language-Agnostic-Contextualized-Encoders" additional="false">AIPHES/Language-Agnostic-Contextualized-Encoders</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/xnli">XNLI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="25">
      <title>Spurious Correlations in Cross-Topic Argument Mining</title>
      <author><first>Terne Sasha</first><last>Thorn Jakobsen</last></author>
      <author><first>Maria</first><last>Barrett</last></author>
      <author><first>Anders</first><last>Søgaard</last></author>
      <pages>263–277</pages>
      <abstract>Recent work in cross-topic argument mining attempts to learn <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">models</a> that generalise across topics rather than merely relying on within-topic spurious correlations. We examine the effectiveness of this approach by analysing the output of single-task and multi-task models for cross-topic argument mining, through a combination of linear approximations of their decision boundaries, manual feature grouping, challenge examples, and ablations across the input vocabulary. Surprisingly, we show that cross-topic models still rely mostly on spurious correlations and only generalise within closely related topics, e.g., a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">model</a> trained only on closed-class words and a few common open-class words outperforms a state-of-the-art cross-topic model on distant target topics.</abstract>
      <url hash="e26daf8d">2021.starsem-1.25</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.25</doi>
      <bibkey>thorn-jakobsen-etal-2021-spurious</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/terne/spurious_correlations_in_argmin" additional="false">terne/spurious_correlations_in_argmin</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Overcoming Poor Word Embeddings with Word Definitions</title>
      <author><first>Christopher</first><last>Malon</last></author>
      <pages>288–293</pages>
      <abstract>Modern natural language understanding models depend on pretrained subword embeddings, but applications may need to reason about words that were never or rarely seen during pretraining. We show that examples that depend critically on a rarer word are more challenging for natural language inference models. Then we explore how a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> could learn to use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Definition">definitions</a>, provided in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural text</a>, to overcome this handicap. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a>’s understanding of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Definition">definition</a> is usually weaker than a well-modeled word embedding, but it recovers most of the performance gap from using a completely untrained word.</abstract>
      <url hash="a823cd7c">2021.starsem-1.27</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.starsem-1.27</doi>
      <bibkey>malon-2021-overcoming</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/snli">SNLI</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>