<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.mwe">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 17th Workshop on Multiword Expressions (MWE 2021)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Paul</first><last>Cook</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jelena</first><last>Mitrović</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Carla Parra</first><last>Escartín</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ashwini</first><last>Vaidya</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Petya</first><last>Osenova</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Shiva</first><last>Taslimipoor</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Carlos</first><last>Ramisch</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="f2cb1188">2021.mwe-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="36cb2cc9">2021.mwe-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>mwe-2021-multiword</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Where Do Aspectual Variants of Light Verb Constructions Belong?</title>
      <author><first>Aggeliki</first><last>Fotopoulou</last></author>
      <author><first>Eric</first><last>Laporte</last></author>
      <author><first>Takuya</first><last>Nakamura</last></author>
      <pages>2–12</pages>
      <abstract>Expressions with an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammatical_aspect">aspectual variant</a> of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_verb">light verb</a>, e.g. ‘take on debt’ vs. ‘have debt’, are frequent in texts but often difficult to classify between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idiom_(language_structure)">verbal idioms</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_verb_construction">light verb constructions</a> or compositional phrases. We investigate the properties of such <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expression_(mathematics)">expressions</a> with a disputed membership and propose a selection of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(linguistics)">features</a> that determine more satisfactory boundaries between the three categories in this zone, assigning the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expression_(mathematics)">expressions</a> to one of them.</abstract>
      <url hash="472c33f2">2021.mwe-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.mwe-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>fotopoulou-etal-2021-aspectual</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Onde pertencem as variantes aspectuais das construções de verbos leves?</title_pt>
      <title_es>¿Dónde pertenecen las variantes aspectuales de las construcciones de verbos ligeros?</title_es>
      <title_ar>أين تنتمي المتغيرات العرضية لتراكيب الفعل الخفيف؟</title_ar>
      <title_hi>प्रकाश क्रिया निर्माण के Aspectual वेरिएंट कहाँ से संबंधित हैं?</title_hi>
      <title_ja>軽い動詞構築のアスペクト変形はどこに属しますか？</title_ja>
      <title_zh>光动词构之 Aspectual 变体安在?</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Cá mBaineann Athróga Gnéthúla de Fhoirgníochtaí Briathra Solais?</title_ga>
      <title_hu>Hol tartoznak a könnyű igék szerkezeteinek aspektuális változatai?</title_hu>
      <title_ka>კყევ აჟოვკრსლნთ გაპთანრთ ჲრ ჟგვრლთფნთრვ გყპბჲგთ?</title_ka>
      <title_el>Πού ανήκουν οι πτυχικές παραλλαγές των ελαφρών κατασκευών ρήμων;</title_el>
      <title_it>Dove appartengono le varianti dimensionali delle costruzioni dei verbi leggeri?</title_it>
      <title_kk>Төмендегі жарық құрылғының аспектуалды айнымалылары қайда болады?</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Каде припаѓаат аспектуалните варијанти на изградбата на светли јазици?</title_mk>
      <title_lt>Where Do Aspectual Variants of Light Verb Constructions Belong?</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Dimana Variansi Aspektual Pembangunan Verb Cahaya Belong?</title_ms>
      <title_ml>ലൈറ്റ് വെര്‍ബ് പണിയിടത്തിന്റെ ആസ്പെക്കല്‍ വേറിയണ്ടുകള്‍ എവിടെയാണ്?</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Fejn jappartjenu l-Varjanti Aspettivi tal-Kostruzzjonijiet ta’ Verbi Ħfief?</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Гэрэл жимс бүтээмжүүдийн аспектийн өөрчлөлт хаана байдаг вэ?</title_mn>
      <title_no>Hvor gjer aspektiv varianter av lysverdikonstruksjonar under?</title_no>
      <title_pl>Gdzie należą aspektowe warianty lekkich konstrukcji czasowników?</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Gde su aspektualne varijante svetlosne vrste izgradnje ispod?</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Unde aparțin Variantele Aspectuale ale Construcțiilor Verbelor Luminoase?</title_ro>
      <title_si>කොහෙද ලයිට් වර්බ් නිර්මාණයේ ප්‍රමාණ වෙනස් කරන්නේ?</title_si>
      <title_so>Halkee waxaa laga helaa dhismaha nuurka ee nuurka?</title_so>
      <title_sv>Var hör Aspektuella Varianter av Ljusverbkonstruktioner hemma?</title_sv>
      <title_ta>ஒளி வெர்ப் கட்டுப்பாடுகளின் காட்சி மாறிகள் எங்கே சேர்க்கிறது?</title_ta>
      <title_ur>روشنی ورب بنانے کی نظریہ مختلف کہاں ہیں؟</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Dấu hiệu xây dựng bằng môi trường ánh sáng thuộc về nơi nào?</title_vi>
      <title_da>Hvor hører Aspektuelle Varianter af Light Verb Konstruktioner hjemme?</title_da>
      <title_bg>Къде принадлежат аспектните варианти на конструкциите на светлите глаголи?</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Waar horen aspectuele varianten van lichte werkwoordenconstructies toe?</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Gdje su aspektualne varijante svetlosne vrste izgradnje ispod?</title_hr>
      <title_de>Wohin gehören Aspektvarianten von Light Verb Constructions?</title_de>
      <title_ko>경동사 구조의 체변체는 어디에 속합니까?</title_ko>
      <title_id>Dimana Varian Aspektual dari Pembangunan Verb Cahaya Belong?</title_id>
      <title_fa>تغییرات نظریه‌ای از ساختارهای نور برق زیر کجا هستند؟</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Je, Mabadiliko ya Miundombinu ya mwanga yanafanyika wapi?</title_sw>
      <title_af>Waar Doen Aspektuele Variantes van Ligte Verb konstruksies onder?</title_af>
      <title_tr>Ýagtyň hatlaryň üýtgewleri nirede bolar?</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Ku janë variantet aspektuale të ndërtimit të verbëve të lehtë?</title_sq>
      <title_am>የፊደል ቅርጽ ምርጫዎች የት ይሄዳሉ?</title_am>
      <title_hy>Որտե՞ղ են լույս բայերի կառուցվածքների առանցքային տարբերակները:</title_hy>
      <title_bn>লাইট ভার্ব ভবন কোথায়?</title_bn>
      <title_az>Aşıq Verb Yapılarının Aspectual Variants Belə Nerə?</title_az>
      <title_cs>Kde patří aspektové varianty světelných slovesníkových konstrukcí?</title_cs>
      <title_bs>Gdje su aspektualne varijante svetlosne vrste izgradnje ispod?</title_bs>
      <title_et>Kuhu kuuluvad valgusverbide konstruktsioonide aspektsed variandid?</title_et>
      <title_ca>On pertanyen les variants aspectuals de les construccions de verbs lleugers?</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Mihin valon verbin rakennelmat kuuluvat?</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Align to:</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Kam spadajo vidikovne različice konstrukcije svetlobnih glagolov?</title_sk>
      <title_ha>@ action: inmenu</title_ha>
      <title_he>איפה שינויים מבחינה של בניית ערבות קלות?</title_he>
      <title_bo>འོད་ཀྱིས་ཀློག་ཚུལ་གྱི་སྒྲིག་འཛུགས་ཀྱི་རྣམ་པ་ཚོའི་ནང་དུ་འདྲ་བྱེད་པ་ཡིན་ནམ།</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>التعبيرات مع متغير الجانب من الفعل الخفيف ، على سبيل المثال تتكرر كلمة "تحمل الدين" مقابل "الديون" في النصوص ولكن يصعب تصنيفها في كثير من الأحيان بين المصطلحات اللفظية أو تراكيب الأفعال الخفيفة أو العبارات التركيبية. نحن نحقق في خصائص مثل هذه التعبيرات ذات العضوية المتنازع عليها ونقترح مجموعة من الميزات التي تحدد حدودًا أكثر إرضاءً بين الفئات الثلاث في هذه المنطقة ، مع تخصيص التعبيرات لإحدى هذه الفئات.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Expressões com uma variante aspectual de um verbo leve, e.g. 'assumir dívida' vs. 'ter dívida' são frequentes em textos, mas muitas vezes difíceis de classificar entre expressões idiomáticas verbais, construções verbais leves ou frases composicionais. Investigamos as propriedades de tais expressões com pertinência disputada e propomos uma seleção de características que determinam limites mais satisfatórios entre as três categorias nesta zona, atribuindo as expressões a uma delas.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Las expresiones con una variante aspectual de un verbo ligero, por ejemplo, «endeudarse» o «tener deudas», son frecuentes en los textos, pero a menudo son difíciles de clasificar entre modismos verbales, construcciones de verbos ligeros o frases compositivas. Investigamos las propiedades de dichas expresiones con una membresía en disputa y proponemos una selección de características que determinan límites más satisfactorios entre las tres categorías de esta zona, asignando las expresiones a una de ellas.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>軽い動詞のアスペクトバリエーションを持つ表現、例えば、「借金を背負う」対「借金を抱える」は、テキストでは頻繁に見られるが、多くの場合、動詞の造語、軽い動詞の構築、または構成句の間で分類することは困難である。紛争メンバーシップを持つこのような表現の特性を調査し、このゾーンの3つのカテゴリ間のより満足のいく境界を決定する機能の選択を提案し、そのうちの1つに表現を割り当てます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>有轻动词意变体,如"任债"与"有债",于文本中常见,然常难于动词习语,轻动词结构短语之类。 按议员资格表达式属性,列特征,以定三界,分表达式为一。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>एक प्रकाश क्रिया के एक पहलू संस्करण के साथ अभिव्यक्ति, उदाहरण के लिए 'ऋण पर ले लो' बनाम 'ऋण है', ग्रंथों में अक्सर होते हैं, लेकिन अक्सर मौखिक मुहावरों, हल्के क्रिया निर्माण या रचनात्मक वाक्यांशों के बीच वर्गीकृत करना मुश्किल होता है। हम एक विवादित सदस्यता के साथ इस तरह की अभिव्यक्तियों के गुणों की जांच करते हैं और उन विशेषताओं के चयन का प्रस्ताव करते हैं जो इस क्षेत्र में तीन श्रेणियों के बीच अधिक संतोषजनक सीमाओं को निर्धारित करते हैं, उनमें से एक को अभिव्यक्तियों को असाइन करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Nathanna a bhfuil leagan gnéitheach de bhriathar éadrom acu, e.g. Is minic i dtéacsanna iad `gabháil ar fhiach' vs. `bíodh fiach' orthu ach is deacair iad a rangú go minic idir nathanna cainte, tógálacha briathar éadroma nó frásaí cumadóireachta. Déanaimid imscrúdú ar airíonna na n-abairtí sin le ballraíocht faoi dhíospóid agus molaimid rogha gnéithe a chinneann teorainneacha níos sásúla idir na trí chatagóir sa chrios seo, ag sannadh na habairtí do cheann amháin acu.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>გამოსახულებები, რომლებიც სინამდვილე გერბის აპექსუალური გარიანტი, მაგრამ `უნდა გავაკეთოთ', `უნდა გავაკეთოთ', `უნდა გავაკეთოთ', `უნდა გავაკეთოთ', `უნდა გავაკეთოთ' ტექსტში, მაგრამ ზ ჩვენ ისეთი გამოსახულების განსაზღვრებების განსაზღვრებით, რომლებიც ამის სამი კატეგორია შორის განსაზღვრებით გავაკეთებთ და გამოსახულების განსაზღვრებით, რომლებიც უფრო დასაკეთესებელი განსაზღვრე</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A könnyű ige aspektuális változatával rendelkező kifejezések, pl. "adósság vállalása" vs. "adósság" gyakoriak a szövegekben, de gyakran nehéz besorolni verbális kifejezések, könnyű igék konstrukciók vagy kompozíciós kifejezések között. Az ilyen kifejezések tulajdonságait vitatott tagsággal vizsgáljuk, és olyan jellemzők kiválasztását javasoljuk, amelyek kielégítőbb határokat határoznak meg a három kategória között ebben a zónában, a kifejezések egyikéhez rendelve.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Οι εκφράσεις με μια οπτική παραλλαγή ενός ελαφρού ρήματος, π.χ. 'ανάληψη χρέους' vs. 'έχω χρέος', είναι συχνές στα κείμενα αλλά συχνά δύσκολο να ταξινομηθούν μεταξύ λεκτικών ιδιοωμάτων, ελαφρών κατασκευών ρήματος ή συνθηματικών φράσεων. Ερευνούμε τις ιδιότητες τέτοιων εκφράσεων με αμφισβητούμενη ιδιότητα μέλους και προτείνουμε μια επιλογή χαρακτηριστικών που καθορίζουν πιο ικανοποιητικά όρια μεταξύ των τριών κατηγοριών αυτής της ζώνης, αντιστοιχίζοντας τις εκφράσεις σε μία από αυτές.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_lt>Tekstuose dažnai vartojami žodžiai su lengvųjų žodžių variantu, pavyzdžiui, "prisiimti skolą" ir "turėti skolą", tačiau dažnai sunku klasifikuoti tarp žodžių idiomų, lengvųjų žodžių konstrukcijų ar sudėtinių frazių. We investigate the properties of such expressions with a disputed membership and propose a selection of features that determine more satisfactory boundaries between the three categories in this zone, assigning the expressions to one of them.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>Le espressioni con una variante aspectuale di un verbo leggero, ad esempio 'prendere il debito' vs 'avere debito', sono frequenti nei testi ma spesso difficili da classificare tra idiomi verbali, costruzioni verbali leggere o frasi compositive. Investighiamo le proprietà di tali espressioni con un'appartenenza contestata e proponiamo una selezione di caratteristiche che determinano confini più soddisfacenti tra le tre categorie in questa zona, assegnando le espressioni ad una di esse.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Өткінші версиясының аспектуалды түрлендірімі, мысалы, `көлемі' және ''көлемі' және ''көлемі' түрлендірілген өрнектері мәтінде көбірек, бірақ көбірек вербалды идиомдар арасында, өткінші версиялық құрылым Біз бұл өрнектердің қасиеттерін сәйкестік бөлімінің қасиеттерін зерттеп, бұл аумақтағы үш категориялардың арасындағы жақсы шектерін таңдап, өрнектерді біріне таңдау үшін таңдаймыз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Експресиите со аспектуален варијант на светло јазик, на пример „ преземете долг “ против „ имајте долг “, се често во текстите, но често тешко се класификуваат меѓу вербалните идиоми, светли јазици конструкции или композициски фрази. Ние ги истражуваме сопственостите на ваквите изрази со спорно членство и предложуваме избор на карактеристики кои одредуваат позадоволни граници меѓу трите категории во оваа зона, додавајќи ги изразите на една од нив.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mt>L-espressjonijiet b’varjant aspettwali ta’ verb ħafif, pereżempju “jieħu d-dejn” vs. “ikollok id-dejn”, huma frekwenti fit-testi iżda ta’ spiss diffiċli biex jiġu kklassifikati bejn idjomi verbali, kostruzzjonijiet ta’ verb ħafif jew frażijiet kompożittivi. Aħna ninvestigaw il-karatteristiċi ta’ espressjonijiet bħal dawn b’sħubija kkontestata u nipproponu għa żla ta’ karatteristiċi li jiddeterminaw fruntieri aktar sodisfaċenti bejn it-tliet kategoriji f’din iż-żona, li jassenjaw l-espressjonijiet lil waħda minnhom.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Ekspresi dengan varian aspektual bagi verb ringan, cth. 'mengambil hutang' vs. 'mempunyai hutang', adalah sering dalam teks tetapi sering sukar untuk diklasifikasikan antara idiom verbal, konstruksi verb ringan atau frasa komposisi. Kami menyelidiki ciri-ciri ungkapan seperti ini dengan anggota yang membantah dan melamar pemilihan ciri-ciri yang menentukan sempadan yang lebih memuaskan antara tiga kategori di zon ini, menyerahkan ungkapan kepada salah satu daripada mereka.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>ലൈറ്റ് വാര്‍ബിന്റെ വ്യത്യസ്ത വ്യത്യാസം, ഉദാഹരണത്തിനായി 'കടം വെക്കുക' എന്നിവയ്ക്ക് വേര്‍തിരിക്കുന്നു. എഴുത്തുകളില്‍ അധികമായി വാക്കുകളില്‍ വെച്ച് വിവരങ്ങളി ഇത്തരം വാക്കുകളുടെ സ്വഭാവങ്ങള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ അന്വേഷിക്കുന്നു. ഒരു തര്‍ക്കിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഒരു മെമ്മറിപ്പ് കൊണ്ട്, ഈ സോണിലെ മൂന്ന് വിഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ക്കിടയില്‍ കൂട</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Хэрэглэгч үгийн хэлбэртэй илэрхийлэл, жишээлбэл "зардал" эсвэл "зардал" гэх мэт, ихэвчлэн текстүүд байдаг, гэхдээ илэрхийлэл үг, гэрэл үгийн бүтээл эсвэл бүтээлч үг хоорондох хэцүү байдаг. Бид энэ хэсгийн гурван хэсгийн хооронд илэрхийллийг илэрхийлдэг хэмжээсүүдийг судалж, тэдний нэгэнд илэрхийллийг тайлбарлаж, илэрхийллийг илэрхийлдэг хэмжээсүүдийг илэрхийлдэг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Uttrykk med e in aspektiv variant av ein lys verb, f.eks. « ta på gjeld » mot « har gjeld », er ofte i tekstar, men ofte vanskeleg å klassifisera mellom verbal e idioma, lyse verbkonstruksjonar eller komposisjonelle fraser. Vi undersøker eigenskapane for slike uttrykk med ein strykt medlemsskap og foreslår eit utval av funksjonar som bestemmer meir tilfredsstillende grenser mellom dei tre kategoriane i denne zonen, og tilbyr uttrykkene til ein av dei.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Wyrażenia o aspektualnym wariancie czasownika lekkiego, np. "weź dług" vs. "maj dług", są częste w tekstach, ale często trudne do klasyfikacji między idiomy werbalne, lekkie konstrukcje czasowników czy zwroty kompozycyjne. Badamy właściwości takich wyrażeń z kwestionowanym członkostwem i proponujemy wybór cech, które określają bardziej satysfakcjonujące granice między trzema kategoriami w tej strefie, przypisując wyrażenia do jednej z nich.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Expresiile cu o variantă aspectuală a unui verb ușor, de exemplu, "luați datorie" vs. "au datorie", sunt frecvente în texte, dar adesea dificil de clasificat între expresii verbale, construcții ușoare de verbe sau fraze compoziționale. Investigăm proprietățile unor astfel de expresii cu un membru contestat și propunem o selecție de caracteristici care determină granițe mai satisfăcătoare între cele trei categorii din această zonă, atribuind expresiile uneia dintre ele.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Izrazi sa aspektualnom varijantom svetlog verb a, npr. „uzimanje duga“ protiv „imaju dug“, često su u tekstima, ali često je teško klasifikovati između verbalnih idioma, laganih verbalnih konstrukcija ili kompozicionalnih fraza. Istražujemo vlasništvo takvih izraza sa spornim članstvom i predlažemo izbor karakteristika koji određuju zadovoljavajuće granice između tri kategorije u ovoj zoni, dodajući izraze jednom od njih.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_sv>Uttryck med en aspektuell variant av ett lätt verb, t.ex. "ta på skuld" vs. "ha skuld", är frekventa i texter men ofta svåra att klassificera mellan verbala idiom, lätta verbkonstruktioner eller kompositionsfraser. Vi undersöker egenskaperna hos sådana uttryck med ett omtvistat medlemskap och föreslår ett urval av funktioner som bestämmer mer tillfredsställande gränser mellan de tre kategorierna i denna zon och tilldelar uttrycken till en av dem.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalka waxaa inta badan ku qoran qoraal, laakiin inta badan waa ku adag tahay inay kala qaybsadaan qofka dhaqdhaqaaqa ah, dhismaha qoraalka fudud ama qoraalka qoyska. We investigate the properties of such expressions with a disputed membership and propose a selection of features that determine more satisfactory boundaries between the three categories in this zone, assigning the expressions to one of them.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ta>வெளிச்சமான எழுத்தின் மாறுபாட்டுகளுடன் கூறுகள் உதாரணமாக 'கடன் மீது எடுத்து' மற்றும் 'கடன்' என்பது எழுத்துகளில் அதிகமாக இருக்கும், ஆனால் பெரும்பாலான முட்டாள்கள், ஒ We investigate the properties of such expressions with a disputed membership and propose a selection of features that determine more satisfactory boundaries between the three categories in this zone, assigning the expressions to one of them.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_si>ප්‍රශ්නයක් ලයිට් වාර්තාවක් වගේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්නේ, උදාහරණයෙන් 'සල්ලි වෙනුවෙන්' vs. `සල්ලි වෙනුවෙන්', සාමාන්‍ය වාර්තාවක් ලිපිත වචනයක්  අපි පරීක්ෂණය කරනවා වගේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් සමඟ ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්නේ සම්බන්ධයක් සමඟ සම්බන්ධයක් තියෙන්නේ, ඒ වගේම මේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් තුන</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>ایک لامٹی ورب کے ایک منظور الفاظت کے مطابق اثرات ہیں، جیسے „لازم پر لازم لگانا” مقابلہ „لازم لگانا“ کے مطابق اثرات میں بہت اثرات ہیں لیکن اثرات میں کلاسیوں کے درمیان کلاسیوں کے بارے میں مشکل ہے، لامٹی ورب ایجاد یا مثال ہم اس طرح کی تعبیر کی خصوصیات کی تحقیق کرتے ہیں ایک جھگڑا ہوا جماعت کے ساتھ اور ایک فرصت کا انتخاب کرنے کی پیشنهاد کرتے ہیں جو اس منطقه میں تین قسموں کے درمیان زیادہ مطمئن ہونے والی حدیں مقرر کرتی ہیں، ان میں سے ایک کے لئے تعبیر کرتی ہیں۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Ikkilamchi harfning qismlari bilan ifodalar, masalan `deym' va `deym' qo'shish mumkin, ko'pincha matnlar yordamida o'zgarishni ko'paytirish juda qiyin. Biz bu ifodalarning xususiyatlarini boshqaramiz va bu maydondagi uchta guruhning orasidagi uchta guruhning chegarasini aniqlash imkoniyatini anglatamiz va ularning birinchisini aytganda aytib beramiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Những lời phát biểu với tính thiên văn của động từ ánh sáng, ví dụ như "g ánh nợ" với "có nợ", thường có trong văn bản nhưng thường rất khó phân loại giữa cử chỉ miệng, thiết kế động từ hay cụm từ liên kết. Chúng tôi nghiên cứu các tính chất của các biểu tượng này với một hội đồng tranh cãi và đề xuất một sự lựa chọn các tính năng xác định giới hạn thỏa mãn hơn giữa ba loại trong khu vực này, sắp đặt các biểu thức cho một trong số chúng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Изрази с аспектуален вариант на лек глагол, например "поемане на дълг" срещу "имаш дълг", са чести в текстовете, но често трудно се класифицират между словесни идиоми, леки глаголни конструкции или композиционни фрази. Проучваме свойствата на такива изрази с оспорвано членство и предлагаме селекция от характеристики, които определят по-задоволителни граници между трите категории в тази зона, приписвайки изразите на една от тях.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Izrazi s aspektualnom varijantom svetlog verb a, na primjer „uzimanje duga“ protiv „imaju dug“, često su u tekstima, ali često je teško klasifikirati između verbalnih idioma, laganih verbalnih konstrukcija ili kompozicionalnih fraza. Istražujemo vlasništvo takvih izraza s spornim članstvom i predlažemo izbor karakteristika koji određuju zadovoljavajuće granice između tri kategorije u ovoj zoni, dodajući izraze jednom od njih.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_da>Udtryk med en aspekt variant af et let verbum, f.eks. "tage på gæld" vs. "have gæld", er hyppige i tekster, men ofte vanskelige at klassificere mellem verbale idiomer, lette verbekonstruktioner eller kompositionssætninger. Vi undersøger egenskaberne af sådanne udtryk med et omtvistet medlemskab og foreslår et udvalg af funktioner, der bestemmer mere tilfredsstillende grænser mellem de tre kategorier i denne zone, og tildeler udtrykkene til en af dem.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Uitdrukkingen met een aspectuele variant van een licht werkwoord, bijvoorbeeld 'neem schuld' vs. 'heb schuld', komen vaak voor in teksten, maar vaak moeilijk te classificeren tussen verbale idiomen, lichte werkwoordenconstructies of compositiezinnen. We onderzoeken de eigenschappen van dergelijke uitdrukkingen met een betwiste lidmaatschap en stellen een selectie van kenmerken voor die bevredigendere grenzen tussen de drie categorieën in deze zone bepalen, waarbij de uitdrukkingen aan een van hen worden toegewezen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Ausdrücke mit einer aspektuellen Variante eines leichten Verbs, z.B. "Schuld annehmen" vs. "Schuld haben", sind in Texten häufig anzutreffen, aber oft schwierig zwischen verbalen Idiomen, leichten Verbkonstruktionen oder kompositorischen Phrasen einzuordnen. Wir untersuchen die Eigenschaften solcher Ausdrücke mit einer umstrittenen Mitgliedschaft und schlagen eine Auswahl von Merkmalen vor, die zufriedenstellendere Grenzen zwischen den drei Kategorien in dieser Zone bestimmen und die Ausdrücke einer von ihnen zuordnen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>경동사체 변체를 가진 표현, 예를 들어'채무를 부담한다'와'채무를 가진다'는 것은 텍스트에서 흔히 볼 수 있지만 동사 습어, 경동사 구조나 조합단어 사이에서 분류하기 어렵다.우리는 이러한 논쟁 구성원 자격을 가진 표현식의 성격을 연구했고 일련의 특징을 제시하여 이 지역의 세 가지 유형 사이의 더욱 만족스러운 경계를 확정하고 표현식을 그 중의 한 유형에 지정했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>واژه‌هایی با یک گونه‌ای منحصری از یک گونه‌ای نور، مثال „بدهی را قبول کنید » با „بدهی داشته باشند، اغلب در متن‌ها معمول می‌شوند، اما اغلب مشکل است که بین احمق‌های زبان، ساختن گونه‌های نور یا جمله‌های ترکیب باشند. ما ویژگی‌های چنین مثالها را با یک عضو مجادله تحقیق می‌کنیم و یک انتخاب ویژه‌ای را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم که مرزهای راحت‌کننده‌تر بین سه گروه در این منطقه تعیین می‌کنند، به یکی از آنها تعیین می‌کنند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_id>Ekspresi dengan varian aspektual dari verb ringan, misalnya 'mengambil hutang' vs. 'memiliki hutang', sering dalam teks tetapi sering sulit untuk diklasifikasi antara idiom verbal, konstruksi verb ringan atau frasa komposisi. Kami menyelidiki properti ekspresi-ekspresi seperti ini dengan anggota yang membantah dan mengusulkan seleksi fitur yang menentukan batas yang lebih memuaskan antara tiga kategori di zona ini, menyerahkan ekspresi kepada salah satu dari mereka.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Expressions with an aspectual variant of a light verb, e.g. `take on debt' vs. `have debt', are frequent in texts but often difficult to classify between verbal idioms, light verb constructions or compositional phrases.  Tunatachunguza utaratibu wa hisia hizi kwa wanachama wenye utata na tunapendekeza uchaguzi wa vipengele vinavyotambua mipaka mitatu yenye furaha kati ya makundi matatu katika eneo hili, na kutoa maoni kwa mmoja wao.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Uitdrukkings met 'n aspektuale variant van 'n ligte verb, bv. `neem op skuld' vs. `het skuld', is dikwels in tekste, maar dikwels moeilik moeilik om tussen verbal e idioms, ligte verb konstruksies of komposisielle frase te klassifiseer. Ons ondersoek die eienskappe van sodanige uitdrukkings met 'n stryd gemeenskap en voorstel 'n keuse van funksies wat meer verstandige grense bepaal tussen die drie kategorie in hierdie sone, en die uitdrukkings aan een van hulle toewys.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Iňlik wersiýasynyň aspektualy warianaty bilen, myselm. `borçly' we ''borçly' sözleriň için e köplenç tekstlerde, we köplenç verbal dilleriň arasynda klasifik etmek kyn, reňk wersiýa düzenlemekleri ýa-da kompozisýol sözleriň arasynda g e çirmek kyn. Biz beýleki ifadeleriň häsiýetlerini mübahisə edip, bu bölgedeki üç kategoriýanyň arasynda nähili howply sınırlaryny belirleýän özellikleri saýlamaga teklip edýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Shprehjet me një variant aspektual të një verbi të lehtë, për shembull "marrë borxh" vs. "të ketë borxh", janë të shpeshta në tekste por shpesh të vështira për të klasifikuar midis idiomave verbal e, ndërtimit të verb ëve të lehtë apo frazave kompozitive. Ne hetojmë pronat e shprehjeve të tilla me një anëtarësim të diskutuar dhe propozojmë një zgjedhje elementesh që përcaktojnë kufij më të kënaqshëm midis tre kategorive në këtë zonë, duke i caktuar shprehjet një prej tyre.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>በጽሑፎች ላይ የሚቆጠሩ እና በብርሃን ቃላት የተለየ ምሳሌ ‹ዕዳ› እና ዕዳ አለባቸው፡፡ እንደነዚህ የንግግር ግንኙነትን በተጨቃጨ አባል እናሳውቃለን፡፡ እና በሦስቱ ክፍሎች መካከል የሚደሰቅ ድንበርን እናስፈልጋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Առաջական բայի ասպեկտուալ տարբերակով արտահայտությունները, օրինակ, "վերցնել պարտքը" և "ունենալ պարտք", հաճախ հաճախ են տեքստներում, բայց հաճախ դժվար է դասակարգել խոսնական իմաստների, թեթև բայերի կառուցվածքների կամ բաղադրական արտահայտությունների միջև: Մենք ուսումնասիրում ենք նման արտահայտությունների հատկությունները վիճելի անդամներով և առաջարկում ենք հատկությունների ընտրություն, որոնք որոշում են ավելի բավարար սահմաններ այս շրջանում գտնվող երեք կատեգորիաների միջև, դրանցից մեկին վերագրելով արտահայտությունները:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Işıq sözlərin aspekti variyası olan ifadələr, məsələn, `borc' vs. `borc' yazılır, sözlərdə çox sıxıntıdır, lakin çox sıxıntılar verbal idiomlar arasında, yüngül verb in şalları və müxtəlif sözlər arasında ayırmaq çətindir. Biz bu ifadələrin xüsusiyyətlərini mübahisə edib, bu bölgedə üç kategoriyanın arasındakı daha müfəssəl sınırlarını belə təklif edirik, bu ifadələri birinə vermək üçün təklif edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_cs>Výrazy s aspektuální variantou lehkého slovesa, např. "přijmout dluh" vs. "mít dluh", jsou v textech časté, ale často obtížně rozlišitelné mezi verbální idiomy, lehké slovesové konstrukce nebo kompoziční fráze. Zkoumáme vlastnosti těchto výrazů se sporným členstvím a navrhujeme výběr vlastností, které určují uspokojivější hranice mezi třemi kategoriemi v této zóně, přiřazením výrazů k jedné z nich.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_bs>Izrazi s aspektualnom varijantom svetlog verb a, npr. „uzimanje duga“ protiv „imaju dug“, često su u tekstima, ali često je teško klasifikirati između verbalnih idioma, laganih verbalnih konstrukcija ili kompozicionalnih fraza. Istražujemo vlasništvo takvih izraza sa spornim članstvom i predlažemo izbor karakteristika koji određuju zadovoljavajuće granice između tri kategorije u ovoj zoni, dodajući izraze jednom od njih.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Expressions with an aspectual variant of a light verb, e.g. `take on debt' vs. `have debt', are frequent in texts but often difficult to classify between verbal idioms, light verb constructions or compositional phrases.  Investiguem les propietats d'aquestes expressions amb un membre controvertit i proposem una selecció de característiques que determinin límits més satisfaccionants entre les tres categories d'aquesta zona, asignant les expressions a una d'elles.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bn>লাইট ভার্বের বিভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন ভিন্ন মন্তব্য, যেমন 'ঋণের উপর নিয়ে নেয়' এবং 'ঋণ আছে' লেখায় প্রায়শই লেখা হয়, কিন্তু প্রায়শই বাজে গাধার বোকা, আলো ভার্ব নির্মাণ অথব আমরা এই ধরনের প্রকাশের বৈশিষ্ট্য তদন্ত করি এক বিতর্কিত সদস্যের সাথে এবং এই অঞ্চলের তিনটি বিভাগের মধ্যে আরো সন্তুষ্ট সীমানা নির্ধারণ করার প্রস্তাব করি, যারা</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_fi>Kevytverbin aspektiaalisen muunnoksen omaavat ilmaisut, esim. "velkaantuminen" vs. "velkaantuminen", ovat usein teksteissä yleisiä, mutta niitä on usein vaikea luokitella sanallisten idiomien, kevyiden verbirakenteiden tai sävellyslauseiden välillä. Tutkimme tällaisten ilmaisujen ominaisuuksia kiistanalaisella jäsenyydellä ja ehdotamme valikoimia ominaisuuksia, jotka määrittävät tyydyttävämmät rajat kolmen luokan välillä tällä alueella, osoittaen ilmaisut yhteen niistä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Väljendid, millel on kerge tegusõna aspektaalne variant, nt "võta võlg" vs. "omada võlgu", on tekstides sagedased, kuid sageli raske klassifitseerida sõnaliste idioomide, kergete tegusõnaliste konstruktsioonide või kompositsioonifraaside vahel. Uurime selliste väljendite omadusi vaidlustatud liikmelisusega ja pakume välja valiku omadusi, mis määravad rahuldavamad piirid kolme kategooria vahel selles tsoonis, määrates väljendid ühele neist.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>EMAIL OF TRANSLATORS Awak dhéwé nyongcah perusahaan karo akeh pisan karo perusahaan karo nganggep kanggo langgar nganggo cah dumadhi iki éwé iso nggawe perusahaan karo perusahaan karo kategori sing katêpakan karo kategori sing dumadhi iki, nggawe ngubah winih dhéwé</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>ביטויים עם שונה ספקטיבית של verb קל, למשל "לקחת על חוב" נגד "יש חוב", הם לעתים קרובות בטקסטים אבל לעתים קרובות קשים להקליף בין אידיומים מילוליים, בניית verbs קלים או ביטויים מורכבים. אנו חוקרים את תכונות הבטאות האלה עם חברות מתווכחת ומציעים בחירה של תכונות שמקביעים גבולות מרוצים יותר בין שלושת הקטגוריות באזור הזה, ומסימנים את הבטאות לאחד מהם.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Izrazi z aspektualno različico lahkega glagola, npr. "prevzemi dolg" in "imaš dolg", so pogosti v besedilih, vendar jih je pogosto težko razvrstiti med verbalnimi idiomi, lahkimi glagolnimi konstrukcijami ali kompozicijskimi frazami. Raziskujemo lastnosti takih izrazov z izpodbijanim članstvom in predlagamo izbor značilnosti, ki določajo zadovoljivejše meje med tremi kategorijami v tem območju, pri čemer jih dodelimo eni izmed njih.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Expressions with an aspectual variant of a light verb, e.g. `take on debt' vs. `have debt', are frequent in texts but often difficult to classify between verbal idioms, light verb constructions or compositional phrases.  Haƙĩƙa, Munã jãyayya properties of such magana da yana mai husũma kuma Munã buɗa zaɓen wasu mistakardu wanda ke iya ƙayyade tsakanin nau'i uku cikin wannan zone, kuma yana gayya ga bayani ga ɗayansu.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>གསལ་བརྗོད་ཀྱི་ཆོས་ཉིད་ཅིག་གི་དབྱེ་རིམ་ཅིག་དང་མཉམ་དུ་དགོས་པ་མིན། ང་ཚོས་དུས་འགའ་ཅན་གྱི་ངོ་བོའི་བརྗོད་ཀྱི་ངོ་བོ</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Data-driven Identification of Idioms in Song Lyrics</title>
      <author><first>Miriam</first><last>Amin</last></author>
      <author><first>Peter</first><last>Fankhauser</last></author>
      <author><first>Marc</first><last>Kupietz</last></author>
      <author><first>Roman</first><last>Schneider</last></author>
      <pages>13–22</pages>
      <abstract>The automatic recognition of idioms poses a challenging problem for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP applications</a>. Whereas <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_language">native speakers</a> can intuitively handle multiword expressions whose compositional meanings are hard to trace back to individual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">word semantics</a>, there is still ample scope for improvement regarding computational approaches. We assume that idiomatic constructions can be characterized by gradual intensities of semantic non-compositionality, formal fixedness, and unusual usage context, and introduce a number of measures for these characteristics, comprising count-based and predictive collocation measures together with measures of context (un)similarity. We evaluate our approach on a manually labelled gold standard, derived from a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus of German pop lyrics</a>. To this end, we apply a Random Forest classifier to analyze the individual contribution of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> for automatically detecting idioms, and study the trade-off between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_(computer_science)">precision</a>. Finally, we evaluate the classifier on an independent dataset of idioms extracted from a list of Wikipedia idioms, achieving state-of-the art accuracy.</abstract>
      <url hash="04e3aa89">2021.mwe-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.mwe-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>amin-etal-2021-data</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>PIE : A Parallel Idiomatic Expression Corpus for Idiomatic Sentence Generation and Paraphrasing<fixed-case>PIE</fixed-case>: A Parallel Idiomatic Expression Corpus for Idiomatic Sentence Generation and Paraphrasing</title>
      <author><first>Jianing</first><last>Zhou</last></author>
      <author><first>Hongyu</first><last>Gong</last></author>
      <author><first>Suma</first><last>Bhat</last></author>
      <pages>33–48</pages>
      <abstract>Idiomatic expressions (IE) play an important role in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language">natural language</a>, and have long been a pain in the neck for NLP systems. Despite this, text generation tasks related to IEs remain largely under-explored. In this paper, we propose two new tasks of idiomatic sentence generation and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paraphrase">paraphrasing</a> to fill this research gap. We introduce a curated dataset of 823 IEs, and a parallel corpus with sentences containing them and the same sentences where the IEs were replaced by their literal paraphrases as the primary resource for our tasks. We benchmark existing deep learning models, which have state-of-the-art performance on related tasks using automated and manual evaluation with our dataset to inspire further research on our proposed tasks. By establishing baseline models, we pave the way for more comprehensive and accurate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_simulation">modeling</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_circuit">IEs</a>, both for generation and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paraphrase">paraphrasing</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="196aa6f7">2021.mwe-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.mwe-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>zhou-etal-2021-pie</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wikilarge">WikiLarge</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Lexical Semantic Recognition</title>
      <author><first>Nelson F.</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Hershcovich</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Kranzlein</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathan</first><last>Schneider</last></author>
      <pages>49–56</pages>
      <abstract>In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_semantics">lexical semantics</a>, full-sentence segmentation and segment labeling of various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phenomenon">phenomena</a> are generally treated separately, despite their interdependence. We hypothesize that a unified lexical semantic recognition task is an effective way to encapsulate previously disparate styles of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annotation">annotation</a>, including multiword expression identification / classification and supersense tagging. Using the STREUSLE corpus, we train a neural CRF sequence tagger and evaluate its performance along various axes of annotation. As the label set generalizes that of previous tasks (PARSEME, DiMSUM), we additionally evaluate how well the model generalizes to those test sets, finding that it approaches or surpasses existing models despite training only on STREUSLE. Our work also establishes <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baseline models</a> and evaluation metrics for integrated and accurate modeling of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_semantics">lexical semantics</a>, facilitating future work in this area.</abstract>
      <url hash="220c2f48">2021.mwe-1.6</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="132180d7">2021.mwe-1.6.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.mwe-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>liu-etal-2021-lexical</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/nert-nlp/streusle" additional="true">nert-nlp/streusle</pwccode>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>