<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.sigmorphon">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 18th SIGMORPHON Workshop on Computational Research in Phonetics, Phonology, and Morphology</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Garrett</first><last>Nicolai</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kyle</first><last>Gorman</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ryan</first><last>Cotterell</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="872e9305">2021.sigmorphon-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="620a81ae">2021.sigmorphon-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sigmorphon-2021-sigmorphon</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Recursive prosody is not finite-state</title>
      <author><first>Hossep</first><last>Dolatian</last></author>
      <author><first>Aniello</first><last>De Santo</last></author>
      <author><first>Thomas</first><last>Graf</last></author>
      <pages>11–22</pages>
      <abstract>This paper investigates bounds on the generative capacity of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prosody_(linguistics)">prosodic processes</a>, by focusing on the complexity of recursive prosody in coordination contexts in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> (Wagner, 2010). Although all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phonology">phonological processes</a> and most <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prosody_(linguistics)">prosodic processes</a> are computationally regular string languages, we show that recursive prosody is not. The output string language is instead parallel multiple context-free (Seki et al., 1991). We evaluate the complexity of the pattern over strings, and then move on to a characterization over <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tree_(graph_theory)">trees</a> that requires the expressivity of multi bottom-up tree transducers. In doing so, we provide a foundation for future mathematically grounded investigations of the syntax-prosody interface.</abstract>
      <url hash="cdaa26e5">2021.sigmorphon-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigmorphon-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>dolatian-etal-2021-recursive</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>The Match-Extend serialization algorithm in Multiprecedence</title>
      <author><first>Maxime</first><last>Papillon</last></author>
      <pages>23–31</pages>
      <abstract>Raimy (1999 ; 2000a ; 2000b) proposed a graphical formalism for modeling <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reduplication">reduplication</a>, originallymostly focused on phonological overapplication in a derivational framework. This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_framework">framework</a> is now known as Precedence-based phonology or Multiprecedence phonology. Raimy’s idea is that the segments at the input to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phonology">phonology</a> are not totally ordered by precedence. This paper tackles a challenge that arose with Raimy’s work, the development of a deterministic serialization algorithm as part of the derivation of surface forms. The Match-Extend algorithm introduced here requires fewer assumptions and sticks tighter to the attested typology. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a> also contains no parameter or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constraint_(mathematics)">constraint</a> specific to individual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(discrete_mathematics)">graphs</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Topological_space">topologies</a>, unlike previous proposals. Match-Extend requires nothing except knowing the last added set of links.</abstract>
      <url hash="ceeb3a26">2021.sigmorphon-1.3</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="776b6b1f">2021.sigmorphon-1.3.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigmorphon-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>papillon-2021-match</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>A Study of Morphological Robustness of Neural Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Sai Muralidhar</first><last>Jayanthi</last></author>
      <author><first>Adithya</first><last>Pratapa</last></author>
      <pages>49–59</pages>
      <abstract>In this work, we analyze the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robustness_(computer_science)">robustness</a> of neural machine translation systems towards grammatical perturbations in the source. In particular, we focus on morphological inflection related perturbations. While this has been recently studied for EnglishFrench (MORPHEUS) (Tan et al., 2020), it is unclear how this extends to AnyEnglish translation systems. We propose MORPHEUS-MULTILINGUAL that utilizes UniMorph dictionaries to identify morphological perturbations to source that adversely affect the translation models. Along with an analysis of state-of-the-art pretrained MT systems, we train and analyze systems for 11 language pairs using the multilingual TED corpus (Qi et al., 2018). We also compare this to actual errors of non-native speakers using Grammatical Error Correction datasets. Finally, we present a qualitative and quantitative analysis of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robustness_(computer_science)">robustness</a> of AnyEnglish translation systems.</abstract>
      <url hash="f9b65799">2021.sigmorphon-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigmorphon-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>jayanthi-pratapa-2021-study</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/murali1996/morpheus_multilingual" additional="false">murali1996/morpheus_multilingual</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Sample-efficient Linguistic Generalizations through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Program_synthesis">Program Synthesis</a> : Experiments with Phonology Problems</title>
      <author><first>Saujas</first><last>Vaduguru</last></author>
      <author><first>Aalok</first><last>Sathe</last></author>
      <author><first>Monojit</first><last>Choudhury</last></author>
      <author><first>Dipti</first><last>Sharma</last></author>
      <pages>60–71</pages>
      <abstract>Neural models excel at extracting statistical patterns from large amounts of data, but struggle to learn <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattern">patterns</a> or reason about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language">language</a> from only a few examples. In this paper, we ask : Can we learn explicit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rule_of_inference">rules</a> that generalize well from only a few examples? We explore this question using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Program_synthesis">program synthesis</a>. We develop a synthesis model to learn <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phonology">phonology rules</a> as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_program">programs</a> in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain-specific_language">domain-specific language</a>. We test the ability of our models to generalize from few training examples using our new dataset of problems from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Linguistic_Olympiad">Linguistics Olympiad</a>, a challenging set of tasks that require strong linguistic reasoning ability. In addition to being highly sample-efficient, our approach generates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human-readable_medium">human-readable programs</a>, and allows control over the generalizability of the learnt programs.</abstract>
      <url hash="2e4fd440">2021.sigmorphon-1.7</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigmorphon-1.7</doi>
      <bibkey>vaduguru-etal-2021-sample</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/saujasv/phonological-generalizations" additional="false">saujasv/phonological-generalizations</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>Adaptor Grammars for Unsupervised Paradigm Clustering<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>daptor <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>rammars for Unsupervised Paradigm Clustering</title>
      <author><first>Kate</first><last>McCurdy</last></author>
      <author><first>Sharon</first><last>Goldwater</last></author>
      <author><first>Adam</first><last>Lopez</last></author>
      <pages>82–89</pages>
      <abstract>This work describes the Edinburgh submission to the SIGMORPHON 2021 Shared Task 2 on unsupervised morphological paradigm clustering. Given raw text input, the task was to assign each token to a cluster with other tokens from the same paradigm. We use Adaptor Grammar segmentations combined with frequency-based heuristics to predict paradigm clusters. Our system achieved the highest average F1 score across 9 test languages, placing first out of 15 submissions.</abstract>
      <url hash="14af72d0">2021.sigmorphon-1.9</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigmorphon-1.9</doi>
      <bibkey>mccurdy-etal-2021-adaptor</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="17">
      <title>CLUZH at SIGMORPHON 2021 Shared Task on Multilingual Grapheme-to-Phoneme Conversion : Variations on a Baseline<fixed-case>CLUZH</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>SIGMORPHON</fixed-case> 2021 Shared Task on Multilingual Grapheme-to-Phoneme Conversion: Variations on a Baseline</title>
      <author><first>Simon</first><last>Clematide</last></author>
      <author><first>Peter</first><last>Makarov</last></author>
      <pages>148–153</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the submission by the team from the Department of Computational Linguistics, Zurich University, to the Multilingual Grapheme-to-Phoneme Conversion (G2P) Task 1 of the SIGMORPHON 2021 challenge in the low and medium settings. The submission is a variation of our 2020 G2P system, which serves as the baseline for this year’s challenge. The system is a neural transducer that operates over explicit edit actions and is trained with imitation learning. For this challenge, we experimented with the following changes : a) emitting phoneme segments instead of single character phonemes, b) input character dropout, c) a mogrifier LSTM decoder (Melis et al., 2019), d) enriching the decoder input with the currently attended input character, e) parallel BiLSTM encoders, and f) an adaptive batch size scheduler. In the low setting, our best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ensemble_cast">ensemble</a> improved over the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(medicine)">baseline</a>, however, in the medium setting, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(medicine)">baseline</a> was stronger on average, although for certain languages improvements could be observed.</abstract>
      <url hash="2f4238ab">2021.sigmorphon-1.17</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigmorphon-1.17</doi>
      <bibkey>clematide-makarov-2021-cluzh</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Recognizing Reduplicated Forms : Finite-State Buffered Machines</title>
      <author><first>Yang</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <pages>177–187</pages>
      <abstract>Total reduplication is common in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phonology">natural language phonology</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morphology_(linguistics)">morphology</a>. However, formally as copying on reduplicants of unbounded size, unrestricted total reduplication requires computational power beyond context-free, while other phonological and morphological patterns are regular, or even sub-regular. Thus, existing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class_(computer_programming)">language classes</a> characterizing reduplicated strings inevitably include typologically unattested context-free patterns, such as reversals. This paper extends <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_language">regular languages</a> to incorporate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reduplication">reduplication</a> by introducing a new computational device : finite state buffered machine (FSBMs). We give its mathematical definitions and discuss some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closure_(mathematics)">closure properties</a> of the corresponding set of languages. As a result, the class of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_language">regular languages</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_language">languages</a> derived from them through a copying mechanism is characterized. Suggested by previous literature, this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class_(set_theory)">class of languages</a> should approach the characterization of natural language word sets.</abstract>
      <url hash="6b070b36">2021.sigmorphon-1.20</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigmorphon-1.20</doi>
      <bibkey>wang-2021-recognizing</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Reconhecendo formas reduplicadas: máquinas em buffer de estado finito</title_pt>
      <title_ar>التعرف على الأشكال المكررة: الآلات المخزنة ذات الحالة المحدودة</title_ar>
      <title_es>Reconocimiento de formularios reduplicados: máquinas almacenadas en búfer de estado finito</title_es>
      <title_ja>重複フォームの認識:有限状態バッファリングマシン</title_ja>
      <title_zh>识复:有限缓冲机</title_zh>
      <title_hi>Reduplicated प्रपत्रों को पहचानना: परिमित-राज्य बफ़र्ड मशीनें</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Foirmeacha Athdhúblacha a Aithint: Meaisíní Maoláin de chuid an Staid Mhinid</title_ga>
      <title_ka>განახლებული ფორმები: Finite- State Buffered Machines</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Az ismételt formák felismerése: Véges állapotú puffergépek</title_hu>
      <title_el>Αναγνώριση των μειωμένων μορφών: Αποθηκευμένες μηχανές τελικής κατάστασης</title_el>
      <title_it>Riconoscimento delle forme ridisplicate: macchine tamponate a stato finito</title_it>
      <title_kk>Қайта жүктелген пішіндерді анықтау: Finite- state Buffered Machines</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Mengenal Bentuk Dilipat Semula: Mesin Penimbal Keadaan-Finite</title_ms>
      <title_lt>Perdubliuotų formų pripažinimas: Finitinės valstybės buferinės mašinos</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Recognizing Reduplicated Forms: Finite-State Buffered Machines</title_mk>
      <title_mt>Ir-Rikonoxximent ta’ Formoli Reduplikati: Magni Buffered mill-Istat Finit</title_mt>
      <title_no>Kjenner omkopierte skjemar: Finite- tilstandsbuffererte maskiner</title_no>
      <title_ml>ചുരുക്കിയ ഫോമുകള്‍ തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നു: ഫൈനിറ്റ്- സ്റ്റേറ്റ് ബുഫര്‍ മെഷീനുകള്‍</title_ml>
      <title_mn>Дахин хуваалцагдсан хэлбэрүүдийг таних: Финит-штат буфер машинууд</title_mn>
      <title_ro>Recunoașterea formelor Reduplicate: Mașini tamponate cu stări finite</title_ro>
      <title_pl>Rozpoznawanie zredukowanych form: maszyny buforowane w stanie końcowym</title_pl>
      <title_sr>Prepoznajući preusmjerene oblike: Finite-State Buffered Machines</title_sr>
      <title_si>ආයුත් පිළිපිළිත ප්‍රකාරය අඳුරගන්න: Finite- state Buffered EnginesNAME OF TRANSLATORS</title_si>
      <title_so>Aqoonsashada foomka lagu saxeeyey: Finite-State Buffered Mashines</title_so>
      <title_sv>Erkännande av omfördelade formulär: buffertmaskiner med sluttillstånd</title_sv>
      <title_ur>دوبارہ ڈبلیکل کی فرموں کی پہچان کی جاتی ہے: فینیٹ- سٹیٹ بافرد ماشین</title_ur>
      <title_ta>சிறிதாக்கப்பட்ட வடிவங்களை அறியப்படுகிறது: Finite- State Buffered machines</title_ta>
      <title_vi>KCharselect unicode block name</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Qisqacha formatlarni aniqlash: Finite- State Buffered Mashines</title_uz>
      <title_nl>Recognition Reduplicated Forms: Finite-State Buffered Machines</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Prepoznajući preusmjerene oblike: Finite-državne buferne mašine</title_hr>
      <title_de>Reduplizierte Formen erkennen: Finite-State Puffered Machines</title_de>
      <title_id>Mengenali Formula Diduplikasi ulang: Mesin Buffered State-Finite</title_id>
      <title_bg>Разпознаване на повторени форми: Финитни буферирани машини</title_bg>
      <title_da>Genkendelse af omdoblerede formularer: Finiste State Buffered Machines</title_da>
      <title_fa>شناسایی فرم‌های دوباره‌پوشیده شده: ماشین‌های ساخته‌شده‌ی ایالت فنی</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Kutambua Mifumo Mipya: Mashine yaliyotengenezwa na Taifa</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Taýlanan Faýllar</title_tr>
      <title_af>Herkenning Herkoppelde Forme: Finite- State Buffered Machines</title_af>
      <title_sq>Njohja e Formave të Rikopjuara: Makinat e Shtetit Finite</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Հետաբազմապատկված ձևեր ճանաչելը. ֆինիտալ-պետական բեռնեցված մեքենաներ</title_hy>
      <title_am>Finite-State Buffered Machines</title_am>
      <title_az>奥湩擉饮⁋쎶쎧쎼狃뱬淃볅鼠얞敫楬泉饲椠瑡滄녭愺⁆楮楴攭却慴攠䉵晦敲敤⁍慣桩湥猊</title_az>
      <title_bn>ফাইনাইট- রাষ্ট্রের বাফারের মেশিন</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Prepoznajući preusmjerene oblike: Finite-State Buffered Machines</title_bs>
      <title_ko>식별 중첩 형식: 유한 상태 버퍼</title_ko>
      <title_ca>Recognir formes rediplicades: màquines buffetades d'estat finit</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Rozpoznávání redukovaných formulářů: vyrovnané stroje s konečným stavem</title_cs>
      <title_et>Ümberpaigutatud vormide äratundmine: lõpliku seisundiga puhverdatud masinad</title_et>
      <title_fi>Uudelleenjulkaisujen muotojen tunnistaminen: Finite-State Puskuroidut koneet</title_fi>
      <title_he>Recognizing Reduplicated Forms: Finite-State Buffered Machines</title_he>
      <title_ha>Finite-State Buffled Machines</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Prepoznavanje ponovno dodeljenih obrazcev: Finite-State Buffered Stroji</title_sk>
      <title_jv>Layout</title_jv>
      <title_bo>བསྐྱར་འདྲ་བཤུ་བྱས་པའི་དབྱིབས་རིགས་ལ་རྟོགས་བཞིན། མཛེས་ཁང་དང་གནས་སྟངས་ཀྱིས་བཏང་བྱས་པའི་སྒྲིག་ཆས</title_bo>
      <abstract_es>La reduplicación total es común en la fonología y morfología del lenguaje natural. Sin embargo, formalmente como copia en reduplicantes de tamaño ilimitado, la reduplicación total sin restricciones requiere una potencia computacional más allá de la libre de contexto, mientras que otros patrones fonológicos y morfológicos son regulares o incluso subregulares. Por lo tanto, las clases de lenguaje existentes que caracterizan cadenas reduplicadas incluyen inevitablemente patrones tipológicamente no comprobados sin contexto, como reversiones. Este documento amplía los idiomas habituales para incorporar la reduplicación mediante la introducción de un nuevo dispositivo computacional: máquinas con búfer de estado finito (FSBM). Damos sus definiciones matemáticas y discutimos algunas propiedades de cierre del conjunto de lenguajes correspondiente. Como resultado, se caracteriza la clase de idiomas regulares y los idiomas derivados de ellos a través de un mecanismo de copia. Sugerido por la literatura anterior, esta clase de idiomas debe abordar la caracterización de los conjuntos de palabras de lenguaje natural.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ar>المضاعفة الكلية شائعة في علم الأصوات والتشكل في اللغة الطبيعية. ومع ذلك ، بشكل رسمي كنسخ على النسخ المكررة ذات الحجم غير المحدود ، تتطلب المضاعفة الكلية غير المقيدة قوة حسابية تتجاوز السياق ، في حين أن الأنماط الصوتية والمورفولوجية الأخرى منتظمة ، أو حتى شبه منتظمة. وبالتالي ، فإن فئات اللغة الحالية التي تميز السلاسل المعاد تكرارها تتضمن حتمًا أنماطًا خالية من السياق غير مدرجة بشكل نمطي ، مثل الانعكاسات. توسع هذه الورقة اللغات العادية لتضمين النسخ المكرر من خلال تقديم جهاز حسابي جديد: آلة مخزنة ذات حالة محدودة (FSBMs). نعطي تعريفاته الرياضية ونناقش بعض خصائص الإغلاق لمجموعة اللغات المقابلة. نتيجة لذلك ، يتم تمييز فئة اللغات العادية واللغات المشتقة منها من خلال آلية النسخ. يجب أن تقترب هذه الفئة من اللغات ، التي اقترحتها الأدبيات السابقة ، من توصيف مجموعات كلمات اللغة الطبيعية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>A reduplicação total é comum na fonologia e morfologia da linguagem natural. No entanto, formalmente como cópia em reduplicantes de tamanho ilimitado, a reduplicação total irrestrita requer poder computacional além do contexto livre, enquanto outros padrões fonológicos e morfológicos são regulares, ou até mesmo sub-regulares. Assim, as classes de linguagem existentes que caracterizam strings reduplicadas inevitavelmente incluem padrões livres de contexto não atestados tipologicamente, como reversões. Este artigo estende as linguagens regulares para incorporar a reduplicação, introduzindo um novo dispositivo computacional: finite state buffered machine (FSBMs). Damos suas definições matemáticas e discutimos algumas propriedades de fechamento do conjunto correspondente de linguagens. Como resultado, caracteriza-se a classe de linguagens regulares e linguagens derivadas delas por meio de um mecanismo de cópia. Sugerida pela literatura anterior, esta classe de linguagens deve abordar a caracterização de conjuntos de palavras de linguagem natural.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>全繰り返しは自然言語音韻論や形態論で一般的である。しかしながら、形式的には、無制限のサイズの冗長体上でのコピーと同様に、無制限の全冗長化は、文脈自由を超えた計算能力を必要とし、他の音声学的および形態学的パターンは、規則的、またはサブ規則的である。したがって、重複した文字列を特徴付ける既存の言語クラスは、必然的に、逆転などの、類型的に認定されていない文脈自由パターンを含む。本論文では、有限状態緩衝機械（ FSBM ）という新しい計算装置を導入することで、正規言語を拡張して冗長化を取り入れている。その数学的定義を与え、対応する言語の集合のいくつかの閉じた性質について議論します。その結果、コピー機構を通じて正規言語とそこから派生した言語のクラスが特徴づけられる。以前の文献から示唆されているように、このクラスの言語は、自然言語の単語セットの特徴付けに近づくべきである。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>全复在自然语言语音学及形态学中常见。 然则以文为无界大小重复词复制,无限者辄重复越上下文之计算能力,而音形法则,甚至次之。 是以表征重复字符串见语言之类,不免于备类型学上未证者上下文无关模式,例如反转。 本文引新算设备:有限缓冲机(FSBM)以广常言以并复。 与其数学定义,并论其应语集者闭包属性。 故常语之类,因复制而生之。 据前文献,此语宜近自然语言词集。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>प्राकृतिक भाषा फोनोलॉजी और आकृति विज्ञान में कुल पुनरावृत्ति आम है। हालांकि, औपचारिक रूप से असीमित आकार के reduplicants पर प्रतिलिपि बनाने के रूप में, अप्रतिबंधित कुल पुनरावृत्ति के लिए संदर्भ-मुक्त से परे कम्प्यूटेशनल शक्ति की आवश्यकता होती है, जबकि अन्य ध्वन्यात्मक और रूपात्मक पैटर्न नियमित रूप से, या यहां तक कि उप-नियमित भी होते हैं। इस प्रकार, reduplicated स्ट्रिंग्स की विशेषता वाले मौजूदा भाषा वर्गों में अनिवार्य रूप से टाइपोलॉजिकल रूप से अनाकर्षित संदर्भ-मुक्त पैटर्न शामिल हैं, जैसे कि रिवर्सल। यह पेपर एक नए कम्प्यूटेशनल डिवाइस को पेश करके पुनरावृत्ति को शामिल करने के लिए नियमित भाषाओं का विस्तार करता है: परिमित राज्य बफ़र्ड मशीन (FSBMs)। हम इसकी गणितीय परिभाषाएं देते हैं और भाषाओं के संबंधित सेट के कुछ समापन गुणों पर चर्चा करते हैं। नतीजतन, एक नकल तंत्र के माध्यम से उनसे व्युत्पन्न नियमित भाषाओं और भाषाओं के वर्ग की विशेषता है। पिछले साहित्य द्वारा सुझाया गया, भाषाओं के इस वर्ग को प्राकृतिक भाषा शब्द सेट के लक्षण वर्णन से संपर्क करना चाहिए।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Tá athdhúbláil iomlán coitianta i bhfóineolaíocht agus i mhoirfeolaíocht na teanga nádúrtha. Mar sin féin, go foirmiúil mar chóipeáil ar athdhúblálaithe de mhéid neamhtheoranta, teastaíonn cumhacht ríomhaireachtúil lasmuigh de chomhthéacs gan srian le hathdhúbláil iomlán gan srian, agus bíonn patrúin fóineolaíochta agus moirfeolaíocha eile rialta, nó fiú fo-rialta. Mar sin, i ranganna teanga atá ann cheana féin ina bhfuil teaghráin athdhéanta, tá patrúin tíopeolaíochta saor ó chomhthéacs, amhail aisiompuithe san áireamh i ranganna teanga atá ann cheana féin. Síneann an páipéar seo teangacha rialta chun athdhúbláil a ionchorprú trí fheiste ríomhaireachtúil nua a thabhairt isteach: meaisín maoláin le staid chríochnaithe (FSBManna). Tugaimid a sainmhínithe matamaiticiúla agus pléimid roinnt airíonna dúnta na sraithe teangacha comhfhreagracha. Mar thoradh air sin, tréithrítear aicme na dteangacha rialta agus na dteangacha a dhíorthaítear uathu trí mheicníocht chóipeála. Mar a mholtar sa litríocht roimhe seo, ba chóir don aicme seo teangacha tabhairt faoi thréithriú tacair focal teanga nádúrtha.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>საერთო განახლება საერთო ენის ფონოლოგიაში და მორფოლოგიაში. მაგრამ, ფორმალურად, როგორც კომპიუალურად უდრიმებული ზომის გადასრულება, უდრიმებული უდრიმებული გადასრულება იჭირდება კომპიუალური ძალია, როგორც სხვა ფონოლოგიური და მოპოროლოგი ასე რომ მსგავსი ენის კლასები, რომლებიც ახალგაზრდა სტრიქტურებული სტრიქტურების შესახებ არ შეიძლება ტიპოლოგიურად უცნობილი კონტექსტური შაბლოები, როგ ეს დოკუტატი განსაზღვრებულ ენების განსაზღვრებით ახალი კომპუტაციალური მოწყობილობას შეყვარებით: დასაზღვრებული სტატური მოწყობილობა (FSBMs). ჩვენ მისი მათემატიკალური განსაზღვრებების და განსაზღვრებით კონფიგურაციის განსაზღვრება. შემდეგ, რეგილური ენების და ენების კლასი, რომელიც მათგანგან გამოიყენებულია კოპორიციის მექანიზმისთვის გამოიყენებული. პირველი ლიტებერტიაში, ეს ენების კლასი უნდა დაახლოებით ნახვა ენის სიტყვების სიტყვების კარაკრატიფიკაციაზე.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>A teljes redukció gyakori a természetes nyelv fonológiájában és morfológiájában. Azonban formálisan, mivel korlátlan méretű reduplikánsokra történő másolás, a korlátlan teljes reduplikáció kontextusmentes számítógépes teljesítményt igényel, míg más fonológiai és morfológiai minták rendszeresek, sőt szubregulárisak. Így a reduplikált karakterláncokat jellemző meglévő nyelvosztályok elkerülhetetlenül tartalmaznak tipológiailag nem tesztelt kontextusmentes mintákat, mint például fordításokat. Ez a tanulmány egy új számítógépes eszköz, a véges állapotú pufferelt gép (FSBM) bevezetésével kiterjeszti a szabályos nyelveket a reduplikáció beépítésére. Megadjuk matematikai definícióit és megvitatjuk a megfelelő nyelvhalmaz zárási tulajdonságait. Ennek eredményeképpen jellemzi a normál nyelvek és nyelvek osztályát, amelyeket egy másolási mechanizmuson keresztül származnak. A korábbi irodalom által javasolt nyelvek ezen osztályának meg kell közelítenie a természetes nyelvű szókészletek jellemzését.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Η συνολική μείωση είναι κοινή στη φωνολογία και μορφολογία της φυσικής γλώσσας. Ωστόσο, τυπικά όπως η αντιγραφή σε αναγωγείς απεριόριστου μεγέθους, η απεριόριστη ολική αναγωγοποίηση απαιτεί υπολογιστική δύναμη πέρα από το περιβάλλον, ενώ άλλα φωνητικά και μορφολογικά μοτίβα είναι τακτικά, ή ακόμη και υπο-τακτικά. Έτσι, οι υπάρχουσες γλωσσικές τάξεις που χαρακτηρίζουν μειωποιημένες συμβολοσειρές αναπόφευκτα περιλαμβάνουν τυπολογικά ανεπιφύλακτα μοτίβα χωρίς πλαίσιο, όπως αντιστροφές. Η παρούσα εργασία επεκτείνει τις κανονικές γλώσσες για να ενσωματώσει την αναγωγή εισάγοντας μια νέα υπολογιστική συσκευή: τη μηχανή με προσωρινή μνήμη πεπερασμένης κατάστασης (FSBM). Δίνουμε τους μαθηματικούς ορισμούς του και συζητάμε κάποιες ιδιότητες κλεισίματος του αντίστοιχου συνόλου γλωσσών. Ως αποτέλεσμα, χαρακτηρίζεται η τάξη των κανονικών γλωσσών και γλωσσών που προέρχονται από αυτές μέσω ενός αντιγραφικού μηχανισμού. Προτείνεται από την προηγούμενη βιβλιογραφία, αυτή η κατηγορία γλωσσών θα πρέπει να προσεγγίσει τον χαρακτηρισμό των συνόλων λέξεων φυσικής γλώσσας.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>La riduzione totale è comune nella fonologia e nella morfologia del linguaggio naturale. Tuttavia, formalmente come copia su reduplicanti di dimensioni illimitate, la riduzione totale senza restrizioni richiede potenza computazionale oltre il contesto libero, mentre altri modelli fonologici e morfologici sono regolari, o addirittura subregolari. Pertanto, le classi linguistiche esistenti che caratterizzano stringhe riduplicate includono inevitabilmente modelli tipologicamente non contestuali, come le inversioni. Questo articolo estende i linguaggi regolari per incorporare la riduzione introducendo un nuovo dispositivo computazionale: macchine buffered a stato finito (FSBM). Diamo le sue definizioni matematiche e discutiamo alcune proprietà di chiusura del corrispondente insieme di lingue. Di conseguenza, si caratterizza la classe di lingue regolari e lingue derivate da esse attraverso un meccanismo di copia. Suggerita dalla letteratura precedente, questa classe di lingue dovrebbe avvicinarsi alla caratterizzazione dei set di parole di linguaggio naturale.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Қайталау жалпы табиғи тіл фологиясы мен морфологиясында жалпы. Бірақ, шектелмеген өлшемдерді қайта көшірмелеу үшін, шектелмеген жалпы қайта көшірмелеу үшін контексті бос емес, басқа фонологиялық және морфологиялық үлгілер үлгілі немесе қайта үлгілі үлгі Бұл үшін, қайта жүктелген жолдарды таңдау тілдер класында типтологиялық үлгілі бос контексті бос үлгілерді, мысалы, қайта жүктелген мәтіндерді көрсетеді. Бұл қағаз жаңа есептеу құрылғысын келтіріп, қайта жүктеу үшін үлгі тілдерді кеңейту үшін кеңейту үшін үлгі тілдерді кеңейту: аяқталған күй- жай буфері Біз оның математикалық анықтамаларын беріп, тілдердің бірнеше жабылу қасиеттерін талқылаймыз. Нәтижесі, көшірмелеу механизмі арқылы олардан шыққан үлгі тілдер мен тілдер класы таңдалады. Алдыңғы әдебиеттің ұсынысы, бұл тілдер класы табиғи тілдер тілдерінің сипаттамасына келеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Visa reduplikacija yra dažna natūralios kalbos fonologijoje ir morfologijoje. Vis dėlto oficialiai kopijuojant neriboto dydžio reduplikantus, neribotam visiškam reduplikacijai reikalinga skaičiavimo galia be konteksto, o kiti fonologiniai ir morfologiniai modeliai yra reguliarūs arba net nereguliarūs. Taigi esamos kalbų klasės, kuriose apibūdinamos dvigubos eilutės, neišvengiamai apima tipologiškai nepatvirtintus konteksto neturinčius modelius, pvz., grįžtamuosius modelius. Šiame dokumente išplečiamos reguliarios kalbos, į kurias įtraukiamas dubliavimas, įvedant naują skaičiavimo prietaisą: ribotos būsenos buferinę mašiną (FSBM). Mes pateikiame jo matematines apibrėžtis ir aptariame kai kurias atitinkamų kalbų rinkinio uždarymo savybes. Todėl apibūdinama iš jų gautų įprastų kalbų ir kalbų klasė naudojant kopijavimo mechanizmą. Remiantis ankstesne literatūra, ši kalbų klasė turėtų būti grindžiama natūralių kalbų žodžių rinkinių apibūdinimu.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mt>It-tnaqqis totali huwa komuni fil-fonoloġija u l-morfoloġija tal-lingwa naturali. Madankollu, formalment bħala kopja fuq reduplikanti ta’ daqs mhux limitat, reduplikazzjoni totali mhux ristretta teħtieġ qawwa komputattiva lil hinn mill-kuntest ħieles, filwaqt li mudelli fonoloġiċi u morfoloġiċi oħra huma regolari, jew saħansitra sottoregolari. Għalhekk, il-klassijiet tal-lingwi eżistenti li jikkaratterizzaw strings reduplikati inevitabbilment jinkludu mudelli tipikament mingħajr kuntest mhux ittestjati, bħal riversjonijiet. Dan id-dokument jestendi l-lingwi regolari biex jinkorpora t-tneħħija ta’ xogħol billi jintroduċi apparat komputattiv ġdid: magna b’riżerva fi stat finit (FSBMs). We give its mathematical definitions and discuss some closure properties of the corresponding set of languages.  B’riżultat ta’ dan, il-klassi ta’ lingwi regolari u lingwi derivati minnhom permezz ta’ mekkaniżmu ta’ kopja hija kkaratterizzata. Suġġerit mil-letteratura preċedenti, din il-klassi ta’ lingwi għandha tilħaq il-karatterizzazzjoni tas-settijiet ta’ kliem tal-lingwa naturali.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mk>Тоталната редупликација е често во природната јазичка фонологија и морфологија. Сепак, официјално како копирање на редупликанти со неограничена големина, неограничена целосна редупликација бара компјутерска моќ надвор од безконтекст, додека другите фонолошки и морфолошки шеми се редовни, или дури и подредовни. Така, постоечките класи на јазик кои карактеризираат раздвојени линии неизбежно вклучуваат типологички неиспитани шаблони без контекст, како што се враќањата. Оваа хартија ги проширува редовните јазици за да вклучи републикација со воведување на нов компјутерски уред: машина со буфер на крајна состојба (FSBMs). Ги даваме своите математички дефиниции и разговараме за некои заклучувачки сопствености на соодветниот набор јазици. Како резултат на тоа, се карактеризира класата на редовни јазици и јазици кои се произведуваат од нив преку механизам за копирање. Предложено од претходната литература, оваа класа на јазици треба да се приближи до карактеризацијата на наборот на природни јазички зборови.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Total reduplication is common in natural language phonology and morphology. Namun, secara rasmi sebagai salinan pada reduplikant saiz tidak terbatas, total reduplikasi tidak terbatas memerlukan kuasa pengiraan melebihi bebas konteks, sementara corak fonologi dan morfologi lain adalah biasa, atau bahkan sub-regular. Oleh itu, kelas bahasa yang wujud yang menggambarkan rentetan bertindak tidak dapat dihindari termasuk corak tanpa konteks yang tidak diuji secara tipologi, seperti pembalikan. Kertas ini memperluas bahasa biasa untuk memasukkan reduplikasi dengan memperkenalkan peranti komputasi baru: mesin penimbal keadaan tertentu (FSBMs). Kami memberikan definisi matematiknya dan membincangkan beberapa ciri-ciri penutupan bagi set bahasa yang sepadan. Sebagai hasilnya, kelas bahasa biasa dan bahasa yang berasal daripadanya melalui mekanisme penyalinan dikarakterisikan. Disarankan oleh literatur terdahulu, kelas bahasa ini patut mendekati keterangan set perkataan bahasa alami.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_no>Totalt gjenoppretting er vanleg i naturspråk- fonologi og morfologi. Men som kopierer på reduksjonar av ungrenserte storleik, krev totalt reduksjonar enn kontekstfri datakraft, mens andre fonologiske og morfologiske mønsterelement er vanleg eller til og med underregulær. Dei eksisterande språkklassar som teiknar gjenopprette strengar, inneheld ikkje noko typologisk uttrykt kontekstfri mønsterelement, som omvendt. Denne papiret utvidar regulære språk for å inkludere gjenoppretting ved å introdusera ein ny datamaskin: avslutta tilstandsbufferd maskin (FSBM). Vi gir matematiske definisjonane sine og diskuterer nokre lukkeeigenskapar for det tilsvarande settet av språk. I resultatet er klassen av regulære språk og språk ut av dei gjennom ein kopimekanisme karakterisert. Førre litteratur må denne klassen av språk næra karakteriseringa av naturspråksordsettet.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ml>സ്വാഭാവികമായ ഭാഷയുടെ ഫോളോളജിയിലും മോര്‍ഫോളജിയിലും മൊത്തം കുറുക്കം സാധാരണമാണ്. എന്നാലും സാധാരണ, അതിരുകളില്ലാത്ത വലിപ്പത്തിന്റെ കുറച്ചുപേരില്‍ പകര്‍ത്തുന്നതിനാല്‍, അസ്ഥിരപ്പെടാത്ത മൊത്തം കുറുക്കം വേണ്ടി കണക്ടിന് ശക്തിയ അതുകൊണ്ട് നിലവിലുള്ള ഭാഷ ക്ലാസുകള്‍ കുറഞ്ഞുപോകുന്ന സ്ട്രിങ്ങുകള്‍ കുറഞ്ഞുപോകുന്നതിനുള്ള അക്ഷരസഞ്ചരിതമാക്കുന ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ പുതിയ കണക്കൂട്ടുണ്ടാക്കുന്ന ഉപകരണത്തിനാല്‍ കുറുക്കം ചേര്‍ക്കാന്‍ സാധാരണ ഭാഷകള്‍ വിശാലമാക്കുന്നു. ഫിനിറ അതിന്റെ ഗണിത വിശദീകരണങ്ങള്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ കൊടുക്കുന്നു. അതിന്റെ പൊരുത്തപ്പെട്ട ഭാഷകളുടെ കൂട്ടത്തില്‍ ചില അട അതിന്റെ ഫലമായി, സാധാരണ ഭാഷകളുടെയും ഭാഷകളുടെയും ക്ലാസില്‍ നിന്നും പകര്‍ത്തുന്ന മെക്കാനിസം ക്രാസ്റ്റ് ചെ മുമ്പുള്ള സാഹിത്യത്താല്‍ ആലോചിക്കപ്പെട്ടിരിക്കുന്നു, സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷയുടെ വാക്കുകളുടെ സ്വഭാവി</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_pl>Całkowita reduplikacja jest powszechna w fonologii i morfologii języka naturalnego. Jednak formalnie jako kopiowanie na reduplikatach o nieograniczonej wielkości, nieograniczona reduplikacja całkowita wymaga mocy obliczeniowej wykraczającej poza kontekst, podczas gdy inne wzorce fonologiczne i morfologiczne są regularne, a nawet subregularne. Tak więc istniejące klasy językowe charakteryzujące reduplikowane ciągi nieuchronnie zawierają typologicznie niezbadane kontekstowe wzorce, takie jak odwrócenia. Niniejszy artykuł rozszerza regularne języki o redukcję poprzez wprowadzenie nowego urządzenia obliczeniowego: maszyny buforowanej w stanie skończonym (FSBM). Podajemy jego definicje matematyczne i omówimy niektóre właściwości zamknięcia odpowiedniego zbioru języków. W rezultacie charakteryzowana jest klasa języków zwykłych i języków pochodzących z nich poprzez mechanizm kopiowania. Sugerowane w poprzedniej literaturze, ta klasa języków powinna podejść do charakterystyki języka naturalnego zbiorów słów.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Байгалийн хэлний фонологи болон морфологи дээр нийтлэг дахин хуваалцах нь ихэвчлэн ихэвчлэн юм. Хязгааргүй хэмжээний дахин хуваалцагчдын хувьд хуулбарлах үед, хязгааргүй нийт дахин хуваалцах нь тооны эрх мэдэл үнэгүй байдлаас гадна хэрэгтэй, бусад фонологик болон морфологик хэлбэрүүд нь хэдий ч,  Иймээс суурилсан хэл хичээлийн хичээл дахин дахин дахин дахин дахин дахин давтагдсан хэлбэрүүдийг тодорхойлж чадахгүй байдлаар байдаг. Энэ цаас шинэ тооцооллын төхөөрөмжийг тайлбарлаж хэвийн хэлнүүдийг дахин хуваалцах гэж нэмэгдүүлдэг: төгсгөл байр суурилсан машин (FSBMs). Бид түүний математикийн тодорхойлолтыг өгч, холбоотой хэл дээр хадгалах тодорхойлолтуудын зарим тодорхойлолтуудыг ярьж байна. Үүний үр дүнд, энгийн хэл болон хэл хэлний хичээл нь хуулбарлах механизмээр гарч ирсэн. Өмнөх уран зохиолынхаа санал болгон, энэ хэл ангид байгалийн хэл хэлний хэлбэрийн харилцааныг ойртох хэрэгтэй.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ro>Reduplarea totală este comună în fonologia și morfologia limbajului natural. Cu toate acestea, formal ca copiere pe reduplicanți de dimensiuni nelimitate, reducerea totală nelimitată necesită putere de calcul dincolo de context, în timp ce alte modele fonologice și morfologice sunt regulate, sau chiar subregulate. Astfel, clasele de limbă existente care caracterizează șirurile reduplicate includ inevitabil modele tipologic neattestate fără context, cum ar fi inversările. Această lucrare extinde limbajele regulate pentru a include reducerea prin introducerea unui nou dispozitiv computațional: mașina tamponată cu stări finite (FSBMs). Oferim definițiile sale matematice și discutăm unele proprietăți de închidere ale setului corespunzător de limbi. Ca urmare, clasa de limbi regulate și limbi derivate din ele printr-un mecanism de copiere este caracterizată. Sugerată de literatura anterioară, această clasă de limbi ar trebui să abordeze caracterizarea seturilor de cuvinte în limbaj natural.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Nusqaamin dhamaantiisu waa mid ku caadi ah luqada dabiicadda ah oo ku qoran foologi iyo morphology. Si kastaba ha ahaatee, si rasmi ah oo koob ka dhigista qiyaastii aan xadeyn, dhamaanka aan la dhigin waxay u baahan tahay xoog xisaab ah oo aan la bilaaban, inta kale qaababka qofka nolojiga iyo morphologiyadu waa mid caadi ah ama xittaa mid hoos-joogta ah. Sidaa darteed fasalka luuqada ah oo ku qoran jaranjarada ay si fudud u leeyihiin waa tusaale ahaan dib loo beddelo. Kanu wuxuu ku fidiyaa luqadaha caadiga ah si uu u qoro koob-dhigista qalabka cusub ee xisaabinta: finite state buffered machine (FSBMs). Waxaannu qoraalka xisaabta ah siinaynaa, waxaana kala sheekaynaa xuquuqda xidhiidhka ah oo luuqadaha la dhigo. Sababtaas darteed fasalka luuqadaha caadiga ah iyo luuqadaha ka soo baxa waxaa lagu qeyb qaataa mekaniisada qoraalka. Fasalkan afka hore ee luqadu waa inay u soo dhowaadaan aqoonta hadalka afka asalka ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sr>Ukupna reduplacija je česta u prirodnoj jezičkoj fonologiji i morfologiji. Međutim, formalno kao kopiranje na redukcijama neograničene veličine, neograničena ukupna redukcija zahteva računalnu moć izvan konteksta bez konteksta, dok su drugi fonološki i morfološki obrasce redovni, ili čak i podredovni. Zato postojeće jezičke klase koje karakteriziraju preusmjerene žice neizbežno uključuju tipološki nepotrebne obrasce bez konteksta, kao što su obrnuti. Ovaj papir proširi redovite jezike da uključuju reduplaciju uvedenjem novog kompjuterskog uređaja: ograničena državna buferna mašina (FSBM). Dajemo njegove matematičke definicije i razgovaramo o nekim svojstvima zatvaranja odgovarajućeg seta jezika. Kao rezultat toga, klasa redovnih jezika i jezika iz njih iz mehanizma kopiranja je karakterizirana. Predložila je prethodna literatura, ova klasa jezika bi trebala pristupiti karakterizaciji prirodnog seta jezika.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ආයුත්‍රක්‍ෂණය සාමාන්‍ය භාෂාවාද්‍යාව සහ මාර්ෆෝලෝජිකයෙන්. නමුත්, සාමාන්‍ය විදියට ප්‍රතිලිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළිපිළ ඉතින්, ඉතින් ඉතින් භාෂාව ප්‍රශ්ණ වර්ගයක් විශේෂයෙන් ප්‍රශ්ණ විශේෂයෙන් ප්‍රශ්ණ විශේෂය නැති ප්‍රශ Name අපි එයාගේ ගණිතික විශ්වාස කරනවා සමහර භාෂාවන් සම්බන්ධ විශ්වාස කරනවා. ඉතින්, සාමාන්‍ය භාෂාවන් සහ භාෂාවන්ගේ වර්ගය ඔවුන්ගෙන් ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක පරික්ෂණය කරන්න ප්‍රත පිරිසිදු සාක්ෂිත්‍රයෙන්, මේ භාෂාවගේ පරිස්සම් භාෂා වචන සැකසුම් වලට ස්වභාවික වචන සැක</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>Total reduppling är vanligt i naturspråkets fonologi och morfologi. Formellt sett som kopiering på reduplicanter av obegränsad storlek kräver obegränsad total reduplikation beräkningskraft bortom kontextfri, medan andra fonologiska och morfologiska mönster är regelbundna, eller till och med subregelbundna. Således innehåller befintliga språkklasser som karaktäriserar reduplicerade strängar oundvikligen typologiskt oattestade kontextfria mönster, såsom omvändningar. Denna uppsats utökar vanliga språk för att införliva reduplicering genom att introducera en ny beräkningsenhet: finite state buffered machine (FSBMs). Vi ger dess matematiska definitioner och diskuterar några slutegenskaper för motsvarande uppsättning språk. Som ett resultat kännetecknas klassen av vanliga språk och språk som härrör från dem genom en kopieringsmekanism. Föreslagna av tidigare litteratur, bör denna klass av språk närma sig karakteriseringen av naturliga språkorduppsättningar.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>کل دوبارہ پلیٹ کرنا طبیعی زبان فونولوژی اور مورفولوژی میں مشترک ہے. However, formally as copying on reduplicants of unbounded size, unrestricted total reduplication requires computational power beyond context-free, while other phonological and morphological patterns are regular, or even sub-regular. اسی طرح، موجود زبان کلاس، دوبارہ دوبارہ دوبارہ پیدا کیے ہوئے استرینگوں کی تعریف کرتی ہیں، غیر ضروری سے تایپولوژیکی طور پر غیر مترس کیے ہوئے مترس کے بغیر پاٹرنے کے ساتھ شامل ہوتے ہیں،  This paper extends regular languages to include a new computer device introducing: finite state buffered machine (FSBMs). ہم اس کی ریاضیات کی تعریف دیتے ہیں اور زبانوں کے مقابلہ دار مقابلہ کی تعریف کے بعض قطعہ کے خصوصے سے بحث کرتے ہیں. اس کے نتیجے میں، ان سے ناگہانی زبانوں اور زبانوں کا کلاس ایک کاپی مکانیسم سے پھیرا گیا ہے۔ پہلے کی ادبیات کے ذریعے پیش کیا گیا ہے، یہ کلاس زبانوں کی نسبت طبیعی زبان لفظ کی تعریف کے قریب ہونا چاہیے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>மொத்த குறைப்பு இயற்கையான மொழியின் தொழில்நுட்ப மற்றும் மோதிரியலில் பொதுவாகும். ஆனால், வடிவத்தில் வரம்பில்லாத அளவின் குறைப்பினை நகலெடுக்கும் போது, மொத்தமில்லாத மொத்தம் குறைப்பிடுதல் கணினியின் மேல் கணினியின் சக்தி தேவை, மற்ற போல பிரித்த சரங்களை குறைக்கும் தற்போதைய மொழி வகுப்பு இந்த தாள் ஒரு புதிய கணக்கீட்டு சாதனத்தை உள்ளிடுவதற்கான சாதாரண மொழிகளை விரிவாக்குகிறது: நிலை நிலை மாற்று இயந்திரம் (FSBMs). நாம் அதன் கணித விளக்கங்களை கொடுக்கிறோம் மற்றும் சில மொழிகளின் மூடுதல் குணங்களை விவாதம் செய்கிறோம். முடிவில், வழக்கமான மொழிகள் மற்றும் மொழிகளின் வகுப்பு நகல் முறைமை வழியாக கிடைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. முந்தைய எழுத்தாக்கத்தால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்படுகிறது, இந்த வகுப்பு மொழிகள் இயல்பான மொழி சொல்லு அமைப்புகளி</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_vi>Sự giảm dị ứng hoàn toàn phổ biến trong ngôn ngữ tự nhiên. Tuy nhiên, nếu sao chép về các dị ứng tự động của kích thước không có khối, sự giảm hoàn toàn hạn chế đòi hỏi sức mạnh tính toán vượt ra khỏi trường hợp tự do, trong khi các biểu đồ âm tính khác đều đặn, hay thậm chí cũng không đều đặn. Như vậy, các lớp ngôn ngữ hiện tại, mô tả các dây bị dị ứng, chắc chắn bao gồm các mô hình không có hình phụ, như ngược. Tờ giấy này mở rộng ngôn ngữ thường xuyên để thêm áp dụng bằng cách nhập một thiết bị tính mới: máy đệm bằng chế độ thần hạn (FSB). Chúng tôi đưa ra các định nghĩa toán học của nó và thảo luận về các tính chất đóng cửa của bộ ngôn ngữ tương ứng. Kết quả là, lớp ngôn ngữ và ngôn ngữ đều đặn bắt nguồn từ đó qua cơ chế sao chép được mô tả. Đề xuất từ văn học trước, lớp ngôn ngữ này nên tiếp cận với mô tả các trường ngôn ngữ tự nhiên.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Umumiy kamaytirish asosiy tilning fonologiya va morfologiga oddiy. Lekin, formatlarni cheksiz oʻlchamini nusxa olishda, cheksiz boʻlmaydi hamma nusxa olish muvaffaqiyatlarni o'zgartirish kerak, va boshqa fonologi va morfologik shakllari oddiy, yoki xato sub- regular. Thus, existing language classes characterizing reduplicated strings inevitably include typologically unattested context-free patterns, such as reversals.  Name Biz buning matematika taʼriflarini bajaramiz va bir xil tilning bir necha toʻxtatish xossalarini javob beramiz. Natijada, ulardan nusxa olish mekanisme orqali oddiy tillar va tillar darajasi belgilangan. Oldingi litteratur orqali talab qilingan, bu tillar sinfi tabiiy so'zlar soʻzlarining chegarasini moslash kerak.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_hr>Ukupna reduplacija je česta u prirodnoj jezičkoj fonologiji i morfologiji. Međutim, formalno kao kopiranje na redukcijama neograničene veličine, neograničena ukupna redukcija zahtijeva računalnu moć izvan konteksta bez konteksta, dok su drugi fonološki i morfološki obrazac obični ili čak i podobični. Stoga postojeće jezičke klase koje karakteriziraju preusmjerene žice neizbježno uključuju tipološki nepotrebne obrasce bez konteksta, kao što su obrnuti. Ovaj papir proširi redovne jezike uključujući reduplaciju uvođenjem novog računalnog uređaja: ograničeni državni bufferirani stroj (FSBM). Dajemo njegove matematičke definicije i razgovaramo o nekim vlasništvima zatvaranja odgovarajućeg seta jezika. Kao rezultat toga, klasa običnih jezika i jezika iz njih iz mehanizma kopiranja je karakterizirana. Predložila je prethodna literatura, ova klasa jezika treba pristupiti karakterizaciji prirodnog jezičkog seta riječi.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Totale reductie komt veel voor in de fonologie en morfologie van de natuurlijke taal. Echter, formeel als kopiëren op reduplicanten van onbeperkte grootte vereist onbeperkte totale reduplicatie rekenkracht die verder gaat dan contextvrij, terwijl andere fonologische en morfologische patronen regelmatig of zelfs sub-regulier zijn. Zo bevatten bestaande taalklassen die geredupliceerde tekenreeksen karakteriseren onvermijdelijk typologisch ongeteste contextvrije patronen, zoals omkeringen. Dit artikel breidt reguliere talen uit om reductie te integreren door een nieuw computerapparaat te introduceren: Finite State Buffered Machine (FSBM's). We geven de wiskundige definities en bespreken enkele sluitingseigenschappen van de overeenkomstige reeks talen. Als gevolg hiervan wordt de klasse van reguliere talen en talen die ervan afgeleid zijn door middel van een kopieermechanisme gekarakteriseerd. Voorgesteld door eerdere literatuur, zou deze taalklasse de karakterisering van natuurlijke taalwoordensets moeten benaderen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_bg>Пълното редуклиране е често срещано в фонологията и морфологията на естествения език. Въпреки това, формално като копиране на редуктиви с неограничен размер, неограниченото тотално редуктивиране изисква изчислителна мощ отвъд контекста, докато други фонологични и морфологични модели са редовни или дори подрегулярни. По този начин съществуващите езикови класове, характеризиращи редуклираните низове, неизбежно включват типологично неизвестни модели без контекст, като обръщане. Тази статия разширява редовните езици за включване на редуктивация чрез въвеждане на ново изчислително устройство: буферирана машина с крайно състояние (FSBMs). Даваме му математически дефиниции и обсъждаме някои затварящи свойства на съответния набор от езици. В резултат на това се характеризира класа на редовните езици и езици, получени от тях чрез копиращ механизъм. Предложено от предишна литература, този клас езици трябва да подхожда към характеризирането на естествените езикови слова.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_de>Totale Reduplizierung ist in der Phonologie und Morphologie der natürlichen Sprache üblich. Formal wie beim Kopieren auf Reduplikatoren unbegrenzter Größe erfordert die uneingeschränkte Totalreduplizierung jedoch Rechenleistung jenseits von kontextfrei, während andere phonologische und morphologische Muster regelmäßig oder sogar subregulär sind. Bestehende Sprachklassen, die reduplizierte Strings charakterisieren, enthalten daher zwangsläufig typologisch ungeprüfte kontextfreie Muster, wie Umkehrungen. Dieses Papier erweitert reguläre Sprachen um Reduplizierung, indem es ein neues Rechengerät einführt: Finite State Buffered Machine (FSBMs). Wir geben seine mathematischen Definitionen und diskutieren einige Schließeigenschaften der entsprechenden Gruppe von Sprachen. Als Ergebnis wird die Klasse der regulären Sprachen und Sprachen charakterisiert, die von ihnen durch einen Kopiermechanismus abgeleitet werden. Diese Klasse von Sprachen sollte sich der Charakterisierung natürlicher Wortsätze nähern.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_da>Total reduktion er almindelig i natursprogets fonologi og morfologi. Formelt som kopiering på reduplicanter af ubegrænset størrelse kræver ubegrænset total reduplikation imidlertid beregningskraft ud over kontekstfri, mens andre fonologiske og morfologiske mønstre er regelmæssige, eller endda subregulære. Således omfatter eksisterende sprogklasser, der karakteriserer reduplicerede strenge uundgåeligt typologisk uattestede kontekstfrie mønstre, såsom omvendelser. Denne artikel udvider regelmæssige sprog til at indarbejde reduplikation ved at introducere en ny beregningsenhed: finite state buffered machine (FSBMs). Vi giver dens matematiske definitioner og diskuterer nogle lukningsegenskaber for det tilsvarende sæt sprog. Som følge heraf karakteriseres klassen af almindelige sprog og sprog, der stammer fra dem gennem en kopieringsmekanisme. Foreslået af tidligere litteratur, bør denne klasse af sprog nærme sig karakteriseringen af naturligt sprog ordsæt.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_id>Total reduplikasi adalah umum dalam bahasa alami fonologi dan morfologi. Namun, secara resmi sebagai salinan pada reduplikant ukuran tidak terbatas, reduplikasi total tidak terbatas membutuhkan kekuatan komputasi di luar konteks bebas, sementara pola fonologi dan morfologi lainnya adalah biasa, atau bahkan sub-regular. Oleh karena itu, kelas bahasa yang ada yang mengkaraterisasikan string reduplikasi inevitably termasuk pola tanpa konteks tipologi yang tidak diuji, seperti reversal. This paper extends regular languages to incorporate reduplication by introducing a new computational device: finite state buffered machine (FSBMs).  Kami memberikan definisi matematika dan mendiskusikan beberapa properti penutupan dari set bahasa yang sesuai. Sebagai hasilnya, kelas bahasa biasa dan bahasa yang berasal dari mereka melalui mekanisme penyalinan dikaraterisasikan. Suggested by previous literature, this class of languages should approach the characterization of natural language word sets.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>Kupungua kwa ujumla ni jambo la kawaida katika utaalamu wa lugha za asili na folojia. Hata hivyo, kama vile kuandika nakala juu ya kupunguza ukubwa usio na mipaka, uchunguzi wa ujumla usioendelea unahitaji umeme wa hisabu zaidi ya mazingira yasiyo na mazingira mengine ya kifolojia na kifolojia ni mara kwa mara, au hata kwa kawaida. Kwa hiyo, darasa zilizopo kwa lugha zinazohusisha viungo vikubwa vinavyopungua bila uhakika unajumuisha mitindo yasiyo ya kibiashara, kama vile mabadiliko. Gazeti hili linaeneza lugha za kawaida kwa kuingiza upungufu kwa kuanzisha kifaa kipya cha kompyuta: mashine ya kisiasa ya serikali (FSBMs). Tunapata maelezo yake ya hisabati na kujadili baadhi ya utaalam wa kufungwa kwa lugha zinazofanana. As a result, the class of regular languages and languages derived from them through a copying mechanism is characterized.  Ikiwa imependekezwa na fasihi iliyopita, aina hii ya lugha inapaswa kusababisha utaalam wa seti za lugha za asili.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_ko>자연 언어의 음운학과 형태학에 완전히 중첩되어 흔히 볼 수 있다.그러나 형식적으로 무한 크기 중첩어에 대한 복제로서 무제한의 완전 중첩은 상하문과 무관한 계산 능력을 넘어야 하고 다른 음성과 형태 모델은 규칙적이며 심지어 차규칙적이다.따라서 기존의 설명 중첩 문자열의 언어 클래스는 형식적으로 테스트되지 않은 상하문 무관 모델, 예를 들어 반전을 포함할 수 없다.본고는 새로운 계산 장치인 유한 상태 버퍼(FSBMs)를 도입함으로써 정규 언어를 포함 중첩으로 확장한다.우리는 그것의 수학적 정의를 제시했고, 상응하는 언어 집합의 일부 폐쇄적인 성질을 토론했다.따라서 정규 언어와 복제 메커니즘을 통해 파생된 언어의 유형이 그려진다.이전의 문헌에 따르면 이런 언어는 자연 언어 어집의 특징에 가까워야 한다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_tr>Täbiýal dil fonologiýasy we morfologiýasynda jemi ýerleşdirim. Ýöne, resmi görkezilmedik ululyklaryň ýene kopiýa edip görkezilmek üçin, taýýarlanmadyk toplam ýene-de seredip bilmedik gücü kontekstsizden öňünde, beýleki fonolojik we morfolojik nusgalar düzgün bolsa we hatda sub-düzgün bolsa gerek. Şol sebäpli, bar diller taýýarlanan düzglerde karakterlerden çykyp bilen sözlemeýän düzglerde, nusgala ýaly sözlemeýän düzglerde ahmal. Bu kagyz täze bir hesap cihazy girdirmek üçin adatça çykyş dilleri ekleýär: howça durmuşy bufferleýän maşyny (FSBMs). Biz matematiksel tanyşlaryny berip, we dilleriň üstine ýakyn hasyşlaryny gürrüň edýäris. Şol sebäpli, adatça diller we diller üçin olardan kop mekanizmasyndan çykan surat karakterlerdir. Öňki edebiýatan tarapyndan maslahat edildi, bu klas dili tebigy dil sözleriniň karakterifikasyna gollanmaly.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_fa>جمعیت بازگشت در تلفن‌شناسی و مورفولوژی زبان طبیعی مشترک است. با این حال، رسمی به عنوان کپی کردن روی دوپلیکن اندازه غیرمحدودیت، دوپلیکن کامل غیرمحدودیت نیاز به قدرت کامپیوتری غیر محدودیت، در حالی که دیگر الگوهای فونیولوژیکی و مورفلوژیکی معمولی یا حتی زیر معمولی هستند. بنابراین، کلاس زبانی موجود که نوشته‌های دوباره‌پراکنده می‌شوند غیرقابل توجه‌ای از الگوهای آزاد محیط‌های بدون استفاده از نوشته‌شناسی شامل می‌شوند، مانند برگشت. این کاغذ زبان‌های معمولی را گسترش می‌دهد تا با توصیف یک دستگاه محاسبه جدید را جمع کند: دستگاه محاسبه‌ی موقعیت محدود (FSBMs). ما تعریف ریاضی‌اش را می‌دهیم و در مورد بعضی ویژه‌های بستنی از مجموعه‌های زبان‌ها صحبت می‌کنیم. به نتیجه، کلاس زبانهای معمولی و زبانهای معمولی که از آنها به طریق یک مکانیسم کپی گرفته‌اند، تعریف می‌شود. توسط ادبیات قبلی پیشنهاد، این کلاس زبانها باید به تعریف زبان طبیعی نزدیک شوند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Totaal herkoppeling is gemeenskap in natuurlike taal fonologie en morfologie. Maar formeel as kopiëring op herverkoperende van ongegrense grootte, ongestrekte totaal herverkopering benodig rekenasielike krag buite konteks-vry, terwyl ander fonologiese en morfologiese patrone gewone is of selfs sub-gewone. Daarom, bestaande taal klasse karakteriseer herverkoppelde strings onbeëindiglik insluit tipologies ongeondersteunde konteksvry patrone, soos omgekeerde. Hierdie papier uitbrei gewone tale om heroplaai te inkorpreer deur 'n nuwe rekenaar toestel te introduseer: eindig staat buffereerde masjien (FSBMs). Ons gee sy matematiese definisies en bespreek sommige sluiting eienskappe van die ooreenstemmende stel van tale. As 'n resultaat is die klas van gewone tale en tale wat van hulle afgelei word deur 'n kopiërmekanisme is karakteriseer. Die voorgestelde deur vorige literature moet hierdie klas tale by die karakterisering van natuurlike taal woord stel aangaan.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Rediplikimi i plotë është i zakonshëm në fonologjinë dhe morfologjinë e gjuhës natyrore. Megjithatë, si kopjim zyrtar mbi reduplikantët e madhësisë së pakufizuar, reduplikimi total i pa kufizuar kërkon fuqi llogaritëse përtej kontekstit pa kontekst, ndërsa modele të tjera fonologjike dhe morfologjike janë të rregullta apo madje jo të rregullta. Kështu, klasat ekzistuese të gjuhës që karakterizojnë rreshta të reduplikuara përfshijnë në mënyrë të pashmangshme modele pa kontekst, të tilla si kthesa. Kjo letër zgjeron gjuhët e rregullta për të përfshirë reduplikimin duke futur një paisje të re kompjuterike: një makinë e mbuluar me gjendje të kufizuar (FSBMs). Ne japim përcaktimet matematike të saj dhe diskutojmë disa pronësi mbylljeje të grupit korrespondent të gjuhëve. Si rezultat, është karakterizuar klasa e gjuhëve të rregullta dhe gjuhëve të nxjerra nga ato nëpërmjet një mekanizmi kopjimi. I sugjeruar nga literatura e mëparshme, kjo klasë gjuhësh duhet të afrohet karakterizimit të grupeve të fjalëve natyrore të gjuhës.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_az>Təbiətli dil fonoloji və morfoloji içində toplam yenilənmək ortaqdır. Halbuki, qeyri fonolojik və morfolojik örtükləri düzgün və ya hətta çox düzgün olduğu halda, ehtiyac edilməmiş tamamlanmış yenidən yüklənmək qurbanlıq gücünün ehtiyacı var. Beləliklə, əvvəlki dil səviyyələri yenidən dağıtılmış səviyyələri təhsil edilməz ki, tipolojik təhsil edilməmiş kontekst boş səviyyələri, böyük təhsil kimi. Bu kağıt yeni hesap avadanlığını təşkil edərək düzgün dilləri ilə yenidən yükləmək üçün genişləşdirir: müəyyən durum bufferləndirilmiş maşına (FSBM). Biz onun matematiksel tanımları veririk və müqayisədə olan dillərin bəzi qapılış özelliklərini danışırıq. Növbəti olaraq, bunlardan alınan düzgün dillər və dillərin sınıfı bir kopyalama mehanizmi vasitəsilə qarşılaşdırılır. Əvvəlki səhifələr təbliğ edilmişdir, bu dillərin səviyyəsi təbiətli dil sözlərin şəkillərinə yaxınlaşması lazımdır.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>প্রাকৃতিক ভাষার ফোলোজিয়া এবং মরোফোলোজিতে মোট কমানোর সাধারণ। কিন্তু আনুষ্ঠানিকভাবে সীমাবদ্ধ আকার কমানোর ক্ষেত্রে কপি করা হিসেবে অন্যান্য ফোনোলজিক্যাল এবং মরোফোলজিক্যাল প্যাটারেন্টার নিয়মিত, অথবা সাব-ন যার ফলে বিদ্যমান ভাষার ক্লাস কমিয়ে দেওয়া সংক্রান্ত সংক্রান্ত পরিস্থিতিতে সাধারণ ভাষায় বিভিন্ন পরীক্ষার প্রতিনিধির মত নতুন গণনামূলক ডিভাইস প্রবেশ করার মাধ্যমে এই পত্রিকাটি নিয়মিত ভাষাকে কমিপিকেশন করার জন্য বিস্তারিত ভাষা প্রসারিত করে: ফিনিট রা আমরা এর গণতান্ত্রিক বিবরণ দিয়েছি এবং সংশ্লিষ্ট ভাষার কিছু বৈশিষ্ট্য নিয়ে আলোচনা করি। এর ফলে সাধারণ ভাষা এবং ভাষার ক্লাস কপি করার মাধ্যমে তাদের কাছ থেকে উৎপাদন করা হয়েছে ক্লাসের চরিত্র। পূর্ববর্তী সাহিত্যে পরামর্শ প্রদান করা হয়েছে, প্রাকৃতিক ভাষার সাহিত্যের এই ক্লাস প্রকৃত ভাষার শব্দের</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_am>ሙሉ ማስታወቂያ በአፍጥረተ ቋንቋ ፎሎጂ እና ሞሮፎሎጂ የተጠቃሚ ነው፡፡ ምንም እንኳን፣ በተለየ ጥያቄ መጠን በማንቀሳቅስ፣ የማይሰራው ሙሉ ጉዳይ ከሥርዓት ሌላ ፎሎጂካዊ እና ሞሮፎሎጂ ዓይነቶች በተዘጋጀ ወይም በትክክል ማድረግ ነው፡፡ እንደዚህ፣ የቋንቋዎች ደረጃዎች አካባቢ ግንኙነትን በመቀነስ በአስቸጋሪው ግንኙነት ነጻ ሥርዓት፣ እንደተመሳሳይ መጠቀሚያ እንደሆነ ያስተካክሉ፡፡ ይህ ገጽ አዲስ ሰብሰባዊ መሣሪያን በመግለጥ ለማሳሰል የደብዳቤ ቋንቋዎችን ለማሳሰል ይዘረጋል፤ ፍጹም የstate buffered machine (FSBMs). የmathematical ግንኙነቶችን እናሳውቃለን እና የቋንቋዎችን ተቃውሞ እናዋርዳለን፡፡ ስለዚህ የመደብዳቤ ቋንቋዎች እና ቋንቋዎች ቋንቋ በመቀበል አካባቢ የተደረገ ነው፡፡ የቀድሞው የቋንቋ ቋንቋዎች የፍጥረት ቋንቋ ቃላትን መግለጫ ለመቀበል ይገባዋል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_ca>La reduplicació total és comú en la fonologia i la morfologia del llenguatge natural. However, formally as copying on reduplicants of unbounded size, unrestricted total reduplication requires computational power beyond context-free, while other phonological and morphological patterns are regular, or even sub-regular.  Així, les classes de llenguatge existents que caracteritzen cadenes reduplicades inclouen inevitablement patrons typològicament no comprovats sense contest, com els inversions. Aquest paper estén les llengües regulars a incorporar la reduplicació introduint un nou dispositiu computacional: una màquina amb buffer d'estat finit (FSBMs). Donem les seves definicions matemàtiques i discutem algunes propietats de tanque del conjunt de llengües correspondents. Com a resultat, es caracterizza la classe de llengües i llengües regulars derivades d'elles a través d'un mecanisme de còpia. Sugerida per la literatura anterior, aquesta classe de llengües hauria d'abordar la caracterització dels conjunts de paraules naturals.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_hy>Բնական լեզվի ֆոնոլոգիայի և մորֆոլոգիայի մեջ ընդհանուր կրկնապատկումն է: Այնուամենայնիվ, որպես վերարտադրություն անսահմանափակ չափի կրկնօրինակներին, անսահմանափակ ընդհանուր կրկնօրինակումը պահանջում է հաշվարկչական ուժ առանց կոնտեքստի, մինչդեռ այլ ֆոնոլոգիական և մորֆոլոգիական կաղապարները սովորական են, կամ նույնիսկ Այսպիսով, գոյություն ունեցող լեզվի դասերը, որոնք բնորոշվում են կրկնօրինակված լարեր, անխուսափելի են ներառում տիպոլոգիապես անվստահված կոնտեքստից ազատ կաղապարներ, ինչպիսիք են հակադարձությունները: Այս թղթին ընդլայնում է սովորական լեզուները, որպեսզի ներառի կրկնապատկումը, ներկայացնելով նոր հաշվարկչական սարք՝ սահմանափակ վիճակում պահպանվող մեքենա (ՖՍԲՄ). Մենք տալիս ենք դրա մաթեմատիկական սահմանումները և քննարկում ենք լեզուների համապատասխան խումբի որոշ վերջնական հատկություններ: Արդյունքում, դրանցից ստացված սովորական լեզուների և լեզուների դասը կոպիայի մեխանիզմի միջոցով բնորոշվում է: Առաջին գրականությամբ առաջարկված լեզուների այս դասարանը պետք է մոտենար բնական լեզվի բառերի համակարգերի բնորոշման:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_et>Täielik ümberkujundamine on tavaline looduskeele fonoloogias ja morfoloogias. Kuid formaalselt, nagu kopeerimine piiramatu suurusega reduplikaatoritele, nõuab piiramatu täielik redupliseerimine arvutusjõudu kontekstivabast kaugemale, samas kui muud fonoloogilised ja morfoloogilised mustrid on regulaarsed või isegi sub-regulaarsed. Seega sisaldavad olemasolevad keeleklassid, mis iseloomustavad redupliseeritud stringe, paratamatult tüpoloogiliselt kontrollimata kontekstivaba mustreid, näiteks pöördeid. Käesolev töö laiendab regulaarseid keeli reduplikatsiooni kaasamiseks, tutvustades uut arvutusseadet: piiratud oleku puhvrid masin (FSBM). Anname oma matemaatilised määratlused ja arutame mõningaid sulgemise omadusi vastav hulk keeli. Selle tulemusena iseloomustatakse tavakeelte klassi ja neist kopeerimismehhanismi kaudu tuletatud keelte klassi. Eelmise kirjanduse soovitatud keelteklass peaks lähenema looduskeelsete sõnakogude iseloomustamisele.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_bs>Ukupna reduplacija je česta u prirodnoj jezičkoj fonologiji i morfologiji. Međutim, formalno kao kopiranje na redukcijama neograničene veličine, neograničena ukupna redukcija zahtijeva računalnu moć izvan konteksta bez konteksta, dok su drugi fonološki i morfološki obrasce redovni ili čak i podredovni. Stoga postojeće jezičke klase koje karakteriziraju preusmjerene žice neizbježno uključuju tipološki nepotrebne obrasce bez konteksta, kao što su obrnuti. Ovaj papir proširi redovne jezike za uključenje reduplacije uvođenjem novog kompjuterskog uređaja: ograničena državna bufferirana mašina (FSBM). Dajemo njegove matematičke definicije i razgovaramo o nekim svojstvima zatvaranja odgovarajućeg seta jezika. Kao rezultat toga, klasa redovnih jezika i jezika iz njih iz mehanizma kopiranja je karakterizirana. Predložila je prethodna literatura, ova klasa jezika bi trebala pristupiti karakterizaciji prirodnog seta riječi.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Celková reduplikace je běžná ve fonologii a morfologii přirozeného jazyka. Nicméně formálně jako kopírování na redulikanty neomezené velikosti, neomezená celková reduplikace vyžaduje výpočetní sílu nad rámec bezkontextu, zatímco jiné fonologické a morfologické vzory jsou pravidelné, nebo dokonce subregulární. Takže existující jazykové třídy charakterizující reduplikované řetězce nevyhnutelně obsahují typologicky neattestované vzory bez kontextu, jako jsou obrácení. Tento článek rozšiřuje běžné jazyky o redukci představením nového výpočetního zařízení: konečný stav buffered machine (FSBM). Uvedeme jeho matematické definice a diskutujeme některé uzavírací vlastnosti odpovídající sady jazyků. V důsledku toho je charakterizována třída běžných jazyků a jazyků odvozených z nich prostřednictvím kopírovacího mechanismu. Navrhuje předchozí literatura, tato třída jazyků by se měla přiblížit k charakterizaci slovních sad přirozeného jazyka.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Täydellinen reduplikaatio on yleistä luonnollisen kielen fonologiassa ja morfologiassa. Muodollisesti kopioituna rajoittamattoman kokoisiin reduplikaattoreihin rajoittamaton täydellinen reduplikaatio vaatii kuitenkin laskennallista voimaa kontekstivapaa pidemmälle, kun taas muut fonologiset ja morfologiset kuviot ovat säännöllisiä tai jopa epäsäännöllisiä. Näin ollen olemassa olevat kieliluokat, jotka luonnehtivat reduplikoituja merkkijonoja, sisältävät väistämättä typologisesti käyttämättömiä kontekstivapaata kuvioita, kuten käänteitä. Tämä artikkeli laajentaa säännöllisiä kieliä sisällyttämään reduplikaation esittelemällä uuden laskennallisen laitteen: finite state puskured machine (FSBM). Annamme sen matemaattisia määritelmiä ja keskustelemme joitakin sulkemisominaisuuksia vastaavan joukon kieliä. Tämän seurauksena on ominaista säännöllisten kielten luokka ja niistä kopiointimekanismin avulla johdetut kielet. Aikaisemman kirjallisuuden perusteella tämän kieliluokan tulisi lähestyä luonnollisen kielen sanasarjojen luonnehdintaa.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ha>Jumlar kwamfyutan na ɗabi'a cikin folojiya da mutalogi na cikin harshen asimi. A lokacin da aka kama da wani kofi kan yin sauri na girma wanda bai ƙẽtare haddi ba, kuma kada-rubutun da aka rubũta shi yana da matsayin lissafi wanda ba'a da shi ba, kuma da wasu shiryoyin folojical da morfological su zama daidai, ko kuma don don a kasa da sauri. Don haka, da kuma, tsarin harshen wanda ke da mai ƙayyade daraja da aka tsohatar da kuma an ƙunsa da shi, ana shigar da wasu shiryoyi na mazaɓa wa mazaɓa da kuma ba da jarraba ba, kamar misãlin tsofarin. Wannan takardar da ke shimfiɗa harshen maras da za'a shigar da kayan lissafa wa kodi: finite state buffeted mashine (FSBM). Munã bãyar da fassararsa na ƙidãya kuma Muke jãyayya wasu properties na rufe lugha da ke daidaita. Saboda haka, ana ƙayyade nau'in harshe da harsunan da aka samar da su zuwa wani matsayin kodi. An buƙata da littãfin da aka riga, wannan nau'in harshen za'a iya kusantar da ƙayyade masu daidaita maganar harshe na farko.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Popolna reduplikacija je pogosta v fonologiji in morfologiji naravnega jezika. Vendar pa formalno kot kopiranje na reduplikatorjih neomejene velikosti neomejena popolna reduplikacija zahteva računalniško moč, ki presega kontekst brez konteksta, medtem ko so drugi fonološki in morfološki vzorci redni ali celo podredni. Tako obstoječi jezikovni razredi, ki označujejo reduplicirane nize, neizogibno vključujejo tipološko neizkušene vzorce brez konteksta, kot so obračanja. Ta prispevek razširja redne jezike za vključitev reduplikacije z uvedbo nove računalniške naprave: končno stanje pufer stroj (FSBM). Podajamo matematične definicije in razpravljamo o nekaterih lastnostih zapiranja ustreznega nabora jezikov. Zato je značilen razred rednih jezikov in jezikov, ki izhajajo iz njih s kopirnim mehanizmom. Ta razred jezikov, ki ga predlaga prejšnja literatura, bi moral pristopiti k karakterizaciji naborov besed naravnega jezika.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>התכפילות מוחלטת היא נפוצה בפונולוגיה והמורפולוגיה בשפה הטבעית. However, formally as copying on reduplicants of unbounded size, unrestricted total reduplication requires computational power beyond context-free, while other phonological and morphological patterns are regular, or even sub-regular.  לכן, שיעורי שפה קיימות שמתאימים חוטים מוכפלים בלתי נמנע כוללים דפוסים חסרי קשר טיפולוגיים, כמו הפוך. הנייר הזה מגדיל שפות רגילות כדי להכיל מחדש כפילה על ידי הכניסה מכשיר מחשבי חדש: מכונת מגבילה במצב מוגבל (FSBMs). אנו נותנים את הגדרות המתמטיות שלה ונדבר על איכויות סגירה של קבוצת השפות המתאימות. כתוצאה מכך, הכיתה של שפות רגילות ושפות שנוצרות מהם דרך מנגנון עותק מותאים. מציע על ידי ספרות קודמות, כיתה זו של שפות צריכה להתקרב לתיאור של קבוצות מילים שפות טבעיות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Total red politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Laptop" and "Desktop Awak dhéwé éné perusahaan gedhèké nggawe barang-barang nggawe gerakan karo nganggo barang nggawe barang nggawe barang. Wurung o, kelas sing luwih dumadhi lan luwih dumadhi sak sekolahan kelas nang nguasai perusahaan seneng pisan. Suggestion Perusahaan anyar luwih-luwih, kelas iki sakjane kudu ngegoleki cara-cara perusahaan langkung</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_bo>སྤྱིར་བཏང་ཚང་མཉམ་དུ་བསྡུར་ན་ཡིན་ནའང་སྤྱིར་བཏང་བ་ཞིག་ཡིན་པས། ཡིན་ནའང་། རྒྱུན་ལྡན་མེད་པའི་ཆེ་ཆུང་ལ་བསྐྱར་བཤིག་པ་ལས་འདྲ་བཤུ་བྱེད་བཞིན་ཡིན་པ་ལྟར་པར་ངོས་འཛིན་གྱི་ནུས་པ་སྟོང་བ་དང་། དེར་བརྟེན། གནས་ཡོད་པའི་སྐད་ཡིག ཤོག་བྱང་འདིས་རྒྱུན ང་ཚོས་རང་གི་གྲངས་རིག་གི་འགྲེལ་བཤད་དང་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་དང་མཐུན་པའི་སྒྲིག་འགོད་ལ་ཁ་ཤས་གཏོང་བ་རེད། དབང་འབྲས་ན། རྒྱུན་ལྡན་སྐད་ཡིག་དང་སྐད་ཡིག་གི་དབྱེ་བ་དེ་འདྲ་བཤུ་ཐབས་ལམ་ཞིག་ནས་ཕན་འབྲི་བ་ཡིན་པ སྔོན་གྱི་literature་རིགས་ལ་བསམ་འཆར་བཀོད་ཡོད་ན། སྐད་རིགས་ཀྱི་གྲྭར་འདིས་རང་བཞིན་པའི་སྐད་ཡིག</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="24">
      <title>Improved pronunciation prediction accuracy using morphology</title>
      <author><first>Dravyansh</first><last>Sharma</last></author>
      <author><first>Saumya</first><last>Sahai</last></author>
      <author><first>Neha</first><last>Chaudhari</last></author>
      <author><first>Antoine</first><last>Bruguier</last></author>
      <pages>222–228</pages>
      <abstract>Pronunciation lexicons and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">prediction models</a> are a key component in several <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">speech synthesis and recognition systems</a>. We know that morphologically related words typically follow a fixed pattern of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pronunciation">pronunciation</a> which can be described by language-specific paradigms. In this work we explore how deep recurrent neural networks can be used to automatically learn and exploit this pattern to improve the pronunciation prediction quality of words related by morphological inflection. We propose two novel approaches for supplying morphological information, using the word’s morphological class and its lemma, which are typically annotated in standard lexicons. We report improvements across a number of European languages with varying degrees of phonological and morphological complexity, and two <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_family">language families</a>, with greater improvements for languages where the pronunciation prediction task is inherently more challenging. We also observe that combining bidirectional LSTM networks with attention mechanisms is an effective neural approach for the computational problem considered, across languages. Our approach seems particularly beneficial in the low resource setting, both by itself and in conjunction with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning">transfer learning</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="d0d96573">2021.sigmorphon-1.24</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigmorphon-1.24</doi>
      <bibkey>sharma-etal-2021-improved</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>