<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.law">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-10-28">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of The Joint 15th Linguistic Annotation Workshop (LAW) and 3rd Designing Meaning Representations (DMR) Workshop</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Claire</first><last>Bonial</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Nianwen</first><last>Xue</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Punta Cana, Dominican Republic</address>
      <month>November</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="45004721">2021.law-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>law-2021-joint</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Representing Implicit Positive Meaning of Negated Statements in AMR<fixed-case>AMR</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Katharina</first><last>Stein</last></author>
      <author><first>Lucia</first><last>Donatelli</last></author>
      <pages>23–35</pages>
      <abstract>Abstract Meaning Representation (AMR) has become popular for representing the meaning of natural language in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(discrete_mathematics)">graph structures</a>. However, AMR does not represent scope information, posing a problem for its overall expressivity and specifically for drawing inferences from negated statements. This is the case with so-called positive interpretations of negated statements, in which implicit positive meaning is identified by inferring the opposite of the negation’s focus. In this work, we investigate how potential positive interpretations (PPIs) can be represented in AMR. We propose a logically motivated AMR structure for PPIs that makes the focus of negation explicit and sketch an initial proposal for a systematic methodology to generate this more expressive structure.</abstract>
      <url hash="375da95b">2021.law-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>stein-donatelli-2021-representing</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.law-1.3</doi>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Can predicate-argument relationships be extracted from UD trees?<fixed-case>UD</fixed-case> trees?</title>
      <author><first>Adam</first><last>Ek</last></author>
      <author><first>Jean-Philippe</first><last>Bernardy</last></author>
      <author><first>Stergios</first><last>Chatzikyriakidis</last></author>
      <pages>46–55</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we investigate the possibility of extracting predicate-argument relations from UD trees (and enhanced UD graphs). Con- cretely, we apply UD parsers on an En- glish question answering / semantic-role label- ing data set (FitzGerald et al., 2018) and check if the annotations reflect the relations in the resulting parse trees, using a small number of rules to extract this information. We find that 79.1 % of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argument_of_a_function">argument-predicate pairs</a> can be found in this way, on the basis of Ud- ify (Kondratyuk and Straka, 2019). Error anal- ysis reveals that half of the error cases are at- tributable to shortcomings in the dataset. The remaining errors are mostly due to predicate- argument relations not being extractible algo- rithmically from the UD trees (requiring se- mantic reasoning to be resolved). The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing">parser</a> itself is only responsible for a small portion of errors. Our analysis suggests a number of improvements to the UD annotation schema : we propose to enhance the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Database_schema">schema</a> in four ways, in order to capture argument-predicate relations. Additionally, we propose improve- ments regarding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_collection">data collection</a> for question answering / semantic-role labeling data.</abstract>
      <url hash="37166656">2021.law-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>ek-etal-2021-predicate</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.law-1.5</doi>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/qa-srl">QA-SRL</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/universal-dependencies">Universal Dependencies</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Classifying Divergences in Cross-lingual AMR Pairs<fixed-case>AMR</fixed-case> Pairs</title>
      <author><first>Shira</first><last>Wein</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathan</first><last>Schneider</last></author>
      <pages>56–65</pages>
      <abstract>Translation divergences are varied and widespread, challenging approaches that rely on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_text">parallel text</a>. To annotate translation divergences, we propose a schema grounded in the Abstract Meaning Representation (AMR), a sentence-level semantic framework instantiated for a number of languages. By comparing parallel AMR graphs, we can identify specific points of divergence. Each <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Divergence">divergence</a> is labeled with both a type and a cause. We release a small corpus of annotated English-Spanish data, and analyze the annotations in our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="375d34f8">2021.law-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>wein-schneider-2021-classifying</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.law-1.6</doi>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/shirawein/spanish-english-amr-corpus" additional="false">shirawein/spanish-english-amr-corpus</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Subcategorizing Adverbials in Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>niversal <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>onceptual <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ognitive <fixed-case>A</fixed-case>nnotation</title>
      <author><first>Zhuxin</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <author><first>Jakob</first><last>Prange</last></author>
      <author><first>Nathan</first><last>Schneider</last></author>
      <pages>96–105</pages>
      <abstract>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) is a semantic annotation scheme that organizes texts into coarse predicate-argument structure, offering broad coverage of semantic phenomena. At the same time, there is still need for a finer-grained treatment of many of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Categorization">categories</a>. The Adverbial category is of special interest, as it covers a wide range of fundamentally different meanings such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affirmation_and_negation">negation</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Causality">causation</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammatical_aspect">aspect</a>, and event quantification. In this paper we introduce a refinement annotation scheme for UCCA’s Adverbial category, showing that UCCA Adverbials can indeed be subcategorized into at least 7 semantic types, and doing so can help clarify and disambiguate the otherwise coarse-grained labels. We provide a preliminary set of annotation guidelines, as well as pilot annotation experiments with high inter-annotator agreement, confirming the validity of the scheme.</abstract>
      <url hash="b9971d4a">2021.law-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>wang-etal-2021-subcategorizing</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.law-1.10</doi>
    <title_ar>التصنيف الفرعي للظروف في التعليق التوضيحي المعرفي التصوري العالمي</title_ar>
      <title_es>Subcategorización de adverbios en Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation</title_es>
      <title_pt>Subcategorizando Adverbiais na Anotação Cognitiva Conceitual Universal</title_pt>
      <title_ja>普遍的概念認知注釈における副詞のサブカテゴリー化</title_ja>
      <title_zh>通以右识注中副词子分类</title_zh>
      <title_hi>यूनिवर्सल वैचारिक संज्ञानात्मक एनोटेशन में क्रियाविशेषण उप-श्रेणीकरण</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Fochatagóiriú Adverbials in Anótáil Chognaíoch Choincheapúil Uilíoch</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Υποκατηγοριοποίηση των επιθέσεων στην καθολική εννοιολογική γνωστική σημείωση</title_el>
      <title_hu>Reklámok alkategorizálása az univerzális koncepciós kognitív jegyzékben</title_hu>
      <title_it>Sottocategorizzare gli effetti negativi nell'annotazione cognitiva concettuale universale</title_it>
      <title_kk>Universal conceptual Cognitive Annotation</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Nepageidaujamų reiškinių klasifikavimas visuotinėje koncepcinėje pažintinėje anotacijoje</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Подкатегоризирање на непријатели во универзалната концептуална коњитивна анотација</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Mengukur Adverbial dalam Annotasi Konceptif Universal</title_ms>
      <title_ml>സര്‍വ്വശക്തിക കോണ്‍സ്പെറ്റല്‍ കോണ്‍ഗ്നിറ്റീവ് ആനോട്ടേഷനില്‍ സബ്ഗ്രാഗ്രേഷന്‍ ചെയ്യുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_mt>Sottokategorijizzazzjoni tal-Adverbjali fl-Annotazzjoni Konċettwali Universali</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation</title_mn>
      <title_no>Underkategoriserar Adverbialar i universelle konseptuelle kognitiv notasjon</title_no>
      <title_pl>Podkategorizowanie przysłówek w uniwersalnej koncepcyjnej adnotacji poznawczej</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Subcategorizarea adversităților în adnotările cognitive conceptuale universale</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Podkategoriziranje Adverbiala u univerzalnoj konceptualnoj kognitivnoj notaciji</title_sr>
      <title_si>සාමාන්‍ය සංස්කර්ණ ක්‍රියාත්මක ක්‍රියාත්මක ක්‍රියාත්මක</title_si>
      <title_so>Isku qeybinta horumarinta ee jaamacadda</title_so>
      <title_sv>Underkategorisera negativa effekter i universell konceptuell kognitiv notering</title_sv>
      <title_ta>உலகளாவிய முறையான குறிப்புரையில் உப ப பிரிப்பாக்குதல் முன்னுரிமைகள்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation in Subcategorizing Adverbials</title_ur>
      <title_vi>Phân loại lại phàm tục trong Thông chú nhận thức chung</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Umumiy kognitive Annotation</title_uz>
      <title_bg>Подкатегоризиране на нежеланите реакции в универсалната концептуална когнитивна анотация</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Podkategoriziranje Adverbiala u univerzalnoj konceptualnoj kognitivnoj oznake</title_hr>
      <title_da>Underkategorisering af reklamer i universel konceptuel kognitiv notering</title_da>
      <title_de>Subkategorisierung von Adverbialen in Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation</title_de>
      <title_nl>Bijwoorden onderverdelen in Universele Conceptuele Cognitieve Annotatie</title_nl>
      <title_ko>통용 개념 인지 표기 중장어의 차범주화</title_ko>
      <title_fa>پایه‌گروهی‌کننده‌های مصنوعی در توضیح شناخته‌ای جهانی</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation</title_tr>
      <title_id>Mengkategorisasi Adverbial dalam Annotasi Konceptif Universal</title_id>
      <title_sw>Kugawanya Tahadhari katika Tamko la Kimataifa</title_sw>
      <title_af>Subkategoriseering Adverbials in Universele Konsensieële Cognitive Annotation</title_af>
      <title_sq>Subkategorizimi i kundërshtarëve në Anotacionin Universal Konceptiv</title_sq>
      <title_am>አውቶማቲክ</title_am>
      <title_hy>Համաշխարհային գաղափարական գիտակցական նշումների ենթակատեգորիալ</title_hy>
      <title_az>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation</title_az>
      <title_bn>বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ের কনসেপ্টুয়াল কোনোগ্নিটিভ অ্যাডবার্বিয়াল</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Podkategoriziranje Adverbiala u univerzalnoj konceptualnoj kognitivnoj Annotaciji</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Subcategoritzar els adversials en l'anotació conceptual universal</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Podkategorizace příznaků v univerzální koncepční kognitivní anotaci</title_cs>
      <title_et>Kõrvaltoimete alamkategooriad universaalses kontseptuaalses kognitiivses annotatsioonis</title_et>
      <title_fi>Haittavaikutusten alakategorisointi yleismaailmallisessa käsitteellisessä kognitiivisessa huomautuksessa</title_fi>
      <title_jv>politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertive</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Podkategorizacija neželenih učinkov v univerzalni konceptualni kognitivni opombi</title_sk>
      <title_he>מתקטגוריזת פריביאלים באנוטציה קונצטיבית יוניברסלית</title_he>
      <title_bo>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (Subcategorizing Adverbials)</title_bo>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <abstract_ar>التعليق التوضيحي الإدراكي المفاهيمي العالمي (UCCA) هو مخطط توضيحي دلالي ينظم النصوص في بنية حجة المسند الخشنة ، مما يوفر تغطية واسعة للظواهر الدلالية. في الوقت نفسه ، لا تزال هناك حاجة إلى معالجة أكثر دقة للعديد من الفئات. تعتبر فئة الظرف ذات أهمية خاصة ، حيث إنها تغطي مجموعة واسعة من المعاني المختلفة جوهريًا مثل النفي والسببية والجانب وتقدير الأحداث. في هذه الورقة ، نقدم مخطط شرح توضيحي محسن لفئة UCCA Adverbial ، والتي توضح أنه يمكن بالفعل تصنيف UCCA Adverbials إلى ما لا يقل عن 7 أنواع دلالية ، ويمكن أن يساعد القيام بذلك في توضيح وتوضيح الملصقات ذات الحبيبات الخشنة. نحن نقدم مجموعة أولية من إرشادات التعليقات التوضيحية ، بالإضافة إلى تجارب التعليقات التوضيحية التجريبية باتفاق عالٍ بين المعلقين التوضيحيين ، مما يؤكد صحة المخطط.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>La anotación cognitiva conceptual universal (UCCA) es un esquema de anotación semántica que organiza los textos en una estructura gruesa de predicado y argumento, que ofrece una amplia cobertura de los fenómenos semánticos. Al mismo tiempo, sigue siendo necesario un tratamiento más detallado de muchas de las categorías. La categoría adverbial es de especial interés, ya que cubre una amplia gama de significados fundamentalmente diferentes, como negación, causalidad, aspecto y cuantificación de eventos. En este artículo presentamos un esquema de anotación de refinamiento para la categoría adverbial de UCCA, que muestra que los adverbiales de UCCA pueden subcategorizarse en al menos 7 tipos semánticos, y hacerlo puede ayudar a aclarar y desambiguar las etiquetas de grano grueso. Proporcionamos un conjunto preliminar de pautas de anotación, así como experimentos de anotación piloto con alta concordancia entre anotadores, lo que confirma la validez del esquema.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>A Anotação Cognitiva Conceitual Universal (UCCA) é um esquema de anotação semântica que organiza textos em uma estrutura predicado-argumento grosseira, oferecendo ampla cobertura de fenômenos semânticos. Ao mesmo tempo, ainda há necessidade de um tratamento mais refinado de muitas das categorias. A categoria Adverbial é de interesse especial, pois abrange uma ampla gama de significados fundamentalmente diferentes, como negação, causação, aspecto e quantificação de eventos. Neste artigo, apresentamos um esquema de anotação de refinamento para a categoria Adverbial do UCCA, mostrando que os Adverbiais do UCCA podem de fato ser subcategorizados em pelo menos 7 tipos semânticos, e isso pode ajudar a esclarecer e desambiguar os rótulos de granulação grosseira. Nós fornecemos um conjunto preliminar de diretrizes de anotação, bem como experimentos piloto de anotação com alta concordância entre anotadores, confirmando a validade do esquema.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>ユニバーサルコンセプチュアル認知アノテーション（ UCCA ）は、テキストを粗い述語論証構造に整理する意味論的アノテーションスキームであり、意味論的現象の広範なカバレッジを提供する。同時に、多くのカテゴリーのより細かい処理が依然として必要である。副詞カテゴリは、否定、因果関係、態様、および事象定量化などの根本的に異なる幅広い意味をカバーするため、特に興味深いものです。この論文では、UCCAの副詞カテゴリの改良アノテーションスキームを紹介し、UCCA副詞が実際に少なくとも7つのセマンティックタイプに下位カテゴリ分類できることを示し、そうでなければ粗粒度のラベルを明確にし、曖昧にするのに役立ちます。私たちは、注釈ガイドラインの初歩的なセットと、スキームの妥当性を確認する注釈者間の高い合意を持つパイロット注釈実験を提供します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>यूनिवर्सल वैचारिक संज्ञानात्मक एनोटेशन (यूसीसीए) एक शब्दार्थ एनोटेशन योजना है जो ग्रंथों को मोटे विधेय-तर्क संरचना में व्यवस्थित करती है, जो शब्दार्थ घटनाओं के व्यापक कवरेज की पेशकश करती है। साथ ही, अभी भी कई श्रेणियों के महीन-दाने वाले उपचार की आवश्यकता है। क्रियाविशेषण श्रेणी विशेष रुचि की है, क्योंकि यह मूल रूप से अलग-अलग अर्थों की एक विस्तृत श्रृंखला को कवर करती है जैसे कि नकार, कारण, पहलू और घटना परिमाणीकरण। इस पेपर में हम यूसीसीए की क्रियाविशेषण श्रेणी के लिए एक शोधन एनोटेशन योजना पेश करते हैं, यह दिखाते हुए कि यूसीसीए क्रियाविशेषणों को वास्तव में कम से कम 7 शब्दार्थ प्रकारों में उप-वर्गीकृत किया जा सकता है, और ऐसा करने से अन्यथा मोटे-दाने वाले लेबल को स्पष्ट करने और विभाजित करने में मदद मिल सकती है। हम एनोटेशन दिशानिर्देशों का एक प्रारंभिक सेट प्रदान करते हैं, साथ ही साथ उच्च अंतर-एनोटेटर समझौते के साथ पायलट एनोटेशन प्रयोग, योजना की वैधता की पुष्टि करते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>通名识注(UCCA)语义注方案,粗结谓词,语义广覆之。 仍须更细粒度。 副词类殊可喜,以其涵盖本异义,如否因果关系,方事量化。 本文引UCCA副词类细化注方案,明UCCA副词实可细分为至少7种语义类,可以助澄清消本粗粒度之歧义。 供初注指南,及高注者间一致性试点注实验,确然有效性。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Scéim nótaí shéimeantach is ea Anótáil Chognaíoch Choincheapúil (UCCA) a eagraíonn téacsanna i struchtúr garbh-argóinte réamhaithrise, a chuireann clúdach leathan ar fheiniméin shéimeantacha ar fáil. Ag an am céanna, tá gá fós le cóireáil níos míne ar go leor de na catagóirí. Tá spéis ar leith ag baint leis an gcatagóir Adverbial, toisc go gclúdaíonn sé raon leathan bríonna atá difriúil ó thaobh bunúsach amhail diúltú, cúisíocht, gné agus cainníochtú imeachtaí. Sa pháipéar seo tugaimid isteach scéim anótála coigeartaithe do chatagóir Adverbial UCCA, a thaispeánann gur féidir UCCA adverbials a fhochatagóiriú go 7 gcineál shéimeantach ar a laghad, agus má dhéantar é sin is féidir cabhrú le soiléiriú agus dí-dhébhríocht a dhéanamh ar na lipéid garbhghnácha. Soláthraímid réamhthacar de threoirlínte anótála, chomh maith le trialacha píolótacha anótála a bhfuil comhaontú ard idir-anóadóirí acu, ag deimhniú bailíocht na scéime.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>უნივერსალური კონცექციური კონტიგური კონტიგური კონტიგური კონტიგური კონტიაცია (UCCA) არის სემენტიური კონტაქციის ქემია, რომელიც ტექსტის ორგანიზაცია კონტაქტიური პრო ერთადერთი დროში, უფრო უკეთესი კატეგორიების მეტად უკეთესი საჭიროა. კონტუალური კატეგორია სპეციალური ინტერესტია, რადგან ის კონტუალურად განსხვავებული განსხვავებულ განსხვავებების განსხვავება, როგორც ნეგერბაცია, მიზეზი, აპექტი ამ დომენტში ჩვენ შევცვალოთ UCCA-ის კონტერბულ კატეგორიის რეფინციური ანტოციის სქემი, რომელიც გამოჩვენება, რომ UCCA კონტერბულები ნამდვილად შეიძლება იყოს საკუთარი 7 semantic ტიპში, და ამიტომ შეგვიძლია დახმარება და განახლობა ჩვენ გვეყვანეთ პირველური ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების ნაწილეების, და</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η καθολική εννοιολογική γνωστική σημείωση (UCCA) είναι ένα σημασιολογικό σχέδιο σχολιασμού που οργανώνει τα κείμενα σε χονδρική δομή προδιάθεσης-ορίσματος, προσφέροντας ευρεία κάλυψη σημασιολογικών φαινομένων. Ταυτόχρονα, εξακολουθεί να υπάρχει ανάγκη για μια λεπτόκοκκη επεξεργασία πολλών από τις κατηγορίες. Η κατηγορία των επιρρεπών παρουσιάζει ιδιαίτερο ενδιαφέρον, καθώς καλύπτει ένα ευρύ φάσμα θεμελιωδώς διαφορετικών εννοιών όπως η άρνηση, η αιτιώδης συνάφεια, η πτυχή και η ποσοτικοποίηση γεγονότων. Σε αυτή την εργασία εισάγουμε ένα σύστημα σχολιασμού για την κατηγορία των επιρρυθμιών της UCCA, δείχνοντας ότι οι επιρρυθμιές UCCA μπορούν πράγματι να υποκατηγοριοποιηθούν σε τουλάχιστον επτά σημασιολογικούς τύπους, και κάνοντας αυτό μπορεί να βοηθήσει στη διευκρίνιση και αποσαφήνιση των κατά τα άλλα χονδροειδείς ετικετών. Παρέχουμε ένα προκαταρκτικό σύνολο οδηγιών σχολιασμού, καθώς και πιλοτικά πειράματα σχολιασμού με υψηλή συμφωνία μεταξύ σχολιαστών, επιβεβαιώνοντας την εγκυρότητα του σχεδίου.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az univerzális koncepciós kognitív megjegyzés (UCCA) egy szemantikus megjegyzési séma, amely durva predikátum-argumentum struktúrába rendezi a szövegeket, széles körű lefedettséget biztosítva a szemantikai jelenségek. Ugyanakkor számos kategória esetében még mindig finomabb szemcsés kezelésre van szükség. Az Adverbial kategória különösen érdekes, mivel alapvetően különböző jelentések széles skáláját fedi fel, mint például a negatív, okozati összefüggés, aspektus és esemény mennyiségi meghatározás. Ebben a tanulmányban bemutatjuk az UCCA Adverbial kategóriájának finomítási jegyzési sémáját, amely azt mutatja, hogy az UCCA Adverbials valóban legalább 7 szemantikai típusra osztható, és ezzel segíthet tisztázni és egyértelműsíteni az egyébként durva szemcsés címkéket. Előzetes jegyzetelési irányelveket, valamint kísérleti jegyzetelési kísérleteket biztosítunk magas jegyzetelési megállapodással, amelyek megerősítik a rendszer érvényességét.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) è uno schema di annotazione semantica che organizza i testi in struttura predicato-argomento grossolana, offrendo un'ampia copertura dei fenomeni semantici. Allo stesso tempo, è ancora necessario un trattamento più fine di molte categorie. La categoria Adverbial è di particolare interesse, in quanto copre una vasta gamma di significati fondamentalmente diversi come negazione, causalità, aspetto e quantificazione degli eventi. In questo articolo introduciamo uno schema di annotazione di perfezionamento per la categoria Adverbial di UCCA, mostrando che gli Adverbial di UCCA possono effettivamente essere sottocategorizzati in almeno 7 tipi semantici, e così facendo può aiutare a chiarire e disambiguare le etichette altrimenti a grana grossa. Forniamo una serie preliminare di linee guida di annotazione, così come esperimenti pilota di annotazione con alto accordo inter-annotatore, a conferma della validità dello schema.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA – Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation) yra semantinė annotacijos schema, kuria tekstai organizuojami į didžiulę predicate-argument struktūrą, siūlant platų semantinių reiškinių aprėptį. Be to, daugeliui kategorijų vis dar reikia geriau apdoroti grūdus. Nepageidaujama kategorija yra ypač svarbi, nes ji apima įvairias iš esmės skirtingas reikšmes, pvz., neigiamą poveikį, priežastinį poveikį, aspektą ir įvykių kiekybinį įvertinimą. Šiame dokumente įvedame UCCA nepageidaujamos kategorijos patobulinimo anotacijų sistemą, kuria parodoma, kad UCCA nepageidaujamos medžiagos iš tiesų gali būti subkategorijuojamos į ne mažiau kaip 7 semantinius tipus, ir tai gali padėti paaiškinti ir išaiškinti kitaip stambių grūdų etiketes. Pateikiame preliminarias anotacinių gairių rinkinį ir bandomuosius anotacinių eksperimentus su dideliu tarpanotatorių susitarimu, patvirtinančiu schemos galiojimą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) деген semantic annotation scheme, мәтіндерді қалыпты аргументтің құрылымына ұйымдастыру сұлбасы, semantic phenomena үлкен мәтіндерді ұйымдастыру сұлбасы. Бірақ сол уақытта, санаттардың көпшілігін жақсы жасау керек. Конвербиялық санаты арнайы қызықтық, себебі ол негізі, себептері, аспекті және оқиғалардың көптеген көптеген мәліметтердің көптеген аумағын жасайды. Бұл қағазда UCCA конвербиялық санаттарының рефининг жазбаларын келтіріп, UCCA конвербиялық санаттарын кемінде 7 семантикалық түрлерге төмендетуге болады дегенді көрсету сұлбасын келтіріп, сондықтан бұл жазбаларды түсіндіруге көмектесе алады. Біз алдыңғы жазбалардың бағыттауларын және pilot жазбалардың тәжірибесін қолданып, сұлбаның дұрыстығын құптау үшін жазбалардың тәжірибесін қолданамыз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mk>Универзалната концептуална коњитивна анотација (УККА) е семантична шема на анотација која организира тексти во груба структура на предикат-аргумент, нудејќи широко покривање на семантични феномени. Истовремено, сé уште постои потреба од подобар третман на многумина од категориите. Абербијалната категорија е од специјален интерес, бидејќи покрива широк опсег на фундаментално различни значења како што се негативноста, причината, аспектот и квантификацијата на настаните. Во овој весник воведуваме схема на анатација за рафинирање за Абербијалната категорија на УККА, која покажува дека УККА Абербијалс навистина може да се подкатегоризира во најмалку 7 семантични типови, и тоа може да помогне да се јасни и да се разјасни инаку грубо зелените етикети. We provide a preliminary set of annotation guidelines, as well as pilot annotation experiments with high inter-annotator agreement, confirming the validity of the scheme.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Anotasi Konceptif Universal (UCCA) adalah skema anotasi semantik yang mengatur teks ke struktur predikat-argumen kasar, menawarkan perlindungan luas fenomena semantik. Pada masa yang sama, masih perlu rawatan yang lebih baik dari banyak kategori. Kategori Adverbial adalah berminat istimewa, kerana ia meliputi julat luas makna yang secara dasar berbeza seperti negatif, penyebab, aspek, dan kuantifikasi peristiwa. Dalam kertas ini kami memperkenalkan skema anotasi penarafan untuk kategori Adverbial UCCA, yang menunjukkan bahawa Adverbial s UCCA benar-benar boleh dikategorikan ke sekurang-kurangnya 7 jenis semantik, dan melakukan itu boleh membantu jelaskan dan nyahambiguasi label-bijian lebar sebaliknya. Kami menyediakan set awal arahan anotasi, serta eksperimen anotasi pilot dengan persetujuan antar-anotasi yang tinggi, mengesahkan kehendak skema.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>L-Annotazzjoni Konċettwali Universali (UCCA) hija skema semantika ta’ annotazzjoni li torganizza t-testi fi struttura grossa ta’ predikat-argument, li toffri kopertura wiesgħa ta’ fenomeni semantiċi. Fl-istess ħin, għad hemm il-ħtieġa għal trattament a ħjar tal-ħbub ta’ ħafna mill-kategoriji. Il-kategorija Adverbjali hija ta’ interess speċjali, peress li tkopri firxa wiesgħa ta’ tifsiriet fundamentalment differenti bħan-negazzjoni, il-kawżalità, l-aspett u l-kwantifikazzjoni tal-avvenimenti. F’dan id-dokument a ħna nintroduċu skema ta’ annotazzjoni tar-raffinar għall-kategorija Adverbjali tal-UCCA, li turi li l-Adverbial s tal-UCCA jistgħu tabilħaqq jiġu sottokategorijati f’mill-inqas 7 tipi semantiċi, u li tagħmel dan jista’ jgħin biex jiġu ċċarati u diżambigwati t-tikketti b’ħbub gross inkella. Aħna nipprovdu sett preliminari ta’ linji gwida ta’ annotazzjoni, kif ukoll esperimenti pilot a ta’ annotazzjoni bi ftehim għoli bejn l-annotaturi, li jikkonfermaw il-validità tal-iskema.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) гэдэг нь мөнгө дүгнэх аргументын бүтэц болгон зохион байгуулагдаж, semantic phenomena дээр шинэ мэдээлэл өгдөг. Яг ижил хугацаанд олон категориудын эмчилгээ илүү сайхан эмчилгээ хэрэгтэй. Адвербал хэсэг нь маш их сонирхолтой, учир нь энэ нь хамаагүй, шалтгаан, асуудал, үйл явдлын тоо хэмжээний олон янз бүрийн утга учиртай. Энэ цаасан дээр бид UCCA-ын Адвербалын хэлбэрийн төлбөрийн төлбөрийн төлбөрийн төлбөрийн загварыг тайлбарлаж, UCCA-ын Адвербалын төлбөрийн төлбөр хамгийн бага 7 семантийн төрлийн төлбөрт хуваалцах боломжтой болно. Бид анзаарлын удирдагчийн хэлбэрүүдийг дамжуулж, туршилтын анзаарлын туршилтуудыг хамгийн өндөр анзаарлын зөвшөөрөл байгуулдаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Uniwersalna koncepcyjna adnotacja poznawcza (UCCA) to semantyczny schemat adnotacji, który organizuje teksty w grubą strukturę predykatów-argumentów, oferując szeroki zakres zjawisk semantycznych. Jednocześnie nadal istnieje potrzeba precyzyjniejszego traktowania wielu kategorii. Szczególnie interesująca jest kategoria Adverbial, ponieważ obejmuje szeroki zakres zasadniczo różnych znaczeń, takich jak negacja, związek przyczynowy, aspekt i ilościowe określenie zdarzeń. W niniejszym artykule przedstawiamy schemat adnotacji dla kategorii przeciwników UCCA, pokazujący, że przeciwniki UCCA rzeczywiście mogą być podkategorizowane na co najmniej 7 typy semantyczne, co może pomóc w wyjaśnieniu i rozproszyć gruboziarniste etykiety. Zapewniamy wstępny zestaw wytycznych adnotacyjnych, a także pilotażowych eksperymentów adnotacyjnych z wysoką zgodą między adnotatorami, potwierdzających ważność schematu.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ml>പൊതുവായ കോണ്‍സെപ്റ്റല്‍ കോണ്‍സ്പെറ്റിവ് കോണ്‍ഗ്രിനിറ്റിവ് ആനോട്ടേഷന്‍ (UCCA) ഒരു സെമാന്റിക് വിവരങ്ങളാണ്. പദാവലികള്‍ കോര്‍സിലേക്ക് പ്രത്യേ At the same time, there is still need for a finer-grained treatment of many of the categories.  അഡ്വെര്‍ബിയേല്‍ വ്യവസ്ഥയില്‍ വ്യത്യസ്തമായ താല്‍പര്യമുള്ളതാണ്, അതിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തില്‍ വ്യത്യസ്തമായ വ്യത്യസ്ത വ്യത്യസ്ത അർത്ഥങ് ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ യുസിക്കായുടെ അഡ്വെര്‍ബിയല്‍ വിഭാഗത്തിനുള്ള ഒരു പ്രക്രിയം നാം പരിശോധിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. യുസിക്കാ ആദ്യാബെര്‍ബിയല്‍സിനെ കുറഞ്ഞത് 7 സെമാന്റിക് തരത്തിലാക്കുന്നതാണ നമ്മള്‍ ഒരു പ്രാথমികമായി വിചാരിക്കുന്ന വഴികാട്ടുകള്‍ നല്‍കുന്നു, പൈലറ്റിന്റെ വിവേകത പരീക്ഷണങ്ങളും ഉയര്‍ത്തിയിരിക്കുന്നു പ്രക്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_no>Universell konseptuelle kognitiv notasjon (UCCA) er eit semantisk notasjonsskjema som organiserer tekstar til korse predikativ argument- struktur, som tilbyr breidde dekning av semantiske fenomenar. Samtidig er det likevel nødvendig å behandla fleire av kategoriane. Adverbialkategorien har spesielt interesse, sidan han dekkar eit brett område av grunnleggjande ulike meningar som negasjon, forårsaken, aspekt og kvantifikasjon av hendingar. I denne papiret introduserer vi ein refineringsnotasjonsskjema for UCCA sin Adverbial- kategori, som viser at UCCA Adverbial s kan vere underkategorisert i minst 7 semantiske typar, og det kan hjelpa å klargjera og slå av dei andre kryssarte etikettane. Vi gjev eit førehandsvising av merkingslinjer, og pilotnotasjonseksperimenter med høg mellommerkingslinjer, som stadfestar om skjemaet er gyldig.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) este o schemă de adnotare semantică care organizează textele în structură predicat-argument grosieră, oferind o acoperire largă a fenomenelor semantice. În același timp, mai este nevoie de un tratament mai fin pentru multe dintre categorii. Categoria Adverbial este de interes deosebit, deoarece acoperă o gamă largă de semnificații fundamental diferite, cum ar fi negarea, cauzalitatea, aspectul și cuantificarea evenimentelor. În această lucrare introducem o schemă de adnotare de rafinare pentru categoria Adverbial UCCA, arătând că Adverbials UCCA pot fi subcategorizate în cel puțin 7 tipuri semantice, și făcând acest lucru poate ajuta la clarificarea și dezambiguizarea etichetelor cu granulație altfel grosieră. Oferim un set preliminar de ghiduri de adnotare, precum și experimente pilot de adnotare cu acord inter-adnotator ridicat, confirmând validitatea schemei.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalka caalamiga ah (UCCA) waa qorshaha halka ka mid ah oo u qabanqaabinaya qoraalka kooxaha dhismaha argumentada, kaasoo bixiya daboolka dhimiska ah. Isla waqtigaas waxaa weli loo baahan yahay daryeel aad u fiican oo kala duduwan. Qaybta Adverbial waa mid gaar ah, sababtoo ah waxay qarisaa noocyo badan oo aasaasi ah, tusaale ahaan negative, sababo, dhinac iyo qiyaastii dhacdooyinka. Warqadan waxaan ku qornaa qorshaha hagaajiya ee UCCA’s Adverbial category, waxaana muujinaynaa in UCCA Adverbials lagu kala qeybin karo ugu yaraan 7 noocyo semantic ah, waxaadna ka caawinaysaa in uu caddeeyo oo kala dudeeyo alaabta kale ee kooxaha lagu qoray. Waxaannu qornaa hagitaanka caadiga ah ee hore, sidoo kale imtixaanka baaritaanka ee pilot ee heshiiska aad u dhexeeya, si aan u xaqiijinno xaqiijinta qorshaha.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) är ett semantiskt annotationsschema som organiserar texter i grov predikat-argumentstruktur, som erbjuder bred täckning av semantiska fenomen. Samtidigt behövs det fortfarande en finkornig behandling av många av kategorierna. Kategorin Adverbial är av särskilt intresse, eftersom den täcker ett brett spektrum av fundamentalt olika betydelser såsom negation, orsakssamband, aspekt och händelsekvantifiering. I denna uppsats introducerar vi ett förfiningsschema för annotering av UCCA:s Adverbial kategori, som visar att UCCA Adverbials verkligen kan underkategoriseras i minst 7 semantiska typer, och att göra det kan hjälpa till att klargöra och missförstå de annars grovkorniga etiketterna. Vi tillhandahåller en preliminär uppsättning riktlinjer för anteckningar, samt pilotförsök med hög inter-annotator överenskommelse, vilket bekräftar systemets giltighet.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_sr>Univerzalna konceptualna kognitivna annotacija (UCCA) je semantička programa annotacije koja organizuje tekste u bezobraznu predikativnu strukturu argument a, nudi široko pokrivanje semantičkih fenomena. U isto vreme, još uvek postoji potreba za boljim terapijom mnogih kategorija. Adverbijalna kategorija ima poseban interes, jer pokriva širok niz osnovno različitih značenja kao što su negacija, uzrok, aspekt i kvantifikacija događaja. U ovom papiru predstavljamo program za annotaciju refinencije za Adverbijalnu kategoriju UCCA-a, pokazujući da Adverbial s UCCA zaista može biti podkategoriziran u najmanje 7 semantičkih tipova, i to može pomoći da objasni i disambiguje inače prezrene etikete. Mi pružamo preliminarni set uputstva za annotaciju, kao i eksperimenti za annotaciju pilot a sa visokim interannotatorskim sporazumom, potvrđujući validnost šeme.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>ජාතික ප්‍රතිස්ථාපනය සම්පූර්ණ සන්පූර්ණ සන්පූර්ණ සන්පූර්ණ සන්පූර්ණ සන්පූර්ණ සම්පූර්ණය (UCCA) තමයි සෙමාන එකම වෙලාවෙන්, තවමත් විශේෂ වර්ගයක් ගොඩක් ගොඩක් ගොඩක් විදිහට අවශ්‍ය වෙනවා. විශේෂ විශේෂ වර්ගයක් විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂ වර්ගයක් තියෙනවා, ඒ වගේම මූලික විශේෂ වෙනස් අදහස් ව මේ පත්තරේ අපි UCCA ගේ ප්‍රවේශණ පත්තර සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ප්‍රවේශනය කරන්න පුළුවන් කියලා, පෙන්වන්නේ, UCCA ක්‍රීඩාර්බියල් ඇත්තටම අඩුම 7 සෙමාන්තික වර්ගයක් වලට අපි ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රයෝජනයක් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා, පියාලෝට් ප්‍රයෝජනයක් ප්‍රයෝජනයක් වගේම ප්‍රයෝජනයක් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා, ස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) ایک سیمنٹی اظہار طریقہ ہے جس نے پیغامات کو کڑک سے اظہار کرنے والی حکومت کی ساختاری میں سازما کرتا ہے، جو سیمنٹی اظہار کی وسیع اظہار کرتی ہے۔ اسی طرح، بہت سی قسموں کے مطابق اچھی دانے کے لئے بھی ضرورت ہے. انڈیربول کاٹی ویسی علاقه کے ساتھ ہے، جیسے اس نے بنیادی طرح مختلف معلومات کو پورا کرتا ہے، جیسے منفی، دلیل، الگو، اور حادثہ کی تعداد. ہم اس کاغذ میں UCCA کے اپنا انڈربیل کائٹیوں کے لئے ایک رافینینٹ انٹوریٹ اسکیم کو پیش آتے ہیں، جو دکھاتے ہیں کہ UCCA انڈربیلز یقیناً حد سے کم ۷ سیمنٹی ٹائپ میں زیر کاٹوریٹ کر دیے جاتے ہیں، اور اس طرح یہ کام صریح کر سکتے ہیں اور غیر طرح طرح طرح کے ان ہم نے ایک پہلی مجموعہ ہدایت دینے والی ہدایت دی ہے، اور pilot annotation experiments with high inter annotator agreement, confirming the validity of the scheme.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>பொதுவான மாற்று குறியீட்டு அறிவிப்பு (UCCA) ஒரு பெமான்டிக் அறிவிப்பு முறைமையாகும். அது உரைகளை முன்னிருப்பு வார்ப்பு அமைப்புகளாக அமைக்கும், ப அதே நேரத்தில், இன்னும் பல வகுப்புகளில் சிறந்த சிகிச்சைக்கு தேவைப்படுகிறது. முன்னிருப்பு வகுப்பு சிறப்பு வட்டியாகும், ஏனெனில் அது நிகழ்வு அளவு போன்ற மாதிரியான வித்தியாசமான வித்தியாசம் மூடுகிறது. இந்த காகிதத்தில் நாம் UCCA's Adverbial வகைக்கு ஒரு புதுப்பிப்பு அறிவிப்பு முறைமையை அறிவிக்கிறோம், UCCA Adverbials உண்மையில் குறைந்தது 7 பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது என்பதை குறைந்தது 7 வகைகளாக பிர நாம் ஒரு முன்னிருப்பு அறிவிப்பு நேர்வழிகாட்டிகளை வழங்குகிறோம், மற்றும் மேலும் திட்டத்தின் மதிப்பை உறுதிப்படுத்தும் விள</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_vi>Thông chú tác nhận thức chung là một chương trình đánh chú theo ngữ nghĩa nghĩa, tổ chức văn bản vào cấu trúc văn bản khó khăn nhất, cung cấp sự ảnh hưởng rộng về hiện tượng ngữ pháp. Tuy nhiên, vẫn cần một cách xử lý tốt hơn nhiều loại. Tính năng làm nghịch thì rất quan trọng, vì nó bao gồm cả một loạt các ý nghĩa về cơ bản khác nhau như là từ chối, nguyên nhân, khía cạnh và định lượng sự kiện. Trong tờ giấy này, chúng ta s ẽ tiến hành một kế hoạch ghi chú tinh chỉnh cho hạng Cơ Quan Trái Đất, cho thấy rằng Cơ Quan Trái Đất có thể được phân loại thành ít nhất bảy loại ngữ văn học, và làm thế có thể giúp làm rõ và phá vỡ các nhãn màu sắc khác. Chúng tôi cung cấp một bộ hướng dẫn ghi chú sơ bộ, cũng như các thí nghiệm ghi chú phi công với thỏa thuận liên tục đạt mức độ cao, xác nhận giá trị của dự án.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Umumiy kognitiv taʼrif (UCCA) ni semantik taʼminlovchi qolipi, bu matnlarni koʻpaytirish uchun pre-argumentlar strukturega qoʻshish mumkin. Bu semantik fenometika kengaytmalarni qoʻllash mumkin. Shunday paytda ko'pchilik guruhlarning ko'pchiligi ajoyib tizimi kerak. Tashqi turi juda muhim qiziqari, chunki u asosiy ko'plab turli ma'lumot, negativ sabablar, aspekt va hodisa aniqlash imkoniyatini qaraydi. Bu hujjatda biz UCCAning Adverbial kategoriga taʼminlov qolipini anglatamiz. UCCA Adverbial s haqida 7 semantik turlariga kattalashtirish mumkin. Bunday qilish uchun boshqa ko'plab qo'llangan lablarni aniqlashga yordam beradi. Biz birinchi birinchi taqdimot qoidalarini, va qo'llanmalarning haqiqiqiyligini tasdiqlash imkoniyatini bajaramiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_bg>Универсална концептуална когнитивна анотация (UCCA) е семантична анотация схема, която организира текстовете в груба предикатно-аргументна структура, предлагаща широко покритие на семантични явления. В същото време все още има нужда от по-фино третиране на много от категориите. Категорията е от особен интерес, тъй като обхваща широк спектър от фундаментално различни значения като отричане, причинно-следствена връзка, аспект и количествено определяне на събитието. В тази статия въвеждаме схема за анотация за категорията, показваща, че рекламите наистина могат да бъдат подкатегоризирани в най-малко 7 семантични типа и това може да помогне за изясняване и изясняване на иначе грубозърнестите етикети. Предоставяме предварителен набор от насоки за анотация, както и пилотни експерименти за анотация с високо междуанотаторно съгласие, потвърждаващи валидността на схемата.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) is een semantisch annotatieschema dat teksten organiseert in grove predicaat-argumentstructuur, met een brede dekking van semantische fenomenen. Tegelijkertijd is er nog steeds behoefte aan een fijnere behandeling van veel van de categorieën. De categorie Adverbiaal is van bijzonder belang, omdat het een breed scala van fundamenteel verschillende betekenissen omvat, zoals ontkenning, causatie, aspect en gebeurteniskwantificering. In dit artikel introduceren we een verfijning annotatieschema voor UCCA's Adverbial categorie, waaruit blijkt dat UCCA Adverbials inderdaad kunnen worden onderverdeeld in ten minste zeven semantische types, en dit kan helpen de anders grove labels te verduidelijken en te verduidelijken. We bieden een voorlopige set annotatie richtlijnen, evenals pilot annotatie experimenten met hoge inter-annotator overeenkomst, die de geldigheid van het schema bevestigen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) er en semantisk anmærkningsskema, der organiserer tekster i grov prædikat-argumentstruktur, der tilbyder bred dækning af semantiske fænomener. Samtidig er der stadig behov for en finere behandling af mange af kategorierne. Kategorien Adverbial er af særlig interesse, da den dækker en bred vifte af fundamentalt forskellige betydninger såsom negation, årsagssammenhæng, aspekt og begivenhedskvantificering. I denne artikel introducerer vi en forbedring annotation ordning for UCCA's Adverbial kategori, der viser, at UCCA Adverbials faktisk kan underkategoriseres i mindst 7 semantiske typer, og at gøre det kan hjælpe med at tydeliggøre og adskille de ellers grovkornede etiketter. Vi leverer et foreløbigt sæt retningslinjer for anmærkninger, samt pilot anmærkninger eksperimenter med høj inter-annotator aftale, der bekræfter ordningens gyldighed.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Univerzalna konceptualna kognitivna annotacija (UCCA) je semantička programa annotacije koja organizira tekste u potpunu predikatnu strukturu argumentacija, nudi široko pokrivanje semantičkih fenomena. U isto vrijeme, još uvijek je potrebna bolja zrnca liječenja mnogim kategorijama. Adverbijalna kategorija ima poseban interes, jer pokriva širok niz temeljno različitih značenja poput negacije, uzroka, aspekta i kvantifikacije događaja. U ovom papiru predstavljamo režim oznake za refinenciju Adverbial kategorije UCCA-a, pokazujući da Adverbial s UCCA-a zaista može biti podkategoriziran u najmanje 7 semantičkih tipova, te to može pomoći da objasni i disambiguje drugačije oznake zrnca. Mi pružamo preliminarni set uputstva za annotaciju, kao i eksperimenti za annotaciju pilot a s visokim interannotatorskim sporazumom, potvrđujući validnost šeme.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) ist ein semantisches Annotationsschema, das Texte in grobe Prädikat-Argument-Struktur organisiert und eine breite Abdeckung semantischer Phänomene bietet. Gleichzeitig besteht noch Bedarf an einer feineren Behandlung vieler Kategorien. Die Kategorie Adverbial ist von besonderem Interesse, da sie ein breites Spektrum grundlegend unterschiedlicher Bedeutungen wie Negation, Kausalität, Aspekt und Ereignisquantifizierung abdeckt. In diesem Beitrag stellen wir ein Annotationsschema für UCCA's Adverbial Kategorie vor, das zeigt, dass UCCA Adverbials tatsächlich in mindestens 7 semantische Typen untergliedert werden können, und dies kann helfen, die ansonsten grobkörnigen Labels zu klären und zu disambiguaren. Wir stellen eine vorläufige Reihe von Annotationsrichtlinien sowie Pilot-Annotationsexperimente mit hoher Inter-Annotator-Übereinstimmung zur Verfügung, die die Gültigkeit des Schemas bestätigen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) adalah skema semantis annotasi yang mengatur teks ke struktur predikat-argumen kasar, menawarkan perlindungan luas fenomena semantis. Pada saat yang sama, masih perlu perawatan yang lebih baik dari banyak kategori. Kategori Adverbial adalah tertarik khusus, karena meliputi jangkauan lebar dari makna yang fundamentally berbeda seperti negatif, penyebab, aspek, dan kuantifikasi peristiwa. Dalam kertas ini kami memperkenalkan skema anotasi refinement untuk kategori Adverbial UCCA, menunjukkan bahwa Adverbial s UCCA benar-benar dapat dibawah kategori ke setidaknya 7 tipe semantis, dan melakukan hal itu dapat membantu mengklarifikasi dan menyambiguasi label-label yang otherwise coarse-grained. Kami menyediakan set awal arah anotasi, serta eksperimen anotasi pilot dengan kesepakatan interanotasi tinggi, mengkonfirmasi kehendak skema.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>유니버설 개념 인지 표기(UCCA)는 텍스트를 대략적인 술어-논원 구조로 구성하여 의미 현상에 대한 광범위한 커버를 제공하는 의미 표기 방안이다.동시에, 여전히 많은 종류에 대해 더욱 세밀한 입도 처리를 해야 한다.장어의 범주는 특수한 의미를 가진다. 왜냐하면 부정, 인과, 체와 사건의 양적 등 광범위한 근본적으로 다른 의미를 포괄하기 때문이다.본고에서 우리는 UCCA 장어의 범주를 정화하는 주석 방안을 소개했는데 UCCA 장어는 적어도 7가지 의미 유형으로 세분화될 수 있음을 나타낸다. 이렇게 하면 굵은 입도 라벨의 잘못된 뜻을 밝히고 없애는 데 도움을 줄 수 있다.우리는 초보적인 주석 지침과 주석자 간의 고도로 일치하는 초보적인 주석 실험을 제공하여 이 방안의 유효성을 증명하였다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>یادآوری شناخته‌ای جهانی (UCCA) یک برنامه‌ی یادآوری semantic است که متن‌ها را به ساختار مجموعه‌های مختلف ساختار می‌کند، پیشنهاد حفاظت گسترده‌ای از پدیده‌های semantic. در همین زمان، هنوز نیاز به درمان زیادی از گروه‌ها وجود دارد. قسمت مصنوعی از علاقه خاصی است، در حالی که آن یک مجموعه عمومی از معنی های متفاوتی مثل منفی، دلیل، منبع و مقدار تعداد رویداد را پوشانده است. در این کاغذ ما یک برنامه اظهار بازسازی برای مجموعه‌ی کاغذ UCCA را معرفی می‌کنیم، که نشان می‌دهد که کنترل‌های UCCA واقعاً می‌توانند به حداقل ۷ نوع semantic تغییر داده شوند، و این‌طور می‌توانند کمک کنند که برنامه‌های غیر قابل توضیح و غیر قابل توضی ما یک مجموعه پیشینه از هدایت‌های نوشته‌ها و آزمایش‌های نوشته‌های خلبان را با توافق بین‌نوشته‌های بزرگ تأیید می‌کنیم، تصدیق می‌کنند قابلیت برنامه‌ها.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Utangazaji wa Kitambua (UCCA) ni mpango wa kutangaza utambulisho wa kimataifa unaoandaa ujumbe wa maandishi katika muundo wa hoja unaoendelea kodi, na kutoa habari pana za matukio ya kimapenzi. Wakati huo huo, bado kuna haja ya matibabu bora zaidi ya makundi mengi. Kikundi cha Utamaduni ni wa maslahi maalum, kwa sababu inahusu mengi mengi ya maana mbalimbali kama vile hasira, sababu, aspect, na uthibitisho wa tukio. Katika karatasi hii tunaonyesha mpango wa kutangaza mabadiliko kwa makundi ya Utetezi wa UCCA, ikionyesha kwamba Utetezi wa UCCA kwa hakika wanaweza kuchaguliwa katika aina ya sekunde 7, na kufanya hivyo inaweza kusaidia kuelezea na kutofautisha maabara mengine yanayofanana na bara. Tunatoa maelekezo ya awali ya uongozi wa taarifa, pamoja na majaribio ya uchochezi wa pili kwa makubaliano makubwa yanayopinga maudhui yanayothibitisha ukweli wa mpango huo.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) bir semantik duyarlama şemasıdır. Metinleri coarse predicate-argument yapısına düzenleyen, semantik fenomenlerin geniş kapasitesi sunuyor. Şol wagtda, kategoriýalaryň köpüsi gowurak tedavi gerek. Rekabetçi kategoriýa häsiýetli gyzyklandyrýar, sebäbi döwletlere görnüşi, sebäbi, aspekt we olaryň ölçülerini golaýlaýar. Bu kagyzda UCCA'yň Adverbial kategoriýasy üçin refinç duýgulama taslamasyny tanyşdyrýarys. Bu şekilde UCCA Adverbiallar hakykatdanam iň azyndan 7 semantik türlere subkategoriýa edilebilir we bu şekilde özüniň üstüne düzümlenmäge kömek edip biler. Biz başlangyç duýdurma düzgünlerini, pilot duýdurma deneyleri bilen ýokary duýdurma ylalaşyklary saýlaýrys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>የዓለምአቀፍ ኮንኖፕትዩተር አቀማመጥ (UCCA) ጽሑፎችን ለኮርፖር ለመቀናቀል የአውራጃ ግንኙነት አካባቢ ነው፡፡ በዚያች ሰዓት ብዙዎቹ አካባቢዎች ለመፈለግ የሚሻል ነው፡፡ አዴርብያዊ ክፍል የፍጥረት ጉዳይ ነው፡፡ በዚህ ፕሮግራም የUCCA አዳራቢ ክፍል ላይ የሚያሳየው የአፍሪካ ደረጃዎችን እናሳውቃለን፡፡ የፕሮግራሙን እውነተኛነት ለማረጋገጥ በተቃዋሚ አስተያየት እና የፕሮግራም ተቃውሞ አካባቢ ተፈተና እናደርጋለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sq>Anotacioni Konceptues Universal (UCCA) është një skemë semantike anotacioni që organizon tekstet në strukturë të mëdha predikate-argument, duke ofruar mbulim të gjerë të fenomeneve semantike. Në të njëjtën kohë, ekziston ende nevoja për një trajtim më të mirë të grurit të shumë kategorive. Kategoria Adverbial ka interes të veçantë, pasi mbulon një gamë të gjerë të kuptimeve thelbësisht të ndryshme të tilla si negativa, shkaku, aspekti dhe kuantifikimi i ngjarjeve. Në këtë letër ne futim një skemë përmirësimi të anotacionit për kategorinë Adverbial të UCCA, duke treguar se Adverbial s UCCA mund të nënkategorizohen në të paktën 7 tipe semantike, dhe duke bërë këtë mund të ndihmojë të qartësohet dhe të çambiguahet etiketat përndryshe me kokrra të mëdha. Ne ofrojmë një sërë udhëzimesh paraprake të anotacionit si dhe eksperimente pilote të anotacionit me marrëveshje të lartë ndër-anotatorë, duke konfirmuar vlerësinë e skemës.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_af>Universele Konsensieële Kognitiewe Opmerking (UCCA) is 'n semantiese annotasie skema wat tekste organiseer in kors predikaat-argument struktuur, wat breeddekking van semantiese fenomene aanbied. Op dieselfde tyd is daar nog nodig vir 'n finer koring behandeling van baie van die kategorie. Die Adverbiale kategorie is van spesiale belang, omdat dit 'n wyde omvang van fundamenteel verskillende betekenings soos negasie, veroorsaak, aspek en gebeurtenis quantifikaasie bedek. In hierdie papier introduseer ons 'n refineeringsannotasie skema vir UCCA se Adverbial kategorie, wys dat UCCA Adverbial s sekerlik subkategoriseer kan word in ten minste 7 semantiese tipes, en dit kan help om die anders coarse-grained etikette te klarifiseer en ontwikkel. Ons verskaf 'n voorafinstelling van annotasie gidsline, en pilot annotasie eksperimente met hoë inter annotator ooreenkoms, bevestig die geldigheid van die skema.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_az>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) bir semantik annotation schemadńĪr ki, m…ôktublarńĪ d…ôyiŇüik-d…ôyiŇüik arq√ľm…ôt strukturasńĪna organize edir, semantik fenomenl…ôrin geniŇü √∂rt√ľs√ľn√ľ t…ôblińü edir. AynńĪ zamanda, √ßoxlu kategoriyalarńĪn daha yaxŇüńĪ t…ôhsil edilm…ôsi lazńĪmdńĪr. Adverbial kategoriyasńĪ x√ľsusiyy…ôtli maraqlardandńĪr, √ß√ľnki o, negasyon, neden, aspekt v…ô olaraq kvantifikasiyasńĪ kimi √ßox f…ôrqli anlamlarńĪ √∂rt√ľr. Bu kańüńĪtda UCCA'nin Adverbial kategoriyasńĪ √ľ√ß√ľn refinement annotation schemi t…ôŇükil edirik, ki UCCA Adverbial s h…ôqiq…ôt…ôn …ôn …ôn az 7 semantik t√ľrl…ôr…ô aparńĪla bil…ôr, v…ô bunu bel…ô ed…ô bil…ôr ki, baŇüqasńĪnńĪn d…ôyiŇüiklik etiketl…ôrini a √ßńĪq-aydńĪnlaŇüdńĪrmańüa v…ô d…ôyiŇüiklik etm…ôy…ô k√∂m…ôk ed…ô bil…ôr. Biz …ôvv…ôlc…ô t…ôblińü dońüruluqlarńĪnńĪ t…ôsdiql…ôyirik, h…ôm√ßinin pilot t…ôblińü etm…ôyi t…ôsdiql…ôyirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ের কনসেপ্টুয়াল কনফিনিটিভ কোনোটেশন (ইউসিকিএ) হচ্ছে একটি সেমেন্টিক বিজ্ঞাপন পরিকল্পনা, যা টেক্সট কোর্সের পূর্ববর্তী যুক্তিক কা একই সাথে অনেক বিভাগের চিকিৎসার প্রয়োজন আছে। এ্যাডভার্বিয়াল বিভাগের বিশেষ আগ্রহের জন্য, কারণ এটি মৌলিক বিভিন্ন ব্যাপারে প্রচার মানে যেমন নেতিবাচক, কারণ, দৃশ্য এবং অনুষ্ঠা এই কাগজটিতে আমরা ইউসিকার অ্যাডভার্বিয়াল বিভাগের জন্য একটি সংস্কারের বিশেষ পরিকল্পনা চিহ্নিত করেছি, যেখানে দেখাচ্ছি যে ইউসিকা এডভার্বার্বিয়ালদের অন্তত ৭ সেম্পেন্টিক ধরনের মধ আমরা প্রাথমিকভাবে একটি পরিচালনা নির্দেশ দিয়েছি এবং একই সাথে পাইলটের বিভিন্ন পরীক্ষার পরীক্ষা দিয়েছি, যারা এই পরিকল্পনার বৈধ বৈধতা ন</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Univerzalna konceptualna kognitivna annotacija (UCCA) je semantička annotacija koja organizuje tekste u bezobraznu predikatnu strukturu argument a, nudi široko pokrivanje semantičkih fenomena. U isto vrijeme, još uvijek postoji potreba za boljim terapijom mnogih kategorija. Adverbalna kategorija ima poseban interes, jer pokriva širok niz osnovno različitih značenja poput negacije, uzroka, aspekta i kvantifikacije događaja. U ovom papiru predstavljamo režimu oznake za refinenciju Adverbijalne kategorije UCCA-e, pokazujući da Adverbial s UCCA-a zaista može biti podkategoriziran u najmanje 7 semantičkih tipova, i to može pomoći da objasni i disambiguje drugačije oznake s kornjama. Mi pružamo preliminarni set uputstva za annotaciju, kao i eksperimenti za annotaciju pilot a sa visokim interannotatorskim sporazumom, potvrđujući validnost šeme.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_hy>Համաշխարհային Կենցեպտիվ Գիտատիվ Նոտացիան (UCCA) սեմանտիկ Նոտացիայի ծրագիր է, որը կազմակերպում է տեքստերը դաժան նախադասությունների կառուցվածքի մեջ, և առաջարկում է սեմանտիկ երևույթների լայն ծավալը: Միևնույն ժամանակ, անհրաժեշտ է ավելի լավ բուժել բազմաթիվ կատեգորիաներից: Աբերբիալ կատեգորիան հատուկ հետաքրքրություն ունի, քանի որ այն ներառում է բազմաթիվ հիմնականում տարբեր իմաստներ, ինչպիսիք են բացասատումը, պատճառը, ասպեկտը և իրադարձությունների չափման: Այս թղթի մեջ մենք ներկայացնում ենք UCCA-ի հակառակ կատեգորիայի բարելավման նշումների ծրագիր, որը ցույց է տալիս, որ UCCA-ի հակառակ կատեգորիաները իսկապես կարող են ենթակատեգորիանել առնվազն 7 սեմանտիկ տեսակի, և դա կարող է օգնել պարզաբանել և անբացատրել հակառակ հակառակ հա Մենք տրամադրում ենք նախաձեռնական խումբ նոտացիաների ուղղություններ, ինչպես նաև փորձարկվող նոտացիաների փորձեր, որոնք ունեն բարձր միջնոտացիաների համաձայնություն, որը հաստատում է ծրագրի ճշմարտությունը:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_cs>Univerzální koncepční kognitivní anotace (UCCA) je sémantické anotace schéma, které organizuje texty do hrubé struktury predikátů-argumentů, nabízející široké pokrytí sémantických jevů. Zároveň je stále potřeba jemnějšího zpracování mnoha kategorií. Kategorie Adverbiální je zvláštním zájmem, protože pokrývá širokou škálu zásadně odlišných významů, jako je negace, příčina, aspekt a kvantifikace událostí. V tomto článku představujeme upřesnění anotace pro kategorii Adverbiální kategorie UCCA, které ukazuje, že Adverbiály UCCA mohou být skutečně podkategorizovány do alespoň sedmi sémantických typů, a to může pomoci objasnit a rozjasnit jinak hrubozrnné štítky. Poskytujeme předběžný soubor anotačních pokynů, stejně jako pilotní anotační experimenty s vysokou dohodou mezi anotátory, které potvrzují platnost schématu.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) on semanttinen huomautusjärjestelmä, joka järjestää tekstit karkeaksi predikaatti-argumenttirakenteeksi tarjoten laajan kattavuuden semanttisista ilmiöistä. Samaan aikaan monien luokkien hienojakoista käsittelyä tarvitaan edelleen. Adverbiaalinen luokka on erityisen mielenkiintoinen, koska se kattaa laajan valikoiman perustavanlaatuisesti erilaisia merkityksiä, kuten kieltäminen, syy-yhteys, aspekti ja tapahtuman kvantifiointi. Tässä artikkelissa esittelemme UCCA:n Adverbial-luokan täsmennysmerkinnän, joka osoittaa, että UCCA Adverbial -merkinnät voidaan todellakin luokitella vähintään seitsemään semanttiseen tyyppiin, ja tämä voi auttaa selventämään ja selventämään muuten karkeita etikettejä. Tarjoamme alustavan joukon huomautusohjeita sekä pilottikokeita, joissa on korkea huomautusten välinen yhteisymmärrys, vahvistaen järjestelmän pätevyyden.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ca>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) és un esquema semàntic d'anotació que organitza textos en una estructura grossa de predicat-argument, oferint una gran cobertura de fenomens semàntics. Al mateix temps, encara hi ha necessitat un tractament millor de grans en moltes de les categories. La categoria adveerbial té un interès especial, perquè cobre una gran varietat de significats fonamentalment diferents com la negatió, la causació, l'aspecte i la quantificació d'events. In this paper we introduce a refinement annotation scheme for UCCA's Adverbial category, showing that UCCA Adverbials can indeed be subcategorized into at least 7 semantic types, and doing so can help clarify and disambiguate the otherwise coarse-grained labels.  Oferecem un conjunt preliminar de directrices d'anotació, i experiments pilotes d'anotació amb un gran acord entre anotators, confirmant la validez del esquema.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_et>Universaalne kontseptuaalne kognitiivne annotatsioon (UCCA) on semantiline annotatsiooniskeem, mis korraldab tekstid jämedaks predikaadi-argumendi struktuuriks, pakkudes laialdast semantilisi nähtusi. Samal ajal on paljude kategooriate puhul endiselt vaja peenemat töötlemist. Erilist huvi pakub Adverbial kategooria, kuna see hõlmab palju põhimõtteliselt erinevaid tähendusi, nagu eitamine, põhjuslik seos, aspekt ja sündmuste kvantifitseerimine. Käesolevas töös tutvustame UCCA Adverbial kategooriale täpsustatud annotatsiooni skeemi, mis näitab, et UCCA Adverbial saab tõepoolest alakategooriaks jagada vähemalt seitsmeks semantiliseks tüübiks ja see võib aidata selgitada ja selgitada muidu jämeda teraga silte. Pakume esialgseid annotatsioonijuhiseid, samuti pilootannotatsioonikatseid kõrge annotatoridevahelise kokkuleppega, mis kinnitavad skeemi kehtivust.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ha>Annonation na Universal Conceptural Cognitive Annonation (UCCA) is a semantic array which organizes text to coare-architectura pre-argument, offers broad coverup of semantic fenomen. Kuma daidai da haka, ba za a ƙayyade wata cuta mai kyau wa wasu nau'i. category The Adverbisl is of special interessence, as it covers widen wasu ma'anar dabam-dabam, kamar negative, sababi, aspecti, da tsarin event. Ga wannan takardan, za mu introduce wani shirin zartar gaske wa UCCA's Adverbiyal, mai nuna cewa, lalle ne za a iya samarara UCCA Adverbiyals ko da a ƙara 7-nau'i, kuma idan an aikata shi yana iya taimakon ka bayyana kuma ka rarrabe wasu alama na daban-hanyoyi. Mu sami shiryarwa na farko, da sami masu jarrabi taƙaitacce da masu gaskatãwa ga shirin ayuka.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Univerzalna konceptualna kognitivna opomba (UCCA) je semantična shema opombe, ki organizira besedila v grobo strukturo predikatov-argumentov in ponuja široko pokritost semantičnih pojavov. Hkrati pa je še vedno potrebna natančnejša obravnava številnih kategorij. Neželena kategorija je posebej zanimiva, saj zajema širok spekter bistveno različnih pomenov, kot so zanikanje, vzročna zveza, vidik in kvantifikacija dogodkov. V tem prispevku predstavljamo shemo označevanja za kategorijo UCCA Adverbial, ki kaže, da je UCCA Adverbials dejansko mogoče podkategorizirati v vsaj 7 semantičnih tipov, kar lahko pomaga pojasniti in razjasniti sicer grobo zrnate oznake. Zagotavljamo predhodni sklop smernic za označevanje, kot tudi pilotne poskuse označevanja z visokim medoznačevanjem, ki potrjujejo veljavnost sheme.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) is a semantic annotation scheme that organizes texts into coarse predicate-argument structure, offering broad coverage of semantic phenomena. དེ་རིང་གཅིག་མཚུངས་ན། དབྱེ་རིགས་མི་མང་པོ་ཞིག་གི་སྐྱེས་རྫས་ལེགས་སྤྱོད་དགོས་མིན་འདུག དབྱེ་སྡུད་གྱི་དབྱེ་སྟངས་དེ་དམིགས་བསལ་བ་ཞིག་ཡོད། In this paper we introduce a refinement annotation scheme for UCCA's Adverbial category, showing that UCCA Adverbials can indeed be subcategorized into at least 7 semantic types, and doing so can help clarify and disambiguate the otherwise coarse-grained labels. This is the case in which UCCA Adverbials can be subcategorized into at least 7 semantic types, and doing so can help clarify and disambiguate the otherwise coarse-grained labels. ང་ཚོས་ཨ་རྟགས་འདི་ལྟ་བུའི་གནད་དོན་གྱི་སྔོན་གྱི་སྒྲིག་འགོད་གནད་དོན་དག་གི་སྒྲིག</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_jv>Universal CoGNual CoGNative Text (UKA) bukane sematik dadi agetan seneng nggawe texti luar arno sistem podhayo perusahaan-argument, iso disenyongno akeh kapan sematik dadi. neng sampeyan ngono, durung-sampeyan nganggo dolanan nganggo dolanan sing paling apik kategori. category In this paper we Intake a refining anntations scheme for the Advertural category of UKA, Display that UKA Advertural s can really be Subcategory Awak dhéwé ngewehke perusahaan nggawe Stifta sing nggawe, lan ngono nggawe Stifta sing perusahaan karo ngono nggawe inter-annTatar sing apik dhéwé, nggawe nguasai perusahaan winih.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>Universal Conceptual Cognitive Annotation (UCCA) is a semantic annotation scheme that organizes texts into coarse predicate-argument structure, offering broad coverage of semantic phenomena.  At the same time, there is still need for a finer-grained treatment of many of the categories.  הקטגוריה הריבית היא של עניין מיוחד, כיוון שהיא מכסה מגוון רחב של משמעות שונות בסיסית כמו שליטה, סיבה, ספקטיב, וקוונטיבי אירוע. בעיתון הזה אנחנו מציגים מערכת ציוני שיפור עבור הקטגוריה הריבית של UCCA, שמראה כי UCCA Adverbial s באמת יכול להיות מתקategorized לתוך לפחות 7 סוגים סמנטיים, וכך שעושים זאת יכול לעזור להבהיר ולהפריע את התוויות אחרת עם גרעינים גסים. אנחנו מספקים קבוצה קודמית של מדריכי ציונים, כמו גם ניסויים ציונים טייסים עם הסכם בין-ציונים גבוה, אשר מאשר את קבילות התוכנית.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    <paper id="18">
      <title>WikiGUM : Exhaustive Entity Linking for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikification">Wikification</a> in 12 Genres<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>iki<fixed-case>GUM</fixed-case>: Exhaustive Entity Linking for Wikification in 12 Genres</title>
      <author><first>Jessica</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Amir</first><last>Zeldes</last></author>
      <pages>170–175</pages>
      <abstract>Previous work on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entity_Linking">Entity Linking</a> has focused on resources targeting non-nested proper named entity mentions, often in data from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia">Wikipedia</a>, i.e. Wikification. In this paper, we present and evaluate WikiGUM, a fully wikified dataset, covering all mentions of named entities, including their non-named and pronominal mentions, as well as mentions nested within other mentions. The dataset covers a broad range of 12 written and spoken genres, most of which have not been included in Entity Linking efforts to date, leading to poor performance by a pretrained SOTA system in our evaluation. The availability of a variety of other annotations for the same data also enables further research on entities in context.</abstract>
      <url hash="a46c418a">2021.law-1.18</url>
      <bibkey>lin-zeldes-2021-wikigum</bibkey>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.law-1.18</doi>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/gum">GUM</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/ipm-nel">IPM NEL</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/nne">NNE</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>