<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.gebnlp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Gender Bias in Natural Language Processing</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Marta</first><last>Costa-jussa</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Hila</first><last>Gonen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Christian</first><last>Hardmeier</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Kellie</first><last>Webster</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="38ae9296">2021.gebnlp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="9df1219b">2021.gebnlp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>gebnlp-2021-gender</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>Gender Bias Hidden Behind Chinese Word Embeddings : The Case of Chinese Adjectives<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese Word Embeddings: The Case of <fixed-case>C</fixed-case>hinese Adjectives</title>
      <author><first>Meichun</first><last>Jiao</last></author>
      <author><first>Ziyang</first><last>Luo</last></author>
      <pages>8–15</pages>
      <abstract>Gender bias in word embeddings gradually becomes a vivid research field in recent years. Most studies in this field aim at measurement and debiasing methods with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> as the target language. This paper investigates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender bias</a> in static word embeddings from a unique perspective, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_adjectives">Chinese adjectives</a>. By training word representations with different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">models</a>, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender bias</a> behind the vectors of adjectives is assessed. Through a comparison between the produced results and a human scored data set, we demonstrate how gender bias encoded in word embeddings differentiates from people’s attitudes.</abstract>
      <url hash="509ba7f6">2021.gebnlp-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.gebnlp-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>jiao-luo-2021-gender</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Evaluating Gender Bias in Hindi-English Machine Translation<fixed-case>H</fixed-case>indi-<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>nglish Machine Translation</title>
      <author><first>Krithika</first><last>Ramesh</last></author>
      <author><first>Gauri</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Sanjay</first><last>Singh</last></author>
      <pages>16–23</pages>
      <abstract>With <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> being deployed increasingly in the real world, it is essential to address the issue of the fairness of their outputs. The word embedding representations of these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language models</a> often implicitly draw unwanted associations that form a social bias within the model. The nature of gendered languages like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a>, poses an additional problem to the quantification and mitigation of bias, owing to the change in the form of the words in the sentence, based on the gender of the subject. Additionally, there is sparse work done in the realm of measuring and debiasing systems for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indo-Aryan_languages">Indic languages</a>. In our work, we attempt to evaluate and quantify the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender bias</a> within a Hindi-English machine translation system. We implement a modified version of the existing TGBI metric based on the grammatical considerations for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a>. We also compare and contrast the resulting bias measurements across multiple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric_(mathematics)">metrics</a> for pre-trained embeddings and the ones learned by our machine translation model.</abstract>
      <url hash="899b8bf2">2021.gebnlp-1.3</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="5b68eee7">2021.gebnlp-1.3.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.gebnlp-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>ramesh-etal-2021-evaluating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Alexa, Google, Siri : What are Your Pronouns? Gender and Anthropomorphism in the Design and Perception of Conversational Assistants<fixed-case>A</fixed-case>lexa, <fixed-case>G</fixed-case>oogle, <fixed-case>S</fixed-case>iri: What are Your Pronouns? Gender and Anthropomorphism in the Design and Perception of Conversational Assistants</title>
      <author><first>Gavin</first><last>Abercrombie</last></author>
      <author><first>Amanda</first><last>Cercas Curry</last></author>
      <author><first>Mugdha</first><last>Pandya</last></author>
      <author><first>Verena</first><last>Rieser</last></author>
      <pages>24–33</pages>
      <abstract>Technology companies have produced varied responses to concerns about the effects of the design of their conversational AI systems. Some have claimed that their voice assistants are in fact not gendered or human-likedespite design features suggesting the contrary. We compare these claims to user perceptions by analysing the pronouns they use when referring to AI assistants. We also examine systems’ responses and the extent to which they generate output which is gendered and anthropomorphic. We find that, while some companies appear to be addressing the ethical concerns raised, in some cases, their claims do not seem to hold true. In particular, our results show that system outputs are ambiguous as to the humanness of the systems, and that users tend to personify and gender them as a result.</abstract>
      <url hash="37fbde43">2021.gebnlp-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.gebnlp-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>abercrombie-etal-2021-alexa</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/GavinAbercrombie/GeBNLP2021" additional="false">GavinAbercrombie/GeBNLP2021</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/persona-chat-1">PERSONA-CHAT</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Gender Bias in Text : Origin, Taxonomy, and Implications</title>
      <author><first>Jad</first><last>Doughman</last></author>
      <author><first>Wael</first><last>Khreich</last></author>
      <author><first>Maya</first><last>El Gharib</last></author>
      <author><first>Maha</first><last>Wiss</last></author>
      <author><first>Zahraa</first><last>Berjawi</last></author>
      <pages>34–44</pages>
      <abstract>Gender inequality represents a considerable loss of human potential and perpetuates a culture of violence, higher gender wage gaps, and a lack of representation of women in higher and leadership positions. Applications powered by Artificial Intelligence (AI) are increasingly being used in the real world to provide critical decisions about who is going to be hired, granted a loan, admitted to college, etc. However, the main pillars of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence">AI</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing (NLP)</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning">Machine Learning (ML)</a> have been shown to reflect and even amplify <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender biases</a> and stereotypes, which are mainly inherited from historical training data. In an effort to facilitate the identification and mitigation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender bias</a> in English text, we develop a comprehensive taxonomy that relies on the following <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender bias types</a> : Generic Pronouns, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexism">Sexism</a>, Occupational Bias, Exclusionary Bias, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantics">Semantics</a>. We also provide a bottom-up overview of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender bias</a>, from its societal origin to its spillover onto language. Finally, we link the societal implications of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender bias</a> to their corresponding type(s) in the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taxonomy_(biology)">taxonomy</a>. The underlying motivation of our work is to help enable the technical community to identify and mitigate relevant biases from training corpora for improved fairness in NLP systems.</abstract>
      <url hash="8a6bc4f6">2021.gebnlp-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.gebnlp-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>doughman-etal-2021-gender</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Sexism in the Judiciary : The Importance of Bias Definition in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP</a> and In Our Courts<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case> and In Our Courts</title>
      <author><first>Noa</first><last>Baker Gillis</last></author>
      <pages>45–54</pages>
      <abstract>We analyze 6.7 million case law documents to determine the presence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_bias">gender bias</a> within our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judiciary">judicial system</a>. We find that current bias detection methods in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> are insufficient to determine gender bias in our case law database and propose an alternative approach. We show that existing algorithms’ inconsistent results are consequences of prior research’s inconsistent definitions of biases themselves. Bias detection algorithms rely on groups of words to represent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a> (e.g., ‘salary,’ ‘job,’ and ‘boss’ to represent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Employment">employment</a> as a potentially biased theme against women in text). However, the methods to build these groups of words have several weaknesses, primarily that the word lists are based on the researchers’ own intuitions. We suggest two new methods of automating the creation of word lists to represent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">biases</a>. We find that our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methods</a> outperform current NLP bias detection methods. Our research improves the capabilities of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP technology</a> to detect <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a> and highlights <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexism">gender biases</a> present in influential case law. In order to test our NLP bias detection method’s performance, we regress our results of bias in case law against <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_Census">U.S census data</a> of women’s participation in the workforce in the last 100 years.</abstract>
      <url hash="0cc4e192">2021.gebnlp-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.gebnlp-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>baker-gillis-2021-sexism</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Investigating the Impact of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_representation">Gender Representation</a> in ASR Training Data : a Case Study on Librispeech<fixed-case>ASR</fixed-case> Training Data: a Case Study on Librispeech</title>
      <author><first>Mahault</first><last>Garnerin</last></author>
      <author><first>Solange</first><last>Rossato</last></author>
      <author><first>Laurent</first><last>Besacier</last></author>
      <pages>86–92</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper we question the impact of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_representation">gender representation</a> in training data on the performance of an end-to-end ASR system. We create an experiment based on the Librispeech corpus and build 3 different training corpora varying only the proportion of data produced by each gender category. We observe that if our system is overall robust to the gender balance or imbalance in training data, it is nonetheless dependant of the adequacy between the individuals present in the training and testing sets.</abstract>
      <url hash="d224b621">2021.gebnlp-1.10</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.gebnlp-1.10</doi>
      <bibkey>garnerin-etal-2021-investigating</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/librispeech">LibriSpeech</pwcdataset>
    <title_es>Investigación del impacto de la representación de género en los datos de capacitación de ASR: un estudio de caso sobre Librispeech</title_es>
      <title_ar>التحقيق في تأثير التمثيل الجنساني في بيانات التدريب على ASR: دراسة حالة على Librispeech</title_ar>
      <title_zh>案ASR培训数代表性:其Librispeech例究之</title_zh>
      <title_ja>ASRトレーニングデータにおける性別表現の影響の調査： Librispeechに対するケーススタディ</title_ja>
      <title_pt>Investigando o impacto da representação de gênero nos dados de treinamento em ASR: um estudo de caso sobre librispeech</title_pt>
      <title_hi>एएसआर प्रशिक्षण डेटा में लिंग प्रतिनिधित्व के प्रभाव की जांच: लिब्रिसपीच पर एक केस स्टडी</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Tionchar Ionadaíocht Inscne i Sonraí Oiliúna ASR a Imscrúdú: Cás-Staidéar ar Librispeich</title_ga>
      <title_hu>A nemek közötti reprezentáció hatásának vizsgálata az ASR képzési adatokban: esettanulmány a Librispeech-ről</title_hu>
      <title_el>Η διερεύνηση των επιπτώσεων της εκπροσώπησης των φύλων στα δεδομένα κατάρτισης ASR: μια μελέτη περίπτωσης για τη βιβλιογραφία</title_el>
      <title_ka>ASR განსწავლების მონაცემების ინტექტირება: Librispeech მონაცემების ინტექტირება</title_ka>
      <title_kk>ASR оқыту деректерінде гендерді таңдау нәтижесін зерттеу: a Case Study on Librispeech</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Lyčių atstovavimo poveikio ASR mokymo duomenise tyrimas: Bibliotekos bylų tyrimas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Истрага на влијанието на полската претстава во податоците за обука на АСР: случајна студија на Librispeech</title_mk>
      <title_it>Indagine sull'impatto della rappresentazione di genere nei dati di formazione ASR: un caso di studio su Librispeech</title_it>
      <title_ml>ASR പരിശീലനത്തിന്റെ ഡേറ്റായില്‍ സ്ത്രീന്‍ പ്രതിനിധികളുടെ പ്രഭാവം അന്വേഷിക്കുന്നു: ലിബ്രിസ്പീചിലെ ഒരു കേസ</title_ml>
      <title_no>Investigerer effekten av generelt representasjon i ASR- treningsdata: ein tilfeldig undersøking om Librispeech</title_no>
      <title_ms>Menyelidiki Kesan Perwakilan Gender dalam Data Latihan ASR: kajian kes pada Librispeech</title_ms>
      <title_pl>Badanie wpływu reprezentacji płci w danych szkoleniowych ASR: studium przypadku Librispeech</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Investigarea impactului reprezentanței de gen în datele de formare ASR: un studiu de caz pe Librispeech</title_ro>
      <title_mt>Investigazzjoni tal-Impatt tar-Rappreżentanza tas-Sessi fid-Dejta dwar it-Taħriġ ASR: Studju ta’ Każ dwar Librispeech</title_mt>
      <title_sr>Istraživanje utjecaja predstavljanja žena u podacima obuke ASR: studija slučajeva o Librispeech</title_sr>
      <title_mn>ASR Training Data: a Case Study on Librispeech</title_mn>
      <title_so>Investigation the Impact of gender Representation in ASR Data Training: a Case Study on Librispeech</title_so>
      <title_si>ASR ප්‍රේෂණික දත්තේ ජෙන්ඩර් ප්‍රතිනිධානයේ පරීක්ෂණය: ප්‍රතිනිධානය සඳහා කේස් පරීක්ෂණය</title_si>
      <title_ta>ASR பயிற்சி தரவில் பெண் பிரதிநிதியின் விளைவு ஆய்வு செய்யப்படுகிறது</title_ta>
      <title_sv>Undersökning av genusrepresentationens effekter i ASR-utbildningsdata: en fallstudie på Librispeech</title_sv>
      <title_ur>ASR ٹرینینگ ڈاٹ میں جنس ریسپانسیٹ کے اثر کا تحقیق کرتا ہے: ایک کیس تحقیق لیبراریسپیچ پر</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Điều tra về ảnh hưởng của quan điểm giới tính trong dữ liệu đào tạo ASR: a Case study on Librispeech</title_vi>
      <title_hr>Istraživanje utjecaja predstavljanja žena u podacima obuke ASR: istraživanje slučaja o Librispeech</title_hr>
      <title_da>Undersøgelse af virkningen af kønsrepræsentation i ASR-uddannelsesdata: et casestudie om Librispeech</title_da>
      <title_bg>Изследване на въздействието на представителството на половете в обучението за АСР данни: казус за Либриспейх</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Onderzoek naar de impact van gendervertegenwoordiging in ASR-opleidingsgegevens: een casestudy op Librispeech</title_nl>
      <title_de>Untersuchung der Auswirkungen der Geschlechtervertretung in ASR-Trainingsdaten: eine Fallstudie zu Librispeech</title_de>
      <title_id>Investigating the Impact of Gender Representation in ASR Training Data: a Case Study on Librispeech</title_id>
      <title_fa>تحقیق اثر نماینده جنسی در اطلاعات آموزش ASR: یک مطالعه پرونده در Librispeech</title_fa>
      <title_ko>ASR 교육 데이터에서 성별의 대표적인 영향에 대한 조사: Librispeech 사례 연구</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Kuchunguza madhara ya kuhakikisha jinsia katika mafunzo ya data ya ASR: Utafiti wa kesi kuhusu Librispeech</title_sw>
      <title_tr>ASR eğitim Maglumatynda Genjer Representationisiň etkisini barlamak: a Case Study on Librispeech</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Hetimi i ndikimit të përfaqësimit të gjinëve në të dhënat e trajnimit të ASR: një studim rasti mbi Librispeech</title_sq>
      <title_am>በASR ትምህርት ዳታ ውስጥ የgender Representation Impact investigating: a Case Study on Librispeech</title_am>
      <title_hy>Սկնդի ներկայացման ազդեցության ուսումնասիրելը ASR-ի ուսումնասիրության տվյալներում. գրադարանի դեպքերի ուսումնասիրություն</title_hy>
      <title_af>Inligting van die Impact van Gender Representation in ASR Oefening Data: 芒聙聶n Kas Studie op Librispeech</title_af>
      <title_bn>আসার প্রশিক্ষণ তথ্যে লিঙ্গ প্রতিনিধির প্রভাব অনুসন্ধান করা হচ্ছে: লিবিস্পেচের একটি কেস স্টিডি</title_bn>
      <title_az>ASR t톛hsil veril톛nl톛rind톛 Gen칞 Representation Impact Investigating in ASR Training Data: a Case Study on Librispeech</title_az>
      <title_bs>Istraživanje utjecaja predstavljanja žena u podacima obuke ASR: istraživanje slučaja o Librispeech</title_bs>
      <title_ca>Investigar l'impacte de la representació de gènere en les dades d'capacitació ASR: un estudi de cas sobre Librispeech</title_ca>
      <title_et>Soolise esindatuse mõju uurimine ASR koolituse andmetes: juhtumiuuring Librispeechi kohta</title_et>
      <title_cs>Vyšetřování vlivu reprezentace pohlaví v ASR tréninkových datech: případová studie na Librispeech</title_cs>
      <title_fi>Sukupuolten edustuksen vaikutusten tutkiminen ASR-koulutuksessa: tapaustutkimus Librispeechistä</title_fi>
      <title_he>חקירת השפעה של מייצג מין בנתונים האימונים של ASR: מחקר מקרים על Librispeech</title_he>
      <title_jv>istraging the Effect of Gender representation in ASR Learning data: a Case Learning on Library</title_jv>
      <title_ha>Inspecting the Effect of gender Reposition in ATR Training Data: a case Research on Librispech</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Preiskava vpliva zastopanosti spolov v podatkih o usposabljanju ASR: študija primera Librispeech</title_sk>
      <title_bo>Investigating the Impact of Gender Representation in ASR Training Data: a Case Study on Librispeech</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>في هذه الورقة ، نشكك في تأثير تمثيل النوع الاجتماعي في بيانات التدريب على أداء نظام ASR الشامل. نقوم بإنشاء تجربة بناءً على مجموعة Librispeech ونبني 3 هيئات تدريب مختلفة تختلف فقط في نسبة البيانات التي تنتجها كل فئة جنس. نلاحظ أنه إذا كان نظامنا قويًا بشكل عام للتوازن بين الجنسين أو عدم التوازن في بيانات التدريب ، فإنه مع ذلك يعتمد على الكفاية بين الأفراد الموجودين في مجموعات التدريب والاختبار.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>En este artículo, cuestionamos el impacto de la representación de género en los datos de capacitación sobre el rendimiento de un sistema ASR integral. Creamos un experimento basado en el corpus de Librispeech y construimos 3 cuerpos de entrenamiento diferentes que varían solo la proporción de datos producidos por cada categoría de género. Observamos que si nuestro sistema es en general sólido para el equilibrio de género o el desequilibrio en los datos de capacitación, depende de la adecuación entre las personas presentes en los conjuntos de capacitación y pruebas.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Neste artigo, questionamos o impacto da representação de gênero nos dados de treinamento no desempenho de um sistema ASR de ponta a ponta. Criamos um experimento baseado no corpus Librispeech e construímos 3 corpora de treinamento diferentes variando apenas a proporção de dados produzidos por cada categoria de gênero. Observamos que, se nosso sistema é globalmente robusto ao equilíbrio de gênero ou desequilíbrio nos dados de treinamento, ele é, no entanto, dependente da adequação entre os indivíduos presentes nos conjuntos de treinamento e teste.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>本稿では，エンドツーエンドのASRシステムのパフォーマンスに対するトレーニングデータにおけるジェンダー表現の影響について疑問を呈する．私たちはLibrispeechコーパスに基づいて実験を作成し、それぞれの性別カテゴリによって生成されたデータの割合のみを変化させる3つの異なるトレーニングコーパスを構築します。私たちは、私たちのシステムがトレーニングデータのジェンダーバランスまたはアンバランスに対して全体的に堅牢である場合でも、トレーニングとテストセットに存在する個人間の妥当性に依存していることを観察します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>इस पेपर में हम एक एंड-टू-एंड एएसआर सिस्टम के प्रदर्शन पर प्रशिक्षण डेटा में लिंग प्रतिनिधित्व के प्रभाव पर सवाल उठाते हैं। हम लिब्रिसपीच कॉर्पस के आधार पर एक प्रयोग बनाते हैं और प्रत्येक लिंग श्रेणी द्वारा उत्पादित डेटा के अनुपात में केवल 3 अलग-अलग प्रशिक्षण निगम का निर्माण करते हैं। हम देखते हैं कि यदि हमारी प्रणाली प्रशिक्षण डेटा में लिंग संतुलन या असंतुलन के लिए समग्र रूप से मजबूत है, तो यह फिर भी प्रशिक्षण और परीक्षण सेट में मौजूद व्यक्तियों के बीच पर्याप्तता पर निर्भर है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Sa pháipéar seo ceistímid an tionchar atá ag ionadaíocht inscne i sonraí oiliúna ar fheidhmíocht an chórais ASR ceann go ceann. Cruthaímid turgnamh bunaithe ar chorpas Librispeech agus tógaimid 3 chorparáid oiliúna dhifriúla nach n-athraítear ach céatadán na sonraí a tháirgeann gach catagóir inscne. Tugaimid faoi deara má tá ár gcóras láidir ar an iomlán don chothromaíocht inscne nó don éagothroime i sonraí oiliúna, go mbraitheann sé mar sin féin ar leordhóthanacht na ndaoine aonair atá i láthair sna tacair oiliúna agus tástála.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_zh>本文质疑培训数中性别代表性对端至端ASR系统性能。 盖Librispeech语料库创一实验,构3异教语料库,性类不同。 吾观之,若吾系统对练数之性,与不平之体,犹决于教试集个体之充分性。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_el>Στην παρούσα εργασία εξετάζουμε τον αντίκτυπο της εκπροσώπησης των φύλων στα δεδομένα κατάρτισης στην απόδοση ενός ολοκληρωμένου συστήματος ΑΣR. Δημιουργούμε ένα πείραμα βασισμένο στο σώμα και κατασκευάζουμε τρία διαφορετικά σώματα εκπαίδευσης που διαφοροποιούν μόνο το ποσοστό των δεδομένων που παράγονται από κάθε κατηγορία φύλου. Παρατηρούμε ότι αν το σύστημά μας είναι γενικά ανθεκτικό στην ισορροπία των φύλων ή στην ανισορροπία στα δεδομένα κατάρτισης, εξαρτάται ωστόσο από την επάρκεια μεταξύ των ατόμων που βρίσκονται στα σύνολα κατάρτισης και δοκιμών.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Jelen tanulmányban megkérdőjelezzük, hogy a nemek közötti reprezentáció milyen hatással van a képzési adatokban egy end-to-end ASR rendszer teljesítményére. Kísérletet hozunk létre a Librispeech corpus alapján, és 3 különböző edzőtestületet építünk, amelyek csak az egyes nemkategóriák szerinti adatok arányát változtatják. Megfigyeljük, hogy ha rendszerünk általánosságban megbízható a nemek közötti egyensúlyhoz vagy a képzési adatok egyensúlyhiányához, akkor azonban attól függ, hogy a képzési és tesztkészletekben részt vevő egyének megfelelő-e.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_ka>ამ დოკუნეში ჩვენ ვაკითხებთ გენდერის გამოსახულების მონაცემების შესახებ ASR სისტემის გაკეთებაზე. ჩვენ ვქმნით ექსპერიმენტი, რომელიც Librispeech corpus-ზე დაბაზიან და 3 განსხვავებული განსწავლების კოპორაცია განსხვავებულია მხოლოდ ყოველ გენდრის კატეგორიაში გამოიყ ჩვენ დავხედავთ, რომ თუ ჩვენი სისტემა ძალიან ძალიან გენექტური ბალანზაციას ან განმავლობას განმავლობაში მონაცემების განმავლობაში, მაგრამ ეს იყოს განმავლობაზე, რომელიც განმავლობაში და ტესტის</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame dokumente mes abejojame lyčių atstovavimo mokymo duomenise poveikiu baigiamosios ASR sistemos veikimui. Mes sukuriame eksperimentą, pagrįstą Librispeech korpusu, ir sukuriame 3 skirtingus mokymo korpusus, kurie skiriasi tik pagal kiekvieną lyties kategoriją gautų duomenų dalis. Mes pastebime, kad jei mūsų sistema apskritai yra patikima siekiant lyčių pusiausvyros ar mokymo duomenų disbalanso, ji vis dėlto priklauso nuo mokymo ir bandymų rinkiniuose dalyvaujančių asmenų tinkamumo.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл қағазда біз ASR жүйесінің соңғы-соңғы жұмыс істеу үшін гендерлік деңгейінің нәтижесін сұрақ береміз. Біз Librispeech корпус негізінде тәжірибе құрып, 3 түрлі оқыту корпорасын құрып, тек әрбір гендер санаттарының деректерінің бөлшегін өзгертіп тұрмыз. Біз, егер жүйеміздің гендер балансы немесе оқыту деректерінің балансы немесе дисбалансы тәжірибесіне қатысты болса, бұл оқыту және сынақтар жиындарының арасындағы адамдардың адамдарының адамдығына тәуелді</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Dalam kertas ini kita mempersoalkan kesan perwakilan jenis dalam data latihan mengenai prestasi sistem ASR akhir-akhir. Kami mencipta eksperimen berdasarkan Librispeech corpus dan membina 3 corpora latihan yang berbeza hanya berbeza proporsi data yang dihasilkan oleh setiap kategori jenis. Kami memperhatikan bahawa jika sistem kita secara keseluruhan kuat untuk keseimbangan jenis atau ketidakseimbangan dalam data latihan, ia tetap bergantung kepada keperluan antara individu yang hadir dalam set latihan dan ujian.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_it>In questo articolo ci interroghiamo sull'impatto della rappresentazione di genere nei dati di formazione sulle prestazioni di un sistema end-to-end ASR. Creiamo un esperimento basato sul corpus Librispeech e costruiamo 3 diversi corpi di allenamento variabili solo la proporzione di dati prodotti da ogni categoria di genere. Osserviamo che se il nostro sistema è complessivamente solido all'equilibrio di genere o allo squilibrio dei dati di formazione, dipende comunque dall'adeguatezza tra le persone presenti nei set di formazione e di test.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ml>ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍ ഞങ്ങള്‍ പ്രദര്‍ശിപ്പിക്കുന്നത് ആസ്ആര്‍ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ അവസാനത്തേക്കുള്ള പ്രകടനത്തെപ്പറ്റിയാണ്. ഞങ്ങള്‍ ലിബ്രിസ്പീച് കോര്‍പ്പുസിനെ അടിസ്ഥാനമാക്കി 3 വ്യത്യസ്ത പരീക്ഷണങ്ങള്‍ ഉണ്ടാക്കുകയും, എല്ലാ ലിബ്രിസ്പീച് വിഭാഗത്തില നമ്മുടെ സിസ്റ്റത്തിന്റെ സംവിധാനത്തെ പൊതുവാക്കുകയോ പരിശീലനത്തിന്റെയും പരിശീലനത്തിന്റെയും ഇടയിലുള്ള വ്യക്തികള്‍ക്കും തമ്മിലുള്ള വ്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>F’dan id-dokument qed nitdubitaw l-impatt tar-rappreżentanza tas-sessi fid-dejta tat-taħriġ dwar il-prestazzjoni ta’ sistema ASR minn tarf sa tarf. Aħna nħolqu esperiment ibbażat fuq il-Librispeech corpus u nibnu 3 korpi differenti ta’ taħriġ li jvarjaw biss il-proporzjon ta’ dejta prodotta minn kull kategorija ta’ sessi. Aħna ninnota li jekk is-sistema tagħna tkun b’mod ġenerali soda għall-bilanċ bejn is-sessi jew l-iżbilanċ fid-dejta tat-taħriġ, hija madankollu dipendenti mill-adegwatezza bejn l-individwi preżenti fis-settijiet tat-taħriġ u l-ittestjar.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ цаасан дээр бид гендер илтгэлийн нөлөөг асууж байна. АСР системийн төгсгөл болон төгсгөл болох өгөгдлийн талаар суралцах өгөгдлийн талаар. Бид Librispeech корпус дээр суурилсан туршилт бий болгож, 3 өөр сургалтын корпора бүтээж, зөвхөн гендер хэлбэрээр бүтээсэн өгөгдлийн хувьд өөрчлөгдөж байна. Хэрэв бидний систем суралцах өгөгдлийн талаар гендерийн тэнцвэрт эсвэл тэнцвэртэй байвал энэ нь суралцах болон шалгах хэмжээнд байгаа хүмүүсийн адилхан байдлын хамааралтай гэдгийг бид анзаарсан.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>W artykule zastanawiamy się nad wpływem reprezentacji płci w danych szkoleniowych na wydajność kompleksowego systemu ASR. Tworzymy eksperyment oparty na korpusie Librispeech i budujemy trzy różne korpusy treningowe zmieniające jedynie proporcję danych produkowanych przez każdą kategorię płci. Zauważamy, że jeśli nasz system jest ogólnie solidny w odniesieniu do równowagi płci lub zaburzeń równowagi w danych szkoleniowych, jest on jednak zależny od adekwatności pomiędzy osobami obecnymi w zestawach szkoleniowych i testowych.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>În această lucrare punem la îndoială impactul reprezentării de gen în datele de formare asupra performanței unui sistem end-to-end ASR. Creăm un experiment bazat pe corpul Librispeech și construim 3 corpuri de formare diferite variind doar proporția de date produse de fiecare categorie de gen. Observăm că, dacă sistemul nostru este, în general, robust în raport cu echilibrul de gen sau dezechilibrul datelor privind formarea, depinde totuși de caracterul adecvat al persoanelor prezente în seturile de formare și testare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mk>Во овој документ се сомневаме во влијанието на претставувањето на половите во податоците за обуката на изведувањето на системот од крај до крај на АСР. Ние создаваме експеримент базиран на Librispeech корпус и изградуваме 3 различни тренинг корпуси кои разликуваат само процентот на податоци произведени од секоја полова категорија. Ние забележуваме дека ако нашиот систем е целосно силен во однос на полова баланс или небаланс во податоците за обука, сепак зависи од соодветноста помеѓу поединците присутни во обуката и тестирањето.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_sr>U ovom papiru sumnjamo na utjecaj predstavljanja spola u podacima o obuci na provedbu sustava ASR-a do kraja. Mi stvorimo eksperiment baziran na Librispeech korpusu i izgradimo 3 različite trening korporacije, razlikujući se samo proporcija podataka proizvođenih od svake kategorije spola. Primećujemo da ako je naš sistem ukupno roban prema spolnoj ravnoteži ili nelagodnosti podataka o obuci, ipak je ovisan o adekvatnosti između pojedinaca koji su prisutni u obuci i testiranju.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_no>I denne papiret spør vi etterspørselen av følgjande representasjon i opplæringsdata om utviklinga av ein ASR- system for slutten til slutten. Vi oppretter ein eksperiment basert på Librispeech corpus og bygger 3 ulike opplæringskorpora som bare varierer proporsjonen av data produserte av kvar sekskategori. Vi observerer at dersom systemet vårt er overalt sterkt til seksbalansen eller ulikheten i opplæringsdata, er det likevel avhengig av adekviteten mellom personene som finst i opplæring og testsettet.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_so>Warqadan waxaynu ka waydiinnaa saamaynta sharciga dadka jinsiga looga dhigo waxbarashada ku saabsan sameynta nidaamka ASR dhammaadka ugu dambaysta. Waxaan sameynaa imtixaan ku saleysan qabriga Librispeech, waxaana dhisnaa shirkado 3 oo kala duduwan oo kala duduwan oo kala duduwan kala duduwan oo kala duduwan kooxo macluumaadka la soo saaray jinsi kasta. Waxaynu fiirinaynaa in haddii nidaamkayagu uu si wada jir ah u geysto balaanshaha jinsiga ama aan la simnaaneyn karo macluumaadka waxbarashada, waxay ku xiran tahay qiimo ku filan dhexdooda dadka ku jira kooxaha waxbarashada iyo imtixaanka.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_si>මේ පත්තරේ අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා ජෙන්ඩර් ප්‍රතිනිධානයගේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් අවසාන ASR පද්ධතියේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් ග අපි ලිබ්රිස්පයිච් කොර්පුස් එක අධාරිත පරීක්ෂණයක් නිර්මාණය කරනවා සහ වෙනස් පරීක්ෂණ කොර්පෝරා තුනක් නිර්ම අපි බලාපොරොත්තු කරනවා අපේ පද්ධතිය සාමාන්‍ය විශ්වාස කරනවා නමුත් අපේ පද්ධතිය සාමාන්‍ය විශ්වාස කරනවා නමුත් ප්‍රශ්නය සහ පරීක්ෂණ ස</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sv>I denna uppsats ifrågasätter vi hur könsrepresentation i utbildningsdata påverkar resultatet av ett heltäckande ASR-system. Vi skapar ett experiment baserat på Librispeech-korpusen och bygger 3 olika träningskorpus som endast varierar andelen data som produceras av varje genuskategori. Vi konstaterar att om vårt system generellt sett är robust mot könsbalansen eller obalansen i utbildningsdata, är det ändå beroende av lämpligheten mellan de individer som deltar i utbildnings- och testuppsättningarna.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த காகிதத்தில் நாம் பெண் பிரதிநிதியின் விளைவுகளை பயிற்சி தகவலில் கேள்வி கேட்கிறோம் ASR முடிவில் முடிவ நாம் லிப்ரிசிக் கூட்டத்தை அடிப்படையில் ஒரு சோதனையை உருவாக்கி ஒவ்வொரு பெண்ணின் வகையில் உருவாக்கும் தரவு வித்தியாசம் மட் We observe that if our system is overall robust to the gender balance or imbalance in training data, it is nonetheless dependant of the adequacy between the individuals present in the training and testing sets.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم اس کاغذ میں سؤال کرتے ہیں کہ جنس کی تعلیم کے ذریعہ ایک آخر-پایان آس آر سیسٹم کے کامیابی پر ڈیٹوں کی تدریس کرتی ہے۔ ہم ایک آزمائش بناتے ہیں لیبریسپیچ کورپوس پر اور تین مختلف ترینس کورپور بناتے ہیں جو صرف ہر جنس کاٹی کے ذریعے پیدا کئے ہوئے ڈاکٹوں کے اندازے متفاوت ہیں. ہم دیکھتے ہیں کہ اگر ہمارا سیستم جنس تعلیم یا غیر قابل تعلیم دیٹوں میں سکھایا گیا ہے تو یہ تعلیم اور آزمائش سٹ میں موجود ہونے والوں کے درمیان مناسب تعلیم کا اعتبار ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu qogʻozdagi biz ASR tizimning oxiriga oxirigi tizimning bajarishi haqida jinsiy representiyasining effekti haqida savol qilamiz. Biz Librispeek kompyuterga asoslangan bir tajribani yaramiz va 3 boshqa ta'lim kompaniyalarini yaratishmiz va faqat har bir jinsiya kategoriga yaratilgan maʼlumot tarkibini o'zgartiradi. Biz tasavvur qilamiz, agar bizning tizimmiz jamiyat jinsiyalar balandligiga yoki taʼminlovchi maʼlumotga o'xshasha bo'lsa, bu ta'lim va sinov satrlarida mavjud odamlarga yetarli bo'lsa.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi đặt câu hỏi về tác động của sự phân phối giới tính trong dữ liệu đào tạo về hiệu quả của hệ thống ASR cuối cùng. Chúng tôi tạo ra một thí nghiệm dựa trên Kinh tế Librispeech và xây dựng ba cơ thể huấn luyện khác nhau chỉ khác với số lượng dữ liệu được sản xuất bởi mỗi loại giới tính. Chúng tôi quan sát rằng nếu hệ thống của chúng tôi hoàn to àn vững chắc về cân bằng giữa giới tính hay mất cân bằng trong dữ liệu về huấn luyện, nó không ảnh hưởng đến sự phù hợp giữa cá nhân có mặt trong các bộ huấn luyện và thử nghiệm.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>In dit artikel onderzoeken we de impact van gender representatie in opleidingsgegevens op de prestaties van een end-to-end ASR systeem. We maken een experiment gebaseerd op het Librispeech corpus en bouwen drie verschillende trainingscorpora's die alleen variëren van het aandeel van de gegevens geproduceerd door elke gendercategorie. Wij constateren dat als ons systeem over het algemeen robuust is tegen het evenwicht tussen mannen en vrouwen of onevenwichtigheid in trainingsgegevens, het desondanks afhankelijk is van de adequaatheid tussen de personen die aanwezig zijn in de trainings- en testsets.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>U ovom papiru sumnjamo na učinak predstavljanja spola u podacima obuke o učinkovitosti sustava ASR-a do kraja. Napravili smo eksperiment na temelju Librispeech korpusa i izgradili 3 različite vježbanje korporacije koje se razlikuju samo dio podataka proizvođenih od svake kategorije spola. Primjećujemo da ako je naš sustav ukupno jak prema spolnoj ravnoteži ili ravnoteži u podacima obuke, ipak je ovisan o adekvatnosti između pojedinaca koji su prisutni u obuci i testiranju.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>In diesem Beitrag wird der Einfluss der Geschlechtervertretung in Trainingsdaten auf die Leistungsfähigkeit eines End-to-End ASR-Systems untersucht. Wir erstellen ein Experiment basierend auf dem Librispeech-Korpus und bauen drei verschiedene Trainingskorpora auf, die nur den Anteil der Daten variieren, die von jeder Geschlechterkategorie produziert werden. Wir stellen fest, dass unser System, wenn es insgesamt robust gegen das Gleichgewicht der Geschlechter oder Ungleichgewichte in den Trainingsdaten ist, dennoch von der Angemessenheit zwischen den in den Trainings- und Testsets anwesenden Personen abhängt.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Dalam kertas ini kita mempertanyakan dampak dari persembahan jenis dalam data latihan tentang prestasi sistem ASR dari akhir ke akhir. Kami menciptakan eksperimen berdasarkan Librispeech corpus dan membangun 3 korpora latihan berbeda yang hanya berbeda proporsi data yang diproduksi oleh setiap kategori jenis. Kita memperhatikan bahwa jika sistem kita secara umum kuat untuk keseimbangan jenis atau ketidakseimbangan dalam data pelatihan, hal itu tetap tergantung dari keperluan antara individu yang hadir dalam set pelatihan dan tes.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>본고에서 우리는 교육 데이터의 성별 대표성이 전체 ASR 시스템 성능에 미치는 영향에 대해 의문을 제기했다.우리는 Librispeech 자료 라이브러리를 토대로 하나의 실험을 만들었고 3개의 서로 다른 훈련 자료 라이브러리를 구축하여 각 성별 유형에 따라 발생하는 데이터 비율만 바꾸었다.만약에 우리 시스템이 교육 데이터 중의 성별 균형이나 불균형에 대해 전체적으로 안정적이라면, 그것은 여전히 교육과 테스트가 집중된 개체 간의 충분성에 달려 있다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_fa>در این کاغذ ما تحت تاثیر نمایش جنسی در داده های آموزش روی انجام یک سیستم ASR پایان و پایان سوال می کنیم. ما یک آزمایش را بر اساس کورپوس لیبریسپیچ ایجاد می کنیم و سه شرکت آموزش متفاوت را ساختیم که تنها نسبت داده های توسط هر گروه جنسی تغییر می دهند. ما مشاهده می کنیم که اگر سیستم ما در کل با تعادل جنسی یا نابرابری در داده های آموزش، بستگی به مناسب بین فردی که در مجموعه آموزش و آزمایش وجود دارند بستگی دارد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_da>I denne artikel sætter vi spørgsmålstegn ved virkningen af kønsrepræsentation i uddannelsesdata på resultaterne af et end-to-end ASR-system. Vi skaber et eksperiment baseret på Librispeech-korpuset og bygger 3 forskellige træningskorpuser, der kun varierer andelen af data produceret af hver kønskategori. Vi bemærker, at hvis vores system generelt er robust i forhold til kønsbalancen eller uligevægten i uddannelsesdata, er det ikke desto mindre afhængigt af tilstrækkeligheden mellem de personer, der deltager i uddannelses- og testsættet.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>В настоящата статия се поставя под въпрос въздействието на представителството на половете в данните за обучението върху ефективността на цялостна система за АСР. Създаваме експеримент на базата на корпуса и изграждаме 3 различни корпуса за обучение, вариращи само пропорцията на данните, произведени от всяка полова категория. Наблюдаваме, че ако нашата система е като цяло здрава за баланса между половете или дисбаланса в данните за обучение, тя все пак зависи от адекватността между лицата, присъстващи в комплектите за обучение и тестване.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_af>In hierdie papier vra ons die vloek van seuns voorstelling in onderwerp data op die prestasie van 'n einde-tot-einde ASR stelsel. Ons skep 'n eksperiment gebaseer op die Librispeech corpus en bou 3 verskillende onderwerp korpora wat net die proporsie van data wat deur elke seunskategorie geproduseer is. Ons aanhou dat as ons stelsel heeltemal kragtig is tot die seunsbalanse of onbalanse in onderwerp data, is dit tog afhanklik van die adekuasie tussen die individuele wat in die onderwerp en toets is.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sw>Katika karatasi hii tunahoji athari ya uwakilishi wa jinsia katika mafunzo ya data kuhusu utendaji wa mfumo wa ASR wa mwisho wa mwisho. Tunaitengeneza jaribio linalohusu makampuni ya Librispeech na kujenga kampuni tatu tofauti ya mafunzo yanatofautiana tu kwa kiwango cha data kilichotengenezwa na kila aina ya jinsia. Tunaona kwamba kama mfumo wetu umekuwa umevurugwa kwa usawa wa jinsia au ukosefu wa usawa katika data za mafunzo, hata hivyo ni kutegemea usawa kati ya watu waliopo katika seti za mafunzo na majaribio.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Bu kagyzda biz jentiller täsirini ASR sistemasynyň soňky we soňky sistemasynyň üstünliklerine görkezmelerinde soraglaýarys. Librispeech korpusyna daýan ýan bir deney bejerdik we 3 dürli okuwçy korpoýasyny diňe her jens kategoriýasy tarapyndan üretilen berýän maglumatyň döwletlerini üýtgedik. Eğer sistemamyz gelişme bergilerinde jentiller dengisligine ýa-da eşitmänligine ýok bolsa, bu durum okuwçylygda we synagda bulunan adamlaryň arasyndaky ýerlikhedigine baglanýar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_hy>In this paper we question the impact of gender representation in training data on the performance of an end-to-end ASR system.  Մենք ստեղծում ենք մի փորձ, որը հիմնված է գրադարանի կորպոսի վրա և կառուցում ենք 3 տարբեր ուսուցման կորպոռներ, որոնք տարբերվում են միայն յուրաքանչյուր սեռի կատեգորիայի կողմից ստացված տվյալ Մենք նկատում ենք, որ եթե մեր համակարգը ընդհանուր առմամբ ուժեղ է գենդերային հավասարակշռության կամ կրթության տվյալների անհավասարակշռության համար, այն այնուամենայնիվ կախված է կրթության և փորձարկումների համակարգերի միջև գտնվող անհա</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bu kańüńĪtda, ASR sisteminin sonuna q…ôd…ôr t…ôhsil edilm…ôsi bar…ôsind…ô cins g√∂st…ôricisinin t…ôsiri bar…ôsind…ô sorńüu-sual edirik. Librispeech korpusuna dayanan bir eksperiment yaradńĪrńĪq v…ô 3 m√ľxt…ôlif t…ôhsil korporasńĪ yaradńĪrńĪq, yalnńĪz h…ôr cins kategoriyasńĪndan √ľr…ôkl…ôn…ôn m…ôlumatlarńĪn proporsiyasńĪnńĪ d…ôyiŇüdirir. ∆Źg…ôr sistemimiz t…ôhsil m…ôlumatlarńĪnda cins balanńĪna v…ô ya m√ľqabiliyy…ôtin…ô istinad edirs…ô, bu t…ôhsil v…ô sńĪnama qurmaqlarńĪnda olan kiŇüil…ôr arasńĪndakńĪ adeqlńĪńüa bańülńĪ olar.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_sq>Në këtë letër ne dyshojmë në ndikimin e përfaqësimit të gjinisë në trajnimin e të dhënave mbi performancën e një sistemi ASR nga fundi në fund. Ne krijojmë një eksperiment bazuar në Librispeech corpus dhe ndërtojmë 3 korpra të ndryshme trajnimi që ndryshojnë vetëm proporcionin e të dhënave të prodhuara nga çdo kategori gjinore. Ne vëzhgojmë se në qoftë se sistemi ynë është përgjithësisht i fortë ndaj ekuilibrit gjinorë apo disbalancit në të dhënat e trainimit, ai megjithatë varet nga përshtatja midis individëve të pranishëm në grupet e trainimit dhe testimit.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>በዚህ ካላት ውስጥ የሴት መልዕክት የሥርዓት አካባቢ ዳታዎችን ለመግለጥ የASR ስርዓት መጨረሻ ውጤት ማድረግ ጠይቃለን፡፡ የሊብሪስpeክ ኮፕስስ በመሠረት ላይ ፈተናን እናደርጋለን፣ የሥርዓት ክፍል የሚደረገውን የዳታ ክፍል ብቻ ይለያያሉ፡፡ ሲስተማርነታችን በሙያዊ ሚዛን ወይም በማስተካከል በማስተካከል ቢሆን፣ ነገር ግን በትምህርት እና በመፈተና ማሰናከል በሚገኙት ሰዎች መካከል በኩል የታመነ ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>এই কাগজটিতে আমরা লিঙ্গ প্রতিনিধিত্বের প্রভাবের প্রশিক্ষণের তথ্য প্রশিক্ষণের প্রশিক্ষা করছি যে শেষ পর্যন্ত এসার সিস আমরা লিব্রিস্পেচ কোর্পাসের উপর ভিত্তি করে একটি পরীক্ষা তৈরি করি এবং তিনটি ভিন্ন প্রশিক্ষণ কোর্পোরা তৈরি করে প্রত্যেক লিঙ্গ বিভি আমরা দেখছি যে যদি আমাদের সিস্টেম প্রশিক্ষণের তথ্যে লিঙ্গ ব্যবস্থা বা বৈষম্য নিয়ে যায়, তবে প্রশিক্ষণ ও পরীক্ষা সেটে উপস্থিত ব্যক্তিদের মধ্যে</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>U ovom papiru sumnjamo na učinak predstavljanja spola u podacima obuke o učinkovitosti sustava ASR-a do kraja. Napravili smo eksperiment baziran na Librispeech korpusu i izgradili 3 različite trening korporacije koje se razlikuju samo proporcija podataka proizvođenih od svake kategorije spola. Primijetimo da, ako je naš sistem ukupno jak na ravnotežu spola ili neravnotežan u podacima obuke, ipak je ovisan o adekvatnosti između pojedinaca prisutnih u obuci i testiranju.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>En aquest paper qüestionem l'impacte de la representació de gènere en les dades d'entrenament sobre el rendiment d'un sistema ASR de final a final. Creem un experiment basat en el Librispeech corpus i construim 3 corpores de formació diferents que només varian la proporció de dades produïdes per cada categoria de gènere. Observem que si el nostre sistema és en general robust per al equilibri de gènere o desequilibri en les dades d'entrenament, depèn encara de l'adequació entre els individus presents en els grups d'entrenament i prova.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>V tomto článku se zabýváme vlivem reprezentace žen a mužů v údajích o vzdělávání na výkonnost end-to-end ASR systému. Vytvoříme experiment založený na korpusu Librispeech a vytvoříme tři různé tréninkové korpusy, které se liší pouze podílem dat produkovaných každou genderovou kategorií. Pozorujeme, že pokud je náš systém celkově robustní vůči rovnováze žen a mužů nebo nerovnováze v údajích o tréninku, je nicméně závislý na přiměřenosti mezi jednotlivci přítomnými ve výcvikových a testovacích sadách.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa pohdimme sukupuolten edustuksen vaikutusta koulutustiedoissa kokonaisvaltaisen ASR-järjestelmän suorituskykyyn. Luomme Librispeech-korpuseen perustuvan kokeilun ja rakennamme kolme erilaista koulutuskorpusta, jotka vaihtelevat vain kunkin sukupuolen tuottaman tiedon osuutta. Havaitsemme, että jos järjestelmämme on yleisesti ottaen vankka sukupuolten tasapainon tai koulutustietojen epätasapainon suhteen, se on kuitenkin riippuvainen koulutus- ja testaussarjoissa olevien henkilöiden riittävyydestä.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas dokumendis küsitakse soolise esindatuse mõju koolitusandmetes täieliku ASR-süsteemi tulemuslikkusele. Loome Librispeechi korpusel põhineva eksperimendi ja ehitame kolm erinevat koolituskorporat, mis varieerivad ainult iga sookategooria andmete osakaalu. Me täheldame, et kui meie süsteem on üldiselt tugev soolise tasakaalu või koolitusandmete tasakaalustamatuse suhtes, sõltub see siiski koolitus- ja katsekomplektides osalevate isikute piisavusest.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_jv>Nang kuwi iki, awake awake dhéwé ngejane perusahaan langkung werak-wong liya neng data nggawe barang nggawe sistem ASR murah berlakkat sabanjuré. Awak dhéwé nggawe éntuk mulai perbudhakan podho suku kelompok Library Awak dhéwé ngerti, nek sistem awak dhéwé nggawe sistem iki luwih nggawe gerakan kanggo nik nglanggar kuwi duluran, kuwi mau, mengko iso nguasai perusahaan langgar-sistem sing gak nggawe gerakan sak kudu, nik nggawe nguasai perusahaan wong-wong iki dadi susahe sak</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>V prispevku postavljamo vprašanje o vplivu zastopanosti spolov v podatkih o usposabljanju na uspešnost celovitega sistema ASR. Ustvarimo eksperiment na osnovi korpusa Librispeech in zgradimo tri različne korpuse usposabljanja, ki spreminjajo le delež podatkov, ki jih proizvaja posamezna spolna kategorija. Ugotavljamo, da je naš sistem na splošno trden za uravnoteženost spolov ali neravnovesje v podatkih o usposabljanju, kljub temu odvisen od ustreznosti posameznikov, prisotnih v sklopih usposabljanja in testiranja.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Ga wannan takardan da Muke tambayar ta wajen muhallin jini cikin shirin data a kan aikin aikin tsarin na ƙari-zuwa-ƙari. Munã sami jarrabo a kan karatun Librispech kuma Muke samar da firma 3 dabam-dabam na dabam-tarakin data da aka samar da kõwace category. Muna gani cewa, idan na sami tsarinmu zuwa balancin jini ko kuma ba da balanci a cikin data na tattalin, sai yana dõgara da adadi a tsakanin mutane da ke cikin shirin da ke jarraba.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>בעיתון הזה אנו מפקפקים בהשפעה של ייצוג מין במידע האימוני על ההופעה של מערכת ASR סוף-סוף. אנו יוצרים ניסוי מבוסס על הקורפוס של Librispeech ולבנות 3 גופות אימונים שונות שונות רק את המספר של נתונים שנוצרים על ידי כל קטגוריה מינית. אנו שומרים על כך שאם המערכת שלנו חזקה באופן כללי לאיזון מין או אי-איזון בנתונים האימונים, היא עדיין תלויה בהתאם בין האדם הנוכחים במערכות האימונים ובניסויים.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ང་ཚོས་ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་གི་ཡིག་ཆའི་ནང་དུ་གུས་མེད་འཚོལ་བ་སྐྱེན་ཚོའི་གནོད་འཚོལ་གསུམ་སྟོན་པའི་གནས་སྟངས ང་ཚོས་Librispeech སྒེར་གྱི་གཙོ་སྟངས་དང་སྒྲིག་འཛུགས་གྱི་ཚད་རྩིས་ཐོག་ལས་བརྟན་དཔྱད་བྱས་པའི་སྒེར་གྱི་ཚད་རྐྱེན་སྒྲིག་མཁན་གསུམ་ ང་ཚོའི་མ་ལག་གི་རྐྱེན་ཚད་ལྡན་སྒྲིག་ཐད་ཀར་བ་ཡིན་ན་མིན་ཐད་ཡོད་པས། གལ་སྲིད་རང་གི་མ་ལག་གི་རྐྱེན་ཚད་དང་བརྟག་དཔྱད་ནང་གི་ཚད་རྐྱེན་ཚད་</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>Generating Gender Augmented Data for NLP<fixed-case>NLP</fixed-case></title>
      <author><first>Nishtha</first><last>Jain</last></author>
      <author><first>Maja</first><last>Popović</last></author>
      <author><first>Declan</first><last>Groves</last></author>
      <author><first>Eva</first><last>Vanmassenhove</last></author>
      <pages>93–102</pages>
      <abstract>Gender bias is a frequent occurrence in NLP-based applications, especially pronounced in gender-inflected languages. Bias can appear through associations of certain adjectives and animate nouns with the natural gender of referents, but also due to unbalanced grammatical gender frequencies of inflected words. This type of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bias">bias</a> becomes more evident in generating conversational utterances where gender is not specified within the sentence, because most current NLP applications still work on a sentence-level context. As a step towards more inclusive NLP, this paper proposes an automatic and generalisable re-writing approach for short conversational sentences. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rewriting">rewriting method</a> can be applied to sentences that, without <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context_(language_use)">extra-sentential context</a>, have multiple equivalent alternatives in terms of gender. The method can be applied both for creating gender balanced outputs as well as for creating gender balanced training data. The proposed approach is based on a neural machine translation system trained to ‘translate’ from one gender alternative to another. Both the automatic and manual analysis of the approach show promising results with respect to the automatic generation of gender alternatives for conversational sentences in Spanish.</abstract>
      <url hash="552391e1">2021.gebnlp-1.11</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="2de0cc30">2021.gebnlp-1.11.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.pdf</attachment>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.gebnlp-1.11</doi>
      <bibkey>jain-etal-2021-generating</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/awslabs/sockeye" additional="false">awslabs/sockeye</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Second Order WinoBias (SoWinoBias) Test Set for Latent Gender Bias Detection in Coreference Resolution<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ino<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>ias (<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>W</fixed-case>ino<fixed-case>B</fixed-case>ias) Test Set for Latent Gender Bias Detection in Coreference Resolution</title>
      <author><first>Hillary</first><last>Dawkins</last></author>
      <pages>103–111</pages>
      <abstract>We observe an instance of gender-induced bias in a downstream application, despite the absence of explicit gender words in the test cases. We provide a test set, SoWinoBias, for the purpose of measuring such latent gender bias in coreference resolution systems. We evaluate the performance of current debiasing methods on the SoWinoBias test set, especially in reference to the method’s design and altered embedding space properties. See https://github.com/hillary-dawkins/SoWinoBias.</abstract>
      <url hash="4a3028b8">2021.gebnlp-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.gebnlp-1.12</doi>
      <bibkey>dawkins-2021-second</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/winobias">WinoBias</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>