<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.humeval">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-04-19">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Workshop on Human Evaluation of NLP Systems (HumEval)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Anya</first><last>Belz</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Shubham</first><last>Agarwal</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yvette</first><last>Graham</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ehud</first><last>Reiter</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anastasia</first><last>Shimorina</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="49abb657">2021.humeval-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="2207b5d3">2021.humeval-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>humeval-2021-human</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Trading Off Diversity and Quality in Natural Language Generation</title>
      <author><first>Hugh</first><last>Zhang</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Duckworth</last></author>
      <author><first>Daphne</first><last>Ippolito</last></author>
      <author><first>Arvind</first><last>Neelakantan</last></author>
      <pages>25–33</pages>
      <abstract>For open-ended language generation tasks such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storytelling">storytelling</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dialogue">dialogue</a>, choosing the right decoding algorithm is vital for controlling the tradeoff between generation quality and diversity. However, there presently exists no consensus on which <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decoding_methods">decoding procedure</a> is best or even the criteria by which to compare them. In this paper, we cast <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decoding_methods">decoding</a> as a tradeoff between response quality and diversity, and we perform the first large-scale evaluation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decoding_methods">decoding methods</a> along the entire quality-diversity spectrum. Our experiments confirm the existence of the likelihood trap : the counter-intuitive observation that high likelihood sequences are often surprisingly low quality. We also find that when diversity is a priority, all methods perform similarly, but when quality is viewed as more important, nucleus sampling (Holtzman et al., 2019) outperforms all other evaluated decoding algorithms.<i>quality</i> and <i>diversity</i>. However, there presently exists no consensus on which decoding procedure is best or even the criteria by which to compare them. In this paper, we cast decoding as a tradeoff between response quality and diversity, and we perform the first large-scale evaluation of decoding methods along the entire quality-diversity spectrum. Our experiments confirm the existence of the likelihood trap: the counter-intuitive observation that high likelihood sequences are often surprisingly low quality. We also find that when diversity is a priority, all methods perform similarly, but when quality is viewed as more important, nucleus sampling (Holtzman et al., 2019) outperforms all other evaluated decoding algorithms.</abstract>
      <url hash="318e99f6">2021.humeval-1.3</url>
      <video href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P0SWVm30MFM" />
      <bibkey>zhang-etal-2021-trading</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Is This Translation Error Critical? : Classification-Based Human and Automatic Machine Translation Evaluation Focusing on Critical Errors</title>
      <author><first>Katsuhito</first><last>Sudoh</last></author>
      <author><first>Kosuke</first><last>Takahashi</last></author>
      <author><first>Satoshi</first><last>Nakamura</last></author>
      <pages>46–55</pages>
      <abstract>This paper discusses a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification-based approach</a> to machine translation evaluation, as opposed to a common <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_analysis">regression-based approach</a> in the WMT Metrics task. Recent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_translation">machine translation</a> usually works well but sometimes makes critical errors due to just a few wrong word choices. Our classification-based approach focuses on such errors using several error type labels, for practical machine translation evaluation in an age of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_machine_translation">neural machine translation</a>. We made additional annotations on the WMT 2015-2017 Metrics datasets with fluency and adequacy labels to distinguish different types of translation errors from syntactic and semantic viewpoints. We present our human evaluation criteria for the corpus development and automatic evaluation experiments using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_corpus">corpus</a>. The human evaluation corpus will be publicly available upon publication.</abstract>
      <url hash="6d5b87b3">2021.humeval-1.5</url>
      <attachment type="Dataset" hash="3b09bc8d">2021.humeval-1.5.Dataset.zip</attachment>
      <video href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=myG72lA2hpo" />
      <bibkey>sudoh-etal-2021-translation</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Towards Objectively Evaluating the Quality of Generated Medical Summaries</title>
      <author><first>Francesco</first><last>Moramarco</last></author>
      <author><first>Damir</first><last>Juric</last></author>
      <author><first>Aleksandar</first><last>Savkov</last></author>
      <author><first>Ehud</first><last>Reiter</last></author>
      <pages>56–61</pages>
      <abstract>We propose a method for evaluating the quality of generated text by asking evaluators to count facts, and computing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">precision</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recall_(memory)">recall</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F-score">f-score</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> from the raw counts. We believe this approach leads to a more objective and easier to reproduce evaluation. We apply this to the task of medical report summarisation, where measuring objective quality and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> is of paramount importance.</abstract>
      <url hash="2fa2ed24">2021.humeval-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>moramarco-etal-2021-towards</bibkey>
    <title_es>Hacia una evaluación objetiva de la calidad de los resúmenes médicos generados</title_es>
      <title_zh>客观评估生医摘要之量</title_zh>
      <title_ja>生成された医療概要の品質を客観的に評価するために</title_ja>
      <title_pt>Para avaliar objetivamente a qualidade dos resumos médicos gerados</title_pt>
      <title_ar>نحو تقييم موضوعي لجودة الملخصات الطبية</title_ar>
      <title_hi>निष्पक्ष रूप से उत्पन्न चिकित्सा सारांश की गुणवत्ता का मूल्यांकन करने की दिशा में</title_hi>
      <title_ga>I dTreo Meastóireacht Oibiachtúil ar Cháilíocht Achoimrí Míochaine Ginte</title_ga>
      <title_el>Προς την αντικειμενική αξιολόγηση της ποιότητας των παραγόμενων ιατρικών περιλήψεων</title_el>
      <title_hu>A generált orvosi összefoglalók minőségének objektív értékelése felé</title_hu>
      <title_ka>მისამართლურად განსაზღვრება განსაზღვრებული მედიცინური კოლეტურის კოლეტურაზე</title_ka>
      <title_it>Verso una valutazione oggettiva della qualità dei riassunti medici generati</title_it>
      <title_lt>Objektyvaus generuotų medicinos santraukų kokybės vertinimo link</title_lt>
      <title_kk>Жалпы медицина тұжырымдарының сапатын мақсатты оқу үшін</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Ke arah Evaluasi Objektif Kualiti Ringkasan Perubatan Yang Dijana</title_ms>
      <title_mn>Нэгдсэн эмнэлгийн хэмжээний хэмжээний чадварыг</title_mn>
      <title_no>Til objektiv evaluering av kvaliteten til genererte medisinske samandrag</title_no>
      <title_mt>Lejn Evalwazzjoni Objettiva tal-Kwalità tas-Sommarji Mediċi Ġenerati</title_mt>
      <title_pl>W kierunku obiektywnej oceny jakości generowanych podsumowań medycznych</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Către evaluarea obiectivă a calității rezumatelor medicale generate</title_ro>
      <title_sr>U cilju objektivne procjene kvalitete generalnih medicinskih sažetaka</title_sr>
      <title_si>සාමාන්‍ය වෛද්‍ය සංවේදනයේ කුළුවත් විශේෂ විශේෂ විශේෂය අවශ්‍ය</title_si>
      <title_sv>Mot en objektiv utvärdering av kvaliteten på genererade medicinska sammanfattningar</title_sv>
      <title_so>Towards Objectively Evaluating Quality of Generated Medical Summaries</title_so>
      <title_ta>உருவாக்கப்பட்ட மருத்துவ சுருக்கங்களின் தரம்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>جنرائٹ میڈیکلی جماریوں کی کیفیت کا ارزش مقرر کرنے کی طرف</title_ur>
      <title_mk>За објективна оценка на квалитетот на генерираните медицински резултати</title_mk>
      <title_ml>സൃഷ്ടിക്കപ്പെട്ട മെഡിക്കല്‍ ചുരുക്കുകളുടെ ഗുണവിശേഷം മുകളിലേക്കു് നിര്‍ണ്ണയിക്കുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_uz>@ info: whatsthis</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Để đánh giá thấp chất lượng của các triệu tập y học phát triển</title_vi>
      <title_da>På vej mod objektiv evaluering af kvaliteten af genererede medicinske resuméer</title_da>
      <title_nl>Naar een objectieve evaluatie van de kwaliteit van gegenereerde medische samenvattingen</title_nl>
      <title_id>Menuju Evaluasi Objektif Kualitas Ringkasan Medis Yang Dibuat</title_id>
      <title_bg>Към обективна оценка на качеството на генерираните медицински резюмета</title_bg>
      <title_hr>U cilju objektivne procjene kvalitete generalnih medicinskih sažetaka</title_hr>
      <title_ko>생성된 의학 요약의 질을 객관적으로 평가하다</title_ko>
      <title_sw>Towards Objectively Evaluating the Quality of Generated Medical Summaries</title_sw>
      <title_de>Zur objektiven Bewertung der Qualität generierter medizinischer Zusammenfassungen</title_de>
      <title_tr>Umumy Döredik Saýlaw Toparynyň Görkezilişi Görkezilişine Görniş Taýýarlama</title_tr>
      <title_af>Gaan na Objektiewe Evalueer die Kwaliteit van Gegenereerde Mediese Opsomming</title_af>
      <title_sq>drejt vlerësimit objektiv të cilësisë së përmbledhjeve mjekësore të gjeneratuara</title_sq>
      <title_am>ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_fa>به مقابل ارزیابی کیفیت جمعیت پزشکی تولید شده</title_fa>
      <title_hy>Մինչև ծրագրավորված բժշկական համառոտագրությունների որակի օբյեկտիվ գնահատումը</title_hy>
      <title_bn>উল্লেখযোগ্য মেডিকেল সংক্ষেপের মান পরীক্ষা করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Towards Objectively Evaluating the Quality of Generated Medical Summaries</title_ca>
      <title_bs>U cilju objektivne procjene kvalitete generalnih medicinskih sažetaka</title_bs>
      <title_cs>K objektivnímu hodnocení kvality generovaných lékařských shrnutí</title_cs>
      <title_az>仃뙶拉饴椠哉饢扩⁔潰污얟擄녲浡污狄녮⁑쎼摲즙瑩湩⁇쎶竉饬瑭즙秉餠瓉饲즙昊</title_az>
      <title_et>Koostatud meditsiiniliste kokkuvõtete kvaliteedi objektiivse hindamise suunas</title_et>
      <title_fi>Kohti tuotettujen lääketieteellisten yhteenvetojen laadun objektiivista arviointia</title_fi>
      <title_ha>QDialogButtonBox</title_ha>
      <title_sk>K objektivnemu ocenjevanju kakovosti ustvarjenih zdravstvenih povzetkov</title_sk>
      <title_jv>Tarjamahan Obtengisasi sing nggambar Kealitas de Sambaran Pangan</title_jv>
      <title_he>לכיוון הערכה אובייקטיבית של איכות סדרות רפואיות יוצרות</title_he>
      <title_bo>སྤྱིར་བཏང་བའི་དབྱིབས་མཐུད་སྣེ་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་ཁྱད་ཚད་ལྟར་བསམ་བྱེད་སྐབས་</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>نقترح طريقة لتقييم جودة النص الذي تم إنشاؤه من خلال مطالبة المقيّمين بحساب الحقائق ، ودقة الحوسبة ، والتذكر ، والنتيجة f ، والدقة من الأعداد الأولية. نعتقد أن هذا النهج يؤدي إلى مزيد من الموضوعية وأسهل في إعادة إنتاج التقييم. نحن نطبق هذا على مهمة تلخيص التقرير الطبي ، حيث يكون قياس الجودة الموضوعية والدقة أمرًا بالغ الأهمية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>Propomos um método para avaliar a qualidade do texto gerado pedindo aos avaliadores que contem fatos e computando precisão, rechamada, f-score e exatidão das contagens brutas. Acreditamos que esta abordagem leva a uma avaliação mais objetiva e mais fácil de reproduzir. Aplicamos isso à tarefa de sumarização de relatórios médicos, onde medir a qualidade e a precisão objetivas é de suma importância.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>Proponemos un método para evaluar la calidad del texto generado pidiendo a los evaluadores que cuenten los hechos y calculen la precisión, la recuperación, la puntuación f y la precisión a partir de los recuentos sin procesar. Creemos que este enfoque conduce a una evaluación más objetiva y fácil de reproducir. Aplicamos esto a la tarea de resumir los informes médicos, donde la medición de la calidad y precisión objetivas es de suma importancia.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>評価者に事実をカウントしてもらい、RAWカウントから精度、リコール、fスコア、精度を算出することで、生成されたテキストの品質を評価する方法を提案する。このアプローチは、より客観的で再現しやすい評価につながると考えています。これは、客観的な品質と正確さを測定することが最も重要である医療報告の要約のタスクに適用されます。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>凡评估生文本之法,求估者计事,以原始计数为精度,召率,f分数准确性。 吾信此法可以致更客、更易重评。 宜用于医告摘要,量准确性至重。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>हम मूल्यांकनकर्ताओं को तथ्यों की गिनती करने के लिए कहकर उत्पन्न पाठ की गुणवत्ता का मूल्यांकन करने के लिए एक विधि का प्रस्ताव करते हैं, और कच्चे गिनती से सटीकता, याद, एफ-स्कोर और सटीकता की गणना करते हैं। हमारा मानना है कि यह दृष्टिकोण मूल्यांकन को पुन: पेश करने के लिए अधिक उद्देश्य और आसान की ओर जाता है। हम इसे चिकित्सा रिपोर्ट सारांश के कार्य पर लागू करते हैं, जहां उद्देश्य गुणवत्ता और सटीकता को मापना सर्वोपरि महत्व का है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Molaimid modh chun cáilíocht an téacs ginte a mheas trí iarraidh ar mheastóirí fíricí a chomhaireamh, agus beachtas, aisghairm, f-scór agus cruinneas a ríomh ó na hamháirimh. Creidimid go mbíonn meastóireacht níos oibiachtúla agus níos fusa a atáirgeadh mar thoradh ar an gcur chuige seo. Cuirimid é seo i bhfeidhm maidir le hachoimriú tuairiscí leighis, áit a bhfuil sé ríthábhachtach cáilíocht agus cruinneas oibiachtúil a thomhas.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Προτείνουμε μια μέθοδο για την αξιολόγηση της ποιότητας του παραγόμενου κειμένου ζητώντας από τους αξιολογητές να μετρήσουν γεγονότα, και υπολογιστική ακρίβεια, ανάκληση, βαθμολογία και ακρίβεια από τους ακατέργαστους υπολογισμούς. Πιστεύουμε ότι αυτή η προσέγγιση οδηγεί σε μια πιο αντικειμενική και ευκολότερη αναπαραγωγή αξιολόγησης. Αυτό το εφαρμόζουμε στο έργο της σύνοψης ιατρικών εκθέσεων, όπου η μέτρηση της αντικειμενικής ποιότητας και της ακρίβειας είναι υψίστης σημασίας.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_kk>Біз жасалған мәтіннің сапасын бағалау әдісін, үндіктерді есептеу және оның дұрыстығын есептеу, есептеу, f- нөмірі және сызық сандарының дұрыстығын сұрайтын әдісін таңдап Бұл тәсілі оқиғаны қайталау үшін оңай мақсатты және оңай болады деп ойлаймыз. Біз бұл медицина хабарламасының тұжырымдамасына қолданып тұрмыз. Мақсатты сапаты мен дұрыстығын өлшеу үшін бұл маңызды маңызды.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Siūlome sukurto teksto kokybės vertinimo metodą, prašydami vertintojų skaičiuoti faktus, apskaičiuoti tikslumą, atšaukimą, f tašką ir tikslumą iš žaliavų skaičiaus. Manome, kad šis požiūris lemia objektyvesnį ir lengviau atkurti vertinimą. Mes tai taikome medicinos ataskaitų santraukos uždaviniui, kuriame labai svarbu vertinti objektyvią kokybę ir tikslumą.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Предложуваме метод за проценка на квалитетот на генерираниот текст со барање од проценувачите да бројат факти, и да пресметаат прецизност, потсетување, f-оценка и точност од суровите бројки. Веруваме дека овој пристап води до пообјективна и полесна репродукција на проценката. We apply this to the task of medical report summarisation, where measuring objective quality and accuracy is of paramount importance.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Kami cadangkan kaedah untuk menilai kualiti teks yang dijana dengan meminta penilai untuk menghitung fakta, dan mengira ketepatan, ingatan, skor-f, dan ketepatan dari kiraan mentah. Kami percaya pendekatan ini membawa kepada lebih objektif dan lebih mudah untuk mengembalikan penilaian. Kami menerapkan ini untuk tugas ringkasan laporan perubatan, di mana pengukuran kualiti dan ketepatan objektif adalah penting yang paling penting.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>സൃഷ്ടിക്കപ്പെട്ട ട ടെക്സ്റ്റിന്റെ സ്വാധീനത്തെ വിലാസപ്പെടുത്താനുള്ള ഒരു രീതിയാണ് ഞങ്ങള്‍ പ്രൊദ്ദേശിക്കുന്നത്. വിലാസങ്ങള്‍ എണ് നമ്മള്‍ വിശ്വസിക്കുന്നു ഈ നടപടി കൂടുതല്‍ ലക്ഷ്യത്തിലേക്കും എളുപ്പമുള്ളതിലേക്കും നയിക്കുന്നു. നമ്മളിത് മെഡിക്കല്‍ റിപ്പോര്‍ട്ടിന്‍റെ ചുരുക്കത്തിന്‍റെ ജോലിയിലേക്ക് പ്രയോഗിക്കുന്നു. അതില്‍ നിന്ന് സാധാരണ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Aħna nipproponu metodu għall-evalwazzjoni tal-kwalità tat-test iġġenerat billi nistaqsu lill-evalwaturi biex jgħoddu l-fatti, u jikkalkulaw il-preċiżjoni, il-ġbir lura, il-punteġġ f, u l-preċiżjoni mill-għadd mhux ipproċessat. Aħna nemmnu li dan l-approċċ iwassal għal evalwazzjoni aktar oġġettiva u aktar faċli biex tiġi riprodotta. Aħna napplikaw dan għall-kompitu tas-sommarju tar-rapport mediku, fejn il-kejl tal-kwalità u l-preċiżjoni oġġettivi huwa ta’ importanza kbira.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Бид үнэндээ тооцоолох, тодорхойлох, санах, f-тоо, мөн шулууны тооны зөв байдлыг хүлээн зөвшөөрөх арга зааж байна. Бид энэ арга баримтууд үнэлгээг үржүүлэхэд илүү зорилготой, амархан болгодог гэдэгт итгэдэг. Бид үүнийг эмнэлгийн мэдээллийн цуглуулалтын даалгаврыг хэрэглэдэг. Зарим чанарыг хэмжих нь хамгийн чухал.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Vi foreslår ein metode for å evaluera kvaliteten på laga tekst ved å spørja at evalueringa skal telja faktum og rekna ut nøyaktighet, rekna opp, f- poeng og nøyaktighet frå råtalla. Vi tror at denne tilnærminga fører til ein meir målrett og lettere å gjenoppretta evalueringa. Vi bruker dette til oppgåva med samansering av medisinsk rapport, der målinga av objektive kvalitet og nøyaktighet er avviktig.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Proponujemy metodę oceny jakości wygenerowanego tekstu poprzez proszenie oceniających o liczenie faktów oraz obliczenie precyzji, przywołania, wyniku f i dokładności z liczb surowych. Uważamy, że takie podejście prowadzi do bardziej obiektywnej i łatwiejszej do odtworzenia oceny. Stosujemy to do zadania podsumowania raportów medycznych, gdzie pomiar obiektywnej jakości i dokładności ma ogromne znaczenie.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Propunem o metodă de evaluare a calității textului generat prin solicitarea evaluatorilor să numere faptele și să calculeze precizia, rechemarea, punctajul f și acuratețea din numărul brut. Considerăm că această abordare duce la o evaluare mai obiectivă și mai ușor de reprodus. Aplicăm acest lucru sarcinii de rezumare a rapoartelor medicale, unde măsurarea calității obiective și a acurateții este de o importanță primordială.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Predlažemo metodu za procjenu kvalitete proizvedenog teksta tražeći ocjene da broju činjenice, računaju preciznost, sećanje, f-rezultat i preciznost iz sirovog broja. Vjerujemo da taj pristup vodi do objektivnije i lakše razmnožavanje procjene. Ovo primjenjujemo na zadatak sažetka medicinskih izveštaja, gdje je mjerenje objektivne kvalitete i tačnosti najvažnije.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_si>අපි ප්‍රවේශනයක් ප්‍රවේශනය කරන්න පුළුවන් විශේෂ පාළුවන් විශේෂාවක් ගැනගන්න පුළුවන් විශේෂ කරනවා විශේෂකයන්ට ඇත්ත ගණ අපි විශ්වාස කරනවා මේ විදියට විශ්වාස කරන්නේ වැඩිය අරමුණක් වගේම ලේසියි. අපි මේක වෛද්‍ය වාර්තාව සම්පූර්ණයේ වැඩකට ඇතුළත් කරනවා, ඒ වගේම අක්ෂිත විශේෂතාව සහ සැකසුම්පූර්</abstract_si>
      <abstract_so>Waxaynu soo jeedaynaa qaab ku qiimeynaya qiimeynta qoraalka la soo saaray, si aan qiimeynayno xaqiiqyada, xisaabinno saxda, xusuuso, f-scor iyo saxda tirada xunxun. Waxaynu aaminsanahay in qabashadan uu ku hoggaamiyo waxyaabo ka sahlan oo uu dib u soo celiyo qiimeynta. Waxaannu u sameynaa shaqada summarinta wargelinta caafimaadka, meesha lagu qiyaasi karo qiimaha la'aanta iyo saxda ay muhiim u tahay.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Vi föreslår en metod för att utvärdera kvaliteten på genererad text genom att be utvärderare att räkna fakta, och beräkna precision, återkallande, f-poäng och noggrannhet från råräkningarna. Vi tror att detta tillvägagångssätt leder till en mer objektiv och lättare att reproducera utvärderingen. Vi tillämpar detta på uppgiften att sammanfatta medicinska rapporter, där mätning av objektiv kvalitet och noggrannhet är av yttersta vikt.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>உருவாக்கப்பட்ட உரையின் தரத்தை மதிப்பீடு செய்ய ஒரு முறையை நாம் பரிந்துரைக்கிறோம் மூலம் மதிப்பீடுகளை கணக்கிடும் சரியான எண்ணிக்கை நாங்கள் நம்புகிறோம் இந்த முறைமை ஒரு மேலும் காரியங்களுக்கு சுலபமாக மற்றும் ஆராய்ச்சியை மீட்டு நாம் இதை மருத்துவ அறிக்கை சுருக்கத்தின் செயல்பாட்டிற்கு பயன்படுத்துகிறோம், பொருள் தரம் மற்றும் சரியான அளவை அளக்க</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>ہم ایک طریقہ پیش کریں گے کہ تخلیق کی کیفیت کا ارزیابی کریں، اس کے ذریعہ سے ارزیابی کرنے والوں سے حقیقت کا شمار کریں، اور دقیق کامپیوتر کریں، یاد کریں، f-اسکور اور روئے گنتی سے دقیق کریں. ہم یقین رکھتے ہیں کہ یہ تقریبا ایک زیادہ موضوع اور آسان مقررہ کے لئے پہنچاتا ہے۔ ہم اسے پزشکی راپورت کے ذریعہ پر لازم کرتے ہیں، جہاں مقررہ کیفیت اور دقیقیت کا اندازہ کرنا بہت اہم ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ka>бғ©бғ•бғ”бғң бғӣбғҳбғңбғ“бғқбғӣбғ”бғ‘бғҳбғ— бғ’бғҗбғ•бғҗбғҷбғ”бғ—бғ”бғ‘бғЈбғҡбғҳ бғўбғ”бғҘбғЎбғўбғҳбғЎ бғҷбғҗбғҡбғҳбғўбғЈбғ бғҳбғЎ бғЁбғ”бғЎбғҗбғ‘бғҗбғӣбғҳбғЎбғ—бғ•бғҳбғЎ, бғ бғқбғӣбғ”бғҡбғЎбғҗбғӘ бғҗбғҷбғ”бғ—бғ”бғ‘бғЈбғҡбғҳ бғ бғ”бғҘбғЎбғўбғЈбғ бғ”бғ‘бғҳбғЎ бғЁбғ”бғЎбғҗбғ‘бғҗбғӣбғҳбғЎбғ—бғ•бғҳбғЎ, бғӨбғҗбғҘбғўбғ”бғ‘бғҳбғЎ бғЁбғ”бғЎбғҗбғ‘бғҗбғӣбғҳбғЎбғ—бғ•бғҳбғЎ, бғ“бғҗбғӣбғ¬бғ”бғ бғ”бғ‘бғҗ, f-score бғ“бғҗ бғ¬бғ”бғЎбғҳбғ”бғ бғ”бғ‘бғҗ бғ¬бғ”бғЎбғҳбғ”бғ бғ”бғ‘ бғ©бғ•бғ”бғң бғ•бғӨбғҳбғҘбғ бғқбғ‘бғ—, бғ бғқбғӣ бғ”бғЎ бғһбғ бғқбғ’бғ бғҗбғӣбғҗ бғЈбғӨбғ бғқ бғқбғ‘бғҳбғ”бғҘбғўбғҳбғЈбғ бғҳ бғ“бғҗ бғЈбғӨбғ бғқ бғӣбғҗбғ бғўбғҳбғ•бғҳбғҗ бғ’бғҗбғ•бғҗбғӣбғЈбғЁбғҗбғ•бғ”бғ‘бғҗ. бғ©бғ•бғ”бғң бғҗбғӣбғҗбғЎ бғ“бғҗбғ•бғ§бғ”бғңбғ”бғ‘бғ— бғӣбғ”бғ“бғҳбғӘбғҳбғңбғЈбғ бғҳ бғЁбғ”бғўбғ§бғқбғ‘бғҳбғңбғ”бғ‘бғ”бғ‘бғҳбғЎ бғЎбғҳбғЎбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–бғҗбғЈбғ–</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Javasoljuk a generált szöveg minőségének értékelésére szolgáló módszert azáltal, hogy az értékelőket megkérjük a tények számítására, valamint a pontosság, visszahívás, f-pontszám és pontosság számítására a nyers számokból. Hisszük, hogy ez a megközelítés objektívabb és könnyebben reprodukálható értékeléshez vezet. Ezt az orvosi jelentések összefoglalására alkalmazzuk, ahol az objektív minőség és pontosság mérése kiemelkedő fontosságú.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Proponiamo un metodo per valutare la qualità del testo generato chiedendo ai valutatori di contare i fatti e di calcolare precisione, richiamo, f-score e precisione dai conteggi grezzi. Crediamo che questo approccio porti ad una valutazione più obiettiva e più facile da riprodurre. Lo applichiamo al compito di sintesi delle relazioni mediche, dove misurare la qualità oggettiva e l'accuratezza è di fondamentale importanza.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_vi>Chúng tôi đề xuất một phương pháp đánh giá chất lượng của văn bản được tạo ra bằng cách yêu cầu thẩm tra đánh giá thực tế, tính chính xác, hồi phục, điểm F, và độ chính xác từ điểm thô. Chúng tôi tin rằng cách tiếp cận này dẫn đến một cách khách quan hơn và dễ dàng tái diễn đánh giá. Chúng tôi áp dụng việc này vào việc tóm tắt báo cáo y tế, nơi đo mức chất lượng khách quan và độ chính xác là tối quan trọng.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_uz>Biz yaratilgan matnning sifatini qiymatish usulini tahrirlash va qiymatlarni qiymatlashni soʻrayapmiz, qiymatni hisoblash, xotira, f- scorning va qiymatni qiymatlashni soʻraymiz. Biz ishonamiz, bu usulni qayta qiymatni qayta chiqarishga qulay qiladi. Biz bu narsalarni tahrirlash vazifasiga qo'llamiz. Bu yerda obʼekt tizim va tasdiqlarni aniqlash juda muhim.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_nl>We stellen een methode voor om de kwaliteit van gegenereerde tekst te evalueren door beoordelaars te vragen feiten te tellen en precisie, recall, f-score en nauwkeurigheid uit de ruwe tellingen te berekenen. Wij geloven dat deze aanpak leidt tot een objectievere en gemakkelijker te reproduceren evaluatie. Dit passen we toe op de taak van het samenvatten van medische rapporten, waarbij het meten van objectieve kwaliteit en nauwkeurigheid van het grootste belang is.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Vi foreslår en metode til evaluering af kvaliteten af genereret tekst ved at bede evaluatorer om at tælle fakta og beregne præcision, tilbagekaldelse, f-score og nøjagtighed ud fra råtællingerne. Vi mener, at denne tilgang fører til en mere objektiv og lettere at gengive evaluering. Dette gælder for opgaven med opsummering af medicinsk rapport, hvor måling af objektiv kvalitet og nøjagtighed er af afgørende betydning.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Predlažemo metodu za procjenu kvalitete proizvedenog teksta tražeći ocjenjivača brojati činjenice i računati preciznost, sjećanje, f-rezultat i preciznost iz sirovog broja. Vjerujemo da taj pristup vodi do objektivnije i lakše reprodukcije procjene. To primjenjujemo na zadatak sažetka zdravstvenog izvješća, gdje je mjerenje objektivne kvalitete i preciznosti najvažnije.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Wir schlagen eine Methode vor, um die Qualität des generierten Textes zu bewerten, indem wir Bewerter bitten, Fakten zu zählen und Präzision, Rückruf, f-Score und Genauigkeit aus den Rohzahlen zu berechnen. Wir glauben, dass dieser Ansatz zu einer objektiveren und leichter reproduzierbaren Bewertung führt. Wir wenden dies auf die Aufgabe der medizinischen Berichterstellung an, bei der die Messung objektiver Qualität und Genauigkeit von größter Bedeutung ist.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_ko>우리는 텍스트 생성의 질을 평가하는 방법을 제시하여 평가자에게 사실을 통계하고 원시 계수에서 정밀도, 리콜율, f점수와 정확성을 계산하도록 요구했다.우리는 이런 방법이 더욱 객관적이고 재현되기 쉬운 평가를 가져올 것이라고 믿는다.우리는 이를 의료 보고서의 총결산 임무에 응용할 것이다. 그 중에서 객관적인 질과 정확성을 평가하는 것이 매우 중요하다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_id>Kami mengusulkan metode untuk mengevaluasi kualitas teks yang dihasilkan dengan meminta evaluasi untuk menghitung fakta, dan perhitungan presisi, ingatan, skor f, dan akurasi dari jumlah raw. Kami percaya pendekatan ini menyebabkan lebih objektif dan lebih mudah untuk mereproduksi evaluasi. Kami menerapkan hal ini untuk tugas pengumpulan laporan medis, di mana mengukur kualitas dan akurasi objektif adalah penting.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_bg>Предлагаме метод за оценка на качеството на генерирания текст, като молим оценителите да преброят фактите, както и изчислителната точност, припомнянето, оценката и точността от суровите бройки. Считаме, че този подход води до по-обективна и по-лесна за възпроизвеждане оценка. Ние прилагаме това към задачата за обобщаване на медицинските доклади, където измерването на обективното качество и точността е от първостепенно значение.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_tr>Biz janlaşdyran metin kalitesini deňlemek üçin bir yöntem teklip berýäris çykyşlaryň faktlary hasaplamagyny, hasaplamagyny, f-scoreny we hatlarynyň dogrylygyny sorap, Biziň pikirimçe bu ýagdaýyň çykyşyny täzeden beýleki maksadyň we düýşürmegini täzeden a ňsatdyr. Biz muny tıbbi hasaplanjaň jemgyýetişine uygulaýarys. Bu ýerde objektif howpsuzlygyny we dogryslygyny ölçüsi örän wajypdyr.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_fa>ما یک روش برای ارزیابی کیفیت متن تولید را از طریق خواستن ارزیابگران که حقیقت را شماره کنند، و دقیق محاسبه کنند، یادآوری، امتیاز f و دقیق از شماره‌های خالی پیشنهاد می‌کنیم. ما باور می‌کنیم که این روش به هدف‌تر و آسون‌تر برای تولید ارزیابی است. ما این را به وظیفه جمع کردن گزارش پزشکی استفاده می کنیم، جایی که مقدار کیفیت و دقیق هدف مهم است.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Ons voorstel 'n metode om die kwaliteit van genereerde teks te evalueer deur die evalueerders te vra om fakte te tel en bereken presisie, herhaal, f- telling en presisie van die raai tel. Ons glo hierdie toegang lei na 'n meer objektief en makliker om evaluasie te reproduseer. Ons het dit aangepas op die taak van mediese raport opsomming, waar die gemeet van objektiewe kwaliteit en presisiteit is van paramount belangrikheid.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sw>Tunazipendekeza njia ya kutathmini ubora wa ujumbe uliotengenezwa kwa kuwaomba watafiti kuhesabu ukweli, na kuhesabu uhakika, kumbuka, score, na uhakika kutoka idadi mbaya. Tunaamini kuwa mbinu hii inapelekea lengo zaidi na rahisi zaidi ya kutathmini tathmini. Tunatumia hili kwenye jukumu la muhtasari wa taarifa za afya, ambapo kupima kiwango cha malengo na ukweli ni muhimu wa muhimu.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_az>Biz təşkil edilmiş metin kalitetini değerləşdirmək üçün bir metodu təklif edirik, həqiqəti saymaq, həqiqəti hesablamaq, yada salmaq, f-score və həmçinin sayılardan doğruluğu istəyirik. Biz inanırıq ki, bu tərzim daha objektif və daha asan bir değerlendirmə tərzinə gətirir. Biz bunu təhsil raportu təmizləməsi üçün istifadə edirik. Gözəl qiyməti və ədaləti ölçürmək çox mövcuddur.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_sq>Ne propozojmë një metodë për vlerësimin e cilësisë së tekstit të gjeneruar duke i kërkuar vlerësuesve të numërojnë fakte, dhe llogaritjen e saktësisë, kujtimin, pikë-f dhe saktësinë nga numrat e papërpunuara. Ne besojmë se kjo qasje shpie në një vlerësim më objektiv dhe më të lehtë për të riprodhuar. Ne e aplikojmë këtë në detyrën e përmbledhjes së raportit mjekësor, ku matja e cilësisë objektive dhe saktësisë është e rëndësishme.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>የእውነትን ቁጥር ለመጠየቅ፣ ቁጥጥር፣ ማስታወስ፣ f-score እና ቁጥጥር እና ቁጥጥር ለመጠየቅ የፍጥረት ጽሑፎችን ውሃት በማስተካከል እናስመክራለን፡፡ እናምናለን ይህ ሥርዓት ማስታወቂያውን ለመመለስ የሚሻል እና የሚቀላል ነው፡፡ We apply this to the task of medical report summarisation, where measuring objective quality and accuracy is of paramount importance.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Մենք առաջարկում ենք ստեղծված տեքստի որակի գնահատման մեթոդ՝ խնդրելով գնահատողներին հաշվարկել փաստերը, հաշվարկել ճշգրտությունը, հիշել, f-գնահատականը և ճշգրտությունը պարզ հաշվարկներից: Մենք հավատում ենք, որ այս մոտեցումը հանգեցնում է առավել օբյեկտիվ և ավելի հեշտ վերարտադրել գնահատումը: Մենք կիրառում ենք սա բժշկական զեկույցի համառոտագրման խնդրի համար, որտեղ օբյեկտիվ որակի և ճշգրտության չափման կարևոր է:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_bn>আমরা একটি পদ্ধতি প্রস্তাব করি তৈরি করা টেক্সটের মানের মূল্য মূল্যের মাধ্যমে মূল্যায়নের মাধ্যমে তথ্য গণনা করতে এবং সুস্পষ্ট, স্মরণ, ফ-স্কোর এব আমরা বিশ্বাস করি এই পদক্ষেপ আরো উদ্দেশ্য এবং আরো সহজেই মূল্য পুনরায় প্রকাশ করে। মেডিকেল রিপোর্টের সারসংক্ষেপের কাজে আমরা এটা প্রয়োগ করি, যেখানে উদ্দেশ্যের মান পরিমাপ এবং সঠিক গুরুত্বপূর্ণ।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Predlažemo metodu za procjenu kvalitete proizvedenog teksta tražeći ocjene da broju činjenice, računaju preciznost, sjećanje, f-rezultat i preciznost iz sirovog broja. Vjerujemo da taj pristup vodi do objektivnije i lakše reprodukcije procjene. Ovo primjenjujemo na zadatak sažetka medicinskog izvješća, gdje je mjerenje objektivne kvalitete i preciznosti najvažnije.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Navrhujeme metodu hodnocení kvality generovaného textu požádáním hodnotících o spočítání faktů a výpočet přesnosti, odvolání, f-skóre a přesnosti z surových počtů. Věříme, že tento přístup vede k objektivnějšímu a snadněji reprodukovatelnému hodnocení. Aplikujeme to na úkol shrnutí lékařských zpráv, kde má měření objektivní kvality a přesnosti prvořadý význam.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Pakume välja meetodi genereeritud teksti kvaliteedi hindamiseks, paludes hindajatel lugeda fakte ning arvutada täpsust, tagasikutsumist, f-skoori ja täpsust toorloendustest. Usume, et selline lähenemisviis viib objektiivsema ja lihtsamalt reprodutseeritava hindamiseni. Me rakendame seda meditsiinilise aruande kokkuvõtliku ülesande puhul, kus objektiivse kvaliteedi ja täpsuse mõõtmine on ülimalt oluline.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ca>Proposem un mètode d'evaluació de la qualitat del text generat demanant als evaluadors que compten els fets, i calculen la precisió, el recordatori, la puntuació f i la precisió dels nombres bruts. Creiem que aquest enfocament condueix a una evaluació més objectiva i més fàcil de reproducir. Això es aplica a la tasca de resum dels informes mèdics, on mesurar la qualitat objectiva i la precisió és de paramèstic importància.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Ehdotamme menetelmää luodun tekstin laadun arvioimiseksi pyytämällä arvioijia laskemaan faktat ja laskemaan tarkkuutta, takaisinkutsua, f-pisteitä ja tarkkuutta raakalaukuista. Uskomme, että tämä lähestymistapa johtaa objektiivisempaan ja helpommin toistettavaan arviointiin. Sovellamme tätä lääketieteellisen raportin yhteenvetoon, jossa objektiivisen laadun ja tarkkuuden mittaaminen on ensiarvoisen tärkeää.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_ha>Tuna goyya da wata hanyoyi wa ka ƙaddara sifar matsayin wanda aka ƙãga a cikin shi, kuma Mu tambayi masu ƙidãya masu gaskiyar, kuma za'a lissafa, kuma don ka tuna, sifar-score, da tsari daga ƙidãyar raw. Tuni yi ĩmãni, wannan hanyor ta ƙara wata kasi da na sauri domin ta karɓi rabo. Munã amfani da wannan zuwa aikin mai tsarinta na takarda mataimaki, a inda ma'auni tsarin abun da gaskiyar ta ƙayyade.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Predlagamo metodo za ocenjevanje kakovosti ustvarjenega besedila z zahtevo ocenjevalcev, da štejejo dejstva, ter natančnost računalništva, odpoklic, f-rezultat in točnost iz surovih števil. Menimo, da ta pristop vodi k objektivnejšemu in lažjemu reproduciranju vrednotenja. To uporabljamo za nalogo povzetka medicinskih poročil, kjer je merjenje objektivne kakovosti in natančnosti izrednega pomena.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Genjer Awak dhéwé nglanggar kuwi diandeksi iki dadi iki luwih apik lan luwih njaluk kanggo mbataluké awak dhéwé. Awak dhéwé nggawe iki dadi nggawe barang pancen urip dadi, ning berarti hasil karo kesempatan kanggo diangkampun kuwi nggawe barang dagatan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>אנו מציעים שיטה להערכה את איכות הטקסט המיוצר על ידי ביקשת ממערכים לספור עובדות, וחשב מדויקה, זיכרון, נקודת f, ודיוקת מהספירות הגדולות. אנו מאמינים שהגישה הזאת מובילה להערכה אובייקטיבית יותר וקל יותר לשחזר. אנו מכניסים את זה למשימה של תיאור דו"ח רפואי, שבו למדוד איכות ודיוק אובייקטיבי הוא חשוב ביותר.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>We propose a method for evaluating the quality of generated text by asking evaluators to count facts, and computing precision, recall, f-score, and accuracy from the raw counts. ང་ཚོས་ཐབས་ལམ་འདིས་དམིགས་འབེབས་བྱས་མིན་པར་ལས་སླ་གཏོང་ཐབས་མེད་པར། འོན་ཀྱང་། འོག་གིས་དམིགས་འབེན་གྱི་རྗེས་སུ་འབྲས་བ་མངོན་གསལ་བཤད་ཀྱི་བྱ་སྤྱོད་སྤྱད་ནས།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Reliability of Human Evaluation for Text Summarization : Lessons Learned and Challenges Ahead</title>
      <author><first>Neslihan</first><last>Iskender</last></author>
      <author><first>Tim</first><last>Polzehl</last></author>
      <author><first>Sebastian</first><last>Möller</last></author>
      <pages>86–96</pages>
      <abstract>Only a small portion of research papers with human evaluation for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_summarization">text summarization</a> provide information about the participant demographics, task design, and experiment protocol. Additionally, many researchers use human evaluation as gold standard without questioning the reliability or investigating the factors that might affect the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliability_(statistics)">reliability</a> of the human evaluation. As a result, there is a lack of best practices for reliable human summarization evaluation grounded by empirical evidence. To investigate human evaluation reliability, we conduct a series of human evaluation experiments, provide an overview of participant demographics, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_of_experiments">task design</a>, experimental set-up and compare the results from different experiments. Based on our empirical analysis, we provide guidelines to ensure the reliability of expert and non-expert evaluations, and we determine the factors that might affect the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reliability_(statistics)">reliability</a> of the human evaluation.</abstract>
      <url hash="b9f00b08">2021.humeval-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>iskender-etal-2021-reliability</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/nesliskender/reliability_humeval_summarization" additional="false">nesliskender/reliability_humeval_summarization</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>Interrater Disagreement Resolution : A Systematic Procedure to Reach Consensus in Annotation Tasks</title>
      <author><first>Yvette</first><last>Oortwijn</last></author>
      <author><first>Thijs</first><last>Ossenkoppele</last></author>
      <author><first>Arianna</first><last>Betti</last></author>
      <pages>131–141</pages>
      <abstract>We present a systematic procedure for interrater disagreement resolution. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subroutine">procedure</a> is general, but of particular use in multiple-annotator tasks geared towards ground truth construction. We motivate our proposal by arguing that, barring cases in which the researchers’ goal is to elicit different viewpoints, interrater disagreement is a sign of poor quality in the design or the description of a task. Consensus among annotators, we maintain, should be striven for, through a systematic procedure for disagreement resolution such as the one we describe.</abstract>
      <url hash="858f30b5">2021.humeval-1.15</url>
      <video href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-O6zZJDxOY" />
      <bibkey>oortwijn-etal-2021-interrater</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/yoortwijn/humevaldisres" additional="false">yoortwijn/humevaldisres</pwccode>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>