<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.unimplicit">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on Understanding Implicit and Underspecified Language</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Michael</first><last>Roth</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Reut</first><last>Tsarfaty</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yoav</first><last>Goldberg</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="2f1d2093">2021.unimplicit-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="ef56eece">2021.unimplicit-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>unimplicit-2021-understanding</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>Evaluation Guidelines to Deal with Implicit Phenomena to Assess Factuality in Data-to-Text Generation</title>
      <author><first>Roy</first><last>Eisenstadt</last></author>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Elhadad</last></author>
      <pages>20–27</pages>
      <abstract>Data-to-text generation systems are trained on large datasets, such as WebNLG, Ro-toWire, E2E or DART. Beyond traditional token-overlap evaluation metrics (BLEU or METEOR), a key concern faced by recent generators is to control the factuality of the generated text with respect to the input data specification. We report on our experience when developing an automatic factuality evaluation system for data-to-text generation that we are testing on WebNLG and E2E data. We aim to prepare gold data annotated manually to identify cases where the text communicates more information than is warranted based on the in-put data (extra) or fails to communicate data that is part of the input (missing). While analyzing reference (data, text) samples, we encountered a range of systematic uncertainties that are related to cases on implicit phenomena in text, and the nature of non-linguistic knowledge we expect to be involved when assessing factuality. We derive from our experience a set of evaluation guidelines to reach high inter-annotator agreement on such cases.</abstract>
      <url hash="56cda1bd">2021.unimplicit-1.3</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.unimplicit-1.3</doi>
      <bibkey>eisenstadt-elhadad-2021-evaluation</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/rotowire">RotoWire</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/wikibio">WikiBio</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>UnImplicit Shared Task Report : Detecting Clarification Requirements in Instructional Text<fixed-case>U</fixed-case>n<fixed-case>I</fixed-case>mplicit Shared Task Report: Detecting Clarification Requirements in Instructional Text</title>
      <author><first>Michael</first><last>Roth</last></author>
      <author><first>Talita</first><last>Anthonio</last></author>
      <pages>28–32</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes the data, task setup, and results of the shared task at the First Workshop on Understanding Implicit and Underspecified Language (UnImplicit). The task requires <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_model">computational models</a> to predict whether a sentence contains aspects of meaning that are contextually unspecified and thus require clarification. Two teams participated and the best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scoring_system">scoring system</a> achieved an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> of 68 %.</abstract>
      <url hash="e7673810">2021.unimplicit-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.unimplicit-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>roth-anthonio-2021-unimplicit</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Human-Model Divergence in the Handling of Vagueness</title>
      <author><first>Elias</first><last>Stengel-Eskin</last></author>
      <author><first>Jimena</first><last>Guallar-Blasco</last></author>
      <author><first>Benjamin</first><last>Van Durme</last></author>
      <pages>43–57</pages>
      <abstract>While aggregate performance metrics can generate valuable insights at a large scale, their dominance means more complex and nuanced language phenomena, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vagueness">vagueness</a>, may be overlooked. Focusing on vague terms (e.g. sunny, cloudy, young, etc.) we inspect the behavior of visually grounded and text-only models, finding systematic divergences from human judgments even when a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a>’s overall performance is high. To help explain this disparity, we identify two assumptions made by the datasets and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_model">models</a> examined and, guided by the philosophy of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vagueness">vagueness</a>, isolate cases where they do not hold.</abstract>
      <url hash="c34ab4ad">2021.unimplicit-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.unimplicit-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>stengel-eskin-etal-2021-human</bibkey>
    <title_ar>اختلاف النموذج البشري في التعامل مع الغموض</title_ar>
      <title_es>Divergencia humano-modelo en el manejo de la vaguedad</title_es>
      <title_pt>Divergência do modelo humano no tratamento da imprecisão</title_pt>
      <title_zh>模糊处中人为模形分歧</title_zh>
      <title_ja>曖昧さの取り扱いにおけるヒューマンモデルの乖離</title_ja>
      <title_hi>अस्पष्टता की हैंडलिंग में मानव-मॉडल विचलन</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Éagsúlacht Mhúnla Daonna i Láimhseáil na Doilleachta</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ადამიანის მოდელური განსხვავება გაგენსის დაკავშირებაში</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Emberi modell eltérések a vaginásság kezelésében</title_hu>
      <title_el>Απόκλιση ανθρώπινου μοντέλου στον χειρισμό της αιφνιδιότητας</title_el>
      <title_it>Divergenza del modello umano nella gestione della vagina</title_it>
      <title_mk>Дивергенцијата на човековиот модел во справувањето со празнината</title_mk>
      <title_ml>വാഗ്വെയിന്റെ കൈകാര്യം ചെയ്യുന്നതില്‍ മനുഷ്യര്‍ മോഡല്‍ ഡിവെര്‍ജെന്‍സ്</title_ml>
      <title_kk>Адам- Моделі Дивергенциясы Вагаенс бағдарламасында</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Žmogaus modelio nevienodumo valdymo srityje</title_lt>
      <title_mt>Diverġenza fil-Mudell tal-Bniedem fl-Immaniġġjar tal-Vagwatezza</title_mt>
      <title_no>Mennesk-modellforskjellighet i behandlinga av Vaguenes</title_no>
      <title_mn>Хүн төрөлхтний загварын өөрчлөлт</title_mn>
      <title_sr>Ljudska modelna razlika u rukovanju Vaguenesa</title_sr>
      <title_ro>Divergența modelului uman în manipularea vagității</title_ro>
      <title_ms>Pencerahan Model Manusia dalam Pengurusan Kekosongan</title_ms>
      <title_sv>Skillnader mellan mänskliga modeller i hanteringen av vaghet</title_sv>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_ta>மாதிரி கையாளியில் மனித மாதிரி பிரிவு</title_ta>
      <title_ur>انسان-مدل مختلف واگوئنس کے تحمل میں</title_ur>
      <title_pl>Rozbieżność modelu ludzkiego w traktowaniu wagi</title_pl>
      <title_so>Difaacsiga dadka-Model in lagu sameeyo Vagueity</title_so>
      <title_vi>Loài người hay biến dạng trong thao tác hư hỏng</title_vi>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_bg>Човешко-моделно различие в справянето с неяснотата</title_bg>
      <title_da>Forskelle mellem menneskelige modeller i håndteringen af vaghed</title_da>
      <title_nl>Mens-model Divergentie in de omgang met vagheid</title_nl>
      <title_hr>Ljudska modelna razlika u rješavanju Vaguenesa</title_hr>
      <title_de>Menschliche Modelldivergenz im Umgang mit Vagueness</title_de>
      <title_id>Divergensi Model Manusia dalam Pengendalian Kekosongan</title_id>
      <title_ko>모호 처리 중인 인체 모형 차이</title_ko>
      <title_fa>مختلف مدل انسان در کنترل واگوئنس</title_fa>
      <title_sw>Utawala wa Kidamu katika Kukabiliwa na Vaguety</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Adamlar-Mody Çeşitlik Faýllary Göçirmekde</title_tr>
      <title_af>Human-Model Divergence in die handling van Vaguenes</title_af>
      <title_sq>Divergjenca e modelit njerëzor në trajtimin e paqartësisë</title_sq>
      <title_bn>ভ্যাগুয়েন্টের হ্যান্ডালিং এ মানুষ-মডেল ডিভারেজেন্স</title_bn>
      <title_hy>Մարդու-մոդելի տարբերությունը դատարկության վերահսկման մեջ</title_hy>
      <title_am>የመስኮት ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_az>İnsan-Model Diversity in the Handling of Vagueness</title_az>
      <title_et>Inimmudeli erinevus häguse käsitlemisel</title_et>
      <title_cs>Divergence lidského modelu v zvládání vahavosti</title_cs>
      <title_bs>Ljudska modelna razlika u rješavanju Vaguenesa</title_bs>
      <title_ca>La divergència entre el model humà i el tractament de la vagància</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Human-Model Divergence in the Handling of Vagueness</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Ngubah-ngubah sing dibenakake uwong nang daftar Vaguenos</title_jv>
      <title_he>גידול בנוגע לדוגמא האנושית בטיפול בעווריות</title_he>
      <title_sk>Razlikovanje človeškega modela pri ravnanju z nejasnostjo</title_sk>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_bo>Vagueness(Vagueness)ཡི་ལག་ལེན་པའི་ནང་དུ་མིའི་མ་དབྱིབས་སྣེ་འདྲ་བ</title_bo>
      <abstract_pt>Embora as métricas de desempenho agregadas possam gerar insights valiosos em grande escala, seu domínio significa que fenômenos de linguagem mais complexos e sutis, como imprecisão, podem ser negligenciados. Concentrando-se em termos vagos (por exemplo, ensolarado, nublado, jovem, etc.), inspecionamos o comportamento de modelos visualmente fundamentados e somente de texto, encontrando divergências sistemáticas de julgamentos humanos, mesmo quando o desempenho geral de um modelo é alto. Para ajudar a explicar essa disparidade, identificamos duas suposições feitas pelos conjuntos de dados e modelos examinados e, guiados pela filosofia da imprecisão, isolamos os casos em que elas não se sustentam.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>في حين أن مقاييس الأداء الإجمالية يمكن أن تولد رؤى قيمة على نطاق واسع ، فإن هيمنتها تعني التغاضي عن ظواهر لغوية أكثر تعقيدًا ودقة ، مثل الغموض. بالتركيز على المصطلحات الغامضة (على سبيل المثال ، مشمس ، غائم ، شاب ، إلخ.) نقوم بفحص سلوك النماذج القائمة على أساس بصري والنصوص فقط ، وإيجاد اختلافات منهجية من الأحكام البشرية حتى عندما يكون الأداء العام للنموذج مرتفعًا. للمساعدة في تفسير هذا التباين ، نحدد افتراضين قدمتهما مجموعات البيانات والنماذج التي تم فحصها ، واسترشادًا بفلسفة الغموض ، نعزل الحالات التي لا تحملها.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Si bien las métricas de rendimiento agregadas pueden generar información valiosa a gran escala, su dominio significa que los fenómenos lingüísticos más complejos y matizados, como la vaguedad, pueden pasarse por alto. Centrándonos en términos vagos (por ejemplo, soleado, nublado, joven, etc.), inspeccionamos el comportamiento de los modelos con base visual y de solo texto, encontrando divergencias sistemáticas con los juicios humanos, incluso cuando el rendimiento general de un modelo es alto. Para ayudar a explicar esta disparidad, identificamos dos suposiciones hechas por los conjuntos de datos y los modelos examinados y, guiados por la filosofía de la vaguedad, aislamos los casos en los que no son válidos.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>集計されたパフォーマンスメトリクスは、大規模な貴重な洞察を生成することができますが、それらの優位性は、曖昧さなどのより複雑で微妙な言語現象を意味し、見落とされる可能性があります。曖昧な用語（例：晴れ、曇り、若いなど）に焦点を当てて、視覚的に基礎づけられたモデルとテキストのみのモデルの挙動を検査し、モデルの全体的なパフォーマンスが高い場合でも、人間の判断から体系的な乖離を見つけます。この格差を説明するために、私たちは調べたデータセットとモデルによって行われた2つの仮定を特定し、曖昧さの哲学に導かれて、それらが保持しないケースを分離します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>虽总性能指标可大生直见,然其主导地位意更杂细微之言(模糊性)可被忽视也。 注于模糊之术语(如阳明之多云,少年之),视其基本,纯文本其行,虽形体性高,与人决系统性异。 为之说异,定其数集和模型为之二假,而于模糊性哲学导之,隔其不立。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>जबकि समग्र प्रदर्शन मीट्रिक बड़े पैमाने पर मूल्यवान अंतर्दृष्टि उत्पन्न कर सकते हैं, उनके प्रभुत्व का मतलब है कि अधिक जटिल और सूक्ष्म भाषा की घटना, जैसे कि अस्पष्टता, को अनदेखा किया जा सकता है। अस्पष्ट शब्दों (जैसे धूप, बादल, युवा, आदि) पर ध्यान केंद्रित करते हुए, हम नेत्रहीन आधार और पाठ-केवल मॉडल के व्यवहार का निरीक्षण करते हैं, मानव निर्णयों से व्यवस्थित विचलन पाते हैं, भले ही एक मॉडल का समग्र प्रदर्शन उच्च हो। इस असमानता को समझाने में मदद करने के लिए, हम डेटासेट और मॉडल द्वारा की गई दो मान्यताओं की पहचान करते हैं और, अस्पष्टता के दर्शन द्वारा निर्देशित, उन मामलों को अलग करते हैं जहां वे नहीं रखते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Cé gur féidir le méadracht chomhiomlán feidhmíochta léargais luachmhara a ghiniúint ar mhórscála, ciallaíonn a gceannasacht go bhféadfaí feiniméin teanga níos casta agus níos nuanálaithe, cosúil le doiléire, a ligean ar lár. Ag díriú ar théarmaí doiléire (m.sh. grianmhar, scamallach, óg, srl.) déanaimid iniúchadh ar iompraíocht samhlacha atá bunaithe ar fhís agus ar théacs amháin, ag aimsiú éagsúlachtaí córasacha ó bhreithiúnais dhaonna fiú nuair a bhíonn feidhmíocht fhoriomlán samhail ard. Chun cabhrú leis an difríocht seo a mhíniú, sainaithnímid dhá thoimhde a rinne na tacair sonraí agus na samhlacha a scrúdaíodh agus, faoi threoir fhealsúnacht na doiléire, aonraimid cásanna nach bhfuil acu.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_hu>Míg az aggregált teljesítménymutatók nagy léptékben értékes betekintéseket hozhatnak létre, dominanciájuk összetettebb és árnyaltabb nyelvi jelenségeket, mint például a homályosságot figyelmen kívül hagyhatják. A homályos kifejezésekre (pl. napos, felhős, fiatal stb.) összpontosítva vizuálisan alapozott és csak szöveges modellek viselkedését vizsgáljuk, rendszeres eltéréseket találunk az emberi ítéletektől még akkor is, ha egy modell teljesítménye magas. Ennek az eltérésnek a magyarázata érdekében a vizsgált adatkészletek és modellek két feltételezését azonosítjuk, és a homályosság filozófiájának vezérlésével elkülönítjük azokat az eseteket, amelyeket nem tartanak fenn.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Mentre le metriche di performance aggregate possono generare informazioni preziose su larga scala, la loro dominanza significa che fenomeni linguistici più complessi e sfumati, come la vaghezza, possono essere trascurati. Concentrandoci su termini vaghi (ad esempio sole, nuvoloso, giovane, ecc.) esaminiamo il comportamento dei modelli visivamente fondati e solo testuali, trovando differenze sistematiche dai giudizi umani anche quando le prestazioni complessive di un modello sono elevate. Per aiutare a spiegare questa disparità, identifichiamo due ipotesi fatte dai dataset e dai modelli esaminati e, guidati dalla filosofia della vaghezza, isoliamo casi in cui non si reggono.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_kk>Бірнеше жылдамдық метрикасы үлкен маңызды түсініктерді құрастыруға болады. Олардың доминистігі көпшілікті және көпшілікті тіл пайдаланулары, мысалы, көпшілік сияқты, көпшіл Күні, бұлттық, жас және т. б. қалыпты терминлерде (мысалы, күні, бұлттық, жас және т. б.) біз көрінетін және тек мәтін үлгілерінің қасиеттерін тексереміз, адамдардың тәжірибелерінен жүйелік түрлерін табу ү Бұл айырмашылығын түсіндіру үшін біз тексерілген деректер қорлары мен үлгілері жасалған екі тапсырмаларды анықтаймыз. Бұл тапсырмалардың философиясы, олардың тұрмаған жерде айырмашылық болып тұрған</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_el>Ενώ οι συγκεντρωτικές μετρήσεις απόδοσης μπορούν να δημιουργήσουν πολύτιμες πληροφορίες σε μεγάλη κλίμακα, η κυριαρχία τους σημαίνει ότι μπορεί να παραβλεφθούν πιο πολύπλοκα και διαφοροποιημένα γλωσσικά φαινόμενα, όπως η ασάφεια. Εστιάζοντας σε αόριστους όρους (π.χ. ηλιόλουστο, συννεφιασμένο, νεαρό κ.λπ.) επιθεωρούμε τη συμπεριφορά των οπτικά γειωμένων και μόνο κειμένων μοντέλων, βρίσκοντας συστηματικές αποκλίσεις από τις ανθρώπινες κρίσεις ακόμα και όταν η συνολική απόδοση ενός μοντέλου είναι υψηλή. Για να βοηθήσουμε στην εξήγηση αυτής της ανισότητας, εντοπίζουμε δύο υποθέσεις που προκύπτουν από τα σύνολα δεδομένων και τα μοντέλα που εξετάζονται και, καθοδηγούμενοι από τη φιλοσοφία της ασάφειας, απομονώνουμε περιπτώσεις όπου δεν ισχύουν.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>თუმცა ადგრაფიური პროცექტის მეტრიკის შესაძლებელია უფრო მნიშვნელოვანი მონაცემები დიდი განზომილებაში, მათი დომინეცია ნიშნავს უფრო კომპლექსიური და ძალიან ენერგიის ფენ ჩვენ ვიზუალურად მხოლოდ ტექსტიური მოდელების მონაცემების მონაცემების მონაცემების შესახებ, სისტემატიური განსხვავებების შესახებ ადამიანის შესახებ, მაგრამ როდესაც მხოლოდ მოდელის საუკეთესო მონაცემების გა რომ დახმარებთ ამ განსხვავებას, ჩვენ განვიცნობით ორი წარმოდგენები, რომლებიც შევხედავთ მონაცემებები და მოდელები, რომლებიც გაგზავრების ფილოსოფიკაცია, თიზოლური შემთხვევაში, რო</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_ms>Sementara metrik prestasi aggregat boleh menghasilkan pandangan berharga pada skala besar, dominasi mereka bermakna fenomena bahasa yang lebih kompleks dan nuans, seperti ketidakjelasan, mungkin dilupakan. Berfokus pada terma yang tidak jelas (cth. matahari, awan, muda, dll.) kita periksa perilaku model yang berdasarkan visual dan hanya teks, mencari perbezaan sistemik dari penilaian manusia walaupun prestasi umum model tinggi. Untuk membantu menjelaskan ketidaksamaan ini, kami mengenalpasti dua asumsi yang dibuat oleh set data dan model yang diperiksa dan, dipandu oleh filosofi ketidaksamaan, mengisolasi kes di mana mereka tidak memegang.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>പ്രകടനത്തിന്റെ മെട്രിക്കുകള്‍ക്ക് വിലപിടിക്കാന്‍ കഴിയുമ്പോള്‍ അതിന്റെ അധികാരം കൂടുതല്‍ കുറച്ചും കൂടുതല്‍ കൂടുതല്‍ ചിന്തിക്കുന്ന ഭാഷ വ്യത്യസ്തമായ വാക്കുകളില്‍ ശ്രദ്ധിക്കുന്നത് (ഉദാഹരണമായ സൂര്യന്‍, മേഘം, ചെറുപ്പക്കാര്‍) നാം കാഴ്ചപ്പെടുത്തിയ സ്വഭാവം പരിശോധിക്കുന്നു. മോഡലിന്റെ മൊത്തം പ് ഈ വ്യത്യാസത്തെ വിശദീകരിക്കാന്‍ സഹായിക്കാന്‍, നമ്മള്‍ പരിശോധിക്കപ്പെട്ട ഡാറ്റാസറ്റുകളും മോഡലുകളും ഉണ്ടാക്കിയ രണ്ട് ഊഹികങ്ങള്‍ കണ്ടെത്</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mk>Иако агрегетните метрики на резултатите можат да генерираат вредни сфаќања на голем степен, нивната доминанција значи покомплексни и нијансирани јазички феномени, како што е нејасноста, може да бидат заборавени. Focusing on vague terms (e.g. sunny, cloudy, young, etc.) we inspect the behavior of visually grounded and text-only models, finding systematic divergences from human judgments even when a model's overall performance is high.  За да помогнеме во објаснувањето на оваа разлика, идентификуваме две претпоставувања направени од податоците и моделите испитани и, водени од филозофијата на нејасноста, изолираат случаи каде што тие не ги држат.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mt>Filwaqt li l-metriċi tal-prestazzjoni aggregata jistgħu jiġġeneraw fehmiet ta’ valur fuq skala kbira, id-dominanza tagħhom tfisser fenomeni lingwistiċi aktar kumplessi u nuanċjati, bħall-vagezza, jistgħu jiġu injorati. Filwaqt li niffokaw fuq termini vagi (pereżempju xemx, imċajpra, żg ħa żagħ, e ċċ.) aħna ninspezzjonaw l-imġiba ta’ mudelli viżwalment ibbażati fuq l-art u biss bit-test, isibu diverġenzi sistematiċi mis-sentenzi umani anki meta l-prestazzjoni globali ta’ mudell hija għolja. Biex ngħinu jispjegaw din id-disparità, nidentifikaw żewġ suppożizzjonijiet magħmula mis-settijiet tad-dejta u l-mudelli eżaminati u, iggwidati mill-filosofija tal-vagezza, niżolaw każijiet fejn dawn ma jżommux.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_pl>Podczas gdy zbiorcze wskaźniki wydajności mogą generować cenne informacje na dużą skalę, ich dominacja oznacza, że bardziej złożone i niuansowane zjawiska językowe, takie jak niejasność, mogą zostać pominięte. Koncentrując się na niejasnych terminach (np. słoneczny, pochmurny, młody itp.) badamy zachowanie modeli uziemionych wizualnie i tekstowych, wykrywając systematyczne rozbieżności od osądów ludzkich, nawet gdy ogólna wydajność modelu jest wysoka. Aby pomóc wyjaśnić tę dysproporcję, identyfikujemy dwa założenia badanych zbiorów danych i modeli oraz, kierując się filozofią niejasności, izolujemy przypadki, w których nie mają zastosowania.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>În timp ce măsurătorile de performanță agregate pot genera informații valoroase la scară largă, dominanța lor înseamnă fenomene lingvistice mai complexe și nuanțate, cum ar fi vagitatea, pot fi trecute cu vederea. Focalizându-ne pe termeni vagi (de exemplu, însorit, noros, tânăr etc.) inspectăm comportamentul modelelor bazate vizual și numai pe text, găsind divergențe sistematice față de judecățile umane chiar și atunci când performanța generală a unui model este ridicată. Pentru a ajuta la explicarea acestei disparități, identificăm două ipoteze făcute de seturile de date și modelele examinate și, ghidate de filozofia vagității, izolăm cazurile în care nu există.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_mn>Хэдийгээр нийтлэг үйл ажиллагааны метрик нь том хэмжээнд үнэ цэнэтэй ойлголт бий болгож чадна. Тэдний давамгайлалт нь илүү нарийн, цогц хэлний явдал гэсэн үг. Гэвч нарны, үүл, залуу гэх мэт тодорхойлолтой хэлбэрээр бид харагдаж, текст зөвхөн загварын загварыг шалгаж, хүн төрөлхтний шийдвэрлэлээс систематик ялгааг олох юм. Энэ ялгааг тайлбарлахын тулд бид өгөгдлийн сангууд, загваруудын шалгалт хийсэн хоёр тодорхойлолтуудыг тодорхойлдог. Мөн тэдний байхгүй газрын философийг удирдлагатай.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_sr>Iako aggregatna emisija metrika može stvoriti vrijedne uvide na velikoj skali, njihova dominacija znači kompleksnije i nuanciranije jezičke fenomene, poput vaguelnosti, mogu biti pregledana. Fokusirajući s e na nevažne uslove (npr. sunce, oblačno, mlade, itd.), provjeravamo ponašanje vizuelno osnovanih i samo tekstualnih model a, pronalaženje sistematičnih razlika od ljudskih osuđivanja čak i kada je ukupna izvedba modela visoka. Da bismo pomogli da objasnimo ovu razliku, identifikujemo dve pretpostavke koje su napravljene ispitivanjem podataka i modela i, vodeće filozofijom nevažnosti, izoliranim slučajevima u kojima ne drže.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Inta lagu sameynayo qaab aad u qiimo leh, xukunkoodu waxay leedahay wax ka badan oo ka qallafsan luqada, tusaale ahaan qalloocan. Iska fiirsanaynaa sharciga caadiga ah (tusaale ahaan qorraxda, daruurka, dhallinyarada, etc.) waxaynu fiirinaynaa dabeecada aragtida iyo tusaalaha saxda oo kaliya, si aan u helno kala duwanaanshaha nidaamka e e xukunka dadka xittaa marka sameynta tusaalka oo dhan aad u sarreeya. Si aan u caawiyo faa'iidadan, waxaynu aqoonsanaynaa laba malooyin oo ay sameyn jireen labada malab oo ay sameyn jireen, waxaana hagay filsafada aan garanayn, gooni ah xaaladaha aan haysan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Medan aggregerade prestandamätningar kan generera värdefulla insikter i stor skala, innebär deras dominans att mer komplexa och nyanserade språkfenomen, såsom vaghet, kan förbises. Med fokus på vaga termer (t.ex. soligt, molnigt, ungt osv.) undersöker vi beteendet hos visuellt grundade och textbara modeller, och finner systematiska avvikelser från mänskliga bedömningar även när en modells övergripande prestanda är hög. För att förklara denna skillnad identifierar vi två antaganden som gjorts av de datauppsättningar och modeller som undersökts och, vägledda av filosofin om vaghet, isolerar fall där de inte håller.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>සම්පූර්ණ ක්‍රියාත්මක මෙට්‍රික්ස් එක්ක විශේෂ ප්‍රමාණයක් ලොකු ප්‍රමාණයකින් විශ්වාස කරන්න පුළුවන්, ඔවුන්ගේ ප්‍රමාණය අපි බලන්න ප්‍රමාණය සහ පාළුවක් විතරයි, මිනිස්සු විධානයෙන් පරීක්ෂා කරනවා (උදාහරණයෙන්, සුද්ධ, වැඩිය, තරුණ, etc.) අපි බලන්න ප්‍රමාණය සහ පාළුව මේ විරුද්ධ විස්තර කරන්න උදව් කරන්න, අපි දත්ත සැටි සහ මදුල් පරීක්ෂණා කරලා තියෙන්නේ දෙකක් හොයාගන්න, ඒ වගේම, විශේෂ විද්‍යා</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>حالانکہ عملکرد متریک ایک بڑے مقدار سے ارزش دار نظر پیدا کر سکتا ہے، ان کی تعلق کا مطلب ہے کہ زیادہ پیچیدہ اور غلطی زبان کی ظاہر، جیسے غلطی، غلطی ہے. ہم نے بغیر متفاوت شرایط پر تمرکز کیا ہے (یعنی سورج، بادل، جوان، اگلے) ہم دیکھتے ہیں کہ بغیر متفاوت اور متن کے متقابل مدلکوں کی رفتاری ہے، اور انسان کے فیصلے سے سیستم اختلاف پاتے ہیں، اگرچہ ایک مدلک کا عملہ بالا ہے۔ اس اختلاف کی توضیح کرنے کے لئے ہم دو فرضیوں کو پہچان لیتے ہیں جنہیں تحقیق کیا گیا ہے اور دکھائے گئے ہیں اور دکھائے گئے ہوئے فرضیوں کے ذریعہ راہ دکھائے جاتے ہیں اور ایک دوسرے کی فرضیوں کو پہچان لیتے ہیں جہاں وہ نہیں پکڑتے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_lt>Nors bendrasis veiklos rodiklis gali sukelti vertingą supratimą plačiu mastu, jų dominuojantis vaidmuo reiškia sudėtingesnius ir nuancingesnius kalbos reiškinius, pvz., neaiškumą, gali būti pamirštamas. Svarstydami neaiškias s ąvokas (pvz., saulės, drumstų, jaunų ir t. t.), tikriname vizualiai pagrįstų ir tik teksto modelių elgesį, nustatydami sisteminius skirtumus nuo žmogaus sprendimų net ir tada, kai modelio bendras veiksmingumas yra didelis. Kad padėtume paaiškinti šį skirtumą, nustatome dvi prielaidas, kurias daro nagrinėjami duomenų rinkiniai ir modeliai, ir, vadovaudamiesi neaiškumo filosofija, atskiriame atvejus, kai jie nėra.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_no>Mens aggregate funksjonsmetrikar kan laga verdilege innsyningar på stor skala, kan dominasjonen deres betyr meir komplekse og nuancerte språksfenomen, slik som vaguens, oversjå. Fokuserer vi på ugyldige uttrykk (f.eks. sol, skygg, unge osv.) Vi kontrollerer atferden av visuelt bakgrunnert og bare tekst- modeller, og finn systematiske forskjeller frå menneske uttrykk sjølv når ein modell har heilt uttrykk. For å hjelpa å forklare denne ulikheten, identifiserer vi to assumpsjonar gjort av dei undersøkte datasetta og modelane og, hjelpet av filosofia av vaguende, isolerte tilfeller der dei ikkje held.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ta>பெரிய அளவில் செயல்பாட்டு முறைகள் மதிப்புள்ள குறிப்புகளை உருவாக்க முடியும் போது, அவர்களுடைய அதிகாரம் என்றால் மிகவும் சிக்கலாம் மற்றும் குற மாதிரியின் மொத்த செயல்பாடு அதிகமாக இருந்தாலும் முறைமையான வித்தியாசங்களை கண்டுபிடிக்கிறோம். இந்த எதிர்பார்ப்பை விளக்க உதவுகிறது, நாம் பரிசோதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள தரவுத்தளங்கள் மற்றும் மாதிரிகள் செய்த இரண்டு எண்ணங்களை கண்டுபிடிக்க,</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>Koʻpaytirish metriklari katta balandda qiymati ko'rinishni yaratish mumkin, ularning xususiyati juda murakkablik va nuqta tillar holatini tushunishi mumkin. Biz oddiy so'zlar (m.g. qora, o'qish, yosh va o'qish) xuddi ko'rinamiz va faqat matn modellarining xuddi ko'rinamiz, va modelning umumiy bajarishi juda katta paydo bo'lganda oddiy o'zgarishlarni o'rganamiz. Bu tarqatishni aytishga yordam beramiz, biz bir g'oyalarni ko'rsatilgan maʼlumotlar va modellar yaratilgan ikkita g'oyalarni aniqlash va muvaffaqiyatli filosofiyatlarni ko'rsatganda o'zgartirish mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Trong khi đo trình độ phổ biến có thể tạo ra những nhận thức quan trọng trên diện rộng, sự thống trị của chúng có nghĩa là hiện tượng ngôn ngữ phức tạp và mơ hồ, như mơ hồ, có thể bị bỏ qua. Tập trung vào các thuật ngữ mơ hồ (v.d. có nắng, mây, trẻ, v.v) chúng tôi kiểm tra hành vi của các mô hình hình hình hình hình hình hình hình hình trực tiếp và chỉ văn bản, tìm ra sai s ót có hệ thống so với phán xét con người kể cả khi mô hình chung cao. Để giải thích sự khác biệt này, chúng tôi xác định hai giả thuyết của các tập tin và các mẫu đã xem xét và, dựa trên triết lý mơ hồ, phân tách các trường hợp không chứa.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>Hoewel geaggregeerde prestatiestatistieken op grote schaal waardevolle inzichten kunnen genereren, betekent hun dominantie dat complexere en genuanceerdere taalfenomenen, zoals vaagheid, over het hoofd kunnen worden gezien. Met de nadruk op vage termen (bijv. zonnig, bewolkt, jong, enz.) inspecteren we het gedrag van visueel geaarde en tekst-only modellen, waarbij we systematische afwijkingen vinden van menselijke oordelen, zelfs wanneer de algehele prestaties van een model hoog zijn. Om deze ongelijkheid te helpen verklaren, identificeren we twee aannames van de onderzochte datasets en modellen en isoleren we, geleid door de filosofie van vaagheid, gevallen waar ze niet van toepassing zijn.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Iako aggregatne mjere učinka mogu proizvesti vrijedne uvide na velikoj mjeri, njihova dominacija znači kompleksniji i nuanciraniji jezički fenomeni, poput vaguenosti, mogu se pregledati. Fokusirajući s e na nevažne uvjete (npr. sunčano, oblačno, mlado, itd.), provjeravamo ponašanje vizualno osnovanih i samo tekstualnih model a, pronalaženje sistematičnih razlika od ljudskih osuđivanja čak i kada je ukupna djelovanja modela visoka. Da bismo pomogli objasniti ovu razliku, identificirali smo dvije pretpostavke koje su napravljene ispitivanim podacima i modelima i, vodeći filozofijom nevažnosti, izoliranim slučajevima u kojima se ne drže.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Докато агрегираните показатели за ефективността могат да генерират ценни прозрения в голям мащаб, тяхното господство означава, че по-сложни и нюансирани езикови явления, като неяснота, могат да бъдат пренебрегнати. Фокусирайки се върху неясни термини (например слънчеви, облачни, млади и т.н.) ние проверяваме поведението на визуално обосновани и текстови модели, откривайки системни отклонения от човешките преценки, дори когато цялостната производителност на модела е висока. За да обясним това несъответствие, идентифицираме две предположения, направени от изследваните набори от данни и модели и, ръководени от философията на неяснотата, изолираме случаите, в които те не се държат.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Mens aggregerede præstationsmålinger kan generere værdifuld indsigt i stor skala, betyder deres dominans, at mere komplekse og nuancerede sprogfænomener, såsom vaghed, kan overses. Med fokus på vage udtryk (f.eks. solrig, overskyet, ung osv.) inspicerer vi opførselen af visuelt grundede og tekstkun modeller og finder systematiske afvigelser fra menneskelige vurderinger, selv når en models samlede præstation er høj. For at hjælpe med at forklare denne forskel identificerer vi to antagelser fremsat af de undersøgte datasæt og modeller og, styret af filosofien om vaghed, isolerer tilfælde, hvor de ikke holder.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_ko>전체적인 성능 지표는 어느 정도에 가치 있는 견해를 나타낼 수 있지만 그들의 주도적인 지위는 더욱 복잡하고 미세한 언어 현상, 예를 들어 모호성을 의미하기 때문에 무시될 수 있다.우리는 모호한 용어(예를 들어 햇빛, 구름이 많고 젊음 등)를 주목하고 시각적 기초 모델과 순수한 텍스트 모델의 행위를 검사한 결과 모델의 전체적인 성능이 높아도 체계적으로 인류의 판단에서 벗어난 것을 발견했다.이러한 차이를 해석하는 데 도움을 주기 위해 우리는 연구한 데이터 집합과 모델이 한 두 가지 가설을 확정하고 모호한 철학의 지도 아래 그것들이 성립되지 않는 상황을 격리시켰다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_de>Während aggregierte Leistungskennzahlen in großem Maßstab wertvolle Erkenntnisse generieren können, bedeutet ihre Dominanz, dass komplexere und nuancierte Sprachphänomene, wie z.B. Unschärfe, übersehen werden können. Mit dem Fokus auf vage Begriffe (z.B. sonnig, bewölkt, jung, etc.) untersuchen wir das Verhalten visuell geerdeter und textbasierter Modelle und finden systematische Abweichungen von menschlichen Urteilen, auch wenn die Gesamtleistung eines Modells hoch ist. Um diese Disparität zu erklären, identifizieren wir zwei Annahmen, die von den untersuchten Datensätzen und Modellen gemacht werden, und isolieren, angeleitet von der Philosophie der Unschärfe, Fälle, in denen sie nicht zutreffen.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Sementara metrik prestasi agregat dapat menghasilkan pandangan berharga pada skala besar, dominasi mereka berarti fenomena bahasa yang lebih kompleks dan nuansi, seperti ketidakjelasan, mungkin diabaikan. Fokus pada istilah-istilah yang tidak jelas (misalnya matahari, awan, muda, dll.) kami memeriksa perilaku dari model yang terletak secara visual dan hanya teks, menemukan divergensi sistematis dari penilaian manusia bahkan ketika prestasi umum model tinggi. Untuk membantu menjelaskan ketidakpersamaan ini, kami mengidentifikasi dua asumsi yang dibuat oleh dataset dan model yang diperiksa dan, dipandu oleh filosofi ketidakpastian, mengisolasi kasus di mana mereka tidak memegang.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>در حالی که متریک عملکرد جمع می‌تواند در مقیاس بزرگ بینایی ارزشمند را تولید کند، فرمانروایی آنها یعنی بینایی‌های زبان پیچیده‌تر و ناتوان‌تر، مثل ناتوانی، ممکن است فراموش شود. تمرکز روی شرایط غیرقابل (مثلاً خورشید، ابر، جوان و غیر قابل توجه) رفتار فقط مدل‌های بنیادی و متن را بررسی می‌کنیم، و در حال پیدا کردن فرق‌های سیستمی از قضاوت‌های انسان حتی هنگامی که عملکرد عمومی مدل بالا است. برای کمک به توضیح این اختلاف، ما دو فرضیه را شناسایی می کنیم که توسط مجموعه‌های داده‌ها و مدل‌های تحقیق شده و، توسط فلسفه‌ای از غیر قابل توجه، پرونده‌های جدا و جدا می‌کنیم که آن‌ها نگه نمی‌دارند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_af>Alhoewel die samelekte prestasie metries waardelike insigs op 'n groot skaal genereer kan word, beteken hulle dominasie meer kompleks en nuanced taal fenomene, soos vaguens, kan oorskou word. Ons inspekteer die gedrag van visuele agtergrond en slegs teks-model e, en on s vind sistematiese verskillinge van menslike oordelings selfs wanneer 'n model se heeltemal produksie hoog is. Om hierdie verskilligheid te verduidelik te help, identifiseer ons twee aanvaardes wat deur die ondersoekte datastelle en modele gemaak is en, wat deur die filosofie van vaguenheid, isolate gevalle waar hulle nie hou nie.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_tr>Topar eserleşmeler metrikleri uly derejede deň pikirleri döredip biler, olaryň dominasiýasy has karmaşık we täsirli dil parçalaryny diýip görkezilip biler. Köp şertlerde üns berilýäris (mysal. g üneş, bulut, ýa ş we bölegi) görnüş we diňe metin modelleriniň davranışyny barýarys, adamlaryň häsiýetlerinden sistematik üýtgeşmeleri ýok bolsa hem nusgalaryň ýokarynda pikir edýäris. Bu tapawutlygy düşündirmek üçin, soraglany we nusgalaryň tarapyndan eden iki pikir belirleýäris we, takyksyzlyklyň filosofiýasy tarapyndan guruldyrylýan, ýöne bolmadyklarynyň ýene-de bir nusga belirleýäris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_sq>Ndërsa metrikat e paraqitjes së përgjithshme mund të gjenerojnë pamje të vlefshme në një shkallë të madhe, mbizotërimi i tyre do të thotë fenomene më komplekse dhe të nuancuara gjuhësh, të tilla si paqartësia, mund të harrohen. Duke u përqëndruar në terma të paqarta (për shembull dielli, i re, i ri, etj.) ne inspektojmë sjelljen e modeleve të themeluar vizualisht dhe vetëm teksti, duke gjetur dallime sistematike nga gjykimet njerëzore edhe kur performanca e përgjithshme e një modeli është e lartë. Për të ndihmuar në shpjegimin e këtij mungese, ne identifikojmë dy supozime të bërë nga grupet e të dhënave dhe modelet e shqyrtuar dhe, të udhëzuar nga filozofia e paqartësisë, izolojmë rastet ku ato nuk mbajnë.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_am>የድምፅ አካባቢ ማህበረሰብ ብዛት ዋጋን ማውጣት የሚችል ሲሆን፣ ግዛታቸው ትክክለኛ እና አካባቢ ቋንቋ አካባቢ፣ ብጤታዊ እንደሆነ መፍጠር ይችላል፡፡ አካባቢ ግንኙነት (ምሳሌ ፀሐይ፣ ደመና፣ ወጣት፣ etc) እና የጽሑፍ ብዛት የተመሠረቱትን እና የጽሑፍ ተግባር ብቻ ምሳሌዎችን እናስመርጣለን፤ የሞላው ሙሉ ሙሉ ፍትሕርት ከፍተኛ ቢሆን እንኳን የሰው ፍርድ ጥያቄዎችን እናገኛለን፡፡ ይህንን ትክክለኛ ለመግለጽ፣ የተመረጠውን ሁለቱን የዳታ ሰርዓቶች እና ሞዴላዎችን እናሳውቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_sw>Wakati mbinu za utendaji unaweza kutengeneza mitazamo ya thamani kwa kiwango kikubwa, utawala wao unamaanisha mambo ya lugha tatizo na yenye umuhimu, kama vile yasiyoeleweka, inaweza kuangaliwa. Kujikita kwenye maneno yasiyo na maana (kama vile jua, mawingu, vijana, etc.) tunachungulia tabia za mifano yenye msingi wa kuona na kwa kutumia maandishi pekee, na kutafuta tofauti za mfumo kutoka kwenye hukumu za binadamu hata kama utendaji wa mifano kwa ujumla ni juu. Ili kusaidia kuelezea tofauti hizi, tunagundua dhana mbili zilizotengenezwa na seti za data na mifano zinazochunguzwa na, zinaongozwa na falsafa ya kutokuwepo na usawa, kutengwa kwa matukio yasiyokuwepo.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_hy>While aggregate performance metrics can generate valuable insights at a large scale, their dominance means more complex and nuanced language phenomena, such as vagueness, may be overlooked.  Մենք կենտրոնացնում ենք անորոշ տերմինների վրա (օրինակ արևային, ամպույտ, երիտասարդ և այլն) մենք ստուգում ենք տեսողական հիմքերի և միայն տեքստի մոդելների վարքագիծը, որոնք համակարգչային տարբերություններ են հայտնում մարդկային դատողություններից նույնիսկ երբ մոդելի ընդհանուր արտադր To help explain this disparity, we identify two assumptions made by the datasets and models examined and, guided by the philosophy of vagueness, isolate cases where they do not hold.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Böyük ölçüdə qiymətli görüntüləri təşkil edə bilərsə, onların dominasyonu daha kompleks və nuanced dil görüntülərini anlamına gəlir, çünki təhlükəsizlik kimi təhlükəsizlik edilər. Müxtəlif şəkillərə (g ünəş, bulud, genç, etc.) tərzdə tərzdə tərzdə tərzdə baxırıq, modelinin bütün performansı yüksək olduğu halda sistematik fərqliyi tapırıq. Bu müxtəlifliyi açıqlamağa kömək etmək üçün, araştırılmış verilənlər və modellər tarafından yapılmış iki təsəvvür təsdiqləyirik və, müxtəlif filosofi ilə yönəldirdik, özlərinin tutmadığı məsələlər isolatırıq.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Iako aggregatna predstavna metrika može stvoriti vrijedne uvide na velikoj skali, njihova dominacija znači kompleksniji i nuanciraniji jezički fenomeni, poput vaguenosti, mogu biti pregledana. Fokusirajući s e na nevažne uvjete (npr. sunčano, oblačno, mlado, itd.), provjeravamo ponašanje vizualno osnovanih i samo tekstualnih model a, pronalaženje sistematičnih razlika od ljudskih osuđivanja čak i kada je ukupna izvedba modela visoka. Da bismo pomogli objasniti ovu razliku, identificirali smo dvije pretpostavke koje su napravile pregledani podaci i modeli i, vodeći filozofijom nevažnosti, izolirali slučajevi u kojima ne drže.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_et>Kuigi tulemuslikkuse koondmõõdikud võivad luua väärtuslikku ülevaadet suures ulatuses, tähendab nende domineerimine keerulisemaid ja nüanssidega keelelisi nähtusi, nagu ebamäärasus, võidakse unustada. Keskendudes ebamäärasetele terminitele (nt päikesepaisteline, pilvine, noor jne) kontrollime visuaalselt maandatud ja tekstiga mudelite käitumist, leides süstemaatilisi erinevusi inimlikest hinnangutest isegi siis, kui mudeli üldine jõudlus on kõrge. Selle erinevuse selgitamiseks tuvastame uuritud andmekogumite ja mudelite põhjal kaks eeldust ning eristame ebamäärasuse filosoofiast lähtuvalt juhtumeid, kus need ei vasta.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_ca>Mentre que les mètriques de rendiment agregades poden generar visions valioses a gran escala, la seva dominació vol dir que es poden ignorar fenomens de llenguatge més complexes i nuances, com la vaguetat. Concentrant-nos en termes vags (per exemple sol, núvol, jove, etc.) inspeccionem el comportament de model s visualment basats i només en text, trobant divergències sistemàtiques dels judicis humans fins i tot quan el rendiment global d'un model és alt. To help explain this disparity, we identify two assumptions made by the datasets and models examined and, guided by the philosophy of vagueness, isolate cases where they do not hold.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Zatímco agregátní výkonnostní metriky mohou generovat cenné poznatky ve velkém měřítku, jejich dominanta znamená, že složitější a nuancovanější jazykové jevy, jako je vágnost, lze přehlédnout. Zaměřením se na vágní termíny (např. slunečný, zatažený, mladý atd.) kontrolujeme chování vizuálně uzemněných a textových modelů a nalezneme systematické odchylky od lidských úsudků, i když je celkový výkon modelu vysoký. Abychom tuto rozdílnost pomohli vysvětlit, identifikujeme dva předpoklady zkoumaných datových sad a modelů a podle filozofie vágnosti izolujeme případy, kdy neplatí.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Vaikka suorituskykymittarit voivat tuottaa arvokkaita näkemyksiä suuressa mittakaavassa, niiden hallitseva asema tarkoittaa monimutkaisempia ja monivivahteisempia kieliilmiöitä, kuten epämääräisyyttä, voidaan jättää huomiotta. Keskitymme epämääräisiin termeihin (esim. aurinkoinen, pilvinen, nuori jne.) ja tarkastelemme visuaalisesti maadoitettujen ja vain tekstiä sisältävien mallien käyttäytymistä ja löydämme systemaattisia eroavaisuuksia ihmisen arvioinneista silloinkin, kun mallin suorituskyky on korkea. Tämän eron selittämiseksi tunnistamme kaksi tutkittujen aineistojen ja mallien tekemää olettamusta ja epämääräisyyden filosofian pohjalta eristämme tapaukset, joissa ne eivät pidä paikkaansa.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bn>যদিও বিশাল পর্যায়ে প্রদর্শনের মূল্যবান দৃষ্টিভঙ্গি তৈরি করতে পারে, তাদের রাজত্বের মানে আরো জটিল এবং নির্ধারিত ভাষার ব্যাপার, যেমন অসস্তা দৃশ্যমান ভিত্তিক এবং শুধুমাত্র টেক্সট মডেলের আচরণ পরীক্ষা করি, মানুষের বিচার থেকে সিস্টেমিক বিভিন্ন পার্থক্য খুঁজে পাওয়া যাচ্ছে, এমনকি যদি মডেলের সারাটিক এই বৈষম্য ব্যাখ্যা করতে সাহায্য করার জন্য আমরা দুটি ধারণা চিহ্নিত করি যা ডাটাসেট এবং মডেল পরীক্ষা করেছে এবং পরীক্ষা করা হয়েছে দুটি ধারণা এবং নির্</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_sk>Medtem ko lahko skupne meritve učinkovitosti ustvarijo dragocene vpoglede v velikem obsegu, njihova prevladujoča vpliva pomeni, da je mogoče spregledati bolj kompleksne in niansirane jezikovne pojave, kot je nejasnost. Z osredotočanjem na nejasne izraze (npr. sončne, oblačne, mlade itd.) preverjamo vedenje vizualno ozemljenih in samo besedilnih modelov ter ugotavljamo sistematične razlike od človeških presoj, tudi če je splošna uspešnost modela visoka. V pomoč pri pojasnitvi te neskladnosti opredelimo dve predpostavki, ki sta jih naredili preučeni nabori podatkov in modeli, ter izoliramo primere, v katerih se ne držita.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_jv>Genjer-genjer esuk karo akeh podho metika iso nggawe barang langkung diolah, kuwi supoyo iso nggawe barang langkung sampeyan karo akeh pakan bakal dumadhi. Ngawe Perintah-Ngerawat sing klêngé awak (adil. sun, nik uwis, itéh-itéh) kéné nyong nyong awak dhéwé éntuk sistem anyar tentang karo model sing nguasai gambaran lan alam sing bakal terus maripé, kita ngubah perusahaan langgar sampeyan winih dadi susahé uwong sing katêpakan uwong. Mbok ndhèwèké wong kejahané iki, awake awake dhéwé luwih-luwih irumbane iki bakal nik sampek dataset lan model sing bisa nyoteré awak dhéwé, nambah-nambah karo dipilesofi sakjane sing ora bakal nggawe.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>A lokacin da metrici za'a iya ƙara gannai masu kima, sai domindomin su yana da muhimmin abu masu kamfata da da ke nufi, kamar misali da ɓanganci, za'a ƙyale. Yana da ƙayyade masu daidaita (misãlan Sun, girgije, ƙarami, etc.) za'a dũba game da shiryoyin misalin da aka baka na gane da shi kawai, kuma munã gane gaura masu iya ƙayyade masu tsari daga hukuncin mutãne, kõ dã sami mai motsi na sami-motel ya yi girma. To, dõmin ya bayyana wannan gaɓanci, za mu gane zato biyu wanda aka sami zaɓaniya da misãlai da aka jarraba su, kuma, ana shiryar da filosofi na yin ɓarna, sai ka rara masu sakan da ba su tsare su ba.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>While aggregate performance metrics can generate valuable insights at a large scale, their dominance means more complex and nuanced language phenomena, such as vagueness, may be overlooked. འུ་ཅག་གིས་མཐོང་བའི་སྣང་ཚུལ་མེ་མཐུན་པ་དང་། དཔེར་ན། ཉེ་བའི་ལྟ་བུའི་ནང་གི་བྱ་སྟངས་ལ་བལྟས་དཔྱད་ཡོད་པ་དང་། མི་འདྲ་བའི་རྣམ་པ་ལ་བལྟས་བཀོད་པའི་མི་རྣམ་པ་ཚོགས་ འུ་ཅག་གི་ཁྱད་པར་འདི་འགྲེལ་བཤད་པར་ལེན་བྱེད་པར་ང་ཚོས་གནད་སྡུད་ཚན་དང་། མིག་དཔྱད་རྣམས་ལ་བལྟས་བྱས་པའི་སྐྱེས་ཚུལ་གཉིས་རྟོགས་ཐུ</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_he>בעוד מטריות ביצועים מוצגות יכולות ליצור תובנות ערכות בקנה מידה גדולה, השליטה שלהם אומרת תופעות שפה מורכבות יותר ונואנציות, כמו העוורות, עלולות להתעלם. מתמקדים במונחים בלתי ברורים (למשל שמש, ענן, צעיר, וכו"כ) אנחנו בודקים את ההתנהגות של דוגמנים מקורקעים מבחינה ראייתית ורק טקסט, למצוא ההבדלות מערכתית משפטים אנושיים אפילו כשההופעה הכללית של דוגמנים גבוהה. To help explain this disparity, we identify two assumptions made by the datasets and models examined and, guided by the philosophy of vagueness, isolate cases where they do not hold.</abstract_he>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>