<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.sigtyp">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-05-24">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Computational Typology and Multilingual NLP</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Vylomova</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Elizabeth</first><last>Salesky</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sabrina</first><last>Mielke</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Gabriella</first><last>Lapesa</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ritesh</first><last>Kumar</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Harald</first><last>Hammarström</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ivan</first><last>Vulić</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Anna</first><last>Korhonen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Roi</first><last>Reichart</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Edoardo Maria</first><last>Ponti</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Ryan</first><last>Cotterell</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="9497be23">2021.sigtyp-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="52a84d6b">2021.sigtyp-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>sigtyp-2021-typology</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>OTEANN : Estimating the Transparency of Orthographies with an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network">Artificial Neural Network</a><fixed-case>OTEANN</fixed-case>: Estimating the Transparency of Orthographies with an Artificial Neural Network</title>
      <author><first>Xavier</first><last>Marjou</last></author>
      <pages>1–9</pages>
      <abstract>To transcribe <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spoken_language">spoken language</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writing">written medium</a>, most <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alphabet">alphabets</a> enable an unambiguous sound-to-letter rule. However, some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writing_system">writing systems</a> have distanced themselves from this simple concept and little work exists in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing (NLP)</a> on measuring such distance. In this study, we use an Artificial Neural Network (ANN) model to evaluate the transparency between written words and their pronunciation, hence its name Orthographic Transparency Estimation with an ANN (OTEANN). Based on datasets derived from Wikimedia dictionaries, we trained and tested this model to score the percentage of false predictions in phoneme-to-grapheme and grapheme-to-phoneme translation tasks. The scores obtained on 17 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthography">orthographies</a> were in line with the estimations of other studies. Interestingly, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_model">model</a> also provided insight into typical mistakes made by learners who only consider the phonemic rule in reading and writing.</abstract>
      <url hash="e6fba9f1">2021.sigtyp-1.1</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigtyp-1.1</doi>
      <bibkey>marjou-2021-oteann</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/marxav/oteann3" additional="true">marxav/oteann3</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/oteannv3">OTEANNv3</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Improving Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis via Conditional Language Adversarial Nets</title>
      <author><first>Hemanth</first><last>Kandula</last></author>
      <author><first>Bonan</first><last>Min</last></author>
      <pages>32–37</pages>
      <abstract>Sentiment analysis has come a long way for high-resource languages due to the availability of large annotated corpora. However, it still suffers from lack of training data for low-resource languages. To tackle this problem, we propose Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), an end-to-end neural architecture for cross-lingual sentiment analysis without cross-lingual supervision. CLAN differs from prior work in that it allows the adversarial training to be conditioned on both learned features and the sentiment prediction, to increase discriminativity for learned representation in the cross-lingual setting. Experimental results demonstrate that CLAN outperforms previous methods on the multilingual multi-domain Amazon review dataset. Our source code is released at https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract>
      <url hash="f666fcb2">2021.sigtyp-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigtyp-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>kandula-min-2021-improving</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan" additional="false">hemanthkandula/clan</pwccode>
    <title_ar>تحسين تحليل المشاعر عبر اللغات عبر شبكات الخصومة اللغوية الشرطية</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Melhorando a Análise de Sentimentos entre Idiomas por meio de Redes Adversariais de Linguagem Condicional</title_pt>
      <title_es>Mejorando el análisis de sentimientos en varios idiomas a través de redes adversarias de lenguaje condicional</title_es>
      <title_ja>条件付き言語対立ネットを介したクロスリンガル感情分析の改善</title_ja>
      <title_zh>因言抗网络改入语言情析</title_zh>
      <title_hi>सशर्त भाषा प्रतिकूल जाल के माध्यम से क्रॉस-लिंगुअल भावना विश्लेषण में सुधार</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Anailís Trastheangach Mothúchán a Fheabhsú trí Líonta Sáraimh Teanga Coinníollacha</title_ga>
      <title_hu>A nyelvközi érzelmek elemzésének javítása feltételes nyelvi reklámhálózatokkal</title_hu>
      <title_el>Βελτίωση της γλωσσικής ανάλυσης συναισθημάτων μέσω των δικτύων αντίθεσης υπό όρους γλώσσας</title_el>
      <title_kk>Шартты тіл көтерілік желілер арқылы көтерілікті сезімді анализдерді жақсарту</title_kk>
      <title_it>Migliorare l'analisi dei sentimenti cross-lingual tramite reti pubblicitarie di linguaggio condizionato</title_it>
      <title_lt>Gerinti tarpkalbinę jautrumo analizę naudojant sąlyginius prieštaringus kalbų tinklus</title_lt>
      <title_mk>Подобрување на анализата на чувствата преку условни јазици</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Menembak Analisi Sensan Selata-Bahasa melalui Rangkaian Adversarial Bahasa Bersyarat</title_ms>
      <title_ka>კროსლიგუალური სენტიმენტის ანალიზაციის გასაკეთება კონდიციონალური ენის კონდერსარიალური ქსელებით</title_ka>
      <title_mn>Үндсэн хэл дамжуулагчдын шинжилгээг сайжруулах</title_mn>
      <title_ml>ക്രോസ്- ലിങ്ഗല്‍ സെന്റിമെന്റ് അന്വേഷണം മുന്‍കൂട്ടുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_no>Å forbetra krysslingssentralanalyse ved hjelp av vilkårleg språk</title_no>
      <title_mt>Titjib fl-Analiżi tas-Sentiment Translingwali permezz ta’ Netwerks Adversarji tal-Lingwa Kundizzjonali</title_mt>
      <title_pl>Poprawa analizy sentymentów między językami za pomocą warunkowych sieci przeciwników językowych</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Îmbunătățirea analizei sentimentelor translingvistice prin intermediul rețelelor adversare condiționale de limbaj</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Poboljšanje križanske sentimentalne analize kroz uvjetne jezičke konservacijske mreže</title_sr>
      <title_si>සාමාන්තික භාෂාව ප්‍රවේශනය සඳහා ක්‍රොස් ලින්ගුවාල් සංවේශනය විශ්ලේෂණය විස්තර කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Horumarinta baaritaanka fasaxa luqada</title_so>
      <title_ur>Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis through Conditional Language Adversarial Nets</title_ur>
      <title_sv>Förbättra tvärspråklig känsloanalys via villkorliga språkreklamnätverk</title_sv>
      <title_ta>கிருஸ்- Lingual Sentiment Analysis by Conditional Language Adversarial Network</title_ta>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Tăng khả năng phân tích tâm lý chữ thập</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Подобряване на междулингвистичния анализ на чувствата чрез условни езикови противоречиви мрежи</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Poboljšanje analize međujezičkih sentimenta putem uvjetnih proizvodnjih mreža</title_hr>
      <title_da>Forbedring af tværsproget følelsesanalyse via betingede sprogadvarselsnetværk</title_da>
      <title_nl>Verbetering van Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis via Conditional Language Adversarial Nets</title_nl>
      <title_de>Verbesserung der sprachübergreifenden Sentimentanalyse über Adversarial Networks in Conditional Language</title_de>
      <title_ko>조건 언어 대항망을 통해 다중 언어 감정 분석을 개선하다</title_ko>
      <title_fa>توسط شبکه‌های پیشرفت‌کننده‌ی زبان‌های متوسط زبان‌</title_fa>
      <title_id>Menembak Analisi Sentimen Selata-Lingua melalui jaringan Adversarial Bahasa Kondisional</title_id>
      <title_sw>Uchambuzi wa Seneti ya Kusini-Lingua kupitia Mtandao wa Utawala wa Lugha</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Çot-Dilli Sentiment Analizi Durumsal Diller (Conditional Language Adversarial Nets)</title_tr>
      <title_af>Verbeter Kruis- Linguaal Sentiment Analisie deur betingelike Taal Rekursariale Netwerke</title_af>
      <title_sq>Duke përmirësuar analizën e ndjenjave ndërgjuhësore nëpërmjet rrjeteve kundërshtare të gjuhës me kusht</title_sq>
      <title_am>አቀማመጥ</title_am>
      <title_hy>Improving Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis via Conditional Language Adversarial Nets</title_hy>
      <title_bn>ক্রস-লিঙ্গুয়াল সেন্টাইমেন্ট বিশ্লেষণের মাধ্যমে সংস্থায়িত ভাষা প্রধান নেটওয়ার্কের মাধ্যমে</title_bn>
      <title_az>İşkil Dili İşkil Ağları vasitəsilə Xərc-Dil Sentiment Analizi</title_az>
      <title_ca>millorar l'anàlisi de sentiments translingües a través de xarxes adversaries de llenguatge condicional</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Zlepšení analýzy mezijazyčných sentimentů pomocí nepříznivých sítí podmíněného jazyka</title_cs>
      <title_bs>Poboljšanje krstoLingualne sentimentne analize putem uvjetnih naprednih mreža jezika</title_bs>
      <title_et>Keeleülese tunnete analüüsi parandamine tingimuslike keelevõrkude abil</title_et>
      <title_fi>Kieltenvälisen tunneanalyysin parantaminen ehdollisten kielten adversariaaliverkkojen avulla</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Progress</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Izboljšanje medjezikovne analize čustev s pogojnimi jezikovnimi neželenimi mrežami</title_sk>
      <title_ha>Analyze na fassarar-Linguin</title_ha>
      <title_he>שיפור ניתוח רגשות בין שפתיים דרך רשתות נגד שפת תנאי</title_he>
      <title_bo>Improving Cross-Lingual Sentiment Analysis via Conditional Language Adversarial Nets</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>لقد قطع تحليل المشاعر شوطًا طويلاً بالنسبة للغات عالية الموارد نظرًا لتوافر مجموعة كبيرة من التعليقات التوضيحية. ومع ذلك ، لا يزال يعاني من نقص بيانات التدريب للغات منخفضة الموارد. لمعالجة هذه المشكلة ، نقترح شبكة الخصومة اللغوية الشرطية (CLAN) ، وهي بنية عصبية شاملة لتحليل المشاعر عبر اللغات دون إشراف عبر اللغات. تختلف CLAN عن العمل السابق من حيث أنها تسمح بتكييف التدريب العدائي على كل من الميزات المكتسبة والتنبؤ بالمشاعر ، لزيادة التمييز للتمثيل الذي تم تعلمه في الإعداد متعدد اللغات. توضح النتائج التجريبية أن CLAN تتفوق في الأداء على الأساليب السابقة في مجموعة بيانات مراجعة Amazon متعددة اللغات. تم تحرير كود المصدر الخاص بنا على https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>A análise de sentimento percorreu um longo caminho para linguagens de alto recurso devido à disponibilidade de grandes corpora anotados. No entanto, ainda sofre com a falta de dados de treinamento para linguagens de poucos recursos. Para resolver esse problema, propomos a Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), uma arquitetura neural de ponta a ponta para análise de sentimentos em vários idiomas sem supervisão em vários idiomas. O CLAN difere do trabalho anterior, pois permite que o treinamento do adversário seja condicionado tanto aos recursos aprendidos quanto à previsão de sentimentos, para aumentar a discriminação da representação aprendida no ambiente multilíngue. Os resultados experimentais demonstram que o CLAN supera os métodos anteriores no conjunto de dados multilíngue de vários domínios da Amazon. Nosso código fonte está disponível em https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>El análisis de sentimientos ha recorrido un largo camino para los lenguajes de gran cantidad de recursos debido a la disponibilidad de grandes corpus anotados. Sin embargo, todavía adolece de falta de datos de capacitación para idiomas de bajos recursos. Para abordar este problema, proponemos Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), una arquitectura neuronal de extremo a extremo para el análisis de sentimientos multilingües sin supervisión multilingüe. CLAN se diferencia del trabajo anterior en que permite que el entrenamiento contradictorio esté condicionado tanto a las características aprendidas como a la predicción de sentimientos, para aumentar la discriminatividad de la representación aprendida en el entorno multilingüe. Los resultados experimentales demuestran que CLAN supera a los métodos anteriores en el conjunto de datos de revisión multilingüe multidominio de Amazon. Nuestro código fuente está publicado en https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>センチメント分析は、大規模な注釈付きコーパスが利用可能なため、高リソース言語にとって長い道のりを歩んできました。しかし、それでもなお、低資源言語のトレーニングデータの不足に悩まされている。この問題に取り組むために、私たちは、クロスリンガル監視なしでクロスリンガル感情分析を行うためのエンドツーエンドのニューラルアーキテクチャである条件付き言語対抗ネットワーク（ CLAN ）を提案します。クランは、対抗訓練が学習された機能と感情予測の両方に条件付けられ、クロスリンガルの場面で学習された表現に対する差別性を高めることを可能にするという点で、以前の仕事とは異なる。実験結果は、クランが多言語のマルチドメインAmazonレビューデータセットの以前の方法よりも優れていることを示しています。ソースコードはhttps://github.com/hemanthkandula/clanで公開されています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>情析于高资言已过长道,盖有大注语料库也。 然犹乏低资源语之数。 为此者,言而抗网络(CLAN),端到端之神经架构也,以跨言情析,而无跨言督也。 CLAN与前事异者,许对抗性训练而以习为资,以增跨语中习得表征之判。 实验结果表明,CLAN 于多言多域 Amazon 论数集上优于前法。 吾源代码发于 https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan 。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>भावना विश्लेषण बड़े एनोटेट कॉर्पोरेट की उपलब्धता के कारण उच्च संसाधन भाषाओं के लिए एक लंबा रास्ता तय किया है। हालांकि, यह अभी भी कम संसाधन वाली भाषाओं के लिए प्रशिक्षण डेटा की कमी से ग्रस्त है। इस समस्या से निपटने के लिए, हम सशर्त भाषा प्रतिकूल नेटवर्क (CLAN) का प्रस्ताव करते हैं, जो क्रॉस-भाषी पर्यवेक्षण के बिना क्रॉस-लिंगुअल भावना विश्लेषण के लिए एक एंड-टू-एंड तंत्रिका वास्तुकला है। CLAN पहले के काम से अलग है कि यह प्रतिकूल प्रशिक्षण को सीखा सुविधाओं और भावना की भविष्यवाणी दोनों पर वातानुकूलित करने की अनुमति देता है, क्रॉस-लिंगुअल सेटिंग में सीखा प्रतिनिधित्व के लिए भेदभाव को बढ़ाने के लिए। प्रयोगात्मक परिणामों से पता चलता है कि CLAN बहुभाषी बहु-डोमेन अमेज़ॅन समीक्षा डेटासेट पर पिछले तरीकों से बेहतर प्रदर्शन करता है। हमारा स्रोत कोड https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan पर जारी किया जाता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Tá anailís meoin tagtha chun cinn go mór do theangacha ard-acmhainne mar gheall ar an bhfáil ar mhórchorpóra anótáilte. Mar sin féin, tá sé fós thíos le heaspa sonraí oiliúna do theangacha íseal-acmhainne. Chun dul i ngleic leis an bhfadhb seo, molaimid Coinníollach Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), ailtireacht néarúil ceann go ceann le haghaidh anailíse tras-teangacha meon gan maoirseacht thrastheangach. Tá difríocht idir CLAN agus obair a rinneadh roimhe seo sa mhéid is go gceadaíonn sé an oiliúint sháraíochta a riocht ar ghnéithe foghlamtha agus ar thuar na meon, chun an t-idirdhealú a mhéadú maidir le hionadaíocht fhoghlamtha sa suíomh trasteangach. Léiríonn torthaí turgnamhacha go sáraíonn CLAN modhanna roimhe seo ar thacar sonraí athbhreithnithe il-fearainn ilteangach Amazon. Eisítear ár gcód foinse ag https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Η ανάλυση συναισθημάτων έχει κάνει μεγάλο δρόμο για γλώσσες υψηλής περιεκτικότητας λόγω της διαθεσιμότητας μεγάλων σχολιασμένων σωμάτων. Ωστόσο, εξακολουθεί να πάσχει από έλλειψη δεδομένων κατάρτισης για γλώσσες χαμηλής περιεκτικότητας σε πόρους. Για να αντιμετωπιστεί αυτό το πρόβλημα, προτείνουμε ένα Δίκτυο Αντιθετικής Γλώσσας (CLAN), μια νευρωνική αρχιτεκτονική για ανάλυση διγλωσσών συναισθημάτων χωρίς διεπαγγελματική εποπτεία. Το CLAN διαφέρει από την προηγούμενη εργασία στο ότι επιτρέπει στην αντίπαλη εκπαίδευση να εξαρτάται τόσο από τα μαθημένα χαρακτηριστικά όσο και από την πρόβλεψη συναισθημάτων, ώστε να αυξηθεί η διακριτικότητα για την μαθημένη αναπαράσταση στο γλωσσικό περιβάλλον. Τα πειραματικά αποτελέσματα καταδεικνύουν ότι το CLAN ξεπερνά τις προηγούμενες μεθόδους στο πολύγλωσσο σύνολο δεδομένων αναθεώρησης πολλών τομέων. Ο πηγαίος μας κώδικας κυκλοφορεί στο https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_ka>სისტემისტის ანალიზაცია ძალიან ძალიან გზა, რომელიც უფრო მეტი რესურსისტის ენაზებისთვის დიდი ანალიზაციული კოპორაციის მისამართლად მოხდა. მაგრამ მას უკვე უფრო მცირე რესურსის ენათებისთვის მონაცემები არსებობს. ამ პრობლემას გადაწყვეტისთვის, ჩვენ შეგვეძლია კონდიციონალური ენის კონპერსაციალური ქსელი (CLAN), ნეიროლური აქტიქტიქტურა კრისი ენგუმენტის ანალიზაციისთვის, კრისი ენგ CLAN განსხვავებულია პირველი სამუშაოდან, რომელიც განსხვავებულია განსხვავებული განსხვავება განსხვავებულ განსხვავებას და განსხვავებულ განსხვავებას, რომ განსხვავებული განსხვავებას კრისი ენგუფიკაციის განსხვ ექსპერიმენტიური შედეგები გამოჩვენებენ, რომ CLAN წინახალი მეტოვების მრავალენგური მრავალენგური მონაცემების Amazon განაცემების მონაცემების შესახებ ჩვენი წიგნის კოდი გახსნა https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Az érzelmek elemzése hosszú utat tett meg a nagy erőforrásokkal rendelkező nyelvek számára a nagy jegyzetelt korpuszok elérhetősége miatt. Azonban továbbra is hiányzik az alacsony erőforrású nyelvekre vonatkozó képzési adatok. Ennek a problémának a megoldása érdekében javasoljuk a Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), egy end-to-end neurális architektúrát, amely többnyelvű felügyelet nélküli, többnyelvű érzelmi elemzéshez szükséges. A CLAN különbözik a korábbi munkától abban, hogy lehetővé teszi, hogy az ellenséges képzés mind a tanult tulajdonságok, mind az érzelmek előrejelzése függvényében legyen, hogy növelje a diszkriminációt a tanult reprezentáció iránt a nyelvek között. A kísérleti eredmények azt mutatják, hogy a CLAN felülmúlja a korábbi módszereket a többnyelvű, több tartományból álló Amazon vizsgálati adatkészleten. A forráskódunk a https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_kk>Сентименттің анализ үлкен белгіленген корпораға жеткізілген үлкен ресурс тілдерінің жоғары жолы болды. Бірақ ол әлі жеткілікті ресурс тілдерінің оқыту деректері жоқ. Бұл мәселеге шешу үшін, біз шарттарлық тіл конверсариялық желі (CLAN), тілдерді бірнеше тілдерді бақылау архитектурасы үшін бірнеше тілдерді шешу үшін невралдық архитектурасын ұсынамыз. КЛАН алдыңғы жұмыс істегеннен айырмашылық, бұл қарсы оқытуға мүмкіндік беретін қарсы оқытуға мүмкіндік береді, бірнеше тілді ортасында оқыту үшін дискриминациялықты көтеру үшін. Эксперименталдық нәтижелер КЛАН көп тілдік көп- домендік Amazon қарау деректер жиынында алдыңғы әдістерді орындайды деп көрсетеді. Біздің көзіміздің кодымыз https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_lt>Sentimento analizė buvo labai didelė didelių išteklių kalbų atžvilgiu dėl didelių anotuotų korprų prieinamumo. Tačiau vis dar trūksta duomenų apie mažai išteklių turinčių kalbų mokymą. Siekiant išspręsti šią problem ą, siūlome „sąlyginio kalbos prieštaringo tinklo“ (CLAN), nuo vienos iki kitos neuralinės architektūros, skirtos tarpkalbinei jautrumo analizei be tarpkalbinės priežiūros. CLAN skiriasi nuo ankstesnio darbo, nes jis leidžia priešingam mokymui priklausyti nuo įgytų savybių ir jausmų prognozės, kad būtų padidintas diskriminavimas mokomo atstovavimo tarpkalbinėje aplinkoje. Eksperimentiniai rezultatai rodo, kad CLAN atitinka ankstesnius daugiakalbių Amazon peržiūros duomenų rinkinio metodus. Mūsų šaltinio kodas skelbiamas https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Анализата на чувствата дошла долг пат за јазиците со високи ресурси поради достапноста на големи анотирани корпора. Сепак, таа сé уште страда од недостаток на податоци за обука за јазици со ниски ресурси. За да го решиме овој проблем, предлагаме Кондиционална Јазична Авенсериска мрежа (КЛАН), нервна архитектура од крај до крај за прекујазична анализа на сентиментите без прекујазичен надзор. КЛАН се разликува од претходната работа со оглед на тоа што овозможува противната обука да биде условена на научени карактеристики и предвидување на чувствата, за зголемување на дискриминативноста за наученото претставување во прекујазичното околинување. Експерименталните резултати покажуваат дека КЛАН ги надминува претходните методи на множјазичниот множјазичен компјутер на податоци за преглед на Амазон. Нашиот изворен код е објавен на https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Analisis perasaan telah datang jauh untuk bahasa sumber-tinggi disebabkan kemampuan korpra besar yang dicatat. Namun, ia masih menderita oleh kekurangan data latihan untuk bahasa sumber rendah. To tackle this problem, we propose Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), an end-to-end neural architecture for cross-lingual sentiment analysis without cross-lingual supervision.  CLAN berbeza dari kerja sebelumnya kerana ia memungkinkan latihan lawan untuk digantung pada kedua-dua ciri belajar dan ramalan perasaan, untuk meningkatkan diskriminasi untuk mewakili belajar dalam tetapan saling bahasa. Keputusan percubaan menunjukkan bahawa CLAN melampaui kaedah terdahulu pada set data ulasan Amazon berbilang-domain berbilang bahasa. Kod sumber kita dibebaskan di https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>L-analiżi tas-sensazzjoni waslet fit-tul għal-lingwi b’riżorsi għoljin minħabba d-disponibbiltà ta’ korpora annotata kbira. Madankollu, għadha tbati minn nuqqas ta’ dejta ta’ taħriġ għal lingwi b’riżorsi baxxi. Biex nindirizzaw din il-problema, nipproponu Netwerk Kundizzjonali tal-Lingwi Adversarji (CLAN), arkitettura newrali minn tarf sa tarf għall-analiżi tas-sentimenti translingwistiċi mingħajr superviżjoni translingwistika. CLAN huwa differenti minn xogħol preċedenti billi jippermetti li t-taħriġ avversarju jkun ikkondizzjonat kemm fuq il-karatteristiċi mitgħallma kif ukoll fuq it-tbassir tas-sensazzjoni, biex tiżdied id-diskriminazzjoni għar-rappreżentanza mitgħallma fl-ambjent translingwistiku. Ir-riżultati esperimentali juru li CLAN iwettaq metodi preċedenti fuq is-sett ta’ dejta multilingwi ta’ reviżjoni Amazon b’diversi dominji. Il-kodiċi tas-sors tagħna jiġi rilaxxat fuq https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_no>Sentimentanalysen har kommet ein lang måte for høg ressursspråk på grunn av tilgjengeleg stor merknad korpora. Det har imidlertid fremdeles mangling av treningsdata for låg ressursspråk. For å løse denne problemen, foreslår vi vilkårleg språk-konserversarialnettverk (CLAN), ein neuralarkitektur for krysspråk-sentimentanalyse utan krysspråk-oversikt. CLAN er forskjellig frå førre arbeid i at den tillater at den adversariale treninga skal vera kondicionalt på både lærte funksjonar og følelsesforhåndsvising, for å økja diskriminativ for lærte representasjon i krysspråk innstillinga. Eksperimentale resultat viser at CLAN utfører førre metodar på multilingual multidomene Amazon review dataset. Kjeldekode vårt er sletta på https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_mn>Хэрвээ сэтгэл санааны шинжилгээ маш олон нийтлэг хэлнүүдийн хувьд маш урт зам ирсэн бөгөөд маш их сэтгэл хангалттай корпора байдаг. Гэвч энэ нь бага боловсролын хэл дээр суралцах өгөгдлийн алдаагүй байдаг. Энэ асуудлыг зогсоохын тулд бид шалтгаан хэл дамжуулагчийн сүлжээ (CLAN), хэл дамжуулагчгүй, олон хэл дамжуулагчдын шинжилгээний сэтгэл хөдлөлийн мэдрэмжтэй шинжилгээний сэтгэл хөдлөл, мэдрэмжтэй байгуул КЛАН өмнөх ажлын хоорондоо ялгаатай учраас тэдний эсрэг сургалтыг суралцах болон мэдрэмжтэй таамаглах боломжтой болгодог, олон хэл хэлний хэлбэрээр суралцаж суралцаж суралцах зан чанарын ялгааг нэмэгдүүлэх болом Үүний туршилтын үр дүнд CLAN олон хэл хэлний олон дотор Амазон шинжилгээний өгөгдлийн санд өмнө арга зам гаргадаг гэдгийг харуулж байна. Бидний эх үүсвэрийн код https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_it>L'analisi dei sentimenti ha fatto molta strada per i linguaggi ad alto contenuto di risorse grazie alla disponibilità di grandi corpora annotati. Tuttavia, soffre ancora della mancanza di dati di formazione per le lingue a basso contenuto di risorse. Per affrontare questo problema, proponiamo Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), un'architettura neurale end-to-end per l'analisi cross-lingual sentiment senza supervisione cross-lingual. CLAN differisce dal lavoro precedente in quanto permette alla formazione avversaria di essere condizionata sia dalle caratteristiche apprese che dalla previsione sentimentale, per aumentare la discriminazione per la rappresentazione appresa nell'ambiente cross-lingual. I risultati sperimentali dimostrano che CLAN supera i metodi precedenti sul set di dati multidominio Amazon multilingue. Il nostro codice sorgente è rilasciato a https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ml>വളരെ വിഭവങ്ങളുടെ ഭാഷകള്‍ക്കുള്ള സെന്റിമെന്റ് അന്വേഷണം വളരെ ദൂരം വന്നിരിക്കുന്നു. എന്നാലും കുറഞ്ഞ വിഭവങ്ങളുടെ ഭാഷകള്‍ക്കുള്ള പരിശീലനത്തിന്റെ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ ഇല്ലാത്തതില്‍ ഇത് ഇപ്പോഴും അന ഈ പ്രശ്നത്തെ പരിചയപ്പെടുത്താന്‍, നിശ്ചയമായ ഭാഷ അഡ്രസറിയല്‍ നെറ്റ്വര്‍ക്ക്(CLAN), ക്രിസ്ലാങ്ഗല്‍ നിരീക്ഷണമില്ലാത്ത ഒരു അവസാനത്തേക്ക് അവസാനിക് സിലാന്‍ മുമ്പ് ജോലിയില്‍ നിന്നും വ്യത്യസ്തമായിരിക്കുന്നു. അതിനാല്‍ വിരോധമായ പരിശീലനം പഠിച്ചിരിക്കുന്ന വിഭാഗങ്ങള്‍ക്കും പ്രവചനങ്ങള്‍ക്കും നിയ പരീക്ഷിക്കുന്ന ഫലങ്ങള്‍ കാണിച്ചുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുന്നു മുന്‍പ് സിലാന്‍ മാത്രം രീതികള്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നത് പല ഭാ നമ്മുടെ ഉറവിട കോഡ് വിട്ടുപോകുന്നു https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_sr>Sentimentna analiza je došla na dug naèin za jezike visokih resursa zbog raspoloženja velike annotirane korpore. Međutim, još uvijek pati od nedostatka podataka o obuci za jezike niskih resursa. Da bi se riješili ovog problema, predlažemo uslovnu konverzacionalnu mrežu jezika (CLAN), neuralnu arhitekturu za analizu preko jezika bez preko jezika nadzora. CLAN se razlikuje od prethodnog rada u tome što omogućava da se adversarna obuka uvodi na naučene karakteristike i predviđanje sentimenta, da povećava diskriminaciju za naučenu predstavu na međujezičkom postavljanju. Eksperimentalni rezultati pokazuju da CLAN iznosi prethodne metode na multijezičkim multidomeničkim podacima Amazon pregledanja. Naš izvorni kod je otpušten u https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_pl>Analiza sentymentów przeszła długą drogę dla języków o wysokich zasobach ze względu na dostępność dużych adnotacji korpusów. Jednak nadal cierpi na brak danych szkoleniowych dotyczących języków o niskich zasobach. Aby rozwiązać ten problem, proponujemy Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), kompleksową architekturę neuronową umożliwiającą analizę sentymentów między językami bez nadzoru między językami. CLAN różni się od wcześniejszych prac tym, że umożliwia uwarunkowanie treningu przeciwnikowego zarówno nauczonych cech, jak i predykcji sentymentów, w celu zwiększenia dyskryminacyjności dla nauczonej reprezentacji w otoczeniu wielojęzycznym. Wyniki eksperymentów pokazują, że CLAN przewyższa poprzednie metody w wielojęzycznym wieloodomenowym zestawie danych przeglądów Amazon. Nasz kod źródłowy jest publikowany pod adresem: https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_so>Shahaadada wakhtiga la xiriiray waxay u timid luuqado aad u dheer, sababtoo ah helitaanka shirkad aad u weyn. Si kastaba ha ahaatee waxay weli ugu dhibaataysaa baahida waxbarashada luqadaha hoose ee luqada. Si aan u tacliino dhibaatadan, waxaan u soo jeedaynaa shabakadda asalka ah (CLAN), dhismaha neurada ee dhammaadka ugu dambeeya, baaritaanka fikrada luuqadaha kala duwan ee aan ilaalinaynin luuqadaha kala duwan. CLAN wuxuu ka duwan yahay shaqada hore, taas oo u ogolaan karaa in waxbarashada cadaawayaasha ah lagu sharciyo tababarka bartay iyo sii sheegidda fikrada, si uu u kordhiyo takoorida aqoonta lagu baro wakiilka afka kala duwan. Imtixaanka waxaa ka muuqda in CLAN uu sameeyo qaabab hore oo ku saabsan baaritaanka macluumaadka kala duduwan ee Amazon. Qorada asalkayaga waxaa lagu furay https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_ro>Analiza sentimentelor a parcurs un drum lung pentru limbajele cu resurse ridicate datorită disponibilității corporelor adnotate mari. Cu toate acestea, acesta suferă încă din cauza lipsei datelor de formare pentru limbile cu resurse reduse. Pentru a aborda această problemă, propunem Rețeaua Adversarială Condiționată a Limbajului (CLAN), o arhitectură neurală end-to-end pentru analiza sentimentelor interlingvistice fără supraveghere interlingvă. CLAN diferă de munca anterioară prin faptul că permite antrenamentului adversar să fie condiționat atât de trăsăturile învățate, cât și de predicția sentimentului, pentru a crește discriminarea pentru reprezentarea învățată în cadrul interlingvistic. Rezultatele experimentale demonstrează că CLAN depășește metodele anterioare în setul de date multilingv de revizuire Amazon multidomeniu. Codul nostru sursă este lansat la https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sv>Känsleanalys har kommit en lång väg för högresursspråk på grund av tillgängligheten av stora kommenterade korpora. Den lider dock fortfarande av brist på utbildningsdata för språk med låg resurs. För att ta itu med detta problem föreslår vi Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), en end-to-end neural arkitektur för tvärspråklig sentimental analys utan tvärspråklig övervakning. CLAN skiljer sig från tidigare arbete genom att det gör det möjligt för motståndarens träning att betyda både lärda egenskaper och sentimentprediktion, för att öka diskrimineringen för lärd representation i den tvärspråkiga miljön. Experimentella resultat visar att CLAN överträffar tidigare metoder på flerspråkiga Amazon-granskningsdatauppsättningar med flera domäner. Vår källkod släpps på https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>විශේෂ විශ්ලේෂණයක් ලොකු කොර්පෝරා විශ්වාස කරලා තියෙන්නේ විශේෂ භාෂාවට ලොකු මාර්ගයක් ඇත ඒත්, ඒක තාමත් අඩුම සම්බන්ධ භාෂාවට තොරතුරු අවස්ථාවක් නෑ. මේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් හරිගන්න, අපි සාමාන්තික භාෂාව ප්‍රශ්නයක් ජාලය (CLAN) ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා, ප්‍රශ්නයක් භාෂාව ප්‍රශ්නයක් නැත CLAN වෙනස් කලින් වැඩේ ඉදිරියට වෙනස් කරනවා කියලා, ඒකෙන් විරෝධ විශ්වාස කරනවා විරෝධ විශ්වාස කරනවා කියලා දැන් ඉගෙන ගත්ත අවශ්‍යා පරීක්ෂණාත්මක ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට CLAN ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක විදිහට ප්‍ අපේ ප්‍රධාන කෝඩ් නිදහස් කරලා තියෙනවා https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ur>سنٹیمینٹ تحلیل بہت زیادہ مضبوط کورپورا کے موجود ہونے کے باعث بہت سی سراسر زبانوں کے لئے ایک دور طریقہ آچکا ہے. لیکن اسے بھی کم منبع زبانوں کے لئے آموزش دادہ کی کمی کی وجہ سے ہے۔ اس مسئلہ کا حل کرنے کے لئے، ہم نے Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN) کی پیشنهاد کرتا ہے، ایک مختلف زبان کے بغیر مختلف زبان نظارت کے لئے ایک نئورل معمار۔ CLAN پہلے کے کام سے مختلف ہے کہ یہ مخالف تعلیم کی اجازت دیتا ہے کہ دونوں تعلیم کی تعلیم اور احساسات کی پیش بینی پر قائم ہو جاتی ہے، اس کے لئے مخالف زبان کی تعلیم کی تعلیم کے لئے تقسیم کی زیادتی کرتا ہے۔ Experimental results demonstrate that CLAN performs previous methods on multilingual multi-domain Amazon review dataset. ہمارے سراسر کوڈ کو آزاد کیا گیا ہے https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_ta>அதிக மூலத்தின் மொழிகளுக்கான உணர்வு விளக்கம் பெரிய குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட நிறுவனத்தினால் நீண்ட வழி வந்துள்ளது. ஆனால் அது இன்னும் குறைந்த மூலத்திற்கு பயிற்சி தரவு இல்லாமல் பாதிக்கும். இந்த பிரச்சனையை நிர்வகிக்க, நாம் பரிந்துரைய மொழி மொழி மேம்பாட்டாளர் வலைப்பின்னல் (CLAN), முடிவு இறுதி முடிவு புதிய நிரல் கட்டுப்பாடு CLAN முன் வேலையில் இருந்து வேறுபாடு இருக்கிறது அது கற்றுக் கொண்ட பண்புகள் மற்றும் உணர்வு முன்னதாகவும் கற்றுக் கொண்டு இருந்த பயிற்சியை நிர்ணயிக்க Name எங்கள் மூல குறியீடு வெளியேற்றப்பட்டது https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_uz>@ info: whatsthis Lekin, bu juda kam manbanli tillar uchun taʼminlovchi maʼlumot yoʻq. Bu muammolani boshqarish uchun, biz Konstant tilning davlat tarmoqni (CLAN), o'sha oxirgi neyron arxituvchisi, har bir necha xil hissiyasiga aniqlash uchun o'zgartiraymiz. Name Experimental results demonstrate that CLAN outperforms previous methods on the multilingual multi-domain Amazon review dataset.  Bizning manba kodi https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Bản phân tích tình cảm đã đi một chặng đường dài cho những ngôn ngữ giàu có nhờ có các hạ sĩ quan có ghi chú lớn. Tuy nhiên, nó vẫn bị thiếu dữ liệu đào tạo về ngôn ngữ nghèo. Để giải quyết vấn đề này, chúng tôi đề nghị hệ thống thần kinh ngôn ngữ ngữ tiếp cận (Clank), một kiến trúc thần kinh kết thúc-tới-cuối cho phân tích cảm xúc xuyên ngôn ngữ mà không cần giám sát ngôn ngữ khác. Bên nguyên thì khác với các hoạt động trước, bởi vì nó cho phép huấn luyện đối thủ được điều chỉnh từ các tính năng học tập và dự đoán cảm xúc, để tăng sự phân biệt học hỏi trong môi trường ngôn ngữ khác nhau. Kết quả thử nghiệm chứng minh rằng CLAY vượt trội với các phương pháp trước đây trên bộ dữ liệu đa miền của Amazon. Mã nguồn của chúng tôi được phát hành tại https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Анализът на сентимента е изминал дълъг път за езици с висок ресурс поради наличието на големи анотирани корпуси. Въпреки това, тя все още страда от липса на данни за обучение за езици с нисък ресурс. За да се справим с този проблем, предлагаме условна езикова противоречива мрежа (CLAN), невронна архитектура от край до край за междуезичен анализ на сентименталните чувства без междуезичен надзор. Клан се различава от предишната работа по това, че позволява на съперническото обучение да бъде обусловено както от научените характеристики, така и от предсказването на сентимента, за да се увеличи дискриминацията за наученото представяне в междуезичната обстановка. Експерименталните резултати показват, че CLAN превъзхожда предишните методи в многоезичния многодомейнен набор от данни за преглед на Amazon. Нашият изходен код е публикуван на https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Sentiment analyse er kommet langt for høj ressource sprog på grund af tilgængeligheden af store annoterede korpora. Den lider dog stadig af manglende uddannelsesdata for sprog med lav ressource. For at løse dette problem foreslår vi Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), en end-to-end neural arkitektur til tværsproget sentimental analyse uden tværsproget overvågning. CLAN adskiller sig fra tidligere arbejde ved, at det gør det muligt for modstandernes træning at blive betinget af både lærte træk og sentiment forudsigelse, for at øge diskrimineringen for lært repræsentation i den tværsprogede indstilling. Eksperimentelle resultater viser, at CLAN overgår tidligere metoder på det flersprogede Amazon-gennemgangsdatasæt med flere domæner. Vores kildekode udgives på https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_nl>Sentiment analyse heeft een lange weg afgelegd voor high-resource talen vanwege de beschikbaarheid van grote geannoteerde corpora. Het lijdt echter nog steeds aan een gebrek aan opleidingsgegevens voor talen met weinig middelen. Om dit probleem aan te pakken, stellen we Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN) voor, een end-to-end neurale architectuur voor meertalige sentimentanalyse zonder meertalige supervisie. CLAN verschilt van eerder werk in dat het toelaat om de tegenstrijdige training te conditioneren op zowel de aangeleerde kenmerken als de sentiment voorspelling, om de discriminatie voor geleerde representatie in de cross-lingual setting te vergroten. Experimentele resultaten tonen aan dat CLAN eerdere methoden overtreft op de meertalige multi-domein Amazon review dataset. Onze broncode wordt vrijgegeven op: https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Analiza osjetljivosti došla je na dug način za jezike visokog resursa zbog raspoloženja velikog annotiranog tijela. Međutim, ona još uvijek pati od nedostatka podataka o obuci za jezike niskih resursa. Za rješavanje ovog problema predlažemo uslovnu porazgovarajuću mrežu jezika (CLAN), neuralnu arhitekturu kraja do kraja za analizu preko jezika sentimenta bez preko jezika nadzora. CLAN se razlikuje od prethodnog rada u tome što omogućava da se adversarna obuka uvjeti na naučene funkcije i predviđanje osjećaja, povećati diskriminaciju za učenje zastupanja na međujezičkom postavljanju. Eksperimentalni rezultati pokazuju da CLAN iznosi prethodne metode na multijezičkim multidomeničkim podacima Amazon pregledanja. Naš izvorni kod je objavljen na https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_de>Die Sentimentanalyse hat aufgrund der Verfügbarkeit großer kommentierter Korpora für ressourcenintensive Sprachen einen langen Weg zurückgelegt. Es leidet jedoch immer noch unter fehlenden Ausbildungsdaten für ressourcenarme Sprachen. Um dieses Problem anzugehen, schlagen wir Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN) vor, eine End-to-End neuronale Architektur für die sprachübergreifende Stimmungsanalyse ohne sprachübergreifende Aufsicht. CLAN unterscheidet sich von früheren Arbeiten dadurch, dass es erlaubt, das gegnerische Training sowohl von erlernten Merkmalen als auch von der Sentiment-Vorhersage zu konditionieren, um die Diskriminierung der erlernten Repräsentation im crosslingualen Setting zu erhöhen. Experimentelle Ergebnisse zeigen, dass CLAN frühere Methoden auf dem mehrsprachigen Amazon Review Dataset mit mehreren Domänen übertrifft. Unser Quellcode wird veröffentlicht unter https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>Analisis perasaan telah datang jauh untuk bahasa sumber daya tinggi karena keberhasilan dari corpora besar yang dicatat. Namun, masih menderita karena kekurangan data pelatihan untuk bahasa sumber daya rendah. Untuk mengatasi masalah ini, kami mengusulkan Jaringan Perlawanan Bahasa Kondisional (CLAN), arsitektur saraf akhir-akhir untuk analisis sentimen saling bahasa tanpa pengawasan saling bahasa. CLAN berbeda dari pekerjaan sebelumnya karena itu memungkinkan pelatihan lawan untuk tergantung pada kedua ciri-ciri belajar dan prediksi sentimen, untuk meningkatkan diskriminasi untuk perwakilan belajar dalam persediaan saling bahasa. Hasil eksperimen menunjukkan bahwa CLAN melampaui metode sebelumnya pada set data multi-domain Amazon review multibahasa. Kode sumber kita dibebaskan di https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>تحلیل احساسات برای زبانهای منابع بالا به دلیل موجودات شرکت بزرگی که مشخص شده است، راه طولانی برای زبانهای منابع بالا آمده است. ولی هنوز از دست داده های آموزش برای زبانهای کم منبع درد می یابد. برای حل این مشکل، ما شبکه مبارزه زبان شرایطی (CLAN) را پیشنهاد می‌کنیم، یک معماری عصبی برای تحلیل احساسات متوسط زبان بدون مدیریت متوسط زبان. CLAN از کار قبلی تفاوت می‌کند که به تمرین دشمنی اجازه می‌دهد که بر هر گونه ویژه‌های آموزش یافته و پیش‌بینی احساسات وضعیت یافته شود، برای افزایش تفاوتی برای نمایش یافته در تنظیم متوسط زبان یافته شود. نتیجه‌های تجربه نشان می‌دهند که CLAN روش‌های قبلی را در مجموعه داده‌های تجربه‌های زیادی دامنه‌های آمازون انجام می‌دهد. کد منبع ما در https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>대형 주석 자료 라이브러리의 가용성 때문에 감정 분석은 고자원 언어에서 큰 발전을 이루었다.그러나 저자원 언어의 훈련 데이터가 여전히 부족하다.이 문제를 해결하기 위해 우리는 조건언어대항네트워크(CLAN)를 제시했는데 크로스 언어 감정 분석에 사용되는 단말기부터 단말기까지의 신경 구조로 크로스 언어 감독이 필요 없다.CLAN은 이전 연구와 달리 대항적인 훈련을 통해 학습 특징과 정서 예측을 조건으로 하여 언어 환경에서 학습 표징의 구분성을 높일 수 있다.실험 결과, CLAN은 다국어 다중 도메인 아마존 리뷰 데이터 세트에서 이전 방법보다 성능이 우수한 것으로 나타났다.우리의 원본 코드는https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Uchambuzi wa muda mrefu umekuja kwa lugha za rasilimali zilizo juu kutokana na upatikanaji wa kampuni kubwa yenye matatizo. Hata hivyo, bado inaumia kutokuwepo na taarifa za mafunzo kwa lugha ndogo ya rasilimali. Ili kukabiliana na tatizo hili, tunapendekeza Mtandao wa Kimataifa wa Lugha (CLAN), ujenzi wa kisasa wa mwisho wa mwishoni kwa ajili ya uchambuzi wa hisia za lugha tofauti bila kufuatiliwa kwa lugha. CLAN inatofautiana na kazi za kabla katika kuwa inaruhusu mafunzo ya upinzani ya kuhusiana na tabia za kujifunza na utabiri wa hisia, kuongeza ubaguzi wa kujifunza uwakilishi katika mazingira ya lugha mbalimbali. Matokeo ya majaribio yanaonyesha kuwa CLAN inafanya mbinu zilizopita kuhusu taarifa za kurekebisha kwa lugha mbalimbali za Amazon. Kodi letu la vyanzo limetolewa https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_sq>Analiza e ndjenjave ka ardhur një rrugë të gjatë për gjuhët me burime të larta për shkak të disponueshmërisë së korprave të mëdha të anotuara. Megjithatë, ajo vuan ende nga mungesa e të dhënave të trainimit për gjuhët me burime të ulta. Për të trajtuar këtë problem, propozojmë Rrjetin Kundërshtar të Gjuhave (CLAN), një arkitekturë nervore nga fundi në fund për analizën e ndjenjave ndërgjuhësore pa mbikqyrje ndërgjuhësore. CLAN ndryshon nga puna e mëparshme në atë që lejon trainimin kundërshtar të kushtëzohet si mbi karakteristikat e mësuara ashtu edhe parashikimin e ndjenjave, për të rritur diskriminimin për përfaqësimin e mësuar në ambientin ndërgjuhësor. Experimental results demonstrate that CLAN outperforms previous methods on the multilingual multi-domain Amazon review dataset.  Kodi ynë burimi është lëshuar në https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Ýük nähili möhüm bolan korpora ulaşandygyna sebäbi duýgymlyk çykyş diller üçin uzak yönden geldi. Ýöne bu ýerde iň azyk ressurs dilleri üçin maglumatlaryň ýok bolmagyndan täzeden bolýar. Bu meseleyi çözmek üçin, olaryň şartly dil jemgyýetli Network (CLAN), cross-lingual supervision bolmadyk bir nuýral arhitektura teklip edip bilýäris. CLAN öň öňki işden üýtgeşik edýän zada çykyş eğitimi hem öwrenmeli özellikler hem duýgular öňünde, cross-lingual düzeninde öwrenmeli terjime etmek üçin diskriminçylygy artmagy mümkin edýär. Aramanyň netijeleri CLAN multi-dilli Amazon duýdury barlamasynda öňki yönlerden çykarýandygyny görkez. Biziň çeşme kodymyz çykylýar https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>ከፍተኛ የኩነቶች ቋንቋዎች በመጠቀም ምክንያት የሲንሰዓት analysis ረጅም ሆኖአል፡፡ ምንም እንኳን፣ የጎደለኛ ክፍል ቋንቋዎች ዳታዎችን ለማግኘት አይታሰቃትም፡፡ ይህንን ጉዳይ ለመቀናቀል፣ የባሕላዊ ቋንቋ አዳራዊ መረብ (CLAN), የቋንቋ ቋንቋ-ቋንቋ አስተያየት ሳይኖር የመጨረሻ የናውራዊ የመሠረታዊ አካውንተር ለመፍጠር እናቀርባታለን፡፡ CLAN ከቀድሞው ሥራ ይለየዋል፤ በተቃዋሚው ትምህርት እና ማስታወቂያውን በመስቀል ቋንቋ ውስጥ ለመማር መልዕክትን እንዲያበዛ በተቃዋሚ ትምህርት ይጨምርበታል፡፡ ፈተናው ውጤቶች CLAN የቀድሞውን የልዩ ቋንቋ-አሜዞን የዳታ ማተሚያ ማድረጊያውን እንዲያሳየው ያሳያል፡፡ ምንጭ https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_am>
      <abstract_af>Sentiment-analiseer het 'n lang manier gekom vir hoë-hulpbronne tale vanweë die beskikbaarheid van groot aanmerkte korpora. Maar dit lyf nog steeds van die ontbreiding van onderwerp data vir lae-hulpbronne tale. Om hierdie probleem te probeer, voorstel ons die voorwaardige Taal Adversarial Network (CLAN), ân end-to-end neurale arkitektuur vir kruistale sentimentanalisie sonder kruistale supervisie. CLAN is verskillende van voorheede werk in dat dit toelaat dat die teenstandaarlike onderwerking op beide geleerde funksies en die sentiment voorskou moet wees, om diskriminasiteit te verhoog vir geleerde voorstelling in die kruistale opstelling. Eksperimentale resultate bevestig dat CLAN vorige metodes uitvoer op die multi-tale multi-domein Amazon oorskou dataset. Ons bronkode is verlos by https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_hy>Զգացմունքների վերլուծությունը երկար ճանապարհ է գալիս բարձր ռեսուրսներ ունեցող լեզուների համար, որովհետև մեծ նշումներ ունեցող մարմնի հասանելիությունն է: Այնուամենայնիվ, այն դեռևս տառապում է ցածր ռեսուրսների լեզուների ուսուցման տվյալների բացակայությունից: Այս խնդիրը լուծելու համար մենք առաջարկում ենք պայմանավոր լեզվի հակառակ ցանց, որը վերջ-վերջ նյարդային ճարտարապետություն է լեզվային զգացմունքների վերլուծության համար առանց լեզվի հակառակ վերահսկման: Այն տարբերվում է նախորդ աշխատանքից, որովհետև հնարավորություն է տալիս հակառակյալ վարժումը կախված լինել սովորված հատկանիշների և զգացմունքների կանխատեսման վրա, որպեսզի աճի տարբերակությունը սովորված ներկայացման համար լեզվային միջավայրում: Փորձարկվող արդյունքները ցույց են տալիս, որ կլան արտադրում է նախորդ մեթոդները Amazon բազլեզու բազմաբնույթի վերանայման տվյալների համակարգում: Our source code is released at  https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Büyük nöqtəli korpora vasitəsilə yüksək ressurs dillərinin istifadə edilməsinin səbəbi təhsil analizi uzun yola gəldi. Ancaq hələ də zəif ressurs dillərinin təhsil edilməsi lazımdır. Bu problemi çəkmək üçün, müddətli Dil Adversarial Network (CLAN) təklif edirik, çox dilli hisslər analizi üçün çox-çox dəlil gözləmədən bir nöral arhitektür. CLAN əvvəlki işlərdən fərqli olar ki, bu təhsil öyrəndiyi təhsil və duyguların təsiri ilə öyrəndiyi təhsil ilə öyrənməsini artırmağa imkan verir. Həqiqətən, CLAN çoxlu dil çoxlu-domani Amazon gözləmə veri quruluğunda əvvəlki metodların üstünlüyünü göstərir. Bizim mənbə kodumuz https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>সেন্টাইমেন্ট বিশ্লেষণ বিশ্লেষণ হাই-সম্পদ ভাষার জন্য অনেক দীর্ঘ পথ এসেছে বিশাল কোর্পোরার কারণে। তবে এটা এখনো কম সম্পদ ভাষার প্রশিক্ষণের অভাবে কষ্ট পেয়েছে। এই সমস্যার মুখোমুখি হওয়ার জন্য আমরা পরিস্থিতি ভাষা এডভারেরিয়াল নেটওয়ার্ক (সিলান) প্রস্তাব করি, ক্রাশ-ভাষাভাষী পর্যবেক্ষণ ছাড়া একটি শেষ নিউরেল কাঠাম সিলান পূর্বের কাজ থেকে ভিন্ন ভিন্ন যে এটি শিক্ষিত বৈশিষ্ট্য এবং অনুভূতির উপর বিরোধীদের প্রশিক্ষণের সুযোগ প্রদান করে, যাতে ক্রিশ ভাষাভাষার প্রতিনি Experimental results demonstrate that CLAN outperforms previous methods on the multilingual multi-domain Amazon review dataset.  আমাদের উৎস কোড প্রকাশ করা হয়েছে https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Analiza osjetljivosti došla je na dug način za jezike visokog resursa zbog raspoloženja velikog annotiranog korporacije. Međutim, još uvijek pati od nedostatka podataka o obuci za jezike niskih resursa. Da bi se riješili ovog problema, predlažemo uslovnu reklamnu mrežu jezika (CLAN), neuralnu arhitekturu kraja do kraja za analizu preko jezika sentimenta bez preko jezika nadzora. CLAN se razlikuje od prethodnog rada u tome što omogućava da se adversarna obuka uvjeti na naučene karakteristike i predviđanje osjećaja, povećava diskriminaciju za naučenu predstavljanje na međujezičkom postavljanju. Eksperimentalni rezultati pokazuju da CLAN nadmašuje prethodne metode na multijezičkom multidomenu Amazon pregledavanje podataka. Naš izvorni kod je objavljen na https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>L'anàlisi dels sentiments ha arribat a un llarg camí per a llengües d'alt recurso degut a la disponibilitat de grans corpores anotats. Tot i així, encara pateix la falta de dades de formació per llengües de baix recursos. Per abordar aquest problema, proposem una Rede Condicional Language Adversary Network (CLAN), una arquitectura neural de final a final per a l'an àlisi del sentiment translingüístic sense supervisió translingüística. CLAN diferèn de la feina anterior en que permet que la formació adversaria sigui condicionada tant per les característiques aprendides com per la predicció del sentiment, per incrementar la discriminació per la representació aprendida en un entorn translingüístic. Els resultats experimentals demostren que CLAN supera els mètodes anteriors en el conjunt de dades multillengües de revisió Amazon. El nostre codi fonts es publica a https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Analýza sentimentů ušla dlouhou cestu pro jazyky s vysokými zdroji kvůli dostupnosti velkých anotovaných korpusů. Stále však trpí nedostatkem údajů o odborné přípravě pro jazyky s nízkými zdroji. Pro řešení tohoto problému navrhujeme CONditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), komplexní neuronovou architekturu pro analýzu sentimentů mezi jazyky bez nadhledu nad jazyky. CLAN se liší od předchozí práce tím, že umožňuje podmínit adversariální trénink jak na naučených rysech, tak na predikci sentimentu, tak zvýšit diskriminaci pro naučené reprezentace v cross-jazyčném prostředí. Experimentální výsledky ukazují, že CLAN překonává předchozí metody na vícejazyčné vícedoménové sadě recenzí Amazon. Náš zdrojový kód je vydán na adrese: https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Sentimendianalüüs on suurte märgetega korpuste kättesaadavuse tõttu tulnud suure ressursiga keelte puhul pika tee. Siiski kannatab ta endiselt vähese ressursiga keelte koolitusandmete puudumise tõttu. Selle probleemi lahendamiseks pakume välja Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), lõpp-otsa neuraalarhitektuuri keeleülese sentimentaalüüsi jaoks ilma keeleülese järelevalveta. CLAN erineb varasematest töödest selles osas, et see võimaldab vastandlikku koolitust sõltuda nii õppinud omadustest kui ka tunnete prognoosimisest, et suurendada diskrimineerimist õppinud esindatuse suhtes keeleüleses keskkonnas. Eksperimentaalsed tulemused näitavad, et CLAN ületab varasemaid meetodeid mitmekeelses mitmedomeenilises Amazoni ülevaateandmekogumis. Meie lähtekood avaldatakse aadressil https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Tunteanalyysi on edennyt pitkälle korkean resurssin kielillä suurten merkintöjen ansiosta. Se kärsii kuitenkin edelleen koulutustietojen puutteesta vähävaraisten kielten osalta. Tämän ongelman ratkaisemiseksi ehdotamme Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), päästä päähän -neuroarkkitehtuuria monikieliseen tunteiden analysointiin ilman monikielistä valvontaa. CLAN eroaa aikaisemmasta työstä siinä mielessä, että se mahdollistaa vastustajan koulutuksen ehdollistamisen sekä opittuihin ominaisuuksiin että tunteiden ennustamiseen, mikä lisää oppitun edustuksen syrjintää kielienvälisessä ympäristössä. Kokeelliset tulokset osoittavat, että CLAN ylittää aiemmat menetelmät monikielisessä Amazon-tarkistusaineistossa. Lähdekoodimme julkaistaan osoitteessa https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Sentiment Nanging, mbok saiki durung ono langkung dadi ora ono nggawe datang kanggo langkung Ngawe nglanggar perbudhakan iki, kita ngubah suaraning langkung Advertorial Network (CLAN), architecture end-to-end Neral kanggo ngawe langgar sampeyan seneng dipunanggé kuwi wis ana luwih-luwih bantuan. CLAN Writing direction context menu item Awak dhéwé kelompok punika dipoleh nang https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>Anarari na zaman shawara ya zo da wata hanya mai tsawo wa harshen masu sarki, saboda haka da za'a samu'a da wata firma mai girma. A lokacin da, yana da kuma bã da data na amfani da lugha masu rauni. To, don mu buɗaɗe wa wannan masu husũma, Munã buɗaɗe Shirin Ayuka na Kwamfyuta (CLN), an ƙara-zuwa-ƙarshen matsakan neural dõmin a yi anarwa ga fassarar-harshe bila ya zama mai tsaro na-harshen. CLEN yana sãɓã wa zaman aikin da yake yarda da wa'anar motsi su zama sharri a kan laban zafi da abin da aka sanar da shi na kalmar, dõmin ya ƙara yin takanci wa masu karatun a cikin fassarar-harshen. Cikakken jarrabai ya nuna CCLEN na tafiyar da metoden zaman a kan kure danne-bayani na multiziman-multi-Domen amazon. Kodinmu na'urar da https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_sk>Analiza čustev je prišla daleč za jezike z visokimi viri zaradi razpoložljivosti velikih korpusov z oznakami. Vendar pa še vedno trpi zaradi pomanjkanja podatkov o usposabljanju za jezike z nizkimi viri. Za reševanje tega problema predlagamo pogojno jezikovno adversarno mrežo (CLAN), celovito nevralno arhitekturo za medjezično analizo sentimentalnih občutkov brez medjezičnega nadzora. CLAN se razlikuje od predhodnega dela v tem, da omogoča, da je kontradiktorsko usposabljanje pogojeno tako z učenimi značilnostmi kot napovedovanjem čustev, da se poveča diskriminativnost za učeno reprezentacijo v medjezičnem okolju. Poskusni rezultati kažejo, da CLAN presega prejšnje metode v večjezičnem večdomenskem naboru podatkov o pregledu Amazon. Naša izvorna koda je objavljena na https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>Sentiment analysis has come a long way for high-resource languages due to the availability of large annotated corpora.  עם זאת, הוא עדיין סובל מחוסר נתוני אימון לשפות משאבים נמוכות. כדי להתמודד עם הבעיה הזאת, אנו מציעים רשת התנגדות לשפה תנאי (CLAN), ארכיטקטורה עצבית סוף-סוף לניתוח רגשות דרך שפתיים ללא פיקוח דרך שפתיים. CLAN שונה מעבודה קודמת כי הוא מאפשר לאימון היריב להיות מונח על שני תכונות למדו וגם על חיזוי הרגשות, כדי לגדל את ההבדל לייצג למדו במסגרת השפה הצלבית. תוצאות ניסיוניות מראות שCLAN מציג שיטות קודמות על קבוצת נתונים של בדיקת אמאזון multilingual multi-domain. קוד המקור שלנו משוחרר ב https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_bo>ཆུ་ཚོད་ལྟ་ཞིབ་བྱས་ཡོད་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་མཐོ་ཤིག་ཡོད་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་མཐོ་རིང་གི་ཐབས་ལམ་ཞིག་ཡིན། ཡིན་ནའང་། རྒྱ་ནག་ཏུ་ཡན་རྐྱེན་ཆེ་ཆུང་བའི་སྐད་རིགས་ལ་ཆུང་བའི་གནད་དོན་ཡིག་ཆ་ཡང་མེད། To tackle this problem, we propose Conditional Language Adversarial Network (CLAN), an end-to-end neural architecture for cross-lingual sentiment analysis without cross-lingual supervision. A CLAN Experimental results demonstrate that CLAN outperforms previous methods on the multilingual multi-domain Amazon review dataset. ང་ཚོའི་ཐོག་ཁུངས་ཨང་རྩིས་ཀྱི་ནང་དུ་ཉར་ཚར་བ https://github.com/hemanthkandula/clan.</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>Anlirika : An LSTMCNN Flow Twister for Spoken Language Identification<fixed-case>LSTM</fixed-case>–<fixed-case>CNN</fixed-case> Flow Twister for Spoken Language Identification</title>
      <author><first>Andreas</first><last>Scherbakov</last></author>
      <author><first>Liam</first><last>Whittle</last></author>
      <author><first>Ritesh</first><last>Kumar</last></author>
      <author><first>Siddharth</first><last>Singh</last></author>
      <author><first>Matthew</first><last>Coleman</last></author>
      <author><first>Ekaterina</first><last>Vylomova</last></author>
      <pages>145–148</pages>
      <abstract>The paper presents Anlirika’s submission to SIGTYP 2021 Shared Task on Robust Spoken Language Identification. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">task</a> aims at building a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robustness_(computer_science)">robust system</a> that generalizes well across different domains and speakers. The training data is limited to a single domain only with predominantly single speaker per language while the validation and test data samples are derived from diverse dataset and multiple speakers. We experiment with a neural system comprising a combination of dense, convolutional, and recurrent layers that are designed to perform better <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generalization">generalization</a> and obtain speaker-invariant representations. We demonstrate that the task in its constrained form (without making use of external data or augmentation the train set with samples from the validation set) is still challenging. Our best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> trained on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a> augmented with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_validation">validation samples</a> achieves 29.9 % <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accuracy_and_precision">accuracy</a> on the test data.</abstract>
      <url hash="57088f18">2021.sigtyp-1.14</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.sigtyp-1.14</doi>
      <bibkey>scherbakov-etal-2021-anlirika</bibkey>
    </paper>
  </volume>
</collection>