<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.dialdoc">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on Document-grounded Dialogue and Conversational Question Answering (DialDoc 2021)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Song</first><last>Feng</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Siva</first><last>Reddy</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Malihe</first><last>Alikhani</last></editor>
      <editor><first>He</first><last>He</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Yangfeng</first><last>Ji</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mohit</first><last>Iyyer</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Zhou</first><last>Yu</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="3e48dd78">2021.dialdoc-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="2ec0943c">2021.dialdoc-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>dialdoc-2021-document</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Automatic Learning Assistant in Telugu<fixed-case>T</fixed-case>elugu</title>
      <author><first>Meghana</first><last>Bommadi</last></author>
      <author><first>Shreya</first><last>Terupally</last></author>
      <author><first>Radhika</first><last>Mamidi</last></author>
      <pages>29–37</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents a learning assistant that tests one’s knowledge and gives feedback that helps a person learn at a faster pace. A learning assistant (based on automated question generation) has extensive uses in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Education">education</a>, information websites, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-assessment">self-assessment</a>, FAQs, testing ML agents, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Research">research</a>, etc. Multiple researchers, and companies have worked on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_Assistance">Virtual Assistance</a>, but majorly in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>. We built our learning assistant for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu language</a> to help with teaching in the mother tongue, which is the most efficient way of learning. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is built primarily based on Question Generation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>. Many experiments were conducted on Question Generation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a> in multiple ways. We have built the first hybrid machine learning and rule-based solution in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>, which proves efficient for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Short_story">short stories</a> or short passages in children’s books. Our work covers the fundamental question forms with question types : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adjective">adjective</a>, yes / no, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adverb">adverb</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verb">verb</a>, when, where, whose, quotative, and quantitative (how many / how much). We constructed rules for question generation using Part of Speech (POS) tags and Universal Dependency (UD) tags along with linguistic information of the surrounding relevant context of the word. We used keyword matching, multilingual sentence embedding to evaluate the answer. Our system is primarily built on question generation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telugu_language">Telugu</a>, and is also capable of evaluating the user’s answers to the generated questions.</abstract>
      <url hash="bd4bbb41">2021.dialdoc-1.4</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.dialdoc-1.4</doi>
      <bibkey>bommadi-etal-2021-automatic</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Combining Open Domain Question Answering with a Task-Oriented Dialog System</title>
      <author><first>Jan</first><last>Nehring</last></author>
      <author><first>Nils</first><last>Feldhus</last></author>
      <author><first>Harleen</first><last>Kaur</last></author>
      <author><first>Akhyar</first><last>Ahmed</last></author>
      <pages>38–45</pages>
      <abstract>We apply the modular dialog system framework to combine open-domain question answering with a task-oriented dialog system. This meta dialog system can answer questions from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia">Wikipedia</a> and at the same time act as a personal assistant. The aim of this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is to combine the strength of an open-domain question answering system with the conversational power of task-oriented dialog systems. After explaining the technical details of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>, we combined a new dataset out of standard datasets to evaluate the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>. We further introduce an evaluation method for this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a>. Using this method, we compare the performance of the non-modular system with the performance of the modular system and show that the modular dialog system framework is very suitable for this combination of conversational agents and that the performance of each agent decreases only marginally through the modular setting.</abstract>
      <url hash="b04297cd">2021.dialdoc-1.5</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.dialdoc-1.5</doi>
      <bibkey>nehring-etal-2021-combining</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/clinc150">CLINC150</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/coqa">CoQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/squad">SQuAD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>CAiRE in DialDoc21 : Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialogue System<fixed-case>CA</fixed-case>i<fixed-case>RE</fixed-case> in <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ial<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>oc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialogue System</title>
      <author><first>Yan</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <author><first>Etsuko</first><last>Ishii</last></author>
      <author><first>Genta Indra</first><last>Winata</last></author>
      <author><first>Zhaojiang</first><last>Lin</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrea</first><last>Madotto</last></author>
      <author><first>Zihan</first><last>Liu</last></author>
      <author><first>Peng</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <author><first>Pascale</first><last>Fung</last></author>
      <pages>46–51</pages>
      <abstract>Information-seeking dialogue systems, including knowledge identification and response generation, aim to respond to users with fluent, coherent, and informative responses based on users’ needs, which. To tackle this challenge, we utilize data augmentation methods and several training techniques with the pre-trained language models to learn a general pattern of the task and thus achieve promising performance. In DialDoc21 competition, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> achieved 74.95 F1 score and 60.74 Exact Match score in subtask 1, and 37.72 SacreBLEU score in subtask 2. Empirical analysis is provided to explain the effectiveness of our approaches.</abstract>
      <url hash="17824f16">2021.dialdoc-1.6</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.dialdoc-1.6</doi>
      <bibkey>xu-etal-2021-caire</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/HLTCHKUST/CAiRE_in_DialDoc21" additional="false">HLTCHKUST/CAiRE_in_DialDoc21</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/mrqa-2019">MRQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/searchqa">SearchQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/triviaqa">TriviaQA</pwcdataset>
    <title_ar>CAiRE in DialDoc21: زيادة البيانات لنظام الحوار البحثي عن المعلومات</title_ar>
      <title_pt>CAiRE no DialDoc21: Aumento de Dados para Sistema de Diálogo de Busca de Informações</title_pt>
      <title_es>CAire en DialDoc21: Aumento de datos para el sistema de diálogo de búsqueda de información</title_es>
      <title_ja>DialDoc 21のCAiRE ：情報検索ダイアログシステムのためのデータ拡張</title_ja>
      <title_zh>DialDoc21中CAiRE:信索其数</title_zh>
      <title_hi>DialDoc21 में CAIRE: संवाद प्रणाली की मांग करने वाली जानकारी के लिए डेटा वृद्धि</title_hi>
      <title_ga>CAiRE in DialDoc21: Méadú Sonraí don Chóras Comhphlé um Lorg Faisnéise</title_ga>
      <title_hu>CAiRE a DialDoc21-ben: Adatbővítés az információkereső párbeszédrendszerhez</title_hu>
      <title_el>CAiRE στο DialDoc21: Ενίσχυση δεδομένων για το σύστημα διαλόγου αναζήτησης πληροφοριών</title_el>
      <title_it>CAiRE in DialDoc21: Aumento dei dati per il sistema di dialogo alla ricerca di informazioni</title_it>
      <title_kk>CAiRE диалогында</title_kk>
      <title_lt>CAiRE DialDoc21: Informacijos paieškos dialogo sistemos duomenų didinimas</title_lt>
      <title_mk>CAiRE во DialDoc21: Агментација на податоци за систем за дијалог за барање информации</title_mk>
      <title_ms>CAiRE dalam DialDoc21: Pembesaran Data untuk Sistem Dialog Pencarian Maklumat</title_ms>
      <title_mt>CAiRE f’DialDoc21: Żieda fid-Dejta għas-Sistema ta’ Djalogu għat-Tfittxija ta’ Informazzjoni</title_mt>
      <title_mn>CAiRE in DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialogue System</title_mn>
      <title_ml>ഡയല്‍ഡോക്ടറിലെ CAiRE: വിവരങ്ങള്‍ തേടുന്നതിനുള്ള വിവരങ്ങള്‍ തേടുന്നതിനുള്ള ഡേറ്റാ ഓഗ്മെന്റേഷന്‍</title_ml>
      <title_pl>CAiRE w DialDoc21: Rozszerzenie danych dla systemu dialogu poszukiwania informacji</title_pl>
      <title_ro>CAiRE în DialDoc21: Augmentarea datelor pentru sistemul de dialog în căutarea informațiilor</title_ro>
      <title_ka>CAiRE DialDoc21: ინფორმაციის ძიება დიალოგის სისტემის მონაცემები</title_ka>
      <title_so>CAiRE ee DialDoc21: Tilmaamaha macluumaadka raadinta nidaamka diyaariga</title_so>
      <title_sv>CAiRE i DialDoc21: Dataförstärkning för informationssökande dialogsystem</title_sv>
      <title_no>CAiRE i DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialog System</title_no>
      <title_sr>CAiRE u DialDoc21: Augmentacija podataka za sustav dialoga za traženje informacija</title_sr>
      <title_si>CAiRE in DialDoc21: තොරතුරු හොයාගන්න සංවාදය පද්ධතියට තොරතුරු විශාලනය</title_si>
      <title_ta>DialDoc21: தகவல் தேடும் உரையாடல் அமைப்புக்கான தகவல் ஒப்பிடுதல்</title_ta>
      <title_ur>CAiRE in DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialog System</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Dial</title_uz>
      <title_vi>tạo số trong Diadoc21: gia tăng dữ liệu cho hệ thống tìm kiếm thông tin</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Увеличаване на данни за диалогова система за търсене на информация</title_bg>
      <title_nl>CAiRE in DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialogue System</title_nl>
      <title_hr>CAiRE u DialDoc21: povećanje podataka za sustav dialoga za traženje informacija</title_hr>
      <title_da>CAiRE i DialDoc21: Dataudvidelse til informationssøgende dialogsystem</title_da>
      <title_de>CAiRE in DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialogue System</title_de>
      <title_ko>DialDoc21의 CAiRE: 정보 검색 대화 시스템의 데이터 확장</title_ko>
      <title_id>CAiRE dalam DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Search Dialogue System</title_id>
      <title_fa>CAiRE در DialDoc21: افزایش داده برای سیستم محاورۀ جستجو اطلاعات</title_fa>
      <title_sw>CAiRE mjini DialDoc21: Kusaidia data kwa ajili ya Taarifa Kutafuta Mfumo wa Dialog</title_sw>
      <title_tr>CAiRE in DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialog System</title_tr>
      <title_af>CAIRE in DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seek Dialog System</title_af>
      <title_sq>CAiRE në DialDoc21: rritja e të dhënave për sistemin e dialogut për kërkimin e informacionit</title_sq>
      <title_hy>Comment</title_hy>
      <title_am>Doc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialog System</title_am>
      <title_bn>ডায়ালড২১-এ কায়েরি: তথ্য অনুসন্ধানের তথ্য অংশগ্রহণের জন্য ডায়ালগ সিস্টেম</title_bn>
      <title_az>CAiRE DialDoc21: Malümat Seek Dialog Sistemi üçün Data Augmentation</title_az>
      <title_bs>CAiRE u DialDoc21: povećanje podataka za sustav dialoga za traženje informacija</title_bs>
      <title_ca>CAiRE a DialDoc21: augmentació de dades per al sistema de diàleg de cerca d'informació</title_ca>
      <title_cs>CAiRE v DialDoc21: Rozšíření dat pro systém dialogu hledání informací</title_cs>
      <title_et>CAiRE dialoogisüsteemis DialDoc21: andmete suurendamine infootsingu dialoogisüsteemi jaoks</title_et>
      <title_fi>CAiRE DialDoc21: Tiedon lisĂ¤Ă¤minen tiedonhakudialogijĂ¤rjestelmĂ¤Ă¤n</title_fi>
      <title_jv>CaiVE in dialDok22: data agement for information Search Dialog System</title_jv>
      <title_sk>CAiRE v DialDoc21: Povečanje podatkov za sistem dialoga iskanja informacij</title_sk>
      <title_ha>KCharselect unicode block name</title_ha>
      <title_he>CAiRE ב DialDoc21: גידול נתונים למערכת דיאלוג חיפוש מידע</title_he>
      <title_bo>CAiRE in DialDoc21: Data Augmentation for Information Seeking Dialog System</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تهدف أنظمة حوار البحث عن المعلومات ، بما في ذلك تحديد المعرفة وتوليد الاستجابة ، إلى الاستجابة للمستخدمين بإجابات طلاقة ومتماسكة وغنية بالمعلومات بناءً على احتياجات المستخدمين ، والتي. لمواجهة هذا التحدي ، نستخدم طرق زيادة البيانات والعديد من تقنيات التدريب مع نماذج اللغة المدربة مسبقًا لتعلم نمط عام للمهمة وبالتالي تحقيق أداء واعد. في مسابقة DialDoc21 ، حقق نظامنا 74.95 درجة F1 و 60.74 نتيجة مطابقة تامة في المهمة الفرعية 1 ، و 37.72 درجة SacreBLEU في المهمة الفرعية 2. يتم توفير تحليل تجريبي لشرح فعالية مناهجنا.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Los sistemas de diálogo de búsqueda de información, incluida la identificación de conocimiento y la generación de respuestas, tienen como objetivo responder a los usuarios con respuestas fluidas, coherentes e informativas basadas en las necesidades de los usuarios, cual. Para hacer frente a este desafío, utilizamos métodos de aumento de datos y varias técnicas de capacitación con modelos de lenguaje previamente entrenados para aprender un patrón general de la tarea y así lograr un rendimiento prometedor. En la competencia DialDoc21, nuestro sistema obtuvo 74,95 puntos de F1 y 60,74 puntos de Concordancia Exacta en la subtarea 1, y 37,72 puntos de SacRebleu en la subtarea 2. Se proporciona un análisis empírico para explicar la eficacia de nuestros enfoques.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Os sistemas de diálogo de busca de informação, incluindo identificação de conhecimento e geração de resposta, visam responder aos usuários com respostas fluentes, coerentes e informativas com base nas necessidades dos usuários. Para enfrentar esse desafio, utilizamos métodos de aumento de dados e várias técnicas de treinamento com os modelos de linguagem pré-treinados para aprender um padrão geral da tarefa e, assim, alcançar um desempenho promissor. Na competição DialDoc21, nosso sistema alcançou 74,95 pontuação F1 e 60,74 pontuação Exact Match na subtarefa 1 e 37,72 pontuação SacreBLEU na subtarefa 2. A análise empírica é fornecida para explicar a eficácia de nossas abordagens.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>ナレッジ識別とレスポンス生成を含む情報を求める対話システムは、ユーザーのニーズに基づいた流暢で一貫性のある情報に基づいたレスポンスでユーザーに対応することを目指しています。この課題に取り組むために、私たちは事前にトレーニングされた言語モデルを用いたデータ拡張方法といくつかのトレーニング技術を活用して、タスクの一般的なパターンを学習し、したがって有望なパフォーマンスを達成します。DialDoc 21コンペティションでは、サブタスク1で74.95 F 1スコアと60.74 Exact Matchスコア、サブタスク2で37.72 SacreBLEUスコアを達成しました。私たちのアプローチの有効性を説明するための実証的分析が提供されています。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>信求言统,识反应生,指随用户用,以流利贯翔实报应用户。 以此挑战,以数益数,与数术、先训之言,以学其务,以成其欲。 于 DialDoc21 竞中,吾系于子职 1 得 74.95 F1 分与 60.74 精配分数,于子职 2 得 37.72 SacreBLEU 分数。 以实论之,以解吾法之有效性。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>ज्ञान की पहचान और प्रतिक्रिया पीढ़ी सहित सूचना-मांग संवाद प्रणालियों का उद्देश्य उपयोगकर्ताओं की जरूरतों के आधार पर धाराप्रवाह, सुसंगत और जानकारीपूर्ण प्रतिक्रियाओं के साथ उपयोगकर्ताओं को जवाब देना है, जो। इस चुनौती से निपटने के लिए, हम कार्य के एक सामान्य पैटर्न को सीखने के लिए पूर्व-प्रशिक्षित भाषा मॉडल के साथ डेटा संवर्धन विधियों और कई प्रशिक्षण तकनीकों का उपयोग करते हैं और इस प्रकार आशाजनक प्रदर्शन प्राप्त करते हैं। DialDoc21 प्रतियोगिता में, हमारे सिस्टम ने 74.95 F1 स्कोर और 60.74 Subtask 1 में सटीक मैच स्कोर हासिल किया, और subtask 2 में 37.72 SacreBLEU स्कोर। अनुभवजन्य विश्लेषण हमारे दृष्टिकोण की प्रभावशीलता की व्याख्या करने के लिए प्रदान किया जाता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Tá sé mar aidhm ag córais comhphlé um lorg faisnéise, lena n-áirítear sainaithint eolais agus giniúint freagartha, freagairtí a thabhairt d’úsáideoirí le freagraí atá líofa, comhleanúnach agus faisnéiseach bunaithe ar riachtanais na n-úsáideoirí, a. Chun dul i ngleic leis an dúshlán seo, bainimid úsáid as modhanna méadaithe sonraí agus roinnt teicníochtaí oiliúna leis na samhlacha teanga réamh-oilte chun patrún ginearálta an taisc a fhoghlaim agus ar an gcaoi sin feidhmíocht dhearfach a bhaint amach. I gcomórtas DialDoc21, ghnóthaigh ár gcóras 74.95 scór F1 agus 60.74 scór Meaitseála Beacht i bhfothasc 1, agus 37.72 scór SacreBLEU i bhfothasc 2. Cuirtear anailís eimpíreach ar fáil chun éifeachtacht ár gcur chuige a mhíniú.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_el>Τα συστήματα διαλόγου αναζήτησης πληροφοριών, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της αναγνώρισης γνώσεων και της δημιουργίας απαντήσεων, αποσκοπούν στην ανταπόκριση στους χρήστες με εύταιστες, συνεκτικές και ενημερωτικές απαντήσεις που βασίζονται στις ανάγκες των χρηστών, οι οποίες. Για να αντιμετωπίσουμε αυτή την πρόκληση, χρησιμοποιούμε μεθόδους αύξησης δεδομένων και διάφορες τεχνικές κατάρτισης με τα προ-εκπαιδευμένα γλωσσικά μοντέλα για να μάθουμε ένα γενικό πρότυπο της εργασίας και έτσι να επιτύχουμε ελπιδοφόρες επιδόσεις. Στο διαγωνισμό το σύστημά μας πέτυχε 74.95 σκορ F1 και 60.74 σκορ ακριβούς αγώνα στην υποταγή 1, και 37.72 σκορ SacreBLEU στην υποταγή 2. Παρέχεται εμπειρική ανάλυση για να εξηγήσει την αποτελεσματικότητα των προσεγγίσεων μας.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az információkereső párbeszédrendszerek, beleértve a tudás azonosítását és a válaszkészítést is, célja, hogy a felhasználók igényei alapján folyékony, koherens és tájékoztató válaszokkal reagáljanak a felhasználókra. Ennek a kihívásnak a megoldása érdekében adatbővítési módszereket és számos képzési technikát alkalmazunk az előre képzett nyelvi modellekkel, hogy megtanuljuk a feladat általános mintáját és ígéretes teljesítményt érjünk el. A DialDoc21 versenyen rendszerünk 74,95 F1 pontszámot és 60,74 pontszámot ért el az 1. részfeladatban, és 37,72 SacreBLEU pontszámot ért el a 2. részfeladatban. Empirikus elemzést nyújtunk megközelítéseink hatékonyságának magyarázatára.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_lt>Informacijos paieškos dialogo sistemos, įskaitant žinių nustatymą ir reagavimo į jas kūrimą, siekia reaguoti į naudotojus, turinčius sklandų, nuoseklų ir informacinį atsaką, pagrįstą naudotojų poreikiais. Siekdami spręsti šį uždavinį, naudojame duomenų didinimo metodus ir keletą mokymo metodų su iš anksto parengtais kalbų modeliais, kad išsiaiškintume bendrą užduoties modelį ir taip pasiektume pažadėtinus rezultatus. DialDoc21 konkurse mūsų sistema pasiekė 74,95 F1 balas ir 60,74 Exact Match balas 1 papunktyje, o 37,72 SacreBLEU balas 2 papunktyje. Siekiant paaiškinti mūsų požiūrių veiksmingumą, pateikiama empirinė analizė.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_it>I sistemi di dialogo alla ricerca di informazioni, compresi l'identificazione della conoscenza e la generazione di risposte, mirano a rispondere agli utenti con risposte fluenti, coerenti e informative basate sulle esigenze degli utenti, che. Per affrontare questa sfida, utilizziamo metodi di aumento dei dati e diverse tecniche di formazione con modelli linguistici pre-addestrati per imparare un modello generale del compito e quindi ottenere prestazioni promettenti. Nella competizione DialDoc21, il nostro sistema ha ottenuto 74,95 punti F1 e 60,74 punti Match esatti nella sottomissione 1 e 37,72 punti SacreBLEU nella sottomissione 2. Vengono fornite analisi empiriche per spiegare l'efficacia dei nostri approcci.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>Системите на дијалог за барање информации, вклучително и идентификација на знаење и генерација на одговор, имаат за цел одговор на корисниците со течни, коефицирани и информативни одговори базирани на потребите на корисниците, кои За да го решиме овој предизвик, користиме методи за зголемување на податоците и неколку техники за обука со предобучените јазички модели за да научиме генерален шаблон на задачата и така да постигнеме ветувачки перформанси. Во натпреварот DialDoc21, нашиот систем постигна 74,95 Ф1 оценка и 60,74 Exact Match оценка во подпрашањето 1, и 37,72 SacreBLEU оценка во подпрашањето 2. Империска анализа е обезбедена за објаснување на ефикасноста на нашите пристапи.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_ms>Sistem dialog pencarian maklumat, termasuk pengenalan pengetahuan dan generasi balas, bertujuan untuk menjawab kepada pengguna dengan balasan fluent, konsisten, dan maklumat berdasarkan keperluan pengguna, yang. Untuk menangani cabaran ini, kami menggunakan kaedah peningkatan data dan beberapa teknik latihan dengan model bahasa yang dilatih-dilatih untuk belajar corak umum tugas dan dengan itu mencapai prestasi yang berjanji. Dalam pertandingan DialDoc21, sistem kami mencapai skor 74.95 F1 dan skor 60.74 Persamaan Tepat dalam subtanya 1, dan skor 37.72 SacreBLEU dalam subtanya 2. Analisis empirik diberikan untuk menjelaskan keefektivitas pendekatan kita.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>Information-seeking dialogue systems, including knowledge identification and response generation, aim to respond to users with fluent, coherent, and informative responses based on users' needs, which.  ഈ ചോദ്യത്തെ എതിര്‍ക്കാന്‍ വേണ്ടി, നമ്മള്‍ ഡേറ്റാ കൂട്ടുന്നതിന്റെ രീതികളും പല പരിശീലിപ്പിക്കുന്ന രീതികളും ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു. മുന്‍പരിശീലന ഭാ ഡയല്‍ഡോക്ടറില്‍ ഞങ്ങളുടെ സിസ്റ്റത്തില്‍ 74. 95 F1 സ്കോര്‍ നേടിയിരുന്നു. 60. 74 എക്സ്ക്സ് മാച്ച് സ്കോര്‍ സൌബ്ബസ് 1, 37. 72 സാക്രീബില്ലൂ സ് നമ്മുടെ സമ്പ്രദാനങ്ങളുടെ പ്രഭാവം വിശദീകരിക്കാന്‍ ശ്രമിക്കുന്നു.</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Is-sistemi ta’ djalogu għat-tfittxija tal-informazzjoni, inklużi l-identifikazzjoni tal-għarfien u l-ġenerazzjoni tar-rispons, għandhom l-għan li jirrispondu għall-utenti bi tweġibiet fluwenti, koerenti u informativi bbażati fuq il-ħtiġijiet tal-utenti, li. Biex nindirizzaw din l-isfida, a ħna nużaw metodi ta’ żieda fid-dejta u diversi tekniki ta’ taħriġ bil-mudelli lingwistiċi mħarrġa minn qabel biex nitgħallmu xejra ġenerali tal-kompitu u b’hekk inkisbu prestazzjoni promettenti. Fil-kompetizzjoni DialDoc21, is-sistema tagħna kisbet 74.95 punteġġ F1 u 60.74 punteġġ Exact Match fis-sottomistoqsija 1, u 37.72 punteġġ SacreBLEU fis-sottomistoqsija 2. Empirical analysis is provided to explain the effectiveness of our approaches.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Мэдээлэл хайж буй диалог системүүд, мэдлэг тодорхойлолт, хариу үйлдвэрлэл, хэрэглэгчийн хэрэгцээнд үндсэн шингэн, нийгмийн, мэдээллийн хариу үйлдвэрлэлтэй хэрэглэгчид хариу өгөх зорилго юм. Энэ сорилтыг зогсоохын тулд бид өгөгдлийн нэмэлт арга болон олон сургалтын техникуудыг өмнө сургалтын хэл загвараар ашиглаж, ажлын ерөнхий загварыг суралцаж, тэгэхээр амлалтай үйл ажиллагааг гаргаж DialDoc21 өрсөлдөөнд бидний систем 74.95 F1 оноо, 60.74 Дуудлалтын 1 оноо, 37.72 Дуудлалтын 2 оноо гарсан. Эзэмшигийн шинжилгээ бидний ойлголтын үр дүнг тайлбарлахын тулд өгсөн.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_pl>Systemy dialogu poszukującego informacji, w tym identyfikacja wiedzy i generowanie odpowiedzi, mają na celu reagowanie na użytkowników w płynnych, spójnych i informacyjnych odpowiedziach opartych na potrzebach użytkowników. Aby sprostać temu wyzwaniu, wykorzystujemy metody powiększania danych i kilka technik szkoleniowych za pomocą wstępnie przeszkolonych modeli językowych, aby nauczyć się ogólnego wzorca zadania i tym samym osiągnąć obiecujące wyniki. W konkursie DialDoc21 nasz system osiągnął wynik 74.95 F1 i 60.74 Exact Match w podzadaniu 1, a 37.72 SacreBLEU w podzadaniu 2. Przeprowadzono analizę empiryczną, aby wyjaśnić skuteczność naszych podejść.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>Informasjonssøkingsdialogsystemet, inkludert kunnskap identifisering og svar, mål å svara til brukarar med flukt, koherent og informativ svar basert på brukarane treng, som. For å løyse denne utfordringen, bruker vi dataaugmentasjon-metodar og fleire treningsteknikk med dei føretrengte språk-modelane for å lære eit generell mønster på oppgåva og derfor oppnår det promiserende utvikling. I konkurransen DialDoc21 fikk systemet vårt 74,95 F1-poeng og 60,74 Ekstra treff-poeng i subtspørjing 1 og 37,72 SacreBLEU-poeng i subtspørjing 2. Empirical analysis is provided for explaining the effectiveness of our approaches.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Sistemele de dialog în căutarea informațiilor, inclusiv identificarea cunoștințelor și generarea de răspunsuri, urmăresc să răspundă utilizatorilor cu răspunsuri fluente, coerente și informative bazate pe nevoile utilizatorilor, care. Pentru a face față acestei provocări, utilizăm metode de mărire a datelor și mai multe tehnici de instruire cu modele lingvistice pre-instruite pentru a învăța un model general al sarcinii și, astfel, pentru a obține performanțe promițătoare. În cadrul competiției DialDoc21, sistemul nostru a obținut scorul F1 74.95 și scorul Match Exact 60.74 în subactivitatea 1 și scorul SacreBLEU 37.72 în subactivitatea 2. Analiza empirică este furnizată pentru a explica eficacitatea abordărilor noastre.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_ka>ინფორმაციის ძებნა დიალოგის სისტემი, რომელიც ცნობიერების ინდენტიფიკაცია და რეაქტის განვითარება, მინდომის გარეგენება მომხმარებისთვის, მუშაობელი, მუშაობელი და ინფორმაციური ამ გამოცდილების გარეშე, ჩვენ გამოყენებთ მონაცემების აგგენტირების მეტოვებით და რამდენიმე განსწავლების ტექნოგიები პროგრამეტრებული ენის მოდელთან დავისწავლოთ საერთო მოდელს საქმე DialDoc21 კონსპენტირებაში ჩვენი სისტემა 74,95 F1 წერტილი და 60.74 წერტილი წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წერტილის წ იმპერიკალური ანალიზია, რომელიც გაახსნა ჩვენი წარმოდგენების ეფექტიურობა.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_so>nidaamka macluumaadka raadinta, kuwaas oo ku jira aqoonta iyo dhaqdhaqaalaha jawaabta aqoonta, waxaa loola jeedaa in ay ka jawaabaan isticmaalayaasha oo ay leeyihiin jawaabo faa’iido leh, wadajir iyo jawaabo macluumaad ku saabsan baahida isticmaalayaasha. Si aan u tacliino dhibaatadan, waxaynu u isticmaalnaa qaabab kordhiska macluumaadka iyo qaabab waxbarasho ah, qaababka afka hore oo la bartay si aan u barto qaab caadi ah oo shaqada u barto, sidaas darteed waxaynu gaadhnaa qaab ballan ah. Dagaalka DialDoc21, nidaamkayagii wuxuu gaadhay 74.95 F1 score iyo 60.74 Exact Match score subtas 1, iyo 37.72 SacreBLEU score subaxda 2. Analyska shahaadada waxaa la siiyaa in uu caddeeyo awoodda qaababkayaga.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Informationssökande dialogsystem, inklusive kunskapsidentifiering och responsgenerering, syftar till att svara användarna med flytande, sammanhängande och informativa svar baserade på användarnas behov, vilka. För att ta itu med denna utmaning använder vi dataförstärkningsmetoder och flera utbildningstekniker tillsammans med de förintränade språkmodellerna för att lära oss ett generellt mönster av uppgiften och därmed uppnå lovande resultat. I DialDoc21 tävlingen uppnådde vårt system 74,95 F1 poäng och 60,74 Exact Match poäng i subaktivitet 1, och 37,72 SacreBLEU poäng i subaktivitet 2. Empirisk analys tillhandahålls för att förklara effektiviteten av våra tillvägagångssätt.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_kk>Мәліметті іздеу диалог жүйелері, мәліметті идентификациялау мен жауап беру жүйелерін қоса, пайдаланушылардың қажеттеріне негізделген тәжірибелі, тәжірибелі, мәліметті жауап Бұл өзгерістерді өзгерту үшін біз деректерді көбейту әдістерін және бірнеше оқыту әдістерін алдындағы тіл үлгілерімен қолданып, тапсырманың жалпы үлгісін үйрену үшін жұмыс істе DialDoc21 конкуренциясында жүйеміз 74,95 F1 нүктесі және 60,74 Дәл 1 нүктесі және 37,72 SacreBLEU нүктесі 2 нүктесі. Эмпериялық анализ біздің жағдайларымыздың ең әсер етілігін түсіндіру үшін қолданылады.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ta>தகவல் தேடும் உரையாடல் முறைமைகள், அறிவு அடையாளம் மற்றும் பதில் உருவாக்கத்தையும் சேர்த்து, பயனர்களின் தேவைகளை அடிப்படையில் பயனீட்டாளர்களுக இந்த சவால்களை எதிர்பார்க்க, நாம் தரவு கூட்டுதல் முறைமைகளையும் பல பயிற்சி தொழில்நுட்பத்தையும் பயன்படுத்தி பணியின் பொதுவான மாதிரியையு DialDoc21 போட்டியில், எங்கள் கணினி 74. 95 F1 புள்ளியை அடைந்தது மற்றும் 60. 74 Exact Match score in subtask 1, and 37. 72 SacreBLEU score in subtask 2. எங்கள் வழிமுறைகளின் விளைவை விளக்க வேண்டும் எம்பிரியல் ஆய்வு வழங்கப்பட்டது.</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_sr>Sistemi dijaloga za traženje informacija, uključujući identifikaciju znanja i generaciju odgovora, ciljevi su da odgovore na korisnike sa tekućim, saslušnim i informativnim odgovorima na temelju potreba korisnika, koji su. Da bi se riješili ovaj izazov, iskoristili smo metode povećanja podataka i nekoliko tehnika obuke sa predobučenim jezičkim modelima da naučimo općeg obrazaca zadatka i tako postignemo obećavajuću provedbu. U konkurenciji DialDoc21, naš sistem je postigao 74,95 F1 rezultat i 60,74 tačni rezultat Match u podpitanju 1, i 37,72 rezultat SacreBLEU u podpitanju 2. Empirička analiza je pružena kako bi objasnila učinkovitost naših pristupa.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_ur>سمجھانے کی شناسایی اور جواب کی نسل کے شامل اطلاعات تلاش کرنے والی دیالوگ سیستموں کے جواب دینے کا ارادہ ہے کہ کارساز کی نیازوں پر بنیاد رکھتے ہیں اور ان کا جواب دینے کا ارادہ ہے. اس چال کے ساتھ ہم ڈیٹا افزایش طریقے اور بہت سی تدریس ٹیکنیک استعمال کرتے ہیں جو پہلے تدریس کی زبان مدل کے ساتھ استعمال کئے جاتے ہیں تاکہ اس کام کا ایک عمومی نمونہ سکھائیں اور اس طرح وعدہ کریں۔ DialDoc21 رقابت میں، ہماری سیسٹم نے 74.95 F1 سکوٹ اور 60.74 دقیق مطالب سکوٹ 1 اور 37.72 SacreBLEU سکوٹ 2 میں پائی۔ امپراتیکی تحقیقات ہماری تقریبا کی عمدگی کو توضیح دینے کے لئے پیش کیا گیا ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_si>තොරතුරු හොයාගන්න සංවාදය පද්ධතිය, දැනගන්න සහ ප්‍රතික්‍රියාව ප්‍රතික්‍රියාපනය සඳහා, ප්‍රතික්‍රියාපකරුවන්ට ප්‍රතික්‍ර මේ අභ්‍යානය වැඩ කරන්න, අපි දත්ත විශාලනය විදිහට සහ ප්‍රශ්නයක් විදිහට ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න පුළුවන් භාෂා මොඩේල් එක්ක ප්‍රයෝ DialDoc21 තර්ජනයේ අපේ පද්ධතිය 74.95 F1 ස්කෝර් සහ 60.74 ප්‍රතිශීල ස්කෝර් 1 වලින් ස්කෝර් 1 වලින් ස්කෝර් 1 වලින් සහ 37.72 SacreBLUE ස්කෝ අධ්‍යාත්මක විශ්ලේෂණය ප්‍රවේශනය කරලා තියෙන්නේ අපේ අවස්ථාවේ ප්‍රශ්නයක් තියෙන්න.</abstract_si>
      <abstract_uz>Name Bu murakkab qilish uchun, biz bir necha taʼminlov usullardan foydalanamiz, vazifaning umumiy shaklni o'rganish uchun bir necha taʼminlovchi usullardan foydalanamiz va shunday qilib ishni bajarish mumkin. DialDoc21 rivojlanishda, bizning tizimmiz 74.95 F1 scori va tub vazifa 1 bilan 60.74 Exact Match scori va 37.72 SacreBLEU scorini bir vazifa 2 bilan tugatdi. Empirical analyzer, bizning murakkablarimizning effektligini aniqlash uchun.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Hệ thống tìm thông tin, bao gồm nhận dạng kiến thức và tạo phản ứng, nhằm đáp ứng người dùng với các đáp ứng thông tin đầy đủ, thông suốt, phù hợp và thông tin dựa trên nhu cầu của người dùng. Để giải quyết thử thách này, chúng tôi sử dụng các phương pháp gia tăng dữ liệu và nhiều kỹ thuật đào tạo với các mô hình ngôn ngữ được đào tạo trước để học một mô hình chung của nhiệm vụ và đạt được những hiệu quả hứa hẹn. Trong cuộc thi Diadoc21, hệ thống của chúng tôi đã đạt được hàng 74.95 F1 và 60.74 Exact score in subtque 1, và 37.72 SacreLEU score in subtask 2. Nền kinh nghiệm được cung cấp để giải thích hiệu quả của các phương pháp.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_da>Informationssøgende dialogsystemer, herunder viden identifikation og responsgenerering, sigter mod at reagere på brugerne med flydende, sammenhængende og informative svar baseret på brugernes behov, som. For at tackle denne udfordring anvender vi data augmentation metoder og flere træningsteknikker med de forudgående sprogmodeller for at lære et generelt mønster af opgaven og dermed opnå lovende resultater. I DialDoc21 konkurrencen opnåede vores system 74,95 F1 score og 60,74 Exact Match score i subaktivitet 1, og 37,72 SacreBLEU score i subaktivitet 2. Empirisk analyse leveres for at forklare effektiviteten af vores tilgange.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_bg>Системите за диалог с търсене на информация, включително идентифициране на знания и генериране на отговор, имат за цел да отговорят на потребителите с плавен, съгласуван и информативен отговор въз основа на нуждите на потребителите, което. За да се справим с това предизвикателство, ние използваме методи за увеличаване на данните и няколко техники за обучение с предварително обучени езикови модели, за да научим общ модел на задачата и по този начин да постигнем обещаващи резултати. В състезанието нашата система постигна 74.95 точки във Формула 1 и 60.74 точен мач в подзадача 1 и 37.72 резултата в подзадача 2. Предоставя се емпиричен анализ, за да се обясни ефективността на нашите подходи.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_hr>Sistemi dijaloga koji traže informacije, uključujući identifikaciju znanja i generaciju odgovora, cilj je odgovoriti na korisnike s tekućim, saskaņotnim i informativnim odgovorima na temelju potreba korisnika, koji su. Da bi se riješili taj izazov, iskoristili smo metode povećanja podataka i nekoliko tehnika obuke s predobučenim jezičkim modelima kako bi se naučili opći obrazac zadatka i tako postigli obećavajuće učinke. U konkurenciji DialDoc21, naš sustav postigao je 74,95 F1 rezultat i 60,74 Exact Match rezultat u podpitanju 1 i 37,72 SacreBLEU rezultat u podpitanju 2. Empirička analiza je pružena kako bi objasnila učinkovitost naših pristupa.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>Systemen voor informatiezoekende dialoog, met inbegrip van kennisidentificatie en het genereren van responsen, zijn erop gericht op gebruikers te reageren met vloeiende, coherente en informatieve antwoorden op basis van de behoeften van de gebruikers. Om deze uitdaging aan te pakken, gebruiken we data augmentation methodes en verschillende trainingstechnieken met de voorgetrainde taalmodellen om een algemeen patroon van de taak te leren en zo veelbelovende prestaties te behalen. In DialDoc21 competitie behaalde ons systeem 74.95 F1 score en 60.74 Exact Match score in subtaak 1, en 37.72 SacreBLEU score in subtaak 2. Er wordt een empirische analyse gegeven om de effectiviteit van onze benaderingen te verklaren.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Informationssuchende Dialogsysteme, einschließlich Wissensidentifizierung und Generierung von Reaktionen, zielen darauf ab, den Nutzern flüssige, kohärente und informative Antworten auf die Bedürfnisse der Nutzer zu geben. Um dieser Herausforderung gerecht zu werden, nutzen wir Methoden der Datenauswertung und verschiedene Trainingstechniken mit den vortrainierten Sprachmodellen, um ein allgemeines Muster der Aufgabe zu erlernen und so vielversprechende Leistungen zu erzielen. Im DialDoc21 Wettbewerb erzielte unser System 74.95 F1 Punktzahl und 60.74 Exact Match Punktzahl in Teilaufgabe 1 und 37.72 SacreBLEU Punktzahl in Teilaufgabe 2. Um die Wirksamkeit unserer Ansätze zu erklären, wird eine empirische Analyse bereitgestellt.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>سیستم‌های گفتگوی برای جستجوی اطلاعات، شامل شناسایی علم و نسل پاسخ، هدف برای پاسخ دادن به کاربران با پاسخ‌دهنده‌های مایع، هماهنگ و اطلاعات بر اساس نیازهای کاربران است. برای حل این چالش، ما از طریق افزایش داده ها و چند تکنیک آموزش با مدل های پیش آموزش زبان استفاده می کنیم تا یک الگو عمومی از این کار یاد بگیریم و به این نتیجه انجام قول دهنده را رسیدیم. در مسابقه DialDoc21، سیستم ما امتیاز 74.95 F1 و 60.74 امتیاز مسابقه دقیق در پاسپرس ۱ و 37.72 امتیاز SacreBLEU در پاسپرس ۲ رسید. تحلیل امپراطوری برای توضیح موثیت نزدیک‌های ما است.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>정보를 찾는 대화 시스템은 지식 식별과 응답 생성을 포함하는데 사용자의 수요에 따라 유창하고 일관되며 정보가 풍부한 응답으로 사용자에게 응답하는 것이 매우 중요하다.이러한 도전에 대응하기 위해 우리는 데이터 강화 방법과 몇 가지 훈련 기술, 그리고 미리 훈련된 언어 모델을 이용하여 임무의 일반 모델을 학습하여 만족스러운 성능을 얻는다.DialDoc21 경기에서 우리 시스템은 하위 퀘스트 1에서 74.95 F1 점수와 60.74의 정확한 일치 점수를 얻었고 하위 퀘스트 2에서 37.72 Sacreblue 점수를 얻었다.본고는 실증 분석을 제공하여 우리 방법의 유효성을 설명하였다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Mfumo wa mazungumzo yanayotafuta taarifa, ikiwa ni pamoja na utambulisho wa ufahamu na kizazi cha majibu, unalenga kuwajibu watumiaji wenye ujasiri, pamoja na miitikio ya taarifa kwa sababu ya mahitaji ya watumiaji, ambayo. Ili kukabiliana na changamoto hili, tunatumia njia za kuongeza taarifa na mbinu kadhaa za mafunzo yenye mitindo ya lugha zilizofundishwa kabla ya kujifunza mwelekeo wa jumla wa kazi hiyo na hivyo kupata ufanisi wa kuahidini. Katika mashindano ya DialDoc21, mfumo wetu ulifanikiwa score 74.95 F1 na score 60.74 Match Exact katika jukumu la 1, na vitu 37.72 SacreBLEU katika kazi ya subira 2. Uchambuzi wa kipekee unatolewa kuelezea ufanisi wa hatua zetu.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Informasiesoek dialoog stelsels, insluitend kennis identifiseering en antwoord genereering, doel om te antwoord na gebruikers met vloeiende, koerende en informatiewe antwoordes gebaseer op gebruikers se behoefte, wat. Om hierdie uitdrukking te probeer, gebruik ons data augmentasie metodes en verskeie onderwerp teknike met die vooraf-onderwerp taal modele om 'n algemene patroon van die taak te leer en daarom beloftende uitdrukking te bereik. In DialDoc21 samekoms het ons stelsel 74.95 F1 aantal en 60.74 Ooreenkomstige aantal in Subask 1 en 37.72 SacreBLEU aantal in Subask 2 bereik. Enige analisie is verskaf om die effektiviteit van ons toegang te verduidelik.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_id>Sistem dialog pencarian informasi, termasuk identifikasi pengetahuan dan generasi respon, bertujuan untuk merespon kepada pengguna dengan respon fluent, koherent, dan informatif berdasarkan kebutuhan pengguna, yang. Untuk mengatasi tantangan ini, kami menggunakan metode peningkatan data dan beberapa teknik pelatihan dengan model bahasa yang terlatih sebelumnya untuk belajar pola umum tugas dan demikian mencapai prestasi yang berjanji. In DialDoc21 competition, our system achieved 74.95 F1 score and 60.74 Exact Match score in subtask 1, and 37.72 SacreBLEU score in subtask 2.  Analisi kerajaan diberikan untuk menjelaskan efektivitas pendekatan kita.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_tr>Bilim tanamak we jogap döredilmesinde maglumatlar gözleýän dijalog sistemleri, isleýän, howply we informasiýa jogaplary ulananlaryň ihtiyaçlaryna daýanýan netijesine jogap bermek niýetlenýär. Bu kynçylyky çözmek üçin, biz veri üýtgetmek metodlaryny we öňünden öňünden bilim sistemasy nusgalaryny öwrenmek üçin birnäçe bilim metodlaryny ulanýarys we şonuň üçin söz berýän zadyny başarmaýarys. DialDoc21 ýaryşykçylykda sistemamyz 74,95 F1 अ we 60,74 Iň üstünde edilen nokatlary subtask 1 we 37,72 SacreBLEU nokatlary subtask 2-de ýetdi. Impirik analyzasy biziň golaýlarymyzyň etkinliýetini düşündirmek üçin berilýär.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>የመረጃ ምርጫዎች፣ እውቀት ማግኘት እና መልዕክት ትውልድ፣ በተጠቃሚ፣ በተጨማሪም እና የመረጃ መልዕክቶች በመጠቀም ለሚጠቃሚዎች ጥያቄዎችን ለመመልስ ይችላሉ፡፡ ይህንን ጥቃት ለመቀናቀል፣ ዳታ ማደጋገሚያ እና ብዙ ተማሪዎችን የቋንቋ ምሳሌዎችን ለመማር እና ስለዚህም ተስፋ የሚያደርገውን ስርዓት ለማግኘት እናስፈልጋለን፡፡ በDialDoc21 ተቃውሞ፣ ስርዓታችን 74.95 F1 score እና 60.74 ውጤታዊ ማስታወሻ score 1 እና 37.72 SacreBLEU score. የግንኙነታችንን ውጤት ለመግለጽ የሚችል ትርጓሜ ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_az>İstifadəçilərin ehtiyaçlarına dayanan, istifadəçilərin istifadəçilərin istifadəçilərinin istifadəçilərinə tərəf verilməsi haqqında məlumat istəyirlər. Bu çətinliklə çəkilmək üçün, məlumatları artırmaq metodlarını və əvvəlcə təhsil edilmiş dil modellərini öyrənmək üçün çoxlu təhsil metodlarını istifadə edirik və buna görə də vəd verici performansını başa düşərik. DialDoc21 müharibəsində, sistemimiz 74,95 F1 score və 60.74 Əksinə 1-dən istisna müharibə score və 37.72 SacreBLEU score 2-dən istisna oldu. İmpariki analizi bizim yaxınlıqlarımızın etkinliğini açıqlamaq üçün təmin edilir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bn>তথ্য অনুসন্ধানের ডায়ালগ সিস্টেম, যার মধ্যে জ্ঞান পরিচয় এবং প্রতিক্রিয়া প্রজন্ম রয়েছে, তার লক্ষ্য হচ্ছে ব্যবহারকারীদের ফ্লায়েন্স, সাথ এই চ্যালেঞ্জের মুখোমুখি হওয়ার জন্য আমরা ডাটা বাড়ানোর পদ্ধতি এবং বেশ কিছু প্রশিক্ষণের পূর্ব প্রশিক্ষিত ভাষার মডেল ব্যবহার করি কাজের একটি সাধারণ প ডায়ালড২১-এ আমাদের সিস্টেম ৭৪. ৯৫ এফ১ স্কোর অর্জন করেছে এবং সাববাজ ১-এ ৬০. আমাদের পদক্ষেপের কার্যক্রম ব্যাখ্যা করার জন্য সামাজিক বিশ্লেষণ প্রদান করা হয়েছে।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_bs>Sistemi dijaloga koji traže informacije, uključujući identifikaciju znanja i generaciju odgovora, ciljevi su odgovoriti na korisnike sa tekućim, saslušnim i informativnim odgovorima na temelju potreba korisnika, koji su. Da bi se riješili ovaj izazov, iskoristili smo metode povećanja podataka i nekoliko tehnika obuke sa predobučenim jezičkim modelima kako bi se naučili opći obrazac zadatka i tako postigli obećavajući učinak. U konkurenciji DialDoc21, naš sistem je postigao 74,95 F1 rezultat i 60,74 Pravi rezultat Match u podpitanju 1 i 37,72 rezultat SacreBLEU u podpitanju 2. Empirička analiza je pružena kako bi objasnila učinkovitost naših pristupa.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>Els sistemes de diàleg que busquen informació, incloent la identificació del coneixement i la generació de resposta, tenen l'objectiu de respondre als usuaris amb respostes fluides, coherents i informatives basades en les necessitats dels usuaris, que. To tackle this challenge, we utilize data augmentation methods and several training techniques with the pre-trained language models to learn a general pattern of the task and thus achieve promising performance.  En la competició DialDoc21, el nostre sistema va aconseguir 74,95 puntuacions F1 i 60,74 puntuacions Exact Match a la subtanya 1, i 37,72 puntuacions SacreBLEU a la subtanya 2. Es proporciona anàlisi empírica per explicar l'eficacia dels nostres enfocaments.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_sq>Sistemet e dialogut për kërkimin e informacionit, duke përfshirë identifikimin e njohurive dhe gjenerimin e përgjigjeve, synojnë t'u përgjigjen përdoruesve me përgjigje fluente, koherente dhe informative bazuar në nevojat e përdoruesve, të cilat. To tackle this challenge, we utilize data augmentation methods and several training techniques with the pre-trained language models to learn a general pattern of the task and thus achieve promising performance.  Në konkurrimin DialDoc21, sistemi ynë arriti 74.95 pikë F1 dhe 60.74 pikë Exact Match në nënpyetjen 1 dhe 37.72 pikë SacreBLEU në nënpyetjen 2. Analiza perandore jepet për të shpjeguar efektshmërinë e qasjeve tona.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_et>Teabepõhise dialoogi süsteemide, sealhulgas teadmiste tuvastamise ja reageerimise loomise eesmärk on reageerida kasutajatele sujuva, sidusa ja informatiivse vastusega, mis põhineb kasutajate vajadustel. Selle väljakutse lahendamiseks kasutame andmete suurendamise meetodeid ja mitmeid koolitusmeetodeid eelõpetatud keelemudelitega, et õppida ülesande üldist mustrit ja saavutada seeläbi paljulubav tulemus. DialDoc21 võistlusel saavutas meie süsteem 1. alamülesandes 74,95 F1 skoori ja 60,74 täpse mängu skoori ja 2. alamülesandes 37,72 SacreBLEU skoori. Meie lähenemisviiside tõhususe selgitamiseks on esitatud empiiriline analüüs.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_hy>Ինֆորմացիայի փնտրող հաղորդակցման համակարգերը, ներառյալ գիտելիքների հայտնաբերումը և արձագանքը ստեղծելը, նպատակում են արձագանքել օգտագործողներին ճկուն, համապատասխանատու և տեղեկատվական արձագանքներով, հիմնված օգ To tackle this challenge, we utilize data augmentation methods and several training techniques with the pre-trained language models to learn a general pattern of the task and thus achieve promising performance.  In DialDoc21 competition, our system achieved 74.95 F1 score and 60.74 Exact Match score in subtask 1, and 37.72 SacreBLEU score in subtask 2.  Իմպրիկական վերլուծությունը տրամադրվում է բացատրելու համար մեր մոտեցումների արդյունավետությունը:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_cs>Systémy dialogu pro hledání informací, včetně identifikace znalostí a generování reakcí, mají za cíl reagovat uživatelům plynulými, soudržnými a informačními reakcemi založenými na potřebách uživatelů, což je. K řešení této výzvy používáme metody rozšíření dat a několik tréninkových technik s předškolenými jazykovými modely, abychom se naučili obecný vzorec úkolu a tím dosáhli slibného výkonu. V soutěži DialDoc21 náš systém dosáhl 74.95 F1 skóre a 60.74 Exact Match skóre v podúkolu 1 a 37.72 SacreBLEU skóre v podúkolu 2. Pro vysvětlení efektivity našich přístupů je provedena empirická analýza.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Tiedonhakujärjestelmien, mukaan lukien tiedon tunnistaminen ja vastausten tuottaminen, tavoitteena on vastata käyttäjiin sujuvalla, johdonmukaisella ja informatiivisella tavalla, joka perustuu käyttäjien tarpeisiin. Haasteeseen vastaamiseksi hyödynnämme datan lisäämismenetelmiä ja useita harjoitustekniikoita esikoulutetuilla kielimalleilla oppiaksemme tehtävän yleisen kaavan ja saavuttaaksemme siten lupaavan suorituskyvyn. DialDoc21-kilpailussa järjestelmämme saavutti 74,95 F1-pistettä ja 60,74 Exact Match -pistettä alatehtävässä 1 ja 37,72 SacreBLEU-pistettä alatehtävässä 2. Empiirisen analyysin avulla selvitetään lähestymistapojemme tehokkuutta.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>Rasané informasi ngilanggar dialog, tambah nambah keamanan karo jenengan respon, iso nggunakake gambaran karo pengguna sing luwih, sisambang, lan mbuluk informasi sing bisa dianggap mungkar ususi yen. Ngawe nglanggar wih-wih beraksi iki, kita ngubah dhéwé ngerti perusahaan dadi nggawe lan alam kuwi tindakan layanan karo model sing wis antara awak dhéwé, nggawe sistem kuwi nggawe sistem kuwi nggawe sistem sing apik dhéwé. Nang barêng-barêng dialDok22, sistèm dhéwé wis nggawe Puntuan 75.75 F1 lan 60.75 Wanggang empiresi punika dipunangé kanggo ngerasakno kapan kanggo diandelaké awak dhéwé</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_he>מערכות דיאלוג חיפוש מידע, כוללות זיהוי ידע ודורת תגובה, מכוונות להגיב למשתמשים עם תגובות נוזלות, תואם ומידע מבוססות על הצרכים של המשתמשים, אשר. כדי להתמודד עם האתגר הזה, אנו משתמשים בשיטות גידול נתונים ומספר טכניקות אימונים עם דוגמני שפה מאומנים מראש כדי ללמוד דפוס כללי של המשימה ולכן להשיג ביצועים מבטיחים. בתחרות DialDoc21, המערכת שלנו השיגה 74.95 נקודת F1 ו-60.74 נקודת התאמה בדיוק בתשובה 1, ו-37.72 נקודת SacreBLEU בתשובה 2. ניתוח אימפריקלי מספק כדי להסביר את היעילות של גישותינו.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Cilj sistemov dialoga za iskanje informacij, vključno z identifikacijo znanja in ustvarjanjem odzivov, je odziv na uporabnike z tekočimi, skladnimi in informativnimi odzivi, ki temeljijo na potrebah uporabnikov, kar. Za reševanje tega izziva uporabljamo metode povečanja podatkov in več tehnik treninga z vnaprej usposobljenimi jezikovnimi modeli, da se naučimo splošnega vzorca naloge in s tem dosežemo obetavno uspešnost. Na tekmovanju DialDoc21 je naš sistem dosegel 74,95 rezultata F1 in 60,74 točne tekme v podnalogi 1 ter 37,72 rezultata SacreBLEU v podnalogi 2. Za pojasnitev učinkovitosti naših pristopov je zagotovljena empirična analiza.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_ha>Ana nemi tsarin zauren akwatin bayani na bayani, tare da zaɓen bayani na gane da shirin ilmi, don ya yi amfani da wajen karɓa wa masu amfani da masu samu'a da masu sami-sami, da kuma masu jibi ga masu amfani da, wanda. Yana amfani da shiryoyin ayuka da kuma masu tsari masu amfani da shiryoyin mutane da misãlai na zaman-wa'anar harshen na zaman-wa'anar da za'a sanar da wani irin na aikin kuma don mu sami aikin da ake yi musu wa'adi. Daga DialDoc21, na'urarmu ya sami score 74.95 F1 kuma 60.74 Exact Match score in subaikon 1, da 37.42 SacreBLEU score in subaikin 2. Anarari mai Empirical ne dõmin ya bayyana fassarar hanyõyinmu.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>Information-seeking dialog systems, including knowledge identification and response generation, aim to respond to users with fluent, coherent, and informative responses based on users' needs, which. གདོང་ལེན་འདི་ལ་འཐབ་རྩོད་མེད་པར། ང་ཚོས་རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལུགས་ཤིག་བྱེད་སྡུད་དང་། སྔོན་གྲངས་བསྒྲིག་པའི་སྐད་རིགས་མིག་གཟུགས DialDoc21 དཔལ་འབྱོར་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོའི་མ་ལག་གིས་74.95 F1 अིག་དང་60.74 Exact Match score in subtask 1 དང་། 37.72 SacreBLEU score in subtask 2 ང་ཚོའི་གནད་དོན་གཙང་འབེད་ཀྱི་ཞིབ་དཔྱད་ནི་གྱིས་ང་ཚོའི་གནད་དོན་ཡོད་པ་དེ་འགྲེལ་བཤད་བྱེ</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Team JARS : DialDoc Subtask 1-Improved Knowledge Identification with Supervised Out-of-Domain Pretraining<fixed-case>JARS</fixed-case>: <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>ial<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>oc Subtask 1 - Improved Knowledge Identification with Supervised Out-of-Domain Pretraining</title>
      <author><first>Sopan</first><last>Khosla</last></author>
      <author><first>Justin</first><last>Lovelace</last></author>
      <author><first>Ritam</first><last>Dutt</last></author>
      <author><first>Adithya</first><last>Pratapa</last></author>
      <pages>103–108</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we discuss our submission for DialDoc subtask 1. The subtask requires systems to extract knowledge from FAQ-type documents vital to reply to a user’s query in a conversational setting. We experiment with pretraining a BERT-based question-answering model on different QA datasets from MRQA, as well as conversational QA datasets like CoQA and QuAC. Our results show that models pretrained on CoQA and QuAC perform better than their counterparts that are pretrained on MRQA datasets. Our results also indicate that adding more pretraining data does not necessarily result in improved performance. Our final model, which is an ensemble of AlBERT-XL pretrained on CoQA and QuAC independently, with the chosen answer having the highest average probability score, achieves an F1-Score of 70.9 % on the official test-set.</abstract>
      <url hash="10419e05">2021.dialdoc-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.dialdoc-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>khosla-etal-2021-team</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/coqa">CoQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/doc2dial-1">Doc2Dial</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/hotpotqa">HotpotQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/mrqa-2019">MRQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/natural-questions">Natural Questions</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/newsqa">NewsQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/quac">QuAC</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/squad">SQuAD</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/triviaqa">TriviaQA</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/doc2dial">doc2dial</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>