<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.wassa">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-04-19">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the Eleventh Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Orphee</first><last>De Clercq</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Alexandra</first><last>Balahur</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Joao</first><last>Sedoc</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Valentin</first><last>Barriere</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Shabnam</first><last>Tafreshi</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Sven</first><last>Buechel</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Veronique</first><last>Hoste</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="142fa187">2021.wassa-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>wassa-2021-approaches</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="5">
      <title>Emotion Ratings : How Intensity, Annotation Confidence and Agreements are Entangled</title>
      <author><first>Enrica</first><last>Troiano</last></author>
      <author><first>Sebastian</first><last>Padó</last></author>
      <author><first>Roman</first><last>Klinger</last></author>
      <pages>40–49</pages>
      <abstract>When humans judge the affective content of texts, they also implicitly assess the correctness of such judgment, that is, their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confidence">confidence</a>. We hypothesize that people’s (in)confidence that they performed well in an annotation task leads to (dis)agreements among each other. If this is true, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confidence">confidence</a> may serve as a diagnostic tool for systematic differences in annotations. To probe our assumption, we conduct a study on a subset of the Corpus of Contemporary American English, in which we ask raters to distinguish neutral sentences from emotion-bearing ones, while scoring the confidence of their answers. Confidence turns out to approximate inter-annotator disagreements. Further, we find that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confidence">confidence</a> is correlated to emotion intensity : perceiving stronger affect in text prompts annotators to more certain <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classification</a> performances. This insight is relevant for modelling studies of intensity, as it opens the question wether automatic regressors or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_classification">classifiers</a> actually predict intensity, or rather human’s self-perceived confidence.</abstract>
      <url hash="69836997">2021.wassa-1.5</url>
      <bibkey>troiano-etal-2021-emotion</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Disentangling Document Topic and Author Gender in Multiple Languages : Lessons for Adversarial Debiasing</title>
      <author><first>Erenay</first><last>Dayanik</last></author>
      <author><first>Sebastian</first><last>Padó</last></author>
      <pages>50–61</pages>
      <abstract>Text classification is a central tool in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a>. However, when the target classes are strongly correlated with other textual attributes, text classification models can pick up wrong <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a>, leading to bad generalization and biases. In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_media_analytics">social media analysis</a>, this problem surfaces for demographic user classes such as language, topic, or gender, which influence the generate text to a substantial extent. Adversarial training has been claimed to mitigate this problem, but thorough evaluation is missing. In this paper, we experiment with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_classification">text classification</a> of the correlated attributes of document topic and author gender, using a novel multilingual parallel corpus of TED talk transcripts. Our findings are : (a) individual classifiers for topic and author gender are indeed biased ; (b) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Debiasing">debiasing</a> with adversarial training works for topic, but breaks down for author gender ; (c) gender debiasing results differ across languages. We interpret the result in terms of feature space overlap, highlighting the role of linguistic surface realization of the target classes.</abstract>
      <url hash="e5197f67">2021.wassa-1.6</url>
      <bibkey>dayanik-pado-2021-disentangling</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Universal Joy A Data Set and Results for Classifying Emotions Across Languages</title>
      <author><first>Sotiris</first><last>Lamprinidis</last></author>
      <author><first>Federico</first><last>Bianchi</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Hardt</last></author>
      <author><first>Dirk</first><last>Hovy</last></author>
      <pages>62–75</pages>
      <abstract>While <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotions</a> are universal aspects of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychology">human psychology</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/They_(2017_film)">they</a> are expressed differently across different languages and cultures. We introduce a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">data set</a> of over 530k anonymized public Facebook posts across 18 languages, labeled with five different <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotions</a>. Using multilingual BERT embeddings, we show that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotions</a> can be reliably inferred both within and across languages. Zero-shot learning produces promising results for low-resource languages. Following established theories of basic emotions, we provide a detailed analysis of the possibilities and limits of cross-lingual emotion classification. We find that structural and typological similarity between languages facilitates cross-lingual learning, as well as linguistic diversity of training data. Our results suggest that there are commonalities underlying the expression of emotion in different languages. We publicly release the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_anonymization">anonymized data</a> for future research.</abstract>
      <url hash="7bbb2112">2021.wassa-1.7</url>
      <bibkey>lamprinidis-etal-2021-universal</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="9">
      <title>An End-to-End Network for Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction</title>
      <author><first>Aaditya</first><last>Singh</last></author>
      <author><first>Shreeshail</first><last>Hingane</last></author>
      <author><first>Saim</first><last>Wani</last></author>
      <author><first>Ashutosh</first><last>Modi</last></author>
      <pages>84–91</pages>
      <abstract>The task of Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) aims to extract all potential clause-pairs of emotions and their corresponding causes in a document. Unlike the more well-studied task of Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), ECPE does not require the emotion clauses to be provided as annotations. Previous works on ECPE have either followed a multi-stage approach where emotion extraction, cause extraction, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pairing">pairing</a> are done independently or use complex architectures to resolve its limitations. In this paper, we propose an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/End-to-end_principle">end-to-end model</a> for the ECPE task. Due to the unavailability of an English language ECPE corpus, we adapt the NTCIR-13 ECE corpus and establish a baseline for the ECPE task on this dataset. On this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a>, the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">method</a> produces significant performance improvements (6.5 % increase in F1 score) over the multi-stage approach and achieves comparable performance to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">state-of-the-art methods</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="9c5ec302">2021.wassa-1.9</url>
      <bibkey>singh-etal-2021-end</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/Aaditya-Singh/E2E-ECPE" additional="false">Aaditya-Singh/E2E-ECPE</pwccode>
    <title_ar>شبكة من طرف إلى طرف لاستخراج أزواج العاطفة</title_ar>
      <title_pt>Uma rede de ponta a ponta para extração de pares de causa emocional</title_pt>
      <title_es>Una red de extremo a extremo para la extracción de pares de causas emocionales</title_es>
      <title_ja>感情-原因ペア抽出のためのエンドツーエンドのネットワーク</title_ja>
      <title_hi>भावना-कारण जोड़ी निष्कर्षण के लिए एक एंड-टू-एंड नेटवर्क</title_hi>
      <title_zh>所以情者,取之端网络</title_zh>
      <title_ga>Líonra Deireadh le Deireadh le haghaidh Eastóscadh Péire Mothúchán-Cúis</title_ga>
      <title_el>Ένα ολοκληρωμένο δίκτυο για την εξαγωγή ζευγαριών συναισθημάτων-αιτίας</title_el>
      <title_ka>Comment</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Egy End-to-End hálózat az érzelem-ok pár kivonásához</title_hu>
      <title_it>Una rete end-to-end per l'estrazione della coppia Emozione-Causa</title_it>
      <title_ms>Name</title_ms>
      <title_lt>Pabaigos ir pabaigos tinklas, skirtas emocinėms poroms ekstrahuoti</title_lt>
      <title_mk>An End-to-End Network for Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction</title_mk>
      <title_kk>Эмоциялық себептердің аяқтау- аяқтау желіName</title_kk>
      <title_ml>ഇമോട്ടോഷന്‍ - കാരണം പേയിര്‍ പുറത്തെടുക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള അവസാന- മുതല്‍ അവസാനിക്കുന്ന ശൃംഖലംName</title_ml>
      <title_mt>An End-to-End Network for Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction</title_mt>
      <title_mn>Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction Network for End-to-End Network</title_mn>
      <title_no>Name</title_no>
      <title_ro>O rețea end-to-end pentru extragerea perechilor emoție-cauză</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Mreža kraja do kraja za ekstrakciju emocija-uzroka</title_sr>
      <title_so>Shabakadda dhamaadka iyo dhamaadka ee xasuusta sababta qalabka dhibaatada</title_so>
      <title_si>Comment</title_si>
      <title_pl>Kompleksowa sieć dla ekstrakcji par emocjonalnych</title_pl>
      <title_sv>Ett heltäckande nätverk för extraktion av känslor och orsaker</title_sv>
      <title_ta>உணர்வு- காரணத்தால் பேர் வெளியேறுதலுக்கான முடிவு- முடிவு பிணையத்தின் பிணையம்Name</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Emotion-Cause دو Extraction کے لئے انڈی-تا-انڈ نیٹ ورک</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Comment</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Một mạng kết thúc cho đồng cảm bóc ra chúng</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Мрежа от край до край за извличане на двойки емоции и причини</title_bg>
      <title_hr>Mreža kraja do kraja za ekstrakciju emocija-uzroka</title_hr>
      <title_nl>Een end-to-end netwerk voor Emotie-Oorzaak Pair Extraction</title_nl>
      <title_de>Ein End-to-End Netzwerk für Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction</title_de>
      <title_da>Et end-to-end netværk til følelsesmæssig-årsag par udtrækning</title_da>
      <title_id>Jaringan Akhir-Akhir untuk Ekstraksi Pasangan Sebab Emosi</title_id>
      <title_sw>Mtandao wa Mwisho wa Kuishia Kutokana na Kutengwa kwa sababu ya Kumbukumbu</title_sw>
      <title_ko>일종의 단도직입적인 감정 원인 추출 네트워크</title_ko>
      <title_fa>Name</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Emotik-sebäbi çift açmak üçin bir Aç Ahyry</title_tr>
      <title_am>ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_hy>Զգացմունքի պատճառով զույգերի վերջնական և վերջնական ցանց</title_hy>
      <title_sq>Një rrjet nga fundi në fund për nxjerrjen e çifteve të shkaktuara nga emocionet</title_sq>
      <title_af>Name</title_af>
      <title_ca>Una xarxa de final a final per extrair parelles per causa d'emocions</title_ca>
      <title_bn>Emotion-reason Pair Extraction এর জন্য একটি শেষ- থেকে শেষ নেটওয়ার্ক</title_bn>
      <title_et>Emotsioonide ja põhjuste paari väljavõtmise lõppvõrgustik</title_et>
      <title_bs>Mreža kraja do kraja za ekstrakciju emocija-uzroka</title_bs>
      <title_fi>Kattava verkosto tunteiden ja syiden parien purkamiseen</title_fi>
      <title_cs>Koncová síť pro extrakci párů emocí a příčin</title_cs>
      <title_az>Emotion-Cause İki Seçmək üçün End-to-End Network</title_az>
      <title_jv>Name</title_jv>
      <title_he>An End-to-End Network for Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction</title_he>
      <title_ha>Ƙaraɗar Cikakken Bayan Aiki na Ƙasa-zuwa-Kashe</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Omrežje od konca do konca za ekstrakcijo parov čustev in vzrokov</title_sk>
      <title_bo>An End-to-End Network for Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction</title_bo>
      <abstract_es>La tarea de Extracción de Par Emoción-Causa (ECPE) tiene como objetivo extraer todos los posibles pares de emociones de cláusulas y sus causas correspondientes en un documento. A diferencia de la tarea más estudiada de Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), la ECPE no requiere que las cláusulas de emoción se proporcionen como anotaciones. Los trabajos anteriores sobre ECPE han seguido un enfoque de múltiples etapas en el que la extracción de emociones, la extracción de causas y el emparejamiento se realizan de forma independiente o utilizan arquitecturas complejas para resolver sus limitaciones. En este artículo, proponemos un modelo integral para la tarea de ECPE. Debido a la falta de disponibilidad de un corpus ECPE en inglés, adaptamos el corpus ECE NTCIR-13 y establecemos una línea de base para la tarea ECPE en este conjunto de datos. En este conjunto de datos, el método propuesto produce mejoras significativas en el rendimiento (~ 6.5% de aumento en la puntuación F1) con respecto al enfoque de múltiples etapas y logra un rendimiento comparable al de los métodos más avanzados.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ar>تهدف مهمة استخراج أزواج العاطفة والسبب (ECPE) إلى استخراج جميع أزواج الجملة المحتملة من المشاعر والأسباب المقابلة لها في المستند. على عكس المهمة المدروسة جيدًا المتمثلة في استخراج السبب العاطفي (ECE) ، لا تتطلب ECPE تقديم جمل العاطفة كتعليقات توضيحية. اتبعت الأعمال السابقة على ECPE إما نهجًا متعدد المراحل حيث يتم استخراج المشاعر والسبب في الاستخراج والاقتران بشكل مستقل أو استخدام بنى معقدة لحل قيودها. في هذه الورقة ، نقترح نموذجًا شاملاً لمهمة ECPE. نظرًا لعدم توفر مجموعة ECPE باللغة الإنجليزية ، قمنا بتكييف مجموعة NTCIR-13 ECE ووضع خط أساس لمهمة ECPE في مجموعة البيانات هذه. في مجموعة البيانات هذه ، تُنتج الطريقة المقترحة تحسينات كبيرة في الأداء (زيادة 6.5٪ في درجة F1) على النهج متعدد المراحل وتحقق أداءً مشابهًا للطرق الحديثة.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>A tarefa de Extração de Pares Emoção-Causa (ECPE) visa extrair todos os pares de cláusulas potenciais de emoções e suas causas correspondentes em um documento. Ao contrário da tarefa mais bem estudada de extração de causa de emoção (ECE), a ECPE não exige que as cláusulas de emoção sejam fornecidas como anotações. Trabalhos anteriores sobre ECPE seguiram uma abordagem de vários estágios em que a extração de emoção, extração de causa e emparelhamento são feitos de forma independente ou usam arquiteturas complexas para resolver suas limitações. Neste artigo, propomos um modelo de ponta a ponta para a tarefa ECPE. Devido à indisponibilidade de um corpus ECPE em inglês, adaptamos o corpus NTCIR-13 ECE e estabelecemos uma linha de base para a tarefa ECPE neste conjunto de dados. Nesse conjunto de dados, o método proposto produz melhorias significativas de desempenho (aumento de aproximadamente 6,5% na pontuação F1) em relação à abordagem de vários estágios e alcança desempenho comparável aos métodos de última geração.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>感情-原因ペア抽出（ ECPE ）のタスクは、すべての潜在的な感情の条項ペアとそれに対応する原因を文書から抽出することを目的としています。感情因子抽出（ ECE ）のよりよく研究されたタスクとは異なり、ECPEは注釈として感情条項を提供する必要はありません。ECPEに関する以前の仕事は、感情の抽出、原因の抽出、ペアリングが独立して行われる多段階アプローチに従っているか、複雑なアーキテクチャを使用してその制限を解決しています。本稿では， ECPEタスクのエンドツーエンドモデルを提案する．英語のECPEコーパスが利用できないため、NTCIR -13 ECEコーパスを適応させ、このデータセット上のECPEタスクのベースラインを確立します。このデータセットでは、提案された方法は、多段階アプローチよりも著しいパフォーマンス向上（ F 1スコアの6.5%増加）をもたらし、最先端の方法と同等のパフォーマンスを達成します。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_hi>भावना-कारण जोड़ी निष्कर्षण (ईसीपीई) के कार्य का उद्देश्य किसी दस्तावेज़ में भावनाओं के सभी संभावित खंड-जोड़े और उनके संबंधित कारणों को निकालना है। भावना कारण निष्कर्षण (ECE) के अधिक अच्छी तरह से अध्ययन किए गए कार्य के विपरीत, ECPE को एनोटेशन के रूप में प्रदान किए जाने वाले भावना खंडों की आवश्यकता नहीं होती है। ईसीपीई पर पिछले कार्यों ने या तो एक बहु-चरण दृष्टिकोण का पालन किया है जहां भावना निष्कर्षण, कारण निष्कर्षण और युग्मन स्वतंत्र रूप से किया जाता है या इसकी सीमाओं को हल करने के लिए जटिल आर्किटेक्चर का उपयोग किया जाता है। इस पेपर में, हम ईसीपीई कार्य के लिए एक एंड-टू-एंड मॉडल का प्रस्ताव करते हैं। एक अंग्रेजी भाषा ईसीपीई कॉर्पस की अनुपलब्धता के कारण, हम एनटीसीआईआर -13 ईसीई कॉर्पस को अनुकूलित करते हैं और इस डेटासेट पर ईसीपीई कार्य के लिए एक आधार रेखा स्थापित करते हैं। इस डेटासेट पर, प्रस्तावित विधि बहु-चरण दृष्टिकोण पर महत्वपूर्ण प्रदर्शन सुधार (F1 स्कोर में 6.5% वृद्धि) का उत्पादन करती है और अत्याधुनिक तरीकों के लिए तुलनीय प्रदर्शन प्राप्त करती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_zh>情者-所以取 (ECPE) 者,取文档之所以然也。 与穷究之情,取(ECE)不同,ECPE不须以情理为注。 前ECPE之事,或循多方,其情取之,则取配对独立,或杂架构以决其局限性。 本文,我们发出ECPE务的端端到端模样。 无英语 ECPE 语料库,调 NTCIR-13 ECE 语料库,立基线于此集上为 ECPE 。 集上数者,比多术之显著者也(F1分数而6.5%)之,与今相当者也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_ga>Tá sé mar aidhm ag tasc Eastóscadh Péire Mothúchán-Cúis (ECPE) gach clásal-péire mothúcháin a d’fhéadfadh a bheith ann agus a gcúiseanna comhfhreagracha a bhaint as i ndoiciméad. Murab ionann agus an tasc a ndéantar staidéar níos fearr air maidir le hEastarraingt Cúise Mothúcháin (ECE), ní éilíonn ECPE go gcuirfí na clásail mhothúcháin ar fáil mar nótaí. Lean saothair roimhe seo ar ECPE cur chuige ilchéime ina ndéantar eastóscadh mothúchán, eastóscadh cúise, agus péireáil go neamhspleách nó ina n-úsáidtear ailtireachtaí casta chun a theorainneacha a réiteach. Sa pháipéar seo, molaimid múnla ceann go ceann do thasc an ECPE. Toisc nach bhfuil corpas ECPE Béarla ar fáil, déanaimid oiriúnú ar chorpas NTCIR-13 ECE agus bunaímid bunlíne don tasc ECPE ar an tacar sonraí seo. Ar an tacar sonraí seo, cruthaíonn an modh molta feabhsuithe suntasacha feidhmíochta (∼ méadú 6.5% ar scór F1) thar an gcur chuige ilchéime agus baintear amach feidhmíocht inchomparáide leis na modhanna úrscothacha.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>Emotion-Cause pair extraction (ECPE) მიზეზია, რომ ყველა პროცენტური ემოციების კლასოზის ზოგი და მათი კომპორცირებული მიზეზები დოკუმენტში გამოკლება. ECPE არ უნდა ემოციონის მიზეზი ექსტრაქციის უფრო მსგავსი რაოდენობის განსხვავებას, რომ ემოციონის კლასების განსხვავება იქნება. ECPE-ის წინა სამუშაო სამუშაო მოქმედება ან მრავალფეციური მოქმედება, რომელიც ემოციონის ექსტრაქცია, გამოიყენება ექსტრაქცია და ექსტრაქცია გავაკეთება უკეთე ამ დოკუნში, ჩვენ ECPE დავალებისთვის დასასრულებელი მოდელს დავიწყებთ. ანგლისური ენის ECPE კოპუსის შესაძლებლობად, ჩვენ NTCIR-13 ECE კოპუსის აეპორტირებით და დავყენეთ ECPE მონაცემებისთვის ბაზი ხაზი. ამ მონაცემების კონფიგურაციაში, საზოგადომის მეტი გავამუშავებს მნიშვნელოვანი კონფიგურაცია (F1 მონაცემების 6,5%-ის ზომაზე) მრავალფედის მონაცემებით და გავამუშავებს შესაბამი</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Το έργο της Εκχύλισης Ζευγαριών Συναισθηματικών Αιτιών (ΕΚΠΕ) στοχεύει στην εξαγωγή όλων των πιθανών ζευγαριών-όρων συναισθημάτων και των αντίστοιχων αιτιών τους σε ένα έγγραφο. Σε αντίθεση με την πιο καλά μελετημένη εργασία της Εκχύλισης Συναισθηματικών Αιτιών (ΕΚΕ), η ΕΚΠΕ δεν απαιτεί τις ρήτρες συναισθημάτων να παρέχονται ως σχόλια. Προηγούμενες εργασίες για το ECPE έχουν είτε ακολουθήσει μια προσέγγιση πολλαπλών σταδίων όπου η εξαγωγή συναισθημάτων, η εξαγωγή αιτίων και η σύζευξη γίνονται ανεξάρτητα ή χρησιμοποιούν πολύπλοκες αρχιτεκτονικές για να επιλύσουν τους περιορισμούς του. Στην παρούσα εργασία, προτείνουμε ένα ολοκληρωμένο μοντέλο για το έργο ECPE. Λόγω της μη διαθεσιμότητας ενός αγγλόγλωσσου σώματος προσαρμόζουμε το σώμα και καθορίζουμε μια βάση για την εργασία του σε αυτό το σύνολο δεδομένων. Σε αυτό το σύνολο δεδομένων, η προτεινόμενη μέθοδος παράγει σημαντικές βελτιώσεις απόδοσης -6,5% αύξηση της βαθμολογίας F1) σε σχέση με την προσέγγιση πολλαπλών σταδίων και επιτυγχάνει συγκρίσιμες επιδόσεις με τις μεθόδους τελευταίας τεχνολογίας.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) feladata, hogy kivonja az érzelmek összes potenciális záradékpárját és azok megfelelő okait egy dokumentumban. Ellentétben az Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE) jól tanulmányozott feladataival, az ECPE nem igényli, hogy az érzelmi záradékokat jegyzetként adják meg. Az ECPE korábbi munkái vagy több lépcsős megközelítést követtek, ahol az érzelmek kivonása, az ok kivonása és a párosítás önállóan történik, vagy komplex architektúrákat használnak a korlátok megoldására. Ebben a tanulmányban egy end-to-end modellt javasolunk az ECPE feladathoz. Az angol nyelvű ECPE korpusz elérhetősége miatt az NTCIR-13 ECE korpuszt adaptáljuk, és ezen adatkészleten létrehozzuk az ECPE feladat alapját. Ezen adatkészleten a javasolt módszer jelentős teljesítményjavulást eredményez (az F1 pontszám 6,5%-os növekedése) a többlépcsős megközelítéssel összehasonlítható teljesítményt eredményez, és a legkorszerűbb módszerekkel összehasonlítható teljesítményt ér el.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_mk>Задачата на екстракција на парови предизвикани од емоции (ECPE) има за цел да ги извади сите потенцијални парови емоции и нивните соодветни причини во документот. За разлика од подобро испитаната задача на екстракција на емоции (ЕЦЕ), ЕЦПЕ не бара да се обезбедат емоционални клаузули како анотации. Претходните дела на ЕЦПЕ или следеа мултифазивен пристап каде емоционалната екстракција, предизвикуваат екстракција и парење се извршуваат независно или користат комплексни архитектури за решавање на нејзините ограничувања. Во овој весник предложуваме модел од крај до крај за задачата на ЕКПЕ. Поради недостигноста на англискиот јазик ЕЦПЕ корпус, го адаптираме НТЦИР-13 ЕЦЕ корпусот и воспоставуваме основна задача за ЕЦПЕ на овој податок. Во врска со овој набор податоци, предложениот метод произведува значителни подобрувања на резултатот ( „ 6,5 отсто зголемување на резултатот F1 “) во однос на повеќефазивниот пристап и постигнува споредливи резултати со најсовремените методи.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_it>Il compito di Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) mira a estrarre tutte le potenziali coppie di clausole di emozioni e le loro cause corrispondenti in un documento. A differenza del compito più studiato di Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), ECPE non richiede che le clausole emotive siano fornite come annotazioni. I lavori precedenti su ECPE hanno seguito un approccio multi-stadio in cui l'estrazione delle emozioni, l'estrazione delle cause e l'accoppiamento sono fatti in modo indipendente o utilizzano architetture complesse per risolvere i suoi limiti. In questo articolo, proponiamo un modello end-to-end per il compito ECPE. A causa dell'indisponibilità di un corpus ECPE in lingua inglese, adattiamo il corpus ECE NTCIR-13 e stabiliamo una base di riferimento per l'attività ECPE su questo set di dati. Su questo set di dati, il metodo proposto produce significativi miglioramenti delle prestazioni (aumento del 6,5% del punteggio F1) rispetto all'approccio multistadio e raggiunge prestazioni paragonabili ai metodi più avanzati.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_ml>സാധ്യതയുള്ള എല്ലാ വികാരങ്ങളും അവയുടെ പൊരുത്തപ്പെട്ട കാരണങ്ങളും ഒരു രേഖയില്‍ പുറത്തെടുക്കാന്‍ ഉദ്ദേശിക്കുന്നു. Unlike the more well-studied task of Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), ECPE does not require the emotion clauses to be provided as annotations.  ECPE-ല്‍ മുമ്പുള്ള പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ ഒന്നുകില്‍ പിന്തുടര്‍ന്നിട്ടുണ്ട്. അവിടെ വികാരങ്ങള്‍ പുറത്തെടുക്കുന്നു, പുറത്തെടുക്കുന്നതിനാല്‍,  ഈ പത്രത്തില്‍, നമ്മള്‍ എക്സിപെയിന്‍റെ ജോലിക്ക് അവസാനിക്കാന്‍ ഒരു മോഡല്‍ നോക്കുന്നു. ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് ഭാഷ ECPE കോര്‍പ്പുസിന്റെ ലഭ്യമല്ലാത്തതിനാല്‍, ഞങ്ങള്‍ NTCIR-13 ECE കോര്‍പ്പുസിനെ പൂര്‍ത്തിയാക്കി ഈ ഡാറ്റാസറ്റില്‍ ECPE ജോല ഈ ഡാറ്റാസെറ്റില്‍, പ്രൊദ്ദേശിച്ച രീതിയില്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിന്റെ മുന്‍ഗണന മെച്ചപ്പെടുത്തുന്നത് ( എഫ്‌1 സ്കോരില്‍ 6. 5% വര്‍ദ്ധിപ്പ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_lt>Emocijų priežasčių poros ekstrakcijos (ECPE) uždaviniu siekiama dokumente ištraukti visas galimas emocijų poras ir jų atitinkamas priežastis. Unlike the more well-studied task of Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), ECPE does not require the emotion clauses to be provided as annotations.  Previous works on ECPE have either followed a multi-stage approach where emotion extraction, cause extraction, and pairing are done independently or use complex architectures to resolve its limitations.  Šiame dokumente siūlome ECPE užduoties pabaigos model į. Kadangi anglų kalba nėra ECPE corpus, pritaikome NTCIR-13 ECE corpus ir nustatome ECPE užduoties pagrindą šiame duomenų rinkinyje. Pagal šį duomenų rinkinį siūlomas metodas, taikant daugiapakopį metodą, gerokai pagerina F1 rezultatus ( ≤ 6,5 proc. padidėja F1 balas), o rezultatai yra panašūs į pažangiausius metodus.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) тапсырмасының мақсаты барлық мүмкіндік емоцияларды және олардың сәйкесті себептерін құжатта тарқатуға мақсат береді. Эмоциялық себептерді тарқату (ECE) тапсырмасының жақсы оқылған тапсырмасына қарамастан, ECPE емоциялық клауларын жазбалар ретінде келтірілмейді. ECPE- де алдыңғы жұмыс істеген көптеген әдістер көптеген әдістерді түсіруге, түсіруге, біріктіру және біріктіру тәуелді немесе комплекс архитектураларды шектеу үшін қолданады. Бұл қағазда ECPE тапсырмасының аяқтау үлгісін таңдаймыз. Ағылшын тілінің ECPE корпусының мүмкіндігі жоқ себебі, NTCIR-13 ECE корпусын адаптап, бұл деректер жиынындағы ECPE тапсырманың негізгі жолын орнатып тұрмыз. Бұл деректер жинағында таңдалған әдістер көп-этап тәсілінің арқылы көптеген жұмыс істеу арқылы (F1 нүктесіне 6,5% көтеру) үшін көптеген жұмыс істеу арқылы жұмыс істейді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_mt>Il-kompitu tal-Estrazzjoni tal-Pawġi kkawżati mill-Emożizzjoni (ECPE) għandu l-għan li jestrezzjona l-pari potenzjali kollha ta’ emozzjonijiet u l-kawżi korrispondenti tagħhom f’dokument. Għall-kuntrarju tal-kompitu aktar studjat tajjeb tal-Estrazzjoni tal-Kawża tal-Emazzjoni (ECE), l-ECPE ma jeħtieġx li jiġu pprovduti klawżoli tal-emozzjoni bħala annotazzjonijiet. Ix-xogħlijiet preċedenti dwar l-ECPE jew segwew approċċ f’diversi stadji fejn l-estrazzjoni emozzjonali, il-kawża tal-estrazzjoni, u l-parir isiru indipendentement jew jużaw arkitetturi kumplessi biex isolvu l-limitazzjonijiet tagħha. In this paper, we propose an end-to-end model for the ECPE task.  Minħabba n-nuqqas ta’ disponibbiltà ta’ ECPE corpus fil-lingwa Ingliża, a ħna nadattaw l-NTCIR-13 ECE corpus u nistabbilixxu linja bażi għall-kompitu ECPE f’dan is-sett ta’ dejta. F’dan is-sett ta’ dejta, il-metodu propost jipproduċi titjib sinifikanti fil-prestazzjoni ( ≤ 6.5% żieda fil-punteġġ F1) matul l-approċċ f’diversi stadji u jikseb prestazzjoni komparabbli mal-metodi l-aktar avvanzati.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Tugas Ekstraksi Pasangan Penyebab Emosi (ECPE) bermaksud untuk ekstrak semua pasangan-klausul-potensi emosi dan penyebab yang sepadan dengan mereka dalam dokumen. Tidak seperti tugas yang dipelajari dengan baik untuk Ekstraksi Sebab Emosi (ECE), ECPE tidak memerlukan klawsul emosi untuk disediakan sebagai anotasi. Kerja sebelumnya pada ECPE sama ada mengikuti pendekatan berbilang-tahap di mana ekstraksi emosi, menyebabkan ekstraksi, dan pasangan dilakukan secara independen atau menggunakan arkitektur kompleks untuk menyelesaikan keterangan. In this paper, we propose an end-to-end model for the ECPE task.  Kerana tidak ada ECPE corpus bahasa Inggeris, kita menyesuaikan NTCIR-13 ECE corpus dan menetapkan dasar untuk tugas ECPE pada set data ini. Pada set data ini, kaedah yang direncanakan menghasilkan peningkatan prestasi yang signifikan (  6.5% peningkatan pada skor F1) atas pendekatan berbilang-tahap dan mencapai prestasi yang sama dengan kaedah-kaedah-state-of-the-art.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mn>Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) даалгаварын зорилго нь бүх боломжтой сэтгэл хөдлөлийн хоёр сэтгэл хөдлөл болон тэдний харилцааны шалтгаануудыг баримт дээр гаргах зорилго юм. Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE) гэх илүү сайн судалсан ажил эсвэл ECPE нь сэтгэл хөдлөлийн хувьд сэтгэл хөдлөлийн хувьд анзаарах хэрэггүй. ЭКПЕ-ийн өмнөх ажиллагаа нь сэтгэл хөдлөл татах, гаргах, хоорондоо өөрсдийгөө холбогдох эсвэл комплекс архитектуруудыг ашиглан хязгаарыг шийдэх боломжтой олон этапын архитектурыг дагасан. Энэ цаасан дээр бид ECPE ажлын төгсгөл загварыг санал болгож байна. Англи хэлний ECPE корпус болохгүй болохоор бид NTCIR-13 ECE корпус-ыг засаж, ECPE-ийн ажил дээр суурь шугам зохион байгуулдаг. Энэ өгөгдлийн сан дээр санал өгсөн арга нь үр дүнтэй үйл ажиллагааны сайжруулалт (F1 оноо дээр 6.5% нэмэгдсэн) олон этапын арга зам дээр гаргаж, урлагийн үйл ажиллагаатай харьцуулах үйл ажиллагааг гаргадаг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Oppgåva av Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) måtar å pakka ut alle potensielle klauspar av følelser og dei tilsvarande grunnene i eit dokument. I motsetjing av det meir godt studierte oppgåva for Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), krev ECPE ikkje at følelsesklausene skal gjerast som notasjonar. Førre arbeidar på ECPE har anten følgja ein fleire stadige tilnærming der emosjonsekstrahering, forårsaker ekstrahering og pare vert gjort uavhengig eller brukt komplekse arkitektur for å løyse grensene. I denne papiret foreslår vi ein sluttmodell for ECPE-oppgåva. På grunn av ikkje tilgjengeleg engelsk ECPE corpus, tilpassar vi NTCIR-13 ECE-korpusen og oppretter ein grunnlinje for ECPE-oppgåva på denne dataset. På denne datasetten gjer den foreslåde metoden signifikante forbedringar av utviklinga (« 6,5 % økt i F1- poeng ») over fleire stadene tilnærming og oppnår sammenlignbare utvikling med kunstmetodane.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_pl>Zadaniem Ekstrakcji Pary Emocji-Przyczyn (ECPE) jest wyodrębnienie wszystkich potencjalnych para para emocji i ich odpowiadających im przyczyn w dokumencie. W przeciwieństwie do bardziej dobrze zbadanego zadania Ekstrakcji Przyczyn Emocji (ECE), ECPE nie wymaga podawania klauzul emocji jako adnotacji. Poprzednie prace nad ECPE albo przyjęły wieloetapowe podejście, w którym ekstrakcja emocji, ekstrakcja przyczyn i parowanie są wykonywane niezależnie, albo wykorzystują złożone architektury do rozwiązania jej ograniczeń. W niniejszym artykule proponujemy kompleksowy model zadania ECPE. Ze względu na brak dostępności angielskojęzycznego korpusu ECPE, dostosowujemy korpus ECE NTCIR-13 i ustanawiamy bazę dla zadania ECPE na tym zbiorze danych. Na podstawie tego zbioru danych proponowana metoda przynosi znaczną poprawę wydajności (6,5% wzrostu wyniku F1) w stosunku do podejścia wieloetapowego i osiąga porównywalną wydajność do najnowocześniejszych metod.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_ro>Sarcina Extracției Perechi Emoție-Cauză (ECPE) își propune să extragă toate perechile potențiale de clauze de emoții și cauzele corespunzătoare ale acestora într-un document. Spre deosebire de sarcina mai bine studiată a Extracției Cauzei Emoționale (ECE), ECPE nu solicită clauzele emoționale să fie furnizate ca adnotări. Lucrările anterioare despre ECPE au urmat fie o abordare în mai multe etape în care extragerea emoțiilor, extragerea cauzelor și asocierea sunt făcute independent sau folosesc arhitecturi complexe pentru a rezolva limitele sale. În această lucrare, propunem un model end-to-end pentru sarcina ECPE. Datorită indisponibilității unui corpus ECPE în limba engleză, adaptăm corpusul ECE NTCIR-13 și stabilim o bază de referință pentru activitatea ECPE pe acest set de date. Pe acest set de date, metoda propusă produce îmbunătățiri semnificative ale performanțelor (creștere cu 6,5% a scorului F1) în raport cu abordarea în mai multe etape și obține performanțe comparabile cu metodele de ultimă generație.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_si>The job of Emotion-cause Pair Extraction Emotion cause extraction (ECE) ගැන හොඳ අධ්‍යානය කරපු වැඩ වගේ වෙනස්, ECPE අවශ්‍ය නැහැ හැඟීම සම්බන්ධයක් ප්‍රවේශනය විදිහට දෙන්න. ECPE වලින් කලින් වැඩ කරලා තියෙන්නේ විශාල ස්ථානයක් පිළිබඳ විදිහට, හැඟීම් පිළිබඳින් පිළිබඳින්න, සහ සම්බන් මේ පත්තරේ අපි ECPE වැඩේ අවසානයෙන් අවසානය කරනවා. ඉංග්‍රීසි භාෂාවක් ECPE කොර්පුස් ගැන පුළුවන් නැති නිසා, අපි NTCIR-13 ECE කොර්පුස් එක සම්බන්ධ කරලා මේ දත්ත සැටේ ECPE වැඩකට ප මේ දත්ත සූදානයේදී, ප්‍රතිචාරිත විදිහට විශේෂ ප්‍රමාණයක් ප්‍රවෘත්ති කරනවා (  6.5% F1 ස්කෝර් වලට විශේෂ වෙනුවෙන්) විශේෂ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sr>Zadatak ekstrakcije par emocija-uzroka (ECPE) je cilj da izvuče sve potencijalne pare emocija i njihove odgovarajuće uzroke u dokumentu. Za razliku od bolje studiranog zadatka izvlačenja emocija uzroka (ECE), ECPE ne zahteva da se klauzule emocija pruže kao annotacije. Prethodni rad na ECPE-u ili su pratili višefazni pristup u kojem se ekstrakcija emocija, uzrokuje ekstrakcija i parenje obavljaju nezavisno ili koriste kompleksne arhitekture kako bi riješili svoje ograničenje. U ovom papiru predlažemo model kraja do kraja za ECPE zadatak. Zbog nepostupnosti engleskog jezika ECPE korpusa, prilagodimo korpus NTCIR-13 ECE-a i uspostavimo osnovnu liniju za zadatak ECPE-a na ovom setu podataka. Na ovom setu podataka, predložena metoda proizvodi značajne poboljšanje učinkovitosti (povećanje rezultata F1 od 6,5%) na višestadijskom pristupu i postiže usporedbenu učinkovitost sa metodama umjetnosti.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Shaqada guurka (ECPE) waxaa loola jeedaa in uu ka soo bixiyo dhammaan isqabashada labo noocyo ah iyo sababaha ku habboon warqada. Unlike the more well-studied task of Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), ECPE does not require the emotion clauses to be provided as annotations.  Shuqullada hore ee ECPE waxay ku socdaan marxalad kala duduwan, meesha ay ka soo bixiso xisaabta, sababtoo la soo bixiyo, isla markaasna ay isku dayaan ama ay isticmaalaan dhismaha adag si uu u xalliyo xadhiidkiisa. Qoraalkan waxan ku qornaa, waxaynu soo jeedaynaa model ugu dhammaad dhammaadka shaqada ECPE. Sababta a an la helin karo qofka afka Ingiriiska ah ECPE, waxaynu ku habboonaynaa NTCIR-13 ECE, waxaana ku sameynaa shuqulka ECPE-da aasaasiga ah ee ku qoran macluumaadkan. Shaqooyinkan macluumaadka waxaa lagu soo jeedaa qaababka la soo jeedo uu sameeyo hagaajinta horumarinta horumarinta (6.5% korodha kooxda F1) oo ku saabsan qaababka farshaxanka kala duduwan wuxuuna gaadhaa sameynta si siman oo u eg qaababka farshaxanka.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Uppdraget med Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) syftar till att extrahera alla potentiella klausulpar av känslor och deras motsvarande orsaker i ett dokument. Till skillnad från den mer väl studerade uppgiften för Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), kräver ECPE inte att känsloklausulerna anges som anteckningar. Tidigare arbeten på ECPE har antingen följt en flerstegsstrategi där känsloextraktion, orsakextraktion och parkoppling görs självständigt eller använder komplexa arkitekturer för att lösa dess begränsningar. I detta dokument föreslår vi en heltäckande modell för ECPE-uppgiften. På grund av bristen på en engelskspråkig ECPE-korpus anpassar vi NTCIR-13 ECE-korpus och fastställer en baslinje för ECPE-uppgiften på denna datauppsättning. På denna uppsättning data ger den föreslagna metoden betydande prestandaförbättringar (6,5% ökning av F1-poäng) jämfört med flerstegsmetoden och uppnår jämförbara prestanda med de senaste metoderna.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>உணர்வு- காரணம் பீர் பிரித்தல் (ECPE) செயல் அனைத்து சாத்தியமான clause- ஜோடி உணர்வுகளையும் அவங்களுடைய ஒத்திருக்கும் காரணங்களையும்  உணர்வு காரணம் வெளியேறுதல் (ECE) மேலும் படிப்படுத்தப்பட்ட செயலுக்கு மாறுபட்டால், ECPE குறிப்புகளாக வழங்க வேண்டிய உணர்வு குறிப Previous works on ECPE have either followed a multi-stage approach where emotion extraction, cause extraction, and pairing are done independently or use complex architectures to resolve its limitations.  இந்த காகிதத்தில், நாம் ECPE பணிக்கு ஒரு முடிவு முடிவு மாதிரி பரிந்துரைக்கிறோம். ஒரு ஆங்கிலம் மொழி ECPE கார்ப்ஸ் இல்லாததால், நாம் NTCIR-13 ECE கார்ப்ஸை ஒப்பிட்டு இந்த தகவல் அமைப்பில் ECPE பணிக்கான மேல்வரிசையை உருவாக்கு இந்த தரவுத்தளத்தில், பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்ட முறைமையான செயல்பாடு முன்னேற்றங்களை உருவாக்குகிறது ( 6. 5% F1 மதிப்பு அதிகரிக்க) பல நிலையின் முறைமையில் ச</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) کے کام کا ارادہ ہے کہ تمام احساسات کے مطابق کلاس جوڑے اور ان کے مطابق دلیلیں ایک دکھانے میں نکالیں۔ احساسات کیسی اخراج (ECE) کے زیادہ عمدہ تحقیق کی کوشش کے بغیر، ECPE نے احساسات کی کوشش کی ضرورت نہیں کی کہ انٹیزوں کے طور پر پیش کیے جائیں. ECPE کے پہلے کاروں نے یا ایک بہت سی مرحلہ کی طرح کی پیروی کی ہے جہاں احساسات اٹھانے کی وجہ سے، اٹھانے کی وجہ سے، اور جوڑانے کی وجہ سے آزاد ہوتی ہے یا پیچیدہ ساختاریوں کا استعمال کرتا ہے کہ اس کی حدود حل کریں. اس کاغذ میں ہم ECPE کے کام کے لئے ایک آخر-to-end موڈل پیشنهاد کرتے ہیں۔ انگلیسی زبان ECPE کورپوس کے غیر موجود ہونے کے باعث ہم NTCIR-13 ECE کورپوس کو اضافہ کرتے ہیں اور اس ڈیٹ سٹ پر ECPE کورپوس کے لئے بنسس لین بناتے ہیں. اس ڈاٹ سٹ پر پیشنهاد کی طریقہ بہت سی مرحلہ کے مطابق اضافہ کرتا ہے (F1 اسکور میں 6.5% زیادہ اضافہ کرتا ہے) اور اس طریقہ کے مطابق مطابق اضافہ کرتا ہے۔</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Hujjatdagi hamma narsalarni ko'paytirish imkoniyatlarini va ularning qisqa sabablarni qoʻshish uchun hamma narsalarni ajratish mumkin. @ info: whatsthis Previous works on ECPE have either followed a multi-stage approach where emotion extraction, cause extraction, and pairing are done independently or use complex architectures to resolve its limitations.  Bu qogʻozda biz ECPE vazifasi uchun oxiriga oxirish modelini talab qilamiz. Ingliz tili ECPE corpusi yetarli emas sababi, biz NTCIR-13 ECE corpusini oʻzgartirib, bu maʼlumot tarkibida ECPE vazifasi bazasining asosiy satrini qoʻllamiz. Ushbu maʼlumotlar tarkibida, talab qilingan usul bir necha darajada bajarish imkoniyatlarini bajaradi (F1 scorini 6.5% oshirish) va bir darajada bir xil qoidaga mos keladi.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Nhiệm vụ của Emotion-Cause pair extremetion (ECPE) nhằm rút ra tất cả các phần tử của cảm xúc và các nguyên nhân tương ứng trong một tài liệu. Không giống như các tác vụ được nghiên cứu kỹ hơn của Emotion Cause extremetion (ECE), ECE không đòi hỏi những điều khoản cảm xúc được cung cấp dưới là chú thích. Những tác phẩm trước về ECPE đã làm theo một cách tiếp cận đa cấp nơi trích xuất cảm xúc, gây ra trích xuất, và kết hợp được thực hiện độc lập hoặc sử dụng các kiến trúc phức tạp để giải quyết giới hạn. Trong tờ giấy này, chúng tôi đề nghị một mô hình cuối cho nhiệm vụ ECPE. Do không có một cơ sở về ngôn ngữ Anh quốc ECPE Corpus, chúng tôi thích hợp NTCIR-13 ECE Corpus, và thiết lập một cơ sở cho nhiệm vụ ECPE trên bộ dữ liệu này. Trên tập tin này, phương pháp được đề nghị hiệu quả có cải tiến đáng kể (6.5=.=) tăng số F1) so với các phương pháp đa giai đoạn và đạt được hiệu suất tương đương với các phương pháp hiện đại.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Задачата на извличане на двойки емоции-причини (ЕКПЕ) има за цел извличане на всички потенциални двойки клаузи от емоции и съответните им причини в документ. За разлика от по-добре проучената задача на извличане на емоционални причини (ИКЕ), не изисква емоционалните клаузи да бъдат предоставени като анотации. Предишни работи по ЕСП или са следвали многоетапен подход, при който извличането на емоции, извличането на причини и сдвояването се извършват самостоятелно, или използват сложни архитектури за решаване на неговите ограничения. В настоящата статия предлагаме модел от край до край за задачата. Поради липсата на корпус на английски език адаптираме корпуса и установяваме база за задачата на този набор от данни. На този набор от данни предложеният метод води до значителни подобрения на ефективността (6,5% увеличение на оценката на Формула 1) в сравнение с многоетапния подход и постига сравними резултати с най-съвременните методи.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Opgaven med Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) sigter mod at udtrække alle potentielle klausulpar af følelser og deres tilsvarende årsager i et dokument. I modsætning til den mere velundersøgte opgave af Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), kræver ECPE ikke, at følelsesklausulerne skal angives som noteringer. Tidligere arbejder på ECPE har enten fulgt en multi-trins tilgang, hvor følelsesudtrækning, forårsageudtrækning og parring udføres uafhængigt eller bruger komplekse arkitekturer til at løse sine begrænsninger. I dette dokument foreslår vi en end-to-end model for ECPE-opgaven. På grund af manglende tilgængelighed af et engelsk sproget ECPE korpus, tilpasser vi NTCIR-13 ECE korpus og fastlægger en baseline for ECPE-opgaven på dette datasæt. På dette datasæt medfører den foreslåede metode betydelige forbedringer af ydeevnen (6,5% stigning i F1 score) i forhold til flertrinsmetoden og opnår sammenlignelige ydeevner med de nyeste metoder.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Zadatak izvlačenja pare emocija-uzroka (ECPE) je cilj izvlačenja svih potencijalnih parova emocija i njihovih odgovarajućih uzroka u dokumentu. Za razliku od dobro ispitivanog zadatka izvlačenja emocija uzroka (ECE), ECPE ne zahtijeva da se klauzule emocija predstave kao annotacije. Prethodni radovi na ECPE-u ili su slijedili višefazni pristup u kojem se ekstrakcija emocija, uzrokuje ekstrakcija i parenje čine nezavisno ili koriste kompleksne arhitekture kako bi riješili svoje ograničenje. U ovom papiru predlažemo model kraja do kraja za zadatak ECPE-a. Zbog nepostupnosti engleskog jezika ECPE corpus, prilagodimo korpus NTCIR-13 ECE-a i uspostavimo osnovnu liniju za zadatak ECPE-a na ovom setu podataka. Na ovoj skupini podataka predložena metoda proizvodi značajne poboljšanje učinkovitosti (povećanje rezultata F1 od 6,5 posto) zbog višefaznog pristupa i postiže usporedbenu učinkovitost s metodama umjetnosti.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_nl>De taak van Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) is om alle mogelijke clausule-paren van emoties en hun bijbehorende oorzaken in een document te extraheren. In tegenstelling tot de meer bestudeerde taak van Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), vereist ECPE niet dat de emotieclausules worden verstrekt als annotaties. Eerdere werken over ECPE hebben ofwel een meerfasige aanpak gevolgd waarbij emotie extractie, oorzaak extractie en pairing onafhankelijk worden uitgevoerd, ofwel complexe architecturen gebruiken om de beperkingen op te lossen. In dit document stellen we een end-to-end model voor voor de ECPE-taak. Vanwege de onbeschikbaarheid van een Engelstalig ECPE corpus passen we het NTCIR-13 ECE corpus aan en stellen we een baseline voor de ECPE taak op deze dataset. Op deze dataset levert de voorgestelde methode significante prestatieverbeteringen op (6,5% stijging van de F1 score) ten opzichte van de meerfasenaanpak en bereikt deze vergelijkbare prestaties als de state-of-the-art methoden.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_de>Die Aufgabe der Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) zielt darauf ab, alle möglichen Klauselpaare von Emotionen und ihre entsprechenden Ursachen in einem Dokument zu extrahieren. Im Gegensatz zu der besser untersuchten Aufgabe der Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE) erfordert ECPE nicht, dass die Emotion-Klauseln als Anmerkungen bereitgestellt werden. Frühere Arbeiten zu ECPE haben entweder einen mehrstufigen Ansatz verfolgt, bei dem Emotionsextraktion, Ursachenextraktion und Paarung unabhängig voneinander durchgeführt werden, oder komplexe Architekturen verwenden, um ihre Grenzen zu lösen. In diesem Beitrag schlagen wir ein End-to-End Modell für die ECPE-Aufgabe vor. Aufgrund der Nichtverfügbarkeit eines englischsprachigen ECPE-Korpus passen wir den NTCIR-13 ECE-Korpus an und legen eine Basis für die ECPE-Aufgabe auf diesem Datensatz fest. Auf diesem Datensatz führt die vorgeschlagene Methode zu signifikanten Leistungsverbesserungen (6,5% Anstieg der F1-Punktzahl) gegenüber dem mehrstufigen Ansatz und erreicht eine vergleichbare Leistung mit den State-of-the-Art-Methoden.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_id>The task of Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) aims to extract all potential clause-pairs of emotions and their corresponding causes in a document.  Tidak seperti tugas yang lebih dipelajari dengan baik dari Ekstraksi Penyebab Emosi (ECE), ECPE tidak memerlukan klausul emosi untuk disediakan sebagai anotasi. Pekerjaan sebelumnya pada ECPE telah mengikuti pendekatan multi-tahap di mana ekstraksi emosi, menyebabkan ekstraksi, dan pasangan dilakukan secara independen atau menggunakan arsitektur kompleks untuk memecahkan batasannya. Dalam kertas ini, kami mengusulkan model akhir-akhir untuk tugas ECPE. Karena tidak tersedia dari bahasa Inggris ECPE corpus, kami menyesuaikan NTCIR-13 ECE corpus dan menetapkan dasar untuk tugas ECPE pada set data ini. Pada set data ini, metode yang diusulkan menghasilkan peningkatan prestasi yang signifikan (  6,5% peningkatan pada skor F1) atas pendekatan multi-tahap dan mencapai prestasi yang dibandingkan dengan metode terbaik.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sw>The task of Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) aims to extract all potential clause-pairs of emotions and their corresponding causes in a document.  Unlike the more well-studied task of Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), ECPE does not require the emotion clauses to be provided as annotations.  Kazi zilizopita kwenye mtandao wa ECPE imefuatilia mitazamo ya viwango vya zaidi ambapo hisia zinatengenezwa, kusababisha utoaji wa hisia, na wanandoa wanafanya kwa uhuru au kutumia majengo magumu ili kutatua mipaka yake. Katika karatasi hii, tunapendekeza muundo wa mwisho wa mwisho wa kazi ya ECPE. Kutokana na kutokuwepo kwa mashirika ya lugha ya Kiingereza ya ECPE, tunabadilisha makampuni ya NTCIR-13 ECE na kuanzisha msingi wa kazi ya ECPE kwenye seti hii ya data. Katika seti hii ya taarifa, mbinu zilizopendekezwa inaleta maboresho makubwa ya utendaji ('6.5% kuongezeka kwa vipindi vya F1) juu ya mbinu za viwanja vingi na kupata ufanisi uliofanana na njia za sanaa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_af>Die taak van Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) is doel om alle potensieele klause-paar van emosies en hulle ooreenstemmende oorsaak in 'n dokument te uitpak. Ongelyks van die meer goed onderwyseerde taak van Emotie Veroorsaak Uitpakking (ECE), verlang ECPE nie die emosie klauses om as notasies te verskaf nie. Vorige werke op ECPE het of 'n multistadige toegang gevolg waar emosie uittrek, veroorsaak uittrek en paar word onvolgens gedoen of gebruik komplekse arkitektuure om sy beperkings te oplos. In hierdie papier, voorstel ons 'n einde-tot-einde model vir die ECPE taak. Dus die onbeskikbaarheid van 'n Engelse taal ECPE corpus, pas ons die NTCIR-13 ECE corpus en stel ons 'n basis lyn vir die ECPE taak op hierdie datastel. Op hierdie datastel produseer die voorgestelde metode betaling effektiviteit verbeteringe ( “ 6.5 % vergroot in F1 telling”) oor die multistadige toegang en bereik vergelykbare effektiviteit met die staat-van-kunstensmetodes.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Detyra e Ekstraksionit të Dyve të shkaktuara nga Emocionet (ECPE) synon të nxjerrë të gjitha çiftet e mundshme të emocioneve dhe shkaqet e tyre korrespondente në një dokument. Unlike the more well-studied task of Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), ECPE does not require the emotion clauses to be provided as annotations.  Previous works on ECPE have either followed a multi-stage approach where emotion extraction, cause extraction, and pairing are done independently or use complex architectures to resolve its limitations.  Në këtë letër, propozojmë një model nga fundi në fund për detyrën e ECPE. Për shkak të mosdisponueshmërisë së një ECPE corpus gjuhës angleze, ne përshtatemi NTCIR-13 ECE corpus dhe vendosim një bazë për detyrën ECPE në këtë set të dhënash. Në këtë grup të dhënash, metoda e propozuar prodhon përmirësime të rëndësishme performancë (  6.5% rritje në rezultatin F1) lidhur me qasjen shumëfazore dhe arrin performancë të krahasueshme me metodat më të larta.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_fa>وظیفه اخراج جفت‌های Emotion-Cause (ECPE) هدف می‌گیرد که همه جفت‌های احساسات و دلایل‌های مربوط به آنها در یک سند خارج کنند. برخلاف کار خوب مطالعه‌تر از اخراج دلایل احساسات (ECE) ECPE نیازی ندارد که کلاس احساسات به عنوان اظهار داده شود. کارهای قبلی روی ECPE یا از طریق چندین مرحله پیروی کردند که اخراج احساسات، باعث اخراج شدن و جفت کردن به تنهایی یا استفاده از معماری پیچیده برای حل محدودیتش است. در این کاغذ، ما یک مدل آخری برای کار ECPE پیشنهاد می کنیم. به دلیل غیرقابل دسترسی یک زبان انگلیسی ECPE corpus، ما Corpus NTCIR-13 ECE را تغییر می دهیم و یک خط بنیادی برای کار ECPE روی این مجموعه داده ایم. در این مجموعه اطلاعات، روش پیشنهاد بهترین عملکرد بزرگی (افزایش 6.5% در امتیاز F1) بر روی طریق چندین مرحله تولید می‌کند و عملکرد قابل مقایسه با روش‌های هنر را می‌رساند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>정서적 원인 추출(ECPE)에 대한 임무는 문서에 잠재되어 있는 모든 정서적 소구와 그에 대응하는 원인을 추출하는 것이다.연구가 많은 정서적 원인 추출 임무(ECE)와 달리 ECPE는 정서 자문을 주석으로 제공하도록 요구하지 않는다.이전에 ECPE에 관한 작업은 여러 단계의 방법을 따르거나 그 중에서 감정 추출, 원인 추출과 배합은 독립적으로 완성되었거나 복잡한 체계 구조를 이용하여 그 한계를 해결했다.본문의 마지막 부분에서 우리는 ECPE 모델을 제시했다.영어 ECPE 자료 라이브러리를 사용할 수 없기 때문에 NTCIR-13 ECE 자료 라이브러리를 조정했고 이 데이터 집합에서 ECPE 작업에 기반을 다졌습니다.이 데이터 세트에서는 다단계 방법에 비해 제시된 방법이 현저한 성능 개선(F1 점수 6.5% 증가)을 가져왔고 최첨단 방법과 비슷한 성능을 실현했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_tr>Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE) nyşanlarynyň has gowy öwrenmeli täblisasy däl, ECPE duýgym klamalaryny duýgym klamalaryny duýgulamak üçin gerek däl. ECPE'de öňki işler duýgularyň a çylygynyň ýagdaýynyň bir multi-staýasynyň ýagdaýyny ýa-da tapylýan, çykarmak we çişelemek bolan ýa-da gaty arhitekturlaryny çözmek üçin ullanýarlar. Bu kagyzda, ECPE işi üçin soňunda bir nusga teklip edýäris. Iňlisçe dil ECPE korpusynyň tapylmadygyna sebäbi NTCIR-13 ECE korpusyny üýtgederis we bu datasetde ECPE işi üçin esasy çyzgylygy çykarýarys. Bu veri düzeninde, teklip edilen yöntemi örän möhüm eserleşmeler gowulaşdyrýar ( “ 6.5% F1 अ' degişlidiginde art ýar) we sungat döwletlerine karşılaştyrylýar.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_am>የኢትዮጵያ አካባቢ ምርጫ (ECPE) የሚችሉትን የዓይነቶች ሁለት ዓይነቶች እና የሚቀጥሉትን ምክንያቶች በሰነድ ውስጥ ለማውጣት ነው፡፡ በተለየ ምርመራው የኢትዮጵያ ውጤት ማውጣት (ECE) በሚያስፈልገው፣ የECPE ስብሰባ ማስታወቂያ እንዲሆን አይፈቅድም፡፡ የቀድሞው በECPE ላይ የሚደረጉት ሥራ፣ የስብሰባ ውጤት፣ ውጤት፣ እና ሁኔታ በተለየ ወይም የተጨማሪው መሠረት ግንኙነቱን ለመፍታት የሚጠቅሙበት የብዙ ደረጃዎች ሥርዓት ተከትሎአል፡፡ በዚህ ፕሮግራም፣ ለECPE ስራ የመጨረሻ መጨረሻ ሞዴል እናሳልጋለን፡፡ እንግሊዝኛ ቋንቋ ECPE ካርፓስ ስላልተገኘ ምክንያት NTCIR-13 ECE ኮፕስ እናስገድዳለን፡፡ በዚህች ዳታሰር ላይ በተፈቀደው ሥርዓት የፍጥረት አካባቢ ማድረግ (F1 score ‹6.5 በመቶ የሚጨመር)› በተለያዩ ደረጃዎች ላይ ይደረጋል፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>ইমোটেশন-কারণ পেয়ার বিদেশ (ECPE) কাজের লক্ষ্য হচ্ছে সকল সম্ভাব্য ক্লাউস-জোড়া আবেগ এবং তাদের সাথে সংশ্লিষ্ট কারণ নথিতে বের করা। ইমোটেশন কারণ বিদেশের (ECE) অনেক ভালো গবেষণা করা কাজের সাথে তুলনা করে ECPE কোন বিরক্তি হিসেবে প্রদান করার জন্য আবেগের ক্ষেত্রে অনুভূ Previous works on ECPE have either followed a multi-stage approach where emotion extraction, cause extraction, and pairing are done independently or use complex architectures to resolve its limitations.  এই পত্রিকায়, আমরা ECPE কাজের জন্য একটি শেষ পর্যন্ত মডেল প্রস্তাব করি। ইংরেজি ভাষার ECPE কোর্পাসের অস্বীকারের কারণে আমরা NTCIR-13 ECE কোর্পাস স্থাপন করি এবং এই ডাটাসেটে ECPE কাজের জন্য একটি বেসেলাইন তৈরি করি। এই ডাটাসেটে প্রস্তাবিত পদ্ধতি মাল্টিমেন্টের মাধ্যমে প্রস্তাবিত কার্যক্রমের উন্নতি প্রদান করে ( এফ১ স্কোরে ৬.</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) işləri bütün potensial hisslərin cüt hisslərini və onların müqayisəsi səhifələrində çıxartmaq məqsədilə məcburiyyət edir. Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE) üçün daha gözəl təhsil edilmiş iş kimi, ECPE duygusal klauzullarını bildirmək üçün tələb etməyə ehtiyacı yoxdur. ECPE'nin əvvəlki işləri ya duyguları çıxartmaq, çıxartmaq və çiftləşmək müstəsna olaraq və ya kompleks arhitektürlərini çəkmək üçün çoxlu fərz tərəfindən istifadə etdilər. Bu kağızda ECPE işi üçün son-son modeli təklif edirik. İngiliz dilinin ECPE korpusu olmadığına görə NTCIR-13 ECE korpusu ayarlayır və bu verilən qutusunda ECPE işinin əsas səhifəsini təyin edirik. Bu verilən qurduğu təklif metodu çoxlu səviyyədə f1 dəyişdirilməsi üzərində möhtərəm performans uzlaşdırmalarını ( F1 dəyişdirilməsi üçün 6,5%-dən art ırmağı ) və sanat metodlarına qarşılaşdırılmış performans yetirir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Zadatak izvlačenja par emocija-uzroka (ECPE) je cilj izvlačenja svih potencijalnih parova emocija i njihovih odgovarajućih uzroka u dokumentu. Za razliku od bolje ispitivanog zadatka izvlačenja emocija uzroka (ECE), ECPE ne zahtijeva da se klauzule emocija predstave kao annotacije. Prethodni rad na ECPE-u ili su slijedili višefazni pristup u kojem se ekstrakcija emocija, uzrokuje ekstrakcija i parenje obavljaju nezavisno ili koriste kompleksne arhitekture kako bi riješili svoje ograničenje. U ovom papiru predlažemo model kraja do kraja za zadatak ECPE-a. Zbog nepostupnosti engleskog jezika ECPE korpusa, prilagodimo korpus NTCIR-13 ECE-a i uspostavimo osnovnu liniju za zadatak ECPE-a na ovom setu podataka. Na ovom setu podataka, predložena metoda proizvodi značajne poboljšanje učinkovitosti (povećanje rezultata F1 od 6,5%) zbog multifaznog pristupa i postiže usporedbenu učinkovitost s metodama stanja umjetnosti.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_hy>Զգացմունքի պատճառով զույգերի արտահանման (EԿՊ) խնդիրը նպատակում է փաստաթղթի մեջ արտահանել բոլոր պոտենցիալ զգացմունքների զույգերը և դրանց համապատասխան պատճառները: Ի տարբերություն էմոցիոն պատճառների արտահանման (EՀԿ) ավելի լավ ուսումնասիրելի խնդիրներին, EՀԿ-ը չի պահանջում, որ զգացմունքների պայմանները տրամադրվեն որպես նշումներ: Անցյալ աշխատանքները, որոնք անցել են ԵԿՊ-ի վրա, կամ հետևել են բազմաաստիճանի մոտեցումներին, որտեղ զգացմունքների վերացումը, վերացումը և զույգը կատարվում են անկախ կամ օգտագործում են բարդ ճարտարապետություններ իր սահմանափակումների In this paper, we propose an end-to-end model for the ECPE task.  Քանի որ անգլերեն անգլերեն Էկպե կորպուսը անհասանելի է, մենք հարմարեցնում ենք ՆԹԻՌ-13 Էկպե կորպուսը և կառուցնում ենք հիմք այս տվյալների համակարգի Էկպե խնդիրների համար: Այս տվյալների համակարգում առաջարկված մեթոդն արտադրում է նշանակալի արդյունավետության բարելավումներ (F1-ի գնահատականների 6.5 տոկոսի աճ) բազմաաստիճանի մոտեցումների ընթացքում և հասնում է համեմատական արդյունավետության բարձրացումների հետ:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ca>La tasca de l'extracció de parells causats per emocions (ECPE) mira a extrair tots els parells potencials d'emocions i les seves causes correspondents en un document. Unlike the more well-studied task of Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE), ECPE does not require the emotion clauses to be provided as annotations.  Els treballs anteriors sobre ECPE han seguit un enfocament multietapa on l'extracció emocional, la causació de l'extracció i el parell es fan independentment o utilitzen arquitectures complexes per resoldre les seves limitacions. En aquest paper, proposem un model final a final per a la tasca ECPE. Gràcies a la falta de disponibilitat d'un corpus ECPE en anglès, adaptem el corpus ECE NTCIR-13 i establezem una base per la tasca ECPE en aquest conjunt de dades. En aquest conjunt de dades, el mètode proposat produeix millores significatives en el rendiment ( &amp;lt; 6,5% increment en la puntuació F1) sobre l'enfocament multietapa i aconsegueix un rendiment comparable als mètodes més avançats.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_cs>Úkolem extrakce emočně-příčinových párů (ECPE) je extrahovat všechny potenciální klauzule-páry emocí a jejich odpovídající příčiny v dokumentu. Na rozdíl od dobře studovaného úkolu extrakce emočních příčin (ECE), ECPE nevyžaduje, aby emoční klauzule byly poskytovány jako anotace. Předchozí práce na ECPE buď sledovaly vícestupňový přístup, kdy extrakce emocí, extrakce příčin a párování probíhají nezávisle, nebo používají složité architektury k řešení jejích omezení. V tomto článku navrhujeme komplexní model pro úlohu ECPE. Vzhledem k nedostupnosti anglického ECPE korpusu upravujeme ECE korpus NTCIR-13 a stanovíme základní základnu pro ECPE úlohu na této datové sadě. Na tomto datovém souboru navrhovaná metoda přináší významné zlepšení výkonnosti – 6,5% zvýšení skóre F1) oproti vícestupňovému přístupu a dosahuje srovnatelného výkonu s nejmodernějšími metodami.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_fi>Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) tehtävän tavoitteena on poimia kaikki mahdolliset lauseparit tunteista ja niitä vastaavat syyt asiakirjasta. Toisin kuin tarkemmin tutkittu Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE) -tehtävä, ECPE ei vaadi emotionaalisten lausekkeiden antamista huomautuksina. Aiemmat ECPE-työt ovat joko noudattaneet monivaiheista lähestymistapaa, jossa tunteiden poisto, aiheuttajien poisto ja pariliitos tehdään itsenäisesti tai joissa käytetään monimutkaisia arkkitehtuureja sen rajoitusten ratkaisemiseksi. Tässä työssä ehdotamme päästä päähän -mallia ECPE-tehtävään. Koska englanninkielistä ECPE-korpusta ei ole saatavilla, mukautamme NTCIR-13 ECE-korpusta ja määritämme ECPE-tehtävän lähtökohdan tälle aineistolle. Tässä aineistossa ehdotettu menetelmä parantaa suorituskykyä merkittävästi (6,5 prosentin lisäys F1-pisteisiin) monivaiheiseen lähestymistapaan verrattuna ja saavuttaa verrattavissa olevan suorituskyvyn uusimpiin menetelmiin.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_et>Emotsioonide-põhjuste paari väljavõtmise (ECPE) ülesande eesmärk on väljavõtta dokumendist kõik potentsiaalsed emotsioonide klauslipaarid ja nende vastavad põhjused. Erinevalt emotsionaalsete põhjuste ekstraheerimise (ECE) põhjalikumast ülesandest ei nõua ECPE emotsionaalsete klauslite esitamist märkustena. Varasemad ECPE-tööd on kas järginud mitmeastmelist lähenemisviisi, kus emotsioonide ekstraheerimine, põhjustavad ekstraheerimist ja sidumist tehakse iseseisvalt või kasutatakse keerukaid arhitektuure selle piirangute lahendamiseks. Käesolevas dokumendis pakume välja ECPE ülesande täieliku mudeli. Kuna ingliskeelset ECPE korpust ei ole kättesaadav, kohandame NTCIR-13 ECE korpust ja seame selle andmekogumi ECPE ülesande lähtekoha. Kõnealuse andmekogumi puhul parandab kavandatud meetod märkimisväärselt tulemuslikkust (6,5% F1 skoori kasv) mitmeastmelise lähenemisviisi puhul ning saavutab võrreldava tulemuslikkuse uusimate meetoditega.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_he>המשימה של חיפוש זוגות רגשות (ECPE) מטרה לחלץ את כל זוגות רגשות פוטנציאליות והסיבות המתאימות שלהם במסמך. בניגוד למשימה המחקרה היטב ביותר של מחלץ סיבות רגשות (ECE), ECPE לא דורש שיספקו את חוקי הרגשות כציונים. עבודות קודמות על ECPE או עקבו אחרי גישה במרבה שלבים שבו החולץ רגשות, גורם לחלץ, וזוג נעשה באופן עצמאי או משתמשים בארכיטקטורות מורכבות לפתור את הגבלות שלה. בעיתון הזה, אנחנו מציעים מודל סוף-סוף למשימה של ECPE. בגלל אי-זמינות של ECPE קורפוס בשפה אנגלית, אנחנו מתאימים את NTCIR-13 ECE קורפוס ולקבוע בסיס למשימת ECPE על קבוצת המידע הזה. במערכת הנתונים הזאת, השיטה המוצעת מייצרת שיפורים משמעותיים ביצועים ( ≤ 6.5% הגידול בתוצאות F1) במהלך הגישה במספר שלבים, ושיגה ביצועים שווים לשיטות המיוחדות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>The task of EMOtion-Proto PAR extract Sing cah luwih akeh luwih basa sing luwih akeh lanjut ning daerahé Emaotoon Cah extract (ESE), macem ESPA ora tau ngomong kapan empatis kanggo ngerasakno tambah. Awak dhéwé éntuk nang ESPA iki dadi akeh akeh Multi-stadigor sing nêmên karo penting, dadi kejahatan, lan ijol-ijolan sing gagar ngomongke or a bisa nguasai architecture sing komplikasi kanggo Resolusi uwong. Nang pemilih iki, kita mudhun model end-to-end kanggo nggawe task ESPA . Akèh hal karo perusahaan kanggo langgambar kanggo ngilanggar pennguasakno , kita ngubah kono nggawe barang nggawe barang nggawe barang para nggawe barang dumadhi OPE sak dataset iki. Nang dataset iki, supoyo nggunakake sistem kang nggawe akeh operasan luwih nyebuturan (6.5% sing paling kanggo kalagayaan puntuan F1) sing ditambah akeh multi-stadium lan iso nggawe operasan kanggo ngerasakno operasan kanggo meh operasan kanggo meh operasan jih dumadhi.</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Naloga izvlečevanja par čustev-vzrokov (ECPE) je izvleči vse potencialne pare čustev in njihove ustrezne vzroke v dokumentu. Za razliko od bolj dobro preučene naloge čustvenega vzroka ekstrakcije (ECE), ECPE ne zahteva, da so čustvene klavzule navedene kot opombe. Prejšnja dela na ECPE so sledila večstopenjskemu pristopu, kjer se ekstrakcija čustev, povzročitev ekstrakcije in združevanje izvajajo neodvisno, ali pa uporabljajo kompleksne arhitekture za reševanje njenih omejitev. V tem prispevku predlagamo celovit model za nalogo ECPE. Zaradi nedostopnosti korpusa ECPE v angleškem jeziku prilagodimo korpus NTCIR-13 ECE in določimo osnovno osnovo za nalogo ECPE na tem naboru podatkov. Na podlagi tega nabora podatkov predlagana metoda prinaša znatne izboljšave učinkovitosti (6,5% povečanje rezultata F1) v primerjavi z večstopenjskim pristopom in dosega primerljivo učinkovitost z najsodobnejšimi metodami.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>The task of Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE)aims to extract all potential clause-pairs of emotions and their corresponding causes in a document. Emotion Cause Extraction (ECE)ཡི་ལས་ཀ་ལེགས་པ་ལས་ལྡན་བྱས་པ་དང་མེད། ECPE་ནི་སེམས་ཚོར་སྟོན་པར་བྱིན་མི་དགོས། ECPE ནང་གི་སྔོན་གྱི་ལས་ཀ་ཚོར་བ་ཅིག་ཡིན་པས་སེམས་ཚོར་འཕར་ཐབས་ཀྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་མང་ཙམ་གྱི་རྗེས་སུ་ཡོད་པས། ཤོག་བྱང་འདིའི་ནང་དུ་ང་ཚོས་ECPE བྱ་འགུལ་ལ་མཇུག་གི་མ་དཔེ་ཞིག་བཤད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། དབུལ་ཡིག་གི་སྐད་ཡིག་ཆ་ཞིག་གི་མིང་བཏགས་པ་དེ་ལས། ང་ཚོས་NTCIR-13 ECE དབུལ་རྩིས་ཡོངས་ལ་སྒྲིག་ཞིབ་ཀྱི་ལས་འགའ་གཞི་རྩོལ་བ་ཞིག་འཛུ On this dataset, the proposed method produces significant performance improvements (  6.5% increase in F1 score) over the multi-stage approach and achieves comparable performance to the state-of-the-art methods.</abstract_bo>
      <abstract_ha>Tayyar da Shirin Hazara da Iron Farawa (ECPA) na aimar ya fitar duk jama'a-biyu na biyu da sabon da ke daidai cikin takarda. @ info: whatsthis Yin aikin da ya gabata a kan ECPA ko kuma aka bi wata hanyoyi na daban-daban multi-daraja, inda za'a zartar da hisãbi, kuma za'a zartar da saurin da sauran, ko kuma a yi amfani da matsakan masu adadi dõmin ya raba tsarin. Ga wannan takardan, Munã buƙata wata misali ta ƙara zuwa ƙara wa aikin ECPA. Dukan ba'a iya sãmun wata nau'in harshen Ingiriya na ECLE ba, sai mu daidaita nau'in NTCIR-13 ECE kuma Mu sami wani bango wa aikin ECPA kan wannan tsari. Daga wannan tsarin database, metoden da aka buƙata, yana ƙara mafarin performance mai girma ('6.5% korya cikin score F1) kan hanyarwa masu multi-daraja kuma yana sãmu mai daidaita zuwa metoden-the-art.</abstract_ha>
      </paper>
    <paper id="11">
      <title>PVG at WASSA 2021 : A Multi-Input, Multi-Task, Transformer-Based Architecture for Empathy and Distress Prediction<fixed-case>PVG</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>WASSA</fixed-case> 2021: A Multi-Input, Multi-Task, Transformer-Based Architecture for Empathy and Distress Prediction</title>
      <author><first>Atharva</first><last>Kulkarni</last></author>
      <author><first>Sunanda</first><last>Somwase</last></author>
      <author><first>Shivam</first><last>Rajput</last></author>
      <author><first>Manisha</first><last>Marathe</last></author>
      <pages>105–111</pages>
      <abstract>Active research pertaining to the affective phenomenon of empathy and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distress_(medicine)">distress</a> is invaluable for improving <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human–computer_interaction">human-machine interaction</a>. Predicting intensities of such complex emotions from textual data is difficult, as these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Construct_(philosophy)">constructs</a> are deeply rooted in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychology">psychological theory</a>. Consequently, for better prediction, it becomes imperative to take into account ancillary factors such as the psychological test scores, demographic features, underlying latent primitive emotions, along with the text’s undertone and its psychological complexity. This paper proffers team PVG’s solution to the WASSA 2021 Shared Task on Predicting Empathy and Emotion in Reaction to News Stories. Leveraging the textual data, demographic features, psychological test score, and the intrinsic interdependencies of primitive emotions and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empathy">empathy</a>, we propose a multi-input, multi-task framework for the task of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empathy">empathy score prediction</a>. Here, the empathy score prediction is considered the primary task, while emotion and empathy classification are considered secondary auxiliary tasks. For the distress score prediction task, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">system</a> is further boosted by the addition of lexical features. Our submission ranked 1st based on the average correlation (0.545) as well as the distress correlation (0.574), and 2nd for the empathy Pearson correlation (0.517).</abstract>
      <url hash="a7e600c1">2021.wassa-1.11</url>
      <bibkey>kulkarni-etal-2021-pvg</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/mr-atharva-kulkarni/EACL-WASSA-2021-Empathy-Distress" additional="false">mr-atharva-kulkarni/EACL-WASSA-2021-Empathy-Distress</pwccode>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>WASSA@IITK at WASSA 2021 : Multi-task Learning and Transformer Finetuning for Emotion Classification and Empathy Prediction<fixed-case>WASSA</fixed-case>@<fixed-case>IITK</fixed-case> at <fixed-case>WASSA</fixed-case> 2021: Multi-task Learning and Transformer Finetuning for Emotion Classification and Empathy Prediction</title>
      <author><first>Jay</first><last>Mundra</last></author>
      <author><first>Rohan</first><last>Gupta</last></author>
      <author><first>Sagnik</first><last>Mukherjee</last></author>
      <pages>112–116</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our contribution to the WASSA 2021 shared task on Empathy Prediction and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_classification">Emotion Classification</a>. The broad goal of this task was to model an empathy score, a distress score and the overall level of emotion of an essay written in response to a newspaper article associated with harm to someone. We have used the ELECTRA model abundantly and also advanced deep learning approaches like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-task_learning">multi-task learning</a>. Additionally, we also leveraged standard machine learning techniques like ensembling. Our system achieves a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pearson_correlation_coefficient">Pearson Correlation Coefficient</a> of 0.533 on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(project_management)">sub-task</a> I and a macro F1 score of 0.5528 on sub-task II. We ranked 1st in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_classification">Emotion Classification sub-task</a> and 3rd in Empathy Prediction sub-task.</abstract>
      <url hash="9a2eaece">2021.wassa-1.12</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="9586d646">2021.wassa-1.12.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>mundra-etal-2021-wassa</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/goemotions">GoEmotions</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Exploring Stylometric and Emotion-Based Features for Multilingual Cross-Domain Hate Speech Detection</title>
      <author><first>Ilia</first><last>Markov</last></author>
      <author><first>Nikola</first><last>Ljubešić</last></author>
      <author><first>Darja</first><last>Fišer</last></author>
      <author><first>Walter</first><last>Daelemans</last></author>
      <pages>149–159</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we describe experiments designed to evaluate the impact of stylometric and emotion-based features on hate speech detection : the task of classifying textual content into hate or non-hate speech classes. Our experiments are conducted for three languages   English, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slovene_language">Slovene</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_language">Dutch</a>   both in in-domain and cross-domain setups, and aim to investigate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hate_speech">hate speech</a> using features that model two linguistic phenomena : the writing style of hateful social media content operationalized as function word usage on the one hand, and emotion expression in hateful messages on the other hand. The results of experiments with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> that model different combinations of these phenomena support our hypothesis that stylometric and emotion-based features are robust indicators of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hate_speech">hate speech</a>. Their contribution remains persistent with respect to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variation_(linguistics)">domain and language variation</a>. We show that the combination of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_(machine_learning)">features</a> that model the targeted phenomena outperforms words and character n-gram features under cross-domain conditions, and provides a significant boost to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning">deep learning models</a>, which currently obtain the best results, when combined with them in an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_ensemble_(mathematical_physics)">ensemble</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="f428f44d">2021.wassa-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>markov-etal-2021-exploring</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="20">
      <title>Creating and Evaluating Resources for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">Sentiment Analysis</a> in the Low-resource Language : Sindhi<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>indhi</title>
      <author><first>Wazir</first><last>Ali</last></author>
      <author><first>Naveed</first><last>Ali</last></author>
      <author><first>Yong</first><last>Dai</last></author>
      <author><first>Jay</first><last>Kumar</last></author>
      <author><first>Saifullah</first><last>Tumrani</last></author>
      <author><first>Zenglin</first><last>Xu</last></author>
      <pages>188–194</pages>
      <abstract>In this paper, we develop Sindhi subjective lexicon using a merger of existing English resources : NRC lexicon, list of opinion words, SentiWordNet, Sindhi-English bilingual dictionary, and collection of Sindhi modifiers. The positive or negative sentiment score is assigned to each <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sindhi_language">Sindhi opinion word</a>. Afterwards, we determine the coverage of the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexicon">lexicon</a> with subjectivity analysis. Moreover, we crawl multi-domain tweet corpus of news, sports, and finance. The crawled corpus is annotated by experienced annotators using the Doccano text annotation tool. The sentiment annotated corpus is evaluated by employing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Support_vector_machine">support vector machine (SVM)</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recurrent_neural_network">recurrent neural network (RNN) variants</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network">convolutional neural network (CNN)</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="32aae211">2021.wassa-1.20</url>
      <bibkey>ali-etal-2021-creating</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="23">
      <title>L3CubeMahaSent : A Marathi Tweet-based Sentiment Analysis Dataset<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>3<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>ube<fixed-case>M</fixed-case>aha<fixed-case>S</fixed-case>ent: A <fixed-case>M</fixed-case>arathi Tweet-based Sentiment Analysis Dataset</title>
      <author><first>Atharva</first><last>Kulkarni</last></author>
      <author><first>Meet</first><last>Mandhane</last></author>
      <author><first>Manali</first><last>Likhitkar</last></author>
      <author><first>Gayatri</first><last>Kshirsagar</last></author>
      <author><first>Raviraj</first><last>Joshi</last></author>
      <pages>213–220</pages>
      <abstract>Sentiment analysis is one of the most fundamental tasks in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a>. Popular languages like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic">Arabic</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_language">Russian</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandarin_Chinese">Mandarin</a>, and also Indian languages such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindi">Hindi</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bengali_language">Bengali</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language">Tamil</a> have seen a significant amount of work in this area. However, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marathi_language">Marathi language</a> which is the third most popular language in India still lags behind due to the absence of proper datasets. In this paper, we present the first major publicly available Marathi Sentiment Analysis Dataset-L3CubeMahaSent. It is curated using tweets extracted from various Maharashtrian personalities’ Twitter accounts. Our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_set">dataset</a> consists of ~16,000 distinct tweets classified in three broad classes viz. positive, negative, and neutral. We also present the guidelines using which we annotated the tweets. Finally, we present the statistics of our dataset and baseline classification results using CNN, LSTM, ULMFiT, and BERT based models.</abstract>
      <url hash="08200ad2">2021.wassa-1.23</url>
      <bibkey>kulkarni-etal-2021-l3cubemahasent</bibkey>
      <pwccode url="https://github.com/l3cube-pune/MarathiNLP" additional="false">l3cube-pune/MarathiNLP</pwccode>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/l3cubemahasent">L3CubeMahaSent</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="26">
      <title>Me, myself, and ire : Effects of automatic transcription quality on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotion</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sarcasm">sarcasm</a>, and personality detection</title>
      <author><first>John</first><last>Culnan</last></author>
      <author><first>Seongjin</first><last>Park</last></author>
      <author><first>Meghavarshini</first><last>Krishnaswamy</last></author>
      <author><first>Rebecca</first><last>Sharp</last></author>
      <pages>250–256</pages>
      <abstract>In deployment, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> that use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech">speech</a> as input must make use of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transcription_(linguistics)">automated transcriptions</a>. Yet, typically when these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System">systems</a> are evaluated, gold transcriptions are assumed. We explicitly examine the impact of transcription errors on the downstream performance of a multi-modal system on three related tasks from three datasets : <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotion</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sarcasm">sarcasm</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personality_test">personality detection</a>. We include three separate transcription tools and show that while all automated transcriptions propagate errors that substantially impact downstream performance, the open-source tools fair worse than the paid tool, though not always straightforwardly, and word error rates do not correlate well with downstream performance. We further find that the inclusion of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audio_signal">audio features</a> partially mitigates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transcription_error">transcription errors</a>, but that a naive usage of a multi-task setup does not.</abstract>
      <url hash="cb4743b9">2021.wassa-1.26</url>
      <bibkey>culnan-etal-2021-ire</bibkey>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/librispeech">LibriSpeech</pwcdataset>
      <pwcdataset url="https://paperswithcode.com/dataset/meld">MELD</pwcdataset>
    </paper>
    <paper id="27">
      <title>Emotional RobBERT and Insensitive BERTje : Combining Transformers and Affect Lexica for Dutch Emotion Detection<fixed-case>R</fixed-case>ob<fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case> and Insensitive <fixed-case>BERT</fixed-case>je: Combining Transformers and Affect Lexica for <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>utch Emotion Detection</title>
      <author><first>Luna</first><last>De Bruyne</last></author>
      <author><first>Orphee</first><last>De Clercq</last></author>
      <author><first>Veronique</first><last>Hoste</last></author>
      <pages>257–263</pages>
      <abstract>In a first step towards improving Dutch emotion detection, we try to combine the Dutch transformer models BERTje and RobBERT with lexicon-based methods. We propose two architectures : one in which lexicon information is directly injected into the transformer model and a meta-learning approach where predictions from transformers are combined with lexicon features. The models are tested on 1,000 Dutch tweets and 1,000 captions from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Television_show">TV-shows</a> which have been manually annotated with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">emotion categories</a> and dimensions. We find that RobBERT clearly outperforms BERTje, but that directly adding lexicon information to transformers does not improve performance. In the meta-learning approach, lexicon information does have a positive effect on BERTje, but not on RobBERT. This suggests that more emotional information is already contained within this latter <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Language_model">language model</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="41d89002">2021.wassa-1.27</url>
      <bibkey>de-bruyne-etal-2021-emotional</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="28">
      <title>EmpNa at WASSA 2021 : A Lightweight Model for the Prediction of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empathy">Empathy</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychological_stress">Distress</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion">Emotions</a> from Reactions to News Stories<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>mp<fixed-case>N</fixed-case>a at <fixed-case>WASSA</fixed-case> 2021: A Lightweight Model for the Prediction of Empathy, Distress and Emotions from Reactions to News Stories</title>
      <author><first>Giuseppe</first><last>Vettigli</last></author>
      <author><first>Antonio</first><last>Sorgente</last></author>
      <pages>264–268</pages>
      <abstract>This paper describes our submission for the WASSA 2021 shared task regarding the prediction of empathy, distress and emotions from news stories. The solution is based on combining the frequency of words, lexicon-based information, demographics of the annotators and personality of the annotators into a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_model">linear model</a>. The prediction of empathy and distress is performed using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_regression">Linear Regression</a> while the prediction of emotions is performed using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_regression">Logistic Regression</a>. Both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Task_(computing)">tasks</a> are performed using the same <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_feature">features</a>. Our models rank 4th for the prediction of emotions and 2nd for the prediction of empathy and distress. These results are particularly interesting when considered that the computational requirements of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solution">solution</a> are minimal.</abstract>
      <url hash="8c2cdbc4">2021.wassa-1.28</url>
      <attachment type="OptionalSupplementaryMaterial" hash="cf823096">2021.wassa-1.28.OptionalSupplementaryMaterial.html</attachment>
      <bibkey>vettigli-sorgente-2021-empna</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>