<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.nlp4posimpact">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-07-25">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on NLP for Positive Impact</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Anjalie</first><last>Field</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Shrimai</first><last>Prabhumoye</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Maarten</first><last>Sap</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Zhijing</first><last>Jin</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Jieyu</first><last>Zhao</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Chris</first><last>Brockett</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>August</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="2a2e6a54">2021.nlp4posimpact-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="4789defb">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>nlp4posimpact-2021-nlp</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>The Climate Change Debate and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a></title>
      <author><first>Manfred</first><last>Stede</last></author>
      <author><first>Ronny</first><last>Patz</last></author>
      <pages>8–18</pages>
      <abstract>The debate around climate change (CC)its extent, its causes, and the necessary responsesis intense and of global importance. Yet, in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">natural language processing (NLP) community</a>, this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_(mathematical_analysis)">domain</a> has so far received little attention. In contrast, it is of enormous prominence in various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_science">social science disciplines</a>, and some of that work follows the text-as-data paradigm, seeking to employ <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantitative_research">quantitative methods</a> for analyzing large amounts of CC-related text. Other research is qualitative in nature and studies details, nuances, actors, and motivations within CC discourses. Coming from both <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_science">Political Science</a>, and reviewing key works in both disciplines, we discuss how social science approaches to CC debates can inform advances in text-mining / NLP, and how, in return, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuro-linguistic_programming">NLP</a> can support policy-makers and activists in making sense of large-scale and complex CC discourses across multiple genres, channels, topics, and communities. This is paramount for their ability to make rapid and meaningful impact on the discourse, and for shaping the necessary policy change.</abstract>
      <url hash="a348fc77">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.2</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4posimpact-1.2</doi>
      <bibkey>stede-patz-2021-climate</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Dialogue Act Classification for Augmentative and Alternative Communication</title>
      <author><first>E. Margaret</first><last>Perkoff</last></author>
      <pages>107–114</pages>
      <abstract>Augmentative and Alternative Communication (AAC) devices and applications are intended to make it easier for individuals with complex communication needs to participate in conversations. However, these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peripheral">devices</a> have low adoption and retention rates. We review prior work with text recommendation systems that have not been successful in mitigating these problems. To address these gaps, we propose applying Dialogue Act classification to AAC conversations. We evaluated the performance of a state of the art <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_model">model</a> on a limited AAC dataset that was trained on both AAC and non-AAC datasets. The one trained on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Audio_Coding">AAC</a> (accuracy = 38.6 %) achieved better performance than that trained on a non-AAC corpus (accuracy = 34.1 %). These results reflect the need to incorporate representative datasets in later experiments. We discuss the need to collect more labeled AAC datasets and propose areas of future work.</abstract>
      <url hash="7dedea7a">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.12</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4posimpact-1.12</doi>
      <bibkey>perkoff-2021-dialogue</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="13">
      <title>Improving Policing with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a></title>
      <author><first>Anthony</first><last>Dixon</last></author>
      <author><first>Daniel</first><last>Birks</last></author>
      <pages>115–124</pages>
      <abstract>This article explores the potential for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing (NLP)</a> to enable a more effective, prevention focused and less confrontational policing model that has hitherto been too resource consuming to implement at scale. Problem-Oriented Policing (POP) is a potential replacement, at least in part, for traditional policing which adopts a reactive approach, relying heavily on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Criminal_justice">criminal justice system</a>. By contrast, POP seeks to prevent crime by manipulating the underlying conditions that allow crimes to be committed. Identifying these underlying conditions requires a detailed understanding of crime events-tacit knowledge that is often held by police officers but which can be challenging to derive from structured police data. One potential source of insight exists in unstructured free text data commonly collected by police for the purposes of investigation or administration. Yet police agencies do not typically have the skills or resources to analyse these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data">data</a> at scale. In this article we argue that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> offers the potential to unlock these <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unstructured_data">unstructured data</a> and by doing so allow police to implement more POP initiatives. However we caution that using NLP models without adequate knowledge may either allow or perpetuate bias within the data potentially leading to unfavourable outcomes.</abstract>
      <url hash="3387a444">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.13</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4posimpact-1.13</doi>
      <bibkey>dixon-birks-2021-improving</bibkey>
    <title_ar>تحسين ضبط الأمن باستخدام معالجة اللغة الطبيعية</title_ar>
      <title_es>Mejora de la vigilancia policial con el procesamiento del lenguaje natural</title_es>
      <title_pt>Melhorando o policiamento com processamento de linguagem natural</title_pt>
      <title_ja>自然言語処理による治安の改善</title_ja>
      <title_zh>因自然语言改警务</title_zh>
      <title_hi>प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रसंस्करण के साथ पुलिसिंग में सुधार</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Póilíneacht a Fheabhsú le Próiseáil Teanga Nádúrtha</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ნაირადი ენის პროცესისთან პოლიტიკაციის უფრო მეტირება</title_ka>
      <title_el>Βελτίωση της αστυνόμευσης με την επεξεργασία φυσικής γλώσσας</title_el>
      <title_it>Migliorare la polizia con l'elaborazione del linguaggio naturale</title_it>
      <title_lt>Politikos gerinimas gamtinių kalbų apdorojimo srityje</title_lt>
      <title_kk>Түзіндік тіл процессорындағы ережелерді жақсарту</title_kk>
      <title_ms>Improving Policing with Natural Language Processing</title_ms>
      <title_mk>Подобрување на политиката со процесот на природен јазик</title_mk>
      <title_ml>സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനപ്രക്രിയയോടൊപ്പം പോലീസ് മുന്‍കൂട്ടുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_hu>A rendőrség javítása a természetes nyelvfeldolgozással</title_hu>
      <title_no>Forbetring av politikk med naturleg språk</title_no>
      <title_mn>Байгалийн хэл үйлдвэрлэлтэй цагдааг сайжруулах</title_mn>
      <title_pl>Poprawa policji dzięki przetwarzaniu języka naturalnego</title_pl>
      <title_ro>Îmbunătățirea poliției cu procesarea limbajului natural</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Poboljšanje policije prirodnim jezikom</title_sr>
      <title_si>ස්වාභාවික භාෂාව ප්‍රක්‍රියාපනය සඳහා පොලිසියට වැඩ කරන්න</title_si>
      <title_so>Horumarinta booliska ka shaqeynta afka asalka ah</title_so>
      <title_sv>Förbättra polisen med naturlig språkbehandling</title_sv>
      <title_ta>இயல்பான மொழி செயல்பாடுடன் மேம்படுத்தப்படுகிறது</title_ta>
      <title_ur>طبیعی زبان پرسس کے ساتھ پولیسی کا بہترین کرنا</title_ur>
      <title_mt>Improving Policing with Natural Language Processing</title_mt>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Tăng cường cảnh xử lý ngôn ngữ tự nhiên</title_vi>
      <title_hr>Poboljšanje politike prirodnim jezikom</title_hr>
      <title_da>Forbedring af politiet med naturlig sprogbehandling</title_da>
      <title_bg>Подобряване на полирането с обработка на естествен език</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Verbetering van policing met natuurlijke taalverwerking</title_nl>
      <title_id>Menembak Kepolisian dengan Proses Bahasa Alami</title_id>
      <title_de>Verbesserung der Policing mit natürlicher Sprachverarbeitung</title_de>
      <title_ko>자연 언어로 처리하여 경찰 업무를 개선하다.</title_ko>
      <title_fa>بهتر کردن پلیسی با پردازش زبان طبیعی</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Dogaty dil işleýişi bilen polisiýasyny gowylaşdyrýar</title_tr>
      <title_sw>Kuboresha Polisi na Utendaji wa lugha ya asili</title_sw>
      <title_am>የፖሊሲ ምርጫዎች</title_am>
      <title_af>Verbeter Polisies met Natuurlike Taal Prosessering</title_af>
      <title_az>Təbiətli Dil İşləməsi ilə polisi yaxşılaşdırma</title_az>
      <title_hy>Բնական լեզվի մշակույթի միջոցով քաղաքականության բարելավումը</title_hy>
      <title_bn>প্রাকৃতিক ভাষার প্রক্রিয়ার সাথে পুলিশের উন্নতি করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_bs>Poboljšanje politike prirodnim jezikom</title_bs>
      <title_cs>Zlepšení policie pomocí zpracování přirozeného jazyka</title_cs>
      <title_sq>Duke përmirësuar politikën me procesimin e gjuhës natyrore</title_sq>
      <title_ca>Improving Policing with Natural Language Processing</title_ca>
      <title_et>Poliitika parandamine loodusliku keele töötlemisega</title_et>
      <title_fi>Polisoinnin parantaminen luonnollisen kielen käsittelyllä</title_fi>
      <title_jv>Gjelongi ipol-ipol sing nganggep Perusahaan langgambar Daerah</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Izboljšanje policije z obdelavo naravnega jezika</title_sk>
      <title_ha>@ action</title_ha>
      <title_bo>རང་བཞིན་གྱི་སྐད་ཡིག་ལས་སྦྱོར་བྱེད་བཞིན་པའི་ནུས་པ་ཞིག་ཡར་རྒྱས་གཏོང་བ</title_bo>
      <title_he>שיפור מדיניות עם מעבדת שפת טבעית</title_he>
      <abstract_pt>Este artigo explora o potencial do Processamento de Linguagem Natural (PLN) para permitir um modelo de policiamento mais eficaz, focado na prevenção e menos conflituoso, que até agora consumia muito recursos para ser implementado em escala. O Policiamento Orientado a Problemas (POP) é um substituto potencial, pelo menos em parte, para o policiamento tradicional que adota uma abordagem reativa, dependendo fortemente do sistema de justiça criminal. Por outro lado, o POP procura prevenir o crime manipulando as condições subjacentes que permitem que os crimes sejam cometidos. A identificação dessas condições subjacentes requer uma compreensão detalhada dos eventos criminais - conhecimento tácito que muitas vezes é detido por policiais, mas que pode ser difícil de derivar de dados policiais estruturados. Uma fonte potencial de insight existe em dados de texto livre não estruturados comumente coletados pela polícia para fins de investigação ou administração. No entanto, as agências policiais normalmente não têm as habilidades ou recursos para analisar esses dados em escala. Neste artigo, argumentamos que a PNL oferece o potencial de desbloquear esses dados não estruturados e, ao fazê-lo, permitir que a polícia implemente mais iniciativas de POP. No entanto, alertamos que o uso de modelos de PNL sem conhecimento adequado pode permitir ou perpetuar viés nos dados, potencialmente levando a resultados desfavoráveis.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ar>تستكشف هذه المقالة إمكانات معالجة اللغة الطبيعية (NLP) لتمكين نموذج شرطي أكثر فعالية وتركيزًا على الوقاية وأقل تصادمية والذي كان حتى الآن يستهلك الموارد بشكل كبير بحيث لا يمكن تنفيذه على نطاق واسع. يعد العمل الشرطي الموجه نحو المشكلات (POP) بديلاً محتملاً ، جزئيًا على الأقل ، للشرطة التقليدية التي تتبنى نهجًا تفاعليًا ، وتعتمد بشكل كبير على نظام العدالة الجنائية. على النقيض من ذلك ، يسعى بروتوكول POP إلى منع الجريمة من خلال التلاعب بالظروف الأساسية التي تسمح بارتكاب الجرائم. يتطلب تحديد هذه الظروف الأساسية فهماً مفصلاً لأحداث الجريمة - المعرفة الضمنية التي غالباً ما يحتفظ بها ضباط الشرطة ولكن يمكن أن يكون من الصعب اشتقاقها من بيانات الشرطة المنظمة. يوجد أحد المصادر المحتملة للرؤية الثاقبة في بيانات النص الحر غير المهيكلة التي تجمعها الشرطة عادة لأغراض التحقيق أو الإدارة. ومع ذلك ، لا تمتلك وكالات الشرطة عادةً المهارات أو الموارد اللازمة لتحليل هذه البيانات على نطاق واسع. في هذه المقالة ، نجادل بأن البرمجة اللغوية العصبية يوفر إمكانية فتح هذه البيانات غير المهيكلة ومن خلال القيام بذلك يسمح للشرطة بتنفيذ المزيد من مبادرات بروتوكول POP. ومع ذلك ، فإننا نحذر من أن استخدام نماذج البرمجة اللغوية العصبية دون معرفة كافية قد يسمح أو يديم التحيز داخل البيانات الذي يحتمل أن يؤدي إلى نتائج غير مواتية.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>Este artículo explora el potencial del procesamiento del lenguaje natural (NLP) para permitir un modelo policial más eficaz, centrado en la prevención y menos conflictivo, que hasta ahora ha consumido demasiados recursos para implementarlo a escala. La Policía Orientada a Problemas (POP) es un reemplazo potencial, al menos en parte, de la policía tradicional que adopta un enfoque reactivo, que depende en gran medida del sistema de justicia penal. Por el contrario, el POP busca prevenir la delincuencia manipulando las condiciones subyacentes que permiten que se cometan delitos. La identificación de estas condiciones subyacentes requiere una comprensión detallada de los eventos delictivos, conocimiento tácito que a menudo poseen los oficiales de policía pero que puede ser difícil de derivar de datos policiales estructurados. Existe una posible fuente de información en los datos de texto libre no estructurados que la policía suele recopilar con fines de investigación o administración. Sin embargo, las agencias de policía no suelen tener las habilidades o los recursos para analizar estos datos a escala. En este artículo argumentamos que la PNL ofrece la posibilidad de desbloquear estos datos no estructurados y, al hacerlo, permitir que la policía implemente más iniciativas de POP. Sin embargo, advertimos que el uso de modelos de PNL sin el conocimiento adecuado puede permitir o perpetuar el sesgo dentro de los datos, lo que podría conducir a resultados desfavorables.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>この記事では、自然言語処理（ NLP ）が、これまで大規模に実施するにはあまりにも資源を消費しすぎていた、より効果的で、予防に焦点を当て、対立の少ない治安維持モデルを可能にする可能性を探る。 問題指向型治安維持（ POP ）は、少なくとも部分的には、刑事司法制度に大きく依存した、反応的アプローチを採用する従来の治安維持の潜在的な置き換えです。 対照的に、POPは犯罪を許容する根本的な条件を操作することで犯罪を防止しようとしています。 これらの根本的な状況を特定するには、犯罪事象の詳細な理解が必要です。これは、警察官がしばしば持っているが、構造化された警察データから導き出すことが困難な暗黙の知識です。 潜在的な洞察の1つのソースは、捜査または管理の目的で警察が一般的に収集する非構造化フリーテキストデータに存在します。 しかし、警察機関は通常、これらのデータを大規模に分析するスキルやリソースを持っていません。 この記事では、NLPがこれらの非構造化データをロック解除する可能性を提供し、警察がより多くのPOPイニシアチブを実施できるようにすると主張しています。 しかし、十分な知識を持たずにNLPモデルを使用すると、データ内のバイアスが許容されるか、または永続化され、不利な結果につながる可能性があることに注意してください。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>本文讨论自然语言理(NLP)之力,以成其效,以豫防为重,与更少对抗性之警务,迄今为止费资源,不可大行。 导者警务(POP)潜也,少者代警务,古者警务用动,甚赖于刑。 比之持久性有机污染物试以操纵为预防犯罪。 立此要须详知罪事 - 常以警察隐性知之,而取于结构化警察数之中可挑战性也。 一洞察所出警方常为勘理所集结构化自由文本数中。 然警察司常不具大数。 本文以为NLP给解锁非结构化数之力,且可使警方行多POP之计。 然吾戒曰,用之不足NLP或许延数偏见,以致不利。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>यह लेख प्राकृतिक भाषा प्रसंस्करण (एनएलपी) के लिए क्षमता की पड़ताल करता है ताकि एक अधिक प्रभावी, रोकथाम केंद्रित और कम टकराव वाले पुलिसिंग मॉडल को सक्षम किया जा सके जो अब तक पैमाने पर लागू करने के लिए बहुत संसाधन खपत कर रहा है। समस्या-उन्मुख पुलिसिंग (पीओपी) एक संभावित प्रतिस्थापन है, कम से कम भाग में, पारंपरिक पुलिसिंग के लिए जो एक प्रतिक्रियाशील दृष्टिकोण अपनाता है, आपराधिक न्याय प्रणाली पर भारी निर्भर करता है। इसके विपरीत, पीओपी अंतर्निहित स्थितियों में हेरफेर करके अपराध को रोकने का प्रयास करता है जो अपराधों को करने की अनुमति देते हैं। इन अंतर्निहित स्थितियों की पहचान करने के लिए अपराध की घटनाओं की विस्तृत समझ की आवश्यकता होती है - मौन ज्ञान जो अक्सर पुलिस अधिकारियों द्वारा आयोजित किया जाता है लेकिन जो संरचित पुलिस डेटा से प्राप्त करने के लिए चुनौतीपूर्ण हो सकता है। अंतर्दृष्टि का एक संभावित स्रोत असंरचित मुक्त पाठ डेटा में मौजूद है जो आमतौर पर जांच या प्रशासन के उद्देश्यों के लिए पुलिस द्वारा एकत्र किया जाता है। फिर भी पुलिस एजेंसियों के पास आमतौर पर पैमाने पर इन आंकड़ों का विश्लेषण करने के लिए कौशल या संसाधन नहीं होते हैं। इस लेख में हम तर्क देते हैं कि एनएलपी इन असंरचित डेटा को अनलॉक करने की क्षमता प्रदान करता है और ऐसा करके पुलिस को अधिक पीओपी पहल को लागू करने की अनुमति देता है। हालांकि हम चेतावनी देते हैं कि पर्याप्त ज्ञान के बिना एनएलपी मॉडल का उपयोग करने से डेटा के भीतर पूर्वाग्रह या तो अनुमति मिल सकती है या बनाए रख सकती है जिससे संभावित रूप से प्रतिकूल परिणाम हो सकते हैं।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Déanann an t-alt seo iniúchadh ar an bpoitéinseal atá ann do Phróiseáil Teanga Nádúrtha (NLP) chun múnla póilíneachta níos éifeachtaí, dírithe ar chosc agus nach bhfuil chomh achrannach céanna a chumasú, samhail póilíneachta a bhí ró-íditheach go dtí seo le cur i bhfeidhm ar scála. Is féidir le Póilíneacht Dhírithe ar Fhadhbanna (POP) athsholáthar a dhéanamh, go páirteach ar a laghad, ar phóilíneacht thraidisiúnta a ghlacann cur chuige frithghníomhach, ag brath go mór ar an gcóras ceartais choiriúil. I gcodarsnacht leis sin, féachann POP le coireacht a chosc trí ionramháil a dhéanamh ar na bunchoinníollacha a cheadaíonn coireanna a dhéanamh. Teastaíonn tuiscint mhionsonraithe ar imeachtaí coireachta chun na bunchoinníollacha seo a shainaithint – eolas intuigthe a bhíonn ag oifigeach póilíní go minic ach a d’fhéadfadh a bheith dúshlánach díorthú ó shonraí struchtúrtha póilíneachta. Tá foinse léargais féideartha amháin ann i sonraí saor-théacs neamhstruchtúrtha a bhailíonn na póilíní de ghnáth chun críocha imscrúdaithe nó riaracháin. Ach de ghnáth ní bhíonn na scileanna ná na hacmhainní ag gníomhaireachtaí póilíneachta chun na sonraí seo a anailísiú ar scála. San Airteagal seo déanaimid argóint go dtugann NLP an cumas na sonraí neamhstruchtúrtha seo a dhíghlasáil agus trí é sin a cheadú do na póilíní níos mó tionscnamh POP a chur i bhfeidhm. Tugaimid rabhadh, áfach, go bhféadfadh úsáid a bhaint as samhlacha NLP gan eolas imleor claonadh laistigh de na sonraí a cheadú nó a bhuanú a bhféadfadh torthaí neamhfhabhracha a bheith mar thoradh orthu.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ამ პროგრამის შესაძლებელია მონაცემების პროცესისთვის პროცესისთვის (NLP) პროცესისთვის, რომელიც უფრო ეფექტიური, პროცესისთვის კონფრონტრაციური პოლიციის მოდელს, რომელიც პრობლემების დასაწყებული პოლიცია (POP) არის პრობლემენტიური შეცვლა, სანამ უფრო ნაწილად, ტრადიციონალური პოლიციაში, რომელიც რექტიური პრობლემენტის გავაკეთება, რომელიც ძალია კონტრასტურად, POP ძირებს წინახოთ გაკეთებას, მანიპულაციას გაკეთებას, რომელიც უნდა გაკეთება საკეთესოები. ამ საშუალო სტრიქტური სტრიქტურაციების განსაზღვრება უნდა დარწმუნოთ კონფიმინტური მოვლენების განსაზღვრება - სტრიქტურაციის მეცნიერება, რომელსაც პოლიციის სტრიქტურაცი ერთი შესაძლებელი გამოყენება არსტრუქტურაციული თავისუფალი ტექსტის მონაცემებში, რომელიც პოლიციაში გამოყენებულია გამოყენებული პასუხისთვის ან ადმინტრაცი მაგრამ პოლიციური ადგინტები არ აქვს სტაცილები ან რესურსები, რომლებიც ამ მონაცემების მაგალითად ანალიზაციას. ამ წესტიდან ჩვენ აპირობით, რომ NLP მოძლევა ამ არსტრუქტურული მონაცემების გახსნა პოლიციაში უფრო მეტი POP ინტივიციაციების გამოყენება. მაგრამ ჩვენ დარწმუნეთ, რომ NLP მოდელების გამოყენება საჭირო ცნობილების გარეშე შეიძლება შეუძლებელია ან შერწმუნელია მონაცემების გარეშე, რომელიც შეიძლება მონაც</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_hu>Ez a cikk a természetes nyelv feldolgozásának (NLP) lehetőségeit vizsgálja, hogy hatékonyabb, megelőzésre összpontosított és kevésbé konfrontációs rendőrségi modellt tegyen lehetővé, amely eddig túlságosan erőforrásokat igényelt ahhoz, hogy széles körben megvalósítsa. A problémaközpontú rendőrség (POP) legalábbis részben helyettesítheti a hagyományos rendőrséget, amely reaktív megközelítést alkalmaz, nagymértékben a büntető igazságszolgáltatási rendszerre támaszkodva. Ezzel szemben a POP a bűncselekmények elkövetését lehetővé tévő feltételek manipulálásával törekszik a bűncselekmények megelőzésére. E mögöttes körülmények azonosítása részletes megértést igényel a bűnözési eseményekről - hallgatólagos ismeretekről, amelyeket gyakran rendőrtisztek birtokolnak, de amelyek strukturált rendőrségi adatokból származhatnak. Az egyik lehetséges betekintési forrás a rendőrség által nyomozás vagy adminisztráció céljából gyűjtött strukturálatlan szabad szöveges adatokban rejlik. A rendőrségi ügynökségek azonban általában nem rendelkeznek megfelelő készségekkel vagy erőforrásokkal ahhoz, hogy ezeket az adatokat nagyságrendű elemzésre elemezzék. Ebben a cikkben azzal érvelünk, hogy az NLP lehetőséget kínál a strukturálatlan adatok feloldására, és ezzel lehetővé teszi a rendőrség számára, hogy több POP kezdeményezést hajtson végre. Figyelmeztetünk azonban arra, hogy a megfelelő ismeretek nélküli NLP modellek használata lehetővé teheti vagy fenntarthatja az adatokon belüli elfogultságot, ami potenciálisan kedvezőtlen eredményekhez vezethet.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_el>Αυτό το άρθρο διερευνά τις δυνατότητες της επεξεργασίας φυσικής γλώσσας για να επιτρέψει ένα πιο αποτελεσματικό, επικεντρωμένο στην πρόληψη και λιγότερο αντιμέτωπο μοντέλο αστυνόμευσης, το οποίο μέχρι στιγμής ήταν υπερβολικά δαπανηρό για να εφαρμοστεί σε κλίμακα. Η Προβληματολογική Αστυνομία (POP) είναι μια πιθανή αντικατάσταση, τουλάχιστον εν μέρει, της παραδοσιακής αστυνομίας που υιοθετεί μια αντιδραστική προσέγγιση, στηριζόμενη σε μεγάλο βαθμό στο σύστημα ποινικής δικαιοσύνης. Αντίθετα, η POP επιδιώκει να αποτρέψει το έγκλημα χειραγωγώντας τις υποκείμενες συνθήκες που επιτρέπουν τη διάπραξη εγκλημάτων. Ο προσδιορισμός αυτών των υποκείμενων συνθηκών απαιτεί λεπτομερή κατανόηση των γεγονότων εγκλήματος και σιωπηρή γνώση που συχνά κατέχουν οι αστυνομικοί, αλλά μπορεί να είναι δύσκολο να αντληθούν από δομημένα αστυνομικά δεδομένα. Μια πιθανή πηγή πληροφοριών υπάρχει στα μη δομημένα δεδομένα ελεύθερου κειμένου που συλλέγονται συνήθως από την αστυνομία για σκοπούς έρευνας ή διοίκησης. Ωστόσο, οι αστυνομικές υπηρεσίες συνήθως δεν έχουν τις δεξιότητες ή τους πόρους για να αναλύσουν αυτά τα δεδομένα σε κλίμακα. Σε αυτό το άρθρο υποστηρίζουμε ότι το NLP προσφέρει τη δυνατότητα να ξεκλειδώσετε αυτά τα μη δομημένα δεδομένα και έτσι να επιτρέψετε στην αστυνομία να εφαρμόσει περισσότερες πρωτοβουλίες POP. Ωστόσο, προειδοποιούμε ότι η χρήση μοντέλων χωρίς επαρκή γνώση μπορεί είτε να επιτρέψει είτε να διαιωνίσει προκατάληψη μέσα στα δεδομένα που ενδέχεται να οδηγήσει σε δυσμενή αποτελέσματα.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_it>Questo articolo esplora il potenziale dell'elaborazione del linguaggio naturale (PNL) per consentire un modello di polizia più efficace, incentrato sulla prevenzione e meno conflittuale che finora è stato troppo dispendioso di risorse per essere implementato su larga scala. Il Problem-Oriented Policing (POP) è un potenziale sostituto, almeno in parte, della polizia tradizionale che adotta un approccio reattivo, basato fortemente sul sistema giudiziario penale. Al contrario, il POP cerca di prevenire il crimine manipolando le condizioni sottostanti che consentono di commettere crimini. L'identificazione di queste condizioni di base richiede una comprensione dettagliata degli eventi criminali - conoscenze tacite che sono spesso detenute dagli agenti di polizia, ma che possono essere difficili da ricavare da dati strutturati della polizia. Una potenziale fonte di informazioni esiste nei dati non strutturati di testo libero comunemente raccolti dalla polizia a fini investigativi o amministrativi. Tuttavia, le agenzie di polizia di solito non dispongono delle competenze o delle risorse per analizzare questi dati su larga scala. In questo articolo sosteniamo che il PNL offre il potenziale per sbloccare questi dati non strutturati e così facendo consentire alla polizia di implementare più iniziative POP. Tuttavia, avvertiamo che l'utilizzo di modelli PNL senza conoscenze adeguate può consentire o perpetuare il bias all'interno dei dati potenzialmente portando a risultati sfavorevoli.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_mk>This article explores the potential for Natural Language Processing (NLP) to enable a more effective, prevention focused and less confrontational policing model that has hitherto been too resource consuming to implement at scale.  Problem-Oriented Policing (POP) is a potential replacement, at least in part, for traditional policing which adopts a reactive approach, relying heavily on the criminal justice system.  За разлика од тоа, ПОП се обидува да го спречи криминалот со манипулирање на основните услови кои овозможуваат извршување на криминалот. Идентификувањето на овие основни услови бара детално разбирање на криминалните настани - тивко знаење кое честопати го држат полицајците, но кое може да биде тешко да се извлече од структурирани полициски податоци. Еден потенцијален извор на разбирање постои во неструктурирани бесплатни текстови податоци кои обично ги собира полицијата за цели на истрага или администрација. Сепак, полициските агенции обично немаат вештини или ресурси за анализирање на овие податоци на скала. Во оваа статија тврдиме дека НЛП нуди потенцијал да ги отклучи овие неструктурирани податоци и со тоа да им овозможи на полицијата да спроведе повеќе иницијативи на ПОП. Сепак, предупредуваме дека употребата на моделите на НЛП без соодветно знаење може или да дозволи или да продолжи со предрасуди во рамките на податоците кои потенцијално водат до неповолни резултати.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_lt>Šiame straipsnyje nagrinėjamas gamtinės kalbos apdorojimo (NLP) potencialas, siekiant sukurti veiksmingesnį, prevencijai orientuotą ir mažiau konfrontacinį policijos model į, kuris iki šiol buvo per daug išteklių, kad būtų įgyvendintas mastu. Į problemas orientuota policija (angl. problem-oriented policing – POP) gali bent iš dalies pakeisti tradicinę policiją, kuri reaguoja ir labai remiasi baudžiamojo teisingumo sistema. Priešingai, POP siekia užkirsti kelią nusikalstamumui manipuliuojant pagrindinėmis sąlygomis, leidžiančiomis padaryti nusikaltimus. Nustatant šias pagrindines sąlygas būtina išsamiai suprasti nusikalstamus įvykius - slaptas žinias, kurias dažnai laiko policijos pareigūnai, bet kurios gali būti sunkios, remiantis struktūriniais policijos duomenimis. Vienas galimas informacijos šaltinis yra neinstruktūrizuotų nemokamų tekstų duomenų, kuriuos policija paprastai renka tyrimo ar administravimo tikslais. Tačiau policijos agentūros paprastai neturi įgūdžių ar išteklių analizuoti šiuos duomenis mastu. Šiame straipsnyje teigiame, kad NLP suteikia galimybę atskleisti šiuos nesukurtus duomenis ir taip leisti policijai įgyvendinti daugiau POP iniciatyvų. Vis dėlto įspėjame, kad naudojant NLP modelius be pakankamų žinių gali būti sudarytos sąlygos arba išlaikomas duomenų pusiausvyra, galinti sukelti nepalankius rezultatus.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бұл мақала Түзіндік тіл процессінің (НLP) мүмкіндігін зерттеп, көтерілген, назардағы және көтерілген конфронтациялық ережелер үлгісін қолдануға мүмкіндік береді. Мәселелерді бағытталған политика (POP) деген әдетті саясаттар үшін қайталау мүмкіндігін алмастыруға мүмкіндік болады. Бұл әдетті саясаттар қайталанатын жағдайды, жұмыс саясаттар жүйесіне қа Осылай-ақ, POP қарсы қарсылық қарсылықтарды қарсылып, қарсылықтарды жасауға мүмкіндік беруге болады. Бұл негізгі шарттарды анықтау үшін қамтамас оқиғаларының егжей- тегжейлі түсініктемесі керек - полицияның оқиғаларының көпшілікті білімін таңдау, бірақ бұл құрылған полицияның дер Құрастырылмаған бос мәтін деректерінде бір мүмкін түсініктер көзі іздеу не әкімшілік үшін полицияның жинақталмаған мәтін деректерінде бар. Бірақ полицейские агенциялары бұл деректерді масштабтағы анализ үшін көңіл не ресурстар жоқ. Бұл мақалада NLP бұл құрылмаған деректерді шешу мүмкіндігін жеткізеді және полицияның көп POP инициативаларын орындауға мүмкіндік береді. Бірақ біз NLP үлгілерін жеткілікті білім жоқ қолдануға немесе деректердің ішінде әрқашанда тұрақтық нәтижелеріне көмектесуге болады деп ескертеміз.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ms>Artikel ini mengeksplorasi potensi untuk Pemprosesan Bahasa Alami (NLP) untuk membolehkan model polisi yang lebih efektif, fokus pencegahan dan kurang konfrontasi yang sehingga kini terlalu menggunakan sumber untuk dilaksanakan pada skala. Polisi Berorientasi ke Masalah (POP) adalah pengganti potensi, sekurang-kurangnya sebahagian, untuk polisi tradisional yang mengadopsi pendekatan reaktif, bergantung dengan sistem keadilan jenayah. Sebaliknya, POP cuba untuk mencegah jenayah dengan memanipulasikan keadaan yang dibenarkan jenayah dilakukan. Identifying these underlying conditions requires a detailed understanding of crime events - tacit knowledge that is often held by police officers but which can be challenging to derive from structured police data.  Satu sumber pemahaman berpotensi wujud dalam data teks bebas yang tidak terstruktur yang biasanya dikumpulkan oleh polis untuk tujuan penyelidikan atau pemerintahan. Tetapi agensi polis biasanya tidak mempunyai kemampuan atau sumber untuk menganalisis data ini pada skala. Dalam artikel ini kami menyangka bahawa NLP menawarkan potensi untuk membuka data yang tidak terstruktur ini dan dengan melakukannya membenarkan polis untuk melaksanakan lebih banyak inisiatif POP. Namun, kita berhati-hati bahawa menggunakan model NLP tanpa pengetahuan yang cukup boleh membenarkan atau kekal bias dalam data yang berpotensi membawa kepada hasil yang tidak baik.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mt>Dan l-artikolu jesplora l-potenzjal għall-Ipproċessar tal-Lingwi Naturali (NLP) biex jippermetti mudell tal-pulizija aktar effettiv, iffukat fuq il-prevenzjoni u inqas konfrontazzjonali li s’issa kien jikkonsma riżorsi wisq biex jiġi implimentat fuq skala. Il-Politika Orientata lejn il-Problemi (POP) hija sostituzzjoni potenzjali, mill-inqas parzjalment, għall-pulizija tradizzjonali li tadotta approċċ reattiv, li jiddependi ħafna fuq is-sistema tal-ġustizzja kriminali. B’kuntrast, il-POP tfittex li tipprevjeni l-kriminalità billi timmanipula l-kundizzjonijiet sottostanti li jippermettu li jitwettqu r-reati. Identifying these underlying conditions requires a detailed understanding of crime events - tacit knowledge that is often held by police officers but which can be challenging to derive from structured police data.  Sors potenzjali wieħed ta’ għarfien jeżisti fid-dejta tat-test ħieles mhux strutturat li ġeneralment tinġabar mill-pulizija għall-finijiet ta’ investigazzjoni jew amministrazzjoni. Madankollu, l-aġenziji tal-pulizija tipikament ma għandhomx il-ħiliet jew ir-riżorsi biex janalizzaw din id-dejta fuq skala. F’dan l-artikolu aħna jargumentaw li l-NLP toffri l-potenzjal li tinfetaħ din id-dejta mhux strutturata u billi tagħmel hekk tippermetti lill-pulizija timplimenta aktar inizjattivi tal-POP. Madankollu, aħna nwissija li l-użu ta’ mudelli NLP mingħajr għarfien adegwat jista’ jippermetti jew jippermetti preġudizzju fi ħdan id-dejta li potenzjalment iwassal għal riżultati mhux favorevoli.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ml>സ്വാഭാവിക ഭാഷ പ്രവര്‍ത്തനങ്ങള്‍ക്കുള്ള സാധ്യതകള്‍ പരിശോധിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള സാധ്യതയാണ് ഈ ലേഖനം പരിശോധിക്കുന്നത് ഇതുവരെ പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിന് വളരെ  പ്രശ്നമായ പോലീസുകാര്‍ (പോപി) ഒരു സാധ്യതയുള്ള സ്ഥാനത്തിന് പകരം ചെയ്യുന്നത് പാരമ്പര്യമായ പോലീസുകാര്‍ക്കും, പ്രതികരിക്കുന്ന രീതിയില്‍  വിരോധമായി പോപി കുറ്റങ്ങള്‍ ചെയ്യാന്‍ അനുവദിക്കുന്ന അടിസ്ഥാനങ്ങള്‍ കൈകാര്യം ചെയ്യുന്നതിനാല്‍ കുറ്റങ ഈ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തെ തിരിച്ചറിയുന്നതിന് കുറ്റകൃത്യങ്ങളെക്കുറിച്ച് വിശദീകരിച്ച് മനസ്സിലാക്കേണ്ടതാണ് - പോലീസ് ഓഫീസറുകള്‍ ആവശ്യമാ അന്വേഷണത്തിനോ നിയന്ത്രണത്തിനോ വേണ്ടി പോലീസുകാര്‍ സാധാരണമായി സംഘടിപ്പിക്കാത്ത വാക്കുകളില്‍ ഒരു സാധ്യതയുള്ള Yet police agencies do not typically have the skills or resources to analyse these data at scale.  ഈ ലേഖനത്തില്‍ നമ്മള്‍ തര്‍ക്കിക്കുന്നത് NLP ഈ സ്ഥാപിക്കപ്പെടാത്ത വിവരങ്ങള്‍ തുറക്കാനുള്ള സാധ്യതയാണെന്നാണ്. അങ്ങനെ ചെയ്യ എന്നാലും നമ്മള്‍ മുന്നറിയിപ്പ് നല്‍കുന്നു, ആവശ്യമായ അറിവില്ലാത്ത NLP മോഡലുകള്‍ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത് വിവരങ്ങളില്‍ അനുവദിക്കുകയോ തുടര്‍</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_pl>Niniejszy artykuł analizuje potencjał przetwarzania języka naturalnego (NLP) w celu umożliwienia skuteczniejszego, ukierunkowanego na prewencję i mniej konfrontacyjnego modelu policji, który do tej pory był zbyt zasobochłonny, aby wdrożyć na skalę. Policja zorientowana na problemy (POP) jest potencjalnym zastępstwem, przynajmniej częściowo, tradycyjnej policji, która przyjmuje reaktywne podejście, polegające w dużej mierze na systemie wymiaru sprawiedliwości karnej. Natomiast POP dąży do zapobiegania przestępczości poprzez manipulowanie warunkami podstawowymi, które umożliwiają popełnienie przestępstw. Określenie tych warunków podstawowych wymaga szczegółowego zrozumienia zdarzeń przestępczych oraz cichej wiedzy, którą często posiadają funkcjonariusze policji, ale której uzyskanie może być trudne do uzyskania ze strukturyzowanych danych policyjnych. Jednym z potencjalnych źródeł wglądu są nieustrukturyzowane dane tekstowe powszechnie gromadzone przez policję na potrzeby dochodzenia lub administracji. Jednak agencje policji zazwyczaj nie posiadają umiejętności ani zasobów do analizy tych danych na skalę. W tym artykule argumentujemy, że NLP oferuje potencjał do odblokowania tych nieustrukturyzowanych danych i umożliwia policji realizację kolejnych inicjatyw POP. Ostrzegamy jednak, że stosowanie modeli NLP bez odpowiedniej wiedzy może albo pozwolić lub utrwalać stronniczość w danych potencjalnie prowadząc do niekorzystnych wyników.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ нийтлэл нь Байгалийн хэл Процессорын (NLP) боломжтой байдлыг судалж, илүү үр дүнтэй, зогсоохын тулд төвлөрсөн, бага зөрчилдөөн загварын загварыг ашигладаг. Олон асуудал дээр орж ирсэн полицей (POP) гэдэг нь хамгийн бага хэсэгт уламжлалтай полицейскийн орлуулах боломжтой байдал юм. Энэ нь урвалд үзүүлэх арга замыг ашиглаж, гэмт хэргийн шүүхийн системд хүндрэлтэй байдаг. Харамсалтай нь, POP гэмт хэрэг үйлдвэрлэхийг хүсэж, гэмт хэрэг үйлдвэрлэх шаардлагатай нөхцөл байдлыг засаж, гэмт хэрэг үйлдвэрлэхийг хүсэж байна. Эдгээр үндсэн нөхцөл байдлыг тайлбарлах нь гэмт хэрэг үйл явдлыг илүү нарийвчлан ойлгох шаардлагатай - цагдааны оффицерт байдаг мэдлэгийг зохицуулах хэрэгтэй. Гэхдээ энэ нь бүтээгдэхүүний мэдээллээс гаргаж Судалгаан эсвэл администрацийн зорилгоор цуглуулагдсан үнэгүй текст өгөгдлийн нэг талаар ойлголтын эх үүсвэр байдаг. Гэвч цагдааны агентлагууд эдгээр өгөгдлийг хэмжээгээр шинжилгээ хийх чадвартай болон баялаг байхгүй. Энэ хэвлэлд бид NLP эдгээр бүтээгдэхүүнийг шинэчлэх боломж олгож, цагдааны ажиллах боломжтой болгон POP инициатив хийх боломж олгож байна. Гэхдээ бид NLP загваруудыг зөв мэдлэг байхгүй ашиглах нь мэдээллийн дотор байнга өргөн байдал болон үргэлжлүүлэх боломжгүй үр дүнд хүргэх боломжтой байх боломжтой.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Denne artikkelen utforskar potensialen for naturspråk-prosessering (NLP) for å slå på ein meir effektiv, forebygging fokusert og mindre konfrontasjonsbrukingsmodell som har til dag vært for ressursbrukar for å implementera på skala. Problemorientert politikk (POP) er eit potensielt bytt ut, minst i del, for tradisjonelle politikk som adopterer ein reaktiv tilnærming, og tilhøyrer kraftig på kriminalsystemet. I contrast, POP prøver å forebygge kriminalitet ved å manipulere dei underliggande vilkåra som let kriminalane vera committed. Å identifisere desse underliggande vilkåra krev ein detaljert forståking av kriminaldarhendingar - takk kjenning som ofte vert holdt av poliofficer, men som kan vera vanskeleg for å derivera frå strukturerte politiske data. Eit potensielt kjelde for oppdaging finst i ikkje strukturerte fri tekstdata som oftast samles av polis for forsøk eller administrasjon. Men politiske agencier har ikkje vanlegvis kvalitetane eller ressursane for å analysera desse data på skala. I denne artikkelen søker vi at NLP tilbyr potensialen for å låsa opp desse ikkje-strukturerte data og ved å gjera dette tillat policien å implementera fleire POP-initiativer. Men vi varslar at bruk av NLP-modeller utan tilgjengelege kunnskap kan anten tillata eller perpetuelle forsikt i dataene som potensielt fører til ugyldige resultat.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Acest articol explorează potențialul procesării limbajului natural (PNL) pentru a permite un model de poliție mai eficient, axat pe prevenire și mai puțin confruntat, care până acum a fost prea consumator de resurse pentru a fi implementat la scară largă. Poliția orientată spre probleme (POP) reprezintă un potențial înlocuitor, cel puțin parțial, al poliției tradiționale care adoptă o abordare reactivă, bazându-se în mare măsură pe sistemul de justiție penală. În schimb, POP urmărește prevenirea criminalității prin manipularea condițiilor subiacente care permit comiterea infracțiunilor. Identificarea acestor condiții fundamentale necesită o înțelegere detaliată a evenimentelor infracționale - cunoștințe tacite care sunt adesea deținute de ofițerii de poliție, dar care pot fi provocate de a obține din datele structurate ale poliției. O sursă potențială de perspectivă există în datele text liber nestructurate colectate în mod obișnuit de poliție în scopul investigației sau administrării. Cu toate acestea, agențiile de poliție nu au, de obicei, competențele sau resursele necesare pentru a analiza aceste date la scară largă. În acest articol susținem că PNL oferă potențialul de a debloca aceste date nestructurate și de a permite poliției să implementeze mai multe inițiative POP. Cu toate acestea, vă avertizăm că utilizarea modelelor PNL fără cunoștințe adecvate poate permite sau perpetua părtinirea în cadrul datelor care pot duce la rezultate nefavorabile.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Ovaj članak istražuje potencijal procesa prirodnog jezika (NLP) kako bi omogućio efikasniji, prevencijski usredotočeni i manji konfrontacijski model politike koji je do sada bio previše potrošenje resursa za provedbu na skali. Problem-Orijentna policija (POP) je potencijalna zamjena za tradicionalnu policiju koja usvoji reaktivni pristup, teško se oslanja na kriminalni pravosudni sistem. Pored toga, POP pokušava spriječiti zločin manipulirajući temeljne uslove koje omogućavaju počiniti zločine. Identifikovanje ovih temeljnih uvjeta zahteva detaljno razumevanje zloèinskih dogaðaja - rešiti znanje koje često drže policajci ali što može biti izazovno iz strukturiranih policijskih podataka. Jedan potencijalni izvor uvida postoji u neostrukturiranim besplatnim tekstskim podacima koje obično prikupljaju policija za svrhu istrage ili administracije. Ipak, policijske agencije obično nemaju veštine ili resurse za analizu tih podataka u skali. U ovom članku tvrdimo da NLP nudi potencijal za otključavanje tih neostrukturnih podataka i tako omogućavamo policiji da provede više inicijativa POP-a. Međutim, oprezujemo da koristeći modele NLP bez odgovarajućih znanja mogu ili omogućiti ili zauvijek pristrasnost unutar podataka koji su potencijalno doveli do nepravilnih ishoda.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Qoraalkan wuxuu ka baaraandegayaa suurtagalka u baaraandegista afka asalka ah (NLP) in uu awoodo qaab ka faa’iido badan, ka hortagga horumarinta iyo modelka booliska ka hor jeeda oo ilaa haatan ka horeeyay ay inay ka shaqeeyaan faa’iido badan. Booliska dhibaatada la soo jeedo (POP) waa bedelka ugu yaraan, booliska caadiga ah ee soo qaada qaab reaktiv ah, oo ku kalsoonayo nidaamka garsooridda dembiga. Si ka duwan, POP wuxuu doonayaa in uu ka hor maro dembiga si uu u baaraandeeyo xaaladaha hoose ee uu dembiyada u ogolaado in la sameeyo. Aqoonsashada shuruudahan hoose ka ah waxaa loola baahan yahay garashada arrimaha dembiga- aqoonta sida badan loo qabto saraakiisha booliska, laakiin taas oo dhibaatada ka heli karta macluumaadka booliska dhisan. Waxaa jira mid ka mid ah soul arag suurtagal ah oo aan la dhisan macluumaad lacag la’aan ah oo boolisku soo ururiyey si ay u baaraandegiso ama maamulka. Si kastaba ha ahaatee hay'adaha boolisku sida caadiga ah ma haystaan aqoonta ama hantida ay ku baarayaan macluumaadkaas qiyaas ahaan. Maktabadan waxaynu ka doodaynaa in NLP wuxuu bixiyaa suurtagal in uu furo macluumaadkan aan la dhisay iyo sidoo kale boolisku uu sameeyo waxqabadyo badan oo POP ah. Si kastaba ha ahaatee waxaynu digtoonaynaa in isticmaalka modelalka NLP oo aan aqoon ku filnayn ay u ogolaan karto ama sii wadi karto khilaafka macluumaadka dhexdiisa, taasoo suurtowda u noqon kara resultiyada aan caqli lahayn.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>Denna artikel undersöker potentialen för Natural Language Processing (NLP) för att möjliggöra en effektivare, förebyggande fokuserad och mindre konfrontationell polismodell som hittills varit för resurskrävande för att implementera i skala. Problemorienterad polisverksamhet (POP) kan åtminstone delvis ersätta traditionell polisverksamhet med reaktiv inriktning och starkt beroende av det straffrättsliga systemet. Däremot försöker POP förebygga brott genom att manipulera de underliggande förhållanden som gör det möjligt att begå brott. Att identifiera dessa underliggande förhållanden kräver en detaljerad förståelse för brottshändelser - tyst kunskap som ofta innehas av poliser men som kan vara utmanande att härleda från strukturerade polisuppgifter. En potentiell källa till insikt finns i ostrukturerad fritextdata som polisen vanligtvis samlar in för utrednings- eller administrationsändamål. Polismyndigheter har dock vanligtvis inte kompetens eller resurser för att analysera dessa uppgifter i stor skala. I den här artikeln hävdar vi att NLP erbjuder potential att låsa upp dessa ostrukturerade data och på så sätt göra det möjligt för polisen att genomföra fler POP-initiativ. Vi varnar dock för att användning av NLP-modeller utan tillräcklig kunskap kan antingen tillåta eller upprätthålla bias inom data som potentiellt leder till ogynnsamma resultat.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_si>මේ ලේඛනය පරීක්ෂා කරනවා ස්වභාවික භාෂාව පරීක්ෂණය (NLP) සඳහා ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක, ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක, ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත්මක පොලිස ප්‍රශ්නයක්-ප්‍රශ්නයක් (POP) පොලිසියට ප්‍රශ්නයක්, අඩුම තරම් කොටසක්, ප්‍රශ්නයක්, ප්‍රශ්නයක් පොලිසියට ප්‍රතික්‍රියාත විරුද්ධ වෙනුවෙන්, POP සැකසුම් කරනවා අපරාධ වෙනුවෙන් අපරාධ වෙනුවෙන් අපරාධ වෙනුවෙන් අපරාධ වෙ අපරාධ සැකසුම් ගැන විස්තර තේරුම් ගන්න අවශ්‍යයි - පොලිස් නිලධාරියෝ ගැන සාමාන්‍ය විස්තර දැනගන්න තේරුම් ගන්න පුළුවන පොලිසියෙන් සංස්ථාපිත නිදහස් පාළුවක් සම්පූර්ණයෙන් පරීක්ෂණය සහ පාලනය සඳහා සංස්ථාපිත විශේෂ ඒත් පොලිසිය ඇජෙන්සින්ට් සාමාන්‍යයෙන්ම මේ දත්ත විශ්ලේෂණය කරන්න ක්‍රියාත්මක නැහැ. මේ ලේඛනයේ අපි ප්‍රශ්නයක් කරනවා NLP මේ නිර්මාණය නැති දත්ත අවස්ථානය කරන්න පුළුවන් කියලා, ඒ වගේම පොලිසියාට තව පොල ඒත් අපි බලාපොරොත්තු වෙන්නේ NLP මෝඩේල් භාවිතා කරන්න හොඳ දැනගන්න බැරි විදිහක් නැති විදිහක් තියෙන්න පුළුවන් නැහ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>இந்த கட்டுரை இயல்பான மொழி செயல்பாடுக்கான சாத்தியம் (NLP) செயல்படுத்துவதற்கான சாத்தியம் தேடுகிறது, மேலும் செயல்படுத்த, முன்னேற்றம் மற்றும் குறைந்த பிரச்சனையில் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட போலீசார்கள் (POP) ஒரு சாத்தியமான மாற்றம், குறைந்ததாவது, ஒரு பாரம்பரிய கொள்கையாளிகளுக்கு, ஒரு பாதிப் மாறாக, POP எதிர்பார்க்கிறது குற்றங்களை செய்ய அனுமதிக்கும் அடிப்படையான நிலைமைகளை கையாளும் மூலம் குற்றம இந்த அடிப்படையான நிலைமைகளை அடிப்படையாக்க வேண்டும் குற்றங்கள் பற்றி விவரமான புரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் - போலீஸ் அதிகாரிகள் பெறு ஒரு சாத்தியமான பார்வையின் மூலம் உள்ளது கட்டப்படாத இலவச உரை தகவல் பொதுவாக போலீஸ் சேகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது ஆய்வு அல்லது நிர் Yet police agencies do not typically have the skills or resources to analyse these data at scale.  இந்த கட்டுரை ஆனால் நாம் எச்சரிக்கை செய்கிறோம் என்றாலும் தேவையான அறிவு இல்லாமல் NLP மாதிரிகளை பயன்படுத்தி தகவல்களில் உள்ள பிரச்சனைகளை அனுமதிக்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>یہ مقالہ طبیعی زبان پرسسس (NLP) کے لئے زیادہ اثرات والی، روکنے والی روکنے والی پولیسی موڈل کے امکانات کا تحقیق کرتا ہے جو یہاں تک زیادہ سرمایہ کا مصرف کرتا ہے۔ مشکل-Oriented Policing (POP) ایک امکانات بدلنے والا ہے، کم کم اندازے سے، سنتی پولیسی کے لئے، جو ایک فعالی طریقہ قبول کرتا ہے، جرم عدالت سیستم پر بھاری بھروسہ رکھتا ہے. بغیر اس کے، POP نے گناہ سے روکنے کی کوشش کی ہے، اس کے ذریعہ سے زیادہ شرایطوں کی تدبیر سے جو گناہ کی اجازت دیتے ہیں. یہ پائیدار شرایطوں کو پہچان کرنے کی ضرورت ہے کہ گناہ حادثوں کی تفصیل معلوم کریں - پولیس افسور کے ذریعے بہت زیادہ سمجھ سکیں لیکن جو ساختہ پولیس ڈیٹوں سے اثر کرنے کے لئے مشکل ہے۔ غیر ساختہ فائدہ ٹیکسٹ ڈیٹے میں ایک امکانات منبع موجود ہے جو پلیس نے تحقیق یا اداریٹ کے مطابق جمع کئے ہیں۔ لیکن پولیس ایجنسیٹیوں کے پاس ان ڈیٹوں کو اندازہ سے تحقیق کرنے کے لئے کثرت یا منابع نہیں ہیں۔ ہم اس مقالہ میں جھگڑتے ہیں کہ NLP نے ان غیر ساختہ ڈیٹوں کو کھولنے کی امکانات دے دی ہے اور اس طرح پولیس کو زیادہ POP شروع کرنے کے لئے اجازت دے دی ہے۔ اگرچہ ہم ڈراتے ہیں کہ NLP موڈلوں کے استعمال سے مناسب علم کے بغیر یا دائٹوں کے اندر ہمیشہ غیرقابل غیرقابل غیرقابل تحقیق کی اجازت دے سکتے ہیں.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Bu maqola taʼminlovchi bo'lgan oddiy nutq jarayonlarini (NLP) ishlab chiqaradi. Bu maqola taʼminlovchi qoidalar modelini ko'proq qoidadan foydalanishga ega bo'ladi. Muammo qoidasi (POP) bir qismda, qismda, qismida, qiziqarli qoidaga reactiv qoidani qo'shish qoidaga qo'shish qoidasi qo'llanmalarni katta ishlatadi. Ikkinchi tomondan, POP kriminalni bajarishga ruxsat beradi. Bu asosiy holatlarni aniqlash uchun kriminal hendelser haqida o'rganish kerak - huquqlarni ko'p qo'llanilgan huquqlarni taklif qilish kerak, lekin buni qo'llangan polish maʼlumotidan olish uchun qidirish mumkin. Qidirish yoki boshqarish uchun polisi qo'llangan boʻsh boʻsh matn maʼlumotida qo'llanmagan eng muhimi ko'p manbasi mavjud. Lekin polish tashkilotlari oddiyda bu maʼlumotlarni o'anavish uchun qobiliyat yoki rasmlar yo'q. In this article we argue that NLP offers the potential to unlock these unstructured data and by doing so allow police to implement more POP initiatives.  Lekin biz taqvim qilamiz, NLP modellari bilan yetarli ilmiy ishlatish mumkin, bu maʼlumot ichida juda noto'xshash natijaga ega bo'lishi mumkin yoki ishlash mumkin.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Bài báo này nghiên cứu khả năng xử lý ngôn ngữ tự nhiên (chọc ngoáy ngôn ngữ) cho phép một mô hình cảnh sát có hiệu quả hơn, chuyên nghiệp và ít cân đối hơn, mà đến nay đã tốn quá nhiều tài nguyên để thực hiện quy mô. Vấn đề cảnh sát xoay hướng là một khả năng thay thế, ít nhất là một phần, cho các hoạt động thanh tra truyền thống có một cách thức hoạt động, dựa trên hệ thống tư pháp hình sự. Tuy nhiên, POTS muốn ngăn chặn tội ác bằng cách thao túng những điều kiện căn bản cho phép tội ác xảy ra. Việc xác định những điều kiện cơ bản này đòi hỏi một sự hiểu biết chi tiết về các sự kiện tội phạm (những kiến thức thầm lặng) mà thường thuộc về cảnh sát nhưng có thể khó khăn đến từ dữ liệu cảnh sát cơ bản. Có một nguồn nhìn rõ tiềm năng tồn tại trong dữ liệu văn bản tự do không xây dựng thường được cảnh sát thu thập để điều tra hay quản lý. Tuy nhiên, cơ quan cảnh sát thường không có đủ kỹ năng hay nguồn lực để phân tích dữ liệu quy mô. Trong bài báo này, chúng tôi cho rằng Njala có tiềm năng giải phóng những dữ liệu không xây dựng này và bằng cách làm vậy để cảnh sát có thể thực hiện nhiều dự án POP. Tuy nhiên, chúng tôi cảnh báo rằng sử dụng mô hình độc lập lập lập không có kiến thức thích hợp có thể cho phép hay duy trì khuynh hướng trong dữ liệu có thể dẫn tới hậu quả bất lợi.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_nl>Dit artikel onderzoekt het potentieel van Natural Language Processing (NLP) om een effectiever, preventiegericht en minder confronterend politiemodel mogelijk te maken dat tot nu toe te veel middelen verbruikt om op schaal te implementeren. Probleemorienteerd policing (POP) is een potentiële vervanging, althans gedeeltelijk, voor traditionele politiediensten die een reactieve aanpak hanteren en sterk afhankelijk zijn van het strafrechtssysteem. POP wil daarentegen criminaliteit voorkomen door de onderliggende omstandigheden te manipuleren die het mogelijk maken misdrijven te plegen. Het identificeren van deze onderliggende omstandigheden vereist een gedetailleerd inzicht in misdaadgebeurtenissen en stilzwijgende kennis die vaak in bezit is van politieagenten, maar die moeilijk kan zijn om te ontlenen aan gestructureerde politiegegevens. Een potentiële bron van inzicht bestaat in ongestructureerde vrije tekstgegevens die gewoonlijk door de politie worden verzameld voor onderzoek of administratie. Toch beschikken politiediensten meestal niet over de vaardigheden of middelen om deze gegevens op schaal te analyseren. In dit artikel stellen we dat NLP het potentieel biedt om deze ongestructureerde data te ontsluiten en zo de politie in staat te stellen meer POP-initiatieven te implementeren. We waarschuwen echter dat het gebruik van NLP-modellen zonder adequate kennis bias binnen de gegevens kan toestaan of vereeuwigen die mogelijk leiden tot ongunstige resultaten.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_hr>Ovaj članak istražuje potencijal procesa prirodnog jezika (NLP) kako bi omogućio učinkovitiji, prevencijski usredotočeni i manji konfrontacijski model politike koji je do sada bio previše potrošenje resursa za provedbu na skali. Problem-Orijentna policija (POP) je potencijalna zamjena za tradicionalnu policiju koja usvoji reaktivni pristup, teško se oslanja na kriminalni pravosudni sustav. Pored toga, POP pokušava spriječiti zločin manipulirajući temeljne uvjete koje omogućavaju počiniti zločine. Otkrivanje ovih temeljnih uvjeta zahtijeva detaljno razumijevanje događaja zločina - otkriti znanje koje često drže policajci, ali što može biti izazovno iz strukturiranih policijskih podataka. Jedan potencijalni izvor uvida postoji u neostrukturiranim besplatnim tekstskim podacima koje obično prikupljaju policija za svrhu istrage ili administracije. Ipak, policijske agencije obično nemaju vještine ili resurse za analizu tih podataka u skali. U ovom članku tvrdimo da NLP nudi potencijal otključanja tih neostrukturnih podataka i tako omogućavamo policiji da provede više inicijativa POP-a. Međutim, oprezujemo da korištenje modela NLP bez odgovarajućih znanja može omogućiti ili zauvijek pristrasnost unutar podataka koji su potencijalno doveli do nepravilnih ishoda.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_bg>Тази статия изследва потенциала за обработка на естествения език (НЛП) да даде възможност за по-ефективен, фокусиран върху превенцията и по-малко конфронтационен модел на полицейско управление, който досега е бил твърде ресурсно потребяващ, за да бъде приложен в мащаб. Проблемно ориентираната полиция е потенциален заместител, поне отчасти, на традиционната полиция, която възприема реактивен подход, разчитайки в голяма степен на системата на наказателното правосъдие. За разлика от това се стреми да предотврати престъпността чрез манипулиране на основните условия, които позволяват извършването на престъпления. Идентифицирането на тези основни условия изисква подробно разбиране на престъпленията - мълчаливи знания, които често се притежават от полицейските служители, но които могат да бъдат трудни за извличане от структурирани полицейски данни. Един потенциален източник на прозрение съществува в неструктурираните данни за свободен текст, които обикновено се събират от полицията за целите на разследване или администрация. Въпреки това полицейските агенции обикновено нямат уменията или ресурсите да анализират тези данни в мащаб. В тази статия ние твърдим, че НЛП предлага потенциала за отключване на тези неструктурирани данни и по този начин позволява на полицията да реализира повече инициативи за ПОП. Въпреки това предупреждаваме, че използването на модели без адекватни познания може или да позволи или да удължи пристрастието в данните, което потенциално води до неблагоприятни резултати.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>Denne artikel undersøger potentialet for Natural Language Processing (NLP) til at muliggøre en mere effektiv, forebyggelsesfokuseret og mindre konfrontationsorienteret politimodel, der hidtil har været for ressourcekrævende til at implementere i omfang. Problemorienteret politi (POP) er en potentiel erstatning, i hvert fald delvist, for traditionel politivirksomhed, der anvender en reaktiv tilgang og er stærkt afhængig af det strafferetlige system. I modsætning hertil søger POP at forebygge kriminalitet ved at manipulere de underliggende forhold, der gør det muligt at begå kriminalitet. At identificere disse underliggende forhold kræver en detaljeret forståelse af kriminalitetsbegivenheder - stiltiende viden, som ofte besiddes af politifolk, men som kan være udfordrende at udlede af strukturerede politidata. En potentiel kilde til indsigt findes i ustrukturerede fritekstdata, der almindeligvis indsamles af politiet med henblik på efterforskning eller administration. Alligevel har politimyndighederne typisk ikke evner eller ressourcer til at analysere disse data i omfang. I denne artikel argumenterer vi for, at NLP giver mulighed for at låse op for disse ustrukturerede data og dermed give politiet mulighed for at gennemføre flere POP-initiativer. Vi advarer dog om, at brug af NLP-modeller uden tilstrækkelig viden enten kan tillade eller vedvare bias inden for dataene, der potentielt fører til ugunstige resultater.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>Dieser Artikel untersucht das Potenzial von Natural Language Processing (NLP), ein effektiveres, präventionsorientiertes und weniger konfrontatives Polizeimodell zu ermöglichen, das bisher zu ressourcenintensiv war, um es in großem Umfang umzusetzen. Problemorientiertes Policing (POP) ist ein potenzieller Ersatz, zumindest teilweise, für traditionelle Polizeiarbeit, die einen reaktiven Ansatz verfolgt und stark auf das Strafjustizsystem angewiesen ist. Im Gegensatz dazu versucht POP, Kriminalität zu verhindern, indem sie die Rahmenbedingungen manipuliert, die es erlauben, Verbrechen zu begehen. Die Identifizierung dieser zugrunde liegenden Bedingungen erfordert ein detailliertes Verständnis von Kriminalitätsereignissen und stillschweigendes Wissen, das häufig von Polizeibeamten gehalten wird, das aber schwierig sein kann, aus strukturierten Polizeidaten abzuleiten. Eine mögliche Quelle für Einsichten besteht in unstrukturierten Freitextdaten, die üblicherweise von der Polizei für Ermittlungs- oder Verwaltungszwecke erhoben werden. Dennoch verfügen Polizeibehörden in der Regel nicht über die Fähigkeiten oder Ressourcen, um diese Daten in großem Umfang zu analysieren. In diesem Artikel argumentieren wir, dass NLP das Potenzial bietet, diese unstrukturierten Daten freizuschalten und so der Polizei zu ermöglichen, mehr POP-Initiativen umzusetzen. Wir weisen jedoch darauf hin, dass die Verwendung von NLP-Modellen ohne ausreichende Kenntnisse entweder Verzerrungen innerhalb der Daten zulassen oder aufrechterhalten kann, was möglicherweise zu ungünstigen Ergebnissen führt.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_fa>این مقاله پتانسیل برای پردازش زبان طبیعی (NLP) را تحقیق می‌کند تا توان یک مدل پلیس‌های مواجه‌تر، جلوگیری‌کننده‌تر و کمتر کنترل کنترل را فعال کند که تا هنوز زیادی از منابع استفاده می‌کند تا به اندازه‌ای عملکرد پلیسی‌های مشکلی (POP) یک جایگزینی پتانسیل است، حداقل بخشی، برای پلیسی سنتی که یک روش فعالی را قبول می‌کند و به سیستم عدالت جرم بسیار اعتماد می‌کند. بر خلاف این، POP تلاش می‌کند با تغییر کردن شرایط پایه‌ای که اجازه می‌دهد جرم‌ها مرتکب شود از جنایت جلوگیری کند. شناسایی این شرایط های پایه نیاز به فهمیدن جزئیات از اتفاقات جنایت است - دانشی که اغلب توسط افسران پلیس نگه می‌دارد - ولی که می‌تواند از داده‌های پلیس ساخته شده سختی داشته باشد. یک منبع پتانسیل مشاهده در داده‌های متن آزادی که عمومی توسط پلیس برای هدف تحقیقات یا اداره ساخته نشده وجود دارد. اما آژانسان پلیس معمولاً مهارت یا منابع برای تحلیل این داده ها در مقیاس ندارند. در این مقاله ما بحث می‌کنیم که NLP پتانسیل باز کردن این داده‌های غیرساخته را پیشنهاد می‌دهد و با این کار به پلیس اجازه می‌دهد که فعالیت بیشتری POP را انجام دهد. با این حال، ما توجه می کنیم که با استفاده از مدل NLP بدون دانشی مناسب ممکن است یا در اطلاعات قابل توجه به نتیجه های غیرقابل پیشرفت اجازه دهد یا جاودانه باشد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_sw>Makala hii inagundua uwezekano wa mchakato wa lugha ya asili (NLP) ili kuwezesha ufanisi zaidi, kuzuia mkanganyiko wenye msimamo mkali na ndogo ya polisi ambao hadi sasa umekuwa matumizi ya rasilimali kwa kiwango kikubwa. Polisi wenye tatizo hilo (POP) ni kubadilishwa kwa uwezekano, angalau kwa sehemu, kwa ajili ya sera za kitamaduni ambazo hutumia mbinu za miitikio, na kutegemea sana mfumo wa haki ya jinai. Pamoja na hayo, POP anataka kuzuia uhalifu kwa kudhibiti hali halisi ambayo inaruhusu makosa. Kutambua hali hizi za msingi zinahitaji kuelewa kina kuhusu matukio ya uhalifu - kuelewa maarifa ambayo mara nyingi yanafanywa na maafisa wa polisi lakini ambayo inaweza kuwa changamoto ya kupata taarifa za polisi zilizojengwa. Chanzo moja cha uwezekano wa kuona kina katika taarifa za maandishi huru zilizojengwa mara nyingi zilizokusanywa na polisi kwa lengo la uchunguzi au utawala. Hata hivyo, mashirika ya polisi kwa kawaida hawana ujuzi au rasilimali za kuchambua taarifa hizi kwa kiasi kikubwa. In this article we argue that NLP offers the potential to unlock these unstructured data and by doing so allow police to implement more POP initiatives.  Hata hivyo, tunatahadhari kwamba kutumia mifano ya NLP bila ufahamu wa kutosha unaweza kuruhusu au kuendelea upendeleo katika taarifa zinaweza kusababisha matokeo yasiyo ya haki.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Bu makala Natural Language Processing (NLP) üçin beýleki bir nusga etmäge mümkin edmek üçin, oňa şu wagt çenli çeşmeli politika nusga etmäge çeşmeli. Mesele Orijinaly Polisiýa (POP) iň azyndan hem däpli-de däpli polisiýa üýtgetmegi üçin däpli bir nusga çykyş etmäge göz ýetirýär, syýasatçylyk adalat sistemine ynanýarlar. Gerçekten, POP jenaýatyň edilen şertlerini üýtgetmek üçin jenaýaty önlemek isleýär. Bu ýagdaýdaky şertleri tanyşdyrmak jenaýat wajyplarynyň detayly düşünmegi gerek - polisiýa ofisleri tarapyndan geçirilýän bilimi çykaryp bilýär ýöne bu ýagdaýyň strukturly polisiýa maglumatlaryndan çykyp biljek kynçylygyny çykaryp Ýaraşdyrma ýa administraciýanyň amaçlary üçin polisiýa tarapyndan ýygnanylýan boş metin maglumatynda bir pikir çeşmesi bar. Ýöne polisiýa ajaýyşlaryň bu maglumaty düýbünden çykarmak üçin ukyplary ýa-da çeşmeleri ýok. Biz bu makaleda NLP bu düzgünsiz maglumatlary çykarmak üçin mümkin edýändigini aýdýarys we şonuň üçin polisiýanyň köp POP girişimleri implementere rugsat bermesine mümkin edýändigini aýdýarys. Ýöne biz NLP modellerini ýeterli bilgi ýok bolmadykdan hem maglumatyň içindeki nLP modellerini ulanmakda, ýa-da sürekli nepislik netijelere mümkin edip bileris.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_af>Hierdie artikel ondersoek die potensiele vir Natuurlike Taal Prosessering (NLP) om 'n meer effektief, voorkoms fokuseerd en minder konfrontationele polisiemodel te aktiveer wat tot nou te hulpbron gebruik het om op skaal te implementeer. Probleem-Orienteerde Politikering (POP) is 'n potensiele vervanging, ten minste in deel, vir tradisionele polisie wat 'n reaktiewe toegang aanvaar, wat swaar vertrou op die kriminale regstelsel. Deur teenstemming soek POP om misdaad te voorkom deur die onderstelde voorwaardes te manipuleer wat misdaad toelaat word. Die identifiseer van hierdie onderstelde voorwaardes vereis 'n gedetale verstanding van misdaad-gebeurtenis - die kennis wat dikwels deur polisienaars gehou word, maar wat kan veranderlik wees om van struktureerde polisiedata af te kry. Een potensiele bron van insig bestaan in ongestruktureerde vry teks data gewoonlik deur polisie versamel vir die doels van ondersoek of administrasie. Nog het policiese agencies nie tipies die kunstenaars of hulpbronne om hierdie data op skaal te analyseer nie. In hierdie artikel het ons gespreek dat NLP die potensiele om hierdie ongestruktureerde data te ontsluit en deur dit te doen, laat polisie meer POP iniciatiewe implementeer. Maar ons waarsku dat die gebruik van NLP-modele sonder adequate kennis kan of toelaat of perpetuur voorskrif binne die data potensieal na onvoorskynlike outekoms.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_id>Artikel ini mengeksplorasi potensi untuk Proses Bahasa Alam (NLP) untuk memungkinkan model polisi yang lebih efektif, fokus preventif dan kurang konfrontasi yang sehingga ini terlalu memakan sumber daya untuk menerapkan pada skala. Polisi Orientasi Masalah (POP) adalah pengganti potensi, setidaknya sebagian, untuk polisi tradisional yang mengadopsi pendekatan reaktif, bergantung dengan sistem keadilan kriminal. By contrast, POP seeks to prevent crime by manipulating the underlying conditions that allow crimes to be committed.  Mengenalpasti kondisi dasar ini membutuhkan pemahaman rinci tentang kejadian kriminal - pengetahuan rahasia yang sering ditahan oleh petugas polisi tetapi yang dapat menantang untuk berasal dari data polisi strukturasi. Satu sumber potensi penglihatan ada dalam data teks gratis tidak struktur yang biasanya dikumpulkan oleh polisi untuk tujuan penyelidikan atau administrasi. Namun agensi polisi biasanya tidak memiliki keterampilan atau sumber daya untuk menganalisis data ini pada skala. In this article we argue that NLP offers the potential to unlock these unstructured data and by doing so allow police to implement more POP initiatives.  Namun kita berhati-hati bahwa menggunakan model NLP tanpa pengetahuan yang cukup mungkin memungkinkan atau menentukan bias dalam data yang berpotensi mengarah ke hasil yang tidak baik.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_ko>본고는 자연언어처리(NLP)의 잠재력을 탐구하여 더욱 효과적이고 예방을 중심으로 대항성이 적은 경찰 업무 모델을 실현하고자 한다. 이런 모델은 지금까지 자원을 너무 소모하여 대규모로 실시할 수 없다.문제를 중심으로 하는 경무(POP)는 전통 경무의 잠재적 대체품으로 적어도 어느 정도는 그렇다. 전통 경무는 수동적인 방식을 채택하고 형사 사법 시스템에 심각하게 의존한다.이에 비해 POP는 범죄를 허용하는 잠재적 조건을 조작해 범죄를 예방하려 한다.이러한 잠재적 조건을 식별하려면 범죄 사건에 대한 상세한 이해가 필요하다. 이것은 경찰이 일반적으로 습득하는 잠재적 지식이지만 구조화된 경찰 데이터에서 이러한 지식을 얻는 것은 매우 어려울 것이다.잠재적인 통찰은 비구조화된 자유 텍스트 데이터에 존재하는데, 이런 데이터는 보통 경찰이 수집하여 조사하거나 관리하는 데 쓰인다.그러나 경찰 기관은 이런 데이터를 대규모로 분석하는 기능이나 자원을 갖추지 못한다.본고에서 우리는 NLP가 이러한 비구조화된 데이터를 해제하는 잠재력을 제공했다고 생각한다. 이렇게 하면 경찰이 더 많은 POP 계획을 실시할 수 있다.그러나 NLP 모델을 충분한 지식 없이 사용하면 데이터의 편차가 허용되거나 영구적으로 존재할 수 있어 불리한 결과를 초래할 수 있다고 경고했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_am>ይህ ጽሑፍ እስከ ዛሬ ድረስ እጅግ የከበረ ሀብት ለመጠቀም የፖሊሲ ሞዴል ለመቻል የሚችል የፍጥረት ቋንቋ ማቀናቀል (NLP) የሚችል ነው፡፡ የፖሊስ ፖሊስ (POP) በሚያሳየው ክፍል፣ በተለየው የባሕላዊ ፖሊሲ ተቃውሞ በሚያሳየው በክሕተት ፍርድ ስርዓት ላይ የሚታመን የፖሊስ መተላለፊያ ነው፡፡ በተለይም፣ ፖሊስ ወንጀልን እንዲያደርጉ የሚፈቅደውን መሠረት በመግለጽ መግለጽ ይፈልጋል፡፡ እነዚህን underlying ጉዳይ ለማወቅ የኃጢአተኞችን ነገር የሚያስተውል ግልፅ ያስፈልጋል - ብዙ ጊዜ በፖሊስ ባለሥልጣናት የሚይዘውን ማወቅ ግን ከፖሊስ ዳታዎችን ለማግኘት የሚችል ነው፡፡ One potential source of insight exists in unstructured free text data commonly collected by police for the purposes of investigation or administration.  ምንም እንኳን የፖሊስ አካባቢዎች እነዚህን ዳራዎችን በመጠቀም የሚያስተምሩ ባለ ብልሃትና ሀብት የላቸውም፡፡ በዚህ ጽሑፍ ውስጥ NLP የተመሠረተውን የዳታ መክፈት ስልጣንን እና እንደዚህ ፖሊስ የበለጠ የፖሊስ ጥያቄዎችን ለማድረግ እንዲፈቅድ ይችላል ብለን እናጋራለን፡፡ ምንም እንኳን የNLP ምሳሌዎች ሳይጠግብ እውቀት በመጠቀም ወይም በአዳራዎች ውስጥ የስልጣን ውጤቶች መግለጥ የሚችል መሆኑን እናስጠነቅቃለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_bn>এই প্রবন্ধে প্রাকৃতিক ভাষা প্রক্রিয়ার (এনএলপি) সম্ভাবনা খুঁজে বের করে যাচ্ছে আরো কার্যকর, প্রতিরোধ, মনোযোগ দেয়া এবং কম সংগ্রামিত পুলিশ মডেল যা এখন পর্যন্ সমস্যার সূত্রপূর্ণ পুলিশ (পোপি) একটি সম্ভাব্য প্রতিস্থাপন, অন্তত ঐতিহ্যবাহী পুলিশের জন্য, যা একটি প্রতিক্রিয়ার পদ্ধতি গ্রহণ করে, অপরাধী বিচ বিপরীতে, পোপি অপরাধের মাধ্যমে অপরাধ প্রতিরোধ করতে চায়। এই অন্তর্ভুক্ত পরিস্থিতিকে পরিচয় করার জন্য অপরাধের ঘটনার ব্যাপারে বিস্তারিত বুঝতে প্রয়োজন - পুলিশ কর্মকর্তাদের প্রায়শই জানা যায়, ক অনুসন্ধান অথবা প্রশাসনের উদ্দেশ্যে পুলিশের সাধারণত মুক্ত টেক্সটের তথ্য সংগ্রহ করে একটি সম্ভাব্য চোখের উৎস রয়েছে। তবে পুলিশ সংস্থা সাধারণত এই তথ্য বিশ্লেষণের ক্ষেত্রে দক্ষতা বা সম্পদ নেই। এই প্রবন্ধে আমরা যুক্তি দিচ্ছি যে এনএলপি এই অকার্যকর তথ্য খুলে দেবার সম্ভাবনা প্রদান করেছে এবং এভাবে পুলিশ আরো পোপি উদ্যোগ বাস তবে আমরা সতর্ক থাকি যে এনএলপি মডেল ব্যবহার করে যথেষ্ট জ্ঞান ছাড়া যে তথ্যের মধ্যে প্রতিযোগিতাকে অনুমতি দিতে পারে অথবা স্থায়ীতে চালি</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_az>Bu məktub təbiətli dil işləməsi (NLP) üçün daha efektiv, önləşdirmək və daha az konfrontacılı polis modelini istifadə etmək üçün çox qüvvət istifadə etmək üçün potensialını keşfetir. Problem-Oriented Policing (POP) ən az bir hissəsi olaraq, vəzifəli polisin yerinə gətirməsi və suçlu ədaləti sisteminə güvən olaraq reaktiv bir tərzi istifadə edir. Bununla belə, POP günahları işlədilməyə izin verən şərtlərin dəyişdirilməsi ilə suçu qadağan etmək istəyir. Bu a şağıdaki şərtlərin təsdiqlənməsi suç olaraqlarının detaylı anlaması lazımdır - polis ofislərinin sık-sıq tutduğu bilgiləri çəkin, amma qurulmuş polis məlumatlarından istifadə edə bilər. Görünüş mümkün olmayan bir mənbəsi olaraq məlumat məlumatlarında polis araşdırması ya da administrasyonun məqsədilə toplanmışdır. Halbuki polis aģentūrları bu məlumatları ölçüdə analiz etmək üçün yeteneklik və resurslar yoxdur. Bu məktublarda NLP bu müəyyən edilməmiş məlumatları açmaq və polisin daha çox POP iniciativlərini yerinə yetirməsinə izin verir. Ancaq biz NLP modellərini uyğun bilgi olmadan istifadə etmək məlumatların içində mümkün olmayan sonuçlarına yol açmaq və ya sürəkli tədbirləri mümkün olar.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>Ovaj članak istražuje potencijal procesa prirodnog jezika (NLP) kako bi omogućio učinkovitiji, prevencijski usredotočeni i manji konfrontacijski model političke politike koji je do sada bio previše potrošenje resursa za provedbu na skali. Problem-Orijentna policija (POP) je potencijalna zamjena za tradicionalnu policiju koja usvoji reaktivni pristup, teško se oslanja na kriminalni pravosudni sistem. Pored toga, POP pokušava spriječiti zločin manipulirajući temeljne uvjete koje omogućavaju počiniti zločine. Identifikovanje ovih temeljnih uvjeta zahtijeva detaljno razumijevanje zločinskih događaja - otkriti znanje koje često drže policajci ali što može biti izazovno iz strukturiranih policijskih podataka. Jedan potencijalni izvor uvida postoji u neostrukturiranim besplatnim tekstskim podacima koje obično prikupljaju policija za svrhu istrage ili administracije. Ipak, policijske agencije obično nemaju vještine ili resurse za analizu tih podataka u skali. U ovom članku tvrdimo da NLP nudi potencijal otključanja tih neostrukturnih podataka i tako omogućavamo policiji da provede više inicijativa POP-a. Međutim, upozoravamo da koristeći modele NLP bez odgovarajućih znanja mogu ili omogućiti ili zauvijek pristrasnost unutar podataka koji su potencijalno doveli do nepravilnih ishoda.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Tento článek zkoumá potenciál zpracování přirozeného jazyka (NLP), který umožňuje efektivnější, prevenčně zaměřený a méně konfrontační policejní model, který byl dosud příliš náročný na zdroje na implementaci v měřítku. Problémově orientovaná policie (POP) představuje alespoň částečně možnou náhradu tradiční policie, která zaujímá reaktivní přístup a silně se spoléhá na systém trestního soudnictví. Naproti tomu se POP snaží předcházet trestné činnosti manipulací se základními podmínkami, které umožňují spáchat trestné činy. Identifikace těchto základních podmínek vyžaduje podrobné porozumění událostem trestné činnosti a tiché znalosti, které jsou často drženy policisty, ale které může být obtížné odvodit ze strukturovaných policejních údajů. Jedním z potenciálních zdrojů poznatků jsou nestrukturované volné textové údaje běžně shromažďované policií pro účely vyšetřování nebo správy. Policejní agentury však obvykle nemají schopnosti ani zdroje k analýze těchto údajů v měřítku. V tomto článku tvrdíme, že NLP nabízí potenciál k odemknutí těchto nestrukturovaných dat a tím umožní policii realizovat další POP iniciativy. Upozorňujeme však na to, že používání NLP modelů bez adekvátních znalostí může buď umožnit, nebo udržet zaujatost v rámci dat potenciálně vedoucí k nepříznivým výsledkům.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Käesolevas artiklis uuritakse looduskeele töötlemise potentsiaali, et võimaldada tõhusamat, ennetusele keskendunud ja vähem vastasseisulist politseimudelit, mis on seni olnud liiga ressursse tarbiv, et seda ulatuslikult rakendada. Probleemidele orienteeritud politsei (POP) on võimalik asendada vähemalt osaliselt traditsioonilist politseitööd, mis võtab kasutusele reageeriva lähenemisviisi, tuginedes suurel määral kriminaalõigussüsteemile. Vastupidiselt püüab POP kuritegevust ennetada, manipuleerides alustingimustega, mis võimaldavad kuritegusid toime panna. Nende alustingimuste kindlakstegemine nõuab kuritegevuse sündmuste üksikasjalikku mõistmist – tihti politseiametnike valduses olevaid vaikimisi teadmisi, mida struktureeritud politseiandmetest võib olla raske saada. Üks võimalik teabe allikas on struktureerimata vaba teksti andmed, mida politsei tavaliselt uurimise või haldamise eesmärgil kogub. Siiski ei ole politseiasutustel tavaliselt oskusi ega ressursse nende andmete ulatuslikuks analüüsimiseks. Selles artiklis väidame, et NLP pakub potentsiaali avada need struktureerimata andmed ja võimaldab nii politseil rakendada rohkem POP algatusi. Siiski hoiatame, et piisavate teadmisteta uue tööprogrammi mudelite kasutamine võib kas lubada või püsida andmete erapooletust, mis võib viia ebasoodsate tulemusteni.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_sq>This article explores the potential for Natural Language Processing (NLP) to enable a more effective, prevention focused and less confrontational policing model that has hitherto been too resource consuming to implement at scale.  Policia me Orientim në Probleme (POP) është një zëvendësim i mundshëm, së paku në pjesë, për policinë tradicionale që miraton një qasje reaktive, duke u mbështetur fort në sistemin e drejtësisë penale. By contrast, POP seeks to prevent crime by manipulating the underlying conditions that allow crimes to be committed.  Identifikimi i këtyre kushteve themelore kërkon një kuptim të hollësishëm të ngjarjeve të krimit - njohuri të fshehtë që shpesh mbahet nga oficerët e policisë por që mund të jetë sfiduese për të përfshirë nga të dhënat e strukturuara të policisë. Një burim i mundshëm i kuptimit ekziston në të dhëna teksti pa strukturë të lira të mbledhura zakonisht nga policia për qëllime të hetimit apo administratës. Yet police agencies do not typically have the skills or resources to analyse these data at scale.  Në këtë artikull argumentojmë se NLP ofron potencialin për të hapur këto të dhëna të pastrukturuara dhe duke e bërë këtë lejojmë policinë të zbatojë më shumë nisma POP. However we caution that using NLP models without adequate knowledge may either allow or perpetuate bias within the data potentially leading to unfavourable outcomes.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_ca>Aquest article explora el potencial del processament de llenguatges naturals (NLP) per permetre un model policial més eficaç, centrat en prevenció i menys confrontador que fins ara ha estat massa consument de recursos per implementar a escala. Problem-Oriented Policing (POP) is a potential replacement, at least in part, for traditional policing which adopts a reactive approach, relying heavily on the criminal justice system.  By contrast, POP seeks to prevent crime by manipulating the underlying conditions that allow crimes to be committed.  Identificar aquestes condicions subjacents requereix una comprensió detallada dels esdeveniments del crim - coneixements tacits que sovint tenen els oficials de la policia però que poden ser difícils derivar de dades estructuradas de la policia. Una fonte potencial de comprensió existeix en dades de textos lliures no estructurats que normalment recollen les policies per investigar o administrar. Però les agències policials normalment no tenen habilitats o recursos per analitzar aquestes dades a escala. En aquest article argumentem que NLP ofereix el potencial de desbloquejar aquestes dades no estructuradas i, fent això, permet a la policia implementar més iniciatives POP. However we caution that using NLP models without adequate knowledge may either allow or perpetuate bias within the data potentially leading to unfavourable outcomes.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_fi>Tässä artikkelissa tarkastellaan luonnollisen kielen prosessoinnin (NLP) mahdollisuuksia mahdollistaa tehokkaampi, ennaltaehkäisevä ja vähemmän vastakkainasetteleva poliisimalli, joka on tähän mennessä ollut liian resursseja vievä toteuttaa laajamittaisesti. Ongelmaohjainen poliisitoiminta (POP) voi korvata ainakin osittain perinteisen poliisitoiminnan, jossa noudatetaan reagoivaa lähestymistapaa ja joka perustuu voimakkaasti rikosoikeusjärjestelmään. Sen sijaan POP pyrkii ehkäisemään rikollisuutta manipuloimalla taustalla olevia olosuhteita, jotka mahdollistavat rikosten tekemisen. Näiden taustalla olevien olosuhteiden tunnistaminen edellyttää rikostapahtumien yksityiskohtaista ymmärtämistä – hiljaista tietoa, joka usein on poliisin hallussa, mutta jonka saaminen strukturoiduista poliisitiedoista voi olla haastavaa. Yksi mahdollinen oivalluksen lähde on strukturoimaton vapaa teksti, jota poliisi yleensä kerää tutkintaa tai hallintoa varten. Poliisivirastoilla ei kuitenkaan yleensä ole valmiuksia tai resursseja analysoida näitä tietoja mittakaavassa. Tässä artikkelissa väitämme, että NLP tarjoaa mahdollisuuden avata nämä rakenteettomat tiedot ja antaa näin poliisille mahdollisuuden toteuttaa enemmän POP-aloitteita. Varoitamme kuitenkin, että NLP-mallien käyttäminen ilman riittävää tietämystä voi joko sallia tai ylläpitää tietojen vääristymiä, jotka saattavat johtaa epäsuotuisiin tuloksiin.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_hy>Այս հոդվածը ուսումնասիրում է բնական լեզվի մշակույթի պոտենցիալը, որը հնարավորություն է տալիս ավելի արդյունավետ, կանխուսափելի կենտրոնացված և ավելի քիչ հակառակցված ոստիկանության մոդել, որը մինչ այժմ չափազանց ռեսուրսներ է Խնդիրների վրա ուղղված քաղաքականությունը (POP-ն) ներուժեղ փոխարինում է, առնվազն մասամբ, ավանդական քաղաքականությունը, որը ընդունում է ռեակտիվ մոտեցում, շատ հիմնված է քրեական արդարադատության համակարգին: Դրան հակառակ, POP-ը փորձում է կանխել հանցագործությունը, մանիպուլյալով այն հիմնական պայմանները, որոնք թույլ են տալիս հանցագործությունները գործել: Identifying these underlying conditions requires a detailed understanding of crime events - tacit knowledge that is often held by police officers but which can be challenging to derive from structured police data.  Մի պոտենցիալ ընկալումների աղբյուր գոյություն ունի անկառուցված ազատ տեքստի տվյալների մեջ, որոնք սովորաբար հավաքվում են ոստիկանության կողմից հետազոտության կամ կառավարման նպատակով: Բայց ոստիկանական գործակալությունները սովորաբար չունեն հմտություններ կամ ռեսուրսներ այս տվյալների վերլուծության մեջ: In this article we argue that NLP offers the potential to unlock these unstructured data and by doing so allow police to implement more POP initiatives.  Այնուամենայնիվ, մենք զգուշացնում ենք, որ օգտագործելով ՆԼՊ մոդելներ առանց բավարար գիտելիքների կարող է թույլ տալ կամ շարունակել կողմնականությունը տվյալների մեջ, որը պոտենցիալ հանգեցնում է սխալ արդյունքների:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_ha>Wannan makala na gane the ikon wa Jarayi na Lugha Natural (NLP) za'a iya amfani da wata alama mai amfani da, wajen hanyowa da fasahan da kuma da ƙaranci da motsi na Polisi wanda ya haɗi daidai a yanzu, ta kasance maɓalli mai amfani da amfani don ya yi amfani da shi a tsakanin. @ item: inmenu Tsarin haka, PoP yana nufin ya kange zunubi da za'a zartar da halin da ke yarda a aikin zunubi. Ina iya gane wannan muhalli na ƙarƙasan, sai ya ƙaddara wani fahimci na halin laifuffuka - takiyar da sanin cẽwa an riƙe su a ofta daga sararin Police, amma wannan yana iya ƙiyayya ga ka sami daga data na tsari na Police. Babu wani sourcen gani yana cikin data na daman matsayin da ba'a gina shi ba, wanda aka samu da shi ɗammãnin a yi kashẽwa ko kuma ba da shirin. Babu da haka, Shirika na Police bã su da abinci ko kuma ma'auni dõmin su yi anadi ga wannan data a tsakanin. Daga wannan makala, Munã jãyayya cẽwa NLP yana da awon ya buɗe waɗannan data ba'a sahu ba da kuma za mu yi amfani da Police da wasu initiati na ƙaranci. Kayya, ko kuma, munã tsõratar da shi, ya yi amfani da misãlai na NLP bã da ilmi mai isa ba, ko ya yarda ko ya daɗa rabo a cikin danganta, mai yiwuwa zai iya ƙara matsalan da ba'a daidai.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>המאמר הזה חוקר את הפוטנציאל לעבודת שפת טבעית (NLP) כדי לאפשר מודל משטרה יותר יעיל, ממוקד למניעה ופחות מתעמת, שהיה עד כה משתמש במקורים מדי כדי להפעיל במידה. משטרה ממוקמת בעיות (POP) היא החליפה פוטנציאלית, לפחות חלקית, למשטרה מסורתית שמאמצת גישה תגובה, תלויה בכבדות על מערכת המשפט הפלילי. בניגוד לזה, POP מנסה למנוע פשע על ידי מניפולציה בתנאים הנוספים שמאפשרים פשעים לבצע. לזהות את התנאים הנוספים האלה דורשת הבנה מפורטת של אירועי פשע - ידע שקט שלעתים קרובות מחזיק על ידי שוטרים אבל שיכול להיות מאתגר להשיג ממידע משטרתי מבוסס. מקור אחד פוטנציאלי של הבנה קיים במידע טקסט חופשי לא מבושל שנאסף בדרך כלל על ידי המשטרה למטרות חקירה או ממשל. למרות זאת, לסוכנות המשטרה אין בדרך כלל את הכישורים או המשאבים כדי לנתח את המידע הזה בקנה מידה. במאמר הזה אנחנו טוענים ש NLP מציע את הפוטנציאל לפתוח את הנתונים הלא מובנים האלה ובכך שעושים זאת מאפשר למשטרה להפעיל עוד יוזמות POP. בכל אופן, אנו מזהירים שהשימוש בדוגמנים של NLP ללא ידע adequate יכול או לאפשר או להמשיך להצדיק בתוך המידע פוטנציאלי מוביל לתוצאות לא טובות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_jv>Artik iki dipoleh kapan kanggo Kebebasan langgambar Daerah-ingkang Pénolèh-Oriented Pénolèh (po-Oriented) sing paling potansi ampuhi, akeh sing gabung, nganggo dolanan politik sing perusahaan ampuhi arep gawe nguasakno aksi, kang dianggalakno ning sistèm hukum sing uwis. politenessoffpolite"), and when there is a change ("assertivepoliteness Ngawe ngilangno kondho sing paling kelas kuwi mesthi soalé awak dhéwé kuwi nggawe barang langkung wigatining- awak dhéwé kuwi kesempatan sing ngubah poliki kondho iso nggawe nguasai winih sing wis kelas nang data sak poliki sing sampek. Omahé kapan kelas nang panggunaké dipunangé awak dhéwé, dadi text ora bisa gegawe barang poliis kanggo nggawe tarjamahan o Administrasi. Nyong-ngopo iya punika dipoles ora ono karo kapan-kapan liyane apa perusahaan kanggo nyelarani awak dhéwé kuwi nggawe gerakan. Nang artikl iki, kita sawetara NLP ngebahi perusahaan kanggo ngilanggar data sing gak ngupakan lan nganggo cah dumadhi kanggo polisi kanggo ngerewakke iniwisiya pop sing luwih dumadhi. Saiki awak dhéwé éntuk sistem NLP nang sampeyan ingkang dipunangé awak dhéwé, iso dianggap dadi iki dadi bisa nguasai perbudhakan kanggo dianggap</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>Ta članek raziskuje potencial za obdelavo naravnega jezika (NLP), da bi omogočil učinkovitejši, preprečevalno usmerjen in manj soočljiv policijski model, ki je bil doslej preveč potreben za izvajanje virov v obsegu. Problem usmerjeno policijo (POP) je vsaj delno nadomestilo tradicionalnega policijskega nadzora, ki uporablja reaktiven pristop in se močno zanaša na kazenskopravosodni sistem. Nasprotno pa skuša POP preprečiti kaznivo dejanje z manipulacijo osnovnih pogojev, ki omogočajo storitev kaznivih dejanj. Opredelitev teh osnovnih pogojev zahteva podrobno razumevanje kriminalnih dogodkov – tiho znanje, ki ga pogosto hranijo policisti, vendar je lahko težko pridobiti iz strukturiranih policijskih podatkov. Eden od potencialnih virov vpogleda obstaja v nestrukturiranih podatkih o prostem besedilu, ki jih policija običajno zbira za namene preiskave ali upravljanja. Vendar policijske agencije običajno nimajo sposobnosti ali sredstev za analizo teh podatkov v obsegu. V tem članku trdimo, da NLP ponuja potencial za odklepanje teh nestrukturiranih podatkov in s tem policiji omogoča izvajanje več pobud POP. Vendar pa opozarjamo, da lahko uporaba modelov NLP brez ustreznega znanja bodisi dopušča ali ohrani pristranskost znotraj podatkov, ki bi lahko vodila do neugodnih rezultatov.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>ཆ་འཕྲིན་འདིས་སྤྱིར་བཏང་ནུས་རང་རུང་བའི་སྐད་ཡིག་ལས་སྦྱོར་བའི་རྒྱུ་དངོས་ལྟ་ཞིབ་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། དཀའ་ངལ་Oriented Police (POP)ནི་འགྲུལ་སྐྱོད་པ་ཞིག་ཡིན་པས་ཉུང་མཐའ་རང་གི་ཆ་ཤས་གཅིག་གི་ཚབ་བཅུག་ཐབས་ཤིག་ཡིན། གདོང་དངོས་འགྱུར་བ། POP་ནི་འཐབ་ལམ་ཞིག་ལག་ལེན་བྱེད་པའི་གནས་ཚུལ་གཞི་བཞག་ཡོད་པའི་གནས་ཚུལ་དང་མཐུན་སྒྲིག་འགོག རང་ཉིད་ཀྱི་གནས་སྟངས་འདི་དག་ལ་ངོས་འཛིན་བྱེད་སྐབས་གསལ་བཤད་ཆེན་ཡོད། ཆེས་ཡོད་པའི་བསམ་ཚུལ་གྱི་འབྱུང་ཁུངས་གཅིག་ནི་རང་དབང་ཡིག ཡིན་ནའང་ཉེན་རྟོག་པ་དོ་དམ་པ་ཚོར་སྟབས་བདེ་བཤད་དང་ཐོག་ཁུངས་མེད་པར། In this article we argue that NLP offers the potential to unlock these unstructured data and by doing so allow police to implement more POP initiatives. འོན་ཀྱང་། ང་ཚོས་NLP མིག་སྔར་སྒྲིག་དབྱིབས་བྱ་རིམ་མེད་པའི་གནས་ཚུལ་ནང་གི་དབྱིབས་ཡུལ་གྱིས་ཡང་ན་གསལ་བཤད་སྤྲོད་ཐབས་མེད</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>A Speech-enabled Fixed-phrase Translator for Healthcare Accessibility</title>
      <author><first>Pierrette</first><last>Bouillon</last></author>
      <author><first>Johanna</first><last>Gerlach</last></author>
      <author><first>Jonathan</first><last>Mutal</last></author>
      <author><first>Nikos</first><last>Tsourakis</last></author>
      <author><first>Hervé</first><last>Spechbach</last></author>
      <pages>135–142</pages>
      <abstract>In this overview article we describe an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software">application</a> designed to enable communication between health practitioners and patients who do not share a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lingua_franca">common language</a>, in situations where professional interpreters are not available. Built on the principle of a fixed phrase translator, the application implements different natural language processing (NLP) technologies, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_recognition">speech recognition</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neural_machine_translation">neural machine translation</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_synthesis">text-to-speech</a> to improve usability. Its design allows easy portability to new domains and integration of different types of output for multiple target audiences. Even though BabelDr is far from solving the problem of miscommunication between patients and doctors, it is a clear example of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">NLP</a> in a real world application designed to help minority groups to communicate in a medical context. It also gives some insights into the relevant criteria for the development of such an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_software">application</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="7830b960">2021.nlp4posimpact-1.15</url>
      <doi>10.18653/v1/2021.nlp4posimpact-1.15</doi>
      <bibkey>bouillon-etal-2021-speech</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>