<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.semspace">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-10-27">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the 2021 Workshop on Semantic Spaces at the Intersection of NLP, Physics, and Cognitive Science (SemSpace)</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Martha</first><last>Lewis</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Mehrnoosh</first><last>Sadrzadeh</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Groningen, The Netherlands</address>
      <month>June</month>
      <year>2021</year>
      <url hash="cc726eaa">2021.semspace-1</url>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="b1af6f8a">2021.semspace-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>semspace-2021-2021</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="2">
      <title>LinPP : a Python-friendly algorithm for Linear Pregroup Parsing<fixed-case>L</fixed-case>in<fixed-case>PP</fixed-case>: a Python-friendly algorithm for Linear Pregroup Parsing</title>
      <author><first>Irene</first><last>Rizzo</last></author>
      <pages>12–19</pages>
      <abstract>We define a linear pregroup parser, by applying some key modifications to the minimal parser defined in (Preller, 2007). These include handling words as separate blocks, and thus respecting their syntactic role in the sentence. We prove correctness of our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a> with respect to parsing sentences in a subclass of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pregroup_grammar">pregroup grammars</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm">algorithm</a> was specifically designed for a seamless implementation in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)">Python</a>. This facilitates its integration within the DisCopy module for QNLP and vastly increases the applicability of pregroup grammars to parsing real-world text data.</abstract>
      <url hash="af3b703d">2021.semspace-1.2</url>
      <bibkey>rizzo-2021-linpp</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="3">
      <title>A CCG-Based Version of the DisCoCat Framework<fixed-case>CCG</fixed-case>-Based Version of the <fixed-case>D</fixed-case>is<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>at Framework</title>
      <author><first>Richie</first><last>Yeung</last></author>
      <author><first>Dimitri</first><last>Kartsaklis</last></author>
      <pages>20–31</pages>
      <abstract>While the DisCoCat model (Coecke et al., 2010) has been proved a valuable tool for studying compositional aspects of language at the level of semantics, its strong dependency on pregroup grammars poses important restrictions : first, it prevents large-scale experimentation due to the absence of a pregroup parser ; and second, it limits the expressibility of the model to context-free grammars. In this paper we solve these problems by reformulating DisCoCat as a passage from Combinatory Categorial Grammar (CCG) to a category of semantics. We start by showing that standard categorial grammars can be expressed as a biclosed category, where all rules emerge as currying / uncurrying the identity ; we then proceed to model permutation-inducing rules by exploiting the symmetry of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compact_category">compact closed category</a> encoding the word meaning. We provide a proof of concept for our method, converting Alice in Wonderland into DisCoCat form, a corpus that we make available to the community.</abstract>
      <url hash="0f7ef6ca">2021.semspace-1.3</url>
      <bibkey>yeung-kartsaklis-2021-ccg</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="4">
      <title>Grammar equations</title>
      <author><first>Bob</first><last>Coecke</last></author>
      <author><first>Vincent</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <pages>32–41</pages>
      <abstract>Diagrammatically speaking, grammatical calculi such as pregroups provide wires between words in order to elucidate their interactions, and this enables one to verify grammatical correctness of phrases and sentences. In this paper we also provide wirings within words. This will enable us to identify <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grammatical_construction">grammatical constructs</a> that we expect to be either equal or closely related. Hence, our work paves the way for a new theory of grammar, that provides novel ‘grammatical truths’. We give a nogo-theorem for the fact that our wirings for words make no sense for preordered monoids, the form which grammatical calculi usually take. Instead, they require <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diagram_(category_theory)">diagrams</a>   or equivalently, (free) monoidal categories.</abstract>
      <url hash="7ed3687d">2021.semspace-1.4</url>
      <bibkey>coecke-wang-2021-grammar</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="6">
      <title>Conversational Negation using Worldly Context in Compositional Distributional Semantics</title>
      <author><first>Benjamin</first><last>Rodatz</last></author>
      <author><first>Razin</first><last>Shaikh</last></author>
      <author><first>Lia</first><last>Yeh</last></author>
      <pages>53–65</pages>
      <abstract>We propose a framework to model an operational conversational negation by applying worldly context (prior knowledge) to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logical_negation">logical negation</a> in compositional distributional semantics. Given a word, our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_framework">framework</a> can create its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affirmation_and_negation">negation</a> that is similar to how humans perceive <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affirmation_and_negation">negation</a>. The framework corrects <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Negation">logical negation</a> to weight meanings closer in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logical_consequence">entailment hierarchy</a> more than meanings further apart. The proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_framework">framework</a> is flexible to accommodate different choices of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Negation">logical negations</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Musical_composition">compositions</a>, and worldly context generation. In particular, we propose and motivate a new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Negation">logical negation</a> using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matrix_inverse">matrix inverse</a>. We validate the sensibility of our conversational negation framework by performing experiments, leveraging <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Density_matrix">density matrices</a> to encode graded entailment information. We conclude that the combination of subtraction negation and phaser in the basis of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affirmation_and_negation">negated word</a> yields the highest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pearson_correlation_coefficient">Pearson correlation</a> of 0.635 with human ratings.</abstract>
      <url hash="81541acc">2021.semspace-1.6</url>
      <attachment type="Attachment" hash="822dd668">2021.semspace-1.6.Attachment.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>rodatz-etal-2021-conversational</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="7">
      <title>Parsing conjunctions in DisCoCirc<fixed-case>D</fixed-case>is<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>o<fixed-case>C</fixed-case>irc</title>
      <author><first>Tiffany</first><last>Duneau</last></author>
      <pages>66–75</pages>
      <abstract>In distributional compositional models of meaning logical words require special interpretations, that specify the way in which other words in the sentence interact with each other. So far within the DisCoCat framework, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conjunction_(grammar)">conjunctions</a> have been implemented as merging both conjuncts into a single output, however in the new framework of DisCoCirc merging between nouns is no longer possible. We provide an account of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logical_conjunction">conjunction</a> and an interpretation for the word ‘and’ that solves this, and moreover ensures certain intuitively similar sentences can be given the same interpretations.</abstract>
      <url hash="8af73a29">2021.semspace-1.7</url>
      <attachment type="Attachment" hash="10c37056">2021.semspace-1.7.Attachment.zip</attachment>
      <bibkey>duneau-2021-parsing</bibkey>
    <title_ar>تحليل الاقترانات في DisCoCirc</title_ar>
      <title_es>Análisis de conjunciones en DiscoCirc</title_es>
      <title_pt>Analisando conjunções no DisCoCirc</title_pt>
      <title_ja>DisCoCircで接続を解析する</title_ja>
      <title_zh>解析连词于 DisCoCirc 中</title_zh>
      <title_hi>DisCoCirc में संयोजन पार्स करना</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Comhcheangail a pharsáil i DisCoCirc</title_ga>
      <title_ka>Name</title_ka>
      <title_el>Ανάλυση επιπεφυκών στο DisCoCirc</title_el>
      <title_hu>Kötőhártyák feldolgozása DisCoCirc-ben</title_hu>
      <title_it>Analisi delle congiuntioni in DisCoCirc</title_it>
      <title_lt>DisCoCirc analizavimo jungtys</title_lt>
      <title_kk>DisCoCirc- де қосымшаларды талдау</title_kk>
      <title_mk>Анализирање на конекции во DisCoCirc</title_mk>
      <title_ms>Menghurai sambungan dalam DisCoCirc</title_ms>
      <title_no>Tolkar samlingar i DisCoCirc</title_no>
      <title_ml>ഡിസ്കോസിര്‍ക്കിലെ ബന്ധങ്ങള്‍ പാര്‍സ് ചെയ്യുന്നു</title_ml>
      <title_pl>Analiza spojówek w DisCoCirc</title_pl>
      <title_mt>Konġunzjonijiet tal-analiżi f’DisCoCirc</title_mt>
      <title_mn>DisCoCirc-д холбоотой шинжилгээ</title_mn>
      <title_sr>Analiza konjunkcije u DisCoCirc</title_sr>
      <title_si>Name</title_si>
      <title_ro>Analizarea conjuncţiilor în DisCoCirc</title_ro>
      <title_sv>Tolkning av konjunktioner i DisCoCirc</title_sv>
      <title_so>Heshiiska iskuulka ee DisCorc</title_so>
      <title_ta>வட்டு வட்டில் இணைப்புகளை பார்க்கிறது</title_ta>
      <title_ur>Name</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Name</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Phát hiện kết quả trong DisCoCirc</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Анализиране на конюнкциите при DisCoCirc</title_bg>
      <title_nl>Konjuncties analyseren in DisCoCirc</title_nl>
      <title_da>Fortolkning af konjunktioner i DisCoCirc</title_da>
      <title_hr>Analiziranje konjunkcija u DisCoCirc</title_hr>
      <title_id>Menganalisis kongsi di DisCoCirc</title_id>
      <title_de>Konjunktionen in DisCoCirc analysieren</title_de>
      <title_ko>DiscoCirc에서 연결된 단어의 해석</title_ko>
      <title_fa>تولید اتصال در DisCoCircComment</title_fa>
      <title_af>Verwerking van konjunksies in DisCoCirc</title_af>
      <title_sw>Kuchapisha muungano katika DisCoCirc</title_sw>
      <title_tr>Diňe ködlemeler okamalýar</title_tr>
      <title_am>ዶሴ `%s'ን ማስፈጠር አልተቻለም፦ %s</title_am>
      <title_az>DisCoCirc'da birlikl톛ri analiz톛 edilir</title_az>
      <title_hy>Comment</title_hy>
      <title_bs>Analiziranje konjunkcija u DisCoCircu</title_bs>
      <title_bn>ডিস্কোসির্কে সংযোগ পার্স করা হচ্ছে</title_bn>
      <title_cs>Analýza spojivek v DisCoCircu</title_cs>
      <title_ca>Analitzant conjuncions a DisCoCirc</title_ca>
      <title_fi>Konjunktioiden jäsentäminen DisCoCirc-hoidossa</title_fi>
      <title_et>Konjunktsioonide analüüsimine DisCoCirc korral</title_et>
      <title_sq>Parsing conjunctions in DisCoCirc</title_sq>
      <title_he>התחברות בדיקת DisCoCirc</title_he>
      <title_jv>Gak Cocok</title_jv>
      <title_sk>Razčlenitev veznic pri DisCoCirc</title_sk>
      <title_ha>Parsing conjunctions in DisCoCirc</title_ha>
      <title_bo>DisCoCirc ནང་ཡོད་པའི་མཉམ་འབྲེལ་ལ་བཤད་པ</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>تتطلب النماذج التركيبية التوزيعية للكلمات المنطقية المعنى تفسيرات خاصة تحدد الطريقة التي تتفاعل بها الكلمات الأخرى في الجملة مع بعضها البعض. حتى الآن في إطار عمل DisCoCat ، تم تنفيذ أدوات الاقتران على أنها دمج كلتا الوصلات في ناتج واحد ، ولكن في إطار العمل الجديد لـ DisCoCirc لم يعد الدمج بين الأسماء ممكنًا. نحن نقدم حسابًا لعمليات الاقتران وتفسيرًا لكلمة "و" التي تحل هذه المشكلة ، علاوة على ذلك نضمن إمكانية إعطاء بعض الجمل المتشابهة حدسيًا نفس التفسيرات.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_es>En los modelos de composición distributiva de significado, las palabras lógicas requieren interpretaciones especiales, que especifican la forma en que otras palabras de la oración interactúan entre sí. Hasta ahora, dentro del marco de DiscoCat, las conjunciones se han implementado como la fusión de ambas en una sola salida, sin embargo, en el nuevo marco de DiscoCirc, la fusión entre sustantivos ya no es posible. Proporcionamos una descripción de la conjunción y una interpretación de la palabra «y» que resuelve esto y, además, asegura que ciertas frases intuitivamente similares puedan recibir las mismas interpretaciones.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_pt>Nos modelos de composição distribucional de significado, as palavras lógicas requerem interpretações especiais, que especificam a maneira pela qual outras palavras na frase interagem umas com as outras. Até agora, dentro da estrutura do DisCoCat, as conjunções foram implementadas como mesclando os dois conjuntos em uma única saída, no entanto, na nova estrutura do DisCoCirc, a fusão entre substantivos não é mais possível. Fornecemos uma explicação da conjunção e uma interpretação para a palavra 'e' que resolve isso e, além disso, garante que certas frases intuitivamente semelhantes possam receber as mesmas interpretações.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_ja>意味論理語の分布構成モデルでは、文中の他の語が互いに相互作用する方法を指定する特別な解釈が必要である。これまでのところ、DisCoCatフレームワーク内では、両方の接続詞を単一の出力にマージする接続詞が実装されていますが、DisCoCircの新しいフレームワークでは、名詞間のマージはもはや不可能です。私たちは、これを解決する「and」という単語の結合と解釈の説明を提供し、さらに、特定の直感的に類似した文に同じ解釈を与えることができるようにします。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>义之布合模形,逻辑词须异说,其说指句中单词相为用也。 至目前为止,在DisCoCat框架中,连词已成合两连词为单输,然于DisCoCirc新框架中,名词之间不复可得。 臣等备连词说,单词"and"之说,以决其事,保其似直观之句可与同说。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>अर्थ के वितरणात्मक रचनात्मक मॉडल में तार्किक शब्दों को विशेष व्याख्याओं की आवश्यकता होती है, जो उस तरीके को निर्दिष्ट करते हैं जिसमें वाक्य में अन्य शब्द एक-दूसरे के साथ बातचीत करते हैं। डिस्कोकैट ढांचे के भीतर अब तक, संयोजनों को लागू किया गया है क्योंकि दोनों conjuncts को एक ही आउटपुट में विलय किया गया है, हालांकि डिस्कोसर्क के नए ढांचे में संज्ञाओं के बीच विलय अब संभव नहीं है। हम संयोजन का एक खाता और शब्द 'और' के लिए एक व्याख्या प्रदान करते हैं जो इसे हल करता है, और इसके अलावा यह सुनिश्चित करता है कि कुछ सहज रूप से समान वाक्यों को एक ही व्याख्या दी जा सकती है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>I múnlaí cumadóireachta dáileacháin de bhrí focail loighciúla éilíonn léirmhínithe speisialta, a shonraíonn an chaoi a n-idirghníomhaíonn focail eile san abairt lena chéile. Go dtí seo laistigh de chreat DisCoCat, cuireadh comhcheangail i bhfeidhm mar an dá chónascadh a chumasc in aon aschur amháin, ach ní féidir a thuilleadh i gcreat nua DisCoCirc a chumasc idir ainmfhocail. Cuirimid cuntas ar chomhcheangal agus léirmhíniú ar an bhfocal `agus' a réitíonn é seo, agus a chinntíonn ina theannta sin gur féidir na léirmhínithe céanna a thabhairt d'abairtí áirithe atá cosúil go hintuigthe.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>განსაზღვრებული კომპოზიციონალური მოდელში ლოგიკური სიტყვების განსაზღვრება მოჭირდება სპეციალური განსაზღვრება, რომელიც განსაზღვრებს სხვა სიტყვების შესახებ ერთ ახლა DisCoCat ფრამეტრის შორის შემდეგ კონჯუქციები იყენებულია, როგორც ორივე კონჯუქციები ერთი შემდეგ შემდეგ ერთადერთი შემდეგ, მაგრამ DisCoCirc-ის ახალი ფრამეტრი, რომელიც სახელის ჩვენ შევცვალოთ სიტყვა `და' რომელიც ამას გადაწყვეტის შესახებ და დავცვალოთ განსხვავებული ინტუტიურად მსგავსი სიტყვა იგივე განსხვავება.</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Στα κατανεμητικά συνθηματικά μοντέλα νοήματος οι λογικές λέξεις απαιτούν ειδικές ερμηνείες, οι οποίες καθορίζουν τον τρόπο με τον οποίο οι άλλες λέξεις της πρότασης αλληλεπιδρούν μεταξύ τους. Μέχρι στιγμής στο πλαίσιο του DisCoCat, οι συνδέσεις έχουν εφαρμοστεί ως συγχώνευση και των δύο συναρτήσεων σε μια ενιαία παραγωγή, ωστόσο στο νέο πλαίσιο του DisCoCirc η συγχώνευση μεταξύ ουσιαστικών δεν είναι πλέον δυνατή. Παρέχουμε μια αναφορά σύνδεσης και μια ερμηνεία για τη λέξη "και" που το λύνει αυτό, και επιπλέον εξασφαλίζει ότι ορισμένες διαισθητικά παρόμοιες προτάσεις μπορούν να δοθούν οι ίδιες ερμηνείες.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_hu>Az elosztási kompozíciós modellekben a logikai szavak speciális értelmezéseket igényelnek, amelyek meghatározzák, hogy a mondat más szavai milyen kölcsönhatásba lépnek egymással. Eddig a DisCoCat keretrendszeren belül a kötőhárításokat úgy valósították meg, hogy mindkét kötőhárítást egyetlen kimenetbe egyesítsék, de a DisCoCirc új keretrendszerében már nem lehetséges a főnevek egyesítése. Beszámolunk az együttműködésről és értelmezésről, amely ezt megoldja, és biztosítjuk, hogy bizonyos intuitív módon hasonló mondatok ugyanazokat az értelmezéseket kapjanak.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>Nei modelli compositivi distributivi di significato le parole logiche richiedono interpretazioni speciali, che specificano il modo in cui altre parole nella frase interagiscono tra loro. Finora all'interno del quadro DisCoCat, le congiunzioni sono state implementate come la fusione di entrambi i congiunti in un unico output, tuttavia nel nuovo quadro di DisCoCirc la fusione tra sostantivi non è più possibile. Forniamo un resoconto della congiunzione e un'interpretazione della parola `e' che risolve questo, e inoltre assicuriamo che alcune frasi intuitivamente simili possano essere date le stesse interpretazioni.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>In distributional compositional models of meaning logical words require special interpretations, that specify the way in which other words in the sentence interact with each other.  Iki šiol pagal DisCoCat sistemą buvo įgyvendintos jungtys, nes abi jungtys sujungiamos į vieną išėjimo sistemą, tačiau naujoje DisCoCirc sistemoje jau neįmanoma sujungti vardų. Mes pateikiame sąsajos ir žodžio "ir" aiškinimo ataskaitą, kuri tai išspręstų, taip pat užtikriname, kad tam tikri intuityviai panašūs sakiniai galėtų būti aiškinami taip pat.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_kk>Бөлімдеу үлгілерінде логикалық сөздердің арнайы толықтамаларды талап етеді. Бұл сөздердің басқа сөздердің бір-бірімен әрқашамдастыру жолын келтіреді. DisCoCat бағдарламасының ішінде, екеуін бір шығыс ішінде біріктіру үшін біріктірілді, бірақ DisCoCirc бағдарламасының жаңа бағдарламасында атаулар арасында біріктіру мүмкін емес. Біз "және" сөзінің түсініктемесін және түсініктемесін таңдаймыз, сондай-ақ бір түсініктемесінің бір түсініктемесін көрсетеді.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_ml>അര്‍ത്ഥമായ ലോഗിക്കല്‍ വാക്കുകളുടെ വിതരണ മാതൃകങ്ങളില്‍ പ്രത്യേക വിശദീകരിക്കേണ്ടതുണ്ട്, വാക്കില്‍ മറ്റു വാക്കുകള്‍ പരസ്പരം  ഡിസ്കോക്കാറ്റിന്റെ ഫ്രെയിമ്പിനുള്ളില്‍, രണ്ടുപേരും കൂട്ടിചേര്‍ക്കുന്നതില്‍ ഒരൊറ്റ പുറത്തേക്ക് ചേര്‍ക്കുന്നതായി ബന്ധങ്ങള്‍ പ്രവര്‍ത് ഇത് പരിഹരിക്കുന്ന വാക്കുകള്‍ക്കും ഒരു കണക്കിനെക്കുറിച്ചും ഒരു വിശദീകരണവും നാം നല്‍കുന്നു. അതുപോലെയുള്ള വാക്കുകള്‍ക്കും ഒരേ വ്യാഖ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mt>Fil-mudelli kompożittivi distributtivi ta’ kliem loġiku jfisser jeħtieġu interpretazzjonijiet speċjali, li jispeċifikaw il-mod kif kliem ieħor fis-sentenza jinteraġixxu ma’ xulxin. S’issa fi ħdan il-qafas DisCoCat, il-konġunzjonijiet ġew implimentati bħala l-għaqda taż-żewġ konġunti f’output wieħed, madankollu fil-qafas il-ġdid ta’ għaqda ta’ DisCoCirc bejn in-nomi ma għadux possibbli. Aħna nipprovdu rendikont tal-konġunzjoni u interpretazzjoni għall-kelma `u' li ssolvi dan, u barra minn hekk niżguraw li ċerti sentenzi intwittivament simili jistgħu jingħataw l-istess interpretazzjonijiet.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_mn>Энэ нь хуваарилсан логикийн үгнээс өөр үгнээс харилцаж буй арга хэрэгтэй. DisCoCat-ын хэлбэрээс хойш хоёр холбоотой холбоотой холбоотой нэг үр дүн рүү нэгтгэдэг болохоор холбоотой. Гэхдээ DisCoCirc-ын шинэ хэлбэрээр нэрлэгдлийн хооронд нэгтгэх боломжгүй. Бид үүнийг шийдвэрлэх "мөн" үгийг холбоотой болон түүний тухай тодорхойлолт өгүүлдэг. Мөн үүнийг тодорхойлолтой ижил хэлбэрүүдийг илэрхийлж чадна.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_ms>Dalam model komposisi distribusi makna perkataan logik memerlukan interpretasi istimewa, yang menentukan cara perkataan lain dalam kalimat berinteraksi satu sama lain. Sejauh ini dalam kerangka DisCoCat, sambungan telah dilaksanakan sebagai menyatukan kedua-dua sambungan ke dalam output tunggal, bagaimanapun dalam kerangka baru menyatukan DisCoCirc antara nama tidak lagi mungkin. We provide an account of conjunction and an interpretation for the word `and' that solves this, and moreover ensures certain intuitively similar sentences can be given the same interpretations.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_mk>Во дистрибуционалните композициски модели со логични зборови бараат специјални интерпретации, кои го спецификуваат начинот на кој другите зборови во реченицата взаемнуваат. So far within the DisCoCat framework, conjunctions have been implemented as merging both conjuncts into a single output, however in the new framework of DisCoCirc merging between nouns is no longer possible.  Ние обезбедуваме приказна за поврзаноста и интерпретација на зборот „и“ кој го решава ова, и покрај тоа, осигуруваме дека одредени интуитивно слични реченици можат да бидат дадени истите интерпретации.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_pl>W dystrybucyjnych modelach kompozycyjnych znaczenia słowa logiczne wymagają specjalnych interpretacji, które określają sposób, w jaki inne słowa w zdaniu oddziałują ze sobą. Dotychczas w ramach DisCoCat spojówki zostały wdrożone jako łączenie obu spojówek w jedno wyjście, jednak w nowym ramie DisCoCirc łączenie rzeczowników nie jest już możliwe. Zapewniamy relację połączenia i interpretację słowa "i", które to rozwiązuje, a ponadto gwarantuje, że pewne intuicyjnie podobne zdania mogą być nadane takie same interpretacje.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_no>I distribusjonske komposisjonske modeller for betydning av logiske ord krev spesielle tolkingar, som spesifiserer måten andre ord i setninga saman med kvarandre. Så langt i rammeverket DisCoCat er samlingane implementerte som samlingar begge samlingar til ein enkelt utdata, men i den nye rammeverket av DisCoCirc samlinga mellom namn er ikkje lenger mogleg. Vi gjev eit konto på samband og eit tolking for ordet « og », som løyser dette, og likevel sikker at nokre intuitivt liknande setningar kan gjerast same tolking.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>În modelele compoziționale distribuționale ale semnificației cuvintelor logice necesită interpretări speciale, care specifică modul în care alte cuvinte din propoziție interacționează între ele. Până în prezent, în cadrul DisCoCat, conjuncțiile au fost implementate ca fuzionarea ambelor conjuncte într-o singură ieșire, cu toate acestea, în noul cadru al DisCoCirc fuzionarea dintre substantive nu mai este posibilă. Oferim o relatare a conjuncției și o interpretare a cuvântului `și' care rezolvă acest lucru și, în plus, asigurăm că anumite propoziții similare intuitiv pot fi date aceleași interpretări.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_so>Tusaalada qeybinta ah ee hadallada xirfadda ah waxaa loo baahan yahay turjubaan gaar ah, kaas oo ku qoran qaabka ay erayada kale isugu xiriiraan. Hada waqtigaas gudaheeda DisCoCat waxaa la soo dejiyey isku xiriir ah oo labada isku xir ah laga soo waday midho kaliya, habase yeeshee qashinka cusub ee DisCorc oo noocyada u dhexeeya lama suurtowdo. Waxaannu u siinaynaa koox ku saabsan islamarkaasna turjubaan erayga `iyo' oo taas xalliyeya, waxaana sidoo kale ku hubsanayaa in la siiyo qoraalo isku mid ah.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_sv>I f繹rdelningssammans瓣ttningsmodeller av mening kr瓣ver logiska ord speciella tolkningar, som anger hur andra ord i meningen interagerar med varandra. Hittills inom ramen f繹r DisCoCat har konjunktioner implementerats som sammanslagning av b疇da konjunkterna till en enda output, men i den nya ramen f繹r DisCoCirc 瓣r sammanslagning mellan substantiv inte l瓣ngre m繹jlig. Vi ger en redog繹relse f繹r konjunktion och en tolkning av ordet `och' som l繹ser detta, och s瓣kerst瓣ller dessutom att vissa intuitivt liknande meningar kan ges samma tolkningar.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ta>விதியாசமான தொகுப்பு மாதிரிகளில் சிறப்பு விளக்கங்கள் தேவைப்படுகிறது, அது வாக்கியில் மற்ற வார்த்தைகள் ஒருவருடன் இணைப்பு வ இப்போது DisCoCat சட்டத்திற்குள் உள்ளிருந்து, இணைப்புகள் செயல்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது இரண்டு இணைப்புகளையும் ஒரு வெளியீட்டிற்குள் சேர்க்கிறது, ஆனால 'மற்றும்' என்ற வார்த்தைக்கான ஒரு இணைப்பு கணக்கையும் விளக்கமையையும் நாம் வழங்குகிறோம், அது தீர்வு செய்கிறது, மற்றும் அதே போன்</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_ur>تقسیم کے مطابق منطقی کلمات کے مطابق مخصوص تعبیر کی ضرورت ہے، جس طرح کلمات میں دوسری کلمات ایک دوسرے کے ساتھ تعبیر کرتی ہیں. یہاں تک کہ دیسکوکٹ فرمیک کے اندر، دونوں کنجینٹوں کو ایک اٹوٹ میں جمع کرنے کے طور پر کامل کیا گیا ہے، لیکن ڈیسکوکرک کے نو فرمیک میں ناموں کے درمیان جمع ہونے کا کچھ بھی ممکن نہیں ہے. اور ہم نے اس بات کی تعبیر اور تعبیر کی ہے جو اسے حل کرتی ہے اور اس سے بھی مطمئن ہوتی ہے کہ بعض ایسے کلمات کے مطابق ایک ہی تعبیر مل سکتے ہیں</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_si>විතරයෙන් විතරයෙන් සංවිධානය විශේෂ වචන වර්තනයේ විශේෂ වර්තනය අවශ්‍යයි, ඒකෙන් විශේෂ වචන වර්තනයේ ව DisCoCat ක්‍රියාමාර්ගයක් ඇතුලේ ඉදන් සම්බන්ධ වෙලා තියෙන්නේ, සම්බන්ධ දෙන්නම් සම්බන්ධයක් එක්ක ප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිප්‍රතිකාරයකට අපි සම්බන්ධ වචන සහ 'සම්බන්ධ' වචන සම්බන්ධ වචන සම්බන්ධ වචන සම්බන්ධ වචන සම්බන්ධ වචන සම්බන්ධ වචන සම්බන්ධ වචන සම්බන</abstract_si>
      <abstract_sr>U distribucijskim kompozicionalnim modelima logièkih reèi zahtevaju posebne interpretacije, koje specifikuju način na koji druge reèi u rečenici interakuju jedni sa drugima. Do sada u okviru okvira DisCoCat-a, konjunkcije su provedene kao okupljanje obje konjunkcije u jedinstveni izlaz, međutim u novom okviru DisCoCirc-a koji se okuplja između imena više nije moguće. Mi pružamo račun veze i interpretacije reči `i' koji to reši, a osigurava se da određene intuitivno slične rečenice mogu dati iste interpretacije.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_uz>In distributional compositional models of meaning logical words require special interpretations, that specify the way in which other words in the sentence interact with each other.  Bu yerda DisCoCat freymida ikkita bogʻlamalarni bir tashqi natijaga birlashtirish uchun bajarildi, ammo, yangi DisCoCirc chegarasini faqat narsalar orada birlashtirish mumkin emas. Biz bir xil hisobi va `va' so'zni aniqlash mumkin, va yana bir xil so'zlarni bir xil tarjima qilishga ishonch hosil qilamiz.</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Trong các mô hình phân phối hợp của các từ logic có ý nghĩa cần phải được phân biệt cách diễn tả, chỉ ra cách các từ khác trong câu nói tương tác với nhau. Cho đến nay, trong phạm vi Đĩa Cat, kết hôn đã được thực hiện khi kết hợp cả hai doanh thu thành một kết xuất duy nhất, tuy nhiên trong hệ thống mới của Đĩa Circ nhập giữa các danh từ không còn khả thi nữa. Chúng tôi cung cấp một tài khoản về sự kết hợp và một cách giải thích cho từ "và" giải quyết chuyện này, và còn đảm bảo những câu nói trực tiếp tương tự nhau có thể được đưa ra những cách giải thích giống nhau.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>В разпределителните композиционни модели на значение логическите думи изискват специални интерпретации, които определят начина, по който другите думи в изречението взаимодействат помежду си. Досега в рамките на DisCoCat конюнкциите са реализирани като сливане на двата конюнкта в един изход, но в новата рамка на DisCoCirc сливането между съществителни вече не е възможно. Ние предоставяме описание на съвпадението и тълкуване на думата "и", което решава това, и освен това гарантира, че някои интуитивно сходни изречения могат да бъдат дадени същите тълкувания.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_da>I distributionsmæssige kompositionsmodeller af betydning kræver logiske ord særlige fortolkninger, der specificerer den måde, hvorpå andre ord i sætningen interagerer med hinanden. Indtil videre inden for DisCoCat rammerne er konjunktioner blevet implementeret som at fusionere begge konjunkter til et enkelt output, men i den nye ramme af DisCoCirc er det ikke længere muligt at fusionere mellem substantiver. Vi giver en redegørelse for konjunktion og en fortolkning af ordet `og' der løser dette, og sikrer desuden, at visse intuitivt lignende sætninger kan gives de samme fortolkninger.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_de>In verteilten kompositorischen Bedeutungsmodellen erfordern logische Wörter besondere Interpretationen, die festlegen, wie andere Wörter im Satz miteinander interagieren. Bisher wurden im DisCoCat-Framework Konjunktionen als Zusammenführung beider Konjunkte zu einer einzigen Ausgabe implementiert, im neuen DisCoCirc-Framework ist das Zusammenführen von Substantiven nicht mehr möglich. Wir liefern einen Konjunktionsbericht und eine Interpretation für das Wort `und', die dies löst und darüber hinaus dafür sorgt, dass bestimmte intuitiv ähnliche Sätze die gleichen Interpretationen erhalten können.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_hr>U distribucijskim kompozicionalnim modelima značenja logičkih riječi zahtijevaju posebne interpretacije, koje specificiraju način na koji druge riječi u rečenici interakcije jedni s drugima. Do sada u okviru okvira DisCoCat-a, konjunkcije su provedene kao okupljanje obje konjunkcije u jedinstven izlaz, međutim u novom okviru DisCoCirc-a koji se okuplja između imena više nije moguće. Mi pružamo račun veze i interpretacije riječi `i' koji to riješi, a osigurava se da određene intuitivno slične rečenice mogu dati iste interpretacije.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_ko>의미의 분포 조합 모델에서 논리어는 특수한 해석을 필요로 하고 문장 중의 다른 단어가 상호작용하는 방식을 설명한다.지금까지 디스코캐스트 프레임워크에서 두 개의 연어를 하나의 출력으로 통합하는 것이 실현되었지만 디스코캐스트의 새로운 프레임워크에서는 명사 간의 합병이 더 이상 불가능하다.우리는'and'라는 단어의 연사와 해석에 대해 설명을 하여 이 문제를 해결했고 일부 직감적으로 비슷한 문장이 같은 해석을 할 수 있도록 확보했다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Katika mifano ya usambazaji wa maneno ya mantiki yanahitaji tafsiri maalum, ambayo inabainisha namna ambapo maneno mengine katika hukumu yanahusiana na wao. Mpaka sasa ndani ya mfumo wa DisCoCat, mahusiano yamekwisha kutekelezwa kama kuungana na mahusiano mawili katika matokeo ya moja, hata hivyo katika mfumo mpya wa DisCoCirc unaohusika kati ya hawana uwezekano tena. Tunatoa akaunti ya ushirikiano na tafsiri ya neno “na” ambalo linasuluhisha hili, na pia inahakikisha visa vinavyofanana vinaweza kutolewa tafsiri sawa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_tr>Paýlaşylyk möhüm sözlerin wajyp terjimeleri gerek bolan aýratyn nusgalarda sözlerin bir-birine nähili terjime etmegini takyklaýarlar. DisCoCat çerçevesinde şu ana kadar, ikisini de bir çizgi haline toplayarak işledildi. Ama DisCoCirc'in yeni çizgisinde isimler arasındaki toplanarak artık mümkün değil. Biz bir birleşik we `we' sözlerin çözmesi üçin bir terjime töredip, we munuň üstünde birnäçe diňe meňzeş sözleriň bir terjime edilmegine garaşýarys.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_nl>In distributionele compositiemodellen van betekenis vereisen logische woorden speciale interpretaties, die specificeren hoe andere woorden in de zin met elkaar omgaan. Tot dusver zijn conjuncties binnen het DisCoCat framework geïmplementeerd als het samenvoegen van beide conjuncten in één output, maar in het nieuwe DisCoCirc framework is het samenvoegen van zelfstandige naamwoorden niet meer mogelijk. We geven een overzicht van conjunctie en een interpretatie van het woord 'en' dat dit oplost, en bovendien zorgt dat bepaalde intuïtief vergelijkbare zinnen dezelfde interpretaties kunnen krijgen.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_id>Dalam model komposisi distribusional yang berarti kata logis memerlukan interpretasi khusus, yang menentukan cara kata lain dalam kalimat berinteraksi satu sama lain. Sejauh ini dalam cadangan DisCoCat, konjunksi telah dieksploitasi sebagai menyatukan kedua konjunksi ke satu output, namun dalam cadangan baru DisCoCirc menyatukan antara nama tidak lagi mungkin. Kami menyediakan rekening tentang konjunksi dan interpretasi untuk kata `dan' yang memecahkan hal ini, dan selain itu memastikan kalimat tertentu intuitif sama dapat diberikan interpretasi yang sama.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_sq>Në modelet përbërëse shpërndarëse të fjalëve logjike kërkojnë interpretime të posaçme, që specifikojnë mënyrën në të cilën fjalët e tjera në frazë ndërveprojnë me njëri-tjetrin. Deri tani brenda kuadrit të DisCoCat, lidhjet janë zbatuar si bashkimin e të dy lidhjeve në një dalje të vetme, megjithatë në kuadrin e ri të bashkimit të DisCoCirc midis emrave nuk është më e mundur. Ne ofrojmë një llogari të bashkimit dhe një interpretim për fjalën `dhe' që zgjidh këtë, dhe gjithashtu sigurojmë që disa fjalë të ngjashme intuitivisht mund të jepen të njëjtat interpretime.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_fa>در مدل‌های ترکیب‌کننده‌ای از معنی کلمات منطقی نیاز به ترکیب‌های ویژه‌ای است که راه‌ای که کلمات دیگر در جمله با یکدیگر تعامل می‌کنند مشخص می‌کنند. تا حالا در چهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچهارچها ما حساب اتصال و تعبیر کلمه "و" را برای حل این کلمه قرار می دهیم، و همچنین مطمئن می شود که کلمه‌های مشابه به نظر مشابه می‌شوند.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_am>በአካባቢው አካባቢ ቃላት የሎጂ ቃላት መተርጉም ያስፈልጋል፤ ሌሎች ቃላት በተቃራኒው ቃል እርስ በርሳቸው የሚታያያየው መንገድ ያስታውቃል፡፡ እስከ አሁን ድረስ በDisCoCat ፍሬማር ውስጥ፣ ሁለቱን ግንኙነት በአንድ ውጤት ለመቀላቀል ተደረገ፤ ነገር ግን በአዲስ ውጤት ውስጥ በዲስኮርክ መካከል ማቀናቀል አይቻልም፡፡ ይህንን ለመፈጸም ‹እና› የሚለውን ቃል እናስገራለን፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Լոգիական բառերի բաղադրական մոդելներում անհրաժեշտ են հատուկ մեկնաբանություններ, որոնք նշում են, թե ինչպես են նախադասության այլ բառերը փոխազդում միմյանց հետ: Այս պահին, դիսկոկատի շրջանակներում, հաղորդակցվածքները իրականացվել են որպես երկու հաղորդակցվածքները միավորելու մեկ արտադրության մեջ, սակայն դիսկոցիրքի նոր շրջանակներում անվանումների միջև միավորման հնարավոր չէ: Մենք տրամադրում ենք "և" բառի հաղորդակցման և մեկնաբանության հաղորդակցություն, որը լուծում է սա, և նաև վստահում է, որ որոշ ինտուիտիվ նման նախադասություններ կարող են տալ նույն մեկնաբանությունները:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Bölünmək məlumatın müxtəlif modellərdə mövcud sözlərin xüsusi tərzlərinə ehtiyacı vardır ki, sözlərin başqa sözlərinin bir-birinə qarşılaşdığı yolu belirtir. DisCoCat framework ünün içində, ikisini birlikdə tək bir çıxış içində birlikləndirmək üçün istifadə edilmişdir, amma dişlərin arasında birliklənmiş DisCoCirc yeni frameworkdə artıq mümkün deyildir. Biz bu sözü çəkən "və" sözü ilə birlikdə və yorumlayıcı hesabı təmin edirik. Daha sonra, bəzi cümlələr də eyni yorumlayıcı olaraq təmin edirik.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_bs>U distribucijskim kompozicionalnim modelima značenja logičkih riječi zahtijevaju posebne interpretacije, koje specifikuju način na koji druge riječi u rečenici interakuju jedni sa drugima. Do sada u okviru okvira DisCoCat-a, konjunkcije su provedene kao okupljanje obje konjunkcije u jedinstven izlaz, međutim u novom okviru DisCoCirc-a koji se okuplja između imena više nije moguće. Mi pružamo račun veze i interpretacije riječi `i' koji to riješi, a osiguravamo se da određene intuitivno slične rečenice mogu dati iste interpretacije.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_ca>In distributional compositional models of meaning logical words require special interpretations, that specify the way in which other words in the sentence interact with each other.  Fins ara dins el marc de DisCoCat, les connexions s'han implementat com a fusió de les dues connexions en una sola producció, però en el nou marc de DisCoCirc la fusió entre noms ja no és possible. Ens proporcionem un compte de connexió i una interpretació de la paraula "i" que ho resol i, a més, assegura que certes frases intuïtivament semblants es poden donar les mateixes interpretacions.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_af>In verspreidingskomposisionele modele van betekening logiese woorde benodig spesiale uitleggings, wat spesifiseer die manier waarin ander woorde in die seting interakseer met mekaar. Toe ver binne die DisCoCat raamwerk is konjunksies geïmplementeer as bymekaar konjunksies in 'n enkele uitset, maar in die nuwe raamwerk van DisCoCirc wat tussen noume versamel is nie meer moontlik nie. Ons verskaf 'n rekening van verbinding en 'n uitlegging vir die woord `and' wat dit oplos, en ook sekere intuitief gelyke teikens kan dieselfde uitleggings gegee word.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_fi>Jakelusommittelumalleissa loogiset sanat vaativat erityisiä tulkintoja, jotka määrittävät tavan, jolla lauseen muut sanat ovat vuorovaikutuksessa keskenään. Tähän mennessä DisCoCat-järjestelmässä konjunktiot on toteutettu yhdistämällä molemmat konjunktit yhdeksi tuotokseksi, mutta DisCoCircin uudessa kehyksessä substantiivien yhdistäminen ei ole enää mahdollista. Annamme selvityksen konjunktiosta ja tulkinnan sanalle `ja`, joka ratkaisee tämän, ja lisäksi varmistamme, että tietyt intuitiivisesti samankaltaiset lauseet voidaan antaa samat tulkinnat.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_bn>বিতরণের মানে লজিক শব্দের বিশেষ ব্যাখ্যা দরকার, যেভাবে বিভাগের অন্যান্য শব্দের পরস্পরের সাথে যোগাযোগ করা যায়, তা নির এই পর্যন্ত ডিস্কোক্যাট ফ্রেমের মধ্যে দুটির সংযোগ বাস্তবায়ন করা হয়েছে এক আউটপুটে যুক্ত করার জন্য, কিন্তু ডিসোকার্কের নতুন ফ্রেমের মধ্যে নিষ্ আমরা ‘এবং’ শব্দের জন্য একাউন্ট এবং এক ব্যাখ্যা দিয়েছি যা এটি সমাধান করে এবং তাছাড়া নিশ্চিত যে কিছু বাক্য একই ধরনের ব্যাখ্যা দেয়া যায়।</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_et>Distributsioonilistes tähendusmudelites vajavad loogilised sõnad spetsiaalseid tõlgendusi, mis täpsustavad, kuidas teised lauses olevad sõnad omavahel suhtlevad. Seni on DisCoCati raamistikus konjunktsioone rakendatud nii, et ühendatakse mõlemad konjunktid üheks väljundiks, kuid DisCoCirci uues raamistikus ei ole enam võimalik ühendada nimisõnu. Me anname kontsentratsiooni ja tõlgenduse sõnale `ja', mis lahendab selle, ning lisaks tagab, et teatud intuitiivselt sarnased laused saab anda samasuguseid tõlgendusi.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_cs>V distribučních kompozičních modelech významu logická slova vyžadují zvláštní interpretace, které určují způsob, jakým ostatní slova ve větě vzájemně interagují. V rámci DisCoCat byly doposud implementovány konjunkce jako sloučení obou konjunktů do jednoho výstupu, nicméně v novém rámci DisCoCirc již není možné sloučit mezi podstatnými jmény. Poskytujeme zprávu o spojení a výkladu slova `a', který to řeší, a navíc zajišťujeme, že určité intuitivně podobné věty mohou být dány stejné výklady.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_jv>Nambah-nambah Saiki ono wektu nang diCoCat frame, ngregani dipun dadi iki luwih klebu dipun Awak dhéwé ngewehke tanggal nggambar lan tarjamahan kanggo kelas 'karo' sing beraksi iki, lan uga sawetara sistem sing dianggap perkarahaan kelas kuwi, bisa dianggap perkarahaan langgar sampeyan liyane</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_sk>V distribucijskih kompozicijskih modelih pomena logične besede zahtevajo posebne interpretacije, ki določajo način, kako druge besede v stavku interagirajo med seboj. V okviru DisCoCat so bile konjunkcije doslej uvedene kot združevanje obeh konjunktov v en izhod, vendar v novem okviru DisCoCirca združevanje med samostalniki ni več mogoče. Zagotavljamo poročilo o konjunkciji in interpretaciji besede `in', ki to rešuje, poleg tega pa zagotavljamo, da lahko določeni intuitivno podobni stavki dobijo enake interpretacije.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_he>In distributional compositional models of meaning logical words require special interpretations, that specify the way in which other words in the sentence interact with each other.  עד כה בתוך המסגרת DisCoCat, התחברות הופעו בתור המיזוג של שני התחברות לתוך יציאה אחת, עם זאת במסגרת החדשה של DisCoCirc המיזוג בין השמות כבר לא אפשרי. אנחנו מספקים חשבון של התחברות ופרשנות למילה "ו" שמפתרת את זה, וחוץ מזה מאבטחים שמשפטים דומים באופן אינטואיטיבי מסוימים יכולים לתת את אותו הפרשנות.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_ha>Kuma a cikin misãlai da aka raba masu husũma na maganar logi, yana da amfani da fassarar masu husũma, wannan yana ƙayyade hanyar da wasu kalmõmi da aka yi danganta da shi. To, har a yanzu a cikin firam-DisCoCat, an samar da haɗi biyu kamar haɗuwa da su zuwa wani Outut guda, kuma amma, a cikin firam guda na DisCoCirc da ke haɗa tsakanin nuna, ba za'a iya iya iya ba. Munã samar da wani hisãbi na haɗi da fassarar wa maganar `da' da ke yin rabo da wannan, kuma yana kasa tabbatar da wasu kalmõmi da ke daidaita, za'a iya ba da fassarar da shi daidai.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_bo>དམིགས་བསལ་བྱ་ཚིག་གི་ཆ་རྐྱེན་གྱི་དཔེ་དབྱིབས་གནད་དོན་དག་གི་དམིགས་བསལ་ཚིག་དགོས་པ་དེ་ཚོར་ཚིག་གཞན་ལས་སྦྲེལ་བ་འདྲ་ཡ DisCoCat གཞུང་གི་ནང་དུ་ཆ་མཐུད་གཉིས་ཀྱིས་རྗེས་སུ་འཇུག ང་ཚོས་མཉམ་དུ་ཚོར་བ་དང་གསལ་བ་གཅིག་གི་གནད་དོན་དག་གི་སྒྲུབ་ཀྱི་ཐ་སྙད་ཅིག་བྱིན་ཡོད། དཔེར་ན། གསལ་ཚིག་འདི་ལྟ་བ་བཟུང་བའི་ཚིག་ར</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>