<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection id="2021.hackashop">
  <volume id="1" ingest-date="2021-04-19">
    <meta>
      <booktitle>Proceedings of the EACL Hackashop on News Media Content Analysis and Automated Report Generation</booktitle>
      <editor><first>Hannu</first><last>Toivonen</last></editor>
      <editor><first>Michele</first><last>Boggia</last></editor>
      <publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
      <address>Online</address>
      <month>April</month>
      <year>2021</year>
    </meta>
    <frontmatter>
      <url hash="30c5e14d">2021.hackashop-1.0</url>
      <bibkey>hackashop-2021-eacl</bibkey>
    </frontmatter>
    <paper id="1">
      <title>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection : Leveraging Signals from a Multi-Genre Corpus.</title>
      <author><first>Costanza</first><last>Conforti</last></author>
      <author><first>Jakob</first><last>Berndt</last></author>
      <author><first>Marco</first><last>Basaldella</last></author>
      <author><first>Mohammad Taher</first><last>Pilehvar</last></author>
      <author><first>Chryssi</first><last>Giannitsarou</last></author>
      <author><first>Flavio</first><last>Toxvaerd</last></author>
      <author><first>Nigel</first><last>Collier</last></author>
      <pages>1–7</pages>
      <abstract>Cross-target generalization constitutes an important issue for news Stance Detection (SD). In this short paper, we investigate adversarial cross-genre SD, where knowledge from annotated user-generated data is leveraged to improve news SD on targets unseen during training. We implement a BERT-based adversarial network and show experimental performance improvements over a set of strong <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baseline_(configuration_management)">baselines</a>. Given the abundance of user-generated data, which are considerably less expensive to retrieve and annotate than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Article_(publishing)">news articles</a>, this constitutes a promising research direction.</abstract>
      <url hash="1f6761b2">2021.hackashop-1.1</url>
      <bibkey>conforti-etal-2021-adversarial</bibkey>
    <title_pt>Treinamento Adversarial para Detecção de Posturas de Notícias: Aproveitando Sinais de um Corpus Multigênero.</title_pt>
      <title_ar>التدريب العدائي لاكتشاف الموقف الإخباري: الاستفادة من الإشارات من مجموعة متعددة الأنواع.</title_ar>
      <title_es>Entrenamiento contradictorio para la detección de posturas periodísticas: aprovechamiento de las señales de un corpus multigénero.</title_es>
      <title_ja>ニューススタンス検出のための対抗トレーニング：マルチジェネレータコーパスからの信号を活用する。</title_ja>
      <title_zh>新闻立场检测的对抗性训练:利用多类语料库的信号。</title_zh>
      <title_hi>समाचार रुख का पता लगाने के लिए प्रतिकूल प्रशिक्षण: एक बहु-शैली कॉर्पस से संकेतों का लाभ उठाना।</title_hi>
      <title_ga>Oiliúint Sáraíochta le haghaidh Braite Seasaimh Nuachta: Comhartha a Ghiaráil ó Chorpas Ilchineálach.</title_ga>
      <title_ka>ახალგაზომის სტანსის განვიხოვრება: მრავალგაზომის სტანსიდან სტანსიგურაცია.</title_ka>
      <title_hu>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Jelek kihasználása egy többműfajú Corpus.</title_hu>
      <title_el>Κατάρτιση εναντίων για την ανίχνευση θέσης ειδήσεων: Αξιοποίηση σημάτων από ένα σώμα πολλαπλών ειδών.</title_el>
      <title_it>Formazione adversariale per il rilevamento delle posizioni di notizie: sfruttare i segnali di un corpo multi-genere.</title_it>
      <title_kk>Жаңалық станцияны анықтау үшін конверсариялық оқыту: Көп жанрлық корпус сигналарын көтеру.</title_kk>
      <title_lt>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Leveraging Signals from a Multi-Genre Corpus.</title_lt>
      <title_ms>Latihan lawan untuk pengesan Stensi Berita: Menyerangkan isyarat dari Corpus Multi-Genre.</title_ms>
      <title_ml>വാര്‍ത്ത സ്റ്റേന്‍സ് ഡിറ്ററിക്ടറിന് വേണ്ടി പ്രവർത്തിക്കുന്നതിനുള്ള പരിശീലനം: ഒരു പല ജന്റ് കോർപ്സില്‍ ന</title_ml>
      <title_mk>Отворен тренинг за детективирање на новинските станици: пренесување на сигнали од мултигенерален корпус.</title_mk>
      <title_mt>Taħriġ Adversarjali għad-Detezzjoni tal-Istazzjon tal-Aħbarijiet: Inżidu s-Sinjali minn Korp Multi ġeneriku.</title_mt>
      <title_pl>Szkolenie przeciwników dla wykrywania stanu wiadomości: wykorzystanie sygnałów z korpusu wielu gatunków.</title_pl>
      <title_no>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Leveraging Signals from a Multi-Genre Corpus.</title_no>
      <title_ro>Instruire adversară pentru detectarea stării de știri: valorificarea semnalelor de la un corpus multi-gen.</title_ro>
      <title_sr>Adversarijska obuka za detekciju novinskih stanica: aktiviranje signala iz višegenerskog korpusa.</title_sr>
      <title_so>Waxbarashada horaadka ah ee baaritaanka shaqaalaha ee warqadaha: Signaadaha la soo dirayo ka soo baxay Korpus badan.</title_so>
      <title_mn>Мэдээлэл Стэнц нээлтийн тусламжлалтын дасгал суралцах: олон төрлийн биеийн дамжуулагч сигналууд.</title_mn>
      <title_si>වාර්තාව ස්ථානය හොයාගන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රශ්නයක් ප්‍රශ්නයක්: ගොඩක් ජීනර් කෝපුස් වලි</title_si>
      <title_ta>செய்தி நிலையத்தை கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்கான முன்னேற்பாடு பயிற்சி: பல ஜென்ர் கார்புஸ் இருந்து குறிகைகளை எழுதுதல்.</title_ta>
      <title_sv>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Utnyttja signaler från en flergenres korpus.</title_sv>
      <title_ur>نیویس سٹنس ڈیسٹنس کے لئے مخالف ترینینگ: Multi-Genre Corpus سے سیگنالوں کو لویر کرنے والا ہے.</title_ur>
      <title_uz>Newspaper Stance Tahrirlash uchun eng taʼminlovchi: Multi-Jane Korpusdan imzolangan signallar yozib olish.</title_uz>
      <title_vi>Tin mới phát hiện ra sân bay Tin tức: Tín hiệu cấp độ từ một cơ thể đa Genre.</title_vi>
      <title_bg>Обучение за оползотворяване на сигналите от многожанров корпус.</title_bg>
      <title_da>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Udnyttelse af signaler fra et multi-genre korpus.</title_da>
      <title_hr>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Leveraging Signals from a Multi Genre Corpus.</title_hr>
      <title_id>Pelatihan Adversarial untuk Deteksi Stasiun Berita: mengangkat sinyal dari Multi-Genre Corpus.</title_id>
      <title_de>Adversarial Training zur Nachrichtenstanz Erkennung: Signale aus einem Multi-Genre Corpus nutzen.</title_de>
      <title_ko>뉴스 입장 검측의 대항적 훈련: 다체재 어료 라이브러리에서 온 신호를 이용한다.</title_ko>
      <title_nl>Adversaire training voor nieuwsstandsdetectie: het inzetten van signalen uit een multi-genre corpus.</title_nl>
      <title_sw>Mafunzo ya zamani kwa ajili ya Kuchunguza Uwekezi wa Habari: Ujumbe wa Signaa kutoka kwa Makosa ya Vijana.</title_sw>
      <title_fa>آموزش مصنوعی برای شناسایی استانس خبری: سیگنال‌های تحویل از یک کورپوس متنوعی جنس.</title_fa>
      <title_tr>Täzelikler Stansy deteksiýasy üçin sowgat trening: Multi-Genre Corpus tarapyndan Sinyallary Leveraging Signals.</title_tr>
      <title_sq>Trenimin kundërshtar për zbulimin e stacionit të lajmeve: nxjerrjen e sinjaleve nga një korpus shumë gjeneral.</title_sq>
      <title_am>የዜና ድረ ገጽ ማስታወቂያውን ለጠቅላላ ትምህርት: ብዙዎች የቆርፓስ ሲንጋሎችን መዘዋወር ነው፡፡</title_am>
      <title_af>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Leveraging Signals from a Multi-Genre Corpus.</title_af>
      <title_hy>Զույթների կայանների հայտնաբերման հակառակ վարժանք' բազմագենդերային կորպոսից ազդանշաններ ստանալը:</title_hy>
      <title_az>X…ôb…ôrl…ôr Stensi keŇüfini t…ôhsil etm…ôk: Multi-Genre Corpus'dan Sinyall…ôri t…ôhsil etm…ôk.</title_az>
      <title_bn>সংবাদ স্টেন্স ডিটেক্টরের জন্য প্রাক্তন প্রশিক্ষণ: বহুজেন্ট কোর্পাস থেকে স্বাক্ষরিং স্বাক্ষর।</title_bn>
      <title_ca>Formació adversaria per a la detecció de les estacions de notícies: Extensió de signals d'un cos multigènere.</title_ca>
      <title_cs>Nepřátelský trénink pro detekci zpráv: využití signálů z vícežánrového korpusu.</title_cs>
      <title_bs>Adversarijska obuka za detekciju stanice vijesti: poticanje signala iz višegenerskog korpusa.</title_bs>
      <title_fi>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Hyödynnä signaaleja monigenren korpusista.</title_fi>
      <title_et>Adversarial Training for News Stance Detection: Leveraging Signals from a Multi-Genre Corpus.</title_et>
      <title_he>אימון נוגדי לגילוי עמדת החדשות, מעביר סימנים מגורפוס של מיני רבים.</title_he>
      <title_jv>Advertorial Learning for New Person</title_jv>
      <title_ha>@ info: status</title_ha>
      <title_sk>Opozorilno usposabljanje za zaznavanje stanja novic: izkoriščanje signalov iz večžanrskega korpusa.</title_sk>
      <title_bo>གསར་འགོད་དང་བཅས་ཀྱི་ལྟ་སྟངས་ལ་སྐྱོན་བརྗོད་གཏོང་། སྒྲ་ཚིགས་ཀྱི་རྣམ་པ་སྣ་ཚོགས་ཀྱི་གནད་སྡུད་མེད།</title_bo>
      <abstract_ar>يشكل التعميم عبر الأهداف قضية مهمة بالنسبة لاكتشاف موقف الأخبار (SD). في هذه الورقة القصيرة ، نتحرى عن SD متعدد الأنواع للخصم ، حيث يتم الاستفادة من المعرفة من البيانات المشروحة التي ينشئها المستخدم لتحسين الأخبار SD على الأهداف غير المرئية أثناء التدريب. نحن ننفذ شبكة معارضة قائمة على BERT ونعرض تحسينات تجريبية في الأداء عبر مجموعة من الخطوط الأساسية القوية. نظرًا لوفرة البيانات التي ينشئها المستخدم ، والتي تكون أقل تكلفة بكثير لاستردادها والتعليق عليها من المقالات الإخبارية ، فإن هذا يشكل اتجاهًا بحثيًا واعدًا.</abstract_ar>
      <abstract_pt>A generalização entre alvos constitui uma questão importante para a Detecção de Postura (SD) de notícias. Neste breve artigo, investigamos o SD de gênero cruzado adversário, onde o conhecimento de dados gerados pelo usuário anotados é aproveitado para melhorar o SD de notícias em alvos não vistos durante o treinamento. Implementamos uma rede adversária baseada em BERT e mostramos melhorias de desempenho experimentais em um conjunto de linhas de base fortes. Dada a abundância de dados gerados pelo usuário, que são consideravelmente mais baratos para recuperar e anotar do que artigos de notícias, isso constitui uma direção de pesquisa promissora.</abstract_pt>
      <abstract_es>La generalización de objetivos cruzados constituye un tema importante para la Detección de Postura (SD) de las noticias. En este breve artículo, investigamos la SD contradictoria entre géneros, donde el conocimiento de los datos anotados generados por los usuarios se aprovecha para mejorar la SD de noticias en objetivos no vistos durante el entrenamiento. Implementamos una red de adversarios basada en BERT y mostramos mejoras experimentales de rendimiento en un conjunto de líneas de base sólidas. Dada la abundancia de datos generados por los usuarios, que son considerablemente menos costosos de recuperar y anotar que los artículos de noticias, esto constituye una dirección de investigación prometedora.</abstract_es>
      <abstract_ja>クロスターゲットの一般化は、ニューススタンス検出（ SD ）にとって重要な課題である。この短い論文では、アノテーションされたユーザー生成データからの知識を活用して、トレーニング中に見えないターゲットのニュースSDを改善する対抗的なクロスジャンルSDを調査します。BERTベースの対抗ネットワークを実装し、一連の強力なベースラインにわたって実験的なパフォーマンスの改善を示します。ニュース記事よりも検索やアノテーションのコストがかなり低いユーザー生成データが豊富であることを考えると、これは有望な研究の方向性です。</abstract_ja>
      <abstract_zh>跨者泛化新闻姿检(SD)之要也。 此篇短论,考对抗性跨形SD,因注释之用户,以成数术,改练不见之新闻SD。 施一BERT之抗网络,展一朋之强基线实验性。 鉴用户成之数富,检注之本多于新闻文低得,此一望之所究也。</abstract_zh>
      <abstract_hi>क्रॉस-टारगेट सामान्यीकरण समाचार रुख का पता लगाने (एसडी) के लिए एक महत्वपूर्ण मुद्दा है। इस छोटे से पेपर में, हम प्रतिकूल क्रॉस-शैली एसडी की जांच करते हैं, जहां एनोटेटेड उपयोगकर्ता-जनित डेटा से ज्ञान प्रशिक्षण के दौरान अनदेखी लक्ष्यों पर समाचार एसडी को बेहतर बनाने के लिए लीवरेज किया जाता है। हम एक BERT-आधारित प्रतिकूल नेटवर्क को लागू करते हैं और मजबूत बेसलाइन के एक सेट पर प्रयोगात्मक प्रदर्शन सुधार दिखाते हैं। उपयोगकर्ता-जनित डेटा की बहुतायत को देखते हुए, जो समाचार लेखों की तुलना में पुनर्प्राप्त करने और एनोटेट करने के लिए काफी कम महंगे हैं, यह एक आशाजनक अनुसंधान दिशा का गठन करता है।</abstract_hi>
      <abstract_ga>Is saincheist thábhachtach é ginearálú tras-sprioc maidir le Brath Seasaimh nuachta (SD). Sa pháipéar gairid seo, déanaimid imscrúdú ar SD tras-seánra sáraíochta, áit a ndéantar eolas ó shonraí anótáilte arna ghiniúint ag úsáideoirí a ghiaráil chun SD nuachta a fheabhsú ar spriocanna nach bhfeictear le linn oiliúna. Cuirimid líonra sáraíochta bunaithe ar BERT i bhfeidhm agus léirímid feabhsuithe feidhmíochta turgnamhacha thar shraith bonnlínte láidre. Ag cur san áireamh an iliomad sonraí a ghintear ag úsáideoirí, atá i bhfad níos saoire le haisghabháil agus le nótaí a dhéanamh ná ailt nuachta, is treoir thaighde a bhfuil gealladh fúthu.</abstract_ga>
      <abstract_ka>ძირითადი გენერალიზაცია იყო გასანიშვნელოვანი პრობლემა ინფორმაციის Stance Detection (SD). ამ კონტაქტის წიგნაში, ჩვენ განსხვავებთ განსაზღვრებული კრესგენერის SD, სადაც მომხმარებული მომხმარების მონაცემების ცნობიერება მომხმარებული მონაცემების განსაზღვრებული მონაცემებ ჩვენ BERT-ის განსაკუთრებულ საქაღალდეს გამოყენებთ და გამოჩვენებთ ექსპერიმენტიური გამოსაკუთრებულება ძალიან ფესტილის ნაწილზე. მომხმარებლის შექმნილი მონაცემების მდინარეობა, რომლებიც ძალიან უფრო ცოტა საკმაოდ აღმოჩენა და აღმოჩენა, ვიდრე ახალგაზომის მონაცემებისთვის, ეს არის საკმაოდ</abstract_ka>
      <abstract_el>Η γενικοποίηση μεταξύ στόχων αποτελεί σημαντικό ζήτημα για την ανίχνευση θέσης ειδήσεων (SD). Σε αυτή τη σύντομη εργασία, ερευνούμε την αντιπαραβολή μεταξύ των ειδών όπου η γνώση από σχολιασμένα δεδομένα που παράγονται από τους χρήστες χρησιμοποιείται για τη βελτίωση των ειδήσεων σε στόχους που δεν φαίνονται κατά τη διάρκεια της εκπαίδευσης. Εφαρμόζουμε ένα αντίπαλο δίκτυο βασισμένο στον BERT και παρουσιάζουμε πειραματικές βελτιώσεις απόδοσης σε ένα σύνολο ισχυρών βασικών γραμμών. Δεδομένης της αφθονίας δεδομένων που παράγονται από τους χρήστες, τα οποία είναι σημαντικά λιγότερο ακριβά στην ανάκτηση και σχολιασμό από τα άρθρα ειδήσεων, αυτό αποτελεί μια ελπιδοφόρα ερευνητική κατεύθυνση.</abstract_el>
      <abstract_kk>Жаңалық Станс анықтау (SD) үшін маңызды мәселе болады. Бұл қысқақ қағазында, біз белгілі көптеген SD-ті зерттейміз. Бұл жерде пайдаланушылардың құрылған деректерінің білімі оқыту кезінде белгілмеген мақсаттары туралы жаңалық SD-ті Біз BERT негіздеген негізгі желі істеп, тәжірибелі негізгі жолдардың жақсартуларын көрсетедік. Пайдаланушылар құрылған деректердің көпшілігін көрсеткен, бұл жаңалық мақалалардан артық алу және түсініктіру үшін көпшілік емес, бұл зерттеу бағыты.</abstract_kk>
      <abstract_hu>A cross-target általánosítás fontos kérdést jelent a hírek Stance Detection (SD). Ebben a rövid tanulmányban az ellenséges műfajok közötti SD-t vizsgáljuk, ahol a jegyzetelt felhasználók által generált adatokból származó ismereteket felhasználjuk a képzés során láthatatlan célpontokra vonatkozó hírek SD javítására. BERT alapú ellenséges hálózatot hozunk létre, és kísérleti teljesítményfejlesztéseket mutatunk számos erős alapkészleten felül. Tekintettel a felhasználók által generált adatok bőségére, amelyek jelentősen kevésbé költségesek, mint a hírek, ez ígéretes kutatási irányt jelent.</abstract_hu>
      <abstract_it>La generalizzazione cross-target costituisce una questione importante per la rilevazione dello Stance Detection (SD). In questo breve articolo, indaghiamo sulla SD avversaria cross-genre, dove la conoscenza dei dati generati dagli utenti annotati viene sfruttata per migliorare la SD delle notizie su obiettivi invisibili durante l'allenamento. Implementiamo una rete avversaria basata su BERT e mostriamo miglioramenti sperimentali delle prestazioni su una serie di solide linee di base. Data l'abbondanza di dati generati dagli utenti, che sono notevolmente meno costosi da recuperare e annotare rispetto agli articoli di notizie, questo costituisce una direzione di ricerca promettente.</abstract_it>
      <abstract_lt>Tarptautinis generalizavimas yra svarbus naujienų padėties nustatymo klausimas. In this short paper, we investigate adversarial cross-genre SD, where knowledge from annotated user-generated data is leveraged to improve news SD on targets unseen during training.  Įgyvendiname BERT grindžiamą prieštaringą tinklą ir parodome eksperimentinius rezultatų pagerėjimus įvairiose pagrindinėse linijose. Atsižvelgiant į naudotojų sukauptų duomenų, kurie yra gerokai mažiau brangūs surinkti ir anotuoti nei naujienų straipsniai, skaičių, tai yra perspektyvi mokslinių tyrimų kryptis.</abstract_lt>
      <abstract_mk>Крстометна генерализација претставува важно прашање за новинската детективност на станиците (СД). Во оваа кратка вест, истражуваме противнички крстогенер СД, каде што знаењето од анотираните податоци генерирани од корисникот се искористува за подобрување на вестите СД за целите кои не се видени за време на обуката. Ние имплементираме противничка мрежа базирана на БЕРТ и покажуваме експериментални подобрувања на резултатите преку сет силни бази. Со оглед на бројот на податоци генерирани од корисникот, кои се значително помалку скапи за собирање и анотирање од вестите, ова претставува ветувачка насока за истражување.</abstract_mk>
      <abstract_mt>Ġeneralizzazzjoni transkonfinali tikkostitwixxi kwistjoni importanti għad-Detezzjoni tal-Istanza tal-Aħbarijiet (SD). F’dan id-dokument qasir, ninvestigaw SD ta’ ġeneru trasversali avversarju, fejn l-għarfien minn dejta annotata ġġenerata mill-utent jiġi sfruttat biex jittejjeb SD ta’ aħbarijiet dwar miri li ma jidhrux waqt it-taħriġ. Aħna nimplimentaw netwerk avversarju bbażat fuq BERT u nuru titjib sperimentali fil-prestazzjoni fuq sett ta’ linji bażi b’saħħithom. Minħabba l-abbundanza ta’ dejta ġġenerata mill-utenti, li hija konsiderevolment inqas għalja biex tinkiseb u tiġi annotata mill-artikoli tal-a ħbarijiet, dan jikkostitwixxi direzzjoni promettenti ta’ riċerka.</abstract_mt>
      <abstract_ms>Pengumuman sasaran-salib merupakan isu penting untuk pengesan Stance (SD) berita. Dalam kertas pendek ini, kami menyelidiki SD cross-genre musuh, di mana pengetahuan dari data yang dihasilkan pengguna yang dicatat digunakan untuk meningkatkan SD berita pada sasaran yang tidak terlihat semasa latihan. We implement a BERT-based adversarial network and show experimental performance improvements over a set of strong baselines.  Mengingat banyak data yang dijana oleh pengguna, yang jauh lebih mahal untuk mendapatkan dan anotasi daripada artikel berita, ini merupakan arah penyelidikan yang berjanji.</abstract_ms>
      <abstract_ml>Cross-target generalization constitutes an important issue for news Stance Detection (SD).  ഈ ചെറിയ പേപ്പറില്‍, നമ്മള്‍ വിരോധമായ ക്രിസ്ജെന്‍ എസ്ഡിയില്‍ അന്വേഷിക്കുന്നു. പരിശീലനത്തില്‍ അഭ്യസിക്കാത്ത ലക്ഷ്യങ്ങളില്‍ നിന്ന ബെര്‍ട്ടി അടിസ്ഥാനമായ ഒരു വിരോധമായ നെറ്റര്‍ക്ക് പ്രവര്‍ത്തിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. പരീക്ഷണത്തിന്റെ പ്രവർത്തനങ്ങള്‍ ഒര ഉപയോക്താവ് സൃഷ്ടിച്ച വിവരങ്ങളുടെ സമൃദ്ധിയായ വിവരങ്ങള്‍ കൊണ്ട്, വാര്‍ത്ത കല്ലുകളെക്കാള്‍ വിലയേറെയും വിവരിക്കാനും വളരെ വിലയേറെയ</abstract_ml>
      <abstract_mn>Олон-зорилготой ерөнхийлөгч байдал нь мэдээллийн Стэнс Detection (SD) дэх чухал асуудал юм. Энэ богино цаасан дээр бид эсэргүүцлийн олон төрлийн SD-г судалж, хэрэглэгчийн өгөгдлийн мэдлэг нь сургалтын үед харагдаагүй зорилго дээр мэдээллийн SD-г сайжруулах хэрэгтэй. Бид БЕРТ-д суурилсан эсрэг сүлжээ хийж, туршилтын үйл ажиллагааны сайжруулалтыг маш хүчтэй суурилуулалт дээр харуулж байна. Хэрэглэгчийн гаргасан өгөгдлийн ихэнх нь мэдээллээс илүү бага үнэтэй. Энэ нь мэдээллийн баримтуудыг авч, сэтгэл хөдлөл өгдөг.</abstract_mn>
      <abstract_no>Generalisering av kryss- mål er ein viktig problem for oppdaging av nyhetsverktøy (SD). I denne korte papiren undersøker vi adversarialt kryssgjenre SD, der kunnskap frå oppmerkte brukaragente er levert til å forbetra nyhetsstyrke for SD om mål som ikkje er vist under opplæring. Vi implementerer ein BERT-basert adversarial nettverk og viser eksperimentelt forbetringar over eit sett sterke baselinjer. Gjennomsiktig mykje store data som er genererte av brukarar, som er mindre kostnad for å henta og oppmerka enn nyhetseinstillingar, er dette eit velkommande forskningsretning.</abstract_no>
      <abstract_ro>Generalizarea cross-target constituie o problemă importantă pentru detectarea stării de știri (SD). În această lucrare scurtă, investigăm SD-uri adversare cross-gen, unde cunoștințele din datele generate de utilizatori adnotate sunt folosite pentru a îmbunătăți SD-urile știrilor despre țintele nevăzute în timpul antrenamentului. Implementăm o rețea adversară bazată pe BERT și prezentăm îmbunătățiri experimentale ale performanței pe un set de linii de bază puternice. Având în vedere abundența datelor generate de utilizatori, care sunt considerabil mai puțin costisitoare pentru a recupera și adnota decât articolele de știri, aceasta constituie o direcție de cercetare promițătoare.</abstract_ro>
      <abstract_sr>Generalizacija krstomete predstavlja važan problem za detekciju vesti Stance (SD). U ovom kratkom papiru istražujemo neprijateljski krstogenarni SD, gdje se znanje od annotiranih podataka koji su generirani korisnici utiče na poboljšanje vijesti o SD-u o mete koje nisu vidjele tokom treninga. Mi implementiramo na BERT baziranu neprijateljsku mrežu i pokazujemo eksperimentalne poboljšanje učinka na setu jakih osnovnih linija. S obzirom na ogromnost podataka od korisnika, koje su mnogo manje skupe da se uzmu i annotiraju od novih članaka, to predstavlja obećavajuće istraživanje smjere.</abstract_sr>
      <abstract_so>Dhaqaalaha iskuullada waxaa ka mid ah arrin muhiim ah oo la xiriira baaritaanka warbixinta (SD). Qoraalkan gaaban waxaynu ka baaraynaa SD-da cadaawayaasha ah, meesha aqoonta laga soo saaray macluumaadka isticmaalayaasha si loo hagaajiyo SD oo ku saabsan waxyaabaha aan la ogayn waqtiga waxbarashada. Waxaynu sameeynaa shabakad cadaawayaal ah oo BERT ku saleysan, waxaana tusnaa horumarinta sameynta sameynta sameynta jirrabka oo ka badan saldhigyo xoog badan. Sida darteed macluumaad badan oo la soo sameeyey isticmaalayaasha, kuwaas oo aad ugu qiimo yar in la helo oo la dhibaateeyo wax ka badan warqadaha warqadaha warqada ah, taasi waxaa ka mid ah hagitaan waxbarashada oo loo ballanqaaday.</abstract_so>
      <abstract_pl>Uogólnienie między celami stanowi ważną kwestię dla wiadomości Stance Detection (SD). W tym krótkim artykule badamy przeciwne między gatunkami SD, gdzie wiedza z adnotacji danych generowanych przez użytkownika jest wykorzystywana do poprawy wiadomości SD na celach niewidocznych podczas treningu. Wdrażamy sieć przeciwniczą opartą na BERT i pokazujemy eksperymentalne poprawy wydajności w zestawie silnych linii bazowych. Biorąc pod uwagę obfitość danych generowanych przez użytkowników, które są znacznie tańsze w pobieraniu i adnotacji niż artykuły wiadomościowe, stanowi to obiecujący kierunek badań.</abstract_pl>
      <abstract_si>ක්‍රොස් ලක්ෂණ සාමාන්‍ය විශ්වාස කරන්න ප්‍රශ්නයක් නිර්මාණය ස්ටැන්ස් හොයාගන්න (SD) ගැන. මේ කොටස් පැත්තේ, අපි විරෝධ විරෝධ විශ්වාසික විශ්වාසික SD පරීක්ෂණය කරනවා, කොහෙද ප්‍රශ්නයක් වෙනුවෙන් නැහැ ඉලක්ක අපි BERT අධාරිත විරෝධ ජාලයක් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා ඒ වගේම ප්‍රයෝජනයක් ප්‍රයෝජනය කරනවා බලාපොරොත්තු ප ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න පුළුවන් සිද්ධිත දත්ත ගොඩක් බලාපොරොත්තු වෙනුවෙන්, ඒවා වාර්තාව ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න ප්‍රයෝජනය කරන්න සහ</abstract_si>
      <abstract_ta>கிருஸ்- இலக்கு உருவாக்கம் செய்தி ஸ்டென்ஸ் கண்டுபிடிப்பதற்கு ஒரு முக்கியமான பிரச்சனை உண்டு. இந்த சிறிய காகிதத்தில், நாம் எதிர்பார்க்கப்பட்ட சிறிய மரபணுக்குறியீடு SD ஐ ஆராய்ச்சி செய்கிறோம். பயிற்சியில் காணப்படாத செய நாம் ஒரு BERT-அடிப்படையிலான எதிர்பார்வை பிணையத்தை நிறைவேற்றுகிறோம் மற்றும் சோதனையான செயல்பாடு முன்னேற் செய்தி கட்டுரைகளை விட குறைவாகவும் மற்றும் அறிவிப்பதற்காகவும் பயனர் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட தகவல்களின் மிகப்பெரும்பாலானது, இது வாக்களிக்கப</abstract_ta>
      <abstract_sv>Cross-target generalisering är en viktig fråga för nyheter Stance Detection (SD). I den här korta uppsatsen undersöker vi adversarial cross-genre SD, där kunskap från kommenterad användargenererad data utnyttjas för att förbättra nyhetsSD på mål som inte syns under träning. Vi implementerar ett BERT-baserat nätverk och visar experimentella prestandaförbättringar över en uppsättning starka baslinjer. Med tanke på överflödet av användargenererade data, som är betydligt billigare att hämta och kommentera än nyhetsartiklar, utgör detta en lovande forskningsriktning.</abstract_sv>
      <abstract_ur>Cross-target generalization constitutes an important issue for news Stance Detection (SD). اس چھوٹے کاغذ میں، ہم مخالف کرس ژنر SD کی تحقیق کرتے ہیں، جہاں استعمال میں غیب کی موجودات کے بارے میں اخبار SD کو اچھی طرح دکھائی جاتی ہے۔ ہم ایک BERT بنیادی مقابلہ نیٹ ورک کی عملی کرتے ہیں اور ایک مجموعہ مضبوط بنیاس لین کے ذریعہ آزمائش کی عملیات کو دکھاتے ہیں. کارساز کے پیدا کئے ہوئے ڈیٹے کی بہت زیادتی کے باعث، جو اخباروں کے مقالہ سے کم خرچ ہیں، اس کا وعدہ دار تحقیق کی طرف سے ہے.</abstract_ur>
      <abstract_uz>Name Bu qisqa hujjatda biz juda qisqarli shaxsiy shaxsiy SD'ni boshqaramiz. Bu yerda foydalanuvchi yaratilgan maʼlumot yozib olingan foydalanuvchining yaratilgan maʼlumot SD haqida maʼlumotni o'zgartirish uchun yordam beradi. Biz BERT asosiy tarmoqni bajaramiz va bir qanchalik asboblar bilan tajriba bajarishni bajaramiz. @ info: status</abstract_uz>
      <abstract_vi>Thông thường xuyên xuyên mục tiêu là một vấn đề quan trọng cho việc phát hiện thời trang (SD). Trong bài viết ngắn này, chúng tôi nghiên cứu đối thủ lai giống mà SD, nơi mà kiến thức từ dữ liệu được ghi chú tạo ra người dùng được hỗ trợ để nâng cao báo cáo về SD về những mục tiêu không bị phát hiện trong huấn luyện. Chúng tôi thiết lập một mạng lưới đối nghịch dựa trên BERT và cho thấy khả năng thử nghiệm cải tiến trên các bản nền vững chắc. Dựa vào số lượng dữ liệu được tạo ra từ người dùng, mà còn ít tốn kém hơn nhiều để thu hồi và ghi chú hơn các báo chí, đây là một hướng nghiên cứu đầy hứa hẹn.</abstract_vi>
      <abstract_bg>Кръстоцелевото обобщаване представлява важен въпрос за откриването на състоянието на новините (УД). В тази кратка статия ние изследваме съперническите междужанрови данни, където знанията от анотирани данни, генерирани от потребителите, се използват за подобряване на новините за цели, невиждани по време на обучението. Ние внедряваме базирана на BERT мрежа за съперничество и показваме експериментални подобрения в ефективността на набор от силни базови линии. Предвид изобилието от генерирани от потребителите данни, които са значително по-евтини за извличане и анотиране от новинарските статии, това представлява обещаваща насока на научните изследвания.</abstract_bg>
      <abstract_nl>Cross-target generalisatie is een belangrijk onderwerp voor nieuws Stance Detection (SD). In dit korte artikel onderzoeken we tegenstrijdige cross-genre SD, waarbij kennis van geannoteerde user-generated data wordt benut om nieuws SD te verbeteren op doelen die niet tijdens de training worden gezien. We implementeren een op BERT gebaseerd tegenstrijdig netwerk en tonen experimentele prestatieverbeteringen over een reeks sterke baselines. Gezien de overvloed aan door gebruikers gegenereerde data, die aanzienlijk goedkoper zijn om op te halen en te annoteren dan nieuwsberichten, vormt dit een veelbelovende onderzoeksrichting.</abstract_nl>
      <abstract_da>Cross-target generalisering udgør et vigtigt spørgsmål for nyheder Stance Detection (SD). I denne korte artikel undersøger vi modstandsdygtighed på tværs af genrer, hvor viden fra annoterede brugergenererede data udnyttes til at forbedre nyhedsdygtigheder om mål, der ikke ses under træning. Vi implementerer et BERT-baseret modstandernetværk og viser eksperimentelle forbedringer i forhold til et sæt stærke basislinjer. I betragtning af overfloden af brugergenererede data, som er betydeligt billigere at hente og kommentere end nyhedsartikler, udgør dette en lovende forskningsretning.</abstract_da>
      <abstract_hr>Generalizacija krstomete predstavlja važno pitanje za otkrivanje vijesti Stance (SD). U ovom kratkom papiru istražujemo neprijateljski krstogenarni SD, gdje se znanje od annotiranih podataka koji su proizvedeni korisnicima utječe na poboljšanje vijesti o SD-u o ciljevima koje nisu vidjele tijekom obuke. Provedemo na BERT-u neprijateljsku mrežu i pokazujemo eksperimentalne poboljšanje učinka na skupu jakih osnovnih linija. S obzirom na ogromnost podataka koji su proizvedeni od korisnika, koje su značajno manje skupe za prikupljanje i annotaciju od novih članaka, to predstavlja obećavajuće istraživanje smjere.</abstract_hr>
      <abstract_id>Cross-target generalization constitutes an important issue for news Stance Detection (SD).  Dalam kertas singkat ini, kami menyelidiki SD cross-genre musuh, di mana pengetahuan dari data yang dibuat oleh pengguna yang dicatat digunakan untuk meningkatkan SD berita pada sasaran yang tidak terlihat selama latihan. Kami menerapkan jaringan musuh berdasarkan BERT dan menunjukkan perkembangan eksperimen prestasi di atas set garis dasar yang kuat. Mengingat banyak data yang dibuat oleh pengguna, yang jauh lebih mahal untuk mendapatkan dan anotasi daripada artikel berita, ini merupakan arah penelitian yang berjanji.</abstract_id>
      <abstract_fa>ژنرال‌سازی متصل هدف یک مسئله مهم برای بازرسی گزارش استنس (SD) است. ما در این کاغذ کوتاه تحقیق می کنیم که دانش از داده های تولید شده از استفاده‌کننده‌ها در حال تحقیق اخبار SD در مورد هدف‌هایی که در طول آموزش غیب‌شده‌اند، تحقیق نمی‌کنند. ما یک شبکه دشمنی بر بنیاد BERT را اجرای می کنیم و بهترین انجام آزمایشی را در مجموعه پایگاه‌های قوی نشان می دهیم. با توجه به فراوانی داده های تولید شده از کاربر، که به اندازه کافی گرون تر از مقاله های اخبار می‌گیرند، این یک مسیر تحقیقات قول می‌دهد.</abstract_fa>
      <abstract_ko>목표를 뛰어넘는 범위화는 뉴스 입장 검측의 중요한 문제이다.이 단문에서 우리는 대항적인 크로스 유형 SD, 즉 사용자가 생성한 주석 데이터의 지식을 이용하여 훈련 기간에 목표를 발견하지 못한 뉴스 SD를 개선하는 것을 연구했다.우리는 BERT 기반의 대항적 네트워크를 실현했고, 강력한 기선에서 실험적 성능 개선을 보여 주었다.대량의 사용자가 생성한 데이터를 감안하여 검색과 주석은 뉴스 기사보다 훨씬 싸다. 이것은 매우 유망한 연구 방향이다.</abstract_ko>
      <abstract_sw>Uzalishaji wa shambulio la Cross unaleta suala muhimu kwa ajili ya Uchunguzi wa Habari (SD). Katika gazeti hili fupi, tunachunguza SD inayotokana na upinzani, ambapo maarifa kutoka kwa taarifa zinazozaliwa na watumiaji wanaotumia vibaya imetumiwa ili kuboresha habari za SD kuhusu malengo yasiyofahamika wakati wa mafunzo. Tunatekeleza mtandao wa upinzani wa BERT na kuonyesha maendeleo ya utendaji wa mazoea zaidi ya misingi yenye nguvu. Kutokana na kiasi kikubwa cha taarifa zilizotengenezwa kwa watumiaji, ambazo ni ghali sana kupata na kutangaza zaidi ya makala za habari, hii inaleta mwelekeo wa utafiti unaotarajiwa.</abstract_sw>
      <abstract_de>Die zielübergreifende Generalisierung stellt ein wichtiges Thema für News Stance Detection (SD) dar. In diesem kurzen Beitrag untersuchen wir gegensätzliche genreübergreifende SD, bei der Wissen aus kommentierten benutzergenerierten Daten genutzt wird, um Nachrichten-SD auf Zielen zu verbessern, die während des Trainings nicht gesehen werden. Wir implementieren ein BERT-basiertes adversariales Netzwerk und zeigen experimentelle Leistungsverbesserungen über eine Reihe starker Baselines auf. Angesichts der Fülle von nutzergenerierten Daten, die wesentlich kostengünstiger zu finden und zu kommentieren sind als Nachrichtenartikel, stellt dies eine vielversprechende Forschungsrichtung dar.</abstract_de>
      <abstract_af>Kruis- doel generellisering is 'n belangrike probleem vir nuus Stance Deteksie (SD). In hierdie kort papier, ondersoek ons teenstandaarlike kruisgenre SD, waar kennis van annotateerde gebruiker genereerde data verplig word om nuus SD te verbeter op doels wat onbesigtig is by onderwerp. Ons implementeer 'n BERT-gebaseerde teenstandaarde netwerk en wys eksperimentale prestasie verbeteringe oor 'n stel sterke basisline. Gien die oorvloedigheid van gebruiker genereerde data, wat is betekenlik minder koste om nuusartikels te ontvang en te annoteer, is dit 'n beloftende ondersoek rigting.</abstract_af>
      <abstract_sq>Përgjeneralizimi ndërobjektiv përbën një çështje të rëndësishme për zbulimin e stacionit të lajmeve (SD). Në këtë letër të shkurtër, ne hetojmë SD të gjenerës kundërshtare, ku njohuritë nga të dhënat e gjeneruara nga përdoruesit janë përdorur për të përmirësuar SD të lajmeve mbi objektivat e padukshme gjatë trajnimit. Ne zbatojmë një rrjet kundërshtar me bazë në BERT dhe tregojmë përmirësime eksperimentale të performancës mbi një sërë linjash bazë të forta. Given the abundance of user-generated data, which are considerably less expensive to retrieve and annotate than news articles, this constitutes a promising research direction.</abstract_sq>
      <abstract_tr>Täzelikler Stans deteksiyony (SD) üçin gaty maksady döredir. Bu gysga kagyzda, biz düşmanlyk çerçe-çeşit SD-i barlaýarys, nähili usulçylar tarapyndan bilgi ýüzerinde görülmeýän maksadlary üçin SD täzeliklerini geliştirmek üçin ýüzelendirilýäris. BERT-dan daýanýan döwlet şebekini implement edip, güýçli döwletler üstünde experimental ukyplaryň gelişmelerini görkez. Ullançylar tarapyndan janlaşdyrylýan maglumatlaryň köpüsi görä, bu täzeliklerden alyp barmak we täzeliklerden has kiçi gymmatdyr, bu söz berýän araştyrymyň yöntemi.</abstract_tr>
      <abstract_bn>ক্রস-লক্ষ্যবস্তুতে সংবাদ স্টেন্স ডিটেকশন (এসডি) এর জন্য একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ বিষয়। এই সংক্ষিপ্ত পত্রিকায়, আমরা বিরোধী বিভিন্ন ব্যবহারকারীদের ক্ষেত্রে জ্ঞানের তথ্য অনুসন্ধান করি, যেখানে প্রশিক্ষণের সময় অদৃশ্য টার্গ আমরা বিবেরেট ভিত্তিক বিরোধী নেটওয়ার্ক ব্যবস্থা করি এবং পরীক্ষার কার্যক্রমের উন্নতি প্রদর্শন করি কয়েকটি শক্তিশালী বেস সংবাদ প্রবন্ধের চেয়ে পুনরুদ্ধার এবং মনোযোগ প্রদান করার জন্য ব্যবহারকারীদের উৎপাদন করা তথ্যের বেশীর ভাগ দেয়া হয়েছে, এটি একটি প্রতিশ্র</abstract_bn>
      <abstract_am>የግንኙነት አቀማመጥ የዜና ድረ-ምርጫዎች (SD) ጉዳይ ነው፡፡ በዚህ አካላት፣ በተቃዋሚ የሥልጣዊ ቋንቋ SD እናምርመራለን፡፡ የትኛውም ተማሪዎች ውስጥ ያልታወቀ የሆኑት ተጠቃሚዎች አካባቢ ዳታዎችን ለማሻሻል እናውቃለን፡፡ We implement a BERT-based adversarial network and show experimental performance improvements over a set of strong baselines.  ከዜና ጽሑፎች ይልቅ ለማግኘትና ለማስታወስ በጣም የከበረ የሆኑት ተጠቃሚዎች የዳታ ብዛት ቢሆን ይህ የተስፋ የጥናት መረጃ መግለጫ ነው፡፡</abstract_am>
      <abstract_hy>Միջնշանակային ընդհանուր ընդլայնումը կարևոր խնդիր է նորությունների Ստենսի Դեկտիվացիայի (ՍՍ) համար: Այս կարճ թղթի մեջ մենք ուսումնասիրում ենք հակառակ խաչը գենդերային դիմադրություն, որտեղ օգտագործողների կողմից ստեղծված տվյալներից ստացված գիտելիքները օգտագործվում են օգտագործողների կողմից ստեղծված տվյալների մասին, որպեսզի բարելավեն սո Մենք իրականացնում ենք BER-ի հիմնված հակառակորդական ցանց և ցույց ենք տալիս փորձարկվող արդյունքների բարելավումներ ուժեղ հիմնական գծերի վրա: Եթե հաշվի առնենք օգտագործողների կողմից ստեղծված տվյալների բազմաթիվ, որոնք ավելի քիչ թանկ են վերցնելու և նշում, քան նորությունների հոդվածները, սա խոստացող ուսումնասիրության ուղղություն է:</abstract_hy>
      <abstract_az>Xüsusi məqsəd generalizasyonu xəbərlər Stance Detection (SD) üçün vacib bir məsəl edir. Bu qısa kağıtda, biz düşmənçilik çox geniş SD təhsil edirik, ki, təhsil sırasında görmədikləri məqsədilər barəsində xəbərləri SD ilə yaxşılaşdırmaq üçün bilgi yaradılır. Biz BERT tabanlı düşmənçi a ğı təyin edirik və bir çox qüvvətli sətir üstündə eksperimental performanslıq uzlaşmalarını göstəririk. İstifadəçilərin yaratdığı məlumatların çoxluğuna görə, xəbər məlumatlarından alınmaq və nəticə etmək üçün daha az mal olan məlumatların çoxluğuna görə, bu və ’ d verici araştırma yöntemidir.</abstract_az>
      <abstract_ca>Cross-target generalization constitutes an important issue for news Stance Detection (SD).  En aquest curt article, investigam SD de gènere transversal adversari, on el coneixement de dades anotates generades per a millorar SD de notícies sobre objectius no vists durant l'entrenament. Implementam una xarxa adversaria basada en BERT i demostram millors experimentals en un conjunt de línies de base fortes. Tenint en compte l'abundància de dades generades per l'usuari, que són considerablement menys costoses per recuperar i anotar que els articles de notícia, això és una direcció prometedora de recerca.</abstract_ca>
      <abstract_bs>Generalizacija krstomete predstavlja važan problem za detekciju novosti Stance (SD). U ovom kratkom papiru istražujemo neprijateljski krstogenarni SD, gdje se znanje od annotiranih podataka koji su generirani korisnicima utiče na poboljšanje vijesti o SD-u o ciljevima koje nisu vidjele tijekom treninga. Mi implementiramo na BERT baziranu neprijateljsku mrežu i pokazujemo eksperimentalne poboljšanje učinka na skupu jakih osnovnih linija. S obzirom na opskrbu podataka od korisnika, koje su značajno manje skupe za prikupljanje i annotaciju od novih članaka, to predstavlja obećavajuće istraživanje smjere.</abstract_bs>
      <abstract_cs>Cross-target generalizace představuje důležitou otázku pro zprávy Stance Detection (SD). V tomto krátkém článku zkoumáme protižánrovou SD, kde jsou znalosti z anotovaných uživatelsky generovaných dat využívány ke zlepšení zpráv SD na cílech neviděných během tréninku. Implementujeme protiprávní síť založenou na BERT a ukazujeme experimentální zlepšení výkonu v souboru silných základních linií. Vzhledem k množství uživatelsky generovaných dat, jejichž vyhledávání a anotování je podstatně levnější než zpravodajské články, představuje to slibný směr výzkumu.</abstract_cs>
      <abstract_et>Sihtmärgiülene üldistamine on oluline teema uudiste seisundi tuvastamisel (SD). Käesolevas lühikeses töös uurime konkurentsivõimelist žanriülest SD-d, kus kasutajate genereeritud andmetest saadud teadmisi kasutatakse, et parandada uudiste SD-d treeningu ajal nähtamatute sihtmärkide osas. Rakendame BERT-põhist konkurentsivõrgustikku ja näitame eksperimentaalseid tulemuslikkuse paranemisi tugevate lähtejoontega võrreldes. Arvestades kasutajate loodud andmete hulka, mida on märkimisväärselt odavam hankida ja märkida kui uudisteartikleid, kujutab see endast paljulubavat uurimissuunda.</abstract_et>
      <abstract_fi>Cross-target yleistäminen on tärkeä asia uutisten Stance Detection (SD) kannalta. Tässä lyhyessä artikkelissa tutkimme ristiriitaista genren välistä SD-muistia, jossa käyttäjän tuottamaa tietoa hyödynnetään parantamaan uutisten SD-muistia harjoituksen aikana näkymättömissä kohteissa. Toteutamme BERT-pohjaisen vastustajaverkoston ja näytämme kokeellisia suorituskykyparannuksia vahvojen lähtölinjojen pohjalta. Tämä on lupaava tutkimussuunta, kun otetaan huomioon käyttäjien tuottaman datan runsaus, jota on huomattavasti halvempi hakea ja kommentoida kuin uutisartikkeleita.</abstract_fi>
      <abstract_jv>ProgressBarUpdates Nang Paper-Ngerungke iki, kita sissisuhi perusahaan kelas-Genr Awak dhéwé éntuk sistem sing paling BERT tambah kuwi nggawe gerakan oleh operasan luwih apik dhéwé kuwi nggawe aturan sing paling nggawe Dino nganggo akeh data Generasi, sing paling nggampang kuwi dianggap luwih dumateng kanggo ngilanggar tarjamahan kanggo ingkang balêt, iki dadi sing perusahaan kelas perusahaan winih</abstract_jv>
      <abstract_ha>General shawarar-aim na ƙididdige wani masu muhimu wa Sauti Stance (SD). Ina cikin wannan takardan nan ƙaranci, Munã tambaya SD-n-mai motsi, inda ilmi daga data wanda aka ƙididdige wa mai amfani da shi ya samu zuwa a samar da lãbãri SD a kan sikẽyen da ba'a sani ba a lokacin da za'a yi amfani da shi. Tuna samar da wani shirin bakin BERT mai bastarwa kuma Muke nũna mazaɓa na aikin jarrabo a kan wasu misãlai masu ƙarfi. Gida yawan data wanda aka haife shi mai amfani da shi, waɗand a bã ya kasancẽwa mai yiwuwa ga retrieve kuma ana zartar da shi mafi kyauta daga makala na lãbãri, wannan yana cikin shirin research mai yi wa'adi.</abstract_ha>
      <abstract_he>הגנרליזציה הצלבית מייצגת בעיה חשובה לחדשות גילוי סטאנס (SD). בעיתון הקצר הזה, אנו חוקרים את סוג הצלב היריב SD, היכן הידע ממידע שנוצר ע"י משתמשים מועטף כדי לשפר חדשות SD על מטרות בלתי נראות במהלך האימונים. אנחנו מפעילים רשת יריבים מבוססת על BERT ולהראות שיפורים ניסויים ביצועים מעל קבוצה של קווי בסיס חזקים. בהתחשב בהרבה של נתונים יוצרים ע"י משתמשים, שהם הרבה פחות יקרים להשיג ולהערות מאמר חדשות, זה יוצר כיוון מחקר מבטיח.</abstract_he>
      <abstract_sk>Navzkrižna posplošitev predstavlja pomembno vprašanje za zaznavanje stanja novic (SD). V tem kratkem prispevku raziskujemo kontradiktorsko medžanrsko SD, kjer se znanje iz označenih uporabniških podatkov uporabnikov uporablja za izboljšanje SD novic o ciljih, ki jih med usposabljanjem niso opazili. Vzpostavljamo kontradiktorsko mrežo, ki temelji na BERT, in prikazujemo eksperimentalne izboljšave zmogljivosti v sklopu močnih osnovnih linij. Glede na obilico podatkov, ki jih ustvarijo uporabniki, ki so precej cenejši za pridobivanje in označevanje kot novinarski članki, je to obetavna smer raziskav.</abstract_sk>
      <abstract_bo>Cross-target generalization is an important issue for news Stance Detection (SD). འོག་གི་ཤོག་བུ་འདི་ཆུང་མཚམས་ནང་དུ་འོང་ཚོས་དུས་མཐུན་པའི་གནད་དོན་དག་གི་སྒེར་གྱི་ཐབས་ལམ་ལ་ཞིབ་བཤེར་བྱེད་ཀྱི་ཡོད། ང་ཚོས་BERT་ལྟ་བུའི་གདོང་འབྲེལ་མཐུད་དྲ་ཞིག་ལག་སྟར་བྱེད་པའམ་སྒྲིག་གཏོང་གི་མཐའ་འཁོར་སྐྱོད་རྒྱས་གཏོང བྱས་ཙང་། སྤྱོད་མཁན་གྱི་འབྱུང་བའི་ཆ་འཕྲིན་ཡིག་ཆ་ལ་ཉུང་བའི་ཚད་གཞི་ཡིན་པས་གསར་འགྱུར་གྱི་ཡིག་ཆ་ལས་ཕར་ལེན་བྱས་ཉེས་མེད།</abstract_bo>
      </paper>
    <paper id="10">
      <title>Aligning Estonian and Russian news industry keywords with the help of subtitle translations and an environmental thesaurus<fixed-case>E</fixed-case>stonian and <fixed-case>R</fixed-case>ussian news industry keywords with the help of subtitle translations and an environmental thesaurus</title>
      <author><first>Andraž</first><last>Repar</last></author>
      <author><first>Andrej</first><last>Shumakov</last></author>
      <pages>71–75</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents the implementation of a bilingual term alignment approach developed by Repar et al. (2019) to a dataset of unaligned Estonian and Russian keywords which were manually assigned by journalists to describe the article topic. We started by separating the dataset into Estonian and Russian tags based on whether they are written in the Latin or Cyrillic script. Then we selected the available language-specific resources necessary for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alignment_system">alignment system</a> to work. Despite the domains of the language-specific resources (subtitles and environment) not matching the domain of the dataset (news articles), we were able to achieve respectable results with manual evaluation indicating that almost 3/4 of the aligned keyword pairs are at least partial matches.</abstract>
      <url hash="c67461bb">2021.hackashop-1.10</url>
      <bibkey>repar-shumakov-2021-aligning</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="12">
      <title>Comment Section <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personalization">Personalization</a> : Algorithmic, Interface, and Interaction Design</title>
      <author><first>Yixue</first><last>Wang</last></author>
      <pages>84–88</pages>
      <abstract>Comment sections allow users to share their personal experiences, discuss and form different opinions, and build communities out of organic conversations. However, many comment sections present chronological ranking to all users. In this paper, I discuss personalization approaches in comment sections based on different objectives for newsrooms and researchers to consider. I propose algorithmic and interface designs when personalizing the presentation of comments based on different objectives including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relevance">relevance</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diversity_(politics)">diversity</a>, and education / background information. I further explain how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transparency_(behavior)">transparency</a>, user control, and comment type diversity could help users most benefit from the personalized interacting experience.</abstract>
      <url hash="fb016a8e">2021.hackashop-1.12</url>
      <bibkey>wang-2021-comment</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="14">
      <title>EMBEDDIA Tools, Datasets and Challenges : Resources and Hackathon Contributions<fixed-case>EMBEDDIA</fixed-case> Tools, Datasets and Challenges: Resources and Hackathon Contributions</title>
      <author><first>Senja</first><last>Pollak</last></author>
      <author><first>Marko</first><last>Robnik-Šikonja</last></author>
      <author><first>Matthew</first><last>Purver</last></author>
      <author><first>Michele</first><last>Boggia</last></author>
      <author><first>Ravi</first><last>Shekhar</last></author>
      <author><first>Marko</first><last>Pranjić</last></author>
      <author><first>Salla</first><last>Salmela</last></author>
      <author><first>Ivar</first><last>Krustok</last></author>
      <author><first>Tarmo</first><last>Paju</last></author>
      <author><first>Carl-Gustav</first><last>Linden</last></author>
      <author><first>Leo</first><last>Leppänen</last></author>
      <author><first>Elaine</first><last>Zosa</last></author>
      <author><first>Matej</first><last>Ulčar</last></author>
      <author><first>Linda</first><last>Freienthal</last></author>
      <author><first>Silver</first><last>Traat</last></author>
      <author><first>Luis Adrián</first><last>Cabrera-Diego</last></author>
      <author><first>Matej</first><last>Martinc</last></author>
      <author><first>Nada</first><last>Lavrač</last></author>
      <author><first>Blaž</first><last>Škrlj</last></author>
      <author><first>Martin</first><last>Žnidaršič</last></author>
      <author><first>Andraž</first><last>Pelicon</last></author>
      <author><first>Boshko</first><last>Koloski</last></author>
      <author><first>Vid</first><last>Podpečan</last></author>
      <author><first>Janez</first><last>Kranjc</last></author>
      <author><first>Shane</first><last>Sheehan</last></author>
      <author><first>Emanuela</first><last>Boros</last></author>
      <author><first>Jose G.</first><last>Moreno</last></author>
      <author><first>Antoine</first><last>Doucet</last></author>
      <author><first>Hannu</first><last>Toivonen</last></author>
      <pages>99–109</pages>
      <abstract>This paper presents tools and data sources collected and released by the EMBEDDIA project, supported by the European Union’s Horizon 2020 research and innovation program. The collected resources were offered to participants of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackathon">hackathon</a> organized as part of the EACL Hackashop on News Media Content Analysis and Automated Report Generation in February 2021. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackathon">hackathon</a> had six participating teams who addressed different challenges, either from the list of proposed challenges or their own news-industry-related tasks. This paper goes beyond the scope of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackathon">hackathon</a>, as it brings together in a coherent and compact form most of the resources developed, collected and released by the EMBEDDIA project. Moreover, it constitutes a handy source for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News_media">news media industry</a> and researchers in the fields of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing">Natural Language Processing</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_science">Social Science</a>.</abstract>
      <url hash="956a7f13">2021.hackashop-1.14</url>
      <bibkey>pollak-etal-2021-embeddia</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="15">
      <title>A COVID-19 news coverage mood map of Europe<fixed-case>COVID</fixed-case>-19 news coverage mood map of <fixed-case>E</fixed-case>urope</title>
      <author><first>Frankie</first><last>Robertson</last></author>
      <author><first>Jarkko</first><last>Lagus</last></author>
      <author><first>Kaisla</first><last>Kajava</last></author>
      <pages>110–115</pages>
      <abstract>We present a COVID-19 news dashboard which visualizes sentiment in pandemic news coverage in different languages across Europe. The dashboard shows analyses for positive / neutral / negative sentiment and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morality">moral sentiment</a> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Article_(publishing)">news articles</a> across countries and languages. First we extract <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Article_(publishing)">news articles</a> from news-crawl. Then we use a pre-trained multilingual BERT model for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis">sentiment analysis</a> of news article headlines and a dictionary and word vectors -based method for moral sentiment analysis of news articles. The resulting dashboard gives a unified overview of news events on COVID-19 news overall sentiment, and the region and language of publication from the period starting from the beginning of January 2020 to the end of January 2021.</abstract>
      <url hash="a33c2c51">2021.hackashop-1.15</url>
      <bibkey>robertson-etal-2021-covid</bibkey>
    </paper>
    <paper id="16">
      <title>Interesting cross-border news discovery using cross-lingual article linking and document similarity</title>
      <author><first>Boshko</first><last>Koloski</last></author>
      <author><first>Elaine</first><last>Zosa</last></author>
      <author><first>Timen</first><last>Stepišnik-Perdih</last></author>
      <author><first>Blaž</first><last>Škrlj</last></author>
      <author><first>Tarmo</first><last>Paju</last></author>
      <author><first>Senja</first><last>Pollak</last></author>
      <pages>116–120</pages>
      <abstract>Team Name : team-8 Embeddia Tool : Cross-Lingual Document Retrieval Zosa et al. Dataset : Estonian and Latvian news datasets abstract : Contemporary news media face increasing amounts of available data that can be of use when prioritizing, selecting and discovering new news. In this work we propose a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methodology">methodology</a> for retrieving interesting articles in a cross-border news discovery setting. More specifically, we explore how a set of seed documents in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estonian_language">Estonian</a> can be projected in Latvian document space and serve as a basis for discovery of novel interesting pieces of Latvian news that would interest Estonian readers. The proposed methodology was evaluated by Estonian journalist who confirmed that in the best setting, from top 10 retrieved Latvian documents, half of them represent news that are potentially interesting to be taken by the Estonian media house and presented to Estonian readers.</abstract>
      <url hash="275a0935">2021.hackashop-1.16</url>
      <bibkey>koloski-etal-2021-interesting</bibkey>
    </paper>
    </volume>
</collection>